<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00686543</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is: to explore the potential for different dosing strategies of posaconazole oral suspension (POS) to increase plasma levels and to profile the pharmacokinetics of these dosing strategies in patients with compromised gastrointestinal function and at high risk for Invasive Fungal Infection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Oral Posaconazole in High Risk Patients With Gastrointestinal Dysfunction (Study P05115)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neutropenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycoses</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Posaconazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects &gt;=18 years of age High risk of poor enteral medication absorption, based on the effects of cytotoxic chemotherapy, as evidenced by, but not limited to, mucositis, nausea, vomiting, and diarrhea, at baseline. High risk of invasive fungal infection (IFI) based on anticipated or documented prolonged neutropenia (absolute neutrophil count [ANC] &lt;500/mm^3 [0.5 x 10^9/L]). Clinical laboratory safety tests within normal limits or clinically acceptable to the investigator or sponsor. Free of any clinically significant disease (other than the primary hematologic disease) that would interfere with the study evaluations. Subjects must be willing to give written informed consent and able to adhere to dosing, study visit schedule, and mandatory procedures. Female subjects who are pregnant, intend to become pregnant, or are nursing. Excluded prior treatments. Subjects receiving systemic antifungal therapy (oral, intravenous, or inhaled) for the treatment of proven or probable IFI within 30 days of Enrollment (ie, voriconazole, fluconazole [FLU], or itraconazole [ITZ]). Subjects receiving posaconazole for prophylaxis against IFI 10 days prior to enrollment. (Subjects who are receiving either voriconazole or micafungin for prophylaxis against IFI should discontinue those therapies upon enrollment.) Subjects with moderate or severe liver dysfunction at Baseline, defined as aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) levels greater than two times the upper limit of normal (ULN), or a total bilirubin level greater than two times the ULN. Subjects who have taken prohibited medications more recently than the indicated washout period prior to Enrollment. Subjects who must take prohibited medications during the study. Subjects who are in a situation or have any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with optimal participation in the study. Subjects who have used any investigational drugs or biologic agents other than their chemotherapy regimens within 30 days of study entry. Subjects who are part of the staff personnel directly involved with this study. Subjects who are a family member of the investigational study staff. Prior enrollment in this study. Subjects with a history of hypersensitivity or idiosyncratic reactions to azole agents. Subjects with Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status &gt;2 prior to induction chemotherapy for their underlying disease. Subjects with proven or probable invasive or systemic fungal infection at Baseline. Subjects with a history of acute lymphoblastic leukemia or chronic myelogenous leukemia without blast crisis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Antifungal Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-Infective Agents</keyword>
</DOC>