<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01658813</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether the combination of a 5-Fluorouracil (5-FU) and interferon, which is able to stimulate the immune system to kill cancer cells, will help to increase tumor shrinkage in previously-treated metastatic gastrointestinal, kidney, or lung Cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>5-Fluorouracil Followed by Interferon-alfa-2b in Previously-treated Metastatic Gastrointestinal, Kidney, or Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Interferon with continuous infusion 5-Fluorouracil (5-FU) regimens have shown response rates ranging from 0-43% in various cancers. Monthly bolus 5-FU + interferon-alfa-2b has not undergone formal phase II testing. In a small pilot study, a 5 consecutive day schedule of 5-FU and interferon-alfa-2b resulted in the limiting toxicities of diarrhea and mucositis. A more limited schedule was recommended. Therefore, it is reasonable to examine such a schedule. In the current study, 5-FU will be followed by interferon-alfa-2b daily for 3 days to attempt to benefit from both the biochemical and immunologic mechanisms described above.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have histologicallyproven, metastatic gastrointestinal, kidney, or lung cancer who have had disease progression on at least two prior systemic therapies. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0, 1, or 2 and estimated survival of at least 3 months. Patients must be felt to have recovered from effects of prior therapy, such as past expected white blood count nadir for chemotherapy (&gt; 2 weeks for most agents, &gt; 6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycinC) Patient consent must be obtained prior to entrance onto study. White blood count &gt; 3500/mm3; platelet count of at least 100,000/mm3; hemoglobin &gt; 9.0 gm/dl; bilirubin, Aspartate aminotransferase (AST), Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) less than 3 times the upper limit of normal; serum creatinine &lt; 1.8. Corticosteroids and immunosuppressive agents are not permitted during the course of the study. Patients must have received no corticosteroids or immunosuppressive medications at least 2 weeks prior to entrance onstudy. Patients with elevated temperatures &gt; 100.5 degrees F, must have sources of occult infection excluded. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test and must take adequate precautions to prevent pregnancy during treatment. Evidence of significant cardiovascular disease including history of recent (&lt; 6 months) myocardial infarction, uncompensated congestive heart failure, primary cardiac arrhythmias (not due to electrolyte disorder or drug toxicity, for example) beyond occasional PVC's, angina, or cerebrovascular accident. Prior history of psychiatric disorder that could be exacerbated by interferon therapy or which could preclude completion of this therapy. Pregnancy or lactation. History of hypersensitivity to interferon alfa or fluoropyrimidines. History of severe debilitating pulmonary disease, such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease requiring continuous oxygen therapy. History of autoimmune disease requiring immunosuppression. Documented inflammatory joint or systemic inflammatory disease (such as Lupus) which could be exacerbated by interferon therapy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic Gastrointestinal</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic Kidney</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic Lung</keyword>
</DOC>