<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01334268</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the in-stent late lumen loss (LLL) at 9 months, defined as the difference between the post-procedure minimal lumen diameter (MLD) and the follow-up angiography MLD, of the Resolute Zotarolimus-Eluting Coronary Stent System compared to Taxus Liberte Paclitaxel-Eluting Coronary Stent System in a real-world all-comer patient population requiring stent implantation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Resolute Zotarolimus-Eluting Stent Versus the Taxus Liberte Paclitaxel-Eluting Stent for Percutaneous Coronary Intervention in China</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a prospective, multicenter, randomized, two-arm, open-label study, designed to assess the non-inferiority of Resolute stent compared to Taxus Liberte stent in in-stent late lumen loss. The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the in-stent late lumen loss (LLL) at 9 months, defined as the difference between the post-procedure minimal lumen diameter (MLD) and the follow-up angiography MLD, of the Resolute Zotarolimus-Eluting Coronary Stent System compared to Taxus Liberte Paclitaxel-Eluting Coronary Stent System in a real-world all-comer patient population requiring stent implantation. This trial will be conducted at approximately 20 sites and will enroll up to 400 subjects, randomized to the Resolute stent and Taxus Liberte stent in a 1:1 ratio. Subjects will be randomized using an interactive voice response system (IVRS). Due to the design characteristics of the devices, the study investigators and operators can not be blinded. However, the clinical event adjudication committee, consisting of cardiologists who are not participating in the study, will be blinded for the treatment arm of the subjects to avoid a potential bias in the adjudication process of events.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arteriosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient must meet all of the following criteria to be eligible for treatment in the trial: 1. Age ≥ 18 years or minimum age as required by local regulations 2. The patient is an acceptable candidate for treatment with a drugeluting stent in accordance with the applicable guidelines on percutaneous coronary interventions, the Instructions for Use of the Resolute stent and Taxus Liberte stent and the Declaration of Helsinki 3. The patient or legal representative has been informed of the nature of the trial and has consented to participate and authorized the collection and release of his/her medical information by signing a Patient Informed Consent Form 4. Intention to electively implant at least one Resolute stent or Taxus Liberte stent 5. The patient is willing and able to cooperate with study procedures and required follow up visits Patients will be excluded from the trial if any of the following criteria are met: 1. Known intolerance to aspirin, clopidogrel or ticlopidin, heparin, bivalirudin, cobalt, nickel, chromium, molybdenum, 316L stainless steel, polymer coatings (e.g. Biolinx), zotarolimus, paclitaxel, rapamycin, tacrolimus, everolimus, or any other analogue or derivative, or contrast media 2. Women with known pregnancy or who are lactating 3. High probability of nonadherence to the followup requirements (due to social, psychological or medical reasons) 4. Currently participating in another trial that has not completed the primary endpoint or that clinically interferes with the current trial requirements 5. Planned surgery within 6 months of PCI unless dual antiplatelet therapy is maintained throughout the perisurgical period 6. Previous enrollment in the Resolute China RCT</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>In-stent Late Lumen Loss (LLL)</keyword>
	<keyword>TARGET VESSEL FAILURE (TVF)</keyword>
	<keyword>MYOCARDIAL INFARCTION (MI)</keyword>
	<keyword>TARGET VESSEL REVASCULARIZATION (TVR)</keyword>
	<keyword>TARGET LESION REVASCULARIZATION (TLR)</keyword>
	<keyword>TARGET LESION FAILURE (TLF)</keyword>
	<keyword>STENT THROMBOSIS</keyword>
	<keyword>RESTENOTIC LESION</keyword>
	<keyword>PERCUTANEOUS CORONARY INTERVENTION (PCI)</keyword>
	<keyword>REAL-WORLD</keyword>
	<keyword>THE RANDOMIZED CONTROLLED TRIAL</keyword>
</DOC>