<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01334346</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The following study proposes to investigate the injury risk associated with the use of a new category of running footwear: the minimalist shoe. A group of experienced adult male and female runners with neutral foot types will take part in this study. All participants will be randomized to receive one of three different shoes: a full minimalist shoe (Vibram 5-Fingers), a partial minimalist shoe (Nike Free 3.0) and a conventional neutral supportive running shoe (Nike Pegasus), while training for a 10k event over a 14-week period. Outcomes to be investigated are pain, footwear perception, and number of injury events. The hypothesizes is that participants using the minimalist footwear during their running program will experience a reduction in running related pain. A greater degree of footwear minimalism will result in a greater reduction in pain (compared to the partial minimalist shoe, Nike Free).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Footwear Minimalism Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Minimum of 5 years experience running Have been running on a regular basis (minimum once per week) over the past 6 months Able to run for 60 minutes continuously Can tolerate 2040km per week in training Neutral foot posture according to the Foot Posture Index. Have not experienced a running related injury requiring a stoppage of 2weeks or more in the past 6 months History of surgery to their plantar fascia or Achilles tendon Have already been running in a minimalist shoe Have a diagnosis of osteoarthritis or other degenerative musculoskeletal disorder affecting the lower extremity Are currently taking analgesic medication.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Running</keyword>
	<keyword>Footwear</keyword>
	<keyword>Injury incidence</keyword>
	<keyword>injury risk</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
</DOC>