<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01144819</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: Dual antithrombotic treatment with aspirin and clopidogrel is recommended in patients with ST elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) undergoing primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI). The European Society of Cardiology (ESC) Guidelines recommend a bolus dose of aspirin of 250-500 mg and a 600 mg bolus dose of clopidogrel as soon as STEMI is suspected. Studies have shown that more newly produced platelets are present in the acute phase of STEMI, and it is likely that these immature platelets are haemostatically more active and might be of importance in thrombus formation. The enhanced platelet reactivity may reduce the effect of aspirin and clopidogrel in the acute phase of STEMI compared to measurements made in the same patients 3 months after primary PCI. Aim: This study aims to compare platelet response to aspirin and clopidogrel in the acute phase of STEMI with the platelet response in the same patients 3 months after STEMI . Design: This study is an observational follow-up study. Materials and methods: 46 patients with STEMI referred to primary PCI at Aarhus University Hospital, Skejby will be included in the study. A total of 3 blood samples are obtained in the acute phase of STEMI: Prior to primary PCI (Blood sample 1), at 4 hours (Blood sample 2) and at 12 hours (Blood sample 3) after administration of loading dose aspirin and clopidogrel. When patients are in a stable phase 3 month later, a final blood sample is taken (Blood sample 4). The blood is analyzed 30 minutes after withdrawal of blood by the platelet aggregation test Multiplate® aggregometry (agonists: Collagen, arachidonic acid and adenosinediphosphate) and VerifyNow® arachidonic acid and P2Y12 aggregometry. Platelet count, volume and the immature platelet fraction (IPF) will be measured using Sysmex® flowcytometry.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Platelet Inhibition in the Acute Phase of STEMI</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Above 18 years of age Patients with STsegment elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) referred to primary PCI at University Hospital of Aarhus, Skejby. Treatment with NSAID, ticlopidine and dipyramidole. Treatment with anticoagulants (Vitamin K antagonists) Patients diagnosed with platelet disease or haemophilia. Patients unable to give written, informed consent to participation in this project.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>STEMI</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute myocardial infarction</keyword>
	<keyword>Antiplatelet therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>aspirin</keyword>
	<keyword>clopidogrel</keyword>
	<keyword>VerifyNow aggregometry</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiplate aggregometry</keyword>
</DOC>