<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="52261">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02425826</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CC-10004-PSOR-012</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02425826</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT02555826</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase 4 Study of Efficacy and Safety of Apremilast in Subjects With Moderate Plaque Psoriasis.</brief_title>
  <acronym>UNVEIL</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 4, Multicenter, Randomized, Placebo-controlled, Double-blind, Study of the Efficacy and Safety of Apremilast (CC-10004) in Subjects With Moderate Plaque Psoriasis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Celgene Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Celgene Corporation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will evaluate the clinical efficacy, patients quality of life, satisfaction, and
      safety of oral apremilast 30 mg twice daily (BID) compared to placebo, in subjects with
      moderate plaque psoriasis during the 16 week Placebo controlled Phase and then upto 1 year
      in the Extension Phase of the trial.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 4, multicenter, randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind study of the
      efficacy and safety of apremilast in subjects with moderate plaque psoriasis.

      Approximately 219 subjects will be randomized 2 (apremilast):1 (placebo) at approximately 25
      sites in the United States. Subjects randomized to the apremilast treatment group will
      receive apremilast 30 mg tablets orally twice daily for 52 weeks. Subjects randomized to the
      placebo treatment group will receive placebo tablets (identical in appearance to the
      apremilast 30 mg tablets) orally twice daily for 16 weeks. Beginning Week 16, subjects
      initially randomized to placebo will be switched to receive apremilast 30 mg BID for an
      additional 36 weeks (52 weeks total).

      Study will enroll adult patients with stable moderate plaque psoriasis, who are naïve to
      systemic psoriasis treatments.

      The primary efficacy endpoint will be assessed at Week 16 and will be the mean percentage
      change from baseline in the product of body surface area (BSA) (%) and static Physician's
      Global Assessment (sPGA).
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary outcome measure is the mean percentage change from baseline in the product of body surface area (BSA) (%) multiplied by the static Physician's Global Assessment (sPGA) at Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 16</time_frame>
    <description>BSA is a measurement of involved skin. The overall BSA affected by psoriasis is estimated based on the palm area of the participant's hand (entire palmar surface or &quot;handprint&quot; including the fingers), which equates to approximately 1% of total body surface area.
The sPGA is a 6-point scale ranging from 0 (clear), 1 (almost clear), 2 (mild), 3 (moderate), to 4 (severe), 5 (very severe) incorporating a separate assessment of the severity of the three primary signs of the plaques of all involved areas: erythema, scaling and plaque elevation. Scores for each assessment are averaged and rounded to the nearest whole number to result in the final sPGA score. For the primary outcome measure, the mean percentage change in the product of BSA (%) multiplied by the sPGA, between baseline and Week 16 will be assessed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI) total score at Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>DLQI is a simple, compact, and practical questionnaire for use in a dermatology clinical setting to assess limitations related to the impact of skin disease. The instrument contains ten items dealing with the participant's skin. With the exception of Item Number 7, the participant responds on a four-point scale, ranging from &quot;Very Much&quot; (score 3) to &quot;Not at All&quot; or &quot;Not relevant&quot; (score 0). Item Number 7 is a multi-part item, the first part of which ascertains whether the participant's skin prevented them from working or studying (Yes or No, scores 3 or 0 respectively), and if &quot;No,&quot; then the participant is asked how much of a problem the skin has been at work or study over the past week, with response alternatives being &quot;A lot,&quot; &quot;A little,&quot; or &quot;Not at all&quot; (scores 2, 1, or 0 respectively). The DLQI total score is derived by summing all item scores, which has a possible range of 0 to 30, with 30 corresponding to the worst quality of life, and 0 corresponding to the best.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent of subjects achieving 0 (clear) or 1 (almost clear) on static Physician's Global Assessment (sPGA) scale at Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 16</time_frame>
    <description>The sPGA is a 6-point scale ranging from 0 (clear), 1 (almost clear), 2 (mild), 3 (moderate), to 4 (severe), 5 (very severe) incorporating a separate assessment of the severity of the three primary signs of the plaques of all involved areas: erythema, scaling and plaque elevation. Scores for each assessment are averaged and rounded to the nearest whole number to result in the final sPGA score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent of subjects achieving 0 (clear) or 1 (very mild) on Patient Global Assessment (PtGA) scale at Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 16</time_frame>
    <description>The PtGA is the assessment by the subject of the overall disease severity and its effect on life activities at the time of evaluation. The PtGA is a 5-point scale ranging from 0 (clear) to 4 (severe).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean change from baseline in Pruritus Visual Analog Scale (VAS) at Weeks 1 and 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 16</time_frame>
    <description>The Pruritus Visual Analog Scores (VAS) is used to measure the amount of itching and discomfort a participant experiences. Participant's Assessment of Pruritus (Itch) asks: On average, how much itch have you had because of your condition in the past week All VAS values range from 0 to 100. Higher scores correspond to more severe symptom or disease. Change from baseline was calculated for the VAS scale, where change = visit value − baseline value.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>In subjects with scalp psoriasis at baseline, proportion of subjects with scalp Physician's Global Assessment (ScPGA) 0 (clear) or 1 (minimal) at Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 16</time_frame>
    <description>The ScPGA will assess scalp involvement, if present at Baseline. The 6-point ScPGA scale ranges from 0 (clear), 1 (minimal), 2 (mild), 3 (moderate), 4 (severe), to 5 (very severe).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment Satisfaction Questionnaire for Medication (TSQM) at Weeks 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to weeks 16</time_frame>
    <description>The TSQM version II is a 11-question self-administrated instrument to understand a subject's satisfaction on the current therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment Satisfaction Questionnaire for Medication (TSQM) at Weeks 52</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to weeks 52</time_frame>
    <description>The TSQM version II is a 11-question self-administrated instrument to understand a subject's satisfaction on the current therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean percentage change from baseline in psoriasis area severity index (PASI) at Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 16</time_frame>
    <description>The PASI score is a measure of psoriatic disease severity taking into account qualitative lesion characteristics (erythema, thickness, and scaling) and degree of skin surface area involvement on defined anatomical regions. PASI scores range from 0 to 72, with higher scores reflecting greater disease severity. Erythema, thickness, and scaling are scored on a scale of 0 (none) to 4 (very severe) on 4 anatomic regions of the body: head, trunk, upper limbs, and lower limbs. Degree of involvement on each of the 4 anatomic regions is scored on a scale of 0 (no involvement) to 6 (90% to 100% involvement). The total qualitative score (sum of erythema, thickness, and scaling scores) is multiplied by the degree of involvement for each anatomic region and then multiplied by a constant. These values for each anatomic region are summed to yield the PASI score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjects who achieve a PASI 50 at Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 16</time_frame>
    <description>PASI-50 response is the percentage of participants who achieve at least a 50% reduction (improvement) from baseline in PASI score at Week 16. The improvement in PASI score is used as a measure of efficacy. The PASI is a measure of psoriatic disease severity taking into account qualitative lesion characteristics and degree of skin surface area involvement on defined anatomical regions. PASI scores range from 0 to 72, with higher scores reflecting greater disease severity. Erythema, thickness, and scaling are scored on a scale of 0 (none) to 4 (very severe) on 4 anatomic regions of the body: head, trunk, upper limbs, and lower limbs. Degree of involvement on each of the 4 anatomic regions is scored on a scale of 0 (no involvement) to 6 (90% to 100% involvement). The total qualitative score (sum of erythema, thickness, and scaling scores) is multiplied by the degree of involvement for each anatomic region and then multiplied by a constant.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjects who achieve a PASI 75 at Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 16</time_frame>
    <description>PASI-75 response is the percentage of participants who achieve at least a 75% reduction (improvement) from baseline in PASI score at Week 16. The improvement in PASI score is used as a measure of efficacy. The PASI is a measure of psoriatic disease severity taking into account qualitative lesion characteristics and degree of skin surface area involvement on defined anatomical regions. PASI scores range from 0 to 72, with higher scores reflecting greater disease severity. Erythema, thickness, and scaling are scored on a scale of 0 (none) to 4 (very severe) on 4 anatomic regions of the body: head, trunk, upper limbs, and lower limbs. Degree of involvement on each of the4 anatomic regions was scored on a scale of 0 (no involvement) to 6 (90% to 100% involvement). The total qualitative score (sum of erythema, thickness, and scaling scores) is multiplied by the degree of involvement for each anatomic region and then multiplied by a constant.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean percentage change from baseline in the product of BSA (%) x sPGA at Week 52</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to week 52</time_frame>
    <description>BSA is a measurement of involved skin. The overall BSA affected by psoriasis is estimated based on the palm area of the participant's hand (entire palmar surface or &quot;handprint&quot; including the fingers), which equates to approximately 1% of total body surface area.
The ScPGA will assess scalp involvement, if present at Baseline. The 6-point ScPGA scale ranges from 0 (clear), 1 (minimal), 2 (mild), 3 (moderate), 4 (severe), to 5 (very severe).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>56 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with adverse events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">197</enrollment>
  <condition>Parapsoriasis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Double-blind Placebo-controlled Phase - Weeks 0 to 16</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive treatment with either
apremilast 30 mg tablets orally twice daily (BID), or
matched placebo tablets orally twice daily (BID)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Open-label Apremilast Extension Phase - Weeks 16 to 52</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All subjects will be switched to (or continue with) apremilast 30 mg twice daily (BID) at Week 16. All subjects will maintain this dosing up to Week 52.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Apremilast</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Double-blind Placebo-controlled Phase - Weeks 0 to 16</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Open-label Apremilast Extension Phase - Weeks 16 to 52</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CC-10004, Otzela</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Double-blind Placebo-controlled Phase - Weeks 0 to 16</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Males or females, ≥ 18 years of age at the time of signing the informed consent
             document.

          2. Understand and voluntarily sign an informed consent document prior to any study
             related assessments/procedures being conducted.

          3. Able to adhere to the study visit schedule and other protocol requirements.

          4. Diagnosis of chronic plaque psoriasis for at least 6 months prior to signing the
             informed consent.

          5. Have moderate plaque psoriasis at screening and baseline as defined by

               1. BSA (Body Surface Area)5% to 10% and

               2. sPGA (Physician's Global Assessment) 3 (moderate) based on a 0 to 5 point scale

          6. Must be in general good health (except for psoriasis) as judged by the investigator,
             based on medical history, physical examination, and clinical laboratories.

          7. No prior exposure to systemic treatments or biologics for the treatment of psoriatic
             arthritis, psoriasis, or any other indication that could impact the assessment of
             psoriasis.

          8. Females of childbearing potential (FCBP)must have a negative pregnancy test at
             Screening and Baseline. While on investigational product and for at least 28 days
             after taking the last dose of investigational product, FCBP who engage in activity in
             which conception is possible must use one of the approved contraceptive§ options
             described below: Option 1: Any one of the following highly effective methods:
             hormonal contraception (oral, injection, implant, transdermal patch, vaginal ring);
             intrauterine device (IUD); tubal ligation; or partner's vasectomy; OR Option 2: Male
             or female condom (latex condom or nonlatex condom NOT made out of natural [animal]
             membrane [for example, polyurethane]) PLUS one additional barrier method: (a)
             diaphragm with spermicide; (b) cervical cap with spermicide; or (c) contraceptive
             sponge with spermicide.

          9. Male subjects (including those who have had a vasectomy) who engage in activity in
             which conception is possible must use barrier contraception (male latex condom or
             nonlatex condom NOT made out of natural [animal] membrane [for example,
             polyurethane]) while on investigational product and for at least 28 days after the
             last dose of investigational product

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Other than psoriasis, any clinically significant (as determined by the Investigator)
             cardiac, endocrinologic, pulmonary, neurologic, psychiatric, hepatic, renal,
             hematologic,immunologic disease, or other major disease that is currently
             uncontrolled.

          2. Any condition, including the presence of laboratory abnormalities, which would place
             the subject at unacceptable risk if he/she were to participate in the study.

          3. Any condition, including other inflammatory diseases or dermatologic conditions,
             which confounds the ability to interpret data from the study, including other types
             of psoriasis (ie, erythrodermic, guttate, inverse, or pustular psoriasis), other than
             plaque psoriasis.

          4. Prior history of suicide attempt at any time in the subject's life time prior to
             signing the informed consent and randomization, or major psychiatric illness
             requiring hospitalization within the last 3 years prior to signing the informed
             consent.

          5. Pregnant or breast feeding.

          6. Active substance abuse or a history of substance abuse within 6 months prior to
             signing the informed consent.

          7. Malignancy or history of malignancy, except for:

               1. treated (ie, cured) basal cell or squamous cell in situ skin carcinomas;

               2. treated (ie, cured) cervical intraepithelial neoplasia (CIN) or carcinoma in
                  situ of the cervix with no evidence of recurrence within 5 years of signing the
                  informed consent.

          8. Topical therapy within 2 weeks of randomization (including, but not limited to,
             topical corticosteroids, retinoids or vitamin D analog preparations, tacrolimus,
             pimecrolimus, or anthralin/dithranol). Use of phototherapy within 4 weeks prior to
             randomization.

          9. Use of any investigational drug within 4 weeks prior to randomization, or 5
             pharmacokinetic/pharmacodynamic half-lives, if known (whichever is longer).

         10. Prolonged sun exposure or use of tanning booths, which may confound the ability to
             interpret data from the study.

         11. Prior treatment with apremilast.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joana Goncalves, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Celgene Corporation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UAB at Birmingham - The Kirklin Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35233</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center For Dermatology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fremont</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94538</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dermatology Research Associates</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90045</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Blue Harbor Dermatology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newport Beach</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92663</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center for Dermatology and Laser Surgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95819</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>East Bay Rheumatology Medical</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Leandro</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94578</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tien Q. Nguyen MD Inc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tustin</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92780</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UConn Health Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Farmington</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dermatology Associates</name>
      <address>
        <city>Panama City</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32405-4542</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>USF Health Faculty Office Building-FOB</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Forward Clinical Trials Inc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33624</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dermatologic Surgery Specialists, P.C.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Macon</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>31217</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shideler Clinical Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Carmel</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dermatology Specialists, PSC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Louisville</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>DermResearch, PLLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Louisville</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40217</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lawrence Green, MD, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rockville</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20850</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Henry Ford Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Las Vegas Skin and Cancer Clinics</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Vegas</city>
        <state>Nevada</state>
        <zip>89052</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Psoriasis Treatment Center of Central New Jersey</name>
      <address>
        <city>East Windsor</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>08520</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Garden City Dermatology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Garden City</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11530</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sadick Research Group</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10075</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dermatology Associates of Rochester PC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14623</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Cincinnati</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinnati</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>45267-0501</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dermatology and Laser Center of Charleston</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29414</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Utah School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84132</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dermatology Consultants, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lynchburg</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>24501</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>August 9, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 3, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Parapsoriasis</keyword>
  <keyword>Plaque Psoriasis</keyword>
  <keyword>CC-10004</keyword>
  <keyword>Apremilast</keyword>
  <keyword>Moderate Plaque Psoriasis</keyword>
  <keyword>Safety</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Parapsoriasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Apremilast</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thalidomide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
