<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02455323</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present study aims to assess the quality of life of patients suffering from tension-type headache (TTH) treated for 4 weeks with different manual therapy-based techniques. The study design involved a factorial, randomized, double-blind, controlled study</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Influence of Manual Therapy in the Quality of Life in Tension-Type Headache</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Object: The present study aims to assess the quality of life of patients suffering from tension-type headache (TTH) treated for 4 weeks with different manual therapy-based techniques. Methods: The study design involved a factorial, randomized, double-blind, controlled study of 76 subjects. They were divided into 4 groups: suboccipital inhibitory pressure was applied to the first group; suboccipital spinal manipulation was applied to the second group; a combination of the two treatments was applied to the third group; and the fourth group was a control group. Quality of life was assessed using the SF-12 questionnaire (both overall and in its different dimensions) at the beginning and at the end of treatment, and after one month as a follow-up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Headache</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tension-Type Headache</mesh_term>
	<criteria>diagnosed by a neurologist, with headache characteristics as established by the International Headache Society and Controlled pharmacologically. Patients with infrequent ETTH, or with probable frequent and infrequent forms of TTH They can never have vomiting or headache episodes during the treatment ETTH patients may experience very occasionally photophobia or phonophobia during their episodes of headache, CTTH patients may experience very occasionally photophobia, phonophobia or mild nausea during headache episodes. Pain aggravated by movement of the head, Metabolic or musculoskeletal problems with similar headache symptoms, Previous trauma to the cervical spine, Active vertigo history Poorly controlled hypertension, Joint stiffness, atherosclerosis, or advanced osteoarthritis, Patients undergoing pharmacological adaptation, Excessive emotional stress, Patients with heart devices Joint instability, Neurological disorders, Laxity of cervical soft tissues, Radiographic abnormalities Generalized hyperlaxity or hypermobility, Pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Tension-type headache</keyword>
	<keyword>Manual therapy</keyword>
</DOC>