<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02455700</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Prospective randomised crossover trial to assess if there is a difference in the level of pain experienced by orthodontic patients undergoing interpromixal enamel reduction at the lower incisor region using either a motor driven reduction device or a hand held device</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pain Associated With Interproximal Enamel Reduction in Orthodontics: a RCT</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Consenting participants will be randomly allocated to one of the two groups ( motor driven device or hand driven device). A pain questionnaire in the form of a Visual Analogue Scale will be used before the treatment to determine a baseline level of pain and after the chosen treatment to determine the effect or the intervention on pain experience. After a washout period of 6 weeks the participants will crossover to have the opposite intervention carried out. A VAS will be filled in before and after the intervention again to determine a baseline pain score and pain score associated with the intervention. The data will be gathered and entered electronically into a statistical package whereby appropriate statistics will be carried out to determine if there is a significant difference in pain experienced between the two methods of enamel reduction. A secondary aim willl be to determine if there is any correlation with pain experienced and age or gender.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Over 18 years Requiring IER in the lower anterior teeth as part of treatment plan mild crowding in the lower incisor region centreline discrepancy discrepancy between the arches mild and thus requiring IPR to correct incisor position requiring IER for arch coordination No medications Willing to participate Under 18 years of age Not requiring IER moderate or severe crowding necessitating extraction for relief of crowding patients with removable appliances as their only mode of treatment Patient taking medication Not willing to participate</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>