<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02455024</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an observational study to further characterize the safety profile of patients with chronic myeloid leukemia in the chronic phase (CP-CML) treated with Iclusig (ponatinib) in routine clinical practice in the US. The study is focused on analysis of vascular occlusive events.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Observational Study to Evaluate the Incidence of and Risk Factors for Vascular Occlusive Events Associated With Iclusig®</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is being conducted in an effort to better understand rates, risk factors, and outcomes associated with vascular occlusive events in patients treated with Iclusig (ponatinib) in real world settings. This study will collect information about patient demographics, leukemia diagnosis, previous anti-cancer treatments, history of cardiovascular disease, risk factors for vascular complications, and concurrent medications (including antiplatelet and/or anticoagulant agents).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelogenous, Chronic, BCR-ABL Positive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Chronic-Phase</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ponatinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adult patients with CPCML (age ≥ 18 years) who are initiating Iclusig monotherapy, or for whom Iclusig monotherapy was initiated within 2 weeks of study enrollment. [The decision to prescribe Iclusig must have been made prior to enrollment in the study]. 2. Patients who have the ability to understand the requirements of the study and provide written informed consent to comply with the study data collection procedures. 3. Patients with a minimum life expectancy of 3 months. 1. Patients previously treated with investigational ponatinib (Iclusig). 2. Patients receiving an investigational agent (e.g., any drug or biologic agent or medical device that has not received approval in the US). 3. Concurrent treatment with another TKI for CML. 4. Prior history of AP or BPCML. 5. Patients who are pregnant and/or breastfeeding.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Leukemia, Myeloid</keyword>
	<keyword>Leukemia, Myelogenous, Chronic, BCR-ABL Positive</keyword>
	<keyword>ponatinib</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacologic Actions</keyword>
	<keyword>Protein Kinase Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>Risk factor</keyword>
	<keyword>Leukemia, Myelogenous, Chronic</keyword>
	<keyword>CML</keyword>
	<keyword>CP-CML</keyword>
	<keyword>Iclusig</keyword>
	<keyword>AP24534</keyword>
</DOC>