<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02455141</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To compare disease-free survival (DFS) rate of adjuvant chemotherapy epirubicin-cyclophosphamide followed by weekly paclitaxel (EC-wP), or weekly paclitaxel-carboplatin (EC-wPCb) in triple-negative breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adjuvant Treatment of EC Followed by wP and wPCb in Triple-Negative Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study plans to enroll triple-negative breast cancer patients who have complete tumor removal. Patients are randomized to receive either EC-wP or EC-wPCb adjuvant chemotherapy. For triple-negative breast cancer, a subgroup of triple-negative breast cancer has DNA repairement deficiency and adding carboplatin to paclitaxel may improve DFS on the basis of weekly paclitaxel adjuvant chemotherapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triple Negative Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epirubicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Histologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the breast, completely tumor removal by either modified radical mastectomy or local excision plus axillary lymph node dissection (i.e., breast conservation therapy) or sentinel node biopsy. (Tumorfree margins at least 1 mm for both invasive and noninvasive carcinoma except for lobular carcinoma in situ (less than 1 mm allowed); Tumor specimens are available for estrogen receptor (ER), progesterone receptor (PgR) and Her2 (human epidermalgrowthfactor receptor 2) detection, patients should be with triple negative breast cancer. Triplenegative disease is defined as ER &lt;1% positivity, PgR &lt;1% positivity, and negativity for Her2 (IHC (immunohistochemistry) 01+ or FISH (fluorescence in situ hybridization) negative); Adequate bone marrow function Adequate liver and renal function Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Score 01; Women with potential childbearing must have a negative pregnancy test (urine or serum) within 7 days of drug administration and agree to use an acceptable method of birth control to avoid pregnancy for the duration of the study; Written informed consent according to the local ethics committee requirements. Prior systemic of breast cancer, including chemotherapy; Metastatic breast cancer; With a history of malignant tumor except uterine cervix cancer in situ or skin basal cell carcinoma; Patients with medical conditions that indicate intolerant to adjuvant therapy and related treatment, including uncontrolled pulmonary disease, diabetes mellitus, severe infection, active peptic ulcer, coagulation disorder, connective tissue disease or myelosuppressive disease; Has active hepatitis B or hepatitis C with abnormal liver function tests (LFTs) or is known to be HIV positive; Contraindication for using dexamethasone; History of congestive heart failure, uncontrolled or symptomatic angina pectoris, arrhythmia or myocardial infarction; poorly controlled hypertension (systolic BP&gt;180 mmHg or diastolic BP&gt;100 mmHg); Has peripheral neuropathy no less than grade 1; Patient is pregnant or breast feeding; Patients with psychiatric disorder or other diseases leading to incompliance to the therapy; Known severe hypersensitivity to any drugs in this study; Treatment with any investigational drugs within 30 days before the beginning of study treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>chemptherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>triple negative</keyword>
	<keyword>paclitaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>carboplatin</keyword>
</DOC>