<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00607672</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Each year over a million patients worldwide undergo cardiac surgery requiring cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB).1 CPB is associated with significant morbidity including hemodynamic instability, the transfusion of allogenic blood products, and inflammation. Blood product transfusion increases mortality after cardiac surgery. Enhanced fibrinolysis contributes to increased blood product transfusion requirements in the perioperative period. CPB activates the kallikrein-kinin system (KKS), leading to increased bradykinin concentrations. Bradykinin, acting through its B2 receptor, stimulates the release of nitric oxide, inflammatory cytokines and tissue-type plasminogen activator (t-PA). Based on data indicating that angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitors reduce mortality in patients with coronary artery disease, many patients undergoing CPB are taking ACE inhibitors. While interruption of the renin-angiotensin system (RAS) reduces inflammation in response to CPB, ACE inhibitors also potentiate the effects of bradykinin and may augment B2-mediated change in fibrinolytic balance and inflammation. In contrast, angiotensin II type 1 receptor antagonism does not potentiate bradykinin and does not inhibit bradykinin metabolism. Studies in animals suggest that bradykinin receptor antagonism inhibits reperfusion-induced increases in vascular permeability and neutrophil recruitment.A randomized, placebo controlled clinical trial of a bradykinin B2 receptor antagonist demonstrated some effect on survival in patients with systemic inflammatory response syndrome and gram-negative sepsis. In addition, we and others have shown bradykinin B2 receptor antagonism reduces vascular t-PA release during ACE inhibition. The current proposal derives from data from our laboratory and others elucidating the role of the KKS in the inflammatory, hypotensive and fibrinolytic response to CPB. Specifically, we have found that CPB activates the KKS and that ACE inhibition and smoking further increases bradykinin concentrations. During CPB, bradykinin concentrations correlate inversely with mean arterial pressure and directly with t-PA. Moreover, we have found that bradykinin receptor antagonism attenuates protamine-related hypotension following CPB. The current proposal tests the central hypothesis that the fibrinolytic and inflammatory response to cardiopulmonary bypass differ during angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibition and angiotensin II type 1 receptor antagonism.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The RAS, Fibrinolysis and Cardiopulmonary Bypass</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ramipril</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Candesartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Candesartan cilexetil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 1. Subjects, 18 to 80 years of age, scheduled for elective cardiac surgery requiring CPB 2. For female subjects, the following conditions must be met: postmenopausal for at least 1 year, or statuspost surgical sterilization, or if of childbearing potential, utilizing adequate birth control and willing to undergo urine betahcg testing prior to drug treatment and on every study day 1. Left ventricle ejection fraction less than 30% 2. History of ACE inhibitorinduced angioedema 3. Hypotension (systolic blood pressure &lt;100 mmHg and evidence of hypoperfusion) 4. Hyperkalemia (baseline potassium &gt;5.0 mEq/L) 5. Inability to discontinue current ACE inhibitor or AT1 receptor antagonist. 6. Emergency surgery 7. Impaired renal function (serum creatinine &gt;1.6 mg/dl) 8. Pregnancy 9. Breastfeeding 10. Any underlying or acute disease requiring regular medication which could possibly pose a threat to the subject or make implementation of the protocol or interpretation of the study results difficult 11. History of alcohol or drug abuse 12. Treatment with any investigational drug in the 1 month preceding the study 13. Mental conditions rendering the subject unable to understand the nature, scope and possible consequences of the study 14. Inability to comply with the protocol, e.g. uncooperative attitude and unlikelihood of completing the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Angiotensin Converting Enzyme</keyword>
	<keyword>Angiotensin Receptor Blockers</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiopulmonary Bypass</keyword>
	<keyword>Fibrinolysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammation</keyword>
</DOC>