<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00607932</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Eating a diet high in vegetables may lower the risk of some types of cancer. Brassica vegetables (such as cabbages, kale, broccoli, Brussels sprouts, and cauliflower) and indole-3-carbinol (a substance found in cruciferous vegetables) may help lower the risk of prostate cancer recurrence. PURPOSE: This randomized clinical trial is studying the side effects and how well Brassica vegetables work compared with indole-3-carbinol in treating patients with PSA recurrence after surgery for prostate cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Brassica Vegetables or Indole-3-Carbinol in Treating Patients With PSA Recurrence After Surgery for Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the feasibility of Brassica vegetable intake and indole-3-carbinol supplement use in patients with prostate cancer with prostate-specific antigen (PSA) recurrence after prostatectomy. - Identify adverse events in these patients. - Quantify the effects of each intervention on PSA in these patients. OUTLINE: Patients are stratified by pretreatment prostat-specific antigen (PSA) growth rate (low [0.00-0.15] vs medium [0.16-0.30] vs high [&gt; 0.30]). They are randomized to 1 of 3 treatment arms, and randomization status to arms II and III is double-blinded. - Arm I (Brassica vegetables): Patients consume Brassica vegetables at least 2 servings (½ cup/serving) daily for 6 months. Patients meet one-on-one with the study dietician, and are instructed on the potential health benefits of Brassica vegetables and purchase and preparation of the vegetables. Patients undergo telephone counseling periodically in months 1-5, to monitor their progress and identify barriers to adherence and to develop solutions to overcome these barriers. - Arm II (Placebo): Patients receive oral placebo once daily for 6 months. - Arm III (Indole-3-carbinol supplement): Patients receive oral indole-3-carbinol supplement (capsules) once daily for 6 months. Blood and urine samples (for urinary isothiocyanate levels) are collected at baseline and at 2, 4, and 6 months. Patients complete questionnaires assessing demographics, family cancer history, and health history and measuring changes in medications, lifestyle, adverse events, and health. Medical records are reviewed for prostate cancer-related information, surgical dates, dose and type of radiation, and PSA history.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Indole-3-carbinol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of prostate cancer with PSA recurrence after prostatectomy PSA recurrence is defined as two consecutively rising PSA tests ≥ 8 weeks since the postsurgical nadir, with a minimal interval of 2 weeks between tests and at least 1 PSA test &gt; 0.4 ng/mL Life expectancy ≥ 9 months No predictors of poor adherence (e.g., erratic lifestyle, mental incompetence) PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics No other concurrent Brassica vegetable consumption &gt; 1 serving/day No other concurrent indole3carbinol supplements No endocrine or radiation treatment within past 4 weeks No other scheduled treatment during study intervention Concurrent prescription medications during the trial allowed At least 2 weeks since prior and no concurrent vitamin or herbal supplement use Patients refusing to stop nonstudy supplements will be asked to maintain constant use</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent prostate cancer</keyword>
</DOC>