<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03087773</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is planned to investigate the impact of Empagliflozin on biomarkers of heart failure in patients with myocardial infarction with and without type 2 diabetes mellitus within 6 months after the event.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of EMpagliflozin on Cardiac Function and Biomarkers of Heart Failure in Patients With Acute MYocardial Infarction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) is associated with an about two to three-fold increased risk for cardiovascular events as compared to subjects without diabetes. Sodium-dependent glucose cotransporter 2 (SGLT-2) is mainly expressed in human kidneys and small intestinal cells. In the proximal tubule of the nephron SGLT-2 is responsible for the reabsorption of approximately 90% of the filtrated glucose. Inhibition of SGLT-2 was shown to increase renal glucose excretion and to lower glucose. Subsequently, a number of SGLT-2 inhibitors were developed and are currently approved for the treatment of type 2 diabetes. Recently, Zinman B. et al published the results of the EMPA-REG-OUTCOME trial where the cardiovascular impact of a glucose lowering regimen including Empagliflozin as compared to usual glucose control without an SGLT-2 inhibitor was investigated. The trial demonstrated an unexpected reduction in the primary composite endpoint, comprising cardiovascular death, non-fatal myocardial infarction and non-fatal stroke. The reduction was mainly driven by a 38% relative risk reduction in cardiovascular deaths; moreover they demonstrated an impressive 35% relative risk reduction in the secondary endpoint hospitalization for heart failure. Of note, the beneficial effects observed in the Empagliflozin group seem to occur very rapidly after commencing the treatment, as suggested by the early separation of the Kaplan-Meier curves. However, the mechanisms responsible for this finding remain unclear. Diuretic effects with subsequent impact on hemodynamics or potential cardioprotective effects of glucagon, which levels rise under the treatment with SGLT-2 inhibitors and the resulting rise in ketone bodies or a small increase in hematocrit have been suggested. The aim of our trial is to investigate whether Empagliflozin treatment commenced within 72-h after acute myocardial infarction has an impact on heart failure in subjects with and without diabetes mellitus type 2.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Empagliflozin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Myocardial infarction with evidence of significant myocardial necrosis defined as a rise in creatinine kinase &gt;1000 U/l and a troponin Tlevel (or troponin Ilevel) &gt;10x ULN. In addition at least 1 of the following criteria must be the met: Symptoms of ischemia ECG changes indicative of new ischemia (new STT changes or new LBBB) Imaging evidence of new regional wall motion abnormality 2. 18 75 years of age 3. Informed consent has to be given in written form 4. eGFR &gt; 45 ml/min/1.73m2 5. Blood pressure before first drug dosing &gt;110/70 mmHg 6. ≤72h after myocardial infarction 1. Any other form of diabetes mellitus than type 2 diabetes mellitus, history of diabetic ketoacidosis 2. Blood pH &lt; 7,32 3. Known allergy to SGLT2 inhibitors 4. Haemodynamic instability as defined by intravenous administration of catecholamine, calcium sensitizers or phosphodiesterase inhibitors 5. &gt;1 episode of severe hypoglycaemia within the last 6 months and treatment with insulin or sulfonylurea 6. Females of child bearing potential without adequate contraceptive methods (i.e. sterilisation, intrauterine device, vasectomised partner; or medical history of hysterectomy) 7. Acute symptomatic urinary tract infection (UTI) or genital infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>