<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03087942</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to assess whether renal impairment could affect fevipiprant pharmacokinetics (PK) to the extent that dosage adjustment is appropriate for this patient population. The study also aims to determine the effect of dialysis on the fevipiprant pharmacokinetic profile as the procedure might remove a significant fraction of the drug.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetics and Safety of Fevipiprant in Patients With Renal Impairment Compared to Matched Healthy Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to determine if the pharmacokinetic profile of fevipiprant is different in patients with renal impariment compared to healthy matched volunteers to an extent that would require an adjustment of the dosage. Data from this study will be used to guide enrollment criteria in future clinical trials and to support regulatory submission and labeling information</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Indoleacetic Acids</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy subjects must satisfy the criteria for normal renal function as evidenced by normal Glomerular Filtration Rate (GFR): eGFR ≥ 90 mL/min/1.73m2; each healthy subject must match in age (+/ 10years), gender, smoking status, and weight (+/ 15%), a patient from the renail impaired patient groups: A body mass index (BMI) within the range of 18 36 kg/m2 ESRD patients on hemodialysis: an glomerulo filtration rat GFR of &lt; 15 mL/min/1.73 m2 patients with severe renal impairment: GFR of&lt; 30 mL/min/1.73m2 (without need of hemodialysis); patients with moderate renal impairment: 30 mL/min/1.73m2 ≤ eGFR &lt; 60 mL/min/1.73m2; patients with mild impairment: 60 mL/min/1.73m2 ≤ eGFR &lt; 90 mL/min/1.73m2 Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women History or evidence of any inherited bilirubin disease or disorder subjects participating in another study malignancies in the past Hemoglobin levels below 10 g/dL at screening HIV positiv Heavy smokers (≥20 cigarettes per day) Liver disease, as indicated by ALT, γGT, AST and alkaline phosphatase which should not exceed twice the upper limit of normal and should be stable (e.g. increased liver values known from previous patient records). Serum bilirubin &gt; 27 μmol/L (1.6 mg/dL) Clinically significant ECG changes and/or arrhythmias Chronic infection with Hepatitis B (HBV) or Hepatitis C (HCV)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>end stage renal disase ESRD</keyword>
	<keyword>dialysis effect on pharmacokinetics PK</keyword>
	<keyword>renal impairment</keyword>
</DOC>