<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03087955</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to assess efficacy and safety of SCYX-7158 given as a single dose oral treatment for adult patients (above or equal 15) in the fasting state with T.b. Gambiense HAT</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Study on Efficacy and Safety of SCYX-7158 in Patients Infected by Human African Trypanosomiasis Due to T.b. Gambiense</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Trypanosomiasis, African</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trypanosomiasis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patient 15 years of age or older Signed informed consent form (as well as assent from illiterate and underage patients, and those unable to give consent) Karnofsky Performance Status above 50 Able to ingest oral tablets Having a permanent address or being traceable by other persons Able to comply with the schedule of followup visits and requirements of the study Agreement to be hospitalised in order to receive treatment For patients with latestage HAT: Confirmation of gHAT by detection of the parasite in the blood and/or the lymph and/or the CSF, at the investigational centre If trypanosomes are found in the blood or lymph, but not in the CSF, the CSF WBC, measured at the investigational centre, must be above 20/μL for the patient to be included in the cohort of patients with latestage HAT For patients with early or intermediatestage HAT: Confirmation of gHAT by detection of the parasite in the blood and/or the lymph, at the investigational centre Absence of parasites in the CSF The CSF WBC, measured at the investigational centre, must be between 6 and 20/μL for the patient to be included in the cohort of patients with intermediatestage HAT and equal to or below 5/μL for the patient to be included in the cohort of patients with earlystage HAT. Severe malnourishment, defined as bodymass index (BMI) below 16 Pregnancy or breastfeeding (for women of childbearing potential, confirmed pregnancy on a urine pregnancy test performed within 24 hours prior to administration of SCYX7158) Clinically significant medical condition that could, in the opinion of the Investigator, jeopardise the patient's safety or interfere with participation in the study, including, but not limited to significant liver or cardiovascular disease, suspected or proven active infection, central nervous system trauma or seizure disorder, coma or consciousness disturbances Severely deteriorated health status, e.g. due to cardiovascular shock, respiratory distress syndrome or endstage disease Previously treated for HAT (except prior treatment with pentamidine) Prior enrolment in the study Foreseeable difficulty complying with followup, including migrant worker, refugee status, itinerant trader etc. Current alcohol abuse or drug addiction Not tested for malaria and/or not having received appropriate treatment for malaria Not having received appropriate treatment for soiltransmitted helminthiasis Clinically significant abnormal laboratory values including Aspartate AminoTransferase(AST) and/or AlanineAminoTransferase (ALT) more than 2 times the upper limit of normal (ULN), total bilirubin more than 1.5 ULN, severe leukopenia at less than 2000/mm3, Potassium below 3.5 mmol/L, any other clinically significant abnormal laboratory value</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>