<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03087994</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The proposed study is a randomized, open, comparative research involving an intervention group and two control groups. The aims of the study are: 1.To compare levels of depression in female adolescents with obesity and a control group of female adolescents with appropriate weight and height. 2. To investigate whether a decrease in weight due to a short range intervention program provided by dietician for female adolescents with obesity will lead to change in the levels of symptoms of depression and cognitive and executive functions in comparison to a control group of adolescent girls with obesity, matched in age that does not receive such an intervention program. 60 Female adolescents with obesity will be recruited to the study and will be randomized to 1 of two groups- 1. intervention group- participants in this group will attend an intervention program consisting of 12 meetings with dietician and will attend three study visits at the clinic- in the beginning of the study, after three months and at the end of the study after a year. 2.Control group- Participants in this group will only come to three study visits at the clinic. In the first two visits they will meet with a dietician and will receive nutrition guidance and hypo-caloric menu. Another 30 girls with appropriate weight will be recruited to second control group- this group will come to three study visits at the clinic- in the beginning of the study, after three months and at the end of the study after a year. In the first two visits participants will receive nutrition guidance by the dietician. In the study visits the following procedures will be performed for all study groups: Blood tests, completion of psychological and nutritional questionnaires, completion of computerized tests and measurements of height, weight, fat mass and circumference of hips.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Influence of Obesity on Level of Depression and Cognitive and Executive Functions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adolescent girls aged 1217, who attend the Endocrinology Institute in Schneider Hospital and comply with the research criteria: obesity (BMI above percentile 95) and appropriate weight (BMI between percentiles 585). 2. Adolescent level according to Tanner: 45. 3. Participants with obesity: BMI above percentile 95 for age group. 4. Participants in control group with appropriate weight: BMI percentile 585 for age group. 5. Appropriate height (Percentiles 397 according to the CDC curve). 6. Parents' signature on informed consent form. 1. Chronic illness or chronic use of medications. 2. Inability to comply with the research conditions.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>