<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03087617</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Imbio is developing a Smoking Cessation Report (Report) that includes data analysis from a CT lung cancer screening exam. This randomized controlled (RCT) trial will clinically validate the Report's effectiveness at motivating smokers to call a Quitline.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Personalized Smoking Cessation Tool Based on Patient Lung CT Image</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Imbio is developing a Smoking Cessation Report (Report) that includes data analysis from a CT lung cancer screening exam. This randomized controlled (RCT) trial will clinically validate the Report's impact on: (a) Lung screening participants' motivation to make a quit attempt by calling a Quitline, and (b) the effectiveness of a 45-minute telephone smoking cessation counseling session for motivating an actual quit attempt and abstinence. The RCT will enroll approximately 400 randomly selected participants from lung screening programs at HealthPartners and University of Michigan. Participants will be randomly assigned to one of four conditions: 1) Usual Care + quitline phone number (created specifically for the trial and maintained for the length of the trial); 2) Usual Care + Report (Report will list Quitline number) 3) Usual Care + Counseling, or 4) Usual Care + Report + Counseling. Follow up assessment calls will be conducted with participants at three weeks, three months, and six months following the mailing of the report.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>30pack year smoking history currently smoke OR quit within the last 15 years and a category 1 or 2 LungRADS scan current use of smoking cessation medications scan read as a category 3, 4A, 4B or 4X in LungRADS unstable medical or psychiatric conditions current alcohol or drug use disorder pastmonth suicidal ideation pastyear suicide attempt</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>