<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02307669</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators hypothesize that aligning adherence with the patient's own clinical course achieves better asthma control and identifies risks for future loss of control, compared to current best practice. The study has an adherence optimisation phase, week 1-12 followed by a medication management phase, week 12 to week 32. The investigators will compare two asthma education interventions, standard Guideline recommended practice and feedback from the individual's own INCA device, which assess inhaler adherence and relates adherence with changes in PEFR and symptom scores over time. The aim of the study is to then incorporate adherence into Guideline recommended medication changes so that asthma control is improved and medication rationalised at the end of the intervention. A secondary aim is to assess the long-term effectiveness of this approach on control and exacerbations.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Inhaler Adherence in Severe Unstable Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators hypothesize that aligning adherence with the patient's own clinical course achieves better asthma control and allows physicians to identify risks for future loss of control, compared to current best practice. The investigators will compare two asthma education interventions, standard Guideline recommended practice and feedback from the individual's own INCA device, which assess inhaler adherence and relates adherence with changes in PEFR and symptom scores over time. The aim of the study is to improve and maintain adherence to preventor therapy, so that medication and other costs as well as quality of life, exacerbation rates are optimal.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must be willing to give voluntary informed consent Must have a clinical diagnosis of asthma Must have a bronchodilator FEV1 &gt; 40% and &lt;80% in the past 1 year Current unstable asthma i.e. ACT score is less than 19 at enrolment. One or more courses of oral corticosteroids in the prior year, or a hospitalization or ED attendance with an asthma exacerbation in the last year Age 18 years or older at time of consent. Capable of understanding and complying with the requirements of the protocol, including ability to attend for all required visits. Able and willing to take inhaled medication via a Diskus. In the opinion of the investigator suitable for use of a salmeterol/fluticasone Diskus inhaler or already using a salmeterol/fluticasone inhaler. Have used any investigational product or device within 3 months of the enrolment visit. Have known previous sensitivity to Seretide (salmeterol/fluticasone). Have a known significant (in the opinion of the investigator) concurrent medical disease that might mean that the participant cannot complete the study. Be taking omalizumab or other biological agent used in the treatment of asthma Concurrent treatment with potent cytochrome P450 3A4 (CYP3A4) inhibitors; Ketoconazole and Ritonavir.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>