<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02656017</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will test to see if metformin is safe and if it is tolerated compared to placebo in adult Autosomal Dominant Polycystic Kidney Disease (ADPKD) patients with beginning stages of chronic kidney disease. We will also measure its effect on progression of kidney disease as reflected in the kidney size and the kidney function, along with its effect on kidney pain and quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Metformin as a Novel Therapy for Autosomal Dominant Polycystic Kidney Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There is growing evidence that metformin, a drug widely used for the treatment of type 2 diabetes and polycystic ovary syndrome, may serve as a novel therapy for individuals in the early stages of Autosomal Dominant Polycystic Kidney Disease ADPKD by activating the metabolic sensor AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK). AMPK is activated under conditions of metabolic and other cellular stresses. Through its actions on downstream mediators, AMPK activation during low energy states decreases cellular energy consumption while stimulating energy generating pathways. It has been shown that AMPK phosphorylates and inhibits cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator (CFTR), thus suppressing epithelial fluid and electrolyte secretion. Similarly, AMPK phosphorylates the tuberin protein, leading to indirect inhibition of the mTOR pathway. Thus, AMPK inhibits both CFTR and mTOR, suggesting that targeted activation of this kinase by metformin may provide a therapeutic benefit in ADPKD. It has been shown that metformin treatment of kidney epithelial cells leads to stimulation of AMPK and subsequent inhibition of both mTOR and CFTR activity. It has also been shown that metformin slows cystogenesis in animal models of PKD, supporting the potential of this drug in ADPKD treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polycystic Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polycystic Kidney, Autosomal Dominant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject has Autosomal Dominant Polycystic Kidney Disease; Subject is fluent in English Subject is not on active military duty; Subject is not currently participating in another clinical trial; Subject's current GFR is not &lt;50 cc/min/1.73m2; Subject does not have diabetes; Subject does not have a systemic disease other than hypertension and PKD; Subject does not have a solitary kidney; Subject does not have an allergy or intolerance to metformin; Subject is not pregnant or lactating or intending to become pregnant within the next three years; Subject does not have an unstable or unclipped cerebral aneurysm; Subject does not have active coronary artery disease; Subject does not have an MRI incompatible device/implant; Subject does not have severe claustrophobia; Subject has not had any solid organ transplant; Subject does not have a Vitamin B12 deficiency; Subject does not currently take any medications that interact with metformin, such as nifedipine, furosemide, cationic drugs (amiloride, ranitidine, triamterene digoxin, procainamide, quinidine, vancomycin, trimethoprim);</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>kidney disease</keyword>
	<keyword>polycystic kidney disease</keyword>
	<keyword>autosomal dominant kidney disease</keyword>
	<keyword>kidney cysts</keyword>
	<keyword>PKD</keyword>
</DOC>