<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02656680</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In a pilot randomized trial of 160 obese participants, investigators will test the feasibility of a behavioral weight loss program delivered entirely via Facebook. Participants will be randomized to a condition in which they will be able to invite their friends, or a condition with study participants only. All participants will receive behavioral counseling via the private Facebook group from the coaches who are present on the network daily. Participants will track their diet and exercise via a free commercial mobile app.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mentoring in mHealth and Social Networking Interventions for CVD Risk Reduction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The overarching goal of the research plan is to test ways to leverage mobile technologies and social media to increase the impact, scalability, cost-effectiveness, and dissemination potential of lifestyle interventions that reduce cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk. Mobile technology and social media have the potential to reduce the intensity of traditional prevention interventions and enhance outcome by delivering behavioral strategies in-the-moment and by connecting patients other patients to generate better communication and a social support system for lifestyle changes. This study includes a behavioral weight loss program delivered entirely via on online social network. The weight loss intervention is based on the Diabetes Prevention Program (DPP), an evidence-based weight loss program focused on lifestyle changes. The goals for the intervention are 175 minutes of moderate physical activity per week and an overall weight loss of 7%. Each participant will get an individualized calorie goal that would facilitate a 1-2 lbs. weight loss weekly. Participants will be connected to one another via Facebook and receive behavioral counseling via posts from coaches who are present on the network daily. Participants will track their diet and exercise via a free commercial mobile app. Participants will be assigned to either a Facebook group allowing the invite of friends or a Facebook group including only study participants. If they are assigned to the group including their friends, they have the opportunity to invite their friends to participate in the weight loss group if they are interested in losing weight as well. Friends of friends may also be invited. They will not have a limit as to how many friends they can invite. Facebook has a feature which will allow anyone to invite friends into a group. The friends that are invited will not undergo the same procedures as the FB+friends study participants, but we will provide them with a factsheet and collect minimal information from them. Feasibility outcomes include engagement (frequency of posts, likes, and comments and number of completed days of tracking posted) retention, acceptability, and weight loss. Post intervention focus groups will gather feedback on the program.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants must be: 1. 1865 years of age; 2. have a BMI 3045 kg/m²; 3. have written clearance from their primary care provider to participate; and 4. have daily internet access; 1. Age under 18 or over 65; 2. BMI under 25 or over 45; 3. No medical clearance from primary care provider; 4. Inactive engagement on Facebook; 5. Does not currently use a smartphone; 6. Is not familiar with using phone apps; 7. Plans to move during study; 8. Pregnant/lactating; 9. Had bariatric surgery, plans to during the study, or had recent weight loss; 10. Condition that precludes lifestyle changes (i.e. a condition that prevents physical activity increase or dietary changes); 11. Medications affecting weight; 12. Incapable of walking ¼ mile without stopping; 13. Type 1 or 2 diabetes; 14. Participated in previous weight loss studies under the PI; 15. Is a UMass employee and is uncomfortable participating in a Facebook group with other UMass employees 16. Unable to attend the orientation visit; 17. Inability to provide consent; 18. Prisoners; and 19. Has concerns about being audiotaped Friends of the subjects participating in the FB+friends and FB w/o friends conditions: 1. Must be: at least 18 years old; 2. BMI of 25 or over; and 3. Have an interest in losing weight.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>