<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02656732</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present randomized, controlled, parallel-grouped trial included twenty patients (aged 20 to 54 years) suffering from Miller's class I or II gingival recession. Patients were randomly assigned into two equal groups; control group; the coronally advanced flap with the subepithelial connective tissue graft (CAF+SCTG) or the test group; coronally advanced flap with amnion chorion allograft membrane (CAF+AC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Amnion Chorion Membrane in Comparison to Subepithelial Connective Tissue Graft in Gingival Recession Coverage</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The participants were randomly assigned to receive coronally advanced flap (CAF) with amnion chorion membrane or CAF with subepithelial connective tissue graft using a simple randomization procedure with a 1:1 allocation ratio. A computer generated randomization list was drawn up by a faculty member who was not involved in the recruitment. Allocation concealment was achieved by sealed coded opaque envelopes that contained the treatment to be performed to the enrolled subjects based on the randomized numbers. Consequently, patients were allocated to either AC membrane (intervention) or SCTG (control) groups. The sealed envelope containing treatment assignment was opened at time of the surgery and the number was picked by another person other than the operator.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Gingival Recession</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects aged between 18 60 years old. Subjects with facial gingival recession defects in anterior and premolar teeth classified as either class I or II defects according to Miller's classification. Subjects able to tolerate surgical periodontal procedures. Accepts the 6 months followup period. Current and former smokers. Pregnant females. Subjects received any periodontal therapy for a minimum of 6 months prior to the study. Subjects taking drugs known to interfere with wound healing. Subjects with unacceptable oral hygiene with plaque index &gt;2. Teeth with noncarious cervical lesions, cervical caries and malalignment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>54 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>