<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00276185</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Botulinum toxin produced beneficial effects in spasticity in the hemiplegic upper limb. This study will test if botulinum toxin injections at earlier phases (&lt;or = 3 months) in spasticity improve functional and motor tests compared with late injections (&gt;or = 6 months).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>HEMITOX : Effect of Botulinum Toxin Injections on Motor and Functional Ability of Upper Limb in Adults at Earlier Phases of Spastic Hemiplegia After Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Muscle Spasticity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemiplegia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Minimum age 18 Spastic hemiplegia after ischemic stroke (carotid occlusion) within the past 3 months. Antispasticity medication stabilized for the last 30 days Severe cognitive impairment such that patient is unable to provide scale assessment. Significant spasticity impeding improvement by reeducation for 2 months or less Lack of muscular retraction defined by a minimal range of articular motion as : finger : complete extension and rolling up wrist : extension 40째/flexion : 45째 elbow : extension 10째/flexion : 120째 shoulder : Enjalbert score 2 or more Antagonist muscles (to spasticity) activity score 1 or more Social Security benefits Ischemic stroke thought to be due to basilar or vertebral vessel occlusion Known motor neuron or neuromuscular junction disease, disorders in which pain limits the ability to inject muscles (algodystrophy) Absence of mobility in proximal part of upper limb that does not predict a functional gain Minor stroke with nondisabling deficit or rapidly improving motor symptoms other serious illness, e.g. severe hepatic, cardiac, or renal failure ; acute myocardial infarction ; or a complex disease that may confound treatment assessment Treatment of spasticity by previous administration of botulinum toxin, if known Known allergy to botulinum toxin Currently participating in other research studies</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>spasticity ;</keyword>
	<keyword>Botulinum toxin ;</keyword>
	<keyword>Upper limb ;</keyword>
	<keyword>motor function.</keyword>
	<keyword>spastic hemiplegia after stoke</keyword>
</DOC>