<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01114321</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Dysfunction of autonomic nervous system is an important non motor feature of Parkinson' disease (PD). Lewy body formation is widely distributed in hypothalamus and in sympathetic and parasympathetic systems. Animal studies suggest a link between hypothalamus sensing of substrates and glucose metabolism. Thus, hypothalamus lesions could lead to change in glucose metabolism. Recently, we showed that fasting blood glucose level was significantly higher in PD patients than in control group suggesting that glucose tolerance may be impaired in PD. Some studies provided evidence for higher diabetes prevalence in PD patients whereas others showed no difference or a reduced risk of diabetes prevalence in PD patients compared to healthy subjects. So, the risk that a PD patient develops a glucose intolerance or a diabetes is not clearly established and merit to be studied considering the damageable consequences for patient healthy. The aim of this prospective study was to determine the risk that a PD patient develop a glucose intolerance or a diabetes compared to a matched control group, using an oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Glucose Tolerance in Patients With an Idiopathic Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>50 patients Inclusion visit : - Clinical examination/ Interview on health and medical history - Complete UPDRS, MMS - Biologic check up Protocol : All patients were studied in the postabsorptive state after a 10-h overnight fast. On the day of the experiment, patients did not receive their treatment. One catheter was inserted for blood sample collections. Patients ingested then 75 g of glucose. Blood samples were collected for plasma glucose and plasma insulin concentration analyses at T0, T30, T60, T90, T120, T150 and T180. Urinary glucose was researched at T0 and T120. In parallel, a dysautonomia evaluation of each patient was made (SCOPA AUT questionnaire, Tilt test).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age : 1870 years Patient with an idiopathic Parkinson's disease according to the criteria of the "Parkinson's Disease Society Brain Bank" with a duration of disease &gt;5years MMS&gt;24/30 No treatment modification 7 days before the inclusion Affiliation to social security Agreement of patients Patient treated with antibiotics, AINS, AIS or other treatment which could interfere with the protocol Patients with significant heart, respiratory, psychiatric, metabolic, hepatic, kidney diseases; diabetes, heart deficiency, chronic kidney deficiency, untreated thyroid disease … Patient treated with a deep brain stimulation Patients with metabolic and/or biological anomalies Pregnant women Medical or chirurgical previous history which could interfere with the protocol Alcohol (&gt;30g/day); Tobacco (&gt;10 cigarettes/day) Participation to an other study at the same time</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Idiopathic Parkinson's disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucose intolerance</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>OGTT</keyword>
	<keyword>Patient with an Idiopathic Parkinson's disease</keyword>
</DOC>