<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="7962">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03003286</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AD-1304-7379</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03003286</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Community Based Intervention for Children With ADHD and ASD</brief_title>
  <official_title>Community Based Intervention for Children With ADHD and ASD</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Children's Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Georgetown University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Children's Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether a new treatment, Unstuck and On Target
      (UOT), works better, worse, or the same as the best treatment that is available now,
      Contingency Behavioral Management (CBM), for low income children with Autism Spectrum
      Disorder (ASD) or Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD). Researchers predict that
      UOT will be better than CBM for children with ASD and ADHD at improving cognitive problem
      solving, executive functioning, self-control and use of medical care, but equal to CBM at
      improving behavior and coping.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This project will compare the effectiveness of an innovative community-based
      cognitive-behavioral Executive Functioning (EF) treatment, Unstuck and On Target (UOT) to
      the current standard of care, a Contingency Behavioral Management (CBM) program in typically
      underserved children with ASD or ADHD. Minimizing the impact of EF deficits in these
      pediatric disorders has broad public health implications, providing the opportunity for
      improvement in the real-world, long-term outcomes that stakeholders have told us are most
      important to them: more educational and vocational success, more functional independence and
      improved Activities of Daily Living skills, and better physical health, with reduced
      morbidity and mortality. The health disparity that this project addresses is the poorer
      outcomes and limited treatment choices associated with being a child from a low-income
      family who also has ADHD or ASD. The research questions are:

        1. Which works better for low-income children with ASD, UOT or CBM? Researchers will test
           the comparative effectiveness of UOT to CBM treatments with low-income children with
           ASD. Hypothesis 1: UOT will be more effective for children with ASD than CBM treatment
           of equal intensity at improving cognitive problem-solving (WASI Block Design (BD)),
           real-world executive functioning (BRIEF Shift and Plan/Org, class observation
           Transitions and Follows Directions, Challenge Task Plan/org, Flexibility scores),
           self-regulation (BRIEF Emotional Control and CBCL Affective Problems scores), and fewer
           non-routine medical visits (service use) and equal to CBM in improving behavior and
           coping skills (classroom observation Negativity and Participation scores and CBCL
           Aggression score)

        2. Which works better for low-income children with ADHD, UOT or CBM? Researchers will test
           the comparative effectiveness of UOT to CBM with low-income children with ADHD, a new
           patient population for UOT. Hypothesis 2: UOT will be more effective for children with
           ADHD than CBM treatment of equal intensity at improving executive functioning,
           cognitive problem-solving, and equal to CBM in improving behavior and coping skills.

        3. Are the effects of UOT and CBM sustained 9-12 months after treatment? Researchers will
           assess whether any benefits ascribed to the interventions are maintained about a year
           after the treatment is completed. Hypothesis 3: Improvements in cognitive abilities,
           EF, problem solving and behavior regulation will be maintained about a year following
           treatment in the UOT children, while gains in behavior and coping skills seen with CBM
           will fade after the treatment ends.

      Patients with ASD and ADHD will be recruited for the study from school systems. Half will
      receive UOT and half will receive CBM. Researchers will recruit interested Title 1 schools
      that serve very different and diverse populations. Recruitment will occur in several stages.
      Specifically, school districts will invite individual schools to participate in the trial
      that have a sufficient number of qualifying children. Interested schools will then contact
      families and provide information about the study. Interested families will initiate contact
      with study staff, and individual schools will be entered into the study if they have three
      or more patients whose families contact study staff. Children will then be scheduled for
      cognitive/diagnostic evaluation. Recruitment will continue until the target enrollment is
      reached, and all remaining interested families from enrolled schools are included. Subjects
      with appropriate assent and consent will be evaluated for eligibility and their school will
      be randomly assigned to treatment condition.

      Cognitive problem-solving abilities, flexibility, planning and organizing, self-regulation,
      behavior problems, coping skills, and the child's use of non-routine urgent medical care
      will be measured before and after treatment through a multi-method, multi-informant format,
      including parent/teacher report, blinded classroom observations and blinded direct child
      measures. Researchers chose measures that have the greatest relevance to functional outcomes
      and &quot;real world&quot; functioning. Rather than define a single outcome, researchers chose
      multiple outcome variables, anticipating differential impacts of the treatment modalities on
      the outcome domains. All of the measures and observations will be gathered at pre- and
      post-treatment time-points in each treatment year.

      Data will be analyzed using a Statistical Package for the Social Sciences (SPSS) v20 and R.
      A comparison of baseline characteristics will be performed between the treatment groups to
      assess that the randomization was successful. The characteristics will include demographics
      as well as the direct child assessments and the behavioral scales. These comparisons will be
      performed using standard statistical methods, such as t-tests for continuous variables or
      (exact) chi-squares for dichotomous variables. If any characteristic is unbalanced between
      treatments, which will be possible with the sample size, secondary analyses will adjust for
      that characteristic.

      Analysis for Specific Aim 1- Which works better for low-income children with ASD, UOT or
      CBM? To test the comparative effectiveness of UOT to CBM treatment with 50 low-income
      children with ASD. RER analysis will be used to determine the effect of treatment on the
      change scores on the primary outcomes. This analysis will also uncover any significant
      covariates, which will be further examined by pairwise comparisons. Effect sizes will be
      calculated and compared to the effect sizes obtained in previous trial with UOT with ASD
      children from middle-income families. Finally, RCI will be calculated to provide an easy to
      interpret guide for families and clinicians to use when making choices among treatments.

      Analysis for Specific Aim 2- Which works better for low income children with ADHD, UOT or
      CBM? To test the comparative effectiveness of UOT to CBM with 100 low-income children with
      ADHD, analyses will proceed as described above, except that the effect sizes for the
      children with ADHD will be compared to the effect sizes obtained with children with ASD in
      Specific Aim 1.

      Analysis for Specific Aim 3- Are the effects of UOT and CBM sustained about a year after
      treatment? To assess whether treatment benefits are maintained about a year after treatment,
      RER analyses will be repeated with the additional time-point included for the patients who
      have multiple post testing assessments.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single Blind (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Challenge Task - Change In Flexibility</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks, 9 months, and 21 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Challenge Task is an unpublished, un-normed measure designed by the researchers to measure the functional outcome of EF skills in socially relevant situations in a standardized way. Specific challenges are posed and the child's flexibility and planning are scored on a 3-point scale for each task. The scale (0-good, 1-intermediate, 2-poor performance) has task-specific behavioral markers to guide scoring (e.g. for the sculpture task described above, a flexibility score of 2 is assigned if: &quot;The participant is unwilling to switch sculptures...&quot;). Researchers predict that UOT participants will improve on the Flexibility and Planning scores more than CBM participants.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Wechsler Abbreviated Scale of Intelligence Block Design - Change in Nonverbal Reasoning</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks, 9 months, and 21 months</time_frame>
    <description>WASI BD subtest is a timed visual construction task that requires efficient nonverbal cognitive problem solving. Performance is represented as T scores (mean=50; SD=10), with higher scores indicating better performance. A previous trial showed significant improvements in performance as a result of treatment with UOT. Researchers predict that UOT participants will improve on Block Design scores more than CBM participants.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Delis-Kaplan Executive Function System - Change in Verbal Fluency</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks, 9 months, and 21 months</time_frame>
    <description>Verbal fluency measures were designed to analyze how individuals process and organize information when prompted to generate language in semantic categories. Two of three verbal fluency measures from the D-KEFS will be administered to participants to gain insight into executive functioning abilities (Delis, Kaplan, &amp; Kramer, 2001). Specifically, flexibility and shift are targeted by asking participants to generate language based on phonemic categories and the ability to switch between semantic categories. The tasks targets The D-KEFS is based on a cognitive process approach and designed for use in research settings in hopes of gaining a better understanding of frontal lobe functioning (Delis, Kaplan, &amp; Kramer, 2001).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Woodcock-Johnson III Tests of Achievement - Change in Reading and Math Fluency</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks, 9 months, and 21 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measures of academic fluency target an important area of executive functioning, processing speed. The rate at which participants read and solve simple arithmetic problems will be analyzed to capture cognitive processing speed and quantitative knowledge (Mather &amp; Wendling, 2014). Scores are based on age-based norms and produce standard scores with a mean of 100 and a standard deviation of 15.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Child Participant Interview</measure>
    <time_frame>21 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Flexibility Project Follow Up questionnaire is intended to measure whether children have learned concepts from the other intervention which they did not receive during the previous treatment year.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Classroom Observations - Change in Teaching Practices</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks and 9 months</time_frame>
    <description>To further assess functional improvement, at least two 15-minute classroom observations will be conducted by a treatment-blind research assistant for every study participant. They will occur randomly during the academic school day. The following behaviors will be coded for children in this study: Handles the Unexpected, Following Rules, Transitions, Gets Stuck, Negativity/Overwhelm, and Classroom Participation. Researchers predict that UOT participants will improve more than CBM in Following Rules and Transitions, and UOT and CBM will improve equally in reduction of Negativity/Overwhelm and increased Classroom Participation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>T-SKAMP - Change in Hyperactivity and Attention Over Time</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks, 9 months, and 21 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Swanson, Kotkin, Agler, M-Flynn and Pelham Scale-Teacher Version is a reliable ADHD instrument which gives insight into difficulties with hyperactivity and attention. The online version was used as teacher's find it easier to complete than the paper version.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Flexibility Interference Questions Questionnaire - Parent Reported Change in Flexibility</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks, 9 months, and 21 months</time_frame>
    <description>A short questionnaire was created by researchers for parents to report how often problems with flexibility interfere with daily adaptive functioning.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parent Feedback Form - Change in Program Satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks, 9 months, and 21 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Parent Feedback questionnaire is intended to measure whether parents enjoyed participation in the program. Parents provide feedback on their perception of their child's development as well as the required time commitment. In addition, parents comment on whether the concepts taught during training were easily applied independently.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Caregiver Questionnaire - Change in Family Functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks, 9 months, and 21 months</time_frame>
    <description>The caregiver questionnaire is a measure of family functioning over the most recent month. Parents are asked to answer questions based on how their child's problems influence themselves, the home, their relationships, and participation in the community.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Services and Interventions Questionnaire - Change in Services</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks, 9 months, and 21 months</time_frame>
    <description>Services and Interventions Questionnaire covers the full range of medical and non-medical treatments, including psychotropic medications, therapies, alternative treatments, or any other service a family turns to for help. To participate in this study, families may continue to use or seek any other treatments they desire, there will be no restrictions on their ability to seek outside effective services. The other services will be explored as a possible moderating effect on children's response to study treatments. This questionnaire will also be used to measure non-routine medical visits, including emergency room or urgent care visits, or pediatrician visits for accidents, as well as any additional measures needed for routine visits (sedation, etc.).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Child Participant Interview</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Flexibility Project Follow Up questionnaire is intended to measure whether children enjoyed participating in the program at their school. It also gives children the opportunity to communicate lessons learned throughout the year. Finally, participants can indicate whether those lessons are helpful across home and school settings.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Behavior Rating Inventory of Executive Function (BRIEF) - Parent Form - Change in Executive Functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks, 9 months, and 21 months</time_frame>
    <description>The BRIEF assesses the functional outcome of EF and behavioral regulation in the home settings. This questionnaire is completed by the child's parent or guardian and contains 86 items, with eight clinical scales and two validity scales. Items on the BRIEF were developed to capture everyday behaviors associated with EF; the items tap eight domains, including: initiate, inhibit, shift, plan/organize, organization of materials, self-monitor, emotional control, and working memory. These scales are combined to form two broader indices (Behavioral Regulation and Metacognition) and a Global Executive Composite score. Researchers predict that UOT participants will improve on the Shift, Plan/Organize and Emotional Control scores more than CBM participants.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Child Behavior Checklist (CBCL) - Change in Emotional and Behavioral Functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 12 weeks, 9 months, 21 months</time_frame>
    <description>The CBCL for 6-18 year olds has 118 items that describe specific behavioral and emotional problems, plus two open ended items to describe any additional problems, as well as 20 competence items covering positive, pro-social behaviors. Children's scores are expressed as T scores (mean=50; SD=10) on eight empirically based syndromes scales which are based on factor analyses: Anxious/Depressed, Withdrawn/Depressed, Somatic Complaints, Social Problems, Thought Problems, Attention Problems, Rule-Breaking Behavior, and Aggressive Behavior. The CBCL will be used to track behavioral change at home as a result of the treatments. Researchers predict that UOT and CBM participants will improve equally on the Aggressive Behavior scale, but that UOT participants will improve more on the CBCL Affective Problems score than CBM participants.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Autism Spectrum Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Attention Deficit-Hyperactivity Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Executive Function</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>UOT Students and Parents</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Parents and Students at Title 1 Schools using the intervention &quot;Unstuck and On Target&quot; in the classroom.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PATSS Students and Parents</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Parents and Students at Title 1 Schools using the intervention &quot;Parents and Teachers Supporting Students&quot; in the classroom</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Unstuck and on Target (UOT)</intervention_name>
    <description>Unstuck and on Target (UOT) is a novel and innovative cognitive-behavioral treatment that directly addresses executive functioning and self-regulation deficits in ASD and ADHD. UOT is the first contextually-based EF treatment that targets flexibility, goal-setting and planning through a cognitive-behavioral program centered on self-regulatory scripts that are consistently modeled and reinforced. Parents, teachers, and interventionists will be taught to model and support flexibility across settings. Children will also participate in a peer group intervention setting.</description>
    <arm_group_label>UOT Students and Parents</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Parents and Teachers Supporting Students (PATSS)</intervention_name>
    <description>The Contingency Behavior Management (CBM) intervention was developed by the researchers and called Parents and Teachers Supporting Students (PATSS) as a current best practice intervention that was comparable in design to Unstuck and on Target. The goal is to improve child behavioral outcomes by training parents, teachers and interventionists in core principles of behavior management like social learning and behavioral change. Children were also included in small group sessions where they identify their own behavior goals and meaningful reinforcers.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PATSS Students and Parents</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  We will recruit children who are referred by teachers and staff at their school for
             concerns of flexibility (rather than those who are responding to an advertisement),
             so that we have a &quot;real world&quot; group of children with whom we will test the
             effectiveness of the treatments.

          -  We will participants who have symptoms of ASD or ADHD, are receiving a combination of
             mainstream and special education supports, and qualify to attend pull-out groups in
             school. All the schools involved are eligible for Title 1 governmental support,
             indicating that the children are from primarily low-income communities, although we
             are not requiring that participant's families themselves meet income cutoffs.

          -  The school systems included are: KIPP DC Charter schools, Latin American Montessori
             Bilingual (LAMB) Charter Schools, Arlington County Public Schools, and Fairfax County
             Public Schools.

          -  Potential participants will be evaluated individually and included in the study if
             they achieve a Full Scale IQ score&gt;70, a verbal mental age&gt;6 years old, and meets
             DSM-IV-TR criteria for either a Pervasive Developmental Disorder or ADHD. IQ and
             verbal mental age will be measured with the Wechsler Abbreviated Scale of
             Intelligence (WASI) Verbal, Performance and Full Scale IQ scores (represented as
             Standard Scores: mean=100; SD=15).

          -  Higher scores indicate better performance.

          -  To evaluate for ASD, research-valid clinical psychologists will administer the Autism
             Diagnostic Observation Schedule, Second Edition Module 3 (ADOS-2), a gold standard
             structured play/conversational interview that elicits symptoms of ASD. It produces
             non-standardized raw scores; higher scores indicate more symptoms.

          -  To be included in the study, each child must obtain an ADOS diagnostic algorithm
             &gt;'ASD' threshold and parents will be asked to complete the Social and Communication
             Questionnaire (SCQ).

          -  In order to include the full autism spectrum, these criteria are relatively
             inclusive.

          -  To confirm diagnosis of ADHD, parents completed the ADHD portion of the MINI-Kid ADHD
             interview with a trained interviewer, and their child must meet DSM-IV criteria for
             any Attention Disorder.

          -  We included children who had observable symptoms in one of three settings. All
             children were referred for the study because teachers or staff at their school
             observed symptoms.

          -  Thus the children either had to meet criteria on the MINI-Kid interview or the
             trained clinician completing their testing had to observed symptoms, or both, for the
             child to be included in the study.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Subjects will be excluded from the study if they have a diagnosis of bipolar
             disorder, schizophrenia, or major depression that is currently preventing them from
             participating in classroom activities.

          -  Students with anxiety, mild depression, obsessive-compulsive disorder or other
             problems that do not prevent them from participating in the majority of classroom
             activities will not be excluded.

          -  We will determine who will be excluded through a two-stage process.

          -  First, subjects will be screened for comorbid symptoms using the Child Behavior
             Checklist (CBCL). The CBCL for 6-18 year olds has 118 items that describe specific
             behavioral and emotional problems.

          -  Parents rate their child for how true each item is now or within the past 6 months.

          -  One of the PIs, both of whom are licensed psychologists with active clinical
             practices, will follow-up with a child's teacher if a child scores above a T score of
             75 on any of the six DSM-oriented scales other than Attention Deficit/Hyperactivity
             Problems (Affective Problems; Anxiety Problems; Somatic Problems; Oppositional
             Defiant Problems; and Conduct Problems).

          -  We will ask teachers targeted questions to determine to what degree the identified
             symptoms interfere with the child's ability to participate in the classroom
             activities or in the treatment group such as &quot;Do you feel that the child can
             participate in most classroom activities? If not, why? Can they listen to and follow
             written and verbal instructions? Can they participate in activities with other
             children when given structure and support?&quot; Note that we are not using the Achenbach
             Teacher Report Form instead of the CBCL because we aim to qualify the subjects by
             September, when the teachers may not know the children well enough to answer the
             questions (the TRF asks the teacher to rate the child's behavior over the past two
             months).

          -  However, because the school programs we are partnering with for this study use an
             inclusion model, students in these mainstream classrooms are unlikely to meet
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lauren Kenworthy, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Children's National Health Services</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Research Institude, Children's National Heath System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>American Psychiatric Association. Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders, 4th Edition, Text Revision. 2000.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clopper CJ, Pearson, ES. The use of the confidence or fiducial limits illustrated in the case of the binomial. Biometrika 26(4): 404-413, 1934.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Delis DC, Kaplan E, Kramer JH. Delis Kaplan executive function system (D-KEFS). San Antonio, TX: The Psychological Corporation. 2001.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gioia GA, Isquith PK, Kenworthy L, Barton RM. Profiles of everyday executive function in acquired and developmental disorders. Child Neuropsychol. 2002 Jun;8(2):121-37.</citation>
    <PMID>12638065</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gioia GA, Isquith PK, Retzlaff PD, Espy KA. Confirmatory factor analysis of the Behavior Rating Inventory of Executive Function (BRIEF) in a clinical sample. Child Neuropsychol. 2002 Dec;8(4):249-57.</citation>
    <PMID>12759822</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mather N, Wendling BJ. Woodcock-Johnson IV tests of achievement: Examiner manual standard and extended batteries. Rolling Meadows, IL: Houghton Mifflin Harcourt. 2014.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weisz JR, Ugueto AM, Cheron DM, Herren J. Evidence-based youth psychotherapy in the mental health ecosystem. J Clin Child Adolesc Psychol. 2013;42(2):274-86. doi: 10.1080/15374416.2013.764824.</citation>
    <PMID>23402704</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wells KC, Pelham WE, Kotkin RA, Hoza B, Abikoff HB, Abramowitz A, Arnold LE, Cantwell DP, Conners CK, Del Carmen R, Elliott G, Greenhill LL, Hechtman L, Hibbs E, Hinshaw SP, Jensen PS, March JS, Swanson JM, Schiller E. Psychosocial treatment strategies in the MTA study: rationale, methods, and critical issues in design and implementation. J Abnorm Child Psychol. 2000 Dec;28(6):483-505.</citation>
    <PMID>11104313</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>December 21, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>November 21, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Contingency Behavior Management</keyword>
  <keyword>Flexible</keyword>
  <keyword>Unstuck</keyword>
  <keyword>Low Income</keyword>
  <keyword>Behavior</keyword>
  <keyword>Coping</keyword>
  <keyword>Disparity</keyword>
  <keyword>Problem Solving</keyword>
  <keyword>Self-Control</keyword>
  <keyword>impulsive</keyword>
  <keyword>intervention</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
