<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01425047</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Mangosteen is a tropical tree. The peel of mangosteen fruit is used in traditional medicine. The purpose of this study was to determine the bioavailability of the xanthones from mangosteen juice in adult human subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bioavailability of Xanthones From Mangosteen</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Garcinia mangostana L. (mangosteen) is a tropical tree native to Southeast Asia. The pericarp of mangosteen fruit is used in traditional medicine to treat inflammation, infections, wounds, and diarrhea. The proposed health-promoting effects have been attributed to a family of polyphenols referred to as xanthones. Since its introduction into the United States, juices and products containing mangosteen fruit have become a top-selling botanical dietary supplement. This commercial success largely has been the result of aggressive marketing of health claims based on in vitro observations and anecdotal reports. The purpose of this study was to determine the bioavailability of xanthones from mangosteen juice in adult human subjects. After an overnight fast of at least 10h, male and female subjects were admitted to the Ohio State University Clinical Research Center. Volunteers ingested 2 ounces of 100% mangosteen juice as part of a western-style breakfast. Pericarp particles accounted for 1% of the mass and 99% of total xanthone content in the juice. This dose provided 130 ± 2 mg total xanthones. Blood was collected prior to breakfast and 1,2,3,4,6,8 and 24h. Subjects were fed a mangosteen-free lunch and released from the unit after the 8h collection, refraining from mangosteen containing products until final collection of blood at 24h. Urine was collected for the 24 test period.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>5 female 5 male body mass index &lt;/= 30 normal renal function nonsmoking smokers acute or chronic diseases history of gastrointestinal diseases &gt;/= 10% weight loss dietary or herbal supplement within 6 months of study pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>mangosteen</keyword>
	<keyword>xanthones</keyword>
	<keyword>dietary supplement</keyword>
	<keyword>botanical supplement</keyword>
	<keyword>bioavailability</keyword>
	<keyword>Determine bioavailability of mangosteen xanthones in adults</keyword>
</DOC>