<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01425801</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the pharmacodynamics of single doses of inhaled LAS100977 QD in patients with persistent asthma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Single Dose Study to Assess Efficacy, Safety and Tolerability of LAS100977 in Asthmatic Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adult male and female patients aged 1870 years (both included). 2. Clinical diagnosis of persistent asthma (according to GINA guidelines 2009 update) for at least 6 months prior to screening. 3. Screening FEV1 value of 60% &lt; FEV1 ≤ 85% of the predicted normal value. 4. FEV1 reversibility ≥ 12% and an absolute increase of at least 200 ml over baseline value after inhalation of 400µg (four inhalations) of salbutamol. 5. Predose FEV1 value of first treatment period within the range of ± 20% of the FEV1 measured at screening prior to salbutamol inhalation. 6. Patients on a stable dose and regimen 1. Current smokers, former smokers within the last 6 months, or exsmokers with a history of more than 10 packyears. 2. Patients diagnosed with COPD. 3. Recent Respiratory tract infections within 6 weeks before Screening Visit. 4. Intubation (ever) or hospitalization for longer than 24 hours for the management of an asthma exacerbation within the preceding 6 weeks of the screening visit. 5. Clinically significant respiratory conditions. 6. Clinically significant cardiovascular conditions. 7. Patients unable to properly use a dry powder or pMDI inhaler device or unable to perform acceptable spirometry. 8. Clinically relevant abnormalities laboratory, ECG parameters or physical examination results at the screening evaluation that in the investigator's opinion, preclude study participation. 9. Patients who intend to use any concomitant medication not permitted by this protocol or who have not undergone the required washout period for a particular prohibited medication.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
</DOC>