<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02627690</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Islet transplantation for type 1 diabetes results are still improving, and actually Insulin-independence with normal HbA1c is obtained in 50% of patients after 5 years, 80% of c-peptide positive patients. In addition to the need of 2 or 3 surgical or radiological interventions to inject islets, an immunosuppressive regimen is needed, which can be deleterious, particularly on kidneys. Moreover, long term beneficial effects of islet transplantation on stabilization or prevention of macro and micro vascular complications of diabetes has not been evaluated. In a preliminary work, it was observed a stabilisation or improvement of microvascular complications when compared to pre-transplant datas. The aim of this study is to compare the evolution of diabetes complications, especially nephrologic, 10 years after islet transplantation and to compare it to patients with a brittle diabetes, 10 years after evaluation for islet transplantation, finally not performed. This case-control study will evaluate nephrologic parameters (creatinine, MDRD creatinine clearance, microalbuminuria, proteinuria) and other micro and macro-vascular complications of type 1 diabetes) before islet transplantation and 10 years after the transplantation or after the first evaluation in patients who finally did not underwent islet transplantation for various non nephrologic reasons</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nephrologic Prognosis 10 Years After Diabetes Cell Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Type 1 diabetic patients, with or without previous renal transplantation who benefit at least 5 years before the inclusion of clinical evaluation in order to perform an islet transplantation Who either benefit of islet transplantation or did not and treated with optimized insulin therapy Cpeptide positive diabetes Type 1 diabetic patient nongrafted of islets due to albuminuria&gt; 300mg / 24h or MDRD &lt;50 ml / min during the pretransplant evaluation (exclusion criterion for islet transplantation) Patients that can not receive clear information Refusal to sign the consent Psychiatric Pathology Participation in another study excluding the possibility of participating in another protocol. Pregnant or breast feeding women Patients under guardianship, persons deprived of freedom Lack of coverage by the social security system</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>