<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02397447</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The hypoglycemic effect of Momordica Charantia has been evaluated in clinical trials in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Important reductions in fasting plasma glucose, glycated hemoglobin (A1C), and fructosamine were observed. It is unknown whether this improvement is due to an improvement in insulin sensitivity and insulin secretion. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effect of the administration of Momordica Charantia on insulin sensitivity and insulin secretion in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Momordica Charantia Administration on Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus, Insulin Sensitivity and Insulin Secretion</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A randomized, double-blind, placebo controlled clinical trial is carried out in 24 patients with diagnosis of diabetes mellitus type 2 according to the criteria of the American Diabetes Association. Patients are assigned to two different arms: one group receives Momordica Charantia, 2 capsules with 500 mg twice daily before breakfast and dinner for 90 days or placebo, under the same scheme of treatment. An oral glucose tolerance test is performed before and after the intervention. Matsuda index, Stumvoll index and Insulinogenic index are calculated to assess insulin sensitivity and insulin secretion. Other clinical and laboratory parameters that are evaluated include: Body weight, body mass index, waist circumference, blood pressure, body fat percentage, fasting plasma glucose, A1C, creatinine, lipid profile and liver transaminases.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Magnesium Oxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of diabetes mellitus type 2 according to the criteria of the American Diabetes Association (&lt;5 years), without pharmacological treatment (oral antidiabetic drugs or insulin) at least for three months before entering the study Fasting glucose: &lt;210 mg/dl A1C: 79% Body mass index: 2534.9 kg/m2 Body weight without variations above or under 5% in the last three months before entering the study Women in childbearing years must have a contraceptive method Letter of consent and release signed by each patient Pregnant or suspected pregnant women Woman breastfeeding Medications known to affect metabolism of glucose and insulin Personal history of liver or renal disease Hypertension, thyroid or cardiovascular disease decompensated Total cholesterol &gt;= 240mg/dl, triglycerides &gt;=400mg/dl, glomerular filtration rate &lt;=60ml/min or liver transaminases &gt;=2.5 the upper normal limit</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Momordica Charantia</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin secretion</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin sensitivity</keyword>
</DOC>