<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02397278</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study plans to learn more about ways to treat a joint problem in the knee called Juvenile Osteochondritis Dissecans (OCD). The goal of this study is to see if injecting platelet-rich plasma (PRP) into the knee can help knee cartilage heal faster, and will try to determine whether the injections lead to improvements in pain, performance of activities of daily living, improvements is sports activities and overall function and symptoms reduction. The investigators will compare PRP treatment to conservative therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intra Articular Injections With Platelet Rich Plasma in Patients With Juvenile Osteochondritis Dissecans of the Knee:</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteochondritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteochondritis Dissecans</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteochondrosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female age 10 17 inclusive with open physis confirmed by MRI 2. Documented symptomatic stable juvenile osteochondritis dissecans of the knee based on MRI without changes of osteoarthritis and no prior history of knee surgery. 3. The patient must be able to hold still without sedation for approximately 1 hour and must pass MRI screening evaluation for retained metal. 4. Patients with Di Paola stage 1 or 2 lesions 1. Patients with polyarticular disease. 2. Patients with blood disorders (Blood disorders (thrombopathy, thrombocytopenia, anemia with hemoglobin &lt;9g/dL). Only those patients with a positive history of blood disorders will have a Complete Blood Count (CBC) performed a week prior to inclusion in the study. 3. Patients who had intraarticular treatment with steroids within 3 months 4. Patients who are pregnant or nursing at the time of consent. 5. Patients with inflammatory arthritic conditions (e.g. rheumatoid arthritis) 6. NonEnglish speaking patients. (Scores used for evaluation have not been validated in Spanish) 7. Patients who had previous knee surgery 8. Additional disabilities in any of the lower limbs that would interfere with any of the clinical assessments. 9. Chronic use of NSAID (defined as taking nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug) regularly every week for the last 6 months), steroids or chemotherapy drugs 10. Treatment with NSAIDs within 15 days prior to randomization in this study 11. Patients with a BMI over 30. Due to the fact that this study utilizes an injection technique which may be inaccurate in obese subjects. 12. Patients with a prolongation of bleeding time, e.g. those receiving anticoagulant drug therapy 13. Patients with a contraindication to MRI including: patients with cardiac pacemaker or nonapproved intracranial vascular clip, and those with orthopedic hardware as the resulting artifact can complicate interpretation 14. Patients with acute or chronic renal failure 15. Patients with a previous anaphylactic reaction to gadolinium enhanced MRI. 16. Patients with Di Paola stage 3 or 4 lesions</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>