<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00702247</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate toxicity profile and efficacy of a tandem autologous-nonmyeloablative transplant approach in newly diagnose myeloma patients younger than 65 years</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tandem Autologous- Nonmyeloablative Allogeneic Transplant for Newly Diagnosed Multiple Myeloma (Trapianto Tandem Autologo-Allogenico Non Mieloablativo Nel Mieloma Alla Diagnosi)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DurieSalmon stage IIAIIIB multiple myeloma Age &gt; 18 and ≤ 65 years Previously untreated myeloma Presence of a sibling (potential donor) Bilirubins &lt; twice normal;ALAT and ASAT &lt; four times normal Left ventricular ejection fraction &gt; 40% Creatinine clearances &gt; 40 mL/min Pulmonary dysfunction with diffusing capacity for carbon monoxide (DLCO) &gt; 40% and/or need for continuous oxygen supplementation Karnofsky performance status &gt; 60% Patients must give written informed consent Age &gt; 65 years Previously treated myeloma Absence of a sibling (genetic randomisation cannot be applied) Karnofsky performance status score &lt; 60% HIVinfection Pregnancy Refusal to use contraceptive techniques during and for 12 months following treatment Patients unable to give written informed consent PS. Informed consent is obtained from each patient according to the Institutional Review Boards of the participating centers. The study is conducted according to the Declaration of Helsinki.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma - Nonmyeloablative transplantation - Autologous Transplant - Graft versus myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Newly diagnosed multiple myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Tandem Auto-Allo Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Overall survival</keyword>
	<keyword>Event free survival</keyword>
	<keyword>Disease response</keyword>
</DOC>