<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00702117</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study evaluates 3 different populations: It is an open, randomized, parallel-group study comparing the effectiveness of intravenous (iv) ajmaline with currently used antiarrhythmic drugs in the acute treatment of : 1. recent-onset atrial fibrillation versus iv flecainide 2. sustained monomorphous ventricular tachycardia versus iv procainamide The study also evaluates in an open, randomized, crossover study, the use of iv ajmaline versus iv flecainide in the diagnosis of Brugada syndrome</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ajmaline Utilization in the Diagnosis and Treatment of Cardiac Arrhythmias</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tachycardia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arrhythmias, Cardiac</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brugada Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tachycardia, Ventricular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Flecainide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ajmaline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lorajmine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Procainamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>AF: Patients with isolated, idiopathic, sustained, symptomatic, recent onset(&gt;10 minutes to &lt;24 hours) atrial fibrillation. VT: Patients with ventricular tachycardia with good haemodynamic tolerability attending the emergency room or induced at the electrophysiology lab during testing for ventricular arrhythmias. Brugada Sd (BrS): Firstdegree relatives of a patient with Brugada Syndrome with a ECG nondiagnostic of the BrS. General: Pregnancy AF: Preexisting heart disease. Secondary AF 2nd and 3rd degree AV block or RBBB associated with LAFB or LPFB (bifascicular block). LVF&lt;40%. Moderatesevere liver failure. AF with haemodynamic compromise. VT:VT with haemodynamic compromise. BrS:Preexisting heart disease. 2nd and 3rd degree AV block or RBBB associated with LAFB or LPFB (bifascicular block). Moderatesevere liver failure.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>