<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00702351</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the induction of multiple follicular growth after single dose administration of 100 μg or 150 μg Org 36286 in a long protocol of GnRH agonist.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Trial of Single Dose Corifollitropin Alfa's Ability to Induce Multiple Follicular Growth During the First Week of Controlled Ovarian Stimulation for IVF or ICSI (38833)(P05788)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this trial, all subjects were (pre)treated daily with subcutaneous triptorelin, a GnRH agonist which is known to provide profound suppression of endogenous LH and FSH. It was evaluated whether these down-regulated subjects show an appropriate ovarian response to 100 μg or 150 μg Org 36286 during the first week of stimulation. To evaluate this, follicular growth was measured by USS, and serum inhibin-B and E2 levels were assessed.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Females of couples with an indication for controlled ovarian stimulation (COS) and IVF or ICSI that have had at least one previous COS cycle with proven normal ovarian response; &gt;=18 and &lt;= 39 years of age at the time of signing informed consent; a. First group: Body weight &gt;= 50 kg and BMI &gt;= 18 and &lt;= 29 kg/m^2; b. Second group: Body weight &lt;= 60 kg and BMI &lt;= 29 kg/m^2; Normal menstrual cycle length: 2435 days; Ejaculatory sperm (use of donated and/or cryopreserved sperm is allowed); Normal routine diagnostic hysteroscopy and endometrial biopsy; Willing and able to sign informed consent. History of or any current (treated) endocrine abnormality; History of ovarian hyperresponse1 or history of ovarian hyperstimulation syndrome (OHSS); History of or current polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS); A basal antral follicle count &gt; 20 (size &lt; 11 mm, both ovaries combined) on USS during the early follicular phase (menstrual cycle day 25); Less than 2 ovaries or any other ovarian abnormality; Presence of unilateral or bilateral hydrosalpinx (visible on USS); Presence of unilateral or bilateral endometriomas (&gt;10 mm; visible on USS); More than three unsuccessful COS cycles since the last established ongoing pregnancy (if applicable); History of non or low ovarian response to FSH/hMG treatment; FSH or LH &gt; 12 IU/L as measured by the local laboratory (sample taken during the early follicular phase: menstrual cycle day 25); Any clinically relevant abnormal laboratory value based on a sample taken during the screening phase; Contraindications for the use of gonadotropins (e.g. tumors, pregnancy/lactation, undiagnosed vaginal bleeding, hypersensitivity, ovarian cysts) or GnRH analogues (e.g. hypersensitivity, pregnancy/lactation); Recent history of or current epilepsy, diabetes or cardiovascular, gastrointestinal, hepatic, renal or pulmonary disease; History or presence of alcohol or drug abuse within 12 months prior to signing informed consent; Previous use of Org 36286; Use of hormonal preparations within 1 month prior to screening; Administration of investigational drugs within three months prior to signing informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>39 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Infertility</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacological effects of drugs</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Hormones</keyword>
	<keyword>GnRH agonist</keyword>
	<keyword>RecFSH</keyword>
	<keyword>Corifollitropin alfa</keyword>
	<keyword>Open-label</keyword>
</DOC>