<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00702442</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Protocol title: Role of low dose droperidol in postoperative vomiting Purpose: Evaluate the efficacy of droperidol to postoperative nausea and vomiting when administrated at the introduction to anesthesia, prior to surgery Design: Prospective, randomized, placebo-controlled study Patient Population: Male or female subjects 18 years of age or older who are scheduled for laparoscopic cholecystectomy No. of Subjects: 100 patients divided into two groups, estimated up to 6 months to enroll Duration of Treatment: Prior operation Duration of Follow-up: Follow-up will be performed for 24 hours postoperatively Endpoints: To evaluate the effectiveness of low dose droperidol when administered Prior surgery</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Role of Droperidol in Postoperative Vomiting</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this prospective, randomized, placebo-controlled study, the researchers determined whether 0.625 mg (1/2 amp) IV droperidol given at the initiation of general anesthesia reduces the incidence of immediate and delayed post operative nausea and vomiting (PONV) in laparoscopic cholecystectomy population. One hundred patients receiving general anesthesia for laparoscopic cholecystectomy received droperidol 0.625 mg (1/2 amp) mg or placebo prior operation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Droperidol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient more than 18 years old Patients scheduled for laparoscopic cholecystectomy Informed consent obtained from the patient Age &lt; 18 years old Contraindication to laparoscopic surgery Present a severe depressive syndrome Pregnancy women Trouble of cardiac rate Alcoholism Contraindication for Droperidol prescription</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Nausea, Vomiting</keyword>
	<keyword>Vomiting episodes</keyword>
</DOC>