<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00803309</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study we intend to treat patients with chronic hepatitis C of genotype 2 or 3 having characteristics associated with poor treatment response for additional 12 or 24 weeks beyond the standard treatment of PEG-IFN alpha-2b plus ribavirin. The objective of this study is to compare the efficacy of a treatment extension of 12 versus 24 weeks in patients with HCV-genotypes 2 and 3 who are treated with 1.5 µg/kg PEG-IFN alpha-2b and 800-1400 mg ribavirin (standard dose) for 24 weeks (standard duration) and who are not HCV-RNA negative (&lt; 15 IU/ml) after 4 weeks of standard treatment but HCV-RNA negative after 16-24 weeks of standard treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Assess the Efficacy of 12 Versus 24 Weeks of Extended Treatment in HCV-Genotype 2/3 Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female patients with HCVgenotype 2/3 chronic hepatitis C documented by detectable plasma HCV RNA (&gt; 15 IU/mL) and positivity of antiHCV antibodies Age ≥ 18 years Compensated liver disease (ChildPugh Grade A clinical classification) Negative urine or blood pregnancy test (one of the both; for women of childbearing potential) documented within the 24hour period prior to the first dose of study drug. Additionally, all fertile males and females must be using two forms of effective contraception during treatment and during the 7 months after treatment end. This includes using birth control pills (no interaction with investigational drugs), IUDs, condoms, diaphragms, or implants, being surgically sterilized, or being in a postmenopausal state. At least one contraception method must be of barrier method Ongoing treatment with 1.5 µg/kg PegInterferon alpha2b (PegIntron®) and &gt; 10.6 mg/kg ribavirin (Rebetol®) No rapid virological response (HCVRNA positive after week 4 of the ongoing therapy) Willingness to give written informed consent and willingness to participate to and to comply with the study protocol Women with ongoing pregnancy or breast feeding Male partners of women who are pregnant Positive tests at screening for antiHAV IgM Ab, HBsAg, antiHBc IgM Ab, HBeAg, antiHIV, HIVRNA History or other evidence of a medical condition associated with chronic liver disease other than HCV associated (e.g., hemochromatosis, autoimmune hepatitis, alcoholic liver disease, toxin exposures) History or other evidence of bleeding from esophageal varices or other conditions consistent with decompensated liver disease Patients with liver cirrhosis with a lesion suspicious for hepatic malignancy on the screening Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt;750 cells/mm3 at screening Platelet count &lt;50,000 cells/mm3 at screening Hb &lt;10 g/dl at screening Dose modification of PegInterferon alpha2b (PegIntron®) or ribavirin (Rebetol®) during the first 4 weeks of the ongoing therapy Interferon alpha or ribavirin therapy at any time point before the actual ongoing treatment Less than 80% adherence to treatment of the ongoing treatment until randomization (week 2022 of ongoing treatment) Serum creatinine level &gt;1.5 times the upper limit of normal at screening History of severe psychiatric disease, especially depression (ICD 10 codes F30F33). Severe psychiatric disease is defined as treatment with an antidepressant medication or a major tranquilizer at therapeutic doses for major depression or psychosis, respectively, for at least 3 months at any previous time. Patients are excluded if any history of suicidal attempts is evident. If hospitalization for psychiatric disease, or a period of disability due to a psychiatric disease are documented, psychiatric consultation is mandatory. Patients with a mild or moderate psychiatric disease (ICD 10 codes F32.0, F32.1, F33.0, F33.1) are only allowed to be included into the trial if a regular monitoring by a psychiatrist is performed during the trial History of a severe seizure disorder or current anticonvulsant use History of immunologically mediated disease (e.g., inflammatory bowel disease, idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura, lupus erythematosus, autoimmune hemolytic anemia, scleroderma, severe psoriasis, rheumatoid arthritis) History or any other evidence of autoimmune diseases History or other evidence of chronic pulmonary disease associated with functional limitation History of significant cardiac disease that could be worsened by acute anemia (e.g. NYHA Functional Class III or IV, myocardial infarction within 6 months prior to treatment with PegInterferon/ribavirin therapy, ventricular tachyarrhythmias requiring ongoing treatment, unstable angina) Evidence of thyroid disease that is poorly controlled on prescribed medications Evidence of severe retinopathy (e.g. CMV retinitis, macular degeneration) History of major organ transplantation with an existing functional graft History or other evidence of severe illness, malignancy or any other conditions which would make the patient, in the opinion of the investigator, unsuitable for the study History of any systemic antineoplastic or immunomodulatory treatment (including supraphysiologic doses of steroids and radiation) 6 months prior to the first dose of study drug or the expectation that such treatment will be needed at any time during the study Patients with evidence for tuberculosis Drug abuse within 6 months prior to the first dose of study drug and excessive alcohol consumption. Patients on methadone/polamidone/buprenorphine programs are not excluded Any investigational drug and/or participation in another clinical study prior 6 months to the actual ongoing antiviral treatment Limited contractual capability</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic HCV-genotype 2/3</keyword>
	<keyword>Efficacy of treatment extension</keyword>
	<keyword>PegIntron</keyword>
	<keyword>pegylated interferon alpha-2b</keyword>
	<keyword>Rebetol</keyword>
	<keyword>ribavirin</keyword>
</DOC>