<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00803010</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research is to compare the effectiveness of Tacrolimus and Rapamycin to Tacrolimus and Methotrexate in the prevention of severe graft-versus-host-disease. Graft-versus-host-disease (GVHD) is a risk associated with allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplants (HCT). An allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplant is a transplant using bone marrow and blood cells that come from someone other than the patient (a donor).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Graft-Versus-Host Disease (GVHD) Prophylaxis After Allogeneic Peripheral Blood Hematopoietic Cell Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All drugs used in this study have been used in the prevention of graft-versus-host-disease after allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplant. Tacrolimus and Methotrexate used in combination are currently used as standard of care in the prevention of graft-versus-host-disease after allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplant. Tacrolimus and Rapamycin is a newer combination we are testing to see if it would be better than Tacrolimus and Methotrexate.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Graft vs Host Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 16 and ≤ 70 Signed informed consent Adequate vital organ function No active infection, or asymptomatic infection well controlled by antibiotic HIV negative by ELISA or RTPCR [if ELISA is positive and RTPCR is negative, the ELISA is considered false positive] Hepatitis B and C negative by serology or RTPCR Performance status: Karnofsky Performance Status Score ≥ 60%. Those with any Sorror's comorbidity factors with score &gt; 3 2 or more Sorror's factors with composite score of ≥ 3</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute Graft Versus Host Disease (aGVHD)</keyword>
	<keyword>GVHD</keyword>
	<keyword>graft-versus-host disease</keyword>
	<keyword>tacrolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>sirolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>methotrexate</keyword>
	<keyword>combination therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>GVHD prophylaxis</keyword>
</DOC>