<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02342288</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A rare but terrible complication of vision loss has been known to occur after surgery, including spine surgery. It is commonly thought that increased intraocular pressure (IOP) is one of the reasons for this rare vision loss. It has been shown that the prone position can increase the IOP, and that tilting the patient with the head down can also increase IOP. The investigators will be measuring IOP before, during, and after a posterior spine surgery to see if the investigators can influence the intraocular pressure with elevated head position change. Two groups will be studied: one group of patients will receive standard care with the head in neutral position, while the other group will have the head slightly elevated 10 degrees during prone spine surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intraoperative Ocular Pressure in Lumbar Spine Fusion Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>It has been reported that postoperative vision loss after lumbar surgery is increasing. It is an uncommon but devastating complication. One of the risk factors that has been reported is increased intraocular pressure (IOP), which may decrease perfusion pressure to the optic nerve. Intraocular pressure in anesthetized, prone spine patients has been studied with the head in neutral position. The prone position and duration of the procedure did increase the IOP. Our hypothesis is that adjusting the position of the head in space will alter the intraocular pressure, with an extended position decreasing IOP. This study is a, randomized, controlled design: neutral head position (standard care) or extended head position (intervention group). Patients who qualify for spinal fusion surgery and meet the inclusion criteria will be randomized to either the neutral (standard practice) or the intervention group.Randomization of patients will be computer generated.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Patients undergoing elective lumbar spinal fusion surgery; ages 1880 Less than 18 years of age Glaucoma, previous eye surgery, eye injury, or eye trauma, cervical myelopathy, prior cervical spine surgery, current neoplasm, patients who have neck pain with 10 degrees active extension.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Intraoperative ocular pressure</keyword>
</DOC>