<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02342522</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether remote ischemic conditioning can reduce cardiac death and hospitalization for heart failure in patients presenting with a ST-elevation myocardial infarction and treated by percutaneous coronary intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Remote Ischaemic Conditioning on Clinical Outcomes in STEMI Patients Undergoing PPCI</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The ERIC-PPCI is a 2000 patient 30 UK site randomised controlled double-blind clinical trial which will investigate whether remote ischemic conditioning (RIC) can reduce cardiac death and hospitalization for heart failure at 12 months in patients presenting with a ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) and treated by percutaneous coronary intervention (PPCI). It also includes 2 sub-studies. The Biomarker sub-study will investigate the enzymatic infarct size at 6 months. The Cardiac Magnetic Resonance (CMR) sub-study will investigate infarct size at 6 months. This study is a research collaboration with Aarhus University in Denmark (CONDI2 trial ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier:NCT01857414).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Reperfusion Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Reperfusion Injury</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria 1. Onset of STEMI symptoms within 12 hours, lasting for more than 30 minutes 2. Patients older than 18 years 3. Suspected STEMI (STelevation at the Jpoint in two contiguous leads with the cutoff points: ≥0.2 millivolt (mV) in men or ≥0.15 mV in women in leads V2V3 and/or ≥0.1 mV in other leads) 4. Eligibility for coronary angiography with follow on PPCI if indicated Exclusion criteria 1. Previous coronary artery bypass graft surgery 2. Myocardial infarction (MI) within the previous 30 days 3. Treatment with thrombolysis within the previous 30 days 4. Left bundle branch block (LBBB) 5. Patients treated with therapeutic hypothermia 6. Conditions precluding use of RIC (paresis of upper limb, use of an av shunt) 7. Life expectancy of less than 1 year due to noncardiac pathology</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cardioprotection</keyword>
	<keyword>STEMI</keyword>
	<keyword>PPCI</keyword>
	<keyword>Myocardial reperfusion injury</keyword>
	<keyword>Myocardial infarct size</keyword>
</DOC>