<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00505960</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the feasibility and efficacy of a culturally-tailored, comprehensive behavioral intervention program specially designed for linguistically challenged ethnic minority immigrant populations (Korean Americans) with type 2 DM.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Culturally Tailored Behavioral Diabetes Care Intervention for Korean Americans</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Korean American immigrants (KAI), one of the most underserved and understudied minority populations in the U.S., suffer from diabetes, which goes under-diagnosed, inadequately treated and has a potential to result in costly and tragic consequences. Language barriers, the lack of self-confidence, and diminished social support that accompany the acculturation process prevent KAI from improving their health-seeking behaviors. Our previous research has indicated that overwhelming numbers of KAI suffer not only from uncontrolled hyperglycemia but also from a loss of self-confidence and social isolation because of language and cultural barriers. They are in urgent need of an intervention to assist them in their efforts to achieve better glycemic control and restore their self-confidence in diabetes and health management so that they are able to adjust successfully in this new environment. Therefore, The purpose of this study is to assess the feasibility and efficacy of a culturally-tailored, comprehensive behavioral intervention program specially designed for linguistically challenged KAIs with type 2 DM. This pilot project will test the hypothesis: Compared to KAI in the control group, KAI with type 2 DM who receive a comprehensive DM management intervention through structured psycho-behavioral education, home glucose monitoring with a telephone transmission system, and interaction with a bilingual nurse case manager will show: (1) a greater level of glucose control; and (2) a greater level of self-help skills including knowledge related to glucose control, problem-solving skills, heightened confidence and mood/affect, adherence to treatment recommendations, and quality of life. An additional outcome will be to measure and obtain an ideal BP as the proposed intervention focuses on management of multiple risk factors with which many KA DM patients often struggle.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Selfidentified as a first generation Korean American Age 30 years or older Resides in WashingtonBaltimore area Expresses willingness to participate in all aspects of the study over its full course Written consent to participate in the screening/eligibility visit Selfidentified with DM and HbA1c &gt;= 8% within 6 months of screening Written consent to participate in the clinical trial: agreeing to participate in study data collection procedures, receiving DM self help education, using HGMT, and permitting contact with their own medical care provider. Unable to give informed consent Physical or mental health conditions that could limit active participation in the study (e.g., blindness in both eyes, severe immobility, psychiatric diseases) Hematological condition that would affect A1C assay, e.g., hemolytic anemia, sickle cell anemia.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>