<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00385736</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to assess the efficacy and safety of adalimumab for the induction of clinical remission in subjects with moderately to severely active ulcerative colitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Adalimumab in Subjects With Moderately to Severely Acute Ulcerative Colitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This was a Phase 3, multicenter, randomized, double-blind (DB), placebo-controlled trial designed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of the human anti-TNF monoclonal antibody adalimumab for the induction of clinical remission in participants with moderately to severely active ulcerative colitis (UC). Adult participants with moderate to severe UC (Mayo score of 6 to 12 points with endoscopy subscore of 2 to 3 points), confirmed by colonoscopy with biopsy or by flexible sigmoidoscopy with biopsy, were enrolled at 80 sites worldwide. The study enrolled 576 participants, including 186 participants under the original protocol and protocol Amendments 1 and 2, and 390 participants under protocol Amendments 3 and 4. Participants enrolled in the study prior to Amendment 3 were randomized in a 1:1 ratio to receive adalimumab or placebo during the 12-week DB induction period. Participants received 4 injections of adalimumab 40 mg (160 mg) or 4 injections of placebo at Baseline (Week 0), followed by 2 injections of adalimumab 40 mg (80 mg) or 2 injections of placebo at Week 2, followed by 1 injection of adalimumab 40 mg or placebo at Weeks 4 and 6. At Week 8, participants randomized to placebo received 4 injections of adalimumab 40 mg (160 mg) followed by 2 injections of adalimumab 40 mg (80 mg) at Week 10. Participants randomized to adalimumab received 3 injections of placebo and 1 injection of adalimumab 40 mg at Week 8 and 1 injection of placebo and 1 injection of adalimumab 40 mg at Week 10. All participants continued to receive 1 injection of open-label (OL) adalimumab 40 mg every other week beginning at Week 12 up to Week 52 (or the early termination visit). Starting at Week 14, participants who had inadequate responses to treatment (as defined using partial Mayo scores) were permitted to dose escalate to adalimumab 40 mg weekly. Participants with persistent inadequate response while on weekly treatment could be discontinued from the study at the discretion of the investigator. In August 2007, the study design was amended to incorporate an additional adalimumab induction dosing arm of 80/40 mg. Earlier that year, both 160/80-mg and 80/40-mg induction regimens had been approved in the EU as induction treatment for Crohn's disease. The adalimumab induction dosing regimen of 80/40 mg was therefore included so that both of these approved induction regimens would be evaluated for the induction of remission of UC. Participants enrolled in the study after Amendment 3 were randomized in a 1:1:1 ratio to receive adalimumab (1 of 2 regimens) or placebo during the 8-week DB induction period. Participants received DB therapy from Baseline until Week 8 and OL therapy from Week 8 until the end of the study. In the first adalimumab dosing arm (adalimumab 80/40), participants received 2 injections of adalimumab 40 mg (80 mg) and 2 injections of placebo at Baseline followed by 1 injection of adalimumab 40 mg and 1 injection of placebo at Week 2, and 1 injection of adalimumab 40 mg every other week thereafter. In the second adalimumab DB induction dosing arm (adalimumab 160/80), participants received 4 injections of adalimumab 40 mg (160 mg) at Baseline followed by 2 injections of adalimumab 40 mg (80 mg) at Week 2, and 1 injection of adalimumab 40 mg every other week thereafter. Participants randomized to placebo received 4 injections of placebo at Baseline followed by 2 injections of placebo at Week 2, and 1 injection of placebo at Weeks 4 and 6. Beginning at Week 8, but after the Week 8 study assessments had been completed, all participants received 1 injection of OL adalimumab 40 mg every other week until Week 52 or early termination. Starting at Week 12, participants who had inadequate responses to treatment (as defined using partial Mayo scores) were permitted to dose escalate to adalimumab 40 mg weekly. Participants with persistent inadequate response while on weekly treatment could be discontinued from the study at the discretion of the investigator. For the analysis of efficacy parameters during the DB Period through Week 8, only participants randomized under Protocol Amendment 3 or later were considered ("Efficacy Analysis Set - Induction" in the participant flow). For the analysis of efficacy parameters during the OL Period through Week 52, all randomized participants (under any version of the protocol) who received at least 1 dose of study drug were considered ("Efficacy Analysis Set - Maintenance" in the participant flow). For the analysis of safety parameters, all participants who received at least 1 dose of study drug were considered ("Safety Analysis Set" in the participant flow). Twelve ranked secondary variables during the DB Period through Week 8 were to be tested in a hierarchical order to account for multiple testing. These variables are identified as "Ranked Secondary Endpoints" in the results section below. Additionally, non-ranked secondary variables during the OL Period through Week 52 were tested and are presented after the ranked secondary endpoints in the results section below.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The following eligibility criteria applied to participants enrolled following Amendment 3 to the study protocol. 1. Male and female participants &gt;= 18 years of age 2. Diagnosis of ulcerative colitis for greater than 90 days prior to Baseline 3. Diagnosis of active ulcerative colitis confirmed by colonoscopy with biopsy or flexible sigmoidoscopy with biopsy during the Screening Period, with exclusion of infection 4. Active UC with a Mayo score of 6 to 12 points and endoscopy subscore of 2 to 3 points, despite concurrent treatment with at least 1 of the following (oral corticosteroids or immunosuppressants or both as defined below): Stable oral corticosteroid dose (prednisone dose of &gt;= 20 mg/day or equivalent) for at least 14 days prior to Baseline or stable oral corticosteroid dose (prednisone of &lt; 20 mg/day) for at least 40 days prior to Baseline. and/or At least a consecutive 90 day course of azathioprine or 6mercaptopurine (6 MP) prior to Baseline, with a dose of azathioprine &gt;= 1.5 mg/kg/day or 6 MP &gt;= 1 mg/kg/day (rounded to the nearest available tablet formulation), or a dose that is the highest tolerated by the participant (e.g., due to leukopenia, elevated liver enzymes, nausea) during that time. Participant was to be on a stable dose for at least 28 days prior to Baseline. Concurrent therapy was not required for participants who were previously treated with corticosteroids or immunosuppressants (azathioprine or 6MP) during the previous 5 years and, in the judgment of the investigator, have failed to respond to or could not tolerate their treatment. 5. Had to be able to selfadminister or has caregiver who can reliably administer subcutaneous injections. 6. Had to be able and willing to give written informed consent and to comply with the requirements of this study protocol. 7. Female had to be either not of childbearing potential, defined as postmenopausal for at least 1 year or surgically sterile (bilateral tubal ligation, bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy), or of childbearing potential and practicing an approved method of birth control throughout the study and for 150 days after last dose of study drug. Examples of approved methods of birth control included the following: Condoms, sponge, foams, jellies, diaphragm or intrauterine device Oral, parenteral or intravaginal contraceptives for 90 days prior to study drug administration A vasectomized partner 8. The results of the serum pregnancy test performed at the Screening Visit and urine pregnancy test performed at the Baseline Visit had to be negative. 9. Judged to be in generally good health as determined by the principal investigator 1. History of subtotal colectomy with ileorectostomy or colectomy with ileoanal pouch, Koch pouch, or ileostomy for ulcerative colitis or is planning bowel surgery. 2. Received infliximab or any other antiTNF agent or any biological therapy in the past. 3. Received previous treatment with adalimumab or previous participation in an adalimumab clinical study. 4. Received cyclosporine, tacrolimus, or mycophenolate mofetil within 30 days prior to Baseline. 5. Received intravenous corticosteroids within 14 days prior to Screening or during the Screening Period. 6. Received therapeutic enema or suppository, other than required for endoscopy, within 14 days prior to the Screening endoscopy and during the remainder of the Screening Period. 7. Current diagnosis of fulminant colitis and/or toxic megacolon. 8. Participants with disease limited to the rectum (ulcerative proctitis). 9. Current diagnosis of indeterminate colitis. 10. Current diagnosis and/or history of Crohn's disease. 11. Currently receiving total parenteral nutrition. 12. Discontinued use of azathioprine or 6MP within 28 days of Baseline. 13. Discontinued use of corticosteroid within 14 days of Baseline. 14. Participants using aminosalicylates for less than 90 days prior to Baseline, not on a stable dose for at least 28 days prior to Baseline, or discontinued use within 28 days of Baseline. 15. Participants with positive Clostridium difficile stool assay. 16. Infections requiring treatment with intravenous (IV) antibiotics, IV antivirals, or IV antifungals within 30 days prior to Baseline or oral antibiotics, oral antivirals, or oral antifungals within 14 days prior to Baseline. 17. History of malignancy other than a successfully treated nonmetastatic cutaneous squamous cell or basal cell carcinoma and/or localized carcinoma in situ of the cervix. If the Screening colonoscopy/flexible sigmoidoscopy showed evidence of dysplasia or a malignancy, the participant was not to be enrolled in the study. 18. History of listeria, histoplasmosis, chronic or active hepatitis B infection, human immunodeficiency virus, immunodeficiency syndrome, central nervous system demyelinating disease, or untreated tuberculosis (TB). 19. Female participants who was pregnant or breastfeeding or considering becoming pregnant during the study. There should be at least a 150day period between the last dose of study drug and either conception or initiation of breastfeeding in women of childbearing potential. 20. Poorly controlled medical condition(s), such as uncontrolled diabetes, unstable ischemic heart disease, moderate to severe congestive heart failure, recent cerebrovascular accident and any other condition, which in the opinion of the investigator, would put the participant at risk by participation in the protocol. 21. Received any investigational agent within 30 days or 5 half lives prior to Baseline (whichever is longer). 22. History of clinically significant drug or alcohol abuse during the previous year. 23. Participants with known hypersensitivity to the excipients of adalimumab as stated in the label. 24. Participants with any prior exposure to Tysabri® (natalizumab). 25. Participants currently taking both budesonide and prednisone (or equivalent) simultaneously.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Moderate to Severe Ulcerative Colitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Double-blind</keyword>
	<keyword>Adalimumab</keyword>
	<keyword>Induction of Clinical Remission</keyword>
</DOC>