<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01321099</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Iron deficiency (ID) is still a main public health problem in sub-Saharan Africa. Iron deficient children have an increased risk for anemia which is associated with adverse infant development that might be partly irreversible. In sub-Saharan Africa, the etiology of ID in children is multifactoral; but the major causes are low iron dietary bioavailability and intake from monotonous cereal-based complementary foods. Children &lt; 5 years old can benefit from iron-fortified complementary foods; however, these fortified complementary foods are often not adapted to the requirements of children in specific setting. The investigators developed a complementary food fortificant (CFF) which is added to local porridge and is deemed to meet the nutrient intake requirement for iron in children 1-3 years of age. The CFF is lipid-based and can therefore, if regularly used, increase the daily energy intake of children which is often too low in developing countries with cereal-based diets. The iron absorption from the mixture of CFF and porridge has to be optimized because it contains quite a high amount of phytate, a well-known inhibitor of iron absorption. To optimize iron absorption the investigators are planning three iron absorption studies using different compounds of iron (FeSO4 + NaFeEDTA), additional vitamin C and phytase, which is able to degrade phytate. In the first study, iron absorption will be determined from a mixture of CFF and porridge fortified with 1) 6 mg FeSO4 and 2) 6 mg FeSO4 plus additional vitamin C. In the second study, the test meals will be fortified with 1) 6 mg FeSO4 and 2) a mixture of 3 mg FeSO4 + 3 mg NaFeEDTA. In the third study, test meals will be fortified with 1) 6 mg FeSO4, 2) 6 mg FeSO4 plus phytase, and 3) 6 mg FeSO4 plus additional vitamin C and phytase. Iron absorption will be determined by incorporation of labeled iron into erythrocytes, 14 days after the administration of a test meal containing labeled iron (stable isotope technique). Sixty apparently healthy Beninese children 12-36 months of age with a body weight &gt; 8.3 kg will be included in the study. Additionally, the investigators will test acceptability of CFFs based on different composition formulas by interviewing the parents/legal guardians of the children after feeding the CFF for a defined period. The results of these studies will provide important insights to optimize the iron absorption of young children from a CFF mixed with local traditional porridge in developing countries. Furthermore the studies will provide information on the acceptability of CFFs in such a setting.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Iron Absorption From Complementary Food Fortificants (CFFs) and Acceptability of CFFs by Beninese Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Iron-Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ascorbic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fe(III)-EDTA</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female or male children, 12 36 months of age A body weight of at least 8.3 kg; weight for age ≥ 3 Zscore No malaria parasites in the blood smear + negative malaria rapid test No hematuria No intake of mineral/vitamin supplements 2 weeks before and during the study No metabolic or gastrointestinal disorders Fever (body temperature &gt; 37.5 °C) Severe anemia (hemoglobin &lt; 8.0 g/dl) Regular intake of medication Blood transfusion or significant blood loss (accident, surgery) over the past 4 months Currently participating in another clinical trial or having participated in another clinical trial during the last 3 months prior to the beginning of this study Former participation in a study involving administration of iron stable isotopes Subject who cannot be expected to comply with study protocol Eating disorders or food allergy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>36 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Iron absorption</keyword>
	<keyword>Complementary food fortificant</keyword>
	<keyword>Young children</keyword>
</DOC>