<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00693862</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to show that higher minimum concentration values are obtained following repeated doses of Stalevo 4 times daily compared to lecodopa/carbidopa treatment with corresponding dosing regimen.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetic Study With Repeated Doses of Stalevo</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carbidopa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levodopa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Entacapone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent obtained Male or female patients with idiopathic Parkinson's disease with either a stable drug response or mild and predictable endofdose wearingoff symptoms. Hoehn and Yahr stage 12.5 performed during the "ON" state. Treatment with 35 daily doses of levodopa/DDCI ± entacapone with a total daily levodopa dose in the range of 300600 mg. Unchanged levodopa/DDCI ± entacapone and other antiparkinsonian medication (dopamine agonists, monoamine oxidase B (MAOB) inhibitor, amantadine and/or anticholinergics with doses recommended by the manufacturer), if any, for at least 2 weeks prior to the first treatment period. Age within 3072 years, inclusive. Secondary or atypical parkinsonism. Patients with moderate to marked wearingoff symptoms or any unpredictable "OFF"periods. Patients with treatmentrelated peakdose dyskinesia. Change in dose strength, daily dose or dosing frequency of any medicinal products used to treat other medical conditions than Parkinson's disease within 2 weeks. Use of any iron preparations or other chelating agents. Patients with a history of a laboratory abnormality consistent with, or clinically significant cardiovascular, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, hepatic, renal, neurological or psychiatric disorder or any other major concurrent illness, which may influence the outcome of the study. History of neuroleptic malignant syndrome (NMS) and/or nontraumatic rhabdomyolysis, malignant melanoma, narrowangle glaucoma or pheochromocytoma. Any abnormalities in laboratory values, vital signs or electrocardiogram (ECG) with clinical relevance. Patients using any antiparkinsonian drugs for rescue medication (including soluble levodopa formulations). Concomitant treatment with apomorphine, MAOA inhibitors or nonselective MAO inhibitors. Known hypersensitivity to active substances or to any of the excipients of the study drugs. Participation in other drug studies within 60 days prior to study entry Unsuitable veins for repeated venopuncture. Blood donation or loss of significant amount of blood within 60 days prior to the screening.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>72 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Focus of the study is pharmacokinetics of the study drug</keyword>
</DOC>