<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00548548</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will compare treatment with bevacizumab in combination with capecitabine and cisplatin versus placebo in combination with capecitabine and cisplatin, as first-line therapy in patients with locally advanced or metastatic gastric cancer who had not received prior chemotherapy for advanced or metastatic disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Bevacizumab in Combination With Capecitabine and Cisplatin as First-line Therapy in Patients With Advanced Gastric Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a 2 arm, randomized, double-blind, multicenter phase III study. Patients will be randomized (1:1) to capecitabine/cisplatin plus bevacizumab or capecitabine/cisplatin plus placebo. This is an event-driven trial with the primary analysis planned after approximately 517 deaths had been observed. After the primary analysis, the study will remain open and patients can continue with study treatment until progressive disease or earlier at the investigator's discretion. After discontinuation of the last patient, the study will end globally.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent obtained prior to any study specific procedures. Age ≥ 18 years. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0, 1, or 2. Life expectancy of at least 3 months. Able to comply with the protocol. Histologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the stomach or gastrooesophageal junction with inoperable, locally advanced, or metastatic disease, not amenable to curative therapy. Measurable disease or nonmeasurable but evaluable disease, according to the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumours (RECIST). Patient not receiving anticoagulant medication must have an International normalized ratio (INR) ≤ 1.5 and activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) ≤ 1.5 x Upper Limit of Normal (ULN) within 7 days prior to randomisation. Previous chemotherapy for locally advanced or metastatic gastric cancer. Patients may have received prior neoadjuvant or adjuvant chemotherapy as long as it was completed at least 6 months prior to randomisation. Previous platinum or antiangiogenic therapy (ie, antivascular endothelial growth factor [VEGF] or VEGF receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitor, etc.). Patients with locally advanced disease who are candidates for curative therapy (including operation and/or chemotherapy and/or radiotherapy). Radiotherapy within 28 days of randomisation. Major surgical procedure, open biopsy or significant traumatic injury within 28 days prior to randomisation, or anticipation of the need for major surgery during the course of the study treatment (planned elective surgery). Minor surgical procedures within 2 days prior to randomisation. Evidence of central nervous system (CNS) metastasis at baseline. History or evidence upon physical/neurological examination of CNS disease unrelated to cancer unless adequately treated with standard medical therapy, eg, uncontrolled seizures. History of another malignancy which could affect compliance with the protocol or interpretation of results. Inadequate bone marrow function. Inadequate liver function. Inadequate renal function. Uncontrolled hypertension or clinically significant (ie, active) cardiovascular disease. Active infection requiring intravenous antibiotics at randomisation. History or evidence of inherited bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy with the risk of bleeding. Serious or nonhealing wound, peptic ulcer, or (incompletely healed) bone fracture. Active gastrointestinal bleeding. History of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation, or intraabdominal abscess within 6 months of randomisation. Neuropathy (eg, impairment of hearing and balance) ≥ grade II according to Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v3.0. Chronic daily treatment with aspirin or clopidogrel. Chronic daily treatment with oral corticosteroids; inhaled steroids and short courses of oral steroids for antiemesis or as an appetite stimulant are allowed. Known hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs or excipients or to Chinese hamster ovary cell products or to other recombinant human or humanised antibodies. Known dihydropyrimidine dehydrogenase (DPD) deficiency. Evidence of any other disease, metabolic or psychological dysfunction, physical examination finding, or clinical laboratory finding giving reasonable suspicion of a disease or condition that contraindicates use of an investigational drug, or that may affect patient compliance with the study, or place the patient at high risk from treatment complications. Known acute or chronicactive infection with hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus (HCV). Pregnant or lactating females. Women of childbearing potential not using effective nonhormonal (intrauterine contraceptive device, barrier method of contraception in conjunction with spermicidal jelly, or surgically sterile) means of contraception. Sexually active men unwilling to practice contraception during the study. Current or recent (within the 28 days prior to randomisation) treatment with another investigational drug or participation in another investigational study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Avastin</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic Adenocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>AVAGAST</keyword>
</DOC>