<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="55874">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02378753</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CDC-NCIRD-6689</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02378753</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>STRIVE (Sierra Leone Trial to Introduce a Vaccine Against Ebola)</brief_title>
  <acronym>STRIVE</acronym>
  <official_title>[rVSVΔG-ZEBOV] Ebola Prevention Vaccine Evaluation in Sierra Leone</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Sierra Leone</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ministry of Health and Sanitation, Sierra Leone</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Department of Health and Human Services</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>eHealth Africa</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The 2014 outbreak of Ebola in West Africa is the largest in recorded history with widespread
      and intense transmission in Guinea, Liberia, and Sierra Leone. The high infectivity of blood
      and secretions, lack of appropriate personal protective equipment (PPE) and challenges in
      following infection control and prevention protocols put healthcare workers at high risk
      during outbreaks, and direct contact with the bodies of deceased Ebola victims can also
      sustain community transmission. This study will accelerate introduction and use of
      monovalent recombinant vesicular stomatitis virus Ebola vaccine (rVSVΔG-ZEBOV) among
      healthcare workers and frontline personnel involved in the Ebola outbreak response in Sierra
      Leone, while concurrently evaluating the safety and efficacy of the vaccine.

      This is an unblinded, randomized trial with phased vaccine introduction in the target
      population. Participation in the study will be voluntary and open to adults 18 years of age
      and older who are at high risk of exposure to Ebola infection through their daily work and
      who work in a selected study area.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Ebola outbreak was confirmed in March 2014 with widespread and intense transmission in
      Guinea, Liberia, and Sierra Leone. While there are no U.S. Food and Drug Administration
      (FDA)-approved pharmaceuticals to prevent or treat Ebola, two candidate vaccines are being
      tested in humans for dosing, tolerability, and safety. This study will evaluate monovalent
      recombinant vesicular stomatitis virus Ebola vaccine that remains replication competent
      (rVSVΔG-ZEBOV) in Sierra Leone.

      The high infectivity of blood and secretions, lack of appropriate personal protective
      equipment (PPE) and challenges in following infection control and prevention protocols put
      healthcare workers at high risk during outbreaks, and direct contact with the bodies of
      deceased Ebola victims can also sustain community transmission.

      This unblinded, randomized trial will evaluate vaccine efficacy (VE) and safety with phased
      vaccine introduction in the target population. Participation in the study will be voluntary
      and open to adults 18 years of age and older who are at high risk of exposure to Ebola
      infection through their daily work and who work in a selected study area. This includes: 1)
      personnel working in healthcare facilities where care is provided for Ebola patients; 2)
      personnel working in non-Ebola healthcare facilities who may have exposure to undiagnosed
      Ebola-infected individuals; and 3) personnel working in one of the following job categories:
      surveillance team, ambulance team, or laboratory worker responsible for swabbing deceased
      persons. Staff members involved in this study are also eligible to receive the vaccine under
      this protocol; study staff will be followed for 6 months post-vaccination to monitor for
      safety of rVSVΔG-ZEBOV.

      Eligible participants within a healthcare facility or frontline team will be enrolled and
      individually randomized to either immediate or deferred vaccination. A single dose of
      rVSVΔG-ZEBOV will be administered intramuscularly. Immediate vaccination is defined as
      vaccination within 7 days of enrollment and deferred vaccination is defined as vaccination
      at the end of an 18-24 week follow-up period. Participants will not be blinded to the
      randomized assignment of immediate or deferred vaccination. All enrolled participants will
      have the opportunity to receive rVSVΔG-ZEBOV by the end of the study. Enrollment and
      vaccination will be phased over time.

      Ebola events that occur during the 18-24 week post-enrollment will be included in the VE
      analysis, with the immediate vaccination arm contributing vaccinated follow-up time and the
      deferred vaccination arm contributing unvaccinated follow-up time. All participants,
      regardless of randomized assignment, will be followed for 6 months after vaccination to
      monitor for safety of rVSVΔG-ZEBOV.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 5, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 8, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>No masking</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Laboratory-confirmed Ebola (study diagnostics)</measure>
    <time_frame>&gt; 21 days following vaccination</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of Serious Adverse Events during the 6 months following the vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months following vaccination</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Death due to laboratory-confirmed Ebola</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months following vaccination</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ebola confirmed by non-study or study diagnostics</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months following vaccination</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Suspected, probable or laboratory-confirmed Ebola</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months following vaccination</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of solicited injection-site and systemic reactogenicity signs and symptoms, including fever, on vaccination day and during the 7 days following the vaccination.</measure>
    <time_frame>Vaccination day and for 7 days following vaccination</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of solicited and unsolicited AEs during the 28 days following the vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>During 28 days following vaccination</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">8651</enrollment>
  <condition>Hemorrhagic Fever, Ebola</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>rVSVΔG-ZEBOV (immediate vaccination)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>One intramuscular (deltoid) injection of rVSVΔG-ZEBOV (2 x 10^7 plaque forming units)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>rVSVΔG-ZEBOV (deferred vaccination)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>One intramuscular (deltoid) injection of rVSVΔG-ZEBOV (2 x 10^7 plaque forming units) in participants randomized to receive deferred vaccination (18-24 weeks after enrollment).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>rVSVΔG-ZEBOV</intervention_name>
    <description>The rVSVΔG-ZEBOV vaccine is comprised of a single recombinant VSV isolate (11481 nontypeable) modified to replace the gene encoding the G envelope GP with the gene encoding the envelope GP from ZEBOV (Kikwit, 1995 strain).</description>
    <arm_group_label>rVSVΔG-ZEBOV (immediate vaccination)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>rVSVΔG-ZEBOV (deferred vaccination)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BPSC-1001</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Age 18 years or older.

          2. Member of target population at the time of enrollment:

               -  active worker in an Ebola care, holding, or treatment center (may include
                  physicians, nurses, nurse aides, lab technicians, pharmacists, pharmacy
                  technicians, cleaners, and security and administrative staff);

               -  active worker in a facility providing non-Ebola-related healthcare (may include
                  physicians, nurses, nurse aides, lab technicians, pharmacists, pharmacy
                  technicians, cleaners, and security and administrative staff);

               -  active frontline worker in one of the following job categories: surveillance
                  team, ambulance team, burial worker, or worker responsible for swabbing deceased
                  persons.

          3. Reasonably anticipates living in Sierra Leone for the 18-24 weeks following
             enrollment.

          4. Reachable by phone throughout the 6 month post-vaccination safety follow-up period.

          5. Willing to adhere to personal protective equipment (PPE) and infection control
             recommendations.

          6. Able and willing to complete the informed consent process and study procedures.

          7. Willing to receive vaccine in either the immediate or the deferred trial arms,
             according to random assignment.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. History of Ebola (self-report).

          2. Prior receipt of experimental Ebola or Marburg vaccine.

          3. History of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or clinically important
             immunodeficiency (self-report).

          4. Any history of allergy or anaphylaxis to prior vaccines

          5. Breast-feeding an infant or child.

          6. Any reason the investigator suspects that data collected from this person would be
             incomplete or of poor quality.

          7. Current pregnancy (a negative urine pregnancy test is required for women participants
             &lt;50 years of age who self-report as not pregnant).

          8. Currently being followed for known exposure to Ebola.

          9. Known experimental research agents or other vaccine within 28 days (4 weeks) before
             vaccination.

         10. Fever ≥ 38.0°C (100.4°F) at time of vaccination.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mohamed Samai, MBChB,PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Sierra Leone</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>College of Medicine and Allied Health Sciences (COMAHS)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Freetown</city>
        <state>Western Area Urban</state>
        <country>Sierra Leone</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bombali</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bombali District</city>
        <country>Sierra Leone</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Port Loko</name>
      <address>
        <city>Port Loko District</city>
        <country>Sierra Leone</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tonkolili</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tonkolili District</city>
        <country>Sierra Leone</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Western Area Rural</name>
      <address>
        <city>Western Area District</city>
        <country>Sierra Leone</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sierra Leone</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 5, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 19, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ebola</keyword>
  <keyword>Sierra Leone</keyword>
  <keyword>vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>rVSVΔG-ZEBOV</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhagic Fever, Ebola</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhagic Fevers, Viral</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
