<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00383565</DOC>
	<brief_summary>FR901228 may stop the growth of cancer cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell to grow and by blocking blood flow to the cancer. This phase II trial is studying how well FR901228 works in treating patients with relapsed or refractory non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>FR901228 in Treating Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the response rate (complete and partial) to FR901228 in patients with relapsed or refractory mantle cell or diffuse large cell non-Hodgkin's lymphoma. II. Evaluate the safety and feasibility of FR901228, in terms of the incidence of toxicity and maximum grade observed and courses delayed or dose reductions, in these patients. III. Determine 2-year progression-free and overall survival. OUTLINE: Patients receive FR901228 IV over 4 hours on days 1, 8, and 15. Treatment repeats every 28 days for at least 6 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 3-6 months for up to 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Mantle-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Romidepsin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Histone Deacetylase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed aggressive Bcell nonHodgkin's lymphoma of 1 of the following subtypes: Mantle cell lymphoma Diffuse large cell lymphoma (Ineligible for or unwilling to undergo stem cell transplantation) Relapsed or refractory disease: Any number of prior therapies allowed for relapsed disease, including peripheral blood stem cell or bone marrow transplantation No more than 2 prior regimens, excluding monotherapy with monoclonal antibody or radiotherapy, for refractory disease Measurable disease, defined as &gt;= 1 lesion &gt;= 1.5 cm in the longest diameter No transformed lymphoma, defined as the transformation of a lowgrade lymphoma, including follicular lymphoma or small lymphocytic lymphoma, to a highgrade lymphoma (e.g., diffuse large cell lymphoma) ECOG performance status 02 Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,000/mm^3 OR &gt;= 500/mm^3 if extensive bone marrow involvement (&gt; 50%) or hypersplenism with palpable splenomegaly Platelet count &gt;= 75,000/mm^3 OR &gt;= 50,000/mm^3 if extensive bone marrow involvement (&gt; 50%) or hypersplenism with palpable splenomegaly Bilirubin normal Alkaline phosphatase =&lt; 2 times upper limit of normal (ULN) AST =&lt; 2 times ULN Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception No significant cardiac disease, including New York Heart Association class IIIIV congestive heart failure No history of serious ventricular arrhythmia QTc &lt; 500 msec No evidence of cardiac hypertrophy on ECG No known HIV positivity No other uncontrolled serious medical condition or active infection (e.g., chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, diabetes) Recovered from prior therapy No prior doxorubicin hydrochloride &gt;= 450 mg/m^2 or mitoxantrone &gt;= 112 mg/m^2 (Patients who received both mitoxantrone and doxorubicin hydrochloride should have a "doxorubicin equivalent dose" &lt; 450 mg/m^2 No prior therapy with a histone deacetylase inhibitor No concurrent dexamethasone or prednisone except for refractory nausea/vomiting No concurrent drugs associated with QTc prolongation (e.g., dolasetron mesylate) Concurrent hydrochlorothiazide, furosemide, or other diuretics allowed provided patient is receiving potassium chloride supplementation (No supplementation needed if switched to a potassiumconserving diuretic) No CNS lymphoma Creatinine normal Cardiac function &gt;= 50% by MUGA</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>