<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01314521</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to examine clinical characteristics of Korean adolescents with depression who have suicidal ideation and behavior. We formulate those hypotheses. 1. Being bullied in peer relationships, excessive use of internet, excessive extra-curricular tutoring, sexual abuse in childhood, physical abuse and emotional neglect are risk factors of suicide in adolescents. 2. Depression of parents and negative child-rearing attitude are risk factors of suicidal ideation and behavior in adolescents. 3. Emotional quotient (EQ) and resilience of adolescent are protective factors of suicide.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Suicidal Ideation and Behavior in Korean Adolescents With Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Korea has reported the highest suicide rate among OECD members and according to the data from the Korea national statistical office, suicide is the second major cause of death in adolescents and is increasing. Depression, one of the well-known risk factors of suicide in adolescents, can cause maladjustments to school and family life, problems of interpersonal relationship and drug abuse so that work to trigger the suicidal ideation and behavior. In his study, we planned to examine the relationship between suicidal ideation and behavior and several risk factors by using the standardized diagnostic clinical interview, especially an objective suicide evaluating method which has recently developed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Suicidal Ideation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>a subject who has depression (Major depressive disorder, dysthymic disorder, depressive disorder NOS) diagnosed by KiddieSchedule for affective disorder and schizophrenia (KSADSPLK) subjects and their family (a parent or a grandparent) or their legal representative consent to participate in this study voluntarily subjects and their family (a parent or a grandparent) or their legal representative are able to understand the meaning of participation in this study and able to reject or ask to leave from this study a patient who has diagnosed with bipolar disorder, psychotic disorder, pervasive developmental disorder, organic brain disease, or epilepsy a patient with mental retardation who is IQ under 70 a patient who has a severe medical illness (chronic physical disease, cardiovascular, hepatobiliary, nephrology, or respiratory disease and so on)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Suicide</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Adolescents</keyword>
</DOC>