<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01875393</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to confirm the Efficacy,the Safety and the Quality of Life after TOOKAD® Soluble VTP in localized prostate cancer patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy,Safety and Quality of Life After TOOKAD® Soluble VTP for Localized Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is designed as a multicenter, single-arm, open label, 12 months follow-up clinical trial. Men with localized prostate cancer will be treated with TOOKAD® Soluble VTP under general anesthesia. Patients will be followed-up for 12 months with patient questionnaires on QoL, erectile and urinary functions, clinical evaluation with study visits at 1, 3, 6 and 12 months , Prostate Specific Antigen(PSA) testing at 3, 6 and 12 months. In addition, they will have biopsy at 6 months (± 2) and 12 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically proven localized prostate carcinoma diagnosed using prostate biopsy showing: Gleason 3+3 prostate Gleason 3+4 prostate adenocarcinoma is acceptable provided it is not present in more than 2 cores and no more than 50% cancer in any core. Clinical stage up to cT2a N0/Nx M0/Mx. Serum prostatespecific antigen (PSA) ˂ 20ng/ml Prostate volume ≥ 25 cc and ≤ 70 cc. Male subjects aged 18 years or older. Signed Informed Consent Form by the patient. Unwillingness to accept the treatment. Any prior or current treatment for prostate cancer, including surgery, radiation therapy (external or brachytherapy)or chemotherapy. Any surgical intervention for benign prostatic hypertrophy. Any condition or history of illness or surgery that may pose an additional risk to men undergoing the VTP procedure. Life expectancy less than 10 years. Participation in another clinical study involving an investigational product within 1 month before study entry. Subject unable to understand the patient's informed consent document, to give consent voluntarily or to complete the study tasks, especially unable to understand and fulfill the healthrelated QoL questionnaire. Subject in custody and or in residence in a nursing home or rehabilitation facility. Any condition or history of active rectal inflammatory bowel disease or other factors which may increase the risk of fistula formation; Any hormonal manipulation (excluding 5alphareductase inhibitors) that alters androgen production or use of androgen supplements within the previous 6 months; Any history of urethral stricture disease; Any history of acute urinary retention within 6 months of study entry</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prostatic Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Genital Neoplasm,male</keyword>
	<keyword>Urogenital neoplasm</keyword>
	<keyword>Genital disease,male</keyword>
	<keyword>Male urogenital disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Neoplasms by site</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostatic neoplasm</keyword>
	<keyword>Carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>