<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01525485</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This prospective study compares quality of life measures of patients with refractory overactive bladder, between two modes of neuromodulation: vaginal electrical stimulation (Group A) and sacral nerve stimulation (Group B). The specific aims are: 1. To characterize patient symptom bother score, quality of life, and body image scores in patients obtaining sacral nerve stimulation, as compared to vaginal electrical stimulation. - Hypothesis 1: Both modes of neuromodulation will impact patients' scores in quality of life, patient symptoms, and body image questionnaires.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vaginal Electrical Stimulation Versus Neuromodulation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All participants will have a standardized intake history which will include age, weight, history of prior treatment for incontinence, medication list, obstetric and gynecologic history, medical history, and surgical history, as well as a complete review of systems. The physical examination will include vital signs (including BMI), genitourinary exam, including Pelvic Organ Prolapse Quantification (POPQ), and neurologic exam. All patients will undergo spontaneous uroflowmetry, urine dipstick from catheterized specimen, multichannel urodynamics, and 3-day voiding diary. Measurement of post-void residual will also be obtained. Completion of the UDI-69, King's Health Questionnaire10, and the Modified Body Image Perception Scale (MBIS) will also be part of the initial visit 11,12. All participants taking anticholinergics will undergo a 2 week flush-out period prior to the intake assessment. After the intake assessment, the provider will determine which treatment option is appropriate to the participant, and they will then be assigned to one of the two treatment arms: Group A will use vaginal electrical stimulation using the Empi Intravaginal Stimulation Unit Minnova (Empi, St. Paul, MN, USA) and participants in Group B will receive sacral neuromodulation using InterStim (Medtronic, Minneapolis, MN, USA).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Overactive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of refractory OAB (+/ UUI)* Female Gender Eligible for both treatment interventions Available for 8 weeks of followup Able to complete study assessments Must discontinue anticholinergics within 2 weeks of intervention Age &lt; 21 Pregnancy Stage 3 or 4 pelvic organ prolapse Current use of anticholinergics Urinary tract infection Undergoing concurrent treatment for pelvic organ prolapse Unstable or serious cardiac arrhythmia Implanted pacemaker Postvoid residual &gt; 100ml Unstable seizure disorder Dementia or inability to follow instructions</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>