<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00546351</DOC>
	<brief_summary>SP746 (NCT00546351) is a multi-center, open-label, follow-on trial. The purpose of this trial is to assess safety and tolerability of long-term exposure of lacosamide (previously referred to as SPM 927) in subjects with painful distal diabetic neuropathy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Evaluating Long-term Safety and Efficacy of Lacosamide in Subjects With Painful Distal Diabetic Neuropathy.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Neuropathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lacosamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who completed Study SP743 (NCT00238524) or SP874 (NCT00350103) and, in the investigator's opinion, might benefit from longterm administration of SP746 (NCT00546351). Exception: subjects who prematurely discontinued SP743 (NCT00238524) or SP874 (NCT00350103) due to lack of efficacy or due to intolerability to trial medication (after Visit 5but prior to entering the Maintenance Phase) may be eligible to participate in SP746 (NCT00546351), after consultation with the medical monitor Subject has clinically relevant ECG abnormalities, or a QTc interval ≥500 ms, and/or a QTc interval increase of ≥60 ms from the mean predose QTc value at Visit 2 of SP743 (NCT00238524) or SP874 (NCT00350103) Subject has aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and/or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≥3 times the upper limit of the normal range (ULN) with total bilirubin ≥2 times ULN or transaminases (AST and/or ALT) ≥5 times ULN Subject has a clinically relevant medical condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, jeopardizes or compromises the subject's ability to participate in this trial Subject is a pregnant or nursing female, or is of childbearing potential and is not surgically sterile, 2 years postmenopausal, or does not practice 2 combined methods of contraception</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lacosamide</keyword>
</DOC>