<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00546780</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase 3, open label trial for patients with multiple myeloma in first relapse. Trial will compare tanespimycin (KOS-953), in combination with a fixed dose of bortezomib versus bortezomib alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Tanespimycin (KOS-953) in Patients With Multiple Myeloma in First Relapse</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Phase 3 combination study comparing tanespimycin (KOS-953) plus bortezomib to bortezomib alone in patients with multiple myeloma in first relapse after failure of previous anti-cancer therapy and/or bone marrow transplantation. Primary objective is to compare the progression-free survival (PFS) associated with the use of tanespimycin (KOS-953) in combination with bortezomib versus that associated with administration of bortezomib alone.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Good Performance Status Documented evidence of multiple myeloma Documented progression of disease after initial response to one line of therapy Measurable disease (serum Mprotein &gt;.5g/dl or &gt; 200 mg urinary M protein excretion) Prior treatment with a heat shock 90 inhibitor or an investigational proteasome inhibitor Known active infections of HAV, HBV, HCV, or HIV Administration of chemotherapy, radiation therapy, or immune therapy within 21 days prior to randomization. Acute diffuse infiltrate pulmonary disease or pericardial dise</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Heat Shock Protein 90</keyword>
	<keyword>Hsp90</keyword>
	<keyword>KOS-953</keyword>
	<keyword>17-AAG</keyword>
	<keyword>bortezomib</keyword>
	<keyword>first relapse</keyword>
	<keyword>tanespimycin</keyword>
	<keyword>TIME-1</keyword>
</DOC>