<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02703558</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a prospective randomized controlled study. Female patients over 18 years of age, who present for treatment of pelvic organ prolapse and/or stress urinary incontinence at the Pelvic Floor Center at the Johns Hopkins Bayview Medical Center, and who consent to undergo a urogynecologic surgical procedure, will be considered for inclusion in the study. Their histories will be reviewed by their attending surgeon and if they meet inclusion and exclusion criteria, they will be recruited for participation. The primary investigator and co-investigators (attending physician, fellows) will determine patient eligibility. Regarding privacy issues, the patients will be consented for both the procedure and for the study with careful attention made to emphasize patient confidentiality. When the patient presents for surgery, they will be randomized to receive either preoperative pyridium or intraoperative fluorescein or no dye. Given the color differences between the dyes, blinding will not occur. The process for recruitment will be consistent and any deviations from the protocol will be reported to the Johns Hopkins Internal Review Board.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Fluorescein Use During Cystoscopy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>• English speaking, female patients, ages 18 and older, undergoing urogynecologic surgery for pelvic organ prolapse or urinary incontinence with a planned concomitant cystoscopy at Johns Hopkins Bayview NonEnglish speaking, Known allergic reactions or sensitivities to sodium fluorescein or phenazopyridine Known glucose6phosphate dehydrogenase or nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide methemoglobin reductase deficiency Pregnant or breastfeeding Known renal disease or renal failure Undergoing concomitant nonurogynecologic procedures Dementia or cognitive impairment</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>