<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00815178</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine if inspiratory muscle training improves inspiratory muscle strength of type 2 diabetes mellitus patients with inspiratory muscle weakness.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Inspiratory Muscle Training on Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus Patients With Inspiratory Muscle Weakness</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In congestive heart failure patients, inspiratory muscle weakness can be reversed by developing diaphragmatic hypertrophy through inspiratory muscle training, improving functional capacity and quality of life. In type 2 diabetes mellitus patients the frequency of inspiratory muscle weakness is unknown, as well as the response to inspiratory muscle training. For this reason, the present study evaluated the inspiratory muscle strength in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients and the effect of inspiratory muscle training on inspiratory muscle strength, pulmonary function, functional capacity and autonomic modulation assessed through heart rate variability.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Aspiration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Complications</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Muscle Weakness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paresis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>diabetes melittus sedentary inspiratory muscle weakness with PImax &lt; 70% of the predicted mass index &gt; 33 kg/m2 exerciseinduced asthma history infectious disease osteoarticular disease regular alcohol or tobacco consumption in the past 6 months cardiac disease pulmonary disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>inspiratory muscle weakness</keyword>
	<keyword>autonomic modulation</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>heart rate variability</keyword>
	<keyword>functional capacity</keyword>
</DOC>