<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="67410">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02228278</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB201400433</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02228278</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Healthcare Text Messaging to Improve Diet, Physical Activity and Weight Loss in a Pediatric Lipid Clinic</brief_title>
  <acronym>Text4Fit</acronym>
  <official_title>Text 4 Fit Project: Healthcare Text Messaging as an Adjunct to Routine Care for Overweight and Obese Adolescents Enrolled in a Pediatric Lipid Clinic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Florida</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Florida</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine if health-related text messages sent from
      healthcare providers to overweight and obese adolescents enrolled at a pediatric lipid
      clinic will result in increased adherence to their nutrition and physical activity goals and
      improve their weight loss. The study will also assess if the volume of texts per week
      impacts outcomes. This will be a small scale pilot study, with plans for a future larger
      scale study to assess for statistically significant effects.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      We will recruit 5 participants the from the UF Pediatric Lipid and Obesity clinic for
      pre-intervention cognitive interviewing to assess acceptability of the intervention and
      request their input on a representative sample of text messages. Then, 20 participants will
      be recruited from the same clinic for the intervention (10 controls, 10 intervention
      participants). Controls will receive current standard care - clinic visits every three
      months anthropometric assessments and counseling on physical activity and nutrition goals by
      a healthcare provider, typically with no patient-provider communication between visits. The
      intervention group will receive the typical clinic visits plus daily text messages in
      between visits with fitness and nutrition messages to support their health goals. All
      participants will have anthropometric measurements at baseline, 3 and 6 months. Each
      participant will complete a Schwartz Diet and Activity History at 0, 3 and 6 month visits,
      and a post intervention survey will be completed at the 3 month time point.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility and Acceptability of text message intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in baseline and 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>This will involve a pre-study interview with a small group of subjects to assess for their opinions on the text messages and study concept. Following this, we will perform a small scale trial of the program, involving 20 participants with 10 subjects in the intervention group and 10 controls. The number of participants will most likely not be adequate to reach statistical significance in detecting differences in healthy food choices, physical activity and BMI z-score between control and experimental groups. However, this study will help guide us in establishing if this healthcare texting system functions well. In addition, it may help determine if there are any trends in improvement of the target variables that would support the need for a future, larger study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes from baseline proportion of healthy food choices versus unhealthy choices</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in baseline, 3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>We aim to have our adolescent subjects fill out a Schwartz Diet and Activity History at time points 0, 3 and 6 months. We will assess their baseline food choices and then assess for changes in food habits over time, with a prediction that this text message communication will help to decrease the &quot;negative&quot; food choices (sugars/syrups, non whole grain starches, processed foods, sugar sweetened beverages) and increase the &quot;positive&quot; food (fruits/vegetables, low fat dairy, water) choices by 10% (based on screener scores pre and post intervention).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes from baseline time spent doing physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in baseline, 3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>We aim to have our adolescent subjects complete a Schwartz Diet and Activity History at time points 0, 3 and 6 months. We will assess their baseline physical activity and then assess for changes in physical activity over time, with a prediction that this text message communication will help to decrease their sedentary time (and TV time) and increase their physical activity by 10% (based on screener scores pre and post intervention).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes from baseline BMI Z-score</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in baseline, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Subjects will have assessments of height, weight, age and sex at 0, 3 and 6 month clinic visits. Researchers will assess for any changes in BMI Z-score across time points.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Pediatric Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Text Message</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Text message arm will receive daily texts for 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Controls will receive current standard care - clinic visits every three months with anthropometric assessments and counseling on physical activity and nutrition goals by a healthcare provider, typically with no patient-provider communication between visits.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Text message</intervention_name>
    <description>Text message arm will receive daily texts for 12 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Text Message</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control Group</intervention_name>
    <description>Controls will receive current standard care - clinic visits every three months with anthropometric assessments and counseling on physical activity and nutrition goals by a healthcare provider, typically with no patient-provider communication between visits.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Adolescents age 13-17

          -  Overweight or obese (BMI &gt; 85th percentile)

          -  Attend or will start attending UF Pediatric Lipid Clinic during the study period

          -  Own a cell phone that can receive text messages

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Current diagnosis of a psychiatric eating disorder (anorexia nervosa or bulimia)

          -  Pregnancy

          -  Medical disease that would contraindicate moderate physical activity, as determined
             by clinician (MD or NP) from the Lipid Clinic
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lindsay Thompson, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Florida Health Shands Children's Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kristin A Dayton, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of Florida Shands Children's Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Florida Gerold L Schiebler Children's Medical Services Center, Pediatric Lipid and Obesity Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32608</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Florida Shands Medical Plaza, Pediatric Lipid and Obesity Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32608</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 12, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 25, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pediatric</keyword>
  <keyword>Obesity</keyword>
  <keyword>Overweight</keyword>
  <keyword>Texting</keyword>
  <keyword>Text message</keyword>
  <keyword>SMS</keyword>
  <keyword>Diet</keyword>
  <keyword>Weight Loss</keyword>
  <keyword>Nutrition</keyword>
  <keyword>Physical activity</keyword>
  <keyword>BMI z-score</keyword>
  <keyword>BMI</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
