<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02387957</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the safety of intravitreal (IVT) Fovista® administered in combination with anti-VEGF therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An 18 Month Phase 2a Open Label, Randomized Study of Avastin®, Lucentis®, or Eylea® (Anti-VEGF Therapy) Administered in Combination With Fovista® (Anti-PDGF BB Pegylated Aptamer)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>60 subjects randomized 1:1:1 and treated with IVT Fovista® 1.5 mg/eye in combination with anti-VEGF therapy as follows: - Avastin® 1.25 mg/eye (20 subjects) - Lucentis® 0.5 mg/eye (20 subjects) - Eylea® 2.0 mg/eye (20 subjects) Subjects will be stratified by lesion size (≤2 DA vs. &gt;2 DA). Subjects will be treated with "combination therapy" of IVT Fovista® and IVT anti-VEGF therapy every month for the first 5 months (Day 1, Months 1,2,3,4), followed by Q12W (every 12 weeks) administration (Months 7,10, 13, and 16), for a total of 18 months. When administered, IVT Fovista® will be given first, followed by IVT anti-VEGF (same day).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects of either gender aged ≥ 50 years. Active subfoveal choroidal neovascularization (CNV) due to AMD. Any intraocular surgery or thermal laser within three (3) months of trial entry. Any prior thermal laser in the macular region, regardless of indication. Subjects with subfoveal scar or subfoveal atrophy Any ocular or periocular infection in the past twelve (12) weeks. History of any of the following conditions or procedures in the study eye: Rhegmatogenous retinal detachment, pars plana vitrectomy, filtering surgery (e.g. trabeculectomy), glaucoma drainage device, corneal transplant.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Wet AMD</keyword>
	<keyword>subfoveal choroidal neovascularization</keyword>
	<keyword>Fovista®</keyword>
	<keyword>Avastin®</keyword>
	<keyword>Lucentis®</keyword>
	<keyword>Eylea®</keyword>
</DOC>