<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00412061</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to evaluate whether everolimus 10 mg / day added to treatment with depot octreotide prolongs progression free survival compared to treatment with octreotide alone in patients with advanced carcinoid tumor.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Everolimus and Octreotide in Patients With Advanced Carcinoid Tumor</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoid Tumor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuroendocrine Tumors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malignant Carcinoid Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Serotonin Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Octreotide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Advanced (unresectable or metastatic) carcinoid tumor Confirmed lowgrade or intermediategrade neuroendocrine carcinoma Documented progression of disease within 12 months prior to randomization. Measurable disease determined by triphasic computer tomography (CT) scan or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). Exclusion criteria: Poorly differentiated neuroendocrine carcinoma, highgrade neuroendocrine carcinoma, adenocarcinoid, goblet cell carcinoma, or small cell carcinoma. Hepatic artery embolization within the last 6 months or cryoablation of hepatic metastasis within 2 months of enrollment. Previous treatment with mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) inhibitors (sirolimus, temsirolimus, everolimus) Intolerance or hypersensitivity to octreotide, everolimus, or other rapamycins. Severe or uncontrolled medical conditions Chronic treatment with corticosteroids or other immunosuppressive agent. Other primary cancer within 3 years. Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria applied</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Carcinoid</keyword>
	<keyword>Tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuroendocrine</keyword>
	<keyword>Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Everolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>Octreotide</keyword>
</DOC>