<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02376686</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether music hearing in the evening before going to sleep can improve sleep quality, depressive symptoms and quality of life in patients with affective disorders.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Music Intervention in the Treatment of Sleep Disorders for Depressed Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Disrupted sleep including Problems of initiating and maintaining sleep are most often symptoms in patients with depressive Syndromes and often persist after successful treatment of affective symptoms. Normally disrupted sleep in the context of affective disorder is treated with sleep medication, which can lead to severe and sometimes intolerable side effects. A non-pharmacological approach for improving sleep Quality is Hearing Music before going to sleep. Classical indian Music can improve sleep Quality in depressed patients. In a danish study protocol Western Music improved sleep quality in patients with disturbed sleep and posttraumatic stress disorder. The investigators want to use western Music to improve sleep . In a three week Intervention time, patients shall hear before going to sleep every night for one hour relaxing Music. The control group receives Treatment as usual. After the end of Intervention, every participant has the possibility to use the sleep inducing Music. The aim of the study is to prove whether Hearing Music before going to sleep over three weeks improves subjective sleep quality, self rated depressive symptoms and Quality of life and objective Parameters such as sleep duration and sleep latency, measured by actigraphy. In a follow-up interview four weeks after the Intervention the investigators want to prove if the effects continue after end of Intervention.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<criteria>inpatient and outpatient treatment in Sanatorium Kilchberg one of the following diagnoses according to ICD 10: F32, F33, F34.1, F34.21, F34.8, Age between 18 and 65 years completed Primary education Level good command of the german language able to understand Patient information, given informed consent, no informed consent one or more of the following diagnoses according to ICD 10: F32.3, F33.2, F31.3, F31.4, F60.31, F10, F13, F00, F01, F02, F03, G47.3, G25.8, H90, H91 patients with acute suicidal tendency pregnant or breastfeeding women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>sleep Quality</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Music</keyword>
	<keyword>quality of life</keyword>
</DOC>