<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01072617</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim of this protocol is to determine whether the use of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) over vermis of the cerebellum may be safe and therapeutically effective in patients with schizophrenia. Because this is the first evaluation of this treatment in this population, the focus of this study is safety.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cerebellar rTMS for the Treatment of Schizophrenic Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age between 1865 years 2. Diagnosis of schizophrenia according to DSMIV criteria(by a boardcertified psychiatrist) 1. Prior neurosurgical procedures 2. Any history of seizure 3. Previous head injury 4. Contraindication to TMS: 1. Implanted pacemaker 2. Medication pump 3. Vagal stimulator 4. Deep brain stimulator 5. Metallic hardware in the head or scalp: shrapnel, surgical clips, or fragments from welding 6. Signs of increased intracranial pressure 5. TENS unit and ventriculoperitoneal shunt 6. Pregnancy or lactating; note that a negative pregnancy test will be required if the patient is a female in reproductive years 7. Advanced liver, kidney, cardiac, or pulmonary disease as defined clinically or a terminal medical diagnosis consistent with survival &lt; 1 year 8. A history of significant alcohol or drug abuse in the prior six months 9. No focal cortical insult can be present, including tumor or vascular malformation 10. Patients may not be actively enrolled in a separate intervention study 11. Patients unable to undergo a brain MR: a. claustrophobia refractory to anxiolytics ferromagnetic metal in the body such as a prosthetic heart valve, a pacemaker, or a brain aneurysm clip). 12. Change in antipsychotic medication during the last 4 weeks 13. Any emergency psychiatry department visit during the last 4 weeks 14. Been an inpatient in a psychiatry clinic within the last month 15. Any other axis I diagnosis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>