<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01072890</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test the safety of temsirolimus and pazopanib at different doses. Patients who have an advanced cancer that is not felt to benefit from standard treatment or are no longer responding to other treatment will be asked to take part in this study. The study hypothesis is that temsirolimus and pazopanib can be administered safely in combination and that combined targeting of the mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) and vascular endothelial growth factor receptor (VEGFR) signaling pathways will be effective in treating patients with advanced solid tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Temsirolimus and Pazopanib in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Despite encouraging clinical activity reported with single-agent VEGF inhibitors, mTOR inhibitors, and other novel agents, patients rarely achieve complete disease response and ultimately undergo disease progression. The limited efficacy of single-target inhibition may be due to numerous, overlapping signaling pathways involved in Renal Cell Carcinoma proliferation and growth. A strategy of multi-target "vertical inhibition" of the overlapping aberrant VEGF and mTOR pathways by combination therapy may translate to enhanced efficacy over each single agent alone. We hypothesize that temsirolimus and pazopanib can be administered safely in combination and that combined targeting of the mTOR and VEGFR signaling pathways will be effective in treating patients with advanced solid tumors.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must have histologically or cytologically confirmed metastatic or unresectable solid tumor for which standard curative or palliative measures do not exist or are no longer effective. Age ≥ 18 years old Zubrod (ECOG) Performance Status 0 2 May have measurable or nonmeasurable disease. Adequate bone marrow and organ function as assessed by the following within 14 days prior to registration. Any number of prior chemotherapy regimens is allowed. Any prior chemotherapy, immunotherapy or targeted therapy must have been completed at least 2 weeks prior to start of this protocol and all side effects (except alopecia, lymphopenia and hyperglycemia) resolved to grade 1 or less. Any prior radiation must have been completed at least 2 weeks prior to start of therapy. Pregnant or nursing women are ineligible because of the risk to the fetus. Women of childbearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception prior to study entry and for the duration of study participation. Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while participating in this study, she should inform her treating physician immediately. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent. Ability to swallow and retain oral medications. Prior treatment with an mTOR inhibitor or pazopanib. Cardiac disease: Congestive heart failure &gt; class II NYHA. Patients must not have unstable angina (anginal symptoms at rest) or new onset angina (began within the last 3 months) or myocardial infarction within the past 6 months. Symptomatic or uncontrolled brain metastasis. Must have a EKG within 14 days of registration and a QTc of &lt; 480 msec. If the initial QTc is &gt; 480 msec, two subsequent EKGs should be obtained within 5 minutes. Uncontrolled hypertension defined as systolic blood pressure &gt; 150 mmHg or diastolic pressure &gt; 90 mmHg, despite optimal medical management. Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection or chronic Hepatitis B or C due to the immunosuppressive effects of temsirolimus. Active clinically serious infection &gt; CTCAE Grade 2. Fasting cholesterol &gt; 350mg/dL and fasting triglycerides &gt; 400mg/dL Thrombolic or embolic events such as a cerebrovascular accident including transient ischemic attacks within the past 6 months. Pulmonary hemorrhage/bleeding event ≥ CTCAE Grade 2 within 4 weeks of first dose of study drug. Any other hemorrhage/bleeding event ≥ CTCAE Grade 3 within 4 weeks of first dose of study drug. Serious nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture. Evidence or history of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy. Therapeutic anticoagulation with warfarin, heparin or low molecular weight heparin is not allowed. Patients may not have had an arterial thrombotic event within the past 6 months. Major surgery, open biopsy or significant traumatic injury within 4 weeks of first dose of study drug. May not take known strong CYP3A4 inducers such as rifampin or St. John's wort or strong CYP3A4 inhibitors such as ketoconazole, diltiazem, or verapamil. Known or suspected allergy to temsirolimus or pazopanib, any similar agents such as the rapamycin analog sirolimus, or any agent given in the course of this trial. Any condition that impairs patient's ability to swallow whole pills.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Temsirolimus, Pazopanib</keyword>
</DOC>