<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00911534</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the efficacy, safety and tolerability of rabeprazole extended release (ER) 50 mg with placebo in subjects with symptomatic gastroesophageal reflux disease (sGERD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparing the Efficacy, Safety, and Tolerability of Rabeprazole ER 50 mg With Placebo in Subjects With Symptomatic Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease (sGERD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Gastroesophageal Reflux</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rabeprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>KEY INCLUSION CRITERIA: Male or female, ages 18 through 75 years will be included in the study. Females should be either of nonchildbearing potential or of childbearing potential. Females of childbearing potential must have negative serum and urine pregnancy tests prior to randomization. Female subjects of childbearing potential must agree to use medically acceptable methods of contraception starting at Visit 1 and throughout the entire study period and for 1 month after the last dose of study drug. Women using hormonal contraceptives must also be using an additional approved method of contraception starting at Visit 1 and throughout the entire study period and for 1 month after the last dose of study drug. Pregnant or lactating females are excluded. Subjects must have a history of heartburn, identified as their main complaint, for 6 months or longer.Subjects must have documentation of a minimum of 5 moderate to severe heartburn episodes, 3 of which occur during the daytime and 1 of which occurs during the nighttime, during the last 7 days before randomization. Subjects must be able to read, write, and understand the language of the symptom dairy. KEY EXCLUSION CRITERIA: Subjects will be excluded from the study if they are found to have erosive esophagitis during esophagogastroduodenoscopy (EGD) at Screening, current or a history of esophageal motility disorders, current or a history of Barrett's esophagus, current esophageal strictures or esophagitis (known or suspected to be due to etiology other than GERD such as infection or medications), current or a history of ZollingerEllison syndrome and acid hypersecretory conditions, or current gastric or duodenal ulcer. Subjects will be excluded if they are found to have current or a history of cancer, with the exception of fully excised skin basal cell carcinoma, inflammatory bowel disease, a history of esophageal, gastric and duodenal surgery, except simple closure of a perforated ulcer. Subjects will be excluded who require daily use of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), oral steroids (&gt;=20 mg/day prednisone or equivalent), or aspirin (&gt;325 mg/day). Female subjects will be excluded who are pregnant, lactating, or have a positive Bhuman gonadotropin test at Screening/Baseline. Subjects will be excluded who are known to be human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) positive, have participated in another investigational drug study within 30 days prior to screening or are expected to receive an investigational drug during this trial. Subjects who are unwilling to provide informed consent will be excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>GERD</keyword>
</DOC>