<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00911859</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate safety and effectiveness of CNTO 328 (siltuximab) when it is administered together with velcade-melphalan-prednisone (VMP) in comparison with VMP alone in participants with multiple myeloma (a type of cancer that affects the blood and bone marrow).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Compare CNTO 328 (Anti-IL-6 Monoclonal Antibody) and VELCADE-Melphalan-Prednisone (VMP) With VMP Alone in Previously Untreated Multiple Myeloma Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will be conducted in 2 parts (Part 1 and Part 2) and will consist of screening period up to 2 weeks; treatment period; maintenance period (CNTO 328 hereafter referred to as siltuximab) for a maximum of 18 months and follow up period until the study ends. Part 1 is an open-label (all people know the identity of the intervention), single group safety lead-in part to evaluate the safety of siltuximab. Approximately 12 patients will be treated with siltuximab in combination with VMP. If the safety profile of the combination is acceptable, the study will proceed to Part 2. Part 2 is a randomized (the study medication is assigned by chance), open-label, 2-arm (Arm A: siltuximab + VMP; Arm B: VMP alone) study. Approximately 104 patients will be equally randomized, followed by a maintenance period with siltuximab in particiants in Arm A who achieve a partial response (PR) or better. Particiants in both parts of the study will be treated up to a maximum of nine 6-week cycles provided there is no evidence of disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, or withdrawal from treatment. Study medication will be continued for at least 2 additional cycles after confirmation of complete response, and preferably for the full 9 cycles of the treatment period. Participants who will be receiving maintenance treatment after the 12-month effectiveness analysis may continue to receive treatment with siltuximab only after careful consideration by the treating physician and on evidence of clinical benefit and in the absence of unwarranted toxicities. Safety assessments will include evaluation of adverse events, clinical laboratory tests, eastern cooperative oncology group performance status, electrocardiogram, vital signs, and physical examination which will be monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Melphalan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Siltuximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed diagnosis of previously untreated multiple myeloma and not a candidate for high dose chemotherapy with stem cell transplantation Eastern cooperative oncology group performance status score of less than or equal to 2 Measurable secretory disease, defined as either serum monoclonal paraprotein greater than or equal to 1 g/dL or urine monoclonal protein greater than 200 mg/24 hours Adequate laboratory results that will be confirmed by a study physician Agrees to protocoldefined use of effective contraception Diagnosed with primary amyloidosis, asymptomatic or smoldering multiple myeloma or monoclonal gammopathy of undetermined significance Diagnosed with Waldenstrom's disease, or other conditions in which IgM Mprotein is present in the absence of a clonal plasma cell infiltration with lytic bone lesions Received prior or current systemic therapy or stem cell transplantation for multiple myeloma Peripheral neuropathy or neuropathic pain (Grade 2 or higher) Received radiation therapy, plasmapheresis or surgery within 14 days Transplanted solid organ, with the exception of a corneal transplant Serious concurrent illness or history of uncontrolled heart disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>CNTO328</keyword>
	<keyword>Interleukin-6 (IL-6)</keyword>
	<keyword>Monoclonal antibody</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-IL-6 monoclonal antibody</keyword>
	<keyword>Bortezomib</keyword>
	<keyword>Velcade</keyword>
	<keyword>Melphalan</keyword>
	<keyword>Prednisone</keyword>
</DOC>