<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00007865</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop cancer cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Monoclonal antibodies such as rituximab can locate cancer cells and either kill them or deliver cancer-killing substances to them without harming normal cells. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of combination chemotherapy combined with rituximab in treating patients who have recurrent or refractory non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination Chemotherapy Plus Rituximab in Treating Patients With Recurrent or Refractory Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the chemosensitivity rate in patients with recurrent or refractory non-Hodgkin's lymphoma treated with ifosfamide, carboplatin, and etoposide (ICE) in combination with rituximab. - Determine whether the addition of rituximab changes the toxicity profile of the ICE chemotherapy regimen in these patients. OUTLINE: Patients receive rituximab IV on days 1, 8, and 15 and ifosfamide IV over 1 hour, etoposide IV over 2 hours, and carboplatin IV on days 2-4. Treatment continues every 21 days for 2 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients who are not candidates for autologous stem cell transplantation may receive 1-4 more courses of chemotherapy without rituximab. Patients are followed at 1 month. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 19-39 patients will be accrued for this study within 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isophosphamide mustard</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ifosfamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed recurrent or refractory Bcell nonHodgkin's lymphoma CD20 positive Bidimensionally measurable or evaluable disease No myelodysplastic syndrome or chronic myeloid leukemia PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 19 and over Performance status: ECOG 02 OR Karnofsky 70100% Life expectancy: At least 3 months Hematopoietic: WBC at least 3,000/mm3 Granulocyte count at least 1,000/mm3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm3 Hepatic: Bilirubin no greater than 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) AST or ALT no greater than 2.5 times ULN Renal: Creatinine no greater than 1.5 mg/dL Other: Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception No other prior malignancy except curatively treated basal cell carcinoma, squamous cell carcinoma, or carcinoma in situ of the cervix No active serious infection No other concurrent serious medical condition that would preclude study PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: No prior bone marrow or peripheral blood stem cell transplantation for nonHodgkin's lymphoma Chemotherapy: No other concurrent chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: No concurrent corticosteroids except transient administration as antiemetic Concurrent nonsteroidal hormonal therapy allowed for nondisease related conditions (e.g., insulin for diabetes) Radiotherapy: No concurrent radiotherapy Surgery: Not specified Other: No other concurrent investigational therapy No other concurrent antitumor agents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 1 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 2 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 3 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult diffuse small cleaved cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult diffuse mixed cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult immunoblastic large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult Burkitt lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent mantle cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent small lymphocytic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>extranodal marginal zone B-cell lymphoma of mucosa-associated lymphoid tissue</keyword>
	<keyword>nodal marginal zone B-cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>splenic marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>