<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00293397</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as doxorubicin, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or stopping them from dividing. Chemoembolization kills tumor cells by blocking the blood flow to the tumor and keeping chemotherapy drugs near the tumor. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is studying how well chemoembolization using doxorubicin works in treating patients with liver cancer that cannot be removed by surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chemoembolization Using Doxorubicin in Treating Patients With Liver Cancer That Cannot Be Removed By Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine, preliminarily, the feasibility of chemoembolization with GelSpheres™ beads mixed with doxorubicin hydrochloride in patients with unresectable hepatocellular carcinoma. OUTLINE: This is a pilot study. Patients undergo catheterization of the hepatic artery followed by chemoembolization comprising an infusion of GelSpheres™ beads mixed with doxorubicin hydrochloride into the target hepatic artery. Patients may receive up to 3 chemoembolization treatments. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed at 1 month, every 2 months for 1 year, and then every 3 months during year 2. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 20 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) according to the European Association for the Study of Liver (EASL) disease diagnostic criteria AND the Okuda staging classification No advanced disease, as defined by any of the following: Barcelona Clinic Liver Cancer (BCLC) class C disease, as defined by the following: Vascular invasion, including segmental portal obstruction Extrahepatic spread Cancerrelated symptoms (PST of 12) BCLC class D disease, as defined by the following: Okuda stage III disease WHO performance status 3 or 4 Diffuse HCC, defined as massive illdefined tumor involvement ChildPugh Class C Not eligible for radical therapies (e.g., resection, liver transplantation, or percutaneous therapies) No significant liver decompensation Preserved liver function (ChildPugh class AB) No ascites (trace ascites allowed) No other active primary tumor Arteries supplying the lesion must be large enough to accept GelSpheres™ beads PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Bilirubin ≤ 3 mg/dL Albumin &gt; 2.0 g/dL AST and ALT ≤ 5 times the upper limit of normal (ULN) Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 5 times the upper limit of normal (ULN) No active gastrointestinal bleeding No encephalopathy No contraindication to hepatic embolization procedures, as indicated by any of the following: Portosystemic shunt Hepatofugal blood flow Platelet count &lt; 50,000/mm^3 INR ≥ 1.8 PTT ≥ 39 seconds Renal failure Severe atheromatosis No contraindication to doxorubicin hydrochloride administration, as indicated by any of the following: Bilirubin &gt; 5 mg/dL WBC &lt; 1,500/mm^3 Ejection fraction &lt; 50% by isotopic ventriculography or echocardiography Not pregnant No known allergy to contrast media No intolerance to occlusion procedures No vascular anatomy or bleeding that would preclude catheter placement or emboli injection, as indicated by any of the following: Active or risk of hemorrhage Patent extratointracranial anastomoses or shunts End arteries leading directly to the cranial nerves Feeding arteries smaller than distal branches from which they emerge Collateral vessel pathways that would potentially endanger normal territories during embolization PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: No prior anticancer therapy for HCC</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult primary hepatocellular carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>localized unresectable adult primary liver cancer</keyword>
</DOC>