<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02433041</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out whether postoperative delirium can be more properly prevented by the combination of determined preventive agents in past studies. Further on the investigators measure pre- and postoperative cortisol, neuron specific enolase (NSE) and S-100beta levels.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Baden Prevention and Reduction of Incidence of Postoperative Delirium Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The postoperative delirium remains a challenge for medical stuff concerning detection, therapy and avoidance of consequences. Over the years numerous risk factors were detected which emphasizes the importance of its prevention. Within these studies some possibilities, but no strictly defined rules of action for pharmacological or neuropsychological prevention are described. This is why in this randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled study, the investigators want to compare two agents that were found to prevent postoperative delirium to a certain level, even in combination: the investigators arrange the patients within four study groups, one receiving Haloperidol, one Ketamine, one both and one placebo. The patients receive the study drug only once right before induction of anesthesia. After the day of recruitment there is the day of operation and a follow-up of three days (5 days of observation in total, where the investigators will test cognitive function with Mini Mental Status Examination (MMSE), Delirium Observation Scale (DOS), Nursing Delirium Screening Scale (Nu-DESC) or Intensive Care Delirium Screening Checklist (ICDSC). Additionally the investigators will measure and compare pre- and postoperative Cortisol, NSE and S-100beta levels.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Delirium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Haloperidol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Haloperidol decanoate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 65 years and older Signed agreement Delirium at admittance or MMSE score &lt;24 points High risk for postoperative ICU treatment Haloperidol or Ketamine intolerance Risk of lack of cooperation Drug an alcohol abuse Dementia QT interval (QTc) prolongation (at least 460ms in men, at least 470ms women) or drugs influencing QT interval, such as class Ia and III antiarrhythmics, Gatifloxacin, Moxifloxacin, Pentamidin, Cotrimoxazol, Tacrolimus, Dolasetron Parkinson's disease Intake of dopaminergic drugs (Levodopa, dopamine agonists) Parkinsonism Epilepsy Unable to be interviewed (severe Dementia, speaking disorders, intubation, respiratory isolation, aphasia, coma, terminal illness) Delay of operation of more than 72 hours past hospital admittance Body weight &gt;100kg</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Postoperative delirium</keyword>
	<keyword>Cortisol</keyword>
	<keyword>NSE</keyword>
	<keyword>S-100beta</keyword>
	<keyword>MMSE</keyword>
	<keyword>Nu-DESC</keyword>
	<keyword>ICDSC</keyword>
	<keyword>DOS</keyword>
	<keyword>Haloperidol</keyword>
	<keyword>Ketamine</keyword>
	<keyword>Combination of Haloperidol and Ketamine</keyword>
	<keyword>Placebo</keyword>
	<keyword>Prevention of</keyword>
</DOC>