<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02433860</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There is a significant need for nicotine cessation programs for pregnant women in Spokane County. SCRIPT has been proven to be an effective method for smoking cessation in pregnant women. This study will evaluate the success of SCRIPT delivered by pharmacists. At the end of the study, the investigators hope to have three questions answered: 1) what is the quit rate of pregnant women in the Spokane area who receive the SCRIPT intervention delivered by pharmacists? 2) How does the quit rate compare to the quit rates of SCRIPT programs delivered by other health care providers as documented in the literature? And 3) Does the SCRIPT intervention have a significant effect on quit rates for pregnant women compared to current Spokane county quit rates? Urine cotinine tests will be used to document smoking status before delivery of the SCRIPT program, approximately one week after quit date and at &gt;36 wks gestation or at delivery for study participants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Pharmacists in Implementing the SCRIPT Protocol</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>1. The goal of this project is to evaluate the success of pharmacists in delivering the SCRIPT smoking cessation program. The research questions that need to be addressed are: i. What is the quit rate of pregnant women in the Spokane area who receive the SCRIPT intervention delivered by a pharmacist? ii. How does this quit rate compare to the quit rates of other SCRIPT programs given by other health care providers (social workers, nurses, etc.)? iii. Does the SCRIPT intervention have a significant effect on quit rates for smoking pregnant women compared to current Spokane county quit rates?</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Nicotine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pregnant nicotine use English speaking 18 years of age or older Males due to pregnancy status not applicable</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>