<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02433886</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Up to 40% of Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder (OCD) patients do not respond to conventional treatments (medications or behavior therapy). For some of them, a neurosurgical treatment can be indicated. A previous study, employing bilateral double-shot ventral capsular/ventral striatal (VC/VS) Gamma capsulotomy (GVC) for OCD has shown that this radiosurgical technique is potentially efficacious and relatively safe. However, a few patients may develop complications associated to radionecrosis (eg., brain cysts) in a long-term follow-up, which are probably associated to lesion volumes. Another study, with the preliminary results of smaller VC/VS Gamma capsulotomy lesions has suggested that this procedure is safe and remains efficacious. Our aim is to investigate the efficacy and safety profiles of smaller, single-shot VC/VS Gamma capsulotomy for OCD. This study will support the development of a future double-blind, randomized clinical trial of single-shot VC/VS Gamma capsulotomy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Adverse Events of Bilateral Single-shot VC/VS Gamma Capsulotomy for OCD: a Pilot Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Behavior</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A DSMV diagnosis of OCD as the main diagnostic entity. If comorbid axis I or II disorders are present, OCD symptoms are the most troublesome among disorders. Age range between 18 and 65 years old. At least 5 years of OCD symptoms. "YaleBrown ObsessiveCompulsive Scale" (YBOCS) scores greater than 26 (or greater than 13, for isolated obsessions or compulsions). Refractoriness criteria fulfilled. To be accepted by the "best estimate" method as a treatment refractory patient. It consists in the careful examination of each patient's history by two OCD specialists, so as to confirm refractoriness status. Refractoriness criteria: At least 3 serotonin reuptake inhibitors (selective or not) have been tried before. One of these trials must have included clomipramine. All drugs were used for a minimum of 12 weeks, at the maximum doses or the maximally tolerated doses. Previous participation in a cognitive behavior therapy program (exposure and response prevention), for a minimum of 20 hours' time; or participation for some time, without subsequent adherence, due to severe OCD symptoms, and acceptance of the independent review board. YBOCS scores reductions after adequate drug therapy and psychotherapy not better than 25 %, or confirmation of no clinical improvements by the mental health professionals who were responsible for the treatments of the patient. By the end of adequately conducted pharmacological trials, "Clinical Global Impression" (CGI) scores not better than minimal improvement. Previous use of at least two antidepressant augmentation strategies (such as the association of a typical or atypical antipsychotic, another serotonin reuptake inhibitor, a benzodiazepine, an anticonvulsant or an antiglutamatergic medication), in adequate doses for a sufficient period of time, without satisfactory responses. Less than 18 years or more than 65 years of age. Past history of head injury, with posttraumatic amnesia. Past or general medical condition, or neurological illness with brain compromise (severe and in active phase) History of physiological effects of a substance, as determinant of psychopathological symptoms, or cumulative signs of alcohol or drug abuse in the Central Nervous System (such cortical atrophy), confirmed by a neuroimaging scan. Pregnancy or lactation. Refusal to participate in radiosurgical procedures. Refusal to sign the Patient Information and Consent Form, or refusal to take part in this study. History of mental retardation and/or being unable to understand the Patient Information and Consent Form, confirmed by poor performance on neuropsychological tests.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>