<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01049373</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate superiority of HDC in comparison to placebo in the treatment of chronic low-back pain in relation to pain, functional impairment, quality of life, and state of health during a 15-week treatment period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Lymphdiaral Basistropfen (HDC) in the Treatment of Chronic Low-back Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Low-back pain is often provoked by inflammatory edema in the region of the facet joints. In naturopathy, a fixed homeopathic drug combination (HDC) is established in the treatment of edema and swellings. For the first time, the efficacy of HDC was investigated in the treatment of low-back pain. Objective: To examine the efficacy and safety of HDC medication vs. placebo in the treatment of chronic low back pain considering constitution and diathesism in a double-blind, randomized controlled clinical trial.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female patients Aged 18 75 years Chronic lowback pain lasting at least for 6 months Hanover functional ability questionnaire (FFbHR) score less than 70% At least one of the following diagnoses: 1. Chronic lumbar ischialgia with or without radicular radiation 2. Chronic degenerative lumbar syndrome 3. Spondylarthrosis 4. Chronic facet syndrome 5. Lumbago with protrusion of the intervertebral disc 6. Lumbar radiculopathy 7. Lumbar and other intervertebral disc impairments with radiculopathy 8. Back pain at different locations of the spine Written, informed consent Participation in another clinical trial/GCPtrial within 30 days prior to screening Participation in this trial in an earlier time Treatment with lymphdiaral basistropfen within 3 month prior to enrolment Pregnancy and lactation Noncompliance Incapability to understand the sense of the study Abuse of analgesics, opiates or other drugs Chronic pain that are as strong as or even stronger than the pain caused by the lowback and that need to be treated with analgesics Malign diseases Pathological neurological states Epilepsy Operation of the spine within 3 month prior to enrolment Fractures of the spine Bechterew's disease Alcohol abuse Consuming diseases Cachexia Palsy of the legs or anal sphincter due to acute impairment of the intervertebral disc Catheterisation or CTcontrolled intraarticular injection in the lumbar region Hypersensitivity against one of the ingredients or excipients of the study drugs or against composite plants in general Systemic, progressive diseases like tuberculosis, leucosis, collagenosis, multiple sclerosis, acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS), human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, or other autoimmune diseases</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>low-back</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic</keyword>
	<keyword>constitution</keyword>
	<keyword>diathesism</keyword>
	<keyword>homoeopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>fixed combination</keyword>
	<keyword>herbal preparation</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic low back pain lasting more than 6 months</keyword>
</DOC>