<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00715364</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the safety and tolerability of NTx™-265 when given to acute ischemic stroke patients. To assess the neurological outcome in acute ischemic stroke patients treated with NTx™-265, when compared with patients given a placebo control.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>REGENESIS (US): A Phase IIb Prospective, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo Controlled Study of NTx™-265: Human Chorionic Gonadotropin (hCG) and Epoetin Alfa (EPO) in Acute Ischemic Stroke Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chorionic Gonadotropin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1885. NIHSS score 624 within 2448 hours after stroke onset and enrolment. Stroke is ischemic in origin, supratentorial, and radiologically confirmed (CT scan or diagnostic MRI) prior to enrolment. Patient is 2448 hours from time of stroke onset when the first dose of NTx™265 therapy is administered. Time of onset is when symptoms began; for stroke that occurred during sleep, time of onset is when patient was last seen or was selfreported to be normal. Reasonable expectation of availability to receive the full 9 day NTx™265 course of therapy, and to be available for subsequent followup visits. Reasonable expectation that patient will receive standard poststroke physical, occupational, speech, and cognitive therapy as indicated. Female patient is either: 1. not of childbearing potential, defined as postmenopausal for at least 1 year or surgically sterile (bilateral tubal ligation, bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy) or, 2. if of childbearing potential, agrees to use two of the following effective separate forms of contraception throughout the study, up to and including the follow up visits: i) condoms, sponge, foams, jellies, diaphragm or intrauterine device (IUD) contraceptives (e.g. implants, injectables, combined oral, etc.) OR ii) a vasectomized partner OR iii) abstinence Patients presenting with lacunar, hemorrhagic and/or brain stem stroke Patients classified as comatose, defined as a patient who requires repeated stimulation to attend, or is obtunded and requires strong or painful stimulation to make movements (NIHSS 1A score must be &lt;2) Women who have tested positive for pregnancy, or are breastfeeding, or are not using a highly effective method of birth control that can be maintained for the duration of the study Serum hemoglobin &gt; 16 g/dL (males) or &gt; 14 g/dL (females); or platelet count &gt; 400,000/mm3 Advanced liver, kidney, cardiac, or pulmonary disease; the former will be operationally defined using NCI Toxicity Criteria (Grade 2 or higher) Serum bilirubin &gt; 1.5 x ULN Alkaline phosphatase &gt; 2.5 x ULN AST or ALT &gt; 2.5 x ULN Creatinine &gt; 2.0 x ULN Patients with known and documented Transferrin saturation &lt;20% or ferritin &lt; 100 ng/ml Patients with known and documented elevated PSA levels Patients with a known history of hypercoagulability, including known cardiolipin/antiphospholipid antibody syndrome Expected survival &lt; 1 year Allergy or other contraindication to hCG Allergy or other contraindication to epoetin alfa: A known diagnosis of cancer (except nonmalignant skin cancer) Uncontrolled hypertension, defined in the context of acute stroke as blood pressure persistently above 220 mm Hg systolic or 120 mm Hg diastolic despite antihypertensive therapy Use of either hCG or epoetin alfa within the previous 90 days Any condition known to elevate hCG, active in the prior 24 months, e.g., choriocarcinoma or germ cell tumor Patients with a prestroke/premorbid modified Rankin Score (mRS) ≥ 2 Any patients living in a nursing home or supervised living center. Patients must be historically fully independent in all activities of daily living including banking, shopping, cooking, toileting, showering and dressing Any other medical condition or degree of stroke such that, in the investigator's opinion, the patient should not be included in the trial With the exception of the qualifying stroke, any other stroke within the previous 3 months Patients who cannot take antiplatelet or anticoagulant therapy Preexisting and active major psychiatric or other chronic neurological disease Consume, on average, greater than 14 alcoholic drinks per week, or have a history of substance abuse or dependency within 12 months prior to the study Currently participating in another investigational study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>