<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00715676</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the effect of a 1-year administration of the vitamin D analog 2-methylene-19-nor-(20S)-1alpha, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 (DP001) on bone mineral density (BMD), safety, and tolerability.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 2 Safety and Efficacy Study of a Vitamin D Compound (DP001) in Postmenopausal Women With Low Bone Mineral Density</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>DP001 is a vitamin D analog that has been shown to stimulate bone formation in pre-clinical studies. In a Phase 1B study of postmenopausal women, an increase in the bone formation marker, osteocalcin, was evident without an increase in serum calcium. The aim of this study is to determine if 1-year administration of DP001 to postmenopausal women with osteopenia results in a significant increase in BMD at doses that are safe and well tolerated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dihydroxycholecalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bone Density Conservation Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinol palmitate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Postmenopausal female subjects, defined as amenorrheic for at least 5 years Body Mass Index of 18 to 35 Osteopenic Generally healthy Informed consent Exclusion Criteria History or evidence of acute or unstable chronic hematological, renal, endocrine, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, psychiatric, or neurologic diseases Current or recent treatment with any medications or products affecting vitamin D metabolism, calcium balance, bone turnover, or an investigational drug therapy 12lead electrocardiogram demonstrating QTc (QT interval corrected for heart rate) &gt;450 milliseconds at screening Abnormal creatinine clearance Elevated urinary calcium levels Vitamin D deficiency Excessive dietary calcium or vitamin D intake Current use of any illicit drug and/or history of alcohol abuse</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Osteoporosis</keyword>
	<keyword>2-methylene-19-nor-(20S)-1a, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D3</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Density Conservation Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Regeneration</keyword>
</DOC>