<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02430090</DOC>
	<brief_summary>45 pregnant women undergoing cesarean section were enrolled in the study in november 2006 to march 2007. 2 ml of 0.5% levobupivacaine was added to 1 ml of saline in group I, 1 ml of 15 µcg of fentanyl in group II and 1 ml of 1,5 µcg sufentanil in group III by intratechal administration. Hemodynamic parameters, characteristics of sensory and motor blockade, peri-operative and postoperative visual analogue scale (VAS) pain scores, the time to the first analgesic requirement and adverse effects were recorded.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Intratechal Levobupivacaine and Adding With Sufetanil and Fentanyl in Ceserean Section</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>45 pregnant women undergoing cesarean section were enrolled in the study in november 2006 to march 2007. Using CSE technique, 2 ml of 0.5% levobupivacaine was added to 1 ml of saline in group I, 1 ml of 15 µcg of fentanyl in group II and 1 ml of 1,5 µcg sufentanil in group III by intratechal administration. Hemodynamic parameters, characteristics of sensory and motor blockade, peri-operative and postoperative visual analogue scale (VAS) pain scores, the time to the first analgesic requirement and adverse effects were recorded.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levobupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sufentanil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>pregnant women with a single live fetus aged 1845 years old and classified as ASA I, undergoing elective cesarean section, were included the study in november 2006 to march 2007 Multiple pregnancies, preterm labor, eclampsia, preeclampsia, concomitant diabetes mellitus, allergy to local anesthetics, fentanyl or sufentanil, contraindication for regional anesthesia were the exclusion criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>regionel anesthesia</keyword>
	<keyword>levobupivacaine</keyword>
	<keyword>ceserean section</keyword>
</DOC>