<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02430987</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVE: To evaluate the prevalence of metabolic syndrome in postmenopausal women with a diagnosis of Hypoactive Sexual Desire Disorder. CASUISTIC AND METHODS: This is a case-control study in postmenopausal women attend in Menopause Clinic of the Faculty of Medical Sciences of Santa Casa de São Paulo. The investigators will select women diagnosed with HSDD. All women will sign the Consentment term. Those selected will assess the prevalence of MS through the ATPIII criteria. Sexual function are assessed by questionnaire Female Sexual Function Index (FSFI). RESULTS: The investigators hope there is greater prevalence of MS in women after menopause with HSDD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prevalence of Metabolic Syndrome in Postmenopause Woman With Hypoactive Sexual Desire Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study was carried out in compliance with the protocol, the principles laid down in the Declaration of Helsinki (1996 Version), in accordance with the International Conference on Harmonization Harmonized Tripartite Guideline for Good Clinical Practice and applicable regulatory requirement. The protocol was approved by the Institutional Review Board and the Independent Ethics Committee. The diagnosis of HSDD was made by a clinician who was experienced and trained in the diagnosis of female sexual disorders using a structured clinical interview for FSD Inclusion criterias: - one year of amenorrhea - FSH &gt; 30 mUI/mL - participants diagnosed or no with generalized acquired HSDD (i.e., HSDD that is not limited to certain types of stimulation, situation, or partner and that developed after a period of normal sexual functioning) according to the American Psychiatric Association's Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 4th edition, text revision (DSM-IV-TR) criteria of &gt; 24 weeks' duration. - participants with secondary arousal and/or orgasmic disorder were if the arousal or orgasmic disorder was deemed to be of lesser concern to the woman than her HSDD and to have developed after her HSDD. - Participants had to be in a monogamous heterosexual relationship of &gt; 1 year's duration and to have a sexually functional partner who was expected to be physically present for &gt; 50% of every month during the study. - participants had to be willing to engage in sexual activity (which included sexual intercourse, oral sex, masturbation, or genital stimulation by the partner) at least once monthly. - estrogens and progestins were permitted if the dose had been stable for 6 months prior to screening, unless prescribed for low sexual desire. Exclusion criterias: - participants with any other form of sexual dysfunction, or with any other psychiatric disorder that could impact sexual function - if the participants had a score of &gt; 14 on the Beck Depression Inventory II, suicide ideation according to the Columbia Suicide Severity Rating Scale (C-SSRS), or a history of suicidal behavior. - if they using any medication that, in the investigator's opinion, may affect sexual function or any of the following medications: antiepileptics, CYP3A4 inducers, dopamine agonists and other parkinsonian drugs, metoclopramide, androgens and antiandrogens, antiestrogens, fluoxetine or any long-acting hormonal implant in the 30 days prior to screening, gonadotrophin-releasing hormone analogues and other hormones and inhibitors, benzodiazepines, non-benzodiazepine prescription sleep aids, sedatives and hypnotics, antidepressants, antipsychotics, mood stabilizers, St. John's wort, narcotics (unless used for short-term pain relief), and vaginal lubricants/moisturizers containing warming and/or enhancing agents. - participants with gynecological disorders such as endometriosis. - participants with significant relationship discord in the opinion of the investigator (who conducted an extensive diagnostic interview with the woman as part of the screening process).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypokinesia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sexual Dysfunctions, Psychological</mesh_term>
	<criteria>one year of amenorrhea FSH &gt; 30 mUI/mL participants diagnosed or no with generalized acquired HSDD (i.e., HSDD that is not limited to certain types of stimulation, situation, or partner and that developed after a period of normal sexual functioning) according to the American Psychiatric Association's Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 4th edition, text revision (DSMIVTR) criteria of &gt; 24 weeks' duration. Participants had to be in a monogamous heterosexual relationship of &gt; 1 year's duration and to have a sexually functional partner who was expected to be physically present for &gt; 50% of every month during the study. Participants had to be willing to engage in sexual activity (which included sexual intercourse, oral sex, masturbation, or genital stimulation by the partner) at least once monthly. Participants with significant relationship discord in the opinion of the investigator (who conducted an extensive diagnostic interview with the woman as part of the screening process) were excluded from the study. Participants with any other form of sexual dysfunction, or with any other psychiatric disorder that could impact sexual function. if the particpant had a score of &gt; 14 on the Beck Depression Inventory II, suicide ideation according to the Columbia Suicide Severity Rating Scale (CSSRS), or a history of suicidal behavior. if the participant use any medication that, in the investigator's opinion, may affect sexual function or any of the following medications: antiepileptics, CYP3A4 inducers, dopamine agonists and other parkinsonian drugs, metoclopramide, androgens and antiandrogens, antiestrogens (estrogens and progestins were permitted if the dose had been stable for 6 months prior to screening, unless prescribed for low sexual desire), fluoxetine or any longacting hormonal implant in the 30 days prior to screening, gonadotrophinreleasing hormone analogues and other hormones and inhibitors, benzodiazepines, nonbenzodiazepine prescription sleep aids, sedatives and hypnotics, antidepressants, antipsychotics, mood stabilizers, St. John's wort, narcotics (unless used for shortterm pain relief), and vaginal lubricants/moisturizers containing warming and/or enhancing agents. participant with gynecological disorders such as endometriosis.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>