<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02430909</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, efficacy and body distribution of Bimekizumab (UCB4940) when added to Certolizumab Pegol treatment in patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis. Neither the patient nor the doctor will know the treatment group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multiple Dose Study of UCB4940 as add-on to Certolizumab Pegol in Subjects With Rheumatoid Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Certolizumab Pegol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria To be eligible to participate in this study, all of the following criteria must be met: Subject is informed and given approved written Informed Consent Form (ICF). Subject is considered reliable and capable of adhering to the protocol. Subject must have a diagnosis of adultonset moderatetosevere RA of at least 6 months' duration as defined by ACR/EULAR 2010 classification criteria. Subject must have: ≥6 tender joints (out of 68) ≥6 swollen joints (out of 66) CRP≥10.0mg/L . Subject must have had inadequate response to at least 1 synthetic DMARD. Subject is at least 18 years and less than 70 years of age at Visit 1 (Screening). Female subjects must either be: postmenopausal permanently sterilized or, if of childbearing potential, must be willing to use at least 2 effective methods of contraception, Male subjects with partners of childbearing potential must be willing to use a condom when sexually active, during the study and for 5 months after last administration of study drug. Exclusion Criteria Subjects are not permitted to enroll in the study if any of the following criteria is met: Subject has previously participated in this study or has previously been assigned to treatment in a study of the investigational medicinal product (IMP) under investigation in this study (UCB4940 and/or CZP). Subject has a history or active systemic/respiratory infection due to fungal, parasitic, or mycotic pathogens. Subjects with known tuberculosis (TB) infection, at high risk of acquiring TB infection, or latent TB infection are excluded. Subject is at high risk of infection. Subject has an active infection or has had a serious infection within 12 weeks prior to the first dose of study drug at Week 0. Subject has renal or liver impairment. Subject has a current or past history of gastrointestinal ulceration. Subject has active neoplastic disease or history of neoplastic disease. Subject has a concomitant diagnosis of any other inflammatory condition. Subject has a secondary, noninflammatory condition or a known diagnosis of fibromyalgia.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>