<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00396188</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the ability of a proprietary software screening tool to discriminate normal corneas (front surface of the eye) from previously diagnosed corneal conditions (diseases/surgeries/pathologies) and to determine the repeatabiltity and reproducibility of the Atlas II corneal topographer in normal human corneas.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Screening Aid to Identify Corneas That May Have Pathologies or Other Conditions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>1. To establish reference values for SF, CIM, and TKM in subjects with normal corneas. 2. To establish reference values for SF, CIM, and TKM in subjects who underwent myopic laser vision correction. 3. To establish reference values for SF, CIM, and TKM in subjects who underwent hyperopic laser vision correction. 4. To establish reference values for SF, CIM, and TKM in subjects who were diagnosed to have keratoconus. 5. To establish reference values for SF, CIM, and TKM in subjects with history of orthokeratology. 6. To establish reference values for SF, CIM, and TKM in subjects with previously diagnosed corneal conditions (diseases/pathologies/surgeries) affecting the corneal surface that are not listed above. 7. To determine the repeatabiltity and reproducibility of the Atlas II corneal topographer in normal human corneas using true elevation data and axial curvature. 8. To determine the sensitivity, specificity, and accuracy of the Pathfinder II Corneal Analysis software in discriminating normal corneas from previously diagnosed corneal conditions (diseases/pathologies/surgeries) affecting the corneal surface (Phase II).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Corneal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Normals Patients seeking initial laser vision correction that were screened to be good candidates for the procedure. No history of refractive or other ocular surgery. No corneal pathologies. Normal corneal topography. Contact lens wearers should discontinue use at least 2 weeks for hard contacts, and 3 days for soft lenses prior to imaging. Keratoconus An irregular cornea determined by distorted keratometry mires, distortion of the retinoscopic, or ophthalmoscopic red reflex (or a combination of these) At least one of the following biomicroscopic signs: Vogt's striae, Fleischer's ring of &gt;2 mm arc, or corneal scarring consistent with keratoconus. Contact lens wearers should discontinue use preferably 1 day or at least half an hour prior to imaging. Myopic Laser Vision Correction Patients who have undergone myopic: LASIK PRK LASEK Hyperopic Laser Vision Correction Patients who have undergone hyperopic: LASIK PRK LASEK Orthokeratology Patients using specially designed rigid contact lenses to reshape the cornea to temporarily reduce or eliminate refractive error. Subjects must be 18 years of age or older; able and willing to make the required visit; and able and willing to give consent. Patients that underwent corneal transplantation or any ocular surgery for the following categories: normal, keratoconus, and orthokeratology) Any active infection or inflammation of the cornea. PI decides that subject is not suitable due to medical risk.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Keratoconus</keyword>
	<keyword>LASIK</keyword>
	<keyword>Orthokeratology</keyword>
	<keyword>Pellucid Marginal Degeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>Refractive Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>normal cornea</keyword>
	<keyword>post myopic LASIK</keyword>
	<keyword>post hyperopic LASIK</keyword>
	<keyword>corneal pathologies (e.g. pellucid marginal degeneration)</keyword>
</DOC>