<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00224666</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The pains chronic neurogeneses remain difficult to treat whatever are their origin and their localization. The pharmacological therapeutic arsenal answers only partially the symptomatology often very invalidating which these chronic painful patients present. Electric stimulations of the central nervous system currently validated, in particular of the posterior cords of marrow made a significant improvement in a certain number of indications. Nevertheless, considerable patients are not relieved significantly, in particular those presenting of the pains neurogeneses of central origin (syndromes thalamic for example). It is within this framework that recently the stimulation of the sensorimotor cortex developed. Principal objective: evaluation of the technique of stimulation under cortical on neuropathic pains .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Cortex Stimulation in Neuropathic Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The pains chronic neurogeneses remain difficult to treat whatever are their origin and their localization. The pharmacological therapeutic arsenal answers only partially the symptomatology often very invalidating which these chronic painful patients present. Electric stimulations of the central nervous system currently validated, in particular of the posterior cords of marrow made a significant improvement in a certain number of indications. Nevertheless, considerable patients are not relieved significantly, in particular those presenting of the pains neurogeneses of central origin (syndromes thalamic for example). It is within this framework that recently the stimulation of the sensorimotor cortex developed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Neurofibromatosis, Rebel chronic neuropathic pain with duration &gt; 1 year and AVS &gt; = 4 Cancer Epilepsy Cognitive deterioration</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cortex stimulation ,Rebel neuropathic pains</keyword>
</DOC>