<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00224965</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This proposal will conduct a prospective examination of the clinical course (intensity, content and duration) of tobacco (nicotine) abstinence effects in male and female smokers who are either heavy/light alcohol drinkers with/without depressive symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Early Tobacco Abstinence - 5</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>1. To compare male and female smokers, with and without current depressive symptoms, in a prospective study of the intensity, content &amp; duration of nicotine abstinence effects during an eight-day abstinence period, and responses to cue exposure (invivo cigarette cues, alcohol and negative affect-inducing imagery cues) during acute vs. prolonged abstinence and, 2. To compare male and female smokers, who are either heavy alcohol drinkers or light alcohol drinkers, in a prospective study of the intensity, content &amp; duration of nicotine abstinence effects during an eight-day abstinence period, and responses to cue exposure (invivo cigarette cues, alcohol and negative affect-inducing imagery cues) during acute vs. prolonged abstinence.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1) between ages 1860 years; (2) able to read and write English (3) SMOKER: Smoking &gt;10 cigarettes per day for at least 1 year, with CO &gt; 10 ppm, and blood cotinine concentration of 150 ng/ml or greater, FTND scores &gt; 5. (4) DEPRESSED SUBJECT: Not meeting SCID criteria for current major depression or more than one past major depressive episode, but having scores &gt; 10 on the CESD indicating presence of depressive symptomatology (5) NONDEPRESSED SUBJECT: Not meeting SCID criteria for current major depression or more than one past major depressive episode, CESD scores &lt;10. (6) HEAVY DRINKER: Not meeting SCID criteria for current alcohol dependence; drinking 20 or more drinks per month. (7) LIGHT DRINKER: Not meeting SCID criteria for current alcohol dependence; drinking ten drinks or less per month 1. Current dependence on cocaine, marijuana, opiates or alcohol 2. Positive urine screen for marijuana, cocaine or opiates at any appointment after the intake appointment. 3. Regular use of any psychoactive drugs including anxiolytics and antidepressants; 4. Current major depression or other psychiatric conditions 5. Subjects with any significant, untreated current medical conditions condition such as neurological, endocrine, cardiovascular, renal, liver, thyroid pathology or on medications for any recent medical events 6) Pregnant or lactating women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2005</verification_date>
	<keyword>nicotine dependence</keyword>
</DOC>