<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01007201</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a laboratory-blinded study in healthy toddlers, children, and teenagers designed to investigate the safety, reactogenicity, and immunogenicity of an inactivated influenza H1N1 vaccine (AdimFlu-S). There are 3 age strata, and each contains at least 50 subjects: greater than or equal to 1 year to less than 3 years, greater than or equal to 3 years to less than 6 years, and greater than or equal to 6 years to less than 18 years. In each age strata, all eligible subjects received 2 injections of AdimFlu-S (A/H1N1) at a designated dosage level (7.5 μg, 15 μg and 15 μg for 1~&lt;3, 3~&lt;6 and 6~&lt;18 years, respectively) at 3 weeks apart. Following immunization, safety is measured by assessment of adverse events for 6 weeks following the first vaccination, serious adverse events and new-onset chronic medical conditions through 7 months post first vaccination, and reactogenicity to the vaccines for 7 days following each vaccination. Immunogenicity testing includes hemagglutination inhibition (HAI) testing on serum obtained before first vaccination, and three and six weeks after first vaccination.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunogenicity and Safety of Influenza Virus Vaccine, AdimFlu-S (A/H1N1), in Pediatric Population</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Boys or girls aged ≧ 1 year old to 18 years old on the day of first vaccination; Subject and/or parents(s)/legal guardian(s) was willing to comply with planned study procedures and be available for all study visits; Subject was in good physical health on the basis of medical history, physical examination; Subject and/or parents(s)/legal guardian(s) must read and signed the studyspecific informed consent prior to initiation of any study procedure. Subject ever received influenza vaccine within the previous 6 months; History of hypersensitivity to eggs or egg protein or similar pharmacological effects to study medication (AdimFluS (A/H1N1)); Personal or family history of GuillainBarré Syndrome; An acute febrile illness within the last 72 hours prior to vaccination; Subject with bleeding disorder or has any coagulation disorder that needs receipt of anticoagulants in the 3 weeks preceding inclusion contraindicating intramuscular injection; Subjects with influenzalike illness as defined by the presence of fever (temperature ≧38.5℃ ) and at least two of the following four symptoms: headache, muscle/joint aches and pains (e.g. myalgia/arthralgia), sore throat and cough; Female subjects who are pregnant, lactating or likely to become pregnant during the study; Women of childbearing potential disagree to use an acceptable method of contraception (e.g., hormonal contraceptives, IUD, barrier device or abstinence) throughout the study; Treatment with an investigational drug or device, or participation in a clinical study, within 3 months before consent; Immunodeficiency, immunosuppressive or household contact with immunosuppression; History of wheezing or bronchodilator use within 3 months prior to study vaccine; Receipt of live virus vaccine within 1 month prior to study vaccination or expected receipt within 2 months after first study vaccination; Receipt of any inactivated vaccine within 2 weeks prior to study vaccination or expected receipt vaccination within 3 weeks after the immunogenicity evaluation period; Receipt of any blood products, including immunoglobulin in the prior 3 months; Underlying condition in the investigator's opinion may be inappropriate for vaccination; Significant chronic illness for which inactivated influenza vaccine is recommended or commonly used.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Influenza</keyword>
	<keyword>H1N1</keyword>
	<keyword>vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunogenicity</keyword>
</DOC>