<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01007474</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the Italian ClinicalService Project is to develop an integrated system composed by a network of Italian hospital departments (for example cardiology departments), a clinical data repository (for example, cardiovascular or neurological data) and a shared environment for the collection, management, analysis and reporting of clinical and diagnostics data from patients treated by Medtronic therapies or patients wearing Medtronic implantable devices used within their intended use. These data are prospectively collected and may be mined to perform observational research.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Italian ClinicalService Project</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The mission of the Italian ClinicalService Project is to improve outcomes and comprehension of diagnostic and therapeutic strategies applied to patients wearing Medtronic implantable devices. ClinicalService provides services to evaluate and improve the quality of clinical care in the Italian clinical practice. ClinicalService collects acute and chronic patient and device data in a large population during routine usage of the device, without specific study interventions, and always within the approved intended use of the device. ClinicalService uses a core database which can be expanded with specific data sets for particular patient populations, diseases, therapies, devices or features. ClinicalService, with its prospective data collection and its data management infrastructure, forms a data-bank where physicians collect patient data and from which they receive reports about clinical and device diagnostics data. Usage and understanding of diagnostics data may help physicians to optimize tailor device programming and patient therapies. This data-bank, queried by retrospective statistical analyses, may help physicians in research, education and scientific activities. Some examples of scientific focus available through the Italian ClinicalService Project include: - Describing the use of implantable devices, such as cardioverter defibrillator (ICD), pacemakers, implantable loop recorders or others in the Italian clinical practice - Identifying predictors or clinical variables correlated with clinical outcomes or therapy response - Evaluating and testing methods to optimize device programming and patient therapy via device diagnostics or patient reports</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Bradycardia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Syncope</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arrhythmias, Cardiac</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients wearing a Medtronic marketreleased device or treated by a Medtronic therapy who have signed a patient data release and informed consent form Patients unwilling or unable to cooperate or give voluntary consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>