<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00801957</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Seven-month study in pediatric patients (2-11 years) with moderate to severe AD who were considered to benefit from vaccination to prevent invasive disease caused by Neisseria meningitides serogroup C.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Equivalence of the Response to Vaccination of Tacrolimus Ointment to a Steroid Ointment Regimen in Children With Atopic Dermatitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>At the week 1 visit, the patients were vaccinated with a protein-conjugated vaccine against meningitis. All patients received a challenge at the month 6 visit with a low dose of meningo polysaccharide vaccine. A control group of healthy subjects (not suffering from atopic dermatitis) received only the vaccination and the challenge dose.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis, Atopic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eczema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrocortisone 17-butyrate 21-propionate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cortisol succinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrocortisone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrocortisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Butyric Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrocortisone-17-butyrate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with moderate to severe atopic dermatitis and in need for treatment Patients require vaccination to prevent invasive disease caused by Neisseria meningitidis serogroup C Patients have known hypersensitivity to macrolides, tacrolimus and any component of the vaccine Patients have an acute severe febrile illness, genetic epidermal barrier defect such as Netherton's syndrome or generalized erythroderma, a skin infection on the affected and to be treated area Patients have already received a meningo polysaccharide or conjugated vaccine against meningitis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>atopic dermatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>meningitis</keyword>
	<keyword>vaccination</keyword>
	<keyword>tacrolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>steroids</keyword>
	<keyword>equivalence response</keyword>
	<keyword>meningococcal vaccine</keyword>
</DOC>