<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02768350</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study include (1) To investigate the efficacy of ventilator hyperinflation technique to re-expand lung atelectasis on patients with critical trauma who intubated and mechanical ventilation in the intensive care unit, (2) To investigate the effectiveness of ventilator hyperinflation technique to improve airway clearance on patients with critical trauma in the intensive care unit, and (3) To explore the acute responses of ventilatory functions to ventilator hyperinflation technique on patients with critical trauma who intubated and mechanical ventilation in the intensive care unit.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Ventilatory Responses to VHI in Atelectasis Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Atelectasis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Critical trauma patients with pulmonary complications who were intubated and mechanical ventilation and have a diagnosis of lobar atelectasis and/or platelike atelectasis (atelectasis demonstrated on chest Xray) will be considered for inclusion. For the sign of platelike atelectasis will be persist on chest Xray for 2 day The injuries may occur alone or combination of these injuries: 1) head injury, 2) chest injuries, including broken ribs, with or without hemothorax, pneumothorax and hemopneumothorax with intercostal chest drainage (ICD), 3) blunt abdominal, and 4) fracture of the limbs and/or spine. acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) acute lung injury (ALI) pulmonary contusion undrained pneumothorax, hemothorax, and hemopneumothorax bronchospasm pulmonary bullae/blebs lung tumors lung abscess haemoptysis mean arterial pressure (MAP) &lt;70 mmHg positive end expiratory pressure (PEEP) &gt;6 cmH2O heart rate (HR) &gt;140 beats/min blood pressure (BP) &lt;90/60 or &gt;180/100 mmHg restlessness oxygen saturation (SpO2) &lt;90% spontaneous respiratory rate (RR) &gt;35 beats/min</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>lung collapse</keyword>
	<keyword>ventilator hyper inflation</keyword>
	<keyword>hemodynamic responses</keyword>
	<keyword>ventilatory responses</keyword>
	<keyword>trauma patients</keyword>
</DOC>