<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02739646</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Rationale: The representation of the breast on the somatosensory cortex has not been precisely located. Therefore, a pilot study with healthy subjects is needed to localize the sensibility of the breast on the somatosensory cortex with the use of a 7 Tesla fMRI. Objective: To determine the exact localization of the representation of the sensibility of the breast and nipple-areola complex on the somatosensory cortex. Secondly, to assess whether there are differences in representation between individuals of the same sex and between both sexes. Study design: A single center pilot study carried out in the Maastricht University Medical Center, the Netherlands. Study population: A total of 10 female and 10 male healthy individuals will be recruited. Intervention: Every subject will undergo a functional MRI scan with stimulators applied to the bare breast in a fixed pattern. These stimulate the skin and sensory nerves of the breast and nipple-areola complex in a random sequence. Main study parameters: The hemodynamic response after stimulation of the skin of the breast and nipple-areola complex, representing neuronal activity in that region, is measured. Within the somatosensory cortex (S1 and S2), the temporo-spatial brain activity patterns after the various stimulation conditions are assessed, and the representation of the breast on the somatosensory cortex is mapped.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Representation of the Sensibility of the Breast on the Somatosensory Cortex</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Man or woman Between 21 and 28 years old Healthy; i.e. no comorbidities Women: breast size cup B or C BMI &lt; 27.0 kg/m2 Informed consent Any comorbidities Previous breast operation of any kind Previous allergic reactions to adhesives or plasters Any MRI exclusion criteria e.g.: (No piercings or other iron materials (except a metal brace behind front teeth) (Claustrophobia)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>28 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>