<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01077544</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess the pharmacokinetics of nilotinib in Ph+ CML pediatric patients that are newly diagnosed or resistant or intolerant to imatinib or dasatinib or refractory or relapsed Ph+ ALL compared to the adult populations. It will also evaluate safety and activity of nilotinib as secondary objectives.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pharmacokinetic (PK) Study of Nilotinib in Pediatric Patients With Philadelphia Chromosome-positive (Ph+) Chronic Myelogenous Leukemia (CML) or Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia (ALL)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelogenous, Chronic, BCR-ABL Positive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Philadelphia Chromosome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Imatinib Mesylate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dasatinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must have one of the following: newly diagnosed CP Ph+CML, CP or AP resistant/ intolerant to imatinib and/or dasatinib, or Ph+ ALL either relapsed after or refractory to standard therapy adequate renal, hepatic and pancreatic function patients receiving therapy with strong CYP3A4 inhibitors and/or inducers and treatments cannot be stopped or changed to a different medication at least 14 days prior to starting study drug patients receiving therapy with any medications with a known risk or possible risk to prolong the QT interval and the treatment cannot be either discontinued or switched to a different medication prior to starting study drug. gastrointestinal impairment or disease that may interfere with drug absorption liver, pancreatic or severe renal disease unrelated to disease under study impaired cardiac function patients who received dasatinib within 3 days of starting study drug patients who received imatinib within 5 days of starting study drug patients receiving hydroxyurea or corticosteroids that has not been discontinued at least 1 week after initiation of nilotinib patients who received hematopoietic growth factors within 7 days of starting study drug or Pegfilgrastim (Neulasta®) within 14 days of starting study drug patients with Stem Cell Transplant (SCT) or Rescue without TBI: Evidence of active graft vs. host disease and &lt; 3 months since SCT Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Myeloid Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Ph+ CML</keyword>
	<keyword>Ph+ ALL</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatric</keyword>
	<keyword>nilotinib</keyword>
	<keyword>imatinib</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic phase</keyword>
	<keyword>accelerated phase</keyword>
	<keyword>newly diagnosed Ph+ CML</keyword>
	<keyword>dasatinib</keyword>
</DOC>