<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01077076</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized, crossover study is to evaluate the early effectiveness, defined as effect on intragastric pH during the first 4 hours after dosing, of Zegerid, Prilosec over-the-counter (OTC) Tablets, and placebo on the 4th day of treatment to inhibit acid secretion. Additional purposes are to: 1. provide pharmacodynamic evidence comparing 24-hr inhibition of acid secretion on the 1st, 4th, and 11th days of dosing with each of the indicated treatments; 2. compare Zegerid and Prilosec OTC for achieving their steady-state effects for controlling 24-hr gastric acidity at steady-state on the 4th and 11th day of dosing. 3. evaluate early effectiveness, defined as effect on intragastric pH during the first 4 hours after administration, of Zegerid, Prilosec OTC Tablets, and placebo on acid inhibition at steady-state when administered on the 11th day of dosing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacodynamic Study Comparing the Effects of Two Different Forms of Omeprazole (P07812) (COMPLETED)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants were randomized in a 3-way crossover design and received, in random order, Zegerid OTC Capsules (20 mg omeprazole and 1100 mg sodium bicarbonate), Prilosec OTC Tablets (20 mg-equivalent omeprazole), and Placebo Capsules. Participants received each treatment for 11 days. There was a minimum of a 2-week washout period between treatment arms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Omeprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Omeprazole, sodium bicarbonate drug combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or nonlactating, nonpregnant female subjects who are 1865 years of age. Physical examination findings within normal limits for age. History of hypersensitivity, allergy or intolerance to omeprazole, or other proton pump inhibitors History of peptic ulcer disease or other acid related gastrointestinal symptoms or heartburn with a frequency of more than one/month. Participation in any study of an investigational treatment in the 30 Days before Screening or participation in another study at any time during the period of this study Any significant medical illness that would contraindicate participation in the study Gastrointestinal disorder or surgery leading to impaired drug absorption Any abnormal Screening laboratory value that is clinically significant in the investigator's opinion Current use of any prescription or OTC medications that affect gastrointestinal function. Currently using or having a history of frequent use of antacids, OTC or prescription (Rx) histamine2 (H2) receptor antagonists, or OTC or Rx use of proton pump inhibitors.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gastric Acid</keyword>
	<keyword>Human Experimentation</keyword>
</DOC>