<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01077180</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Rheos Feasibility Trial is designed to assess safety, device performance, and protocol parameters of the CVRx Rheos Baroreflex Therapy in patients with severe hypertension that are refractory to full drug therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rheos Feasibility Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Be at least 21 years of age. 2. Have been assessed to have bilateral carotid bifurcations located at or below C3C4. 3. Have an office cuff systolic blood pressure greater than or equal to 160 mmHg and a 24hour ambulatory systolic blood pressure greater than or equal to 150 mmHg despite at least one month of full therapy with at least three (3) antihypertensive medications, of which at least one (1) must be a diuretic. 4. Must be certified by the investigator hypertension specialist as compliant with taking full doses of medication. 5. Have signed a CVRx approved informed consent for participation in this study. 1. Have been diagnosed with: Baroreflex failure Cardiac bradyarrhythmias Chronic atrial fibrillation 2. Had a heart transplant 3. Have carotid atherosclerosis producing a 50% or greater reduction in linear diameter as determined by ultrasound or angiographic evaluation as determined within six months of enrollment in the trial. 4. Have Grade C ulcerative plaques in the carotid artery as determined by ultrasound or angiographic evaluation. 5. Have prior surgery or radiation in either carotid sinus region. 6. Currently have implanted electrical medical devices such as cardiac pacing, defibrillation or neurologic stimulation systems. 7. Are pregnant or contemplating pregnancy during the 13month followup period. 8. Currently undergoing dialysis. 9. Have hypertension secondary to a treatable cause. 10. Have clinically significant cardiac valvular disease. 11. Are unable or unwilling to fulfill the protocol medication compliance and followup requirements. 12. Are unlikely to survive the protocol followup period. 13. Are enrolled in another concurrent clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>