<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00255190</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the long-term safety profile of daily treatment with dexlansoprazole MR in subjects with gastroesophageal reflux disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Quality of Life Study of Dexlansoprazole Modified Release Formulation to Treat Heartburn</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This open-label study is intended to determine the long-term safety profile of dexlansoprazole MR over 12 months of dosing with 60 mg once-daily (QD) or 90 mg QD in subjects with gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD), including those with esophageal erosions. Prior to a protocol amendment, 300 subjects successfully completed one of the symptomatic nonerosive gastroesophageal reflux studies T-GD04-082 (NCT00251745) or T-GD04-083 (NCT00251758) in which they were randomly assigned to receive placebo or dexlansoprazole MR 60 or 90 mg QD. Subjects who were enrolled from one of these symptomatic GERD studies were randomly assigned in a 1:1 ratio to receive either dexlansoprazole MR 60 or 90 mg QD in this long-term study. After implementation of protocol amendment #4, an additional 300 subjects with gastroesophageal reflux disease including those with erosive esophagitis will be enrolled and treated with dexlansoprazole MR 90 mg QD for 12 months. Approximately 200 study sites in the U.S. will participate. For all analyses involving visits during treatment from subjects enrolled prior to protocol amendment #4, baseline refers to pretreatment to Study T-GD04-082 (NCT00251745) or T-GD04-083 (NCT00251758). For subjects enrolled under protocol amendment #4, baseline is based on screening or predosing measurement.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Gastroesophageal Reflux</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexlansoprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lansoprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must have successfully completed either TGD04082 (NCT00251745) or TGD04083 (NCT00251758) or have a diagnosis of gastroesophageal reflux disease with or without erosive esophagitis. Any condition that may require inpatient surgery during the course of the study. Use of prescription or nonprescription proton pump inhibitors, histamine (H2) receptor antagonists, sucralfate, misoprostol or prokinetics throughout the study. Use of antacids [except for study supplied Gelusil®]. Subjects using drugs with significant anticholinergic effects such as tricyclics who cannot stay on a stable dose for 4 weeks prior to dosing and throughout the study. Evidence of uncontrolled systemic disease. Allergy to any proton pump inhibitor including Prilosec, Nexium, Prevacid, or others, any component of dexlansoprazole MR, or Gelusil/antacid. Need to take blood thinners. Need to take more than 12 doses of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs per month. Had cancer (except basal cell cancer of the skin) within 3 years prior to screening. Has other esophageal disease including Barrett's esophagus or strictures requiring dilation. Has had radiation or cryotherapy to the esophagus. Has active gastric or duodenal ulcers within 4 weeks of starting study drug. Has a history of hypersecretory conditions such as Zollinger Ellison Syndrome. History of alcohol abuse. Has acquired immunodeficiency syndrome. Has had acute upper gastrointestinal bleeding within 4 weeks of endoscopy. Received a blood product transfusion within 3 months of taking the first dose of study drug. Has previously participated in another dexlansoprazole MR longterm treatment clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease</keyword>
</DOC>