<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00255021</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present clinical study will assess the immunogenicity and reactogenicity of Sanofi Pasteur's DTacP-IPV// PRP~T combined vaccine (Pentavac™ or Pentaxim™) as a three-dose primary vaccination at 2, 4, and 6 months of age followed by a booster dose during the second year of life and concomitant hepatitis B vaccine at 2 and 6 months of age in infants in Thailand.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunogenicity and Safety of Sanofi Pasteur Pentaxim Combined Vaccine in Infants in Thailand</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Whooping Cough</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tetanus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diphtheria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Poliomyelitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Haemophilus Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged 53 to 70 days inclusive on the day of inclusion Participation in another clinical trial in the 4 weeks preceding the (first) trial vaccination Planned participation in another clinical trial during the present trial period Congenital or acquired immunodeficiency; immunosuppressive therapy such as longterm systemic corticosteroid therapy. Systemic hypersensitivity to any of the vaccine components or history of a life threatening reaction to the trial vaccine or a vaccine containing the same substances Chronic illness at a stage that could interfere with trial conduct or completion. Blood or bloodderived products received in the past. Mother known as seropositive to HIV or hepatitis B Any vaccination in the 5 weeks preceding the first trial vaccination (except Bacille CalmetteGuerin [BCG]) History of diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis, poliomyelitis, Haemophilus influenzae type b infection or hepatitis B (confirmed either clinically, serologically or microbiologically). Previous vaccination against the diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis, poliomyelitis diseases or Haemophilus influenzae type b infection with the trial vaccine or another vaccine. Thrombocytopenia or a bleeding disorder contraindicating intramuscular vaccination History of/current seizures Febrile illness (rectal temperature ≥ 38.0°C or axillary temperature ≥ 37.4°C) or acute illness on the day of inclusion.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>2 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diphteria</keyword>
	<keyword>Tetanus</keyword>
	<keyword>Pertussis</keyword>
	<keyword>Poliomyelitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Haemophilus influenzae type b</keyword>
	<keyword>acellular</keyword>
</DOC>