<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00446524</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate long-term safety and tolerability of once daily administration of the combination of Valsartan and Amlodipine 80/5 mg for 52 weeks in patients with essential hypertension.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long Term Study of Valsartan and Amlodipine in Patients With Essential Hypertension (Extension to Study CVAA489A1301)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Valsartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amlodipine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amlodipine, Valsartan Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who successfully complete the core study (Study CVAA489A1301. Patients whose blood pressure at Visit 7 of the Study CVAA489A1301 had to be well controlled defined as MSDBP &lt; 90 mmHg and MSSBP &lt; 140 mmHg. At the investigator's or subinvestigator's discretion, those patients who were not well controlled (MSDBP ≥ 90 mmHg or MSSBP ≥ 140 mmHg), and whose MSDBP was &lt; 100 mmHg and MSSBP was &lt; 160 mmHg might participate in the extension if this was considered an acceptable level of blood pressure control for the patient. Male or female outpatients. Patients who have written informed consent to participate in this study. Presence of major protocol violation in Study CVAA489A1301. Patients who experienced any adverse events considered serious and drug related in Study CVAA489A1301. Patients who experienced any adverse events considered serious and drug related in Study CVAA489A1301. Patients who are considered unlikely to comply with the requirements specified in the protocol by the investigator or subinvestigator. Patients who have gout or gouty arthritis. Patients hypersensitive to diuretics (except for potassium sparing diuretics). Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hypertension, Valsartan, Amlodipine, high blood pressure</keyword>
</DOC>