<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00446680</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the efficacy and safety of chronic treatment with inhaled dry powder mannitol in subjects with cystic fibrosis. Previous studies have demonstrated an improvement in lung function related to small airways obstruction and a significant improvement in respiratory symptoms and quality of life after a 2 week treatment with mannitol. This current study seeks to support these early findings and to extend the evidence to support its use as a mucoactive therapy in cystic fibrosis. In particular, the hypothesis that enhanced mucus clearance will improve the lung function and clinical presentation in this population, will be investigated. We also hypothesize that enhanced mucociliary clearance will result in a sustained reduction in mucus load, thus providing less opportunity for bacteria to proliferate, affording a reduction in antibiotic use and hospitalizations. The initial 6 month blinded phase will be followed with an additional 6 months of open label treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long Term Administration of Inhaled Dry Powder Mannitol In Cystic Fibrosis - A Safety and Efficacy Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mannitol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Main Written informed consent Confirmed diagnosis of cystic fibrosis Aged &gt; 6 years FEV1 &gt;30 % and &lt; 90% predicted Able to perform all the techniques necessary to measure lung function Main "Terminally ill" or listed for lung transplantation Had a lung transplant Using nebulised hypertonic saline Significant episode of haemoptysis (&gt;60 mL) in the three months prior to enrolment Recent myocardial infarction or cerebral vascular accident Breast feeding or pregnant, or plan to become pregnant while in the study participating in another investigative drug study, parallel to, or within 4 weeks of study entry Allergy or intolerance to mannitol Using beta blockers Have a condition or be in a situation which in the Investigator's opinion may put the subject at significant risk, may confound results or may interfere significantly with the patient's participation in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mannitol</keyword>
	<keyword>Cystic Fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Mucolytic</keyword>
	<keyword>Exacerbation</keyword>
	<keyword>FEV1</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
</DOC>