<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02485470</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to test, in a randomized controlled trial among head and neck cancer patients, the short and longer term effects of the MPACT (Maintaining Physical Activity during Cancer Treatment) program (infused with motivational interviewing and self-determination theory-based strategies) initiated at the time of concurrent chemotherapy with radiation (CCRT), on key outcomes such as functional mobility and quality of life, and ultimately physical activity. The central hypotheses is that in head and neck cancer patients undergoing CCRT, the MPACT program, as compared to usual care controls, will result in less acute decline, faster recovery, and better maintenance of these key outcomes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Benefits of MPACT in Locally Advanced Head and Neck Cancer Patients Undergoing Chemoradiotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients greater than or equal to 40 years old with AJCC (American Joint Committee on Cancer) stage IIIV head and neck squamous cell carcinoma who are beginning firstline nonsurgical treatment with concurrent chemoradiotherapy (CCRT) and who are capable of understanding and adhering to the protocol requirements Patients must be willing to comply with the study procedures and visits. Active or symptomatic cardiopulmonary disease Substantial dementia Acute medical conditions, such as acute flareup of joint condition or infection Participants must not be actively receiving physical therapy in a relevant area, at the time of enrollment, or participating in intensive (30 min per day) aerobic program three times per week. Patients are actively being treated for another cancer at the time of enrollment Active or unstable metabolic conditions such as brittle diabetes or severe anemia Alcohol intake less than 3 ounces per day Hemiplegia or lower limb amputation Significant orthopedic or musculoskeletal condition that does not allow weight bearing Unable to maintain safe stance and walk, either with or without an assistive device</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>