<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02485847</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The IRIS™ Registry (Intelligent Research in Sight) is the nation's first comprehensive eye disease clinical registry. The American Academy of Ophthalmology is developing it as part of the profession's shared goal of continual improvement in the delivery of eye care.The IRIS Registry will be a centralized system for ophthalmology practices to promote practice innovations and achieve clinical excellence.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>IRIS Registry: Intelligent Research in Sight Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The IRIS Registry is primarily a clinical self-improvement tool. It will allow ophthalmologists to compare their patient outcomes, professional performance and care processes against other ophthalmologists across the country. The IRIS Registry will be able to measure the continuum of care from initial patient contact, through intervention and follow up. Improve Patient Care - Monitor patient interactions, track interventions, identify and address gaps in quality of care, and measure quality outcomes. Manage Patient Populations - Proactively manage clinical conditions for entire patient populations by running reports on specific care criteria. Benchmark Your Practice - Identify practice strengths and weaknesses using the IRIS Registry's ophthalmology-specific clinical data from other practices to compare to the performance and outcomes data of your practice. Run quality reports on demand - Providing clinician- and practice-level results, plus national results and patient-level detail for all IRIS Registry measures. Enhance Quality and Practice Efficiency - Use the IRIS Registry data to analyze practice processes and procedures and as a source for fact-based decision-making. Because the IRIS Registry will capture data over time at the individual and practice level, it will help practices efficiently manage patient care and optimize practice resources. Join a Community of Quality - Become a member of a like-minded community of quality-driven professionals striving to continuously improve patient care. Interact with your peers to create opportunities for sharing quality improvement strategies and broaden your professional network.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Eye Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who meet the denominator requirements for each measure.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Eye Diseases</keyword>
</DOC>