<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00545662</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Citicoline Brain Injury Treatment (COBRIT) is a randomized, double-blind, placebo controlled, multi-center trial of the effects of 90 days of citicoline on functional outcome in patients with complicated mild, moderate and severe traumatic brain injury.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Citicoline for the Treatment of Traumatic Brain Injury (COBRIT)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Traumatic brain injury (TBI) is a major cause of death and disability. In the United States alone approximately 1.4 million sustain a TBI each year, of which 50,000 people die, and over 200,000 are hospitalized. Despite numerous prior clinical trials no standard pharmacotherapy for the treatment of TBI has been established in either the acute or post acute setting. Citicoline is a naturally occurring endogenous compound. This compound offers the potential of employing neuroprotection, neuro-recovery and neurofacilitation to enhance recovery after TBI. The primary goal of this study is to assess the efficacy of citicoline compared to placebo on functional and cognitive outcome in participants with traumatic brain injury.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cytidine Diphosphate Choline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Nonpenetrating traumatic brain injury. 2. Age 18 (19 in Alabama) 70 years. 3. GCS criteria on/off paralytics as specified in protocol 4. Reasonable expectation of completion of outcomes measures at a network center at six months postinjury. 5. Able to swallow oral medication or, if unable to swallow, a gastric tube or peg are placed by 23 hours after injury. 6. Reasonable expectation of enrollment within 24hour time window. 7. Englishspeaking 1. Intubated patients with GCS motor score = 6 and not meeting CT criteria. 2. Bilaterally fixed and dilated pupils 3. Positive pregnancy test, known pregnancy, or currently breast feeding 4. Evidence of diseases that interfere with outcome assessment 5. Current acetylcholinesterase inhibitor use (Appendix 1) 6. Imminent death or current lifethreatening disease 7. Currently enrolled in another study 8. Prisoners</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>traumatic brain injury</keyword>
	<keyword>cognition</keyword>
	<keyword>behavioral outcome</keyword>
	<keyword>functional outcome</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>early intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>citicoline</keyword>
</DOC>