<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00545701</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The trial is a Phase II, open-label trial in healthy subjects aged 18 to 60 years to support the immunogenicity data from previous clinical studies. Objectives: - To describe the immune response 21 days after each vaccination. - To describe the safety profiles following each vaccination.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunogenicity and Safety of an Intramuscular A/H5N1 Inactivated, Split Virion Pandemic Influenza Vaccine in Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Orthomyxoviridae Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged 18 to 60 years on day of inclusion. Informed Consent Form signed. Able to attend all scheduled visits and to comply with all trial procedures. For a woman, inability to bear a child or negative urine pregnancy test. For a woman of childbearing potential, use of an effective method of contraception or abstinence for at least 4 weeks prior to and at least 4 weeks after each vaccination. Systemic hypersensitivity to any component of the vaccine or a lifethreatening reaction after previous administration of a vaccine containing the same substances (egg proteins, chick proteins, thimerosal, aluminum, neomycin, formaldehyde, and octoxinol 9). Febrile illness (oral temperature &gt;= 37.5°C) on the day of inclusion. Breastfeeding. Previous vaccination with an avian flu vaccine. Participation in a clinical trial (drug, device, or medical procedure) within 4 weeks prior to the first vaccination. Planned participation in another clinical trial during the present trial period. Congenital or acquired immunodeficiency, or receipt of immunosuppressive therapy such as anticancer chemotherapy or radiation therapy within the preceding 6 months, or longterm systemic corticosteroid therapy. Chronic illness that could interfere with trial conduct or completion (e.g. cardiac, renal, diabetes, or autoimmune disorders). Current alcohol or drug abuse that may interfere with the subject's ability to comply with trial procedures. Receipt of blood or bloodderived products in the past 3 months, that might interfere with the assessment of immune response. Receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks preceding the first trial vaccination. Planned receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks following any trial vaccination. Thrombocytopenia or bleeding disorder contraindicating intramuscular vaccination. Subject deprived of freedom by an administrative or court order, or in an emergency setting, or hospitalized without his/her consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Influenza</keyword>
	<keyword>A/H5N1 strain</keyword>
	<keyword>Orthomyxoviridae Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza Pandemics</keyword>
</DOC>