<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00888732</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The hypothesis is that an optimal formulation of fast acting and intermediary acting insulin analogues will improve post prandial glycaemic control in patients with type 1 diabetes</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Comparison of Pharmacodynamics and Pharmacokinetics of Insulin Aspart, BIAsp70, BIAsp50 and Fast-acting Human Insulin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This trial is a single centre, open-label, randomised 4 period cross-over trial, comparing the pk and pd profiles of IAsp, BIAsp 50, BIAsp 70 and Fast-acting Human Insulin after a standard test meal in subjects with type 1 diabetes. The profiles will be derived over a 12-hour period after subcutaneous injection in the abdominal region with a single dose of IAsp, BIAsp 50, BIAsp 70 or Fast-acting Human Insulin at a test meal. The trial consists of a screening period of 4-21 days and 4 treatment visits.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin degludec, insulin aspart drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Biphasic Insulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Aspart</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Long-Acting</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent obtained before any trialrelated activities. Diagnosed type 1 diabetes before the age of 40 and on insulin treatment within one year of diagnosis. Insulin treatment of any regime for more than one year at time of inclusion. Total insulin demand ≥ 0,4 U/IU/kg/24 hrs HbA1c between 7% and 12% (both values included). Age ≥ 18 years. BMI between 18 and 35 kg /m2 (including both values). Known or suspected allergy to trial product(s) or related products. Recurrent major hypoglycaemic episodes. Heart: Unstable Angina Pectoris, AMI &lt; 12 months or heart insufficiency classified according to NYHA IIIIV Blood Pressure: Severe uncontrolled hypertension with BP &gt; 180/110 mmHg, sitting Liver: Impaired hepatic function corresponding to serumALAT or basic phosphatase &gt; 2 x upper reference limit of the local laboratory. Kidneys: Impaired renal function corresponding to serumcreatinin &gt; 150 μmol/l according to the local laboratory. Any disease judged by the investigator to affect the trial. Pregnancy, breastfeeding or the intention of becoming pregnant or fertile women not using adequate contraceptive measures adequate contraceptive method is sterilisation, hysterectomy or current use of contraceptive pills or intra uterine device.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
</DOC>