<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01297348</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Lybrel® is an oral contraceptive that delivers low doses of levonorgestrel and ethinyl estradiol (90 μg/20 μg). Lybrel is taken on a continuous basis without a placebo or pill-free interval to inhibit menstrual cycle bleeding by delivering a steady level of the 2 hormones for as long as the drug is used. Lybrel was marketed in the US in July of 2007. The objective of this database case-control study is to estimate the risk of idiopathic VTE (deep vein thrombosis and pulmonary embolism) in current users of Lybrel (ethinyl estradiol 20ug/levonorgestrel 90ug) compared to current users of other oral contraceptives containing 20μg of ethinyl estradiol.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Of Lybrel In Relation To Venous Thromboembolism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The base population consists of all currently available data on current users (15-49 years old) of Lybrel and other oral contraceptives (OC) containing 20 µg ethinyl estradiol in the PharMetrics/IMS and MarketScan databases. From among the base population, the databases are then searched for any diagnosis of deep vein thrombosis (DVT), pulmonary embolism (PE), or cerebral venous sinus thrombosis (CVST) [referred to collectively as venous thromboembolism or VTE] that occurred after receipt of Lybrel or other oral contraceptives containing 20 µg ethinyl estradiol. The intent is to include newly diagnosed cases of VTE.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Embolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Embolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sinus Thrombosis, Intracranial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intracranial Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethinyl Estradiol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polyestradiol phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Contraceptives, Oral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levonorgestrel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethinyl estradiol, levonorgestrel drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol 17 beta-cypionate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol 3-benzoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol valerate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Contraceptive Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>New users of the study drugs (i.e., Lybrel and the comparison OCs) No specific exclusion criteria for the base study cohort.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lybrel</keyword>
	<keyword>levonorgestrel</keyword>
	<keyword>ethinyl estradiol</keyword>
	<keyword>venus thromboembolism (VTE)</keyword>
	<keyword>oral contraceptives (OC)</keyword>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
	<keyword>database study</keyword>
	<keyword>case-control study</keyword>
</DOC>