<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02151045</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In discal sciatica, after failure of medical treatment, the investigators propose frequently a spinal infiltration of corticoids the most closer of disco-radicular conflict. Recently, some cases of paraplegia during lumbar foraminal infiltrations have induce a reduction of indications of this type of infiltration. An alternative would be to propose a lateral epidural infiltration on contact with conflict.The objective of this study is to compare, in 112 patients with a less than 6 months discal sciatica, the efficacy on pain of a non target posterior epidural space infiltration of corticoids done at L3-L4 stage on scan control versus an epidural infiltration of the same corticoid done in lateral on contact of disco radicular conflict on scan control.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of a Cortivazol (ALTIM®) Infiltration of Posterior Epidural Space at L3-L4 Stage Versus an Epidural Infiltration of Cortivazol (ALTIM®) on Contact With Disco Radicular Conflict in Discal Sciatica</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sciatica</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cortivazol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent Aged from 18 to 65 years Affiliated or benefit from an insurance regimen Patient with a sciatic answering to the definition Discal sciatica more than 15 days and less than 6 months Discal hernia (scan or RMI) Negative BHCG and normal coagulation parameters History of lumbar surgery Spinal infiltration of corticoids in 30 days before inclusion Iode allergy Anticoagulation therapy, unbalanced type 2 diabetes, instable HTA Motor loss &lt; 4 (muscular testing) Sphincter disorder (cauda equida syndrome)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Epidural infiltration of Corticoids</keyword>
	<keyword>L3-L4 stage</keyword>
	<keyword>On contact of disco radicular conflict</keyword>
	<keyword>Scan control</keyword>
</DOC>