<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01358292</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Multicentre Prospective Randomized Clinical Trial, to evaluate patients after surgery for extra-articular tibial fractures treated with Smith&amp; Nephew's Trigen META intramedullary nailing system; comparing two surgical techniques: Group A=standard technique(90ยบ of knee flexion) and Group B=with the semi-extended surgical technique. (2*100 patients) Research Objectives: The primary research objectives are to evaluate: i) anterior knee pain and ii) the nail position and overall fracture alignment Outcome Measures: 1. Nail positioning by means of intra-operative fluoroscopy and post operative x-rays. 2. Anterior Knee pain by means of VAS-scores, a Kneeling test and Subjective outcomes by means of Patient questionnaires 3. Knee-related adverse events 4. Overall fracture alignment</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Study of Surgical Technique in Intramedullary Tibia Nailing, Using Trigen META Tibia Nails</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After surgery with standard intramedullary nailing technique in tibia fractures, 40-80% of the patients still complain of anterior knee pain postoperative. The expected advantages of the semi-extended nailing technique is less anterior knee pain and less malunion of the fracture. Using the semi-extended nailing technique also might give the advantage of better position of the nail by a more concentric reaming of the tibia, due to less tension on the patella tendon during reaming process.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tibial Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient has sustained a closed (Tscherne Classification) or open tibial fracture (GustilloAnderson Classification) that is amendable for operative fixation with an intramedullary nail. Patient has an isolated tibia and fibula fracture Skeletally mature Patients aged between/including 18 to 70 years Patient has given formal consent to be involved in the trial and has completed the study consent form Patient is likely to comply with study followup requirements Pathologic fractures Other fractures involving the same lower extremity Soft tissue injuries/problems that would prevent the surgeon from using both of the surgical techniques to insert an intramedullary nail Patient having preexisting knee joint disease causing anterior knee pain Patient likely to have problems with followup Patient unwilling to give informed consent to be included in the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Intramedullary tibia nailing</keyword>
	<keyword>Anterior Knee Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Nail positioning</keyword>
</DOC>