<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01358357</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multi-center, randomized, placebo-controlled, flexible-dose, parallel-group study designed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of lurasidone (in combination with lithium or divalproex) for the maintenance treatment of bipolar I disorder in subjects with or without rapid cycling and /or psychotic features.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bipolar Maintenance Study of Lurasidone Adjunctive to Lithium or Divalproex</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of lurasidone (in combination with lithium or divalproex) for the maintenance treatment of bipolar I disorder in subjects with or without rapid cycling and/or psychotic features.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lurasidone Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Openlabel Phase 18 years of age or older Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 4th Ed., Text Revision (DSMIVTR) diagnosis of bipolar I disorder •≥ 1 manic, mixed manic, or depressed episode in past 2 years YMRS or MADRS total score ≥ 14 if on lithium or divalproex; ≥ 18 if not on lithium or divalproex Doubleblind Phase Subjects must achieve consistent clinical stability, defined as total scores ≤ 12 on the YMRS and MADRS over at least 12 weeks, with the allowance of two excursions (YMRS and/or MADRS total scores up to 13 or 14, respectively) except during the last 4 weeks before randomization Open Label Phase Diagnosis of an Axis I or Axis II disorder, other than bipolar I disorder, that is the primary focus of treatment within 3 months of screening Subjects for whom diagnostic agreement between the Investigator and United BioSource Corporation (Boston) (UBC) cannot be reached Ultrafast rapid cycling (defined as ≥ 8 mood episodes over the previous 12month period) Subjects who test positive for drugs of abuse at screening. In the event a subject tests positive for cannabinoids (tetrahydrocannabinol), the Investigator will evaluate the subject's ability to abstain from cannabis during the study Unstable/inadequately treated medical illness The subjects answers "yes" to "Suicidal Ideation" items 4 or 5 on the CSSRS (at time of evaluation) Double Blind Phase Subjects who in the Investigator's judgment have not been compliant with study medication during the stabilization phase Subjects who have not stabilized during the openlabel phase (within 20 weeks) Subjects who test positive for drugs of abuse at doubleblind phase baseline. In the event a subject tests positive for cannabinoids (tetrahydrocannabinol), the Investigator will evaluate the subject's ability to abstain from cannabis during the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lurasidone</keyword>
	<keyword>Latuda</keyword>
	<keyword>Bipolar I</keyword>
</DOC>