<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01634568</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled study of the safety, tolerability and pharmacokinetics of single and multiple ascending oral doses of V81444 in healthy male volunteers</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Trial to Find Out V81444's Side Effects and Blood Levels in Healthy Men</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Part A - Single Ascending Dose (SAD) Double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, single ascending dose study. Each study subject will participate in a screen visit, three identical treatment periods, in each of which they will receive a single oral dose of V81444 or placebo in accord-ance with the randomisation schedule, and one post-study visit. In each treatment period, subjects will be admitted the day before dosing (Day -1) and, subject to satisfactory medical review, discharged in the morning, 4 days later (Day 4). Part B - Multiple Ascending Dose (MAD) Double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, parallel group, multiple ascending dose study Each study subject will participate in a screen visit, one treatment period in which they will receive repeated oral doses of V81444 or placebo in accordance with the randomisation schedule, and one post-study visit. In each treatment period, subjects will be admitted the day before dosing (Day -1), dosed daily on Days 1 to 14 and, subject to satisfactory medical review, will be discharged in the morning, 3 days after the final dose (Day 17).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy male volunteers: aged 18 to 45 years, in good general health as determined by medical history, physical examination and screening investigations, and taking no regular medication. Confirmation to be sought for all volunteers that their general practitioner has provided an acceptable medical history. have a history or evidence of clinically significant gastrointestinal disease, including ulcers, gastrooesophageal reflux disease or gastritis any known malformations that would make OGD difficult or unsafe(Part B only) have taken V81444 in any previous investigational study have taken any restricted concomitant medication have multiple drug allergies or be allergic to any of the components of V81444 study medication or its matching placebo or midazolam (Part B only) in the 4 calendar months before study drug administration have smoked more than 5 cigarettes per day have consumed more than 28 units of alcohol per week have donated blood or plasma in excess of 500 mL been exposed to any new investigational agent or any other adenosine A2A receptor antagonist used nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs regularly had a new tattoo or body piercing have any clinically relevant abnormal findings at screening and/or admission intend to father a child with their female partner or through sperm donation within 4 months after the last dose of study medication</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>