<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01634061</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open label study of abiraterone acetate in combination with BEZ235 and abiraterone acetate in combination with BKM120 in CRPC patients with abiraterone acetate failure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase Ib of Abiraterone Acetate Plus BEZ235 or BKM120 in Castration-resistant Prostate Cancer (CRPC) Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A dose-escalation part will first determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and/or recomended dose for expansion (RDE) of abiraterone acetate in combination with BEZ235 and abiraterone acetate in combination with BKM120 in CRPC patients with abiraterone acetate failure. Subsequently, the MTD and/or RDE of each combination will be investigated in two expansion treatment groups of CRPC patients who have failed abiraterone acetate therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abiraterone Acetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult males ≥ 18 years old Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status ≤ 2 Patient must have a castrate level of testosterone (&lt;= 50 ng/dL or 1.7 nmol/L). ( Castrate status must be maintained by continued GnRH analogues unless patient has undergone surgical orchiectomy). Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of advanced or metastatic prostate cancer. Advanced or metastatic castrationresistant prostate cancer progression after abiraterone acetate failure Patients should have no more than 2 lines of prior chemotherapies including cytotoxic agents Discontinuation of all antiandrogen, antineoplastic or investigational treatment &gt;= 4 weeks (6 weeks for bicalutamide). Previous treatment with PI3K pathway inhibitors (e.g. PI3K, AKT, mTOR inhibitor), ketoconazole, CYP17 inhibitors (exception of AA), or enzalutamide. Patient has active uncontrolled or symptomatic CNS metastases Inadequately controlled hypertension (e.g. systolic blood pressure &gt;=160 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;=95 mmHg) Patient has a QTcF &gt; 480 msec on the screening ECG (using the QTcF formula), has a short/long QT syndrome, or history of QT prolongation/Torsades de Pointes Patient has impairment of gastrointestinal (GI) function or GI disease that may significantly alter the absorption of study drugs Patient has a medically documented history of or active major depressive episode, bipolar disorder (I or II), obsessivecompulsive disorder, schizophrenia, a history of suicidal attempt or ideation, or homicidal ideation (e.g. risk of doing harm to self or others) Patients who experienced dose reductions and/or treatment interruptions due to abiraterone acetate related toxicities (i.e. serious AEs, AEs, liver toxicities during abiraterone acetate treatment</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Castration-resistant prostate cancer, abiraterone acetate, BEZ235, BKM120, dose escalation, abiraterone acetate failure</keyword>
</DOC>