<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00779129</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Women with metastatic breast cancer are usually treated with anthracyclines (ie, doxorubicin or epirubicin) but cardiac toxicity limits their use. The aim of this study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of Caelyx in combination with cyclophosphamide in women with metastatic breast cancer who have received adjuvant anthracyclines with or without a taxane.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate Safety and Efficacy of Caelyx in Combination With Cyclophosphamide in the Treatment of Metastatic Breast Cancer (P02948)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female, aged &gt;=18 years. Subject must have histologic diagnosis of breast carcinoma. Subject must have documented measurable metastatic breast cancer by appropriate radiologic imaging. Subject must have previous anthracyclinbased adjuvant regimen and diseasefree status for at least one year following the completion of adjuvant therapy. Subject must have ECOG performance status 0, 1, or 2. Subject must have life expectancy &gt; 6 months Subject must have left ventricular ejection fraction &gt;=55% as determined by MUGA scan. Subject must have normal organ function, except if abnormal due to tumor involvement: Adequate bone marrow function (platelets &gt;=100 X 10^9/L, hemoglobin &gt;=90 g/L, Neutrophils &gt;=1.5 X 10^9/L) Adequate renal function (serum creatinine &lt; 2 X the upper limit of normal (ULN) Adequate liver function (bilirubin &lt; 2 times ULN, AST or ALT &lt; 2 times ULN in the absence of liver metastasis, AST or ALT &lt; 5 times ULN in the presence of liver metastasis. Women of childbearing potential must be using adequate contraception and have a negative pregnancy test at the time of enrollment. Subject must be able to understand and give informed consent. Age &gt; 75 years old. Subject who is pregnant or breastfeeding or is unwilling to use adequate contraception. Subject who has had a previous chemotherapy for metastatic disease. Subject who has history of cardiac disease, with New York Heart Association Class II or greater with congestive heart failure. Subject who has clinically significant hepatic disease in regard to Hepatitis B, Hepatitis C, cirrhosis, or other liver diseases unrelated to the underlying metastatic breast cancer. Subject who has uncontrolled bacterial, viral, or fungal infection. Subject who exhibits confusion or disorientation. Subject with any condition which would prevent adequate followup. Subject who has received radiotherapy in the last 4 weeks. Subject with any other active primary tumor under treatment, except basal cell carcinoma of the skin, or carcinoma in situ of the cervix. Subject who has brain metastasis. Subject who is not able to give informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>