<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01751230</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to help women lose the weight they gained during their pregnancy using a SmartPhone app the investigators have developed called E-Moms. The investigators hypothesize that the moms given the app to use during the study will lose more weight than the moms who do not use the app.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Personalized Telehealth Intervention for Health and Weight Loss in Postpartum Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The E-Moms Study will last about 4 months. The weight management program is 4 months long and will end about 6 months after the participant's baby is born. All participants will receive Women, Infants and Children (WIC) services. For the weight management program, participants will be put into one of these groups: 1. WIC Moms: receive advice and services for nutrition and weight management after pregnancy from their WIC clinic. 2. WIC E-Moms: receive a personalized diet and exercise plan to help them lose the weight they gained during their pregnancy. All information will be given to them using a SmartPhone, such as an iPhone. They will also get advice and services from your WIC clinic.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Are a female who has delivered a baby within the last 2 months Are 18 years of age or older Have a body mass index ≥25 kg/m2 or &lt;40 kg/m2 Are accepted for postpregnancy WIC services Are Englishspeaking Are participating in the Nurse Family Partnership program Had multiples in your most recent pregnancy Are unwilling to be assigned at random to either of the 2 study groups Are planning to move out of the study area within the next 6 months Have a history of psychiatric conditions or chronic disease than can impact body weight, appetite, or energy intake such as HIV/AIDS, cancer, bipolar disorder or schizophrenia Currently use antipsychotic medications or have used such medications in the previous 12 months Have been diagnosis with type I diabetes Report having a heart attack, stroke, or being hospitalized or treated for chest pain Currently taking medications or supplements to aid in weight loss Have had weight loss surgery in the past year or plan to have it prior to study completion. Currently participating in another interventional study that influences weight control Currently abusing drugs or alcohol (up to 14 drinks per week allowed)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>weight loss</keyword>
</DOC>