<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02737293</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This project will evaluate the daily intake of whole eggs in the Mediterranean Diet (Med Diet). Cholesterol levels are normally related to cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk. Dietary fat and the total diet makeup are well known modifiers of CVD risk. The Med Diet has been shown to decrease blood lipids (fats) and reduce inflammation. Cholesterol intake from eggs may not be as bad as once thought and, in fact, may help to improve the blood lipid (fat) levels. This study is being done to test how the addition of eggs to a Med Diet affects blood lipids and other risk markers for CVD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Whole Egg Intake and the Mediterranean Diet</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Elevated serum cholesterol is a major contributor to cardiovascular disease (CVD), which is responsible for ~1/3 of all deaths in the US. However, about 50% of those who experience heart attacks have normal cholesterol levels. Cholesterol is carried in lipoproteins (HDL, LDL, and VLDL) and the amount in circulation is used to evaluate CVD risk. However, the particle size and density of lipoprotein subfractions may be more predictive for atherogenesis than their total levels. Dietary fatty acids are well recognized modulators of lipoproteins, and ultimately CVD risk. Saturated and trans fatty acids have a negative effect on CVD risk while poly- and monounsaturated fatty acids (PUFA, MUFA) appear to be protective. The Mediterranean Diet (Med Diet) decreases atherogenic lipoproteins and reduces systemic inflammation. It is unknown how high cholesterol intake within a Med Diet will affect these parameters, although recent evidence implies that the fatty acid content of the diet is more important than the cholesterol content. Therefore, this project will evaluate the daily inclusion of whole eggs, a high cholesterol food, in the Med Diet on lipid profiles, lipoprotein particle size and density and biomarkers of systemic inflammation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Willingness to comply with the demands of the experimental protocol Not performing vigorous exercise &gt;2 times per week BMI 2539.9 kg/m2 Nonsmoking Egg allergy Blood glucose &lt;60 or &gt;126 mg/dL at screening Plasma lipid values consistent with familial hypercholesterolemia or hypertriglyceridemia (T Chol &gt;300 mg/dL; LDL &gt;220 mg/dL; triglycerides &gt;500 mg/dL) Low Total or LDL cholesterol (T Chol &lt;150 mg/dL; LDL &lt;80 mg/dL) Uncontrolled hypertension (BP &gt; 160/100 mmHg) Prescription medications or over the counter use of lipid lowering drugs or antiinflammatory medications (steroids, NSAIDS) on a regular basis; use of omega 3 supplements, plant stanol or sterol esters History of an eating disorder Pregnancy, lactation Inability to give consent Unwillingness or inability to consume the treatment diets</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>