<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02737683</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients with indigestion were often found in gastroenterology clinic, those who about 20 % was caused by organic, while the rest of patients are showed abnormal inspection, and these are so called functional dyspepsia. Functional dyspepsia is a chronic and repeated occurrence of digestive disorders, patients often visit hospitals frequently and unable to get fully cured. Current Symptom diagnoses are based on Rome III criteria as diagnostic criteria. Although functional dyspepsia condition should combine with physical and mental treatments, due to the reasons behind the complex, there is still no effective classification could be acted in health education and drug intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Heterogeneous Distribution of Health Literacy and Emotional State on Patients With Functional Dyspepsia.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Health literacy can be defined as "ability for obtaining basic health information and understanding medical services." Within 10 years, healthy development and application of knowledge used in medical care and public health fields that have raised more attentions, many European countries set health knowledge as one of the main indicators for health care policy in the future. To promote behavior of self-care health for people, enhance the effective use of medical service , also reduce health care cost and unequally medical information. Anxiety and depression are two common reactions when it comes to negative emotional states, which related to a body and caused a vicious cycle of disease. Some patients suffer from functional dyspepsia symptoms were diagnosed with anxiety or depression symptoms often ignore body care due to lack of health literacy. The purpose of this study is to investigate the distribution of functional dyspepsia patients with health literacy and emotional status, in order to provide more effective health education mode, thereby reducing the waste of medical resources, and promote patient health.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dyspepsia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients diagnosed with functional dyspepsia , can Selfreading and the selfadministered questionnaire. Due to physical illness, cognitive ability is limited and other factors can not were completed selfadministered questionnaires.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>depression</keyword>
	<keyword>combine</keyword>
	<keyword>negative emotional states</keyword>
	<keyword>functional dyspepsia</keyword>
</DOC>