<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02766335</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II trial studies how well anti-B7H1 monoclonal antibody MEDI4736 (MEDI4736) works in treating patients with stage IV squamous cell lung cancer that has come back after previous treatment. This is a "non-match" sub-study that includes all screened patients not eligible for a biomarker-driven sub-study. Monoclonal antibodies, such as MEDI4736, may be able to shrink tumors. MEDI4736 may be effective in treating patients with squamous cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>S1400A Lung-Map: MEDI4736 as Second-Line Therapy in Treating Patients With Recurrent Stage IV Squamous Cell Lung Cancer and No Matching Biomarkers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>CO-PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the response rate (confirmed and unconfirmed, complete and partial) among patients treated with MEDI4736. II. To assess the response rate (confirmed and unconfirmed, complete and partial) among programmed death ligand 1 (PD-L1) positive patients treated with MEDI4736. SECONDARY AND EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess investigator-assessed progression-free survival (IA-PFS) among patients treated with MEDI4736. II. To assess IA-PFS among PD-L1 positive patients treated with MEDI4736. III. To assess overall survival (OS) in patients treated with MEDI4736. IV. To assess OS in PD-L1 positive patients treated with MEDI4736. V. To evaluate the frequency and severity of toxicities associated with MEDI4736. VI. To assess immune-related IA-PFS using a modified response criteria adapted for immunotherapy (immune-related response criteria [irRC]-IA-PFS) in all patients and in the subset of patients determined to be PD-L1 positive treated with MEDI4736. VII. To compare IA-PFS, irRC-IA-PFS, OS, toxicity and response rates between patients randomized to MEDI4736 versus docetaxel. TRANSLATIONAL MEDICINE OBJECTIVES: I. To identify additional predictive or prognostic tumor/blood biomarkers beyond the chosen biomarker. II. To identify potential resistance biomarkers at disease progression. III. To establish a tissue/ blood repository from patients with refractory squamous cell cancer. MEDI4736 RE-TREATMENT OBJECTIVES: I. To evaluate response rates (confirmed and unconfirmed, complete and partial responses) among patients re-treated with MEDI4736. II. To estimate median PFS from the date of re-treatment. OUTLINE (CLOSED TO ACCRUAL 12/18/2015): Patients with tumors that do not match one of the currently active drug-biomarker combinations receive anti-B7H1 monoclonal antibody MEDI4736 intravenously (IV) over 60 minutes on day 1. Courses repeat every 2 weeks for 12 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Upon evidence of progression following discontinuation of 12 months of treatment, patients may restart treatment and continue for up to 12 additional months (Arm III). ARM I: (Closed to accrual 12/2015) Patients receive anti-B7H1 monoclonal antibody MEDI4736 intravenously (IV) over 60 minutes on day 1. Treatment repeats every 14 days for 12 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. ARM II (CLOSED TO ACCRUAL 4/2015): Patients receive docetaxel IV on day 1. Courses repeat every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. (closed to accrual with Revision #2 4/22/15) ARM III: For patients assigned to Arm 1, MEDI4736: Upon evidence of progression following discontinuation of 12 months of treatment, patients may restart treatment with Arm 3, MEDI4736 for up to 12 months with the same treatment guidelines followed during the initial 12-month treatment period. Patients will only be able to restart treatment once; thus a maximum of two 12-month periods will be allowed. Patients receive anti-B7H1 monoclonal antibody MEDI4736 IV over 60 minutes on day 1. Treatment repeats every 14 days for 12 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, all patients are followed up every 6 months for the first 2 years and then at the end of the year 3 from date of sub-study/re-registration.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulin G</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must meet all SCREENING/PRESCREENING and SUBSTUDY REGISTRATION COMMON ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA as specified in S1400: Phase II/III BiomarkerDriven Master Protocol for Previously Treated Squamous Cell Lung Cancer (LungMap) Patients must have been assigned to S1400A Patients must not have any prior exposure to immunotherapy such as, but not limited to other to antiprogrammed death 1 (PD1) or antiPDL1 antibodies; prior exposure to the following is allowed: anticytotoxic T lymphocyte antigen 4 (CTLA4) antibodies, live attenuated vaccines, antiEpidermal Growth Factor Receptor (EGFR) agents and sargramostim (GMGSF) Patients must not have received nitrosoureas or mitomycinc within 42 days prior to substudy registration Patients must not have any active or prior documented autoimmune or inflammatory disease (including inflammatory bowel disease, diverticulitis with the exception of diverticulosis, celiac disease, irritable bowel disease; Wegner syndrome; Hashimoto syndrome) within 3 years prior to substudy registration; patients with vitiligo, alopecia, Grave's disease, or psoriasis requiring systemic treatment within the past 3 years are not eligible Patients must not have any history of primary immunodeficiency Patients must not have received any immunosuppressive medication within 28 days prior to substudy registration and must not be planning to receive any such agents while on protocol treatment; however, intranasal and inhaled corticosteroids or systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses not to exceed 10 mg/day of prednisone or equivalent are allowed Patients must not have any prior grade &gt;= 3 immunerelated adverse event (irAE) or any unresolved irAE &gt; grade 1 Patients must not have any history of organ transplant that requires use of immunosuppressives Patients must not have any known allergy or reaction to any component of the MEDI4736 formulation Patients must not have a known history of tuberculosis Patients must not have received a live attenuated vaccination within 28 days prior to substudy registration Patients must not have known HIV, hepatitis B or C positivity Patients must also be offered participation in banking for future use of specimens STEP 2 TO MEDI4736 RETREATMENT REGISTRATION: Patient must have progressed following 12 months of treatment with MEDI4736; patients who discontinue MEDI4736 prior to the completion of 12 months (for any reason) are not eligible; patients who have already completed two 12month periods of treatment are not eligible Patients may have measurable or nonmeasurable disease documented by computed tomography (CT) or (magnetic resonance imaging) MRI; the CT from a combined positron emission tomography (PET)/CT may be used to document only nonmeasurable disease unless it is of diagnostic quality; measurable disease must be assessed within 28 days prior to retreatment registration; pleural effusions, ascites and laboratory parameters are not acceptable as the only evidence of disease; nonmeasurable disease must be assessed within 42 days prior to retreatment registration; all disease must be assessed and documented on the Baseline Tumor Assessment Form; patients whose only measurable disease is within a previous radiation therapy port must demonstrate clearly progressive disease (in the opinion of the treating investigator) prior to RETREATMENT registration Patients must have a CT or MRI scan of the brain to evaluate for central nervous system (CNS) disease within 42 days prior to RETREATMENT registration; patient must not have leptomeningeal disease, spinal cord compression or brain metastases unless: metastases have been locally treated and have remained clinically controlled and asymptomatic for at least 14 days following treatment, AND patient has no residual neurological dysfunction and has been off corticosteroids for at least 1 day prior to RETREATMENT registration Patients must not have received any treatment after discontinuing MEDI4736 with the following exceptions; localized palliative radiation therapy is allowed for symptom management, provided and treatment is completed &gt;= 14 days prior to RETREATMENT registration; local treatment for brain metastases is allowed Patients must not have received any immunosuppressive medication within 28 days prior to RETREATMENT registration and must not be planning to receive any such agents while on protocol treatment; however, intranasal and inhaled corticosteroids or systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses not to exceed 10 mg/day of prednisone or equivalent are allowed Patients must not have any prior grade &gt;= 3 immunerelated adverse event (irAE) or any unresolved irAE &gt; grade 1 (MEDI4736 RETREATMENT) Patients must not have received a live attenuated vaccination within 28 days prior to RETREATMENT registration Patients must not have known HIV, Hepatitis B or Hepatitis C positivity Patients must not be planning to receive any concurrent chemotherapy, immunotherapy, biologic or hormonal therapy for cancer treatment; concurrent use of hormones for noncancerrelated conditions (e.g., insulin for diabetes and hormone replacement therapy) is acceptable Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1,500/mcl obtained within 28 days prior to RETREATMENT registration Platelet count &gt;= 100,000 mcl obtained within 28 days prior to RETREATMENT registration Hemoglobin &gt;= 9 g/dL obtained within 28 days prior to RETREATMENT registration Serum bilirubin =&lt; Institutional Upper Limit of Normal (IULN) within 28 days prior to RETREATMENT registration; for patients with liver metastases, bilirubin must be =&lt; 5 x IULN Either alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; 2 x IULN within 28 days prior to RETREATMENT registration (if both ALT and AST are done, both must be &lt; 2 IULN); for patients with liver metastases, either ALT or AST must be =&lt; 5 x IULN (if both ALT and AST are done, both must be =&lt; 5 x IULN) Patients must have a serum creatinine =&lt; the IULN OR measured or calculated creatinine clearance &gt;= 50 mL/min Patients must have Zubrod performance status of 01 documented within 28 days prior to RETREATMENT registration Prestudy history and physical exam must be obtained within 28 days prior to RETREATMENT registration Patients must not be pregnant or nursing; women/men of reproductive potential must have agreed to use an effective contraceptive method; a woman is considered to be of "reproductive potential" if she has had menses at any time in the preceding 12 consecutive months; in addition to routine contraceptive methods, "effective contraception" also includes heterosexual celibacy and surgery intended to prevent pregnancy (or with a sideeffect of pregnancy prevention) defined as a hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy or bilateral tubal ligation; however, if at any point a previously celibate patient chooses to become heterosexually active during the time period for use of contraceptive measures outlined in the protocol, he/she is responsible for beginning contraceptive measures As a part of the Oncology Patient Enrollment Network (OPEN) registration process the treating institution's identity is provided in order to ensure that the current (within 365 days) date of institutional review board approval for this study has been entered in the system Patients with impaired decisionmaking capacity are eligible as long as their neurological or psychological condition does not preclude their safe participation in the study (e.g., tracking pill consumption and reporting adverse events to the investigator) Patients must be informed of the investigational nature of this study and must sign and give written informed consent in accordance with institutional and federal guidelines</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>