<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02032004</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to determine whether transendocardial delivery of allogeneic human bone marrow-derived MPCs (rexlemestrocel-L) is effective in the treatment of chronic heart failure due to LV systolic dysfunction.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Allogeneic Mesenchymal Precursor Cells (Rexlemestrocel-L) for the Treatment of Heart Failure.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of a single transendocardial delivery in the cardiac catheterization laboratory of human bone marrow-derived allogeneic MPCs (rexlemestrocel-L) for improvement in clinical outcomes (HF-MACE), preventing further adverse cardiac remodeling (LVESV and LVEDV), and increasing exercise capacity (6MWT) in patients with chronic HF due to LV systolic dysfunction of either ischemic or nonischemic etiology who have received optimal medical/revascularization therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient is 18 to 80 years of age, inclusive; both men and women will be enrolled. The patient has a diagnosis of chronic HF of ischemic or nonischemic etiology for at least 6 months The patient is on stable, optimally tolerated dosages of HF therapies including betablockers (approved for countryspecific usage), angiotensinconverting enzyme (ACE) inhibitors or angiotensinreceptor blockers (ARBs), and/or aldosterone antagonists, without change in dose for at least 1 month before study intervention The patient is on a stable, outpatient, oral diuretic dosing regimen in which the patient remains clinically stable during screening. Other Criteria apply, please contact the investigator The patient has NYHA Functional Class I or Functional Class IV symptoms. Other Criteria apply, please contact the investigator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Heart Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>CHF</keyword>
	<keyword>Left Ventricular Systolic Dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Ischemic Heart Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Nonischemic Heart Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Stem Cells</keyword>
	<keyword>Allogeneic Mesenchymal Precursor Cells</keyword>
</DOC>