<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02032602</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: Non-specific shoulder pain has a high prevalence in older adults and provokes functional alterations. Besides, there are difficulties for its clinical diagnosis, lack of effectiveness in the treatment and not much evidence is found regarding invasive physical therapy techniques in this population. Purpose: To determine the efficacy of a single physical therapy intervention with deep dry needling on latent and active myofascial trigger points in older adults with non-specific shoulder pain. Methods: Pilot Study, Single Blind Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial on 60 subjects aged 65 and over, will be diagnosed with nonspecific shoulder pain. The study will be approved by the Clinical Research Ethics Committee of the area. Sample will be recruited at their home and at a care center, and randomly will be distributed in Experimental Group (n=30), which will be received a session of Deep Dry Needling on an active and a latent Myofascial Trigger Points of the infraspinatus muscle; and Control Group (n=30), receiving a session of Deep Dry Needling only on an active Myofascial Trigger Point. A blind examiner will be evaluated Pain Intensity, Pain Pressure Threshold (anterior deltoid; extensor carpi radialis brevis) and Grip Strength, before, immediately after intervention and after a week of treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dry Needling on Myofascial Trigger Points in Older Adults With Nonspecific Shoulder Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Shoulder Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>people aged 65 or over with uni or bilateral nonspecific shoulder pain and with at least one active and one latent MTrP in the infraspinatus homolateral to the painful shoulder prior diagnosis of myopathy or neuropathy; cognitive deficit in the medical record; cervical spine, rotator cuff tendons or glenohumeral joint problems in the medical record; corticoid infiltration or local anaesthetic during the previous year or during followup; surgical procedure affecting the upper limb or preceding cervical; ingestion of antiaggregant, anticoagulant, analgesic or antiinflammatory medication or abusive substances in the week prior to treatment and during followup were excluded from the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Myofascial Pain Syndromes</keyword>
	<keyword>Trigger Point</keyword>
	<keyword>Shoulder Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Aged</keyword>
</DOC>