<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01675544</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose of the study: To identify whether Electrocardiographic QRS voltage changes (between admission and pre-discharge) and pre discharge 6- minute walk test in patients admitted with acute heart failure can identify patients at risk for recurrent admissions for heart failure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PRospective Evaluation of Electrocardiographic Voltage Changes and Six Minute Walk Test for Predicting Readmissions in Heart Failure (PREEMT-HF Study)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary Objective Determine the ability of EKG voltage changes and pre discharge 6-minute walk test (6-MWT) to predict repeat heart failure hospitalization (HFH) in patients admitted with acute decompensated heart failure (ADHF). Secondary Objectives 1. Determine the ability of EKG voltage changes and pre discharge 6-MWT) to predict a composite of 1 year mortality and HFH in patients admitted with ADHF. 2. Determine the ability of proportionate pulse pressure, orthostatic blood pressure changes and pre discharge inferior vena cava (IVC) diameter by portable ultrasound to predict HFH and mortality</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients &gt; 18 years of age, admitted with a diagnosis of ADHF and fulfilling the following criteria: 1. Evidence of systemic congestion (manifested by any 2 of the following criteria: jugular venous distension, edema, pulmonary rales, Left ventricular S3, or radiographic evidence of pulmonary venous congestion) 2. Elevated Brain natriuretic peptide 3. Need for at least 1 dose of intravenous loop diuretic Cardiogenic shock, Acute coronary syndromes (patients with mild elevation in troponin related to heart failure will not be excluded), patients who are admitted for another principal problem and develop ADHF in the hospital, pregnant females, end stage renal disease on hemodialysis, expected survival &lt; 6 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Heart failure</keyword>
</DOC>