<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01607112</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the immunogenicity and safety of GSK Biologicals' trivalent influenza vaccine manufactured for the 2012/2013 influenza season administered in adults (18 to 60 years) and in elderly (over 60 years).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study for Evaluation of Immunogenicity and Reactogenicity of Fluarix/Influsplit SSW 2012/2013 in People Aged 18 Years and Above</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Subjects who the investigator believes can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol. A male or female aged 18 years or above at the time of vaccination. Written informed consent obtained from the subject. Healthy subjects or subjects with wellcontrolled chronic diseases as established by medical history and clinical examination before entering the study. Female subjects of nonchildbearing potential may be enrolled in the study. Female subjects of childbearing potential may be enrolled in the study, if the subject: has practiced adequate contraception for 30 days prior to vaccination, and has a negative pregnancy test on the day of vaccination, and has agreed to continue adequate contraception during the entire treatment period and for 2 months after completion of vaccination. Use of any investigational or nonregistered product other than the study vaccine within 30 days preceding the dose of study vaccine, or planned use during the study period. Chronic administration of immunosuppressants or other immunemodifying drugs within the six months prior to vaccination. Inhaled and topical steroids are allowed. Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within the three months preceding the administration of the study vaccine or planned administration during the study period. Administration of an influenza vaccine within the six months preceding the study vaccination. Planned administration/ administration of a vaccine other than the study vaccine within 30 days before study vaccination and during the entire study period. Clinically or virologically confirmed influenza infection within the six months preceding the study vaccination. Acute disease and/or fever at the time of enrolment. Acute, clinically significant pulmonary, cardiovascular, hepatic or renal functional abnormality, as determined by physical examination or laboratory screening tests. Chronic underlying disease, not stabilized or clinically serious. History of chronic alcohol consumption and/or drug abuse. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, based on medical history and physical examination. History of GuillainBarré syndrome. History of allergic disease or reactions likely to be exacerbated by any component of the vaccine. Anaphylaxis following the administration of vaccine(s). Pregnant or lactating female. Female planning to become pregnant or planning to discontinue contraceptive precautions. Any condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, prevents the subject from participating in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Influenza</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunogenicity</keyword>
	<keyword>Elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Adults</keyword>
</DOC>