<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02706548</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Many persons with chronic health conditions fail to take their medications as prescribed, resulting in declines in health and function. Unfortunately, current interventions for medication nonadherence are not very effective. This objective of this study is to test a new intervention, the Integrative Medication Self-management (IMedS) intervention to improve medication adherence in adults with chronic health conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Feasibility of the Integrative Medication Self-Management Intervention to Promote Medication Adherence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Many persons with chronic health conditions fail to take their medications as prescribed, resulting in declines in health and function. Objective: The purpose of this study was to perform a phase I feasibility study to understand if an integrated occupational therapy intervention could help people with chronic health conditions improve their adherence to medications. Method: Using a small-N design, we report single-subject analyses of the medication adherence, behavior counts, and perceptions of medication adherence of participants before and after either an occupational therapy intervention or standard of care intervention. We used a multiple baseline approach with inter-subject replication, and blinding.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosed with a chronic health condition Live in the community A medication regimen of 5 or more medications a day recommended by a health care professional Independently manage medications Difficulty taking medications as prescribed Live in the Milwaukee area Significant cognitive impairment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>occupational therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>medication adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>intervention studies</keyword>
</DOC>