<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02706483</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Multi-center, open-label, long-term safety study</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long Term Safety Study of Plecanatide</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase 3, multicenter, open-label, long-term safety and tolerability study of 6 mg daily dose of plecanatide administered orally. Patients who are Study Completers or Eligible Screen Failures whose eligibility is confirmed at the end of their participation in the double-blind plecanatide studies SP304203-04 or SP304203-05 will be enrolled. Beginning on Day 1, patients will take one (1) plecanatide 6.0 mg tablet in the clinic and thereafter every morning with approximately 240 mL (8 ounces) of liquid, with or without meals. Safety and tolerability assessments and patients' self-assessment of disease severity will be performed according to the Schedule of Assessments. Patients who discontinue early from the study will undergo an Early Withdrawal (EW) visit within 5 days after stopping study drug.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with documented diagnosis of IBSC who: Completed plecanatide study SP30420304 or SP30420305, were compliant with the previous study's requirements, and did not experience any Serious Adverse Event (SAE) deemed related to study drug during the course of the previous study, OR Failed screening in study SP30420304 or SP30420305 due to diary noncompliance (an exclusion in the core study) or due to an administrative reason and is allowed to enter this study by notification from Sponsor or delegate. Key Patient is unwilling or unable to: participate in the study for the required duration, understand and sign the informed consent form (ICF) and undergo all protocol related tests and procedures throughout the study. Female patient of childbearing potential with a positive urine pregnancy test on Day 1. Male and female patients of childbearing potential who do not agree to continue to use the method of birth control used in the core doubleblind plecanatide study for the duration of this clinical trial. Patient has experienced a significant negative change in health status during the course of participation in the core doubleblind plecanatide study or after completion of the study. In the opinion of the Investigator or Medical Monitor, it is not in the patient's best interest to participate in the study. The reason(s) for the patient's exclusion must be specified.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>