<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00290251</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate whether the experimental drug ulipristal acetate can shrink uterine fibroids in pre-menopausal women.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Uterine Fibroids With the Selective Progesterone Receptor Modulator CDB-2914</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Uterine leiomyomata (fibroids) are a common benign tumor of the uterine muscle in pre-menopausal women that may cause bleeding, pelvic pain and pressure. Because fibroids grow in the presence of estrogen, medical therapies that decrease estrogen levels (like Gonadotropin releasing hormone,GnRH analog) cause fibroids to shrink and so may relieve symptoms. However, such medication can only be given short-term and has inconvenient side effects such as hot-flashes. Thus, many women with symptomatic fibroids choose to have them removed surgically, either individually or by removing the uterus via hysterectomy. Women between 25 and 50 years of age who have regular menstrual cycles and a history of uterine fibroids that cause heavy bleeding, pressure, or pain may be eligible for this study. Candidates are screened with a medical history and physical examination, including breast and pelvic examination, blood and urine tests, a quality-of-life questionnaire, and a home urine test for leuteinizing hormone (LH) surge. They are given a diary to record the LH surge, days of vaginal spotting or bleeding, and symptoms. Participation includes the following: Baseline Studies (First Menstrual Cycle) - Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI): The subject lies in the MRI scanner, a narrow cylinder with a strong magnetic field, for imaging the uterus. - Saline hysterosonogram: This is an ultrasound examination of the uterus. A speculum is placed in the vagina and a small amount of liquid is inserted into the uterus. A probe is then inserted into the vagina. The probe emits and receives sound waves that are used to visualize the fibroids and surrounding structures. Study Drug Phase (Second through Fourth Menstrual Cycles) - Subjects are randomly assigned to take ulipristal acetate or placebo (inactive compound) once a day by mouth on an empty stomach for three menstrual cycles or up to 102 days if menstrual cycles are irregular or stop. - Pregnancy test on first or second day of every menstrual cycle. - Blood tests every 2 weeks to measure effects of study medication on hormones, blood count, blood chemistries and liver function. - 24-hour urine collections three times during the study, about once a month, to measure cortisol and check adrenal gland function. - Repeat transvaginal ultrasound after 4-6 weeks of study drug to check fibroid growth. - Repeat hysterosonogram and MRI within 2 weeks of surgery to count and measure the fibroids. or placebo (inactive compound) once a day by mouth on an empty stomach for three menstrual cycles or up to 102 days if menstrual cycles are irregular or stop. - Pregnancy test on first or second day of every menstrual cycle. - Blood tests every 2 weeks to measure effects of study medication on hormones, blood count, blood chemistries and liver function. - 24-hour urine collections three times during the study, about once a month, to measure cortisol and check adrenal gland function. - Repeat transvaginal ultrasound after 4-6 weeks of study drug to check fibroid growth. - Repeat hysterosonogram and MRI within 2 weeks of surgery to count and measure the fibroids. or placebo (inactive compound) once a day by mouth on an empty stomach for three menstrual cycles or up to 102 days if menstrual cycles are irregular or stop. - Pregnancy test on first or second day of every menstrual cycle. - Blood tests every 2 weeks to measure effects of study medication on hormones, blood count, blood chemistries and liver function. - 24-hour urine collections three times during the study, about once a month, to measure cortisol and check adrenal gland function. - Repeat transvaginal ultrasound after 4-6 weeks of study drug to check fibroid growth. - Repeat hysterosonogram and MRI within 2 weeks of surgery to count and measure the fibroids.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leiomyoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myofibroma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Progesterone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Female genderto evaluate effects in the target population for clinical trials. History of uterine leiomyoma causing symptoms of bleeding, pressure, or pain, as defined by the American College of Obstetrics and Gynecology (ACOG) practice bulletin: Excessive uterine bleeding will be evidenced by either of the followingprofuse bleeding with flooding or clots or repetitive periods lasting for more than 8 days; or anemia due to acute or chronic blood loss; OR Pelvic discomfort caused by leiomyomata, either acute and severe or chronic lower abdominal or low back pressure or bladder pressure with urinary frequency not due to urinary tract infection. Uterine leiomyoma(ta) of at least 2 cm size. In good health. Chronic medication use is acceptable except for glucocorticoid use. Other chronic medication use may be acceptable at the discretion of the research team. Interval use of overthecounter drugs is acceptable but must be recorded. Menstrual cycles of 24 35 days. Hemoglobin greater than 10 g/dL (for those wishing surgery); iron may be administered to improve red blood cell counts. Willing and able to comply with study requirements. Age 25 to 50. Using mechanical (condoms, diaphragms) sterilization or abstinence methods of contraception for the duration of the study. Negative urine pregnancy test. Body mass index (BMI) less than or equal to 33, if a surgical candidate or less than or equal to 35, if not a surgical candidate. Creatinine less than 1.3 mg/dL. Liver function tests within 130% of upper limit. If interested in hysterectomy, no desire for fertility. EXCLUSION CRITERIA: Significant abnormalities in the history, physical or laboratory examination. Pregnancy. Lactation. Use of oral, injectable or inhaled glucocorticoids or megestrol within the last year. Unexplained vaginal bleeding. History of malignancy within the past 5 years. Use of estrogen or progesteronecontaining compounds, such as oral contraceptives and hormone replacement therapy, within 8 weeks of study entry, including transdermal, injectable, vaginal and oral preparations. Use of agents known to induce hepatic P450 enzymes; use of imidazoles. Current use of Gonadotropinreleasing hormone (GnRH) analogs or other compounds that affect menstrual cyclicity. Follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) greater than 20 IU/mL. Untreated cervical dysplasia. Need for interval use of narcotics. Abnormal adnexal/ovarian mass. Use of herbal medication having estrogenic or antiestrogenic effects within the past 3 months. Contradiction to anesthesia, for women planning surgery. Genetic causes of leiomyomata. Previous participation in the study. Known recent rapid growth of fibroids, defined as a doubling in size in six months.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Endometrium</keyword>
	<keyword>Progesterone</keyword>
	<keyword>Estrogen</keyword>
	<keyword>Fibroid</keyword>
	<keyword>Hysterectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>Leiomyoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Uterine Fibroids</keyword>
	<keyword>Fibroids</keyword>
</DOC>