<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00290056</DOC>
	<brief_summary>We hypothesize that oral supplementation with omega-3 PUFA will decrease occurrence of arrhythmic events among post-MI, ICD recipients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Supplemental Intake of Omega-3 Polyunsaturated Fatty Acids on the Rate and Complexity of Spontaneously Occurring Ventricular and Supraventricular Arrhythmias in Patients With Implantable Cardioverter Defibrillator (ICD) - A Randomized Clinical Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, crossover, double- blind interventional study. Patients will receive 3.6 g of EPA and DHA fish oil and placebo oil for 6 months, randomly, in a crossover design, with a four month washout period between treatments. Randomization will be stratified by ejection fraction (≤ 35% or &gt; 35%), and the type of the index arrhythmia (VT - spontaneous or inducible by electrophysiologic study (EPS), versus other - VF, SCD, Primary prevention - MADIT II). Ischemia severity was chosen to be evaluated by Single Photon Emission Computed Tomography (SPECT) during stress (dipyridamol infusion). Subcutaneous adipose-tissue biopsy, a biomarker considered the gold-standard for the objective assessment of long-term habitual dietary intake of fish and marine omega-3 PUFA (EPA and DHA) will be obtain. Compliance will be monitored by counting returned capsules or bottles and by measuring the omega-3 PUFA composition in red blood cells (RBC). Three different types of questionnaires will be used in this trial to obtain more information as to the additional potential benefit of omega-3 PUFA supplementation: 1. The newly Israeli Food Frequency Questionnaire (FFQ) will be used to examine dietary intake of other nutritional habits/patterns and its relationship to the study outcomes. 2. The Hebrew language SF-36 health survey will be used to examine general health status. 3. The Back questionnaires will be use to examine possible beneficial effects of fish oil supplementation on depressive symptomatology.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>postMI patients. Both single and Dual chamber ICD recipient. implanted more than 3 months ago. Agree to give written informed consent. Less than 18 years of age. ICD implantation as a `bridge` to heart transplantation. Stable antiarrhythmic medication over the last month prior to enrollment. Patients taking class I antiarrhythmic medication. A projected lifespan less than one year. Participation in another trial (during or within 90 days before the study). Use of supplemental n3 fatty acids during the last 3 months. Women who are pregnant and of childbearing potential who do not use adequate contraception. Patients known to have a history of recent drug or alcohol abuse. 10) History or current intestinal or hepatic disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>CHD</keyword>
	<keyword>Arrhythmia</keyword>
	<keyword>ICD</keyword>
	<keyword>Omega-3 PUFA</keyword>
	<keyword>Nutrition</keyword>
</DOC>