<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01146574</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is the first study in hemodialysis subjects with anemia to evaluate the pharmacokinetics, safety, efficacy, tolerability, and pharmacodynamics of sotatercept (ACE-011)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 2a Study To Evaluate The Pharmacokinetics, Safety, Efficacy, Tolerability, And Pharmacodynamics of Sotatercept (ACE-011) for the Correction of Anemia in Subjects With End-stage Renal Disease on Hemodialysis.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Part 1: Approximately 8 subjects will be randomized to receive either a single 0.1 mg/kg subcutaneous dose of sotatercept or matching placebo in a 3:1 ratio Part 2: Approximately 8 subjects will be randomized to each of the 3 sequential dose groups (0.3mg/kg or 0.5mg/kg or 0.7 mg/kg) with a 3:1 ratio of sotatercept or placebo (6 subjects in the sotatercept arm and 2 in the placebo arm). A total of 24-36 subjects may be randomized in the 3 dose groups.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males or females ≥18 years of age. Subjects on hemodialysis for at least 12 weeks before screening Subjects on a stable dose of Erythrocyte Stimulating Agents product to maintain Hemoglobin (Hb) for at least 6 weeks prior to screening. 3 consecutive predialysis Hb concentrations with a mean ≥10 to ≤ 12 g/dL (≥100 to ≤120 g/L) at screening and one predialysis Hb concentration ≥8 to &lt; 10 g/dL (≥ 80 to &lt; 100 g/L) before randomization. Adequate iron status defined as serum transferrin saturation ≥ 20% before randomization. Non renal causes of anemia. Subjects on peritoneal dialysis. Systemic hematological disease High sensitivity Creactive protein &gt;50mg/L at screening. Alanine transaminase (ALT) or aspartate transaminase (AST) laboratory values &gt; 2 times the upper limit of normal (ULN) at screening. Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus (HbA1c &gt; 9) at screening. Uncontrolled hypertension. Red Blood Count (RBC) transfusions within 8 weeks prior to screening. Active serious infection or history of recurrent serious infection likely to recur during the study History of severe allergic or anaphylactic reactions or hypersensitivity to recombinant proteins or excipients in the investigational product or to the iron products needed to normalize iron levels for subjects. Subjects that received treatment with another investigational drug or device within 28 days prior to Day 1 Pregnant or lactating females.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>End-Stage Renal Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemodialysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>ESRD</keyword>
</DOC>