<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02960594</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase I, open label study to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and immunogenicity of INO-1400 alone or in combination with INO-9012, delivered by electroporation in subjects with high-risk solid tumor cancer with no evidence of disease after surgery and standard therapy. Subjects will be enrolled into one of six treatment arms. Subjects will be assessed according to standard of care. Restaging and imaging studies will be performed to assess disease relapse per NCCN guidelines. RECIST will be used to validate the findings in cases of relapse.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>hTERT Immunotherapy Alone or in Combination With IL-12 DNA Followed by Electroporation in Adults With Solid Tumors at High Risk of Relapse</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interleukin-12</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Signed and dated written IRB approved informed consent; 2. Males or females aged ≥18 years; 3. Subjects with breast, lung or pancreatic carcinoma who are at high risk of relapse post definitive therapy at least 4 and no more than 24 weeks from completion of definitive therapy at the time of signing informed consent as described below for each indication: Breast carcinoma: Lung carcinoma: Pancreatic carcinoma: Head and neck squamous cell carcinoma: Ovarian cancer: Colorectal cancer Gastric and esophageal cancer Hepatocellular carcinoma 1. Previous treatment wth any TERT or IL12 containing therapy, or any other DNA immunotherapy; 2. Any concurrent condition requiring the continued or anticipated use of systemic steroids (excluding nonsystemic inhaled, topical skin and/or eye dropcontaining corticosteroids) or immunosuppressive therapy (excludes low dose methotrexate). All other systemic corticosteroids must be discontinued at least 4 weeks prior to first Study Treatment; 3. Administration of any vaccine within 4 weeks of the first study treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Human Telomerase Reverse Transcriptase (hTERT)</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Lung Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Pancreatic Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>High Risk of Relapse</keyword>
	<keyword>Post Definitive Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Post Adjuvant Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>No Evidence of Disease</keyword>
</DOC>