<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03069326</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test any good and bad effects of the study drugs called ruxolitinib and thalidomide. Ruxolitinib and thalidomide could shrink the cancer, but it could also cause side effects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Study to Test the Effects of Ruxolitinib And Thalidomide Combination for Patients With Myelofibrosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Primary Myelofibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thalidomide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of myelofibrosis (either primary or post essential thrombocythemia/polycythemia vera) requiring therapy, including those previously treated and relapsed or refractory, or if newly diagnosed, with intermediate1 or 2 or high risk according to International Working Group (IWG) criteria. Patients taking ruxolitinib at the time of enrollment must have been taking ruxolitinib for a minimum of 3 months, and must have been on a stable dose of ruxolitinib for a minimum of 4 weeks immediately prior to enrollment. Patients taking ruxolitinib at the time of enrollment must be deemed to have had a suboptimal response (less than partial response per IWG criteria) to ruxolitinib singleagent therapy or deemed to have progression of disease (per IWG criteria). Age ≥ 18 years at the time of signing the informed consent. ECOG performance status 0 to 2. Patients must have adequate organ function as demonstrated by the following: 1. Direct bilirubin &lt; 2.0 mg/dL, unless due to Gilbert's disease 2. Serum creatinine &lt; 2.0 mg/dL. 3. ALT and AST ≤ 3 x upper limit of normal (unless the transaminitis is considered to be related to MF Females of childbearing potential (FCBP)† must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test with a sensitivity of at least 50 mIU/mL within 14 days prior to and again within 24 hours* of starting thalidomide and must either commit to continued abstinence from heterosexual intercourse or begin TWO acceptable methods of birth control, one highly effective method and one additional effective method AT THE SAME TIME, at least 4 weeks before she starts taking thalidomide. FCBP must also agree to ongoing pregnancy testing. Men must agree to use a condom during sexual contact with a female of child bearing potential even if they have had a successful vasectomy. All patients must be counseled at a minimum of every 28 days about pregnancy precautions and risks of fetal exposure. All study participants must be registered into the mandatory REMS® program, and be willing and able to comply with the requirements of REMS® Platelets ≥ 50000/uL and ANC ≥ 1000 All study participants must be able to swallow oral medication Use of any other standard antineoplastic drug or growth factor (e.g., anagrelide, GCSF, revlimid, clofarabine) except hydroxyurea or experimental drugs, with the exception of Ruxolitinib, less than 14 days or 5half lives prior to starting study therapy and/or lack of recovery from all toxicity from previous therapy to grade 1 or better. Known prior clinically relevant hypersensitivity reaction to thalidomide, including the development of erythema nodosum if characterized by a desquamating rash. Prior therapy with thalidomide in combination with ruxolitinib Any serious medical condition, laboratory abnormality, or psychiatric illness that would prevent the subject from signing the informed consent form, which places the subject at unacceptable risk if he/she were to participate in the study or which confounds the ability to interpret data from the study. Lactating females. Known positive for HIV or hepatitis B or C per institutional standard of care Participants with prior history of thromboembolic disease (i.e. deep venous thrombosis (DVT) or pulmonary embolism (PE) within the last six months, as thalidomide has demonstrated an increased risk of DVT or PE Known to have a hypercoagulability syndrome (e.g.: antithrombin III, deficiency, anticardiolipin syndrome etc). Concurrent use of strong inducers or strong inhibitors of CYP3A4 (strong inducers are rifampin and St. John's Wort, carbamazepine, phenytoin, and barbiturates such as phenobarbital; strong inhibitors are HIVantivirals, clarithromycin, itraconazole, ketoconazole, nefadozone and telithromycin). Concurrent use of strong inducers or strong inhibitors of CYP3A4 (strong inducers are rifampin and St. John's Wort, carbamazepine, phenytoin, and barbiturates such as phenobarbital; strong inhibitors are HIVantivirals, clarithromycin, itraconazole, ketoconazole, nefadozone and telithromycin).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ruxolitinib</keyword>
	<keyword>Thalidomide</keyword>
	<keyword>16-1498</keyword>
</DOC>