<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03069703</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study hypothesis is that a "reinforced" pneumococcal combined vaccine strategy in patients with ANCRA-associated vasculitides treated with rituximab will induce a better immune response than the current standard regimen, with an acceptable safety profile. This study therefore aims at evaluating the immunogenicity and safety of two "reinforced" innovative pneumococcal vaccine regimen [a double or a quadruple dose of 13-valent anti-pneumococcal conjugate vaccine (PCV13) followed by one dose of 23-valent unconjugated vaccine (PPV23) at month 5], compared to the standard regimen (one dose of PCV13 followed by one dose of PPV23 at month 5), in patients with ANCA-associated vasculitides receiving rituximab therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Innovative Anti-pneumococcal Vaccine Strategies in Patients With ANCA-associated Vasculitis Receiving Rituximab Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Description of research methodology Experimental plan This is a comparative, multicenter, prospective, randomized, open label, phase 2 trial in France, comparing two innovative "reinforced" anti-pneumococcal vaccine strategies to standard vaccination regimen in patients with ANCA-associated vasculitides receiving rituximab therapy. Participants will be randomized 1:1:1 to three parallel arms to receive: - Arm 1 (standard vaccination regimen): prime-boost strategy combining a single dose of 13-valent pneumococcal conjugate vaccine (Prevenar, PCV13) at Day 0 (lying within a window of ± 2 days of the first infusion of rituximab), followed by a single dose of 23-valent unconjugated vaccine (Pneumo 23, PPV23) at month 5 (M5) - Arm 2 (innovative vaccine strategy 1): prime-boost strategy combining 2 doses of PCV13 at Day 0 and 2 doses of PCV13 at Day 7, followed by a single dose of PPV23 at M5 - Arm 3 (innovative vaccine strategy 2): prime-boost strategy combining 4 doses of PCV13 at Day 0, followed by a single dose of PPV23 at M5 All participants will receive rituximab at 375 mg/m2/week for 4 consecutive weeks, at Days 0 ± 2 days, Day 7 ± 2 days, Day 14 ± 2 days and Day 21 ± 2 days, as induction therapy of vasculitis flare, followed by 500 mg-rituximab infusion every 6 months as maintenance therapy, i.e. at Month 6, Month 12 and Month 18 (Stone, NEJM, 2010, Jones, NEJM, 2010; Guillevin, NEJM, 2014), as recommended. Day 0 will be defined as the first vaccine injection (within ± 2 days of the first infusion of rituximab). PCV13 vaccine injections will be performed at Day 0, and at Day 7 ± 1 day in the Arm 2. PPV23 injections will be performed at M5 ± 7 days in all arms. Analysis of immune responses will be performed in a centralized laboratory blinded for the trial arm, by ELISA at Day 0 (pre-vaccination sample), M1, M5, M6, M12, and M18 for the 12 serotypes common to both conjugate and unconjugated vaccines, by OPA at Day 0, M6, M12, and M18 for the 12 serotypes common to both conjugate and unconjugated vaccines, and by ELISA at Day 0 and M6 for the 3 specific serotypes of PPV23. Safety monitoring Relevant adverse events related to vaccination will be continuously monitored throughout the trial, and pausing rules have been specified in the protocol that trigger an ad-hoc iDSMB meeting in case of any safety concern Number of participating centres This multicenter research will involve the participation of the French Vasculitis Study Group (FVSG) network, which includes more than 100 clinical departments involved in the management of ANCA-associated vasculitides. As previous trials conducted by the FVSG on this topic, around 50 centers will participate in the PNEUMOVAS research. Randomization Participants who fulfill all eligibility criteria for the study will be enrolled and randomized in a ratio of 1:1:1 between the three different parallel arms. Randomization will be stratified on: personal history of PPV23 injection and age (&gt; or &lt; 65 years). Blinding methods and provisions put in place to maintain blinding Trial participants and site staff are not blinded to the vaccine arm. The central laboratory performing the immunogenicity assessment (ELISA and OPA) will be blinded for the trial arm in order to limit measurement bias.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vasculitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumococcal Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Neutrophil Cytoplasmic Antibody-Associated Vasculitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heptavalent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Participants with a diagnosis of ANCAassociated vasculitis, in particular GPA and MPA, according to ACR 1990 criteria and/or revised Chapel Hill Consensus Conference definitions and/or European Medical Agency algorithm 2. Participants (males and females) aged of 18 years or older 3. Participants with childbearing potential having reliable contraception for the all duration of the study 4. Participants with newlydiagnosed disease at the time of inclusion or presenting with a relapse of the disease. For relapsing patients, maintenance therapy at stable dose during the last 3 months will be admitted : prednisone dose &lt;10 mg/day, azathioprine dose &lt;3 mg/kg/day, methotrexate dose &lt;25 mg/week, or mycophenolate mofetil dose &lt;3 g/j 5. Participants with an active disease defined as a BVAS ≥ 3 6. Participants planned to receive rituximab as induction therapy using the recommended regimen (i.e. 375 mg/m2/week for 4 consecutive weeks) 7. Participants able to give written informed consent prior to participation in the study 8. Participants covered by social security regimen or equivalent 1. Participants with eosinophilic granulomatosis with polyangiitis or other vasculitis 2. Participants having thrombocytopenia or other coagulation disorders 3. Participants with acute infections or chronic active infections at inclusion visit. 4. Documented positive serology result for HIV, HBV (Ag Hbs), HCV at inclusion. 5. Participants with disease associated with decreased immune response (splenectomy, hematopoietic stem cell transplantation, primary immune deficiency such as common variable immunodeficiency, cancer within the previous 5 years, drepanocytosis), 6. Participants treated with rituximab within the previous 12 months, 7. Participants who have received blood, blood products, and/or plasma derivatives including parenteral immunoglobulin preparations in the past 12 weeks before enrolment, 8. Participants treated with new other immunosuppressive or immunomodulatory agents within the previous 3 months (including cyclophosphamide, antiTNFalpha, intravenous immunoglobulins, abatacept), 9. Participants treated with prednisone dose &gt;10 mg/day for a duration greater than 15 days before inclusion, 10. Participants with vaccination with a conjugate antipneumococcal vaccine at any time, 11. Participants with vaccination with PPV23 within the previous 3 years, 12. Participants who have received any another vaccines within 4 weeks prior to enrolment or who are planning to receive any vaccine within the first 6 months of the study (except annual influenza vaccination which is permitted 4 weeks before and after each vaccination visit of the study and then allowed at any time during the study follow up) 13. Pregnant women and lactation, 14. Participants with contraindication to use rituximab, 15. Participants with contraindication to intramuscular injections (hemophilia, anticoagulant therapy) 16. Participants with hypersensitivity to previous vaccination 17. Participants with hypersensitivity to aluminium phosphate, phenol or protein CRM197 protein from Corynebacterium diphtheria. 18. Participants included in another investigational therapeutic study in the month prior D0. Participation to an observational research is allowed. 19. Participants under legal guardianship or incapacitation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>ANCA- associated vasculitides</keyword>
	<keyword>pneumo 23</keyword>
	<keyword>prevenar</keyword>
	<keyword>pneumovas</keyword>
</DOC>