<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03069573</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out some potential biomarkers for the Eosinophilic Esophagitis (EoE) in pediatric patients through the prospective clinical characterization and assessment of samples collected during the diagnostic process</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phenotypic Characterization and Biomarkers Investigation for Eosinophilic Esophagitis in Pediatric Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study collects clinical information from pediatric patients between 0-18 years old who have been undergoing upper gastrointestinal endoscopy due to general complaints. The demographic, clinical symptoms, endoscopy, pH monitoring, and histology data are assessed during the diagnostic process. In the baseline endoscopy procedure samples (blood, saliva, esophageal tissue, and esophageal mucus) are taken. After diagnostic process of EoE and Gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD) supported by International Guidelines the patients are divided into three groups - EoE, GERD, and Control. The techniques are used for patients characterization and assessment: 1. Symptoms score: General symptom score and/or Pediatric Eosinophilic Esophagitis Symptom Score (PEESS v2.0) - translated and adapted version for Brazilian Portuguese 2. Endoscopic Score: Eosinophilic Esophagitis (EoE) Endoscopic Reference Score (EREFS) 3. Peak eosinophil count (PEC) and histological features description 4. Proteomic analyses 5. Microbiome analyses 6. Immunohistochemistry analyses</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Gastroesophageal Reflux</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophagitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eosinophilic Esophagitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pediatric patients who are undergoing upper gastrointestinal endoscopy for diagnostic purpose Pediatric patients who are undergoing upper gastrointestinal endoscopy for therapeutic procedures The presence of other eosinophilic diseases Patients have been taken corticosteroids and/or gastric acid secretion inhibition drugs for the last four weeks</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Eosinophilic Esophagitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Gastroesophageal Reflux</keyword>
	<keyword>Diagnose</keyword>
	<keyword>Biomarker</keyword>
</DOC>