<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01149486</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The object of this study was to compare the relative bioavailability (rate and extent of absorption) of 100/25 mg Losartan potassium/Hydrochlorothiazide Tablets manufactured by Teva Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd. and distributed by Teva Pharmaceuticals USA with that of Hyzaar® 100/25 mg Tablets distributed by Merck &amp; Co., Inc. following a single oral dose (1 x 100/25 mg tablet) in healthy adult subjects administered under fasting conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Losartan Potassium/Hydrochlorothiazide 100/25 mg Tablets in Healthy Subjects Under Fasting Conditions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Criteria for Evaluation: FDA Bioequivalence Criteria Statistical Methods: FDA Bioequivalence Statistical Methods</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hydrochlorothiazide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Losartan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy men and women, 1845 years of age (inclusive). Body mass index should be less than or equal to 30 Screening procedures completed within 28 days prior to dosing. If female and: of child bearing potential, is practicing an acceptable barrier method of birth control for the duration of the study is postmenopausal for at least 1 year is surgically sterile (bilateral tubal ligation, bilateral oophorectomy, or hysterectomy) Subjects with a recent history of drug or alcohol abuse or addiction. Subjects with the presence of a clinically significant disorder involving the cardiovascular, respiratory, renal, gastrointestinal, immunologic, hematologic, endocrine, or neurologic system(s) or psychiatric disease (as determined by the clinical investigators). Subjects whose clinical laboratory test values the accepted reference range and when confirmed on reexamination are deemed to be clinically significant. Subjects demonstrating a positive hepatitis B surface antigen screen, a positive hepatitis C antibody screen, or a reactive HIV antibody screen. Subjects demonstrating a positive drug abuse screen when screened for the study. Female subjects demonstrating a positive pregnancy screen. Female subjects who are currently breastfeeding. Subjects who have used implanted or injected hormonal contraceptives anytime during the 180 days prior to study dosing or hormonal contraceptives within 14 days of dosing will not be allowed to participate. Subjects with a history of allergic response(s) to losartan, hydrochlorothiazide or related drugs. Subjects with a history of clinically significant allergies including drug allergies. Subjects with a clinically significant illness during the 4 weeks prior to dosing (as determined by the clinical investigators). Subjects who have taken any drug known to induce or inhibit hepatic drug metabolism in the 28 days prior to dosing. Subjects who have used tobacco products within 90 days of Period 1 dose administration. Subjects who report donating greater than 150 mL of blood within 14 days prior to dosing. Subjects who report receiving any investigational drug within 28 days prior to dosing. Subjects who report taking any systemic prescription medication in the 14 days prior to dosing. Subjects who report an intolerance of direct venipuncture. Subjects who report consuming an abnormal diet within the 28 days prior to dosing.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bioequivalence</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy Subjects</keyword>
</DOC>