<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03017469</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Nurses are exposed to myriad stressors, both in the workplace and in their everyday lives, which can lead to adverse personal and professional outcomes. While workplace stress cannot be eliminated, nurses can learn techniques to build resilience, mitigate stress, and decrease fatigue. Organizational employee health, wellness, and assistance programs are all intentioned to provide this type of support; however, nurses often lack awareness of options and opportunities, and access can be a challenge. The purpose of the proposed study is to assess the outcomes of a multi-modal intervention and toolkit, ARISE, designed to enhance resilience and promote awareness of organizational resources for health, wellness, and employee assistance. We will evaluate the impact of participation in ARISE on resilience and other outcomes in nurses in critical care and trauma settings. As a Best Practice Spotlight Organization designated by the Registered Nurses Association of Ontario (RNAO), this project will incorporate relevant recommendations from Best Practice Guidelines (BPG) related to Workplace Health, Safety, and Well-being of the Nurse; and Preventing and Mitigating Nurse Fatigue in Health Care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Achieving Resilience in Acute Care Nurses (ARISE).</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress, Psychological</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Compassion Fatigue</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Nurse in the medicalsurgical and traumaneurosurgical intensive care units (MSICU and TNICU) and the medical/surgical floor (9CCN), fulltime or parttime employment status, approval of clinical leader manager (CLM), receipt of written informed consent. Exclusion Crieria: casual employment status inability to attend intervention days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Resilience</keyword>
	<keyword>Workplace Stress</keyword>
	<keyword>Occupational Fatigue</keyword>
	<keyword>Compassion Fatigue</keyword>
	<keyword>Peer Support</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Employee Assistance</keyword>
</DOC>