<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02370992</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Low dose rate brachytherapy using iodine 125 is well established as a treatment for low and intermediate risk prostate cancer. Currently there is uncertainty as to the safety of this technique in patients who have had a previous transurethral resection of the prostate gland (TURP) for obstruction of the urine flow through the prostatic urethra. Early experience when the technique was being developed in the 1980s suggested that there was a higher incidence of urinary incontinence after brachytherapy if there had been a previous TURP. It is however clear that with increasing experience many centres offer this treatment to patients who have had previous TURP, using various parameters to select patients including time from the TURP and persence or absence of a significant cavity within the gland on MRI scanning. There has been no systematic study of I125 brachytherapy after TURP in the current era which might address and inform the practice for future patient. Hence this study is designed to formally assess the safety of I125 brachytherapy after previous TURP.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>I125 Brachytherapy After TURP</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>WHO performance status 01 No contraindication for anaesthesia No history of irradiation of the pelvis No other oncologic malignancy except adequately treated basal cell carcinoma of the skin or other malignancy from which the patient is disease free for at least 5 years. Absence of any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially hampering compliance with the study protocol and followup schedule; Prostate (cancer) related: Histologically proven prostate cancer (adenocarcinoma) of low or intermediate risk following the D'Amico classification. Prostate volume &lt; 50 cc as measured on transrectal ultrasound Neoadjuvant antiandrogen hormonal treatment is permitted to downsize the prostate volume or to cover waiting time till brachytherapy procedure. No adjuvant hormonal treatment is permitted. History of TransUrethral Resection of the prostate (TURp), performed at least 3 months before the brachytherapy procedure. Rim of prostate tissue of at least 1 cm around the postTURp urethral defect at theposterolateral sides of the prostate Absence of significant TURpinduced urinary incontinence IPSS &lt;15 Locally advanced (stage T3 or T4 , or metastatic (stage N+ or M+) prostate cancer High grade tumours defined by Gleason score 8 or above Comorbidity which would exclude the patient from a transperineal implant procedure. Unable to give informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>