<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02370121</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Gymnema sylvestre has demonstrated promising effects in the treatment of obesity, dyslipidemia, hypertension, insulin secretion, among others. The above mentioned findings show that Gymnema sylvestre has an excellent potential for the prevention and treatment of metabolic syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Gymnema Sylvestre on Metabolic Syndrome and Insulin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial was carried out in 24 patients with a diagnosis of metabolic syndrome in accordance with the modify International Diabetes Federation criteria. The patients received 300 mg capsules of Gymnema sylvestre or placebo, two times daily before breakfast and dinner for 90 days. Before and after intervention the investigators evaluated: The components of metabolic syndrome (waist circumference, triglycerides, high-density lipoprotein, fasting glucose and blood pressure), body weight, body mass index, total cholesterol, low-density lipoprotein, very-low-density lipoprotein, creatinine, aspartate transaminase and alanine transaminase. Were calculated: Areas under the curve of glucose and insulin were calculated with de Trapezoidal formula. Total insulin secretion was evaluated with the Insulinogenic index and the insulin sensitivity was estimated using the Matsuda index.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Letter of consent and release signed by each patient Body mass index: 2534.99 kg/m2 Body weight without variations above or under 5% during the three months prior to the study Diagnostic of metabolic syndrome according to the modified International Diabetes Federation definition: Central obesity (defined as waist circumference ≥ 80 cm in women and ≥ 90 cm in men) Plus any two of the following four factors: Triglycerides: 150499 mg/dL. High density lipoprotein: Woman &lt; 50 mg/dL, man &lt; 40 mg/dL. Blood pressure systolic:130139 mmHg and/or Blood pressure diastolic: 8589 mmHg Fasting glucose: 100125 mg/dL Type 1 or 2 diabetes mellitus Previous pharmacological treatment for components of metabolic syndrome Mental or physical illness interfering with the study Thyroid or cardiovascular disease Pregnant or suspected pregnant women Woman breastfeeding Index of body mass: ≥ 35 kg/m2 Treatments known to affect metabolism of glucose, fats and affecting arterial tension Patients with hepatic or renal diseases background Patients diagnosed with kidneys disease Calcined magnesium intolerance Gymnema Sylvestre intolerance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gymnema Sylvestre</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin Secretion</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin Sensitivity</keyword>
	<keyword>Central Obesity</keyword>
</DOC>