<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01119677</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized, 3-arm, dose-blinded, parallel-group study. Subjects will be randomized to one of 3 treatment titration regimes (slow titration over 6 weeks, fast titration over 3 weeks, and no titration).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Avonex® to Determine the Effects of Dose Titration on the Incidence of Flu Like Symptoms in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Interferon beta-1a</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must be healthy males or females aged 18 to 55 years old at the time of informed consent. Must have a Body Mass Index of 19 to 30 kg/m2, and a minimum body weight of 50.0 kg at Screening. Female subjects of childbearing potential must practice effective contraception during the study and be willing and able to continue contraception for 30 days after their last dose of study treatment. Known history of or positive test result for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis C virus (test for hepatitis C virus antibody [HCV Ab]) or hepatitis B virus (test for hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg] and hepatitis B core antibody [HBcAb]) Known history of chronic fatigue syndrome or fibromyalgia Within one month, flulike illnesses (e.g., gastroenteritis, upper respiratory infection, common cold) History of severe allergic reactions to any drug or anaphylactic reactions Known allergy to Avonex or any of its components Serious infection (e.g., pneumonia, septicemia) within the 3 months prior to Screening or active bacterial or viral infection History of alcohol or substance abuse (as defined by the Investigator) Female subjects who are pregnant or currently breastfeeding Any previous treatment with any interferon product.10. Vaccinations within 2 weeks or 5 halflives, whichever is longer, prior to Day 1 Blood donation within 30 days prior to Screening Use of any tobacco product more than 5 times within 30 days prior to Screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>