<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01119053</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this monocentre two-armed double blind randomised placebo-controlled study - in which the control group obtains the VNS therapy within a defined space of time after 12 weeks - the impact of vagus nerve stimulation on depressive symptomatology of patients with therapy-resistant depressive personality disorders shall be analysed. Particularly in comorbid disorders, medicamentous treatment shows exceedingly bad response rates. Against the background of hitherto insufficient treatment strategies for chronic or persistent depression with comorbidities, the proceeding of a study on the effects of VNS on depressive patients with comorbid disorders is absolutely essential.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Vagus Nerve Stimulation (VNS) as a Treatment of Persistent Depression With Comorbid Personality Disorders (Impulse-VNS</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Personality Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria embedding criteria according to "VNS manual for doctors" diagnosis of a recurrent depressive disorder (based on ICD10 criteria) and a comorbid personality disorder (according to SKID I/II) with an ailment period of more than six months age 1880 years verbal IQ (WST) 85 points HAMD sum score &gt; 20 points at least four depressive episodes in the anamnesis no amelioration of current depressive episodes under two different antidepressants in appropriate dosage for six weeks constant medication within the last two weeks (at the discretion of the supervising doctor) written consent after informing the patient about the study no VNS treatment to date no misuse of illegal drugs or alcohol Women in childbearing age are not permitted to participate in the study if a doctor has asserted the nonexistence of pregnancy before the beginning of the study. Furthermore, the procedure of a pregnancy test is recommended after the completion of the study. During the study, a reliable type of contraception (such as the Pill) should be taken. The doctor provides further information. Exclusion criteria according to "VNS manual for the doctor" present hospitalisation according to the federal states' PsychKG clinically relevant unstable bodily concomitant diseases former VNS treatment reduction of intelligence with verbal IQ &lt; 85 (WST) conceivable use of an MRT examination after the implantation of the VNSsystem for diagnostic examinations with the dTMS and the MRT: electric devices (such as cardiac pacemakers, medicine pumps etc.) or pieces of metal (ferromagnetic, e.g. screws after bone fractures) within or at the body, or largescale tattoos conditions that do not allow to use VNS, such as relevant dysfunctions of the heart's stimulus conduction system or cardiac arrhythmia, stomach ulcer, dysphagia, palsy of parts of the nvagus nerve insufficient knowledge of the German language pregnancy or lactation current misuse of substances</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>VNS</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Personality-Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Stimulation</keyword>
</DOC>