<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01782781</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to evaluate traditional analgesic therapy after abdominal hysterectomy with single infiltration of local anesthetics in the surgical area at the end of surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Local Infiltration Analgesia After Abdominal Hysterectomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is a controlled, double blind, prospective, randomized and performed at Sahlgrenska University Hospital in Goteborg, Sweden. The injectant mixture consists of 300 mg ropivacaine mixed with 30 mg ketorolac and 0.5 mg epinephrine. Total volume of the solution is 156 ml. The normal saline injection is used in the control group in the same manner as in the LIA group. The parameters which would be evaluated are consumption of morphine, pain intensity and side effects. The primary objective is to evaluate whether local infiltration analgesia (LIA) into the operating field will reduce morphine consumption during the first 24 postoperative hours in patients undergoing abdominal hysterectomy (AH). Secondary end-points are pain intensity, incidence of nausea and vomiting, sedation intensity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketorolac</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Analgesics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epinephrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Racepinephrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epinephryl borate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients requiring abdominal hysterectomy Body mass index &gt; 35 American Society of Anesthesiologists classification &gt; 3 Renal dysfunction Allergic to acetylsalicylic acid Unwilling to provide informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Analgesia</keyword>
	<keyword>Local infiltration analgesia</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain, relief</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain, Postoperative</keyword>
	<keyword>Ropivacaine</keyword>
	<keyword>Ketorolac</keyword>
	<keyword>Epinephrine</keyword>
	<keyword>Adrenergic Agonists</keyword>
	<keyword>Sympathomimetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Therapeutic Uses</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</keyword>
	<keyword>Analgesics, Non-Narcotic</keyword>
	<keyword>Analgesics</keyword>
	<keyword>Opioids</keyword>
	<keyword>Morphine</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Postoperative Complications</keyword>
	<keyword>Physiological Effects of Drugs</keyword>
	<keyword>Anesthetics, Local</keyword>
	<keyword>Anesthetics</keyword>
</DOC>