<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01782989</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective, randomized study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of ORACEA® in the treatment of geographic atrophy due to dry age-related macular degeneration (AMD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Study to Evaluate Treatment With ORACEA® for Geographic Atrophy (TOGA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Eligible participants will complete a 6-month Observation Phase, followed by a 24-month Treatment Phase, followed by an End of Study Visit. Eligible participants will be randomized at Month 6 in a 1:1 ratio to either ORACEA (40 mg doxycycline) or placebo capsule to be taken once-daily for 24 months. Over the course of the 31-month study, a total of 9 clinic visits and 3 telephone calls are required.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Geographic Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxycycline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female, age &gt;/=55 years Best corrected visual acuity of 20/20 20/400 in the study eye Best corrected visual acuity of hand motion or better in the nonstudy eye Clinical diagnosis of geographic atrophy secondary to nonexudative agerelated macular degeneration in at least one eye (study eye) Geographic atrophy lesions of ≥ 0.5 and ≤ 7.0 MPS disc areas History of or active presence of choroidal neovascularization secondary to exudative agerelated macular degeneration in the study eye History of or active presence of choroidal neovascularization secondary to exudative agerelated macular degeneration in the nonstudy eye requiring any treatment within 12 months prior to Day 0 or expected to require treatment for the duration of the study Prior treatment for nonexudative agerelated macular degeneration Current or previous history of treatment of the study eye with any tetracycline derivative for any ocular condition. History of vitreoretinal surgery, corneal transplant, or laser photocoagulation in the study eye Any intraocular or periocular surgery within 90 days prior to Day 0 in the study eye. History of any hypersensitivity to tetracycline components Use of a tetracycline derivative therapy for a concurrent systemic or ocular disorder within 90 days of Day 0 History of sensitivity to the sun</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>geographic atrophy</keyword>
	<keyword>non-exudative age-related macular degeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>macular degeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>dry macular degeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>dry AMD</keyword>
</DOC>