<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00885690</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cognition is one of the core symptoms of schizophrenia. This study is a head-to-head trial between olanzapine and sertindole with cognition as primary outcome. The design is a 12-week double-blinded randomized controlled flexible dose study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparing the Effects of Sertindole and Olanzapine on Cognition (SEROLA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Olanzapine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sertindole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>AnICD10 schizophrenia diagnosis F20.0F20.9. Contraception. A negative pregnancy test for women. No known allergy to any of the substances in the study medication Baseline QTc &lt; 450 milliseconds for men and &lt; 470 milliseconds for women Spotassium and smagnesium within normal reference range. Suboptimally treated on current antipsychotic medication Stable dosage of antidepressants and mood stabilizers one month before the inclusion Signed informed consent and power of attorney Withdrawal of consent QTc prolongation &gt;500 milliseconds during the study Patients with known clinical important cardiovascular disease Significant substance abuse Earlier partial or nonresponse in treatment or intolerability to sertindole or olanzapine. Calgary Depression Scale score ≥ 7 Treatment that interferes with the metabolism of sertindole or olanzapine, Oxazepam, zopiclone or zolpidem treatment the last 48 hours before cognitive testing Prescription of notallowed medication, or a change in dosage of antidepressant, or mood stabilizers in the study period Treatment with an anticholinergic after the first three weeks of the study Somatic illness, as judged by investigator, interfering with cognition Known risk of narrow angle glaucoma Treatment with electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) the last three months before inclusion, or treatment with ECT in the study period Treatment with clozapine or depot antipsychotics before inclusion</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Antipsychotic</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognition</keyword>
</DOC>