<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01565863</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test the effectiveness of the Progressive Goal Attainment Program (PGAP) in improving employment outcomes and community engagement among U.S. veterans with disabilities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Progressive Goal Attainment Program for Veterans</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Veterans with disabilities often have low self-esteem and motivation, significant depression and a belief that their disability precludes them from gainful employment. The Progressive Goal Attainment Program (PGAP) is specifically designed to target these psycho-social risk factors of disability. PGAP is a structured, 10-week intervention that focuses on helping clients develop a planned activity schedule to assist them in resuming desirable life activities, including employment. The PGAP for Veterans Project will test the feasibility of delivering PGAP to U.S. military veterans. The research will focus on the best means of service delivery, staffing needs and how to coordinate PGAP in a larger veteran service system. MDRC will also gather information on the target population, recruitment methods, the feasibility of scaling and replication, and employment outcomes among the sample. Two hundred veterans will be enrolled and randomly assigned into the study across two sites: Errera Community Care Center within (part of the VA Connecticut Health Care System) and the Michael DeBakey VA Medical Center in Houston, Texas.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Selfreporting a disability. Unemployed or underemployed. Likely to benefit from PGAP (i.e. unengaged in social and community activities, difficulty attaining work due to motivational factors). Does not consent to be in the study. Significant barriers: serious substance abuse, significant psychotic disorders and cognitive disabilities that would preclude them from active participation in PGAP.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Perceived Disability</keyword>
	<keyword>Mental Wellness</keyword>
	<keyword>Employment</keyword>
	<keyword>Social Integration and Engagement</keyword>
	<keyword>Goal Achievement</keyword>
</DOC>