<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01226537</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Diabetes mellitus (DM) and its vascular complications are the one of the most prevalent diseases in the state of Qatar. It is a multifactorial disease associated with the development of retinopathy, nephropathy, neuropathy, cardiomyopathy, and severe vascular dysfunction. The complications of diabetes are caused by either insulin deficiency (type 1 DM) or insulin resistance (type II DM).Unfortunately, effective and sustainable prevention programs of diabetes are limited, and treatment options for type II DM are restricted. Current therapy is based upon control of blood glucose, cholesterol and triglycerides, primarily through insulin replacement in type I diabetes or oral hypoglycemic agents and/or insulin replacement in type II diabetes. New therapies able to prevent vascular complications of diabetes are needed to decrease the occurrence of end organ damage and improve the quality of life of the people. Safe and effective nutritional supplements that could be given along with the regular treatment of the patients that might reduce the need for insulin replacement therapy provide tighter glucose control and protect against oxidative stress and the vascular pathology associated with diabetes mellitus are the need of the hour. Our hypothesis is that supplementation of Taurine in the diets of diabetic patients might reduce the dose or need for insulin replacement therapy and protect them against oxidative stress that is responsible for the complications of diabetes mellitus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Taurine on Glycemic Control in Type I and Type II Diabetic Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperglycemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or Female 2. Above 1865 Years of old 3. Known diabetic patients with HbA1c&gt;8.0% 4. People who provide signed informed consent 1. Pregnancy 2. Diabetic patients with HbA1c &lt;8.0 % 3. Recent or prospective surgical interventions 4. Complications of Type I and Type II DM, e.g., Active cardiovascular disease, nephropathy, retinopathy, neuropathy 5. People who do not provide signed informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Taurine,Diabetes mellitus,oxidative stress,glycemic control</keyword>
</DOC>