<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00859456</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the clinical response rate (complete response and partial response) in patients with metastatic, locally advanced, or locally recurrent vascular soft tissue sarcoma treated with sunitinib.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sunitinib in Soft Tissue Sarcoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase II, open label, nonrandomized single institution study to determine efficacy and toxicity of sunitinib in certain subtypes of soft tissue sarcomas. Patients are stratified according to sarcoma histology (angiosarcoma vs. hemangioendothelioma vs. Kaposi's sarcoma). The purpose of this study is to determine the clinical response rate (complete response and partial response) in patients with metastatic, locally advanced, or locally recurrent vascular soft tissue sarcoma treated with sunitinib. Secondary objectives will be to 1) To determine 3 month and 6 month progression free survival, defined as patients that are alive and without evidence of progression of disease on reassessment of disease after while being treated; 2) To determine overall survival of patients treated with this regimen; 3) To determine safety and tolerability of sunitinib in this patient population.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sunitinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histopathologicallyproven diagnosis of angiosarcoma, epithelioid sarcomalike hemangioendothelioma or Kaposi's sarcoma. Both HIVRelated and HIVUnrelated Kaposi's patients will be included in the trial. Patients with HIVRelated Kaposi's will be required to have a CD4 count &gt;50 cells/µL and Viral Load &lt; 50 copies/ml. They will also need to be willing to take HAART. They can either have stable Kaposi's on HAART for at least 3 months or have progression of their Kaposi's after having been on HAART for at least 10 weeks. Not amenable to surgery, radiation, or combined modality treatment with curative intent. Evidence of unidimensionally measurable disease by conventional radiographic techniques. In patients with Kaposi's sarcoma, skin lesions at least 10 mm will be considered measurable disease. Bone lesions, ascities, or lymphangitis of skin or lung are not considered measurable. No more than 2 prior chemotherapy regimens for metastatic or unresectable disease. Patients may have received prior bevacizamab or other Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitors, excluding sunitinib. Treatment with bevacizamab or other Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitors will not be counted as prior chemotherapy regimens. Four weeks since prior chemotherapy, surgery or radiation therapy and resolution of all toxic effects of any prior therapy, surgical procedure or radiation. ECOG performance status 02. Age 18 or greater. Patients with a "currently active" second malignancy other than nonmelanoma skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix are not to be registered. Patients who are not considered to have a "currently active" malignancy if they have completed therapy and are considered by their physician to be at less than 30% risk of relapse. No areas of measurable disease by CT or MRI. Any of the following within the 6 months prior to study drug administration: myocardial infarction, severe/unstable angina, coronary/peripheral artery bypass graft, symptomatic congestive heart failure, or cerebrovascular accident. or transient ischemic attack, or pulmonary embolism. Ongoing cardiac dysrhythmias, atrial fibrillation or prolongation of the QTc interval to &gt;450 msec for males of &gt; 470 msec for females. Medications that may prolong the QT intervals should be discontinued or switched to another medication prior to starting Sutent unless determined by the investigator to be absolutely necessary. Pregnancy or breastfeeding. Other severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory abnormality that may increase the risk associated with the study participation or study drug administration. Major surgery or radiation therapy within 4 weeks of starting the study treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>