<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02386774</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In vivo confocal microscopy (IVCM) used in tertiary care ophthalmology centers is performed with two reflectance microscopes attached on a mounting with limited movement along the XYZ axes. Consequently, ocular diseases in the central area have been described (mostly cornea and adjacent conjunctiva). Two dermatology IVCM (an handheld small IVCM and a multifluorescent one) present significant innovations that the investigators want to assess in ophthalmology for the diagnosis of conjunctiva, cornea, eyelid and lachrymal tract diseases. The handheld IVCM have unlimited degrees of freedom and a small diameter objective. It could dramatically increase the area accessible to IVCM (whole conjunctiva, eyelids, proximal lachrymal tract) (part 1 of the present study). The fluorescent IVCM allows the use of a wide range of fluorescent markers liable to increase the specificity of the diagnosis by revealing staining patterns corresponding to a specific disease and not to others (part 2 of the study)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Innovative Imaging of the Conjunctiva, Cornea, and Ocular Adnexa</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Blepharitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Corneal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lacrimal Apparatus Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tetrahydrozoline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Benoxinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Procaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Presenting with an ocular or ocular adnexa disease (infectious keratitis, stromal dystrophy, corneal surgery, ocular surface toxicity of eyedrops, corneaconjunctival tumors, chronic blepharitis, eyelid tumors, diseases of the proximal lachrymal tract). For the microangiography: diabetic patients Allergy to one of the 3 dyes (fluorescein, indocyanine green, rose Bengal) Pregnancy and breast feeding Predicable impossible follow up For patient volunteer for intravenous injections: beta blockers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>In vivo confocal microscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>corneal disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Blepharitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Lacrimal Apparatus Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Microscopy, Confocal</keyword>
</DOC>