<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00691613</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Rationale: The investigators hypothesize that EPO protects against apoptosis after acute ischemia in man and that it is detectable using the annexin-A5 model. Objective: Does infusion of a single dose of Epoetin Alfa, a short-acting EPO, protect against apoptosis in man after acute ischemia? Study design: A double blinded randomised cross-over study. Study population: 12 Healthy male volunteers, between 18 and 40 years old. Intervention: All 12 volunteers will receive a single dose of EPO and placebo in a randomized order. A six week wash-out period is obtained in order to avoid interference of both treatments. Main study parameters/endpoints: The percentage of difference between radioactivity (quantified as counts per pixel) of the experimental and control thenar muscle at one and four hours after reperfusion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Infusion of a Single Dose of Erythropoietin to Prevent Injury in an Ischemia Reperfusion Forearm Model</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Reperfusion Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy volunteers between 18 and 40 years of age male Volunteers are not allowed smoking 24 hours before the start of the experiment Female Hypertension (SBP &gt;140 mmHg, DBP &gt;90 mmHg) Diabetes Mellitus (DM) (fasting glc &gt;6.9 mmol/l, glc &gt;11.0 mmol/l) Hypercholesterolemia Renal dysfunction (eGFR &lt; 60 ml/min, calculated using MDRD formula) Any known hypersensitivity/allergic reaction to one of the constituents of Epoetin Alfa A history of use of any form of EPO Any current medication use Cardiovascular disease in medical history Smoking less than 24 hours prior to Epoetin alpha infusion Participation in research in the last 5 years in which any form of radioactivity was used No participation in any research trial in the last 30 days or 5 times the halflife of the used substance</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Apoptosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Annexin</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypoxia</keyword>
	<keyword>Ischemia-Reperfusion Injury</keyword>
</DOC>