<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02074423</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate the effect of MealShape, a Ceylon cinnamon extract (Cinnamomum zeylanicum) on blood glucose and insulin response after consumption of a standard meal composed of white bread, in healthy male and female volunteers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Human Clinical Trial Evaluating the Effect of MealShape™ on Blood Glucose Level Following Consumption of Standard Meal</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Healthy male and female volunteers, able to read and write, aged from 18 to 45 years inclusive at time of screening Good physical condition Body Mass Index (BMI) ≥ 18,5 and &lt; 25 kg/m² Written informed consent provided prior to screening, after receiving and understanding the subject information Stable body weight (&lt; 5% variation) within the last 3 months prior to screening. Subject accepting to keep the same lifestyle throughout the study regarding physical activity, no smoking etc. Registered with the French Social Security, in agreement with the French law on biomedical experimentation. Subject with type 1 or 2 diabetes Smoker. Light smoker (less than 5 cigarettes per day) or former smoker (smoking more than 5 cigarettes per day) having stopped less than three months. Smoking (or use of smoking substitute e.g. nicotine patch) is not permitted from screening throughout the study. Subject with fasting capillary blood glucose level &gt; 110 mg/dl. Subject with fasting capillary blood glucose level ≤ 110 mg/dl and 2 hours postprandial capillary blood glucose level &gt; 140 mg/dl during an Oral Glucose Tolerance Test. Subject with any sensitivity or allergy to any of the products used within this clinical trial. Intake of product (food and dietary supplement) having an effect on glycemia and insulinemia. Intake of all chronic medication excepted oestroprogestative or progestative contraception started at least three months preceding the screening visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cinnamon extract</keyword>
	<keyword>Postprandial glycemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Glycemic index</keyword>
	<keyword>Pre-diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>