<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02074579</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to assess the effect of orally administered TU-100 (5 g three times daily [TID]) as compared to placebo on abdominal bloating rating in female IBS patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Safety and Efficacy Study of Daikenchuto (TU-100) to Relieve Abdominal Bloating in Female Subjects With Irritable Bowel Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Meet Rome III criteria for IBS (any subtype) Female aged 18 to 65 years, inclusive If of childbearing potential, prepared to use suitable forms of contraception throughout the study and for 30 days after the last dose i.e., hormonal contraceptives (such as oral contraceptives, DepoProvera, NuvaRing, Essure), condoms used with a spermicide, an intrauterine device, or abstinence. Females are not considered to be of childbearing potential if they are naturally postmenopausal (no menses for at least 1 year and, if &lt; 55 years of age, have a documented folliclestimulating hormone [FSH] level of ≥ 35 mIU/mL) or have documentation of surgical sterility Have a BMI between 18 and 30 kg/m2, inclusive Have a negative pregnancy urine screening at Visit 1, if of childbearing potential Able to provide written consent Able to take oral administration of the testing medications Have a selfreported average abdominal bloating rating (&gt;3 daily ratings over the preceding 7 days) equal or greater than 4 on a numerical scale of 0 to 20. Have a structural or metabolic disease or condition that affects the GI system, excluding asymptomatic gallstones or uncomplicated gastroesophageal reflux disease, or any medical condition that may be a cause of constipation or diarrhea (e.g., hypothyroid status, poorly controlled diabetes, diabetic neuropathy or autonomic neuropathy) Be taking any medication that, in the opinion of the Principle Investigator (PI), has potential to alter GI transit. A full list of prohibited medications is provided in the protocol. Have history or presence of any chronic lung disease Have presence of hepatic dysfunction, jaundice, or abnormal serum alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) values exceeding 2.5 x upper limit of normal Currently pregnant or lactating Have a positive urine drug test at screening (subjects who initially test positive will be allowed one retest) Be a known substance abuser or be considered to be an alcoholic not in remission Have participated in another clinical study in the past 30 days Use of supplemental ginger, ginseng, or Zanthoxylum fruit for 2 weeks prior to randomization and throughout the course of the study. Have a history of allergic reaction to ginseng, ginger or Zanthoxylum fruit Be clinically lactoseintolerant Have any other condition that, in the opinion of the PI, causes the subject to be unsuitable to participate Have taken antibiotics in the last 3 months Have had gastroenteritis ("stomach flu") in the last 3 months Have taken probiotics in the last 3 months (overthecounter [OTC] products or supplements only; food products such as yogurts are permitted).</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Rome III criteria</keyword>
	<keyword>abdominal bloating</keyword>
	<keyword>natural</keyword>
	<keyword>herbal</keyword>
	<keyword>Kampo</keyword>
	<keyword>Adult ages 18 to 65</keyword>
	<keyword>Female subjects</keyword>
</DOC>