<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02809183</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-design, 6-arm, fixed dose study. The study will enroll approximately 130 adult male and female subjects with Stage 3 or 4 chronic kidney disease and low serum bicarbonate levels. The study will be conducted in two parts. In Part 1 study drug dosing (TRC101 or placebo) will continue for 14 days twice daily. In Part 2 study drug dosing (TRC101 or placebo) will continue for 14 days once daily. The maximum study duration is anticipated to be up to 42 days.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of TRC101 in Subjects With Chronic Kidney Disease and Metabolic Acidosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acidosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) of 20 to &lt;60 mL/min/1.73m2 Serum bicarbonate level of 12 to 20 mEq/L Any level of low serum bicarbonate that, in the opinion of the Investigator, requires emergency intervention. Severe comorbid conditions other than chronic kidney disease. Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Anticipated changes in doses of any of the following drugs or drug classes: diuretics, nonophthalmic carbonic anhydrase inhibitors, oral diabetes drugs, antihypertensive drugs, antacids, H2blockers, or proton pump inhibitors. Excluded drugs or drug classes: insulin, nondaily or "as needed" diuretics, herbal products, dietary supplements, multivitamins, naturopathic remedies, sodium bicarbonate, potassium citrate, sodium citrate or other alkali therapy, nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), fiber supplements, laxatives, calcium and magnesium supplements, or electrolyte binders and other binder drugs.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>metabolic acidosis</keyword>
	<keyword>serum bicarbonate</keyword>
	<keyword>kidney disease</keyword>
</DOC>