<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02809508</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of FiSK Junior is to investigate whether intake of oily fish compared to poultry affects cardiovascular risk markers, cognitive function, and behaviour in healthy children.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Oily Fish and Poultry on Children's Cardiometabolic Health and Cognitive Function</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The FiSK Junior study compares the effects of consuming oily fish versus poultry (control) in healthy 8-9 year-old Danish children. The children will be randomized to consume approximately 300 g/week of either oily fish or poultry for 12 weeks. Measurements and biological sampling will be performed at baseline and at the end of the intervention. The main objective of the study is to investigate the effect on cardiovascular risk markers, primarily blood pressure and plasma triacylglycerol. Moreover, the effects on cognitive function, behaviour, emotions and physiological stress response will be assessed. In addition, change in n-3 long chain polyunsaturated fatty acid status (compliance), anthropometry, body composition, vitamin D status, inflammatory markers, growth markers, physical activity and diet will be measured. Outcomes will be analysed with focus on potential gender- and genotype-specific effects.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Children must: Be 8 9 years of age at the start of the intervention Be healthy Like oily fish and chicken Be willing to be randomized to eat fish or chicken Not consume oily fish more than once per week 3 months prior to intervention start Not consume fish oil 3 months prior to intervention start Speak Danish in order to understand the study procedures Moreover: Parents must read and speak Danish, in order to be properly informed about the study procedures The child must live in a household with ≤5 persons Serious chronic illnesses and diseases that may interfere with study outcomes Diagnosed ADHD or other psychiatric illness Intake of medication that may affect study outcomes Concomitant participation in other studies involving dietary supplements or blood sampling Living in a household with another participating child</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>9 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Omega-3</keyword>
	<keyword>Child nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>Dietary recommendations</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular risk markers</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive function</keyword>
	<keyword>Mental health</keyword>
</DOC>