<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4715">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03045549</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RCT-THR-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03045549</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SWORD Phoenix Versus Standard of Care in the Rehabilitation After Total Hip Replacement</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Home-based Rehabilitation With SWORD Phoenix Versus Standard of Care After Total Hip Replacement: a Pragmatic Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sword Health, SA</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital da Prelada</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sword Health, SA</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study was designed to evaluate the effectiveness of a novel kinematic biofeedback system
      - SWORD Phoenix- in the rehabilitation after total hip replacement . SWORD Phoenix allows
      the patients to perform independent rehabilitation sessions at home, under remote monitoring
      from the clinical team. The investigators hypothesise that the clinical outcomes of a
      home-based rehabilitation program will be at least similar to the outcomes of a traditional
      home-based rehabilitation with face-to-face sessions. This is a randomised controlled trial
      with active comparator. Patients will be enrolled and allocated pre-operatively into 2
      groups: intervention group and control group. Both groups will perform 8 weeks of
      rehabilitation starting on day 7 after surgery. The intervention group will perform daily
      rehabilitation sessions at home using SWORD Phoenix, under remote monitoring from a physical
      therapist. The control group will perform 1h rehabilitation sessions 3 times a week, at
      home, given by a physical therapist. Outcomes will be measured at weeks 4 and 8. The primary
      outcome is the performance in the Timed-up-and-Go (TUG) test between in each patient in
      comparison with the pre-operative score. Secondary outcomes will be measured in terms of: a)
      range of motion of the hip joint (flexion/extension/abduction/adduction/internal and
      external rotation); b) Hip Osteoarthritis Outcome Score; c) quality of life, as measured by
      the SF-36 scale.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 19, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Outcomes Assessor</masking>
    <masking_description>All patients will be assessed for clinical outcomes by an independent rater blinded to the study arm</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Timed Up and Go Test score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; 4 weeks after surgery; 8 weeks after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The timed up and go requires a patient to rise from a chair walk three meters around a piece of tape and return to the chair again as quickly as possible.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Hip injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score (KOOS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; 4 weeks after surgery; 8 weeks after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The HOOS is a standardized and validated patient outcome score that assesses functional limitation in patients with hip problems.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Short Form-36 Health Questionnaire (SF-36)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; 4 weeks after surgery; 8 weeks after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The SF-36 is a widely used quality of life questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Range of Motion (degrees)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; 4 weeks after surgery; 8 weeks after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the hip range of motion (Flexion/extension/abduction/external and internal rotation) measured in degrees</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">54</enrollment>
  <condition>Hip Osteoarthritis</condition>
  <condition>Hip Arthrosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Rehabilitation using SWORD Phoenix</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Home-based rehabilitation sessions performed with SWORD Phoenix.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Traditional home-based rehabilitation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Home-based rehabilitation sessions provided by a Physical Therapist</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SWORD Phoenix</intervention_name>
    <description>SWORD Phoenix will be used independently by the patients to perform rehabilitation sessions at home, under remote monitoring from the clinical team. A tailored rehabilitation program will be prescribed, based on the following principles:
STAGE 1 (Weeks 0-6) Open kinetic chain exercises without added resistance: lying, sitting and standing (with support) Strengthening of hip flexors and abductors (mainly) Ice pack application STAGE 2 (weeks 7-8) Open kinetic chain exercises with added resistance: lying, sitting (high chair) and standing (with progression to standing without support) Strengthening of hip flexors and abductors (mainly) Ice pack application after each session</description>
    <arm_group_label>Rehabilitation using SWORD Phoenix</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Smart Wearable Operative Rehabilitation Device</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Traditional home-based rehabilitation</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will perform 3 weekly rehabilitation sessions, with a duration of 1 hour, for 8 weeks, provided by a physical therapist. The rehabilitation program will respect the following principles:
STAGE 1 (Weeks 0-6) Soft tissue massage Active assisted mobilization of the hip joint to increase range of motion (avoiding internal rotation and adduction) Gait training with bilateral assistive devices Isometric exercises progressing to open chain, low-impact, concentric exercises with strengthening of hip abductors and flexors Ice pack application STAGE 2 (weeks 7-8) Soft tissue massage Gait training with progressive withdrawal of assistive devices Balance exercises with progression to one-leg support Open-chain strengthening exercises against resistance with progression to closed-chain exercises Ice pack application</description>
    <arm_group_label>Traditional home-based rehabilitation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients over 18 years old

          -  Clinical and imaging evidence of hip osteoarthritis

          -  Indication for total hip replacement according to the patient´s orthopedic surgeon

          -  Ability to walk unaided, with unilateral or bilateral support

          -  Availability of a carer to assist the patient after surgery

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients admitted for revision of total hip replacement

          -  Contralateral hip or knee osteoarthritis severely limiting patient mobility and
             ability to comply with a rehabilitation program

          -  Aphasia, dementia or psychiatric comorbidity interfering with the communication or
             compliance to the rehabilitation process

          -  Respiratory, cardiac, metabolic or other condition incompatible with at least 30
             minutes of light to moderate physical activity

          -  Major medical complications occurring after surgery that prevent the discharge of the
             patient within 7 days after the surgery

          -  Other medical and/or surgical complications that prevent the patient from complying
             with a rehabilitation program

          -  Blind and/or illiterate patients
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Fernando D Correia, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Sword Health, SA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Fernando D Correia, MD</last_name>
    <phone>966557789</phone>
    <email>fcorreia@swordhealth.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital da Prelada - Dr. Domingos Braga da Cruz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Porto</city>
        <zip>4250-449</zip>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>José R Seabra, MD</last_name>
      <phone>228 330 600</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Portugal</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B2kmuI2zObfcOFhUalV6d1BucmM/view?usp=sharing</url>
    <description>Study Protocol</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 14, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 3, 2017</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Hip</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual Participant Data will not be made available to other researchers</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
