<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02976753</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate the effectiveness of Elocta compared to conventional factor products in the prophylactic treatment of patients with haemophilia A over a 24-month prospective period. Data will also be collected for a 12 month retrospective period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective, Non-interventional Study to Evaluate the Effectiveness of Elocta Compared to Conventional Factor Products</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Factor VIII</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male patients with a diagnosis of haemophilia A Received prophylactic treatment with a factor product for management of haemophilia A in the 12 months prior to enrolment At enrolment prescribed prophylactic treatment with Elocta or conventional factor product regardless of participation in the study Having at least 12 months documented prestudy treatment data regarding prophylactic treatment prescriptions and bleeding episodes prior to the baseline visit Signed and dated informed consent provided by the patient or the patient's legally acceptable representative for patients under the legal age before any studyrelated activities are undertaken. Assent should be obtained from paediatric patients according to local regulations Enrolment in a concurrent clinical interventional study involving intake of an investigational medicinal product (IMP), within 1 year prior to enrolment Previously treated with commercially available extended halflife products other than Elocta Presence of factor VIII inhibitors (≥0.60 Bethesda Unit [BU]/mL ) at the latest available inhibitor test using the Nijmegen modified Bethesda assay</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Blood Coagulation Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Hematologic Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Coagulation Protein Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemorrhagic Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Genetic Diseases, Inborn</keyword>
</DOC>