<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01917149</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Dilated cardiomyopathy (DCM) is a poorly understood cause of systolic heart failure and is the most common indication for heart transplantation worldwide. Despite advances in medical and device therapy, the 5-year mortality of patients with DCM remains high. Patients diagnosed of dilated cardiomyopathy with a NYHA functional class of II to IV and left ventricular ejection fraction(LVEF) &lt;35% were selected for randomized controlled study of the efficacy and safety of high dose Renin-angiotensin system (RAS) inhibitor (benazepril or valsartan), in comparison with low dose RAS inhibitor(benazepril or valsartan) and standard beta-adrenergic blocker therapy (metoprolol). The primary endpoint was all cause death or admission for heart failure. Additional prespecified outcomes included all-cause death, cardiovascular death, all-cause admission, heart failure admission. Secondary cardiovascular outcomes included the changes from baseline to the last available observation after treatment in NYHA functional class, quality-of-life scores, LVEF, LVEDD, mitral regurgitation and wall-motion score index assessed by ECG. Adverse events were reported during in-hospital observation and follow-ups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Supramaximal Titrated Inhibition of RAAS in Dilated Cardiomyopathy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathy, Dilated</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metoprolol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Benazepril</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Valsartan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of dilated cardiomyopathy Left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 35% NYHA Functional classes of IIIV Symptomatic but not rapidly deteriorating 1 month before enrollment Signed informed consent Contradictions and intolerance of the studied drugs: supine systolic arterial blood pressure &lt; 90 mmHg, renal artery stenosis &gt;50%, pregnancy or lactation, impaired renal function (estimated glomerular filtration rate &lt; 60 ml/min/1.73m2, impaired liver function (total bilirubin &gt;2 times upper limit of normal, serum aspartate AST or alanine ALT &gt;3 times the upper limit of normal), hemoglobin less than 8 mg/dl, hyperkalaemia (serum potassium &gt;5.5mmol/l), obstructive lung disease, advanced atrioventricular block, any comorbidity with impact on survival, and known intolerance to benazepril, valsartan and metoprolol succinate; HF secondary to a known cause: coronary artery disease based on coronary angiography (≥50% stenosis in ≥1 of the major coronary arteries) and/or a history of myocardial infarction or angina pectoris, acute or subacute stage of myocarditis, primary valve disease, diabetes mellitus, excessive use of alcohol or illicit drugs; Expected or performed cardiac resynchronization therapy and heart transplantation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dilated cardiomyopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>High dose ACEI/ARB</keyword>
</DOC>