<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01917682</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To collect data on the routine patterns of use, safety and effectiveness, including the clinical and technical performance of the CorPath 200 System, in the delivery and manipulation of coronary guidewires and stent/balloon catheters during PCI procedures.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Post-Market CorPath Registry on the CorPath 200 System in Percutaneous Coronary Interventions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, single-arm, open-label, multi-center patient registry of the CorPath 200 System to examine its performance during PCI procedure and patient outcomes through 72 hours post-procedure or hospital discharge, whichever occurs first.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arteriosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arterial Occlusive Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age &gt;18 years. 2. Patients with coronary artery disease undergoing Percutaneous Coronary Intervention (PCI) with the CorPath 200 system. 3. The subject or the legal representative has been informed of the nature of the study, agrees to its provisions and has provided written informed consent. 1. Concurrent enrollment in another device or drug study protocol that specifically excludes concurrent enrollment or that prevents collection of data required in this registry (concurrent participation in another registry is not an automatic exclusion criterion for this study). 2. Failure/inability/unwillingness to provide informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>robotic-assisted PCI</keyword>
	<keyword>coronary intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>CorPath PRECISION Registry</keyword>
	<keyword>PCI</keyword>
	<keyword>angioplasty</keyword>
</DOC>