<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00087048</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as topotecan, work in different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well high-dose topotecan works as second-line therapy in treating patients with recurrent extensive-stage small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Topotecan in Treating Patients With Recurrent Extensive-Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the overall survival of patients with recurrent extensive stage small cell lung cancer treated with high-dose topotecan hydrochloride. Secondary - Determine the safety and toxic effects of this drug in these patients. - Determine the recurrence-free survival of patients treated with this drug. - Determine time to response and tumor response in patients treated with this drug. - Determine the quality of life of patients treated with this drug. OUTLINE: This is a non-randomized, multicenter study. Patients receive high-dose topotecan hydrochloride IV over 30 minutes on days 1, 8, 15, 22, 29, and 36. Treatment repeats every 56 days for 4 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Quality of life is assessed at baseline, day 1 of each course (except course 1), at the end of study treatment, and then every 3 months thereafter. Patients are followed at 7-14 days and then every 3 months thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 65 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Topotecan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed small cell lung cancer (SCLC) Recurrent extensive stage disease No mixed histology Measurable disease At least 1 bidimensionally measurable, noncentral nervous system (CNS), indicator lesion confirmed by CT scan or MRI Sensitive disease Responded to prior firstline therapy AND relapsed ≥ 60 days after response (90 days after initiation of firstline therapy) Eligible for highdose chemotherapy No symptomatic brain metastases affecting performance status PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 18 and over Performance status Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) 02 Life expectancy At least 2 months Hematopoietic Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL Hematocrit &gt; 35% (without transfusion) Hepatic Serum glutamicoxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) and serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase (SGPT) ≤ 2 times normal* Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2 times normal* Bilirubin ≤ 2.0 mg/dL Albumin &gt; 2.5 g/dL Hepatitis B surface antigen negative No significant hepatic disease Note: *≤ 5 times upper limit of normal if liver metastases are present Renal Creatinine clearance ≥ 40 mL/min Cardiovascular No history of cardiac arrhythmias No congestive heart failure No ischemic heart disease No stroke or other embolic disease requiring daily treatment that would preclude study participation Other Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 3 months after study participation HIV negative No known seizure disorder No active infection requiring systemic therapy within the past 2 weeks No known hypersensitivity to topotecan hydrochloride No medical or psychiatric condition that would preclude study participation No other malignancy except adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, carcinoma in situ of the cervix, or stage A lowgrade prostate cancer PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy Not specified Chemotherapy See Disease Characteristics More than 4 weeks since prior antineoplastic and/or myelosuppressive chemotherapy No more than 1 prior chemotherapy regimen (except for adjuvant chemotherapy) for SCLC No prior topotecan hydrochloride Endocrine therapy Not specified Radiotherapy Not specified Surgery Not specified Other More than 2 months since prior investigational agent No other concurrent investigational agent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>extensive stage small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>