<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03099382</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study, participants with advanced or metastatic squamous cell carcinoma of the esophagus that has progressed after first-line standard therapy will be randomized to receive either single agent SHR-1210 or the Investigator's choice of standard therapy with docetaxel or irinotecan. The primary study hypothesis is that treatment with SHR-1210 will prolong overall survival (OS) as compared to treatment with standard therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of SHR-1210 Versus Investigator's Choice Standard Therapy for Participants With Advanced Esophageal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. age:1875 years, male or femal. 2. Histologically or cytologically confirmed Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Esophagus, locally advanced, unresectable disease or Metastatic disease. 3. Fail to the firstline standard therapy. 4. Measurable disease based on Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1. 5. Can provide either a newly obtained or archival tumor tissue sample. 6. ECOG 01. 7. Life expectancy of greater than 12 weeks. 8. Adequate organ function. 9. Female: child bearing potential, a negative urine or serum pregnancy test result within 72 h before study treatment. Participants of reproductive potential must be willing to use adequate contraception for the course of the study through 3 months after the last dose of SHR1210 or through 180 days after the last dose of docetaxel or irinotecan. 10. Patient has given written informed consent. 1. Has a known additional malignancy within the last 5 years before study treatment with the exception of curatively treated basal cell and squamous cell carcinoma of the skin and/or curatively resected insitu cervical and/or breast cancers. 2. Known central nervous system (CNS) metastases. 3. Subjects with any active autoimmune disease or history of autoimmune disease. 4. Uncontrolled clinically significant heart disease, including but not limited to the following: (1) &gt; NYHA II congestive heart failure; (2) unstable angina, (3) myocardial infarction within the past 1 year; (4) clinically significant supraventricular arrhythmia or ventricular arrhythmia requirement for treatment or intervention; 5. Active infection or an unexplained fever &gt; 38.5°C during screening or before the first scheduled day of dosing (subjects with tumor fever may be enrolled at the discretion of the investigator); 6. History of Interstitial Pneumonia or active noninfectious pneumonitis. 7. Known Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) infection、active Hepatitis B or Hepatitis C. 8. Prior therapy with a PD1, antiPDLigand 1 (PDL1) agent. 9. Known history of hypersensitivity to macromolecular protein preparation or any components of the SHR1210 formulation, allergy, hypersensitivity, or contraindication to docetaxel, or irinotecan. 10. Concurrent medical condition requiring the use of cortisol (＞10mg/day Prednisone or equivalent dose) or other systematic immunosuppressive medications within 14 days before the study treament. Except: inhalation or topical corticosteroids. Doses &gt; 10 mg/day prednisone or equivalen for replacement therapy. 11. Has received prior anticancer monoclonal antibody (mAb), chemotherapy, targeted small molecule therapy, or radiation therapy within 4 weeks prior to study Day 1 or not recovered from adverse events due to a previously administered agent. 12. Currently participating or has participated in a study within 4 weeks of the first dose of study medication. 13. Received a live vaccine within 4 weeks of the first dose of study medication. 14. Pregnancy or breast feeding. 15. According to the investigator, other conditions that may lead to stop the research.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>