<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00862875</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objectives is to compare the changes in body composition (primary objective), diabetes parameters, energy expenditure and energy intake between Insulin detemir (Levemir® - Novolin® 4 pen) and insulin glargine (Lantus® - Solostar®) both in combination with Metformin and insulin secretagogues (SU) between baseline and after 6 months of insulin therapy in 80 type 2 diabetic patients failing on oral diabetic agents .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Levemir-Body Composition and Energy Metabolism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Detemir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Long-Acting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Glargine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 2 diabetic patients who require basal (longacting) insulin for the control of hyperglycemia according to the opinion of the investigator. Inadequate Glucose control: Hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) percentage in the range of ≥ 7.5 12.0% Stable body weight for previous 3 months (± 5 kg). Structured exercise lower than 4 hours per week. Metformin ≥1.5 g/day Any medical, social or geographic condition, which, in the opinion of the investigator would not allow safe or reliable completion of the protocol. Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus Previous treatment with insulin (&lt; 6 months prior inclusion). Insulin therapy for less than 6 days at the time of an acute event is acceptable. Secondary diabetes mellitus (i.e. steroid induced, Cushing syndrome, chronic pancreatitis, cystic fibrosis, etc.) and maturityonset diabetes of the young Proliferative retinopathy/maculopathy requiring treatment Hypoglycemia unawareness or recurrent major hypoglycaemia Pregnancy and breastfeeding Unstable coronary artery disease Heart Failure as defined by class IV according to NYHA classification Recent (&lt; 6 months) history of myocardial infarction, stroke or T.I.A, ventricular arrhythmias, or unstable supraventricular arrhythmias. Renal Insufficiency. Creatinine clearance &lt; 40 ml/min (MDRD formula). Acute (&lt; 2 months) or Chronic infectious diseases requiring either hospitalization or antibiotic treatment for more than 2 weeks Recent (&lt; 1 year) diagnosis of systemic malignancies except thyroid and skin cancer Major psychiatric diseases History of drug addiction Previous bariatric surgery Medication that affects weight such as Systemic corticosteroids (prednisone) Antiobesity medication (Xenical® or Meridia®) Megace ® Antidepressant medication associated with significant weight impact such as Zyprexa®, Remeron® based on investigator judgment. Growth hormone therapy or testosterone supplementation should be initiated for at least 6 months and at stable dose for 3 months prior to enrolment Medication that affects glycemic control and hypoglycemic unawareness based on investigator judgment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Insulin initiation</keyword>
	<keyword>oral therapy failure</keyword>
</DOC>