<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00862680</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this clinical research study is to learn if adjusting the PET/CT scanner to allow for breathing motion can improve the quality of PET/CT images.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>4D PET/CT Imaging in Lung and Colorectal Cancer With Liver Metastasis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Routine PET/CT scans are taken while patients are breathing normally. The motions made by breathing can reduce the image quality of the scan. Minimizing the effects of this motion by taking the images and processing the scans differently may improve the image quality. The PET/CT Scan: If you agree to take part in this study, a small plastic box (weighing less than 1 ounce) will be placed on your abdominal area before your routine PET/CT scan. This box is used to track your breathing motion. This information will be used to help process the scan. Your PET/CT scan will be performed as usual. During the scan, the researchers will focus on your lower chest/upper abdomen (areas that experience breathing motion). Having to focus on this area might extend the scan by up to 12 minutes. Length of Study: Your participation on this study will be complete when your scheduled PET/CT scan is complete. This is an investigational study. The imaging focused on your lower chest/upper abdomen during the scan is investigational. Up to 75 patients will take part in this study. All will be enrolled at MD Anderson.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients with suspected colorectal cancer with nodules in the lung or liver (12 cm in diameter) will be eligible for this study. 2. Patients with suspected lung cancer with nodules in the lung or liver (12 cm in diameter) will be eligible for this study. 1. Pediatric patients (younger than 18 years) will be excluded. 2. Patients that cannot tolerate being scanned for an additional 12 minutes with arms above their head will be excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lung Colorectum</keyword>
	<keyword>Colorectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Liver Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
	<keyword>4D PET/CT Imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>Positron emission tomography/computed tomography</keyword>
	<keyword>PET/CT scan</keyword>
	<keyword>Breathing motion</keyword>
</DOC>