<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01393990</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to determine a safe dose of LY2228820 that may be given to patients with advanced cancer. Part A of this study will consist of dose escalation, and Part B will consist of dose confirmation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of LY2228820 in Patients With Advanced Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have histological or cytological evidence of a diagnosis of cancer (including lymphoma) that is advanced or metastatic disease for which no therapy of higher priority (approved therapies or therapies with published substantial evidence of effectiveness) is available, or for whom no standard therapy exists Have the presence of measurable or nonmeasurable disease as defined by Modified Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) Have adequate hematologic, renal, and hepatic organ function Have a performance status of less than or equal to 2 on the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) scale Have discontinued all previous therapies for cancer, including chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or other investigational therapy for at least 14 days (42 days for mitomycinC or nitrosoureas) prior to study enrollment and recovered from the acute effects of therapy Males and females with reproductive potential must agree to use medically approved contraceptive precautions during the trial and for 3 months following the last dose of study drug. Females with child bearing potential must have had a negative serum pregnancy test less than or equal to 7 days prior to the first dose of study drug. Have an estimated life expectancy of greater than or equal to 12 weeks Are able to swallow capsules and/or tablets Have received treatment within 14 days of the initial dose of study drug with a drug that has not received regulatory approval for any indication Have a history of major surgical resection involving the stomach or small bowel, or have serious preexisting medical conditions (based on judgment of the investigator) Have symptomatic central nervous system malignancy or metastasis (screening is not required) Have a diagnosis of inflammatory bowel disease (Crohn's disease or ulcerative colitis) Have an active hematologic malignancy other than lymphoma Have known positive test results in human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B surface antigen (HBSAg), or hepatitis C antibodies (HCAb). Screening at baseline will not be required for enrollment Concurrent administration of any immunosuppressive therapy Females who are pregnant or lactating Have received, within 7 days of the initial dose of study drug, either grapefruit juice or treatment with a drug that is a known inhibitor or inducer of Cytochrome P450 Enzyme 3A4 (CYP3A4). In addition, patients should not receive grapefruit juice or treatment with a CYP3A4 inhibitor or inducer during the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>