<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01393301</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is the 1-year initial phase of a study to develop an integrated treatment for quitting smoking for anxiety-vulnerable HIV+ smokers. During this first phase of the study, start-up activities will include piloting the integrated treatment on a small group of individuals (N = 12), obtaining expert consultant and participant feedback, and development of the final treatment manual and procedures. The goal during this phase will be to establish feasibility of treatment delivery, participant acceptability, and potential for a treatment effect before conducting a pilot randomized trial of the treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Integrated Treatment for Smoking Cessation &amp; Anxiety in People With HIV Phase 1</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study represents an important step in treating nicotine dependence in HIV-positive individuals. This study addresses an important public health issue by assessing an intervention that may lead to a more effective application for the treatment of at-risk HIV+ smokers. The 1-year initial phase of the study will develop an integrated treatment for quitting smoking for anxiety-vulnerable HIV+ smokers. The proposed treatment will include cognitive-behavioral talk therapy for quitting smoking, a nicotine patch, and cognitive-behavioral talk therapy for anxiety. The pilot of the proposed treatment will be done with a small group of individuals (N = 12). This phase will be used to establish feasibility of treatment delivery, participant acceptability, and potential for a treatment effect before conducting a pilot randomized trial of the treatment. Additionally, this phase will monitor smoking cessation history through Point Prevalence Abstinence (PPA), as well as anxiety symptoms through the Anxiety Sensitivity Index (ASI) at the baseline and follow-up assessments. This study represents an important step in treating nicotine dependence in HIV-positive individuals. This study addresses an important public health issue by assessing an intervention that may lead to a more effective application for the treatment of at-risk HIV+ smokers.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tobacco Use Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1865 years old Informed consent Daily smoker Motivated to quit smoking Anxiety symptom elevation Use of other tobacco products Untreated or unstable psychiatric disorders Current use of cognitivebehavioral therapy or medication for smoking cessation treatment Cognitivebehavioral therapy for anxiety within the past year Insufficient command of English</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Nicotine dependence</keyword>
	<keyword>Smoking, cessation</keyword>
	<keyword>Quitting</keyword>
	<keyword>Anxiety symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive-behavioral therapy</keyword>
</DOC>