<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03033212</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This investigation will assess how the timing and type of rehabilitation after a transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion will affect the efficacy of the surgical procedure. The efficacy of the procedure will be evaluated through patients' quality of life, measured by health-related quality of life questionnaires up to 24 months following the procedure. These measures will be compared to the patients' baseline value.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Single-Level TLIF: Post-Fusion Rehabilitation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients will undergo transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion for degenerative pathology at the L4-5 vertebral level. They will be randomized to one of three postoperative rehabilitation groups. Group 1 will receive "structured early rehabilitation" beginning at 7 weeks. Group 2 will receive "Delayed rehabilitation" beginning at 13 weeks postoperatively. Group 3 will undergo "Self Rehabilitation" beginning at 7 weeks postoperatively. Groups 1 and 2 will undergo rehabilitation under the supervision of a certified physical therapist for 10 total weeks. Group 3 will undergo non-supervised rehabilitation for 10 total weeks, and will be given educational materials regarding which exercises to perform and at which intervals.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neurodegenerative Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>i. Singlelevel L4L5 TLIF for degenerative pathology, including: radiculopathy, neurogenic claudication, intervertebral disc disease, facet joint disease, degenerative spondylolisthesis, degenerative myelopathy degenerative kyphosis and scoliosis ii. Back and/or leg pain iii. Failed at least 3 months of conservative treatment i. Older than 65 years of age ii. Prior spinal surgery excluding laminectomy/discectomy iii. Greater than Grade 2 spondylolisthesis iv. Greater than 10 degrees scoliosis v. Not worked for greater than 6 months or unemployed as a result of lumbar condition vi. History of spinal infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>