<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03033667</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Comparative study between conventional fasting versus overnight infusion of lipid or carbohydrate on free fatty acids and insulin in obese patients undergoing elective first time on-pump coronary artery bypass grafting.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Conventional Fasting Versus Lipid/Carbohydrate Infusion for Coronary Bypass Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Obese patients scheduled for bypass surgery randomly assigned to three groups: Group I (Glucose-group): patients received 500 cc of glucose 10% containing 50 g of glucose and providing patients with 200 Kcal with an osmolarity of 556 mosm/L. Group II (Lipid-group): patients received 100 cc of lipid solution (soybean 30%, medium chain triglycerides 30%,olive oil 25%,fish oil 15% and 20 mg vitamine E) containing 20 g lipid and provides patients with 200 Kcal with an osmolarity of 380 mosm/L. Group III (Control-group): patients fasted overnight from 11 pm till 9 am except for clear fluids which were allowed till 5 am.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients (&gt; 18 years) with American Society of Anesthesia (ASA) class IIIII, BMI 3040, and New York Heart Association (NYHA) functional capacities III, undergoing elective onpump coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) using cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB). All patients were type 1a World Health Organisation (WHO)/Fredrickson classification of primary hyperlipidemias. Patients with diabetes mellitus Patients on fibrates Patients type 1,2b,3,4 and 5 WHO/Fredrickson classification of primary hyperperlipidemias Patients with history of allergic reactions to fish, egg yolk containing foods peanut or soy products Patients with carbohydrate or fat intolerance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>perioperative fasting</keyword>
	<keyword>free fatty acids</keyword>
	<keyword>coronary bypass grfting</keyword>
</DOC>