<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03033511</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 3, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multinational, and multicenter study to evaluate the efficacy of rovalpituzumab tesirine as maintenance therapy following first-line platinum-based chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Rovalpituzumab Tesirine as Maintenance Therapy Following First-Line Platinum-Based Chemotherapy in Participants With Extensive Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer (MERU)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed extensivestage disease small cell lung cancer (ED SCLC) with ongoing clinical benefit (stable disease [SD], partial response [PR], or complete response [CR]) following completion of 4 cycles of firstline platinumbased therapy At least 3 but no more than 9 weeks between the administration of the last cycle of platinumbased chemotherapy and randomization. Participants with a history of central nervous system (CNS) metastases prior to the initiation of firstline platinumbased chemotherapy must have received definitive local treatment and have documentation of stable or improved CNS disease status Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance score of 0 or 1 Participants must have adequate bone marrow, renal and hepatic function Availability of archived or representative tumor material for assessment of DLL3 expression Any prior systemic chemotherapy, small molecule inhibitors, immune checkpoint inhibitors, other monoclonal antibodies, antibodydrug conjugates, radioimmunoconjugates, Tcell or other cellbased or biologic therapies, or any other anticancer therapy than that described in inclusion criteria Any diseasedirected radiotherapy (except prophylactic cranial irradiation or preplanned radiotherapy for CNS metastases present prior to start of firstline therapy and nonprogressing) after last dose of firstline chemotherapy. Prior exposure to a pyrrolobenzodiazepine (PBD) or indolinobenzodiazepinebased drug, prior participation in a rovalpituzumab tesirine clinical trial, or known hypersensitivity or other contraindications to rovalpituzumab tesirine or excipient contained in the drug formulation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Extensive-Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer (ED SCLC)</keyword>
	<keyword>Rovalpituzumab tesirine</keyword>
	<keyword>first-line chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Platinum-Based Chemotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>