<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03033238</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate opportunities for prevention and treatment of knee osteoarthritis (OA) by evaluating potentially modifiable risk factors for disease and poor pain and physical function outcomes especially among those with early or mild knee symptoms. The goal of the study is to find novel strategies to prevent disease at an early stage and to limit the impact of disease once it has occurred.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicenter Bone and Joint Health Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>MOST study participants in the "Existing Cohort" (3,026 subjects) were enrolled in the original study in 2003-2005. Surviving Existing Cohort participants without end-stage knee osteoarthritis will be asked to participate in the 144-, 152-, 160- and 168-month follow-up contacts. In addition, in 2016-2018 the cohort will be enriched by the recruitment of an additional 1,500 "New Cohort" participants with early or mild knee symptoms. The goal of the study is to find novel strategies to prevent disease at an early stage.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria for "New Cohort" Participants: Age 45 to 69 Years (Adult, Senior) Males and Females Healthy Volunteers Communitybased Sample Exclusion Criteria for "New Cohort" Participants: Rheumatoid or inflammatory arthritis (based on selfreport and use of medications specific to these conditions) Serious health condition e.g., endstage renal disease, etc. that would likely limit followup to less than 23 years Plan to relocate out of geographic region in next 3 years Not able to walk without the aid of a person or assistive device Knee joint replacement surgery in either knee Neither knee fits in the MRI knee coil (determined during Screening Visit). Not competent to give informed consent Advanced structural tibiofemoral or patellofemoral knee OA disease (KL grade 3 or 4) in either knee (Determined by Knee Xray Screening)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>