<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02507973</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators will conduct an observational crossover study. The investigators aim to recruit 50 participants with severe Traumatic Brain Injury (TBI) requiring intracranial pressure (ICP) monitoring during their stay at the Neuro Trauma ICU at the R Adams Cowley Shock Trauma Center. Overall, participants will be monitored, on average, for approximately 6-8 hours during the study period. The investigators do not anticipate the need for prolonged monitoring during the duration of their hospital stay or post hospital period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Airway Pressure Release Ventilation and Intracranial Pressure in Patients With Severe Traumatic Brain Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Each participant at admission will initially receive a primary mode of mechanical ventilation as determined by the attending trauma intensivists. 12-18 hours after recruitment, continuous monitoring of participants' ICP and hemodynamic status will commence to collect participants' baseline data for 30 minutes. Participants will then undergo low tidal volume mechanical ventilation (LOTV), serving as a control mode of ventilation, for 2 hours prior to switching back to the primary mode of ventilation for 30 minutes. Next, patients will be placed on Airway Pressure Release Ventilation (APRV) for 2 hours. While receiving APRV, participants Intracranial pressure and hemodynamic status will be continuously monitored and recorded for comparison and analysis. After 2 hours of APRV, patients will be switched back to their previous mode of ventilation and more data collected for another 30 minutes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Intracranial Pressure Monitoring device present Mechanically Ventilated Clinically Stable as determined by the Critical Care attending Age &lt;14 Prisoners Initial Mode of ventilation is APRV Provider's Judgement Pregnant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mechanical Ventilation</keyword>
	<keyword>Intracranial Pressure</keyword>
	<keyword>Airway Pressure Release Ventilation</keyword>
</DOC>