<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02507336</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study seeks to provide long-term follow-up and/or to offer continued maintenance thalidomide (THALOMID) therapy to those patients enrolled in 20030165. Patients will be followed until withdrawal of consent, or death.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-Term Followup and/or Thalidomide Maintenance Therapy for Patients Enrolled on Clinical Trial 20030165</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is designed to provide long-term follow-up and/or to offer continued maintenance thalidomide (THALOMID®) therapy to those patients enrolled in 20030165. - Group A: Patients who achieved complete response (CR) in 20030165 and continue to receive maintenance Thalidomide. - Group B: Patients who achieved complete response (CR) in 20030165, but are not receiving maintenance Thalidomide. - Group C: All other patients enrolled in 20030165 who expired or experienced disease progression. Thalidomide (THALOMID®) will be administered as per standard of care guidelines to Group A; in compliance with Risk Evaluation and Mitigation Strategy (REMS™) program requirements. Patients in Group A, B and C will be followed until withdrawal of consent, or death. All other patients in Group C who expired on 20030165 will also be included in all analyses.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Mantle-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thalidomide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Enrolled on the 20030165 clinical trial. 2. Ability to understand and willingness to sign a written informed consent document. 1. Patients who were discontinued from 20030165 for any reason prior to the completion of protocolspecified treatment (e.g. withdrawal of consent). 2. Uncontrolled, intercurrent serious illness including but not limited to ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, and/or cardiac arrhythmia likely in the judgment of the PI to interfere with clinical study requirements. 3. Psychiatric illness/condition likely in the judgment of the PI to limit compliance with clinical study requirements.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mantle Cell Lymphoma (MCL)</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma (NHL)</keyword>
</DOC>