<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00808899</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Phase II study of temsirolimus in combination with standard chemotherapy (irinotecan; cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin and etoposide (CAE); cisplatin and etoposide (HiPE) and topotecan (TPT) followed by and additional six courses of induction chemotherapy and then intensification with autologous hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. The first five courses of induction chemotherapy will also evaluate the feasibility of combining weekly temsirolimus with these standard chemotherapy combinations. This will be followed by 16 months of oral maintenance therapy with eight months of 13-cis-retinoic acid and then eight months of oral topotecan.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neuroblastoma Protocol 2008: Therapy for Children With Advanced Stage High Risk Neuroblastoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All children will receive fixed doses of intravenous temsirolimus (50 mg/m2 weekly 6 times ) concomitantly with two courses of fixed dosages of irinotecan (20 mg/m2 intravenously daily 5 times ,2 days off, repeated daily 5 times .If these initial dosages are not tolerable then subsequent patients will be given a reduced dosage of temsirolimus (25 mg/m2 weekly 6 times) with 20 mg/m2 of irinotecan.If this dosage combination is not tolerable, the irinotecan dosage will be decreased to 15 mg/m2 .If this dosage combination is not tolerable then further enrollment to the initial six week treatment will be terminated.The second course of irinotecan will begin on day 22 and response will be determined after six weeks (two courses). Resection of primary tumor will be attempted after this initial therapy, whenever possible. Following initial treatment children will undergo alternating courses of induction chemotherapy with cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, etoposide, topotecan, and cisplatin (Block 2). The first cohort of 17 patients will receive Block 2 with temsirolimus (50mg/m2) for all three courses, weekly 2 times. If this is not tolerated subsequent patients will receive Block 2 chemotherapy with reduced dosages of temsirolimus (25mg/m2).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tretinoin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Topotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isotretinoin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients &lt;18 years old with newly diagnosed, advanced stage, highrisk neuroblastoma defined as one of the following: Children &lt; 1 yo with International Neuroblastoma Staging System (INSS) stage 2a, 2b, 3, 4 or 4S disease and MYCN amplification (&gt;10 copies, or greater than fourfold increase in MYCN signal as compared to reference signal) INSS 2a or 2b disease and MYCN amplification, regardless of age or additional biologic features INSS stage 3 and: 1. MYCN amplification (&gt;10 copies, or greater than fourfold increase in MYCN signal as compared to reference signal, regardless of age or additional biologic features 2. Age &gt; 18 mo (&gt; 547 days) with unfavorable pathology, regardless of MYCN status INSS stage 4 and: 1. MYCN amplification, regardless of age or additional biologic features 2. Age &gt; 18 months (&gt; 547 days) regardless of biologic features 3. Age 12 18 months (365 547 days) with any of the following three unfavorable biologic features (MYCN amplification, unfavorable pathology and/or DNA index =1) or any biologic feature that is indeterminant/unknown Children less than or equal to 365 days initially diagnosed with: INSS stage 1, 2, 4S who progressed to a stage 4 without interval chemotherapy. Histologic proof of neuroblastoma or positive bone marrow for tumor cells with increased urine catecholamines. Adequate renal and hepatic function (serum creatinine &lt;3 x upper limit of normal for age, (AST) aspartate aminotransferase &lt; 3 x upper limit of normal). No prior therapy, unless an emergency situation requires local tumor treatment (discuss with PI) Written, informed consent according to institutional guidelines Any evidence, as judged by the investigator, of severe or uncontrolled systemic disease (e.g., unstable or uncompensated respiratory, cardiac, hepatic, or renal disease). Pregnant or breast feeding (women of childbearing potential). Children with INSS 4 disease, age &lt;12 months with all 3 favorable biologic features (nonamplified MYCN, favorable pathology and DNA index &gt;1).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neuroblastoma</keyword>
</DOC>