<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03012295</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Monogenic hypertension, which follows the rules of Mendel's genetic law, is one of the most important causes of hypertension. Generally, patients occur hypertension in early age, have family history, and often manifest severe hypertension or refractory hypertension. At present, only a few hypertension centers of hospitals in China will help clinically difficult diagnosis hypertensive patients to test some selective genes, while most of other hospitals still perform diagnosis based on biochemical examination and clinical symptoms. Therefore, in order to provide better guidance for the diagnosis and treatment for hypertensive patients, this project aims to develop a single gene detection panel for genetic hypertension, so as to provide new diagnostic technology for early intervention, prevention and treatment of hypertension in clinics.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Genetic Testing of Monogenic Hypertension in Chinese Population</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<criteria>hypertension patients meet one of the following criteria 1. Beginning age of hypertension: &lt;35 years (regardless of family history of hypertension); 2. refractory hypertension (blood pressure is difficult to control): triple antihypertensive drugs treatment for 1 months, 3 times of noncontinuous high blood pressure in consulting room (SBP ≥140mmHg and/or DBP≥90mmHg); patients suspected of secondary hypertension, meeting one of the following criteria 1. pheochromocytoma or Cushing syndrome; 2. hypertension with hypokalemia; 3. hypertension with hyperkalemia; 4. hypertension with special body shape, such as central obesity, moon face, acne etc.. 5. adrenal tumor; renal parenchymal / renovascular hypertension patients exceed age of 50, and with coronary heart disease and arteriosclerosis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Genetic Testing</keyword>
	<keyword>Chinese Population</keyword>
</DOC>