<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03012945</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Surgical resection is one of the most important treatments for malignant tumor; on the other hand, tumor recurrence and/or metastasis are the major reasons of treatment failure. The outcome after surgery mostly depends on the balance between the immunity of human body and the capability of implantation, proliferation and neovascularization of the tumor. Preclinical and retrospective studies suggest that anaesthetic techniques and drugs may affect the long-term prognosis in patients undergoing cancer surgery. The investigators hypothesize that epidural anesthesia-analgesia may improve the long-term outcome of the elderly patients who are scheduled to undergo major thoracic and abdominal surgery for the treatment of malignant tumor.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Epidural Anesthesia-analgesia and Long-term Outcome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Surgical resection is the main treatment for potentially curable solid tumors. However, it is unavoidable that some tumor cells are disseminated into the circulatory or lymphatic system during surgery. And quite a number of patients develop tumor metastasis and/or recurrence after surgery, which are associated with poor long-term outcome. The development of tumor recurrence and/or metastasis after surgery is mostly dependent on the balance between the anti-tumor immune function of the human body and the ability of implantation, proliferation and neovascularization of the tumor cells. Multiple surgical factors may influence the balance between the anti-tumor immune function and tumor recurrence. For example, the presence of the primary tumor inhibits angiogenesis, whereas tumor resection eliminates this safeguard against angiogenesis; surgical manipulation releases tumor cells into the circulation; surgical response inhibits natural killer (NK) cell activity and can promote the development of tumor metastases; local and systemic release of growth factors during surgery may also promote tumor recurrence both locally and at distant sites. Furthermore, studies show that general anaesthetic techniques and drugs may influence the cellular immune function and long-term outcome. For example, it was found that ketamine and thiopental, but not propofol, suppressed NK cell activity; all three drugs caused a significant reduction in NK cell number; isoflurane and halothane inhibit interferon (IFN) stimulation of NK cell cytotoxicity; nitrous oxide interferes with DNA, purine, and thymidylate synthesis and depresses neutrophil chemotaxis; opioids have been shown to suppress cell-mediated and humoral immunity. Considering the potential harmful effects of general anesthesia/anesthetics, there is increasing interest on the effect of regional anaesthesia. Retrospective studies investigating the relationship between epidural anesthesia and outcome after cancer surgery give different results. In a meta-analysis, regional anesthesia was associated with increased the survival rate (HR = 0.84, 95% confidence interval [CI] 0.74-0.96, P = 0.013), but had no effect on the rate of tumor recurrence/metastasis (HR = 0.88, 95% Cl 0.64-1.22, P = 0.457). The investigators hypothesize that epidural anesthesia may produce favorable effects on the long-term outcome of the elderly patients who were scheduled for major cancer surgery under general anesthesia. However, there is no sufficient evidence in this aspect.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Propofol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sufentanil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rocuronium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Elderly patients (age &gt;= 60 years, &lt; 90 years); Scheduled to undergo open thoracic or open abdominal surgery with an expected duration of 2 hours or longer. For those who undergo thoracoscopic or laparoscopic surgery, the expected length of incision must be 5 centimeters or more; Agree to receive patientcontrolled postoperative analgesia. Refused to participate; Previous history of schizophrenia, epilepsy or Parkinson disease, or unable to complete preoperative assessment due to severe dementia, language barrier or endstage disease; History of myocardial infarction within 3 months before surgery; Presence of any contraindication to epidural anesthesia and analgesia, including abnormal vertebral anatomy, previous spinal trauma or surgery, severe chronic back pain, coagulation disorder (prothrombin time or activated partial prothrombin time longer than 1.5 times of the upper limit of normal, or platelet count of less than 80 * 10^9/L), local infection near the site of puncture, and severe sepsis; Severe heart dysfunction (New York Heart Association functional classification 4 or above), severe hepatic insufficiency (ChildPugh grades C), or severe renal insufficiency (serum creatinine of 442 umol/L or above, with or without serum potassium of 6.5 mmol/L or above, or requirement of renal replacement therapy); Any other conditions that were considered unsuitable for study participation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Epidural anesthesia and analgesia</keyword>
	<keyword>Long-term survival</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
</DOC>