<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="156595">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01061151</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1077BF (PROMISE)</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10777</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>IMPAACT 1077BF</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01061151</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating Strategies to Reduce Mother-to-Child Transmission of HIV Infection in Resource-Limited Countries</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROMISE</acronym>
  <official_title>Breastfeeding Version of the PROMISE Study (Promoting Maternal and Infant Survival Everywhere)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to examine effective methods of preventing the transmission of
      HIV from mother to child during pregnancy, labor and delivery, and breastfeeding. This is
      one part of the three-part PROMISE study and will be conducted at locations in Africa and
      other parts of the world where women typically receive a short course of highly active
      antiretroviral therapy (HAART) during pregnancy and where breastfeeding is common.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The incidence of mother-to-child transmission (MTCT) of HIV has decreased in recent years in
      the United States, Europe, and other resource-advantaged countries. Several factors have
      contributed to this decrease, including the administration of HAART during pregnancy,
      caesarean section delivery methods, and the use of formula instead of breastfeeding to feed
      infants. However, in resource-limited countries, the incidence of pediatric HIV infection
      remains high. Many pregnant women in these countries do not receive an adequate course of
      HAART, and the majority breastfeed their children.

      The PROMISE study is evaluating effective methods of preventing the transmission of HIV from
      a mother to her baby during pregnancy, labor and delivery, and breastfeeding. This version
      of the PROMISE study will be conducted at research sites in eastern and southern Africa and
      other parts of the world where breastfeeding is common.

      This study is divided into three components (Antepartum, Postpartum, and Maternal Health
      Components). Each component includes three steps (Steps 1, 2, and 3). Following is a
      description of each component of the study, and the three steps within each component:

        1. Antepartum Component: This part of the study will compare the safety and effectiveness
           of different HAART regimens at preventing the transmission of HIV during pregnancy,
           labor, and delivery.

           Pregnant HIV-infected women will be randomly assigned to one of the following three
           groups:

           Arm A: Participants will receive zidovudine (ZDV) + single dose nevirapine (sdNVP) +
           emtricitabine-tenofovir disoproxil fumarate (Truvada [TRV]) tail. Participants will
           receive ZDV from study entry through delivery, sdNVP and TRV intrapartum, and TRV
           postpartum for 7 days or through the Week 1 visit, whichever is later.

           Arm B: Participants will receive lamivudine (3TC)-zidovudine (ZDV) + lopinavir
           (LPV)-ritonavir (RTV). Participants will receive the triple ARV study drug regimen from
           study entry through the Week 1 visit (6-14 days postpartum).

           Arm C: Participants will receive TRV/LPV-RTV. Participants will receive the triple ARV
           study drug regimen from study entry through the Week 1 visit (6-14 days postpartum).

           Fixed-dose FTC-TDF-RPV (Complera) may be used as an alternative first-line regimen for
           mothers who are not able to tolerate or adhere to LPV-RTV or ATV-RTV. The FTC-TDF-RPV
           regimen is not defined in the protocol and should be determined at the discretion of
           staff at the study sites.

           All infants born to women enrolled in this study will receive NVP once a day through 42
           days of age or until the Week 6 study visit, whichever is later, regardless of which
           study arm their mother is enrolled in. Should women need HAART or to switch HAART
           regimens for their own health, they will be moved into Step 2 or Step 3 of this part of
           the study.

           During pregnancy, participants will attend study visits at study entry, 2 and 4 weeks
           after entry, and then every 4 weeks until labor and delivery. Women and infants will be
           monitored during labor and delivery and will attend a study visit 6 to 14 days after
           delivery. Study staff will discuss the other three parts of the study with participants
           and decide if they are eligible to enroll. Follow-up visits will occur at Weeks 1, 6,
           10, and 14. Thereafter, they will be once a month for infants and every 3 months for
           women. Each study visit will include a medical history review, questionnaires,
           interviews, physical exam, blood collection, and a breast milk collection (during
           breastfeeding).

        2. Postpartum Component: This part of the study will compare the safety and effectiveness
           of different HAART regimens at preventing HIV infection in infants who are being
           breastfed by an HIV-infected mother.

           Participants will be randomly assigned to one of two arms:

           Arm A: Women will receive LPV-RTV plus TRV from the Week 1 postpartum visit through the
           end of maternal follow-up (2 to 5 years). Infants will receive NVP once a day through 6
           weeks (42 days) of age.

           Arm B: Infants will receive NVP once a day from 6 (up to 14) days of age until there is
           no longer a risk of MTCT or until the end of follow-up (104 weeks).

           Until infants are 6 months of age, study visits will occur once a month. After that,
           study visits will occur once every 3 months. Study visits will include a medical
           history review, questionnaires, physical exam, blood collection, and a breast milk
           collection. Should women need HAART or to switch HAART regimens for their own health,
           they will be moved into Step 2 or Step 3 of this part of the study. If a woman
           initiates HAART, NVP for her infant should be discontinued when the mother has been on
           HAART for 12 weeks or when her viral load has been suppressed to undetectable levels,
           whichever comes first.

           As part of an optional substudy, study researchers may collect hair samples from women
           and infants at some study visits to measure antiretroviral drug concentrations present
           in the hair.

           Another optional substudy will examine antibody responses in plasma and breast milk in
           some participants. No additional study visits or procedures will be required for this
           substudy.

        3. Maternal Health Component: This part of the study will examine if women who received a
           triple ARV regimen during pregnancy and while breastfeeding have better health outcomes
           than women who discontinue a triple ARV regimen.

      Participants will include women who were receiving the triple ARV regimen in the Postpartum
      Component or receiving the triple ARV regimen in the Antepartum Component and were
      ineligible for the Postpartum Component.

      Participants will be randomly assigned to one of two study arms:

      Arm A: Participants will continue to receive the triple ARV regimen (TRV and LPV-RTV).

      Arm B: Participants will discontinue the triple ARV regimen.

      Study visits will occur at Weeks 4 and 12 and then every 3 months thereafter. Study visits
      will include a medical history review, questionnaires, physical exam, and blood collection.
      Should women need a triple ARV regimen or to switch triple ARV regimens for their own
      health, they will be moved into Step 2 or Step 3 of this part of the study.

      As part of an optional substudy, study researchers may collect hair samples from some women
      at certain study visits to measure antiretroviral drug concentrations present in the hair.

      The total duration of the three study components is 5 years. Women will remain in the study
      for follow-up for 2 to 5 years, depending on when they enroll. Infants will remain in the
      study through 74 to 104 weeks of age. Follow-up for all women and infants will be completed
      by the end of September 2016.

      As of October 1, 2014, participants are no longer being enrolled in any of the three
      components of this study. Women who have completed one of the Antepartum Component regimens
      should be referred for care according to the standard of care for postpartum women in their
      country. Study-supplied drugs may be provided to these women if the drugs are not available
      as a country's standard of care and if a woman and her health care provider decide that
      continuing the study drugs would be in her best interest.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Antepartum Component: Confirmed presence of infant HIV infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at birth or Week 1 study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as HIV nucleic acid test (NAT) positivity of the specimen drawn at either the birth (Day 0-5) or Week 1 (Day 6-14) visit, confirmed by HIV NAT positivity of a second specimen collected at a different time point</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Antepartum Component: Grade 3 or higher toxicity (for women, also selected Grade 2 hematologic, renal, and hepatic adverse events)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through the Week 1 postpartum study visit</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Postpartum Component: Confirmed presence of infant HIV infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through complete cessation of breastfeeding or 18 months of age, whichever comes first</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as HIV NAT positivity of a specimen drawn at any post-randomization visit (i.e., any visit after the Week 1 [Day 6-14] visit), confirmed by HIV NAT positivity of a second specimen drawn at a different time point</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Postpartum Component: Grade 3 or higher adverse events (for women, also selected Grade 2 hematologic, renal, and hepatic adverse events)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through complete cessation of breastfeeding or 18 months of age, whichever comes first</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Composite endpoint of progression to AIDS-defining illness or death</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Antepartum Component: Obstetrical complications</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through the Week 1 postpartum study visit</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Antepartum Component: Adverse pregnancy outcomes (e.g., stillbirth, preterm delivery at less than 37 weeks gestation, low birth weight less than 2,500 grams, and congenital anomalies)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through the Week 1 postpartum study visit</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antepartum Component: Infant HIV infection detected by HIV NAT positivity in the birth sample</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the birth (Day 0-5) visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antepartum Component: Overall and HIV-free infant survival through 24 months of age (in conjunction with infants in the Postpartum Component)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through 24 months of age</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antepartum Component: Adherence to the maternal antiretroviral (ARV) regimen, as measured by maternal report</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through the Week 1 postpartum study visit</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antepartum Component: Maternal and infant viral resistance to the maternal and infant ARV strategies</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antepartum Component: Cost effectiveness and feasibility of the trial ARV regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antepartum Component: Maternal HIV RNA less than 400 copies/mL at delivery</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the time of delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antepartum Component: Antepartum change in HBV DNA viral load between Week 8 and baseline levels (using log HBV DNA) among women with detectable HBV DNA viral loads at baseline and other HBV outcome measures</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Week 8</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postpartum Component: Infant HIV-free survival through 24 months post-delivery</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through 24 months post-delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postpartum Component: Overall infant survival through 12 and 24 months post-delivery</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 12 and 24 months post-delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postpartum Component: Adherence to the maternal and/or infant ARV regimens, as measured by maternal report and hair measures</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through complete cessation of breastfeeding or 18 months of age, whichever comes first</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postpartum Component: Rates and patterns of maternal and infant resistance to the maternal and infant ARV regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postpartum Component: Cost-effectiveness and feasibility of the study ARV prophylaxis regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Death</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: AIDS-defining illness</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Composite endpoint of progression to AIDS-defining illness, death, or a serious non-AIDS cardiovascular, hepatic, or renal event</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: HIV/AIDS-related events</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Cardiovascular or other metabolic events</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Other targeted medical conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Composite endpoint of HIV/AIDS-related event or death</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Composite endpoint of HIV/AIDS-related event or World Health Organization (WHO) Clinical Stage 2 or 3</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Composite endpoint of any condition outlined in Appendix IV of the protocol or death</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Tuberculosis</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Toxicity: Grade 3 or greater laboratory results or signs and symptoms and selected Grade 2 hematologic, renal, and hepatic laboratory results</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Viral resistance</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Self-reported adherence</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Changes in plasma concentrations of inflammatory and thrombogenic markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal Health Component: Cost-effectiveness</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at the end of the 5-year study period</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postpartum Component: Pharmacokinetic parameters of ARV drugs measured in maternal plasma, hair, breast milk, and infant blood (plasma or dried blood spot) samples collected at birth; Weeks 1, 6, 14, and 26; and subsequent visits during breastfeeding</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through the last study visit during breastfeeding, or 18 months postpartum, whichever comes first</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postpartum Component: Functional maternal antibody and HIV-envelope binding responses in breast milk and plasma, until cessation of breastfeeding or 18 months postpartum, whichever comes first</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through the time of cessation of breastfeeding or 18 months postpartum, whichever comes first</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>8</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">3484</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Arm A (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive ZDV + sdNVP + TRV.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Arm B (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive 3TC-ZDV + LPV-RTV.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Arm C (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive TRV + LPV-RTV.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Infant Prophylaxis Regimen</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All infants in the antepartum part of the study will receive NVP each day through 42 days of age or until the Week 6 study visit, whichever is later, regardless of the mother's study arm assignment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Postpartum: Arm A (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Women will receive LPV-RTV plus TRV from the Week 1 postpartum visit through the end of maternal follow-up (2 to 5 years). Infants will receive NVP once a day through 6 weeks (42 days) of age.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Postpartum: Arm B (Infant Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Infants will receive NVP from 6 (up to 14) days of age until there is no longer any risk of MTCT or until the end of follow-up (104 weeks), whichever comes first.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Maternal Health: Arm A (Continue triple ARV regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will continue receiving the triple ARV regimen (TRV + LPV-RTV).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Maternal Health: Arm B (Discontinue triple ARV regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will discontinue the triple ARV regimen.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Zidovudine (ZDV)</intervention_name>
    <description>Antepartum Arm A: 300 mg orally twice daily beginning at greater than or equal to 14 weeks gestation (at study entry) through delivery</description>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Arm A (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nevirapine (NVP)</intervention_name>
    <description>For women, 200 mg orally (one single dose) at onset of labor; for infants, oral suspension (dosing according to birth weight) once a day beginning as soon as possible after birth until there is no longer any risk of MTCT or until the end of follow-up (104 weeks), whichever comes first.
Postpartum Arm B infants: NVP age-based daily dosing starting from Week 1 postpartum visit (day 6-14) and continuing for up to 2 weeks after complete breastfeeding cessation or completion of follow up, whichever comes first.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Arm A (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Infant Prophylaxis Regimen</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Postpartum: Arm A (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Postpartum: Arm B (Infant Regimen)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Emtricitabine-tenofovir disoproxil fumarate (Truvada [TRV])</intervention_name>
    <description>Antepartum Arm A: 200 mg/300 mg x 2 tablets for a total dose of 400 mg/600 mg orally once ideally at onset of labor or as soon as possible thereafter; 200 mg/300 mg (1 tablet) orally each day after delivery for 7 days or the date of the Week 1 visit (up to 14 days), whichever is later.
Antepartum Arm C: 200 mg/300 mg orally once daily beginning at greater than or equal to 14 weeks gestation (at study entry) until Week 1 postpartum visit (up to 14 days)
Postpartum Arm A: 200 mg/300 mg orally once daily from Week 1 postpartum visit until completion of followup.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Arm A (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Arm C (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Postpartum: Arm A (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Maternal Health: Arm A (Continue triple ARV regimen)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lamivudine-Zidovudine (3TC-ZDV)</intervention_name>
    <description>Antepartum Arm B: 150 mg/300 mg orally twice daily beginning at greater than or equal to 14 weeks gestation (at study entry) through delivery and until 1 week postpartum visit (up to 14 days)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Arm B (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lopinavir-ritonavir (LPV-RTV)</intervention_name>
    <description>Antepartum Arm B: A daily dose of 400 mg/100 mg orally twice daily beginning at &gt;/= 14 weeks gestation (at study entry) through 28 weeks gestation (through second trimester); daily dose of 600 mg/150 mg orally twice daily beginning at &gt;/= 28 weeks gestation or at next visit (during third trimester) through delivery; daily dose of 400 mg/100 mg orally twice daily after delivery until Week 1 postpartum visit (up to 14 days).
Antepartum Arm C: dailly dose of 400 mg/100 mg orally twice daily beginning at &gt; 14 weeks gestation (at study entry) through 28 weeks gestation (through second trimester); daily dose of 600 mg/150 mg orally twice daily beginning &gt; 28 weeks gestation, or at the next visit (during third trimester) through delivery; daily dose of 400 mg/100 mg orally twice daily after delivery until week 1 postpartum visit (up to 14 days).
Postpartum Arm A: a total daily dose of 800 mg/200 mg orally twice daily from Week 1 postpartum visit until completion of followup.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Arm B (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Antepartum: Arm C (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Postpartum: Arm A (Maternal Regimen)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Maternal Health: Arm A (Continue triple ARV regimen)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Antepartum Component Inclusion Criteria (Step 1):

          -  Confirmed HIV-1 infection, defined as documented positive results from two samples
             collected at different timepoints prior to study entry. More information on this
             criterion can be found in the protocol.

          -  Currently pregnant and greater than or equal to 14 weeks gestation based on clinical
             or other obstetrical measurements

          -  CD4 count greater than or equal to 350 cells/mm^3, or greater than or equal to the
             country-specific threshold for initiation of treatment (if that threshold is greater
             than 350 cells/mm^3), on a specimen obtained within 30 days prior to study entry

          -  Results of HBV screening (HBsAg testing) available from specimen obtained within 30
             days prior to study entry

          -  The following laboratory values from a specimen obtained within 30 days prior to
             study entry:

               1. Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 7.5 g/dL

               2. White blood cell count (WBC) greater than or equal to 1,500 cells/mm^3

               3. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) greater than or equal to 750 cells/mm^3

               4. Platelets greater than or equal to 50,000 cells/mm^3

               5. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) less than or equal to 2.5 times the upper limit
                  of normal (ULN)

               6. Estimated creatinine clearance of greater than or equal to 60 mL/min using the
                  Cockroft-Gault equation for women

          -  Plans to deliver in the study-affiliated clinic or hospital

          -  Has no plans to move outside of the study site area during the 24 months following
             delivery

          -  Age of legal majority for the respective country and willing and able to provide
             written informed consent

          -  Intends to breastfeed

        Antepartum Component Exclusion Criteria (Step 1):

          -  Participation in PROMISE for a prior pregnancy

          -  Ingestion of any antiretroviral (ARV) regimen with three or more drugs (regardless of
             duration) or more than 30 days of a single or dual ARV regimen during current
             pregnancy, according to self report or available medical records

          -  Requires triple ARV therapy (HAART) for own health based on local standard guidelines

          -  World Health Organization (WHO) stage 4 disease

          -  Prior receipt of HAART for maternal treatment indications (e.g., CD4 less than 350
             cells/mm^3 or clinical indications); however, could have received ARVs for the sole
             purpose of prevention of mother-to-child transmission (PMTCT) in previous pregnancies
             (prior PMTCT regimens could have included a triple ARV regimen, ZDV, 3TC-ZDV, and/or
             sdNVP for PMTCT, as well as use of a short dual nucleoside reverse transcriptase
             inhibitor [NRTI] &quot;tail&quot; to reduce risk of NVP resistance.)

          -  In labor - at onset or beyond (may be eligible for the Late Presenter registration)

          -  Clinically significant illness or condition requiring systemic treatment and/or
             hospitalization within 30 days prior to study entry

          -  Current or history of tuberculosis (TB) disease (positive PPD without TB disease is
             not exclusionary)

          -  Use of prohibited medications within 14 days prior to study entry (refer to the
             protocol for a list of prohibited medications)

          -  Fetus detected to have serious congenital malformation (ultrasound not required to
             rule out this condition)

          -  Current documented conduction heart defect (specialized assessments to rule out this
             condition are not required; a heart murmur alone and/or type 1 second-degree
             atrioventricular block [also known as Mobitz I or Wenckebach] is not considered
             exclusionary)

          -  Known to meet the local standard criteria for treatment of HBV (Note: HBV DNA testing
             or other specialized assessments are not expected to be performed as part of this
             study. A woman would be excluded only if this information is documented from other
             sources and she meets the local standard criteria for HBV treatment based on those
             assessments.)

          -  Social or other circumstances that would hinder long-term follow-up, in the opinion
             of the site investigator

          -  Currently incarcerated

        Antepartum Component Inclusion Criteria (Step 2):

          -  On Antepartum Step 1 Arm A (ZDV + sdNVP + TRV tail); OR on Antepartum Step 1 Arm B or
             C (maternal triple ARV prophylaxis) and currently receiving triple ARV prophylaxis
             but does not meet the criteria for switching to a second line regimen and Step 3
             entry; OR on Antepartum Step 1 Arm B or C (maternal triple ARV prophylaxis) and is
             not enrolled in the Postpartum Component or Maternal Health Component but remains in
             the observational follow-up and is not currently receiving a triple ARV regimen
             (stopped the regimen)

          -  Reached an indication for triple ARV therapy (HAART) for own health, as specified in
             the protocol

          -  Willing and able to initiate HAART

        Antepartum Component Exclusion Criteria (Step 2):

        Antepartum Component Inclusion Criteria (Step 3):

          -  On Antepartum Step 1 Arm B or C or on Step 2

          -  Met the criteria for switching to a second line regimen, as specified in the
             protocol, while on a triple ARV regimen

          -  Willing and able to initiate an alternative triple ARV regimen

        Antepartum Component Exclusion Criteria (Step 3):

          -  Women on Antepartum Step 1 Arm B or C who were not enrolled in the Postpartum
             Component or Maternal Health Component but remain in observational follow-up and are
             not currently receiving a triple ARV regimen

        Postpartum Component Inclusion Criteria (Step 1):

          -  Participation in the Antepartum Component or registered as a Late Presenter

          -  Intent to breastfeed

          -  Provided written informed consent

          -  Has no plans to move outside of the study site area during the 24 months following
             delivery

          -  Maternal CD4 count greater than or equal to 350 cells/mm^3, or greater than or equal
             to the country-specific threshold for initiation of treatment (if that threshold is
             greater than 350 cells/mm^3), from a specimen obtained within 30 days prior to study
             entry. More information on this criterion can be found in the protocol.

          -  The following maternal laboratory values within 30 days prior to entry:

               1. Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 7.0 g/dL

               2. WBC greater than or equal to 1,500 cells/mm^3

               3. ANC greater than or equal to 750 cells/mm^3

               4. Platelets greater than or equal to 50,000 cells/mm^3

               5. ALT less than or equal to 2.5 times the upper limit of normal (ULN)

               6. Estimated creatinine clearance of greater than or equal to 60 mL/min using the
                  Cockroft-Gault equation for women

          -  Infant alive, healthy, less than or equal to 14 days of age, and uninfected (negative
             HIV NAT result on specimen drawn prior to study entry)

          -  The following infant lab values on specimen obtained prior to study entry (within 14
             days of birth):

               1. Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 10 g/dL

               2. WBC greater than or equal to 1,500 cells/mm^3

               3. ANC greater than or equal to 750 cells/mm^3

               4. Platelets greater than or equal to 50,000 cells/mm^3

               5. ALT less than or equal to 2.5 times the ULN

          -  For Registered Late Presenters: Confirmed maternal HIV-1 infection, defined as
             documented positive results from two samples collected at different time points at
             any time prior to entry. More information on this criterion can be found in the
             protocol.

        Postpartum Component Exclusion Criteria (Step 1):

          -  Positive infant HIV NAT result on specimen drawn prior to entry or no infant HIV NAT
             result on specimen drawn prior to entry

          -  Life-threatening infant illness or birth condition incompatible with life

          -  Infant birth weight less than 2.0 kg

          -  Social or other circumstances that would hinder long-term follow-up, as judged by the
             site investigator

          -  Current or history of TB disease (positive PPD without TB disease is not
             exclusionary)

          -  Current documented conduction heart defect (specialized assessments to rule out this
             condition are not required; a heart murmur alone and/or type 1 second-degree
             atrioventricular block [also known as Mobitz I or Wenckebach] is not considered
             exclusionary)

          -  Requires triple ARV therapy (HAART) for own health (includes women who are on Step 2
             of the Antepartum Component and women who are on Step 3 of the Antepartum Component
             for immunologic/clinical disease progression requiring a change in their triple ARV
             regimen). Note: Women on Step 3 of the Antepartum Component who were never on Step 2
             and who entered Step 3 for toxicity or virologic failure without clinical or
             immunologic disease progression requiring a complete change in the triple ARV regimen
             are eligible for the Postpartum Component.

        Postpartum Component Inclusion Criteria (Step 2):

          -  On Step 1 Arm B (infant prophylaxis); OR on Step 1 Arm A (maternal prophylaxis) and
             currently receiving triple ARV prophylaxis but does not meet the criteria for
             switching to a second line regimen and entry into Step 3; OR on Step 1 Arm A
             (maternal prophylaxis) and not enrolled in the Maternal Health Component but remains
             in observational follow-up and is not currently receiving a triple ARV regimen
             (stopped the regimen)

          -  Reached an indication for triple ARV therapy (HAART), as specified in the protocol

          -  Willing and able to initiate HAART

        Postpartum Component Exclusion Criteria (Step 2):

        Postpartum Component Inclusion Criteria (Step 3):

          -  On Step 1 Arm A or on Step 2

          -  Met the criteria for switching to a second line regimen, as specified in the
             protocol, while on a triple ARV regimen

          -  Willing and able to initiate an alternate triple ARV regimen

        Postpartum Component Exclusion Criteria (Step 3):

          -  On Step 1 Arm A and was not enrolled in the Maternal Health Component but remains in
             observational follow-up and is not currently receiving a triple ARV regimen

        Maternal Health Component Inclusion Criteria (Step 1):

          -  Randomly assigned to triple ARV prophylaxis as part of the Postpartum Component and
             has continued triple ARV prophylaxis until the current randomization without
             treatment interruption (defined as more than 14 consecutive days of missed dosing)
             within the previous 30 days; OR randomly assigned to triple ARV prophylaxis in the
             Antepartum Component but ineligible for the Postpartum Component and has continued
             triple ARV prophylaxis until the current randomization without treatment interruption
             (defined as more than 7 consecutive days of missed dosing) within the previous 30
             days

          -  Within 8 weeks after complete breastfeeding cessation is achieved (defined as
             completely stopping all exposure to breast milk for greater than or equal to 28
             days); i.e., within 29 to 84 days of last breast milk exposure, or reached 18 months
             postpartum (whichever comes first). Women who reach 18 months postpartum while still
             breastfeeding will be eligible for entry within 2 weeks before and 4 weeks after the
             Week 74 visit (Week 72-78); OR if the woman was randomized to triple ARV prophylaxis
             in the Postpartum Component and her infant is infected and still breastfeeding, she
             will be eligible for the Maternal Health Component within 42 days of specimen
             collection for the confirmatory infant HIV NAT; OR if the woman was randomized to
             triple ARV prophylaxis in the Antepartum Component but mother-infant pair was
             ineligible for the Postpartum Component she will be eligible for the Maternal Health
             Component beginning at the Week 1 visit (6-14 days postpartum) through 28 days after
             delivery; these women should be randomized as soon as possible, ideally within 6-14
             days after delivery; OR if the woman was randomized to triple ARV prophylaxis in the
             Postpartum Component and breastfeeding risk for MTCT ceases for other reasons (e.g.,
             infant death or permanent removal from home through legal services or adoption)
             within 28 days of event. More information on this criterion can be found in the
             protocol.

          -  Provided written informed consent

          -  CD4 cell count greater than or equal to 350 cells/mm^3, or greater than or equal to
             the country-specific threshold for initiation of treatment (if that threshold is
             greater than 350 cells/mm^3), on a specimen obtained within 30 days prior to study
             entry

          -  The following laboratory values on a specimen obtained within 30 days prior to study
             entry:

               1. ANC greater than or equal to 750 cells/mm^3

               2. Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 7.0 gm/dL

               3. Platelet count greater than or equal to 50,000 cells/mm^3

               4. ALT (SGPT) less than or equal to 2.5 times the ULN

               5. Estimated creatinine clearance of greater than or equal to 60 mL/min using the
                  Cockroft-Gault equation for women

          -  Intend to remain in current geographical area of residence for the duration of study

        Maternal Health Component Exclusion Criteria (Step 1):

          -  WHO Stage 4 disease

          -  Clinically significant illness or condition requiring systemic treatment and/or
             hospitalization within 30 days prior to study entry

          -  Current or history of TB disease (positive PPD without TB disease is not
             exclusionary)

          -  Use of prohibited medications within 14 days prior to study entry

          -  Social or other circumstances that would hinder long term follow-up as judged by the
             site investigator

          -  Current documented conduction heart defect (specialized assessments to rule out this
             condition are not required; a heart murmur alone and/or type 1 second-degree
             atrioventricular block [also known as Mobitz I or Wenckebach] is not considered
             exclusionary)

          -  Requires a triple ARV regimen for own health (includes women who are on Step 2 of the
             Antepartum Component or the Postpartum Component and women who are on Step 3 of the
             Antepartum Component or the Postpartum Component who entered Step 3 for
             immunologic/clinical disease progression requiring a change in their triple ARV
             regimen [HAART]).

        Maternal Health Component Inclusion Criteria (Step 2):

          -  On Step 1 Arm B (discontinue the study triple ARV regimen arm); OR on Step 1 Arm A
             (triple ARV regimen) and currently on the triple ARV regimen but does not meet the
             criteria for switching to a second line regimen and entry into Step 3

          -  Reached an indication for triple ARV treatment for own health, as specified in the
             protocol

          -  Willing and able to re-initiate or continue triple ARV therapy

        Maternal Health Component Exclusion Criteria (Step 2):

        Maternal Health Component Inclusion Criteria (Step 3):

          -  On Step 1 Arm A or Step 2

          -  Meets the criteria for switching to a second line regimen, as specified in the
             protocol, while on a triple ARV regimen

          -  Willing and able to initiate an alternate triple ARV regimen (HAART)

        Maternal Health Component Exclusion Criteria (Step 3):

          -  On Step 1 Arm B
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mary Glenn Fowler, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins Medical Institute, Makerere U.-JHU Research Collaboration</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Byramjee Jeejeebhoy Medical College (BJMC) CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pune</city>
        <state>Maharashtra</state>
        <zip>411001</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Blantyre CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Blantyre</city>
        <country>Malawi</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Malawi CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lilongwe</city>
        <country>Malawi</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Soweto IMPAACT CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Johannesburg</city>
        <state>Gauteng</state>
        <zip>1862</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shandukani Research CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Johannesburg</city>
        <state>Gauteng</state>
        <zip>2001</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Durban Paediatric HIV CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <state>KwaZulu-Natal</state>
        <zip>4001</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Umlazi CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <state>KwaZulu-Natal</state>
        <zip>4001</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Family Clinical Research Unit (FAM-CRU) CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tygerberg</city>
        <state>Western Cape Province</state>
        <zip>7505</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kilimanjaro Christian Medical Centre (KCMC)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moshi</city>
        <country>Tanzania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MU-JHU Research Collaboration (MUJHU CARE LTD) CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kampala</city>
        <country>Uganda</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>George CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lusaka</city>
        <country>Zambia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seke North CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chitungwiza</city>
        <country>Zimbabwe</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Mary's CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chitungwiza</city>
        <country>Zimbabwe</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Harare Family Care CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Harare</city>
        <country>Zimbabwe</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
    <country>Malawi</country>
    <country>South Africa</country>
    <country>Tanzania</country>
    <country>Uganda</country>
    <country>Zambia</country>
    <country>Zimbabwe</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Taha T, Nour S, Li Q, Kumwenda N, Kafulafula G, Nkhoma C, Broadhead R. The effect of human immunodeficiency virus and breastfeeding on the nutritional status of African children. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2010 Jun;29(6):514-8. doi: 10.1097/INF.0b013e3181cda531.</citation>
    <PMID>20054287</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Becquet R, Ekouevi DK, Arrive E, Stringer JS, Meda N, Chaix ML, Treluyer JM, Leroy V, Rouzioux C, Blanche S, Dabis F. Universal antiretroviral therapy for pregnant and breast-feeding HIV-1-infected women: towards the elimination of mother-to-child transmission of HIV-1 in resource-limited settings. Clin Infect Dis. 2009 Dec 15;49(12):1936-45. doi: 10.1086/648446. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19916796</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>October 11, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 1, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lopinavir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nevirapine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Zidovudine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Emtricitabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lamivudine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lamivudine, zidovudine drug combination</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Emtricitabine, Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
