<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01147029</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: GSAO may stop the growth of solid tumors by blocking blood flow to the tumor. PURPOSE: This phase I trial is studying the side effects and best dose of GSAO in treating patients with advanced solid tumors that have not responded to therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>GSAO in Treating Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors That Have Not Responded to Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - To determine the maximum-tolerated dose and recommended phase II dose of angiogenesis inhibitor GSAO in patients with advanced, refractory solid tumors. - To assess the safety and toxicity profile and dose-limiting toxicity of this drug in these patients. Secondary - To determine the pharmacokinetics of this drug in these patients. - To determine the pharmacodynamics of this drug in these patients. - To determine possible anti-tumor activity in patients treatment with this drug. Tertiary - To further determine the pharmacodynamics of this drug in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter, dose-escalation study. Patients receive angiogenesis inhibitor GSAO IV over 1 hour on days 1-5 and 8-12. Treatment repeats every 21 days for 6 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients showing clinical benefit (i.e., stable disease, partial response, or complete response) may receive 6 additional courses of treatment. Patients receive angiogenesis inhibitor GSAO IV over 1 hour on day -7 to obtain pharmacokinetics information of a single IV dose of the drug. Patients also undergo dynamic contrast-enhanced magnetic-resonance imaging (DCE-MRI) prior to, during, and after study to determine blood flow parameters. Blood samples are collected periodically for pharmacokinetic, pharmacodynamic, and biomarker studies. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 28 days and then once a month thereafter. Peer Reviewed and Funded or Endorsed by Cancer Research UK.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Angiogenesis Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed advanced solid tumor Refractory to conventional treatment or for which no conventional therapy exists Disease assessable by DCEMRI and should be of a size that can be adequately assessed by these techniques No known primary brain tumors or brain metastases PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: WHO performance status 01 Life expectancy ≥ 12 weeks Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL Platelet count ≥ 100 x 10^9/L Neutrophil count ≥ 1.5 x 10^9/L Serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) ALT and AST ≤ 2.5 times ULN Creatinine clearance ≥ 50 mL/min (uncorrected value) Serum potassium and magnesium normal No proteinuria &gt; grade 1 either on 24hour urine or on 2 consecutive dipsticks taken no less than 1 week apart Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception 4 weeks prior to, during, and for 6 months after completion of study therapy Not at high medical risk due to nonmalignant systemic disease, including active uncontrolled infection No serologically positive hepatitis B, hepatitis C, or HIV No concurrent congestive heart failure or prior NYHA class IIIIV cardiac disease None of the following medical conditions: Angina (stable or severe, even if well controlled on medication) Myocardial infarction in the past 2 months by ECG Congestive cardiac failure Arrhythmias, including any condition associated with QTc prolongation (e.g., LangeNeilson syndrome or Romano Ward syndrome) Evidence of ischemia QTc &gt; 480 msec Other clinically significant abnormalities No uncontrolled hypertension (defined as BP consistently greater than 160/100 mm Hg irrespective of medication) No other condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would not make the patient a good candidate for this clinical trial No pacemakers No metal fragments in the eyes or shrapnel or bullet injuries PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics Recovered from all prior treatments (except for alopecia or certain grade 1 toxicities which, in the opinion of the investigator and Cancer Research UK, should not exclude the patient) At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy (except for palliative reasons), endocrine therapy, immunotherapy, or chemotherapy (6 weeks for nitrosoureas and mitomycin C) At least 1 week since prior and no concurrent shellfish At least 6 weeks since prior major surgery (including thoracic and/or abdominal surgery) and recovered Concurrent luteinizinghormone releasinghormone (LHRH) analogues allowed for patients with castrationrefractory prostate cancer provided the prostatespecific antigen level is rising No prior heart or brain surgery No concurrent drug known to prolong the QTc interval No concurrent warfarin (1 mg for maintenance of a Hickman line is acceptable) or heparin (flushing of arterial lines, if necessary, is acceptable) No concurrent naproxen (other NSAIDs are acceptable) No concurrent prophylactic use of antiemetics during the first treatment Domperidone and lorazepam must not be used as antiemetics No other concurrent anticancer therapy or investigational drugs Concurrent bisphosphonates allowed</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>unspecified adult solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
</DOC>