<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01868516</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Overactive bladder (OAB) is a syndrome characterized by symptoms of a sudden need to urinate with or without incontinence (leaking). The purpose of this study is to test whether dexmecamylamine is safe and effective compared to placebo for the treatment of symptoms of OAB.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Evaluating the Safety, Tolerability, and Efficacy of Dexmecamylamine (TC-5214) for Treatment of Overactive Bladder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study included a three- or five-week screening period, followed by a 12-week treatment period during which patients received either one of three doses of dexmecamylamine or placebo twice daily, randomized in a ratio of 2:1:1:1 (placebo, low dose, mid dose, high dose), with a two-week follow-up period. A total of 768 subjects with overactive bladder were randomized into the double-blind treatment period of the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Overactive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Verified medical history of overactive bladder for at least 6 months Capable of walking unassisted to use the bathroom Able to measure voided urine volume and complete the diary without assistance If the subject is currently being treated with an OAB medication, the subject is willing to discontinue OAB medications while participating in this study Diagnosis of a neurological disease affecting bladder function Stress incontinence, insensate incontinence, overflow incontinence or incontinence due to urinary fistula History of incomplete bladder emptying, bladder outflow obstruction or postvoid residual bladder volume &gt; 150 mL Males with benign prostatic hyperplasia or with a prostatespecific antigen (PSA) of 4 ng/mL or more Other urinary tract pathology such as malignancy, ureteric reflux, bladder stone, uninvestigated hematuria, urethral stricture, or cystitis Prior treatment with intravesical or intraprostatic botulinum toxin in the last 2 years Myasthenia gravis Angle closure glaucoma Current implantation of interstim electrodes or vaginal surgical mesh Presence of a clinically significant medical condition at any time during the study Presence of clinically significant abnormalities in laboratory findings, physical exam findings or vital signs Participated in an investigational drug trial within 3 months of screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>