<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01868945</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the dose of Hy.D Calcifediol 25 SD/S (a metabolite of vitamin D3) which will achieve the range of mean serum 25(OH)D between 75-100nmol/L in physically frail elderly people after 24 weeks of daily supplementation with different doses of Hy.D Calcifediol 25 SD/S compared to vitamin D3.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose Finding Study in Physically Frail Elderly to Measure 25(OH) Vitamin D Levels After Supplementation With Hy.D Calcifediol 25 SD/S and Vitamin D3</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcifediol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>25(OH)D levels between 25 50 nmol/L; Age 65 and older; Physically frail, based on the criteria designed by Fried et al. [1]. Frailty will be defined as a clinical syndrome in which one or more of the following criteria are present: unintentional weight loss (4.5 kg in past year), selfreported exhaustion (CESD questionnaire), weakness (grip strength), slow walking speed and low physical activity (Minnesota questionnaire). These criteria are easily assessable and have been commonly used to determine frailty; Men and women; Body mass index between 20 and 35 kg/m2 (used for stratification); Willingness and ability to comply with the protocol. Medical Illness: malabsorption syndrome: known intestinal malabsorption, celiac diseases, inflammatory bowel disease; diseases that may enhance serum calcium concentration: sarcoidosis, lymphoma, kidney stone in the last 10 years, primary hyperparathyroidism; abnormal indices of calcium metabolism, uncontrolled hypocalcaemia; diagnosed renal insufficiency, diagnosed cancer, diagnosed liver failure. Hypercalcemia : serum calcium adjusted for albumin of &gt; 2.6 nmol/L. Medication: bisphosphonate or Parathyroid hormone (PTH) treatment, tuberculostatics, epilepsy medication, interfering with vitamin D metabolism and vitamin D supplementation. Use of vitamin D supplementation in the last three months (excluding multivitamin supplementation). Not willing to stop the use of multivitamin supplementation during the study. (Expected) increase in exposure to sunlight (e.g. travelling to a sunny resort). Patient heavily consumes alcohol containing products defined as greater than (&gt;) 3 drinks (beer, wine, or distilled spirits) of alcoholic beverages per day. Donating blood in the period of 2 months before, until 1 month after the end of the study. Planned surgery. Participation in another clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vitamin D3</keyword>
	<keyword>Calcifediol 25</keyword>
	<keyword>Frail</keyword>
	<keyword>Dose-response</keyword>
</DOC>