<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01868308</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Our objective is to investigate the predictive value of a panel of biomarkers associated with two biologically plausible pathways of preterm birth: membrane breakdown and cervical remodeling. The investigators will obtain cervical length, cervicovaginal fetal fibronectin, and a panel of novel cervicovaginal biomarkers associated with cervical remodeling in a prospective cohort of symptomatic women with a singleton pregnancy at high risk for preterm birth in an effort to better risk stratify this cohort.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Screening To Obviate Preterm Birth</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Preterm Birth is a complex syndrome for which several different biologically plausible pathways have been proposed, including mechanical uterine distension, abruption, inflammation, and/or activation of the fetal hypothalamic-pituitary-axis. However, despite our knowing the complexity of this syndrome and the different pathways involved, there is a paucity of clinical studies investigating whether detection of more than one of these pathways in a single patient might enhance the identification of those at greatest risk for preterm birth. We propose investigating the predictive value of a panel of biomarkers associated with two biological plausible pathways - membrane breakdown and cervical remodeling - that must be involved in the pathogenesis of preterm birth. Specifically, we propose measuring cervical length and collecting cervicovaginal fetal fibronectin as well as a panel of novel cervicovaginal biomarkers that reflect molecular pathways involved in cervical remodeling in a prospectively collected cohort of symptomatic women with singleton fetuses at high risk for preterm birth. Through this study we hope improve risk stratification of this high risk cohort.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obstetric Labor, Premature</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Singleton pregnancy between 22 33 6/7 weeks of gestational age. Must be experiencing one ore more of the following symptoms including but not limited to preterm contractions, abdominal cramping, back pain, vaginal pressure, or light vaginal bleeding. Women with a multifetal pregnancy Intra uterine fetal demise Preterm premature rupture of membranes Overt chorioamnionitis</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>