<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02515565</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Acute respiratory infections are the fourth cause of hospitalization in elderly. Various studies have examined the impact of hospitalization in patients with respiratory pathology, showing the need of interventions in order to reduce the impact of hospitalization. The objective of this study is to examine whether a physical therapy intervention can reduce impairment in patients hospitalized due to pneumonia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physiotherapy in Patients Hospitalized Due to Pneumonia.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Acute respiratory infections are the fourth cause of hospitalization in elderly. Hospital admissions due to pneumonia range from the 1.1 and 4 per 1,000 patients, increasing with age. Hospitalization causes a decline in physical and functional status. Physical impairment involves a higher risk of disability and mortality in elderly people. Various studies have examined the impact of hospitalization in patients with respiratory pathology, and it has been shown that hospitalization implies a significant physical impairment in patients admitted for pneumonia showing that this deterioration increases with age. That highlights the need of interventions in order to reduce the impact of hospitalization. The objective of this study is to examine whether a physical therapy intervention can reduce impairment in patients hospitalized due to pneumonia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin Estolate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin Ethylsuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin stearate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cephalosporins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of pneumonia. No contraindication of physiotherapy. Signed written consent. Medical approval for inclusion. Contraindications of physiotherapy. Neurological, orthopedic or heart disease. Prosthetic devices in lower limbs.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>pneumonia</keyword>
	<keyword>Exacerbation</keyword>
	<keyword>physiotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>hospitalization</keyword>
</DOC>