<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00788229</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether artificial tears are safe and effective in the treatment of Dry Eye Syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Study of ATs in Patients With Dry Eye Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Keratoconjunctivitis Sicca</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dry Eye Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Keratoconjunctivitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female adults aged 18 years and over. Subjects should diagnosed as dry eye syndrome in both eyes or one eye, keratoconjunctivitis sicca (KCS), or should have at least a 3month history diagnosed as dry eye syndrome due to Sjögren syndrome. Subjects must agree to discontinue all artificial tears from Screening for 2 weeks Subjects must discontinue lens wear one week before Screening and agree not to wear contact lenses during the entire study. Subjects who have taken Restasis® are eligible for inclusion if they have not used Restasis® during the 4 weeks prior to Screening Subjects must provide signed informed consent prior to participation in any studyrelated procedures Subjects who dose not Participate in same clinical trial within 6 month prior to Screening. Pregnancy or lactation. Females of childbearing potential who are not using systemic contraception,are not postmenopausal (≥ 1 year), or are not surgically sterilized. Ocular surgery (of any type, including laser surgery) or ocular trauma within the 4 months prior to Screening. Any active inflammation of the eye not due to KCS Other diseases or characteristics judged by the investigator to be incompatible with the assessments needed in this study or with reliable instillation of the study medication.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dry Eye Syndromes</keyword>
	<keyword>Keratoconjunctivitis Sicca</keyword>
	<keyword>artificial tears</keyword>
	<keyword>carboxymethylcellulose sodium</keyword>
	<keyword>sodium hyaluronate</keyword>
</DOC>