<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00788255</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Oxytocin is normally administered following delivery in pregnant patients to reduce postpartum bleeding by increasing uterine tone. It is unclear whether the use of intravenous oxytocin alters coagulation in pregnant patients. The purpose of the in-vitro study is to assess the coagulation changes of oxytocin in blood samples from pregnant patients using thromboelastrography (TEG). TEG is a point-of-care device which measures the viscoelastic properties of clot formation, and can provide rapid and detailed information about coagulation changes. We aim to collect blood samples from pregnant patients to assess the in-vitro effects of synthetic oxytocin on coagulation using TEG.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>In-vitro Study to Assess the Coagulation Effects of Exogenous Oxytocin Using Thromboelastography.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All obstetric patients presenting for elective induction of labor or elective Cesarean delivery will be informed about the study prior to and on admission to the labor and delivery unit. Admission blood sampling will take place by venepuncture for the following analysis:TEG, PT, PTT, INR, Hct, Platelet count.The results of oxytocin influence on thromboelastogram parameters will be compared to a control. The control is an aliquot of parturient blood with no added oxytocin. Thromboelastography will be used to assess coagulation changes between control samples and blood samples with added oxytocin. The results will not be used to influence clinical management of any case.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Oxytocin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All obstetric patients with singleton pregnancies admitted to the labor and delivery unit at Lucile Packard Childrens Hospital awaiting elective induction of labor or elective Cesarean delivery. We will select 25 healthy ASA 1 patients with singleton pregnancies who are scheduled for uncomplicated elective induction of labor. Gestational age equal to or greater than 37 weeks. Patients with underlying coagulation disorders. Patients with thrombocytopenia. Patients with pregnancyinduced hypertension, preeclampsia. Patients admitted for nonelective cesarean section. Patients in active labor. Patients requiring the following medications prior to surgery: NSAIDS, aspirin, anticoagulants. Patients with significant obstetric or medical disease. No patients &lt;18 years of age will be recruited.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>