<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00788034</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will evaluate the long-term maintenance of efficacy of Lu AA21004 in patients with Generalized Anxiety Disorder (GAD) who responded to acute treatment with Lu AA21004.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Relapse-prevention Study With Lu AA21004 (Vortioxetine) in Patients With Generalized Anxiety Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>GAD is a common and disabling mental disorder associated with substantial medical and psychiatric comorbidity and occupational impairment. It is characterized by inappropriate or excessive anxiety and worrying that persists over time for more than six months. Common features include apprehension, with worries about future misfortune; inner tension and difficulty in concentrating; motor tension, with restlessness, tremor and headache; and autonomic anxiety symptoms, with excessive perspiration, dry mouth and epigastric discomfort. GAD is typically a chronic disorder with a high relapse rate and therefore requires effective long-term treatment. Long-term studies are necessary to demonstrate that the short-term effect is maintained.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vortioxetine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient has GAD as the primary diagnosis according to DSMIVTR criteria (classification code 300.02). The patient has a HAMA total score &gt;=20 at screening and baseline visits The patient has a HAMA score &gt;=2 on both Item 1 (anxious mood) and Item 2 (tension) at screening and baseline visits The patient has a MADRS total score &lt;=16 at screening and baseline visits Any current psychiatric disorder other than GAD as defined in the DSMIVTR (assessed with the MINI) Any substance disorder (except nicotine and caffeine) within the previous 6 months as defined in the DSMIVTR Women of childbearing potential not using effective contraception Other protocoldefined inclusion and exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Relapse prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>GAD</keyword>
	<keyword>Maintenance</keyword>
	<keyword>Double-blind</keyword>
	<keyword>Multicentre</keyword>
</DOC>