<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01575379</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Recent evidence from epidemiological studies suggests that serum uric acid levels higher than average predispose diabetic patients to kidney damage. The purpose of this study is to gather preliminary information on whether lowering serum uric acid by means of oral allopurinol (a drug commonly used for the treatment of gout) can be used to prevent or delay the loss of kidney function that may accompany diabetes. The results of this study will help us design a larger study to find out whether this medication can prevent kidney problems, in particular the loss of kidney function, in people with type 1 diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pilot Study of Allopurinol to Prevent Kidney Function Loss in Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Nephropathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Allopurinol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female T1D patients between 18 and 60 years of age. T1D diagnosed before age 35 and continuously treated with insulin within one year from diagnosis. If the onset was between ages 31 and 35, body mass index (BMI) will be required to be &lt; 26 kg/m2 at the time of diagnosis; Duration of T1D ≥ 5 years; Presence of microalbuminuria or moderate macroalbuminuria (at least two out of three consecutive urinary albumin excretion rates [AER] or urinary albumin/creatinine ratios (ACR) measured during the preceding two years in the 301500 mg/24 hr or the 301500 mg/g range, respectively). Estimated GFR (based on serum creatinine and the CKDEPI equation) between 35 and 109 ml/min/1.73 m2 at the screening visit. Measured GFR between 45 and 99 ml/min/1.73 m2 at the end of the runin period; Serum UA ≥ 4.5 mg/dl at the screening visit. Willing to comply with schedule of events and protocol requirements. History of gout requiring uric acid lowering therapy or xanthinuria or other indications for uric acid lowering therapy such as cancer chemotherapy or extremely high serum uric acid values (≥12 mg/dl) Recurrent renal calculi. Use of uratelowering agents within 3 months before enrollment. Current use of azathioprine, 6mercaptopurine, didanosine, warfarin, tamoxifen, amoxicillin/ampicillin, or other drugs interacting with allopurinol. Known allergy to xanthineoxidase inhibitors or iodine containing substances. HLA B*58:01 genotype (determined at the time of randomization) indicating increased risk of StevensJohnson syndrome in response to allopurinol. Renal transplant. Nondiabetic kidney disease as indicated by medical history and/or laboratory findings. SBP&gt;160 or DBP &gt;100 mmHg at screening or SBP&gt;140 or DBP&gt;90 mmHg at the end of the runin period. Cancer treatment within two years before enrollment. History of clinically significant hepatic disease including hepatitis B or C and/or ALT (SGPT) &gt;2.50 x ULN at screening; History of acquired immune deficiency syndrome or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV); Hemoglobin concentration &lt;11 g/dL (males), &lt;10 g/dL (females) at screening. Platelet count &lt;100,000/mm3 at screening. History of alcohol or drug abuse in the past 12 months Breastfeeding or pregnancy or unwillingness to be on contraception. Poor mental function or any other reason to expect patient difficulty in complying with the requirements of the study. Serious preexisting medical problems other than diabetes, e.g. congestive heart failure, pulmonary insufficiency.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>allopurinol</keyword>
	<keyword>uric acid</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>nephropathy</keyword>
</DOC>