<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01878838</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study compares two FDA approved Cataract Lasers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Comparison of Cataract Lasers Using the Optimedica Catalys Laser and the Alcon LenSx Laser.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to systematically evaluate the performance of two commercially available and FDA cleared femtosecond laser systems in patients undergoing femtosecond laser-assisted cataract surgery. Objective data on the repeatability and accuracy of the studied parameters will be gathered and reported as endpoints of the study. The two systems studied are the Catalys™ Precision Laser System (OptiMedica, CA, USA) and the LenSx® Laser System (Alcon Laboratories, Inc., Fort Worth, TX). Published data have suggested that the femtosecond laser is a useful tool for cataract surgery. This study is to determine whether differences or similarities exist in specific treatment parameters achieved with two FDA cleared and commercially available femtosecond laser cataract surgery platforms</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cataract</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have grade 2 to 4 nuclear sclerotic and or cortical or posterior subcapsular cataracts with visual impairment. Pupillary dilation of at least 6.0 mm Axial length between 21 mm to 26 mm Age ≥ 22 years of either gender Require laser assisted corneal incisions, capsulotomy and nucleus segmentation Understand and sign a written Informed Consent form Be able to comply with the treatment and followup schedule Enrolment in another drug or device study within the prior 3 months History of ocular trauma Acute or chronic disease or illness that would increase risk or confound study results (e.g., uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, immunocompromised, etc.) Uncontrolled systemic or ocular disease Corneal abnormalities (e.g., stromal, epithelial or endothelial dystrophies, severe corneal opacities, significant corneal edema, etc) Diminished aqueous clarity that obscures OCT imaging of the anterior lens capsule Corneal ring and/or inlay implant(s) Pseudoexfoliation Known steroid IOP responder or ocular hypertension IOP &gt;25 mmHg by tonometry Retinal detachment within the last 6 months Anterior chamber depth less than 2.5 mm</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>22 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>