<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01878825</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the immunogenicity, reactogenicity and safety of Fluviral™ containing the influenza strains recommended for the 2013-2014 season in adults aged 18 years and older.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunogenicity and Safety Study of GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) Biologicals' Trivalent Split Virion Influenza Vaccine Fluviral™ (2013-2014 Season) in Adults Aged 18 Years and Older</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who, in the opinion of the investigator, can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol. A male or female 18 years of age and older at the time of the first vaccination. Written informed consent obtained from the subject. Healthy subjects or subjects with wellcontrolled chronic disease, as established by medical history and clinical examination before entering into the study. Female subjects of nonchildbearing potential may be enrolled in the study. Nonchildbearing potential is defined as premenarche, current tubal ligation, hysterectomy, ovariectomy or postmenopause. Female subjects of childbearing potential may be enrolled in the study, if the subject: has practiced adequate contraception for 30 days prior to vaccination, and has a negative pregnancy test on the day of vaccination, and has agreed to continue adequate contraception during the entire treatment period and for 2 months after completion of the vaccination dose. Use of any investigational or nonregistered product (drug or vaccine) other than the study vaccine 30 days preceding the dose of study vaccine, or planned use during the study period. Chronic administration (defined as more than 14 days in total) of immunosuppressants or other immunemodifying drugs within six months prior to the vaccine dose. For corticosteroids, this will mean prednisone ≥ 20 mg/day, or equivalent. Inhaled and topical steroids are allowed. Any administration of a longacting immunemodifying drug (e.g. rituximab, infliximab etc.) within 6 months before study start, or planned administration during the study period. Administration of any influenza vaccine within 6 months preceding the study start or planned use of such vaccines during the study period. Administration of any other vaccine(s) within 30 days prior to study enrollment or during the study period. Clinically or virologically confirmed influenza infection within the 6 months preceding the study vaccination. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, based on medical history and physical examination (no laboratory testing required): History of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, Cancer or treatment for cancer, within 3 years of study enrollment. Persons with a history of cancer who are diseasefree without treatment for 3 years or more are eligible. Acute disease and/or fever at the time of enrollment. Acute disease is defined as the presence of a short term, moderate or severe illness, with or without fever. Fever is defined as temperature ≥ 38.0°C/100.4°F for oral, axillary or tympanic route. The preferred route for recording temperature in this study will be oral. Subjects with a minor illness (such as mild diarrhea, mild upper respiratory infection) without fever may, be enrolled at the discretion of the investigator. Significant acute or chronic, uncontrolled medical or psychiatric or neurological illness. "Uncontrolled" is defined as: Requiring institution of new medical or surgical treatment within one month prior to study enrollment, or Requiring the reinstitution of a previously discontinued medication or medical treatment within one month prior to study enrollment, or Requiring a change in medication dosage in the one month prior to study enrollment due to uncontrolled symptoms or drug toxicity (elective dosage adjustments in stable subjects are acceptable), or Hospitalization or an event fulfilling the definition of a SAE within one month prior to study enrollment. Acute or chronic, clinically significant pulmonary, cardiovascular, hepatic or renal functional abnormality, as determined by physical examination or laboratory screening tests. Subjects who participated in the registration trial [116664 (FLU QTIV014)] for Fluviral™ 2012/2013 conducted in the 20122013 season. Presence of blood dyscrasias, including hemoglobinopathies and myelo or lymphoproliferative disorder. A history of any demyelinating disease including Multiple Sclerosis and GuillainBarré syndrome. Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within the 3 months preceding the dose of study vaccine or planned administration during the study period. Any known or suspected allergy to any constituent of Fluviral™ and/or a history of anaphylactic type reaction to consumption of eggs, and/or reactions to products containing mercury. A history of severe adverse reaction to a previous influenza vaccination. Pregnant or lactating female. History of chronic alcohol consumption and/or drug abuse as deemed by the investigator to render the potential subject unable/unlikely to provide accurate safety reports. Any condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, prevents the subject from participation in the study or would make the intramuscular injection unsafe.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Immunogenicity</keyword>
	<keyword>Trivalent</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Adults</keyword>
	<keyword>Elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza</keyword>
</DOC>