<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02137499</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators will be evaluating the immediate and longer term effect of treatment with a medical device on the symptoms of chronic venous disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Venous Insufficiency and Neuromuscular Stimulation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>STUDY AIMS 1. To obtain ultrasound blood flow and velocity measurements in the leg to compare the hemodynamic profiles obtained using a neuromuscular stimulation device with those obtained at rest. 2. To ascertain if a 6 week protocol of electrical neurostimulation of the muscle pumps in the leg and foot can reduce clinical symptoms and improve quality of life. METHODS Controlled interventional trial. Group 1 (10 subjects) will be healthy subjects with no clinical venous disease. Subjects with venous incompetence to be recruited into one of three groups. Group 2 (10 subjects) will have superficial venous incompetence; Group 3 (10 subjects) will have deep venous incompetence; Group 4 (10 subjects) will have deep vein occlusion. These will be clinical diagnoses confirmed with duplex ultrasound. The device used in this study will be the geko™ T-1 device (Firstkind Ltd, UK). A geko™ device will be fitted to each leg. The device stimulation level is set to the minimum level that can achieve the desired response (outward and upward twitching of the foot when raised from the ground). ENDPOINTS Primary end-point - Increase in venous flow Secondary end points - Improvement in clinical symptoms at 6 weeks, as judged by questionnaire - Reduction in absolute leg diameter and volume at 6 weeks</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Venous Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Group 1 Inclusion criteria 18+ years old, 17&lt;BMI&lt;30 Exclusion criteria Heart/lung/kidney failure, pregnancy, diagnosis of peripheral vascular disease, previous VTE, ABPI&lt;0.9, active infection, previous leg fracture or metal implant in leg Group 2 Inclusion criteria 18+ years old, 17&lt;BMI&lt;30, clinical diagnosis of superficial venous insufficiency (CEAP C26) confirmed with duplex US Exclusion criteria Heart/lung/kidney failure, pregnancy, ABPI&lt;0.9, active infection, previous leg fracture or metal implant in leg Group 3 Inclusion criteria 18+ years old, 17&lt;BMI&lt;30, clinical diagnosis of deep venous insufficiency (CEAP C26) confirmed with duplex US Exclusion criteria Heart/lung/kidney failure, pregnancy, ABPI&lt;0.9, active infection, previous leg fracture or metal implant in leg Group 4 Inclusion criteria 18+ years old, 17&lt;BMI&lt;30, clinical diagnosis of deep venous obstruction confirmed with duplex US Exclusion criteria Heart/lung/kidney failure, pregnancy, ABPI&lt;0.9, active infection, previous leg fracture or metal implant in leg</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>