<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00682643</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess long-term ocular safety of fluticasone furoate nasal spray in adult and adolescent subjects diagnosed with perennial allergic rhinitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Study With Fluticasone Furoate Nasal Spray And Vehicle Placebo For The Treatment Of Perennial (Year-round) Allergic Rhinitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic, Perennial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects eligible for enrollment in the study must meet all of the following criteria: Informed consent Subject has provided an appropriately signed and dated informed consent. An appropriately signed and dated assent must be obtained from the parents or guardian if the subject is a child under 18 years of age. Outpatient Subject is treatable on an outpatient basis. Age 12 years of age and older at Visit 2 Male or eligible female Female subjects should not be enrolled if they plan to become pregnant during the time of study participation. To be eligible for entry into the study, females of childbearing potential must commit to the consistent and correct use of an acceptable method of birth control, as defined by the following: Abstinence Females of childbearing potential who are not sexually active must commit to complete abstinence from intercourse for two weeks before exposure to the study drug, throughout the clinical trial, and for a period after the trial to account for elimination of the drug (minimum of six days). Oral contraceptive (either combined estrogen/progestin or progestin only) Injectable progestogen Implants of levonorgestrel Percutaneous contraceptive patches Intrauterine device (IUD) or intrauterine system (IUS) with a documented failure rate of less than 1% per year, Male partner who is sterile (vasectomy with documentation of azoospermia) prior to the female subject's entry into the study and is the sole sexual partner for that female subject, or Double barrier methodcondom or occlusive cap (diaphragm or cervical /vault caps) plus Spermicide, Estrogenic vaginal ring. A urine pregnancy test will be done at the screening visit to confirm females of childbearing potential are not pregnant upon entry into the study. In addition, urine pregnancy tests will be done for all females of childbearing potential at each clinic visit. Diagnosis of PAR to include: A positive skin test (by prick method) response to appropriate perennial allergen (house dust mites, animal dander, mold, or cockroach) within last 12 months prior to Visit 1 or at Visit 1. A positive skin test is defined as a wheal ³3mm larger than the diluent control for prick testing. •Two year medical history and past treatment of PAR (written or verbal confirmation) which includes perennial, i.e., yearround, symptoms. PAR symptoms could include nasal congestion, rhinorrhea, nasal itching and sneezing. In vitro tests for specific IgE (such as RAST, PRIST) will not be allowed for the diagnosis of PAR. NOTE: Subjects who meet the above criteria and who also may have seasonal allergic rhinitis (SAR) and/or perennial nonallergic rhinitis (PNAR) are eligible for randomization. Environment •Subject must be symptomatic to appropriate perennial allergen (animal dander, house dust mites, cockroach, mold) and willing to maintain, as much as possible, the same environment throughout the study. Ability to comply with study procedures Subject understands and is willing, able and likely to comply with study procedures and restrictions. Literate Subject must be able to read, comprehend, and record information in English Subjects meeting any of the following criteria must not be enrolled in the study: Significant concomitant medical conditions, defined as but not limited to: A historical or current evidence of clinically significant uncontrolled disease of any body system (e.g., tuberculosis, psychological disorders, eczema). Significant is defined as any disease that, in the opinion of the investigator, would put the safety of the subject at risk through study participation or which would confound the interpretation of the study results if the disease/condition exacerbated during the study. History or current diagnosis of diabetes mellitus Uncontrolled hypertension (i.e., systolic blood pressure ³ 140mm Hg or diastolic blood pressure ³ 90mm Hg) A severe physical obstruction of the nose (e.g., deviated septum or nasal polyp) or nasal septal perforation that could affect the deposition of double blind intranasal study drug Nasal (e.g., nasal septum) or ocular injury/surgery in the last 6 months (including LASIK eye surgery) Asthma, with the exception of mild intermittent asthma [National Asthma Education and Prevention Program (NAEPP) Guidelines for the Diagnosis and Management of Asthma Expert Panel Report 3, National Institutes of Health, August 28, 2007. NOTE: Subjects will be allowed to use shortacting inhaled beta2 agonists ONLY on an as needed basis. Rhinitis medicamentosa Bacterial or viral infection (e.g., common cold) of the eyes or upper respiratory tract within two weeks of Visit 1 or during the screening period Documented evidence of acute or significant chronic sinusitis, as determined by the individual investigator Current or history of glaucoma and/or ocular herpes simplex Current cataract and/or previous history of cataract surgery Physical impairment that would affect subject's ability to participate safely and fully in the study Clinical evidence of a Candida infection of the nose History of psychiatric disease, intellectual deficiency, poor motivation, substance abuse (including drug and alcohol) or other conditions that will limit the validity of informed consent or that would confound the interpretation of the study results History of adrenal insufficiency History of Hepatitis B or C Use of corticosteroids, defined as: Intranasal corticosteroid within 4 weeks prior to Visit 1 (e.g., VERAMYST, FLONASE™, Nasonex, Rhinocort). Inhaled, oral, intramuscular, intravenous, ocular, and/or topical corticosteroids (with the exception of topical hydrocortisone, 1% or less, or equivalent) within 8 weeks prior to Visit 1. Use of other allergy medications within the timeframe indicated relative to Visit 1 Intranasal or ocular cromolyn within 14 days prior to Visit 1 (e.g., Nasalcrom, Crolom) Shortacting prescription and nonprescription antihistamines, including ocular preparations and antihistamines contained in insomnia and "night time" pain formulations, within 3 days prior to Visit 1 (e.g., Benadryl, Chlortrimeton, Dimetane, Tavist) Longacting antihistamines within 10 days prior to Visit 1 (e.g., Allegra, Claritin, Clarinex, Zyrtec). Intranasal antihistamines (e.g., Astelin) within 2 weeks prior to Visit 1 Oral or intranasal decongestants within 3 days prior to Visit 1 (e.g., Sudafed) Longacting betaagonists within 3 days prior to Visit 1 (e.g., SEREVENT™, Foradil) Intranasal, oral, or inhaled anticholinergics within 3 days prior to Visit 1 (e.g., Atrovent) Oral antileukotrienes within 3 days of Visit 1 (e.g., Singulair) Subcutaneous omalizumab (Xolair) within 5 months of Visit 1 Use of other medications that may affect allergic rhinitis or its symptoms Chronic use of concomitant medications, such as tricyclic antidepressants, that would affect assessment of the effectiveness of the study drug Use of other intranasally administered medications (e.g., Miacalcin) Use of immunosuppressive medications 8 weeks prior to screening and during the study Immunotherapy Immunotherapy patients may be enrolled in the study if the immunotherapy was not initiated within 30 days of Visit 1, if the dose has remained fixed over the 30 days prior to Visit 1, and the dose will remain fixed for the duration of the study. Use of any medications that significantly alter the pharmacokinetics of fluticasone furoate (ritonavir and ketoconazole) Use of chronic treatment with agents known to promote the development of cataracts (e.g., potassiumsparing diuretics and allopurinol) Allergy/Intolerance Known hypersensitivity to corticosteroids or any excipients Clinical trial/experimental medication experience Has recent exposure to an investigational study drug within 30 days of Visit 1 Participation in a previous or current FFNS (GW685698X) clinical study Positive urine pregnancy test or female who is breastfeeding Has a positive or inconclusive pregnancy test at Visit 1 or Visit 2 Affiliation with investigational site Subject is a participating investigator, subinvestigator, study coordinator, or employee of a participating investigator, or is an immediate family member of the aforementioned. Tobacco use Subject currently uses smoking products including cigarettes, cigars, and pipe or chewing tobacco, or has used these products in the last 6 months Chickenpox or measles A subject is not eligible if he/she currently has chickenpox or measles, or has been exposed to chickenpox or measles during the last three weeks and is nonimmune. If a subject develops chickenpox or measles during the study, he/she will be withdrawn from the study. If a nonimmune subject is exposed to chickenpox or measles during the study, his/her continuation in the study will be at the discretion of the investigator, taking into consideration the likelihood of developing active disease. Findings of a clinically significant, abnormal ECG Findings of a clinically significant laboratory abnormality</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Perennial Allergic Rhinitis</keyword>
	<keyword>fluticasone furoate</keyword>
	<keyword>ocular safety</keyword>
</DOC>