<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00101985</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the effectiveness and safety of the investigational drug talnetant in treating subjects with irritable bowel syndrome (IBS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Eight-Weeks Of Treatment With Talnetant In Subjects With Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Subjects will be required to conduct selfassessments of their IBS symptoms using a touchtone telephone system for the duration of the study (15 weeks). Must be diagnosed with IBS consistent with the Rome II criteria. Must have normal results from a colonic procedure within 2 years of randomization. Must have conducted selfassessments on at least 12 days and have a documented average IBS pain or discomfort score of greater than or equal to 1.5 during the twoweek screening phase. Exclusion criteria: Selfassessment of no stool for 7 days during the twoweek screening phase. Clinically significant abnormal laboratory tests. Current evidence or history of various conditions, comorbidities, or surgeries such as Irritable Bowel Disease (IBD), gastrointestinal surgeries, and diverticulitis. Inability to use the touchtone telephone system. Hypersensitivity to quinolone antibiotics or quinolone derivatives. Diagnosis of a psychiatric disorder within the past 2 years and not on a stable dose of medication for at least 6 months. Women who are pregnant, breast feeding, or planning to become pregnant during the study. Permitted medications: The subject is allowed to take any of the following medications, provided they maintain a stable dose for at least 30 days prior to the Screening visit and throughout the remainder of the study: Antidepressants, except REMERON Antihypercholesterolemics Iron supplements Bulking agents Fiber supplement Thyroid replacement therapy (levothyroxine) Antipsychotics Cox2 inhibitors (CELEBREX) Prohibited medications: Subjects must stop taking any medications they are taking to treat their IBS symptoms and must not have taken any of the prohibited medications at least 7 days prior to the Screening visit and must remain off these medications for the duration of the study. Anticholinergics (dicyclomine, hyoscyamine, propantheline) Cholinomimetic (bethanechol, pyridostigmine, tacrine, physostigmine) All narcotics (morphine, codeine, TYLENOL #3, propoxyphene, either alone or in combination) Tramadol hydrochloride (ULTRAM) Colchicine Orlistat (XENICAL) Misoprostol, alone or in combination (ARTHROTEC, CYTOTEC) 5HT3 receptor antagonists (ondansetron, tropisetron, dolasetron, granisetron, mirtazapine, cilansetron, alosetron) Tegaserod (ZELNORM) Gabapentin Lupron Antacids containing magnesium or aluminium Antidiarrheal agents Bismuth compounds Prokinetic agents (cisapride, metoclopramide) Sulfasalazine Laxatives Cholestyramine</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
	<keyword>Irritable bowel syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>IBS</keyword>
	<keyword>SB223412</keyword>
	<keyword>Qol</keyword>
</DOC>