<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00101582</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to test the safety and effectiveness of palifermin to determine if weekly doses can be safely administered to reduce the incidence (occurrence of), duration (length of time) and severity (amount of pain) of oral mucositis (painful sores in the mouth). Mucositis is a common side effect for patients receiving chemotherapy (cancer-killing drug) and radiotherapy (cancer-killing x-rays) for the treatment of head and neck cancer (HNC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Palifermin for the Reduction of Oral Mucositis in Patients With Locally Advanced Head and Neck Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study consisted of 2 phases. The acute oral mucositis (OM) evaluation phase includes the time from randomization to the time of severe OM (WHO Grade 3 or 4) resolution (up to Week 12 or up to Week 15 for participants whose severe OM is not resolved at Week 12). In the acute OM evaluation phase, participants were randomized to receive either a single IV dose of palifermin or placebo at 180 μg/kg, 3 days before the start of radiotherapy, plus 7 once-weekly palifermin or placebo doses at the same dose level during a 7-week radio/chemotherapy course. In the long-term follow up phase, participants are followed until death, withdrawal of consent, or loss to follow-up. The long-term follow up phase is still ongoing.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mucositis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stomatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitogens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Histologically documented squamous cell carcinoma involving either the oral cavity, oropharynx, nasopharynx, hypopharynx, or larynx Newly diagnosed, locally advanced stage head and neck cancer (unresectable/unresected disease); American Joint Committee on Cancer [AJCC] Stage III, IVA or IVB amenable to radiotherapy with concurrent chemotherapy as the definitive treatment modality At least 50 Gray of radiation treatment to areas of the oral cavity/oropharynx mucosa that can be visualized Concurrent chemotherapy regimen of Cisplatin 100mg/m^2 on days 1, 22, and 43 Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) less than or equal to 2 Adequate hematologic, renal and hepatic function Negative pregnancy test by serum or urine Signed informed consent Key Presence or history of any other primary malignancy (other than curatively treated in situ cervical cancer, or basal cell carcinoma of the skin without evidence of disease for greater than 3 years)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>SCCHN</keyword>
	<keyword>Palifermin</keyword>
	<keyword>Mucositis</keyword>
	<keyword>Oral Cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>Oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>Nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>Larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>Mouth Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Mouth Sores</keyword>
	<keyword>Radiation Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Radiotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Radiochemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Concurrent Chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Xerostomia</keyword>
	<keyword>Stomatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Mucosa</keyword>
	<keyword>KGF</keyword>
	<keyword>rHuKGF</keyword>
	<keyword>Keratinocyte Growth Factor</keyword>
	<keyword>HNC</keyword>
	<keyword>Head and Neck Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Oral Mucositis</keyword>
</DOC>