<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02804568</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will determine the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics (PK) of olanzapine and samidorphan in adults with schizophrenia following 14 consecutive days of oral administration of ALKS 3831.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 1 Safety Study in Adults With Schizophrenia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Has a body mass index (BMI) of 18.035.0 kg/m^2, inclusive Has a primary diagnosis of schizophrenia Capable of understanding and complying with the procedures, requirements, and restrictions of the protocol. Appropriate for outpatient treatment Agrees to abide by the contraception requirements specified in the protocol for the duration of the study or is surgically sterile Willing and able to provide governmentissued identification Is in good physical health Agrees to maintain normal tobacco use as well as normal activities/exercise throughout the study Additional criteria may apply Is currently pregnant or breastfeeding Initiated first antipsychotic treatment within the past 12 months, or &lt;1 year has elapsed since the initial onset of activephase schizophrenia symptoms Poses a current suicide risk at Visits 1 or 2 Has a history of poor or inadequate response to treatment with olanzapine Has used a longacting injectable antipsychotic medication in the last 6 months with the exception of 3month paliperidone, which must not have been received within the past 12 months. Requires or has had electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) treatment in the 6month period prior to Visit 1 Has a diagnosis of alcohol or drug use disorder (with the exception of nicotine) Has taken opioid agonists (codeine, oxycodone, tramadol, or morphine) within the 14 days prior to Visit 1 and/or anticipates a need to take opioid medication during the study period. Has taken opioid antagonists including naltrexone (any formulations) and naloxone within 60 days prior to Visit 1, or has used any extendedrelease formulation of an opioid antagonist within 2 months prior to screening Tests positive for amphetamines/methamphetamine, cocaine, barbiturates, opioids (codeine, hydrocodone, hydromorphone, methadone, morphine, oxycodone, oxymorphone, and buprenorphine), phencyclidine and benzodiazepines. Has a known or suspected intolerance, allergy or hypersensitivity to olanzapine or opioid antagonists. Additional criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Alkermes</keyword>
	<keyword>ALK 3831</keyword>
	<keyword>Samidorphan</keyword>
</DOC>