<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02804477</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims at finding degree of adherence of patients to their chronic pain medication prescriptions containing opioid e.g. Morphine, using Morisky Medication Adherence Scale 8, self- reported questionnaire. Also relationship of various demographic, disease related and opioid related factors to medication adherence.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Validation and Assessment of Patient Adherence to Opioids for Cancer Pain Using MMAS 8 Pain Clinic</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After institutional review board approval, a Pilot study including 30 patients will be conducted to validate Morisky Medication Adherence Scale 8 to validate the questionnaire for cross cultural variation. The data collected will be analyzed and result will be submitted to institutional review board for approval to conduct the parent study. Following the above approval, all adult patients , more than 18 yrs. of age, who are on a strong opioid for their chronic cancer pain, taken prescription from pain clinic at least once in past, who are able to understand and communicate Hindi will be invited to participate in the study. Each patient will be verbally asked about their medication and same will be confirmed by their previous medical records. An informed written consent will be obtained. Data will be collected by PI or co-investigator after obtaining written consent at Pain clinic(general and private) of Tata Memorial Hospital. Fund for purchasing the copyright to use the Hindi translation of Morisky Medication Adherence Scale 8, was provided by the department of Anesthesia Account, Tata Memorial Hospital, after due permission obtained from, Director Tata Memorial Center and Head of the department of Anesthesiology, critical care and pain, Tata Memorial Center. The precise scoring and permission to use the Hindi translation of the scale has been obtained from the developer. For income we will be considering private and general category of the patients respectively.Data will be analyzed using International Business machines software package for statistical analysis version 20.0.Pilot study data will be analyzed applying tests as internal consistency (Cronbach's alfa), Test retest variability and factor analysis.For parent study in the uni-variate analysis all variables listed above will consecutively tested for significant associations with ''good adherence'' as the outcome variable. Chi-square tests and Student's t-tests will used for categorical and continuous variables, respectively. All variables will be unconditionally entered into a binary logistic multi variate analysis. All p values #0.05 will regarded as statistically significant.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Analgesics, Opioid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. All adult patients &gt; 18 yrs. of age 2. Patients suffering from chronic pain of any type and severity 3. On opioid i.e. Morphine, taken prescription at least once 4. Who can understand and communicate Hindi 1. Refusal of consent 2. Paediatric patients 3. Patients who cannot understand or communicate Hindi</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>opioid</keyword>
	<keyword>MMAS 8, morisky medication adherence scale</keyword>
	<keyword>validation</keyword>
</DOC>