<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02804308</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Breast cancer is a multifactorial disease affecting women, and one of the treatments for its healing and survival is hormone therapy. Aromatase inhibitors are third-generation drugs that promote lower chance of metastasis, but their side effects include the loss of bone mineral density and increased fat percentage. In this way, the Combined Training (combined resistance and endurance training) may be an interesting strategy to minimize the side effects of aromatase inhibitors, providing better quality of life, survival and changes in body composition.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combined Training on Body Composition of Postmenopausal Women Undergoing Treatment for Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aromatase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Postmenopausal, defined by the absence of periods for the past 12 months; Breast cancer diagnosis stages 1 to 3; The adjuvant treatment for breast cancer and / or neoadjuvant aromatase inhibitors No abnormalities on screening physical or any health problems that contraindicate study participation; No contraindications for treadmill testing or entry into a training program, including any of the following: Myocardial infarction within the past 6 months Pulmonary edema Myocarditis Pericarditis Unstable angina Pulmonary embolism or deep vein thrombosis Uncontrolled hypertension (i.e., blood pressure &gt; 200/100 mm Hg) Uncontrolled arrhythmia No significant mental illness Have medical certificate to perform exercise testing and participate in combined training Able to answer Questionnaires No concurrent participation in any other organized exercise program; Live in Presidente Prudente Sign the consent form and formal clarification for participation in the study. Accumulating 3 unexcused absences or 4 consecutive unexcused absences during the month.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Combined Training</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Body Composition</keyword>
	<keyword>Postmenopausal Women</keyword>
	<keyword>Aromatase Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
</DOC>