<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00763893</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate if losartan limits aortic dilatation in patients with Marfan syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Efficacy of Losartan on Aortic Dilatation in Patients With Marfan Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Aim : evaluate the efficacy of losartan for limiting aortic dilatation in patients with marfan syndrome receiving standard therapy Inclusion criteria : 10 years or older Marfan syndrome according to international criteria Signed informed consent Non inclusion : Previous surgery of the ascending aorta, or surgery planned Non echogenicity Contre-indication lactose Pregnancy on going or planned within 3 years Breast feeding Participation in another clinical study Non member of the social security or CMU Number of subjects : the number of subjects (150 per group) is derived from the study from Shores et al (1994) demonstrating the benefit of beta-blockade in Marfan patient and uses a decrease by half of the aortic dilatation with losartan Follow-up is 3 years, after inclusion period of 2 years. A total of 5 years is expected Methods : randomised double blind vs placebo study. All French centres de competence for marfan syndrome and the centre de reference are participating in the study. End points : main endpoint is evolution of normalised aortic diameter. Secondary endpoints include clinical events (cardiac surgery or aortic dissection, hospitalisation in cardiology department, death), tolerance of the drug, and quality of life.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Marfan Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arachnodactyly</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Losartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiotensin II Type 1 Receptor Blockers</mesh_term>
	<criteria>10 years or older Marfan syndrome according to international criteria Signed informed consent Previous surgery of the ascending aorta, or surgery planned Non echogenicity Contreindication lactose Pregnancy on going or planned within 3 years Breast feeding Participation in another clinical study Non member of the social security or CMU</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Marfan syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Angiotensin II Type 1 Receptor Blockers</keyword>
	<keyword>Aortic Aneurysm, Thoracic</keyword>
</DOC>