<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00951288</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a pilot interventional study whose aim is to determine the effect of a dietary supplementation with a Crocus Sativus extract, Saffron, on macular cone-mediated function in patients with early age-related macular degeneration (AMD). Pre-clinical evidence ( Maccarone R, Di Marco S, Bisti S. Saffron supplement maintains morphology and function after exposure to damaging light in mammalian retina. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2008 Mar;49(3):1254-61.) indicates the potential effectiveness of Saffron as a retinal neuroprotectant in animal models of retinal degenerative disorders.The macular function will be tested by visual acuity and macular cone-mediated electroretinogram (focal electroretinogram, FERG) according to a standardized technique (see citations).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Saffron Supplementation on Macular Cone-mediated Function in Age-related Macular Degeneration</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A group of 30 AMD patients with typical lesions (drusen and/or retinal pigment epithelial defects) and relatively preserved central retinal function and visual acuity will be enrolled. AMD patients will be randomly divided into two groups: 1. placebo group [n = 15), taking for three months an oral placebo; 2. Saffron group (n = 15), taking Saffron oral treatment (20 mg/day) for three months. After three months of placebo or Saffron supplementation, patients will be tested with standard ophthalmic examination and FERGs. Then, placebo with Saffron and vice-versa will be changed to the same patients in a cross-over design. After a further three month period of placebo or study drug supplementation, patients will undergo again a standard ophthalmic examination, and FERG. Throughout the study, both patients and experimenters will be masked as to the identity of pills (i.e. whether placebo or study drug), whose identification key number will be kept in a sealed envelope that will be opened only at the completion of the study. Therapeutic compliance will be tested by careful questioning, either at two weeks of treatment (by telephone interview) or at the end of the treatment period, as well as by pill count. Main outcome measures of the study will be FERG amplitude and phase.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt; 55 yrs Diagnosis of Early, non exudative AMD Visual acuity of 20/40 or better Concomitant ocular or systemic disorders which may affect macular function Drugs that may affect macular function</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>AMD</keyword>
	<keyword>Retinal Function</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuroprotection</keyword>
</DOC>