<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00617344</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a follow up study using three different formulations for each serotype with the aim of testing immunogenicity and reactogenicity Primary Objective: Immunogenicity: To evaluate immunogenicity by neutralizing antibody response post dose 2. Secondary Objectives: Safety: To evaluate safety following three formulations of ChimeriVax™ Tetravalent Dengue Vaccine. Immunogenicity: To describe the neutralizing antibody responses after each dose.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunogenicity and Safety of Three Formulations of Dengue Vaccines in Healthy Adults Aged 18 to 45 Years in the US</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase II, double-blind, randomized, descriptive, multicenter study in US adult subjects. Subjects will be randomized to receive a total of three doses of ChimeriVax™ Tetravalent Dengue Vaccine from one particular formulation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dengue</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhagic Fevers, Viral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Severe Dengue</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy, as determined by medical history, clinical examination, and biological safety parameters. Aged 18 to 45 years on the day of inclusion. Provision of informed consent signed by the subject or another legally acceptable representative. For a woman of childbearing potential, use of an effective method of contraception or abstinence for at least 4 weeks prior to the first vaccination, and until at least 4 weeks after the last study vaccination. Able to attend all scheduled visits and to comply with all trial procedures. Personal or family history of thymic pathology (thymoma), thymectomy, or myasthenia. For a woman of childbearing potential, known or suspected pregnancy or positive serum/urine pregnancy test. Breastfeeding woman. Participation in another clinical trial investigating a vaccine, drug, medical device, or a medical procedure in the 4 weeks preceding the first trial vaccination. Planned participation in another clinical trial during the present trial period. Known or suspected congenital or acquired immunodeficiency, immunosuppressive therapy such as anticancer chemotherapy or radiation therapy within the preceding 6 months, or longterm (at least 2 weeks within the previous 3 months) systemic corticosteroids therapy (at a dose of at least 10 mg). Topical steroids are allowed. Known systemic hypersensitivity to any of the vaccine components or history of a lifethreatening reaction to the trial vaccine or to a vaccine containing any of the same substances. Chronic illness at a stage that could interfere with trial conduct or completion, in the opinion of the investigator. Current or past alcohol abuse or drug addiction that may interfere with the subject's ability to comply with trial procedures. Receipt of blood or bloodderived products in the past 3 months, that might interfere with the assessment of immune response. Receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks preceding the first trial vaccination. Planned receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks following each of the trial vaccinations. Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV), hepatitis B surface antigen, or hepatitis C seropositivity in blood sample taken at Screening. Subject deprived of freedom by an administrative or court order, or in an emergency setting, or hospitalized without his/her consent. Clinically significant laboratory test abnormalities (as determined by the investigator) in blood sample taken at Screening. Previous residence in, travel or planned travel of more than 2 weeks during the study period to areas with high dengue infection endemicity. (Please refer to Appendix 5 of the protocol.) Reported history of flavivirus infection as reported by the subject. Previous vaccination against flavivirus diseases (including Japanese encephalitis, tickborne encephalitis, and yellow fever) Flavivirus vaccination planned during the trial period.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dengue fever</keyword>
	<keyword>Dengue hemorrhagic fever</keyword>
	<keyword>Dengue virus</keyword>
</DOC>