<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01103271</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Placebo pills (pills with no active ingredients) have been shown in research studies to somehow produce self-healing processes. The purpose of this study is to determine whether people will be willing to enter an open-label non-deceptive placebo treatment for Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) and whether open-label placebo can be effective for treating MDD in the context of a supportive physician-patient relationship.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Study of Open-label Placebo to Treat Major Depressive Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men or women aged 1860 years old. Current Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) Pregnant women or women of child bearing potential not using a medically accepted means of contraception. Patients who are a serious suicide or homicide risk. Unstable medical illness including cardiovascular, hepatic, renal, respiratory, endocrine, neurological, or hematological disease. The following Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental DisordersIV diagnoses: 1) organic mental disorders; 2) substance use disorders, including alcohol, active within the last year; 3) schizophrenia; 4) delusional disorder; 5) psychotic disorders not elsewhere classified; 6) bipolar disorder; 7) acute bereavement; 9) severe borderline or antisocial personality disorder; 10) current primary diagnoses of panic disorder, social phobia, generalized anxiety disorder (GAD), or obsessive compulsive disorder (OCD) (disorders that present as chief complaint and/or have their onset preceding the onset of major depressive disorder). Uncontrolled seizure disorder. Patients with mood congruent or mood incongruent psychotic features. Current use of other psychotropic drugs. Exception: Patients who have been on a stable dose for 30 days of classes of medications such as nonbenzodiazepine sedatives, anxiolytic benzodiazepines, nonnarcotic analgesics may be included. Flexibility will be allowed based on physician discretion. Clinical or laboratory evidence of hypothyroidism. Patients who have taken an investigational psychotropic drug within the last year. Patients who have not responded to two or more antidepressant trials of adequate doses (e.g., fluoxetine 40 mg/day or higher) and duration (e.g.,for six weeks or more) over the past five years. Any concomitant form of psychotherapy (depression focused)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>depression</keyword>
	<keyword>placebo effect</keyword>
	<keyword>complementary therapies</keyword>
	<keyword>alternative therapies</keyword>
</DOC>