<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01103817</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to study the role of low vitamin D levels on the health of blood vessels or vascular function in adolescents and young adults with type 1 diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Influence of Vitamin D on Vascular Function in Adolescents and Young Adults With Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Vitamin D deficiency is known to be common in patients with type 1 diabetes. Studies in adults have shown that vitamin D deficiency is associated with cardiovascular events such as stroke, myocardial infarction and peripheral arterial disease. However, the impact of this deficiency on vascular health in adolescents with diabetes has not been examined. Furthermore given that endothelial dysfunction is reversible, early detection of this process may have therapeutic and prognostic implications in this population.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosed with type 1 diabetes, according to Canadian Diabetes Association guidelines 2. Diagnosed with type 1 diabetes for at least 2 years 3. Between the ages of 12 and 18 years 1. Previous organ transplantation 2. Diagnosed with familial hypercholesterolemia 3. Active smoker 4. Receiving lipid lowering medications 5. Receiving anti hypertensive medication 6. Significant chronic medical illness, including granulomatous disease 7. History of hypertension 8. BMI &gt;95%tile 9. Known renal failure 10. HbA1c greater than 12% on two successive occasions 11. Known peripheral vascular disease 12. Known hypercalcemia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 1 Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Adolescents and Young Adults</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular Disease</keyword>
</DOC>