<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01103375</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase I trial is studying the side effects and best dose of erlotinib hydrochloride when given with isotretinoin in treating patients with recurrent malignant glioma. Erlotinib hydrochloride may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth. Isotretinoin may help cells that are involved in the body's immune response to work better. Giving erlotinib hydrochloride together with isotretinoin may kill more tumor cells</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Erlotinib Hydrochloride and Isotretinoin in Treating Patients With Recurrent Malignant Glioma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the recommended phase II doses of erlotinib (erlotinib hydrochloride) and 13-cis-retinoic acid (CRA) when administered to adults with recurrent malignant glioma who are not receiving cytochrome P450 enzyme-inducing antiepileptic drugs (EIAEDs). SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess dose-related toxicities. II. To measure 6 month progression-free survival and overall survival. III. To estimate response rates in those patients with measurable disease. IV. To evaluate for epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)vIII, phosphatase and tensin homolog (PTEN), cyclin D1, cyclin E, and RARbeta1 expression in tumor samples from enrolled patients as predictors of clinical benefit from this combination. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study. Patients receive isotretinoin orally (PO) once daily (QD) on days 1-21 and erlotinib hydrochloride PO QD on days 1-28. Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed for up to 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Astrocytoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gliosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oligodendroglioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isotretinoin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically proven malignant glioma (glioblastoma multiforme, anaplastic astrocytoma, anaplastic oligodendroglioma, or anaplastic mixed oligoastrocytoma) which is progressive or recurrent after radiation therapy +/ chemotherapy; patients with previous low grade glioma who progressed after radiotherapy +/ chemotherapy and are biopsied and found to have a high grade glioma are eligible Karnofsky performance status of &gt;= 60% Patients both males and females with reproductive potential (i.e., premenopausal or menopausal for less than 1 year and not surgically sterilized) must practice at least 2 contraceptive measures throughout the study Patients must be registered and meet all the requirements of iPLEDGE in order to receive 13cisRetinoic Acid (CRA) Patients must provide verbal and written informed consent to participate in the study Patients must have a Mini Mental Status Exam score &gt;= 15 Patients must have a 12lead electrocardiogram (EKG) without evidence of any clinically significant abnormalities Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1,500/mm^3 Platelets &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; 2.5 upper limit of normal (ULN) (ULN = 50 U/L) Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) =&lt; 2.5 ULN (ULN = 50 U/L) Total Bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 mg/dL Alkaline phosphatase (Alk. Phos) =&lt; 5X ULN (ULN = 125 U/dL) Estimated (Estim.) creatinine (Cr) Clearance &gt; 50 ml/min Fasting total cholesterol &lt; 300 mg/dL Fasting triglycerides &lt; 250 mg/dL Two separate, laboratory pregnancy tests within 14 days of registration (for women of childbearing potential) Patients must have recovered from the toxicity of prior therapy; specifically, there must be at least a 3 month interval from the completion of the most recent course of radiation therapy, at least a 3 month interval from the implantation of Gliadel wafer(s), at least a 3 week interval from the completion of a nonnitrosoureacontaining chemotherapy regimen, and at least a 6 week interval from the completion of a nitrosoureacontaining chemoregimen Pregnant or breastfeeding women Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, severe cardiovascular disease including recent (&lt; 6 months) myocardial infarction, severe psychiatric illness that would limit compliance with study requirements, or any other disorder that would be incompatible with the study therapy Any history of inflammatory bowel disease Any history of uncontrolled depression, any history of hospitalization for depression, or any history of suicidal thoughts or attempt(s) Patients receiving concurrent therapy for their tumor (with the exception of steroids) Must have at least a 10 day interval from last dose of vitamin A, tetracyclines, microdosed progesterone preparations, norethindrone/ethinyl estradiol, St. John's Wort, fish oil supplements, or phenytoin or other P450 enzyme inducing antiepileptic drugs Current smokers (Smoking &gt;= 11 cigarettes per day), as smoking increases metabolism and decreases serum levels of erlotinib Participants may not have received prior EGFR inhibitors for any disease Patients with a history of allergic reactions to 13cisretinoic acid (CRA) or compounds of similar biologic or chemical composition to CRA Known allergy to proton pump inhibitors</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>