<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01837342</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sigmoid diverticular diseases is a pathologie frequent in patients above 60 years old. A person with diverticulosis may have few or no symptoms. When a diverticulum ruptures and infection sets in around the diverticulum the condition is called diverticulitis. An individual suffering from diverticulitis may have abdominal pain, abdominal tenderness, and fever. Bleeding originates from a diverticulum, it is called diverticular bleeding. Frequent hospitalisations as a result of the evolution of purulent peritonitis that originates from diverticulitis treated by mini-invasive surgery results. Radiological percutaneous drainage and washing of the abdominal cavity during laparoscopic generalized purulent peritonitis of diverticular origin have been identified as therapeutic options by HAS (French health authorities), followed by second stage resection-anastomosis under elective surgery. It has been observed in patients that if only drainage and washing are performed (without resection), then the morbidity (10%) and mortality (1.5%) rates are much lower than usual rates (after resection) respectively 20-40% and 10-30%. Furthermore this reduces the risks of postoperatory complications. Some studies have shown that the attitude of non-distance resection of the acute episode was associated with a recurrence rate of diverticulitis less than 5% recurrence without gravity. In addition, the morbidity associated with intervention sigmoid resection is around 30%. The question arises in our daily practice, or not to propose systematic resection of sigmoid diverticulitis after an acute episode of severe purulent peritonitis or abscess types supported initially by minimally invasive. The primary objective of the study is to determine, after clinical improvement linked to conservative treatment of perforated diverticulitis Hinchey peritonitis stage II and III, if a conservative approach reduces morbidity compared with a cold sigmoid resection attitude as currently recommended. The secondary objective of the study is to determine if conservative treatment reduces mortality, length of hospital stay compared with cumulative sigmoid diverticular disease and improves quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicenter Study Comparing Morbidity and Quality of Life Associated in the Treatment by Surgical Resection and the Conservative Treatment, After Favorable Evolution of Purulent Peritonitis That Originates From Diverticulitis Treated by Mini-invasive Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Peritonitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diverticulitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who have had an episode of sigmoid diverticulitis as a result of pelvic or purulent peritonitis (Hinchey stage II and III) complications and treated by conservative treatment such as per cutaneous radiological drainage or laparoscopicassisted per cutaneous drainage. Male and female individuals aged from 18 to 65 years old (both ages included). Absence of contraindication for surgery ASA Score ≤3 Participants must have signed informed consent document indicating that they understand the purpose and procedures required for the study and are willing to participate in the study and comply with the study procedures and restrictions Patients will sign an informed consent after haven been informed of the results of the previous medical visit. Patients must be affiliated with, or a beneficiary of a social security system Subjects in the exclusion period (haven participated in a previous trial or an ongoing trial ) Contra indication to surgery ASA Score &gt;3 Past history of evolutive neoplasm, Subjects unable to consent (case of emergency, subjects having difficulties in understanding) Patients for which consultation visits will not be possible (e.g. tourists and people who cannot stay above 18 months in France). Pregnant and breastfeeding women Subjects under tutorship or curator ship Subjets under judicial protection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>