<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00424515</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate how effective imatinib (Gleevec) is in treating acral/lentiginous and mucosal melanoma which has spread to other parts of the body in patients who's disease carries a c-kit mutation. Imatinib is a protein-kinase inhibitor. It is believed that imatinib may be effective in blocking signals on certain cancer cells which allow the malignant cells to multiply and spread.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Imatinib in Patients With Mucosal or Acral/Lentiginous Melanoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - To determine the response rate of patients with metastatic mucosal, acral/lentiginous, or chronically sun damaged melanomas to treatment with of imatinib. - To determine the time to progression. Secondary - To correlate c-kit mutational status with response to therapy. - To evaluate the use of FDG-PET scanning in determining early biologic response to therapy. - Tolerability of imatinib. - To assess amplification of c-kit status through quantitative PCR and/or FISH and other related molecular pathway targets. - To correlate c-kit amplification status with response to therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Imatinib Mesylate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Melanomas that arise on chronically sun damaged skin and have pathologic evidence of solar elastosis History of primary mucosal or acral/lentiginous melanoma Histologically documented stage IV metastatic melanoma ECOG performance status 0,1, or 2 Estimated life expectancy of 6 months or greater Age 18 years or older Creatinine &lt; 1.5 x ULN ANC &gt; 1500 ul Platelets &gt; 100,000 ul Total bilirubin, AST, and ALT &lt; 2 x ULN Amylase and lipase &lt; 1.5 x ULN Ckit mutation documented from either primary or metastatic tumor site &gt; 4 weeks from prior chemotherapy or investigational drug At least one measurable site of disease as defined by at least 1 cm in greatest dimension Severe and/or uncontrolled medical disease Pregnant or nursing mothers Any other significant medical, surgical, or psychiatric condition that my interfere with compliance Patient is &lt; 5 years free of another primary malignancy except: basal cell skin cancer or a cervical carcinoma in situ Concurrent treatment with Warfarin Prior treatment with ckit inhibitor Patient with Grade III/IV cardiac problems as defined by NYHA criteria No H2 blockers or proton pump inhibitors Known brain metastasis Known chronic liver disease Known diagnosis of HIV infection Previous radiotherapy to &gt; 25% of the bone marrow Major surgery within 2 weeks prior to study entry Patient has received any other investigational agent within 28 days of first study drug dosing Chemotherapy within 4 weeks prior to study entry</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Imatinib</keyword>
	<keyword>Gleevec</keyword>
</DOC>