<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00311623</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as sirolimus, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is studying the best dose of sirolimus and to see how well it works before surgery in treating patients with advanced localized prostate cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sirolimus Before Surgery in Treating Patients With Advanced Localized Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the pharmacodynamically optimal dose (POD) of continuous daily oral sirolimus (rapamycin) in patients with advanced localized prostate cancer when given prior to radical prostatectomy, as measured by tumor S6 kinase inhibition by immunohistochemistry (IHC). - Determine the proportion of men with downstream target inhibition in prostate tumor tissue at the POD using paired tumor biopsies from before and after rapamycin administration. - Correlate tumor pharmacodynamic (PD) efficacy with a surrogate marker of tumor PD efficacy, peripheral blood mononuclear cell (PBMC) S6 kinase activity inhibition. Secondary - Characterize the serum and prostate tissue pharmacokinetics of daily oral rapamycin at 2 dose levels. - Determine the relationship of PD target inhibition of S6 kinase activity with pretreatment Akt activity and PTEN loss by IHC in prostate cancer. - Describe the relationship between PD inhibition with the mTOR inhibitor rapamycin and pretreatment prostate biopsy Gleason sum, Ki-67 index of proliferation, Akt activity, p27 IHC, and PTEN. - Correlate PD efficacy as measured by downstream S6 kinase activity inhibition with markers of increased apoptosis (activated caspase 3) and reduction in markers of proliferation (change in Ki-67) in prostate tumor specimens. - Quantify and characterize the toxicity of daily continuous rapamycin at 2 dose levels in generally healthy men with prostate cancer prior to surgery. - Evaluate the activity of rapamycin in prostate cancer as measured in prostate specific antigen response prior to surgery. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter, dose-escalation study. Patients receive oral sirolimus (rapamycin) once daily on days 1-14 in the absence of unacceptable toxicity. Cohorts of 12-21 patients receive escalating doses of rapamycin until the pharmacodynamically optimal dose is determined. Patients undergo radical prostatectomy on day 15. Patients undergo blood collection and tumor biopsies periodically during study for pharmacologic and correlative biomarker studies. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed at 30 and 90 days. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 42 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically determined adenocarcinoma of the prostate Stage T1cT3b disease No evidence of disease that has spread beyond the prostate or seminal vesicles No metastatic prostate cancer, including bone, visceral, brain, and lymph node metastases Tumor Gleason score sum of 710 (4+3 and 3+4 allowed) with tumor involving at least 2 discrete core biopsy sections Scheduled to undergo radical prostatectomy No other subtypes of prostate cancer, including any of the following: Sarcoma Neuroendocrine tumors Small cell cancer Ductal cancer Lymphoma PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: ECOG performance status 01 WBC &gt; 3,500/mm^3 Absolute neutrophil count &gt; 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count &gt; 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin &gt; 9 g/dL Creatinine &lt; 2.0 mg/dL Bilirubin &lt; 2 mg/dL ALT and AST &lt; 2 times upper limit of normal (ULN) Alkaline phosphatase &lt; 2 times ULN Triglycerides and total cholesterol &lt; 2 times ULN No history of allergy to sirolimus (rapamycin) or its derivatives No uncontrolled medical condition that would increase risk or limit compliance with study requirements, including the following: Immunodeficiency Gastrointestinal disease that would limit ability to swallow, take oral medications, or absorb them No active infections No other concurrent malignancy PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics No prior chemotherapy, biologic therapy, radiotherapy, or immunotherapy for prostate cancer No concurrent chronic treatment with immunosuppressants or medications that interfere with the metabolism of sirolimus (rapamycin) No concurrent medication or agents that would interfere with the metabolism or excretion of rapamycin or its derivatives, including any of the following: Phenytoin Carbamazepine Cyclosporine Clarithromycin Clotrimazole Erythromycin Amiodarone Protease inhibitors used to treated HIV infection Cisapride Grapefruit juice Diltiazem Tacrolimus Hypericum perforatum (St. John's wort) Barbiturates Rifampin Phenobarbital Rifabutin Efavirenz Nevirapine At least 7 days since prior herbal medicines and medications, including any of the following: Hydrastis canadensis (goldenseal) Uncaria tomentosa (cat's claw) Echinacea angustifolia roots Trifolium pretense (wild cherry) Chamomile Glycyrrhiza glabra (licorice) Dillapiol Naringenin Norfloxacin Atorvastatin Pravastatin Cimetidine Fluconazole</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage III prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIB prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIA prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma of the prostate</keyword>
</DOC>