<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00227617</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as fluorouracil, leucovorin, and oxaliplatin, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Monoclonal antibodies, such as bevacizumab, can block tumor growth in different ways. Some block the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Others find tumor cells and help kill them or carry tumor-killing substances to them. Bevacizumab may also stop the growth of neuroendocrine tumors by blocking blood flow to the tumor. Giving combination chemotherapy together with bevacizumab may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: This phase I/II trial is studying the side effects of giving combination chemotherapy together with bevacizumab and to see how well it works in treating patients with advanced neuroendocrine tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination Chemotherapy and Bevacizumab in Treating Patients With Advanced Neuroendocrine Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the safety of fluorouracil, leucovorin calcium, and oxaliplatin (FOLFOX) with bevacizumab in patients with advanced neuroendocrine tumors. - Determine the best overall response rate in patients treated with this regimen. Secondary - Determine the overall survival of patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the time to treatment failure and progression in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the biochemical marker response in patients treated with this regimen. OUTLINE: This is an open-label, pilot study. Patients are stratified according to tumor type (carcinoid vs islet cell vs poorly differentiated neuroendocrine). Patients receive oxaliplatin IV over 2 hours and leucovorin calcium IV over 2 hours on day 1 and fluorouracil IV continuously over 46-48 hours beginning on day 1. Patients also receive bevacizumab IV over 30-90 minutes on day 1. Treatment repeats every 14 days for up to 26 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 3 months. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 39-102 patients (13-34 per stratum) will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuroendocrine Tumors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoid Tumor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malignant Carcinoid Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenoma, Islet Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed neuroendocrine tumor (NET) Carcinoid at any site, with or without carcinoid syndrome Pancreatic islet cell tumor Prior streptozocinbased therapy not required Poorly differentiated NET of any primary site (this arm closed to accrual May 2009) Progression with prior treatment with cisplatin, or carboplatinbased chemotherapy required (unless contraindicated) The following tumors are not allowed: Endocrine organ carcinoma Adrenal gland malignancies Thyroid carcinoma of any histology Pheochromocytoma/paraganglioma Advanced disease Disease not amenable to surgery, radiotherapy, or combined modality therapy with curative intent Radiologically or clinically confirmed progressive disease At least 25% increase in radiologically or clinically measurable disease At least 20% increase in the longest diameter (LD) of any previously documented lesion Increase in the sum of the LD of multiple lesions in aggregate of 20%, OR appearance of new lesions OR deterioration in clinical status Measurable disease At least 1 unidimensionally measurable lesion ≥ 20 mm by conventional radiographic techniques OR ≥ 10 mm by spiral CT scan Ultrasound or positronemission tomography alone not sufficient Bone lesions, ascites, peritoneal carcinomatosis, pleural or pericardial effusion, and irradiated lesions are not considered measurable disease Primary tumors of the pancreas should not invade adjacent organs (e.g., stomach or duodenum) No history or evidence of brain or leptomeningeal disease (baseline CNS imaging required if clinical suspicion of CNS metastases) PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 18 and over Performance status ECOG 01 Life expectancy More than 12 weeks Hematopoietic Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 No history of hemoptysis or bleeding diathesis No coagulopathy unrelated to therapeutic anticoagulation No significant bleeding events within the past 6 months unless the source of the bleeding has been resected Hepatic Bilirubin &lt; 2 mg/dL ALT ≤ 2.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) (5 times ULN if due to liver metastases) Renal Creatinine ≤ 2 mg/dL Protein ≤ 1+ OR Protein &lt; 1 gm on 24hour urine collection Urine protein:creatinine ratio &lt; 1.0 Cardiovascular History of thromboembolic condition allowed provided patient is on therapeutic anticoagulation at a stable dose for ≥ 4 weeks Concurrent daily prophylactic aspirin (&lt; 325 mg/day) allowed No uncontrolled hypertension, myocardial infarction, clinically significant peripheral arterial ischemia, visceral arterial ischemia or angina within the past 6 months No serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication No cerebrovascular event (e.g., stroke or transient ischemic attack) within the past 12 months No history of peripheral vascular disease ≥ grade 2 No history New York Heart Association class IIIV congestive heart failure Blood pressure ≤ 160/90 mm Hg Gastrointestinal No abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation, or intraabdominal abscess within the past 6 months No predisposing uncontrolled small bowel or colonic disorder Baseline diseaserelated diarrhea allowed if symptoms are stable and wellcharacterized (i.e., # stools/day stable) No gastric or esophageal varices No gastroduodenal ulcers determined to be active by endoscopy Pulmonary No interstitial pneumonia or extensive and symptomatic interstitial fibrosis No lung tumor in close proximity to a major vessel, or with associated cavitation No pleural effusion or ascites that causes ≥ grade 2 dyspnea Other Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for at least 3 months after completion of study treatment No significant traumatic injury within the past 28 days No currently active second malignancy other than, nonmelanoma skin cancer or carcinoma in situ Patients are not considered to have a currently active malignancy if they have completed therapy and are considered by their physician to be at ≤ 30% risk for relapse No known hypersensitivity reaction attributed to study drugs or to compounds of similar chemical or biological composition No symptomatic peripheral neuropathy &gt; grade 1 No other severe disease or comorbidity that would preclude study participation No medically uncontrolled seizures No active infection No serious nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture No psychiatric illness or social situation that would preclude study compliance No other severe, concurrent disease, infection, or comorbidity that in the judgement of the investigator would constitute a hazard for study participation PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy Recovered from prior cytokine therapy At least 4 weeks since prior immunotherapy No prior tyrosine kinase inhibitors or antivascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) angiogenic inhibitors Chemotherapy See Disease Characteristics At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy No prior oxaliplatin Prior chemoembolization therapy allowed provided it did not affect areas of measurable disease Endocrine therapy Prior and concurrent somatostatin analogs allowed for symptomatic control and/or control of hormone hypersecretion only provided treatment was initiated &gt; 3 months prior to study entry Radiotherapy See Disease Characteristics At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy and recovered Prior radiotherapy must not affect areas of measurable disease No concurrent radiotherapy to only site of measurable disease Surgery Recovered from prior surgery Prior cryotherapy allowed provided it did not affect areas of measurable disease At least 28 days since prior major surgical procedure or open biopsy At least 7 days since minor surgical procedure, fineneedle aspirations, or core biopsy No prior organ allograft No concurrent major surgery Other At least 4 weeks since prior participation in an experimental drug study No other concurrent investigational agents No other concurrent anticancer therapy No halogenated antiviral agents Concurrent antiplatelet agents allowed</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent gastrointestinal carcinoid tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>regional gastrointestinal carcinoid tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>pulmonary carcinoid tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>gastrinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>insulinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>WDHA syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>glucagonoma</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreatic polypeptide tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>somatostatinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent islet cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic gastrointestinal carcinoid tumor</keyword>
</DOC>