<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00227812</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test whether cognitive behavioral therapy and bupropion hydrochloride will help cocaine users, who are depressed, reduce or end their cocaine use and improve their mood.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Integrated Treatment for Cocaine and Mood Disorders - 1</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The global aim of this study is to evaluate an "integrated" treatment approach for cocaine dependent patients with comorbid unipolar depression. It is hypothesized that a cognitive-behavioral psychotherapy that targets both disorders, in combination with a pharmacotherapy, i.e., bupropion, is expected to provide the best coverage for dual disorders and thus maximize treatment outcomes. Specifically, we will conduct a double blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial involving the random assignment of participants into one of four treatment conditions according to a full 2x2 factorial research design. One independent variable will be pharmacotherapy (bupropion versus placebo); the other independent variable will be psychotherapy (integrated CBT versus clinical management). The study will enroll 140 cocaine dependent patients with comorbid major depressive disorder. A secondary objective is to further elucidate "primary" and "secondary" paradigms of depressive illness symptoms in cocaine-dependent adults and better understand how this distinction influences treatment outcome. This will be accomplished by enrolling a subsample of patients with substance-induced mood disorder. Taken together, this proposal will examine the feasibility and relative efficacy of a novel integrated treatment model for dually-diagnosed patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mood Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cocaine-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupropion</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cocaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Generally physically healthy Aged 1855 Meets cocaine dependence by DSMIV criteria Meets major depressive disorder or substanceinduced depression disorder by DSMIV criteria. Willing and able to participate in the 12 week treatment study and one year follow up. Pregnant or breastfeeding. Taking medications that interact with the study medication (MAO inhibitors, anticonvulsants, haloperidol, phenothiazines,selegiline, anesthetics Have other psychiatric diagnoses requiring therapy or medication. Physically dependent on opiates or alcohol. Currently being treated with bupropion hydrochloride (e.g. Zyban).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>cocaine dependence</keyword>
</DOC>