<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00158704</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Provide adefovir dipivoxil (Hepsera) 10 mg once daily to patients with chronic hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection who have completed a Gilead-sponsored study of adefovir dipivoxil and require continued access to adefovir dipivoxil.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Continued Access Study of Adefovir Dipivoxil (ADV) for Patients w/Chronic HBV Infection.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of this study is to provide adefovir dipivoxil 10 mg once daily to patients with chronic hepatitis B virus(HBV) infection who have completed a Gilead-sponsored study of adefovir dipivoxil and require continued access to adefovir dipivoxil. The secondary objective of this study is to evaluate the safety of chronic therapy with adefovir dipivoxil 10 mg.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adefovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adefovir dipivoxil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must have completed one of the following Gileadsponsored studies as indicated: GS96412, GS98437, GS98438, GS00461 and GS00481. If the patient has participated in another Gileadsponsored study, the CRO or Sponsor's Medical Monitor will evaluate for participation in this study on a case by case basis. Any serious or active medical or psychiatric illness that would interfere with patient treatment, assessment or compliance with the protocol or dosing requirements. Currently receiving nephrotoxic drugs such as aminoglycosides (e.g. amikacin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, netilmicin, streptomycin, tobramycin), amphotericin B, vancomycin, cidofovir, foscarnet, cisplatin, or pentamidine OR competitors of renal excretion such as probenecid and sulfinpyrazone. These agents must be discontinued at least 7 days prior to starting treatment with adefovir dipivoxil. Currently receiving investigational agents with activity against hepatitis B virus. Hypersensitivity to any of the components of the drug product. Pregnant or lactating females. Inability to comply with study requirements. Experienced a treatment limiting toxicity of adefovir dipivoxil that has not yet resolved or resulted in permanent discontinuation of adefovir dipivoxil in the previous study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Hepatitis B</keyword>
</DOC>