<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02661061</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Randomised, controlled, parallel-group, pilot clinical trial of ketamine vs. midazolam for depression relapse prevention in persons at high risk. The main purpose of the pilot study is to assess trial processes to help inform a future definitive trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ketamine for Relapse Prevention in Recurrent Depressive Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants will be recruited at admission to St Patrick's University Hospital for treatment of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 4th Edition (DSM-IV)-diagnosed recurrent unipolar depression and followed-up weekly to assess recovery according to standard criteria. Blood samples for epigenetic studies will be taken at baseline. Treatment-as-usual will continue throughout the entire trial. Participants who meet standardised response criteria will then be invited to be randomised to course of four two-weekly ketamine or midazolam (active comparator) infusions. Block randomisation will be independently performed. Physical, psychotomimetic and cognitive outcomes will be monitored before, during and after infusions. Blood samples will be taken at four time-points in the first infusion session and before the final infusion for neuroplasticity biomarker studies.Trial Interventions: participants will receive four two-weekly infusions of either ketamine at 0.05mg/kg or midazolam at 0.045mg/kg. All infusions will be administered by a consultant anaesthetist. Repeated infusions of ketamine have been shown to be safe and well-tolerated by patients with mental illness. Minor haemodynamic changes and psychotomimetic side-effects can occur and will be assessed regularly during infusions and for 200 minutes afterwards. Participants will be followed up over six months to assess for relapse according to standardised criteria. This is the highest-risk period for relapse and investigators hypothesize that ketamine will provide additional neurotrophic support (assessed by the laboratory biomarker project) which will result in lower relapse rates when compared to midazolam.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Midazolam</mesh_term>
	<criteria>≥18 years old Hamilton Rating Scale for Depression, 24item (HRSD24) score of ≥21 Voluntary admission for treatment of acute depressive episode Meet DSMIV criteria for recurrent depressive disorder (RDD): ≥2 previous depressive episodes with at least 2months(consecutive) subthreshold or no symptoms in between PLUS(to enrich the sample for those at high risk for relapse) must also have experienced ≥3 major depressive episodes(including index episode) within the previous 2 years For the randomised pilot trial, RDD patients must have: received antidepressant treatment for the acute depressive episode(pharmacological, psychotherapeutic or multidisciplinary) ≥60% decrease from baseline HRSD24 score and score ≤16 Standardised MiniMental State Examination (sMMSE) score of ≥24 able to provide informed consent Current involuntary admission Medical condition rendering unfit for ketamine/midazolam Active suicidal intention Dementia History of Axis 1 diagnosis other than RDD Electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) for treatment of current depressive episode Alcohol/substance abuse in previous six months Pregnancy or inability to confirm use of adequate contraception during the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>ketamine</keyword>
	<keyword>glutamate</keyword>
	<keyword>relapse prevention</keyword>
</DOC>