<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02661178</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will investigate the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics of single ascending doses of emodepside (BAY 44-4400) in healthy male volunteers. This study will also conduct an exploratory investigation of the relative bioavailability of emodepside administered as tablets.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>First in Man Clinical Trial of Emodepside (BAY 44-4400)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Male, Caucasian volunteers, deemed healthy on the basis of a clinical history, physical examination, ECG, vital signs, and laboratory tests of blood and urine. Optionally, after further evaluation during the study, at the sponsor's discretion other ethnic groups may be recruited. Aged 18 to 55 years. With a body mass index (BMI; Quetelet index) in the range of 18 to 30.1 kg/m2 at screening. Sufficient intelligence to understand the nature of the trial and any hazards of participating in it. Ability to communicate satisfactorily with the investigator and to participate in, and comply with the requirements of, the entire trial. Willingness to give written consent to participate, after reading the information and consent form, and after having the opportunity to discuss the trial with the investigator or his delegate Participation in another clinical trial within 3 months prior and during the study, or 5times the halflife of the drug tested in the previous clinical trial, whichever is longer (time calculated relative to the last dose in the previous clinical trial) Clinically relevant abnormal medical history, concurrent medical condition, acute or chronic illness or history of chronic illness sufficient to invalidate the subject's participation in the trial or make it unnecessarily hazardous. Surgery (eg stomach bypass) or medical condition that might affect absorption of study drug taken orally. Presence of abnormal physical findings, ECG, or laboratory values at the pretrial screening assessment that could interfere with the objectives of the trial or the safety of the subject. Positive tests for hepatitis B &amp; C, HIV Presence or history of drug or alcohol abuse during the last 10 years, or intake of more than 21 units of alcohol weekly. Regular daily consumption of more than one liter of xanthinecontaining beverages Regular daily consumption of more than 5 cigarettes daily, or use more than 3 grams (1/8 ounce) of tobacco Use of a prescription medicine during the 28 days before the first dose of trial medication or use of an overthecounter medicine, with the exception of acetaminophen (paracetamol), during the 7 days before the first dose of trial medication Use of dietary supplements or herbal remedies (such as St John's Wort) known to interfere with the CYP3A4 and/or Pgp metabolic pathways during the 28 days before the first dose of trial medication (see list in Study Procedures Manual)</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Parasitic Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Helminthiasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Nematode Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Secernentea Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Spirurida Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Filariasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Diseases, Parasitic</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin and Connective Tissue Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Diseases, Infectious</keyword>
	<keyword>Depsipeptides</keyword>
	<keyword>Emodepside</keyword>
	<keyword>Neglected disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Africa</keyword>
	<keyword>New drug</keyword>
	<keyword>Oral drug</keyword>
	<keyword>Parasite</keyword>
	<keyword>Anthelmintic drug</keyword>
	<keyword>Cyclooctadepsipeptide</keyword>
	<keyword>Single ascending dose</keyword>
	<keyword>Volunteers</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase 1</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Tolerability</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Relative bioavailability</keyword>
	<keyword>Onchocerciasis</keyword>
</DOC>