<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01012336</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The current recommended guideline for patients receiving moderately emetogenic chemotherapy (MEC) is the combination of a 5-HT3 receptor antagonist and corticosteroid. Incidence of chemotherapy induced nausea and vomiting (CINV) is approximately 50% in patients receiving MEC. An incidence rate of 25-38% for delayed emesis and 55-60% for delayed nausea has been observed. Hence, there is clearly a need for more effective prevention of CINV in patients receiving MEC, especially in women with ovarian carcinoma who are particularly susceptible to these symptoms. Therefore the investigators designed a study with the objective to evaluate if new combination (Aprepitant/Ramosetron/Dexamethasone) may improve actual CINV control in ovarian carcinoma patients treated with taxane/carboplatin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Aprepitant, Ramosetron, and Dexamethasone for Chemotherapy-Induced Nausea and Vomiting in Patients With Ovarian Cancer Treated With Taxane/Carboplatin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nausea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aprepitant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fosaprepitant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ramosetron</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Taxane</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria 1. patient is over 18 years 2. ovarian carcinoma patients who are treated with moderately emetogenic chemotherapy 3. Karnofsky score &gt; 60 4. Life expectancy &gt; 4 months Exclusion criteria 1. Any of following conditions (mentally incapacitated or emotional or psychiatric disorder, user of any illicit drugs, has an active infection, hypersensitivity to ramosetron or aprepitant) 2. Patients have received a nonapproved drug within last 4 weeks 3. abnormal laboratory values (AST &gt; 2.5 normal, ALT &gt; 2.5 normal, Bilirubin &gt; 1.5 normal, Creatinine &gt; 1.5 normal) 4. Antiemetic drugs within 48 hours of study 5. Benzodiazepine or opiate within 48 hours 6. CYP3A4 substrates within 7 days (terfenadine, cisapride, astemizole, pimozide) 7. CYP3A4 inhibitors (clarithromycin, ketoconazole) 8. CYP3A4 inducers within 30 days (Barbiturates, rifampicin, carbamazepine)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>efficacy and safety of Aprepitant/Ramosetron/Dexamethasone in ovary cancer patients with taxol and carboplatin</keyword>
</DOC>