<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01210053</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Sunitinib may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth and by blocking blood flow to the tumor. It is not yet known whether sunitinib is effective in treating non-small cell lung cancer. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying sunitinib to see how well it works when given as maintenance therapy in treating patients with stage III or stage IV non-small cell lung cancer which is previously treated with combination chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sunitinib as Maintenance Therapy in Treating Patients With Stage III or Stage IV Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - To investigate the effect of sunitinib malate on the progression-free survival of patients with stage IIIB or IV non-small cell lung cancer Secondary - To evaluate the toxicity of sunitinib when administered in the maintenance setting. - To evaluate the additional response rate to sunitinib malate when administered in the maintenance setting. - To evaluate the overall survival of patients treated with sunitinib. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 2 months for 1 year, every 6 months for 1 year, and periodically for 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sunitinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>No evidence of symptomatic or untreated brain metastases, spinal cord compression, or carcinomatous meningitis Histologically or cytologically confirmed primary nonsmall cell lung cancer who have stable or responding disease after prior treatment with 36 courses of platinum based therapy Not a candidate for combined modality therapy No cavitary lesions Evidence of symptomatic or untreated brain metastases, spinal cord compression, or carcinomatous meningitis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>