<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00271713</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Efficacy: To investigate changes of structural bone properties in vivo using 3DpQCT ("Xtreme" CT, Scanco) in monthly oral ibandronate therapy for women with postmenopausal osteoporosis. Major structural bone parameters which determine bone strength and predict fracture risk earlier and more precisely are measurable in vivo by 3DpQCT. Safety: To assess the tolerability and safety of ibandronate therapy</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Oral Ibandronate 150 mg Monthly on Structural Properties of Bone in Postmenopausal Osteoporosis (SPIMOS-3D)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis, Postmenopausal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ibandronic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diphosphonates</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age between 60 and 75 years Menopause &gt; 5 years Spine (L1 L4) or hip BMD ≤ 2.0 and &gt; 3.5 SD Tscore measured by DXA Patients who, in the opinion of the investigator, are able and willing to comply with the protocol for its duration Written informed consent 3DpQCT measurable at both skeletal sites, distal tibia and radius Spine or hip BMD ≤ 3,5 SD TScore measured by DXA Vertebral fractures Multiple (&gt;2) low trauma peripheral fractures Disease/disorder known to influence bone metabolism History of major upper gastrointestinal (GI) disease Diagnosed malignant disease within the previous 10 years Previous treatment with a bisphoshonate at any time Treatment with fluoride for osteoporosis (dose greater than 10 mg/day) within the last 12 months, or for more than 2 years (total duration) Treatment with PTH and similar agents or strontium ranelate at any time Treatment with other drugs affecting bone metabolism within the last 6 months Chronic systemic corticosteroid treatment Estrogens, progestins, SERMs, anabolic steroids, active vitamin D analogues/metabolites, calcitonin Calcineurin inhibitors (e.g. cyclosporine, tacrolimus) or methotrexate Total serum calcium &lt; 2.2 mmol/l or &gt; 2.6 mmol/l Vitamin D deficiency (serum 25hydroxy vitamin D &lt; 12 ng/ ml) ALT above triple upper limit of normal range Renal impairment (serum creatinine &gt; 210 µmol/l) Contraindications for ibandronate, calcium or vitamin D Employees of the Centre for Muscle and Bone Research, or their relatives</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>bone structure</keyword>
	<keyword>ibandronate</keyword>
</DOC>