<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT00003858</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE : Drugs use chemotherapy use different way stop tumor cell divide stop grow die . Giving chemotherapy surgery may kill tumor cell . PURPOSE : Phase II trial study effectiveness mitoxantrone give surgery treat patient prostate cancer high risk recurrence .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mitoxantrone Following Surgery Treating Patients With Prostate Cancer High Risk Recurrence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES : I. Assess feasibility enrol patient adenocarcinoma prostate high risk recurrence follow radical prostatectomy adjuvant mitoxantrone trial . II . Determine adjuvant therapy result delay time failure decrease number treatment failure compare historical control patient population .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitoxantrone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS : Adenocarcinoma prostate treat radical prostatectomy within past 3 month Considered high risk recurrence define least 1 follow characteristic radical prostatectomy specimen : Positive seminal vesicle Gleason 6 preoperative PSA great 18 ng/mL Gleason 7 preoperative PSA great 14 ng/mL Gleason 8 , 9 , 10 preoperative PSA Undetectable PSA ( i.e. , less 0.1 ng/mL ) within 3 month follow radical prostatectomy time enrollment Negative lymph node time radical prostatectomy lymphadenectomy perform Extracapsular penetration and/or positive surgical margin allow PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS : Age : 18 Performance status : Zubrod 01 Life expectancy : Not specify Hematopoietic : Granulocyte count least 1,500/mm3 Platelet count least 100,000/mm3 Hepatic : Bilirubin great 1.5 time upper limit normal ( ULN ) SGOT great 2 time ULN Renal : Not specify Cardiovascular : No New York Heart Association class III IV cardiac disease angina pectoris No myocardial infarction within past 6 month PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY : Biologic therapy : No concurrent filgrastim sargramostim except febrile neutropenia Chemotherapy : No concurrent chemotherapy Endocrine therapy : No prior neoadjuvant adjuvant hormonal therapy prostate cancer No concurrent hormonal therapy except nondisease relate condition ( e.g. , insulin diabetes ) No concurrent systemic corticosteriods unless adrenal insufficiency No concurrent prednisone , dexamethasone , steroidal antiemetic At least 6 month since prior finasteride No concurrent finasteride No concurrent antiandrogens ( e.g. , flutamide , bicalutamide , nilutamide ) gonadotropin release hormone agonist ( e.g. , leuprolide , goserelin ) Radiotherapy : No prior adjuvant radiotherapy prostate cancer No prior pelvic radiotherapy prostate cancer Surgery : See Disease Characteristics Other : At least 6 month since prior saw palmetto No concurrent compound 5 alphareductase inhibitor activity ( e.g. , saw palmetto )</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma prostate</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIB prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIA prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV prostate cancer</keyword>
</DOC>