<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01325753</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot clinical trial studies the side effects of cryotherapy (cryoablation [CA]) in treating patients with lung cancer. Cryotherapy kills cancer cells by freezing them.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cryotherapy in Treating Patients With Lung Cancer That Has Spread to the Other Lung or Parts of the Body</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Assess the initial safety of the CA for lung tumors less than or equal to 3.5 cm in size including acute toxicity (30 days). SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. Estimate local control. II. To assess physical function for this cohort of patients. III. To evaluate the impact of treatment on generic and disease-specific quality of life. IV. To obtain pilot data useful for the design of a subsequent phase II or randomized phase II trial. V. Evaluate changes in pulmonary function at 3 months. OUTLINE: Patients undergo computed tomography (CT)-guided CA After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 1 week and 1, 3, 6, 12, 24, 36, 48, and 60 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mesothelioma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC) seventh edition metastatic carcinoma or sarcoma involving the lungs or pleura. Pathologic diagnosis of stage 4 cancer prior to enrollment by biopsy or on imaging with known (biopsied) primary disease The target lesion is determined (by CT or magnetic resonance imaging [MRI] images) to be in a location where cryoablation is technically achievable based on the proximity of adjacent organs and structures Maximum number of lesions per patient will be 5 total (a maximum of 3 on either the right or left side and 2 lesions on the respective contralateral side) Of these, any lesion not treated with cryoablation will be planned to be treated with radiotherapy or radiofrequency ablation, such that all known active pulmonary disease is planned to be treated with a definitive local therapy If treatment of both lungs is to occur by cryoablation, these treatments must be separated by at least one week The lesion(s) treated with cryoablation may be intrapulmonary or pleural and must be =&lt; 3.5 cm in greatest dimension All patients are required to have been evaluated either in consultation with a radiation oncologist or at least in a multidisciplinary tumor conference to ensure that all local therapy options are appropriately considered for each patient Performance Status 02 (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group [ECOG]); Karnofsky Performance Scale &gt;= 60 Life expectancy &gt; 3 months Clinically suitable for cryoablation procedure as determined by the treating physician Platelet count &gt; 50,000/mm^3 within 60 days prior to study registration International normalized ratio (INR) &lt; 1.5 within 60 days prior to study registration Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt; 1000 within 21 days prior to study registration A signed study specific consent form is required Primary lung cancer Unable to lie flat or has respiratory distress at rest Uncontrolled coagulopathy or bleeding disorders Evidence of active systemic, pulmonary, or pericardial infection Pregnant, nursing or wishes to become pregnant during the study Debilitating medical or psychiatric illness that would preclude giving informed consent or receiving optimal treatment or follow up Currently participating in other experimental studies that could affect the primary endpoint</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>