<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01325558</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase I, open-label, multi-center, competitive enrollment and dose-escalation study of ALT-836 in combination with standard of care gemcitabine in participants who have locally advanced or metastatic solid tumors. The purpose of this study is to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD), and to assess the safety and pharmacokinetic profile of ALT-836 given with gemcitabine. The clinical benefit, progression-free survival and overall survival of study participants will also be assessed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of ALT-836 in Combination With Gemcitabine for Locally Advanced or Metastatic Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Tissue Factor (TF) is over-expressed in most cancer types. Results from many recent studies have suggested a key role for TF in the development of cancer-associated thrombosis, tumor growth, tumor angiogenesis, and tumor metastasis. ALT-836, a recombinant human-chimeric monoclonal antibody, is designed as a direct TF antagonist to block TF displayed by cancers and to inhibit cancer-associated venous thromboembolism, tumor growth, tumor angiogenesis and tumor metastasis. In numerous pre-clinical studies in laboratory animals, including non-human primates, ALT-836 exhibits potent anti-tumor, anti-thrombotic and anti-inflammatory activities with a remarkable safety profile. In humans, ALT-836, administered as a single bolus and monotherapy in patients with coronary artery disease (CAD) and acute lung injury/acute respiratory distress syndrome (ALI/ARDS), is safe and exhibits anti-coagulant and anti-inflammatory effects. A Phase II study using a multi-dose regimen of ALT-836 is being conducted in patients with ALI/ARDS. In the dose-escalation study described in this protocol, the investigators will assess the safety and determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of ALT-836 in combination with gemcitabine in patients with advanced malignancies known to overexpress TF and in which venous thromboembolism is a major complication.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulin G</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed Locally advanced or metastatic nonhematologic malignancies Measureable Refractory to standard therapies or single agent gemcitabine is indicated as a standard treatment option PRIOR/CONCURRENT THERAPY: No concurrent radiotherapy, chemotherapy, immunotherapy or other investigational agents Must have recovered from side effects of prior therapies PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks Performance Status ECOG 0 or 1 Bone Marrow Reserve Absolute Neutrophil count (AGC/ANC) ≥ 1,500/uL Platelets ≥ 100,000/uL Hemoglobin &gt; 9 g/dL Renal Function Calculated Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &gt; 59mL/min/1.73M^2 Hepatic Function Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 X ULN AST, ALT, and ALP ≤ 3 X ULN or ≤ 5.0 x ULN, if liver metastasis exists PT INR ≤ 1.5 X ULN Cardiovascular No history of clinically significant vascular disease No New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class &gt; II heart failure Hematologic No history of bleeding disorders No evidence of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy No presence of clinically significant hemoptysis or hematuria, presence of serious nonhealing wound or ulceration, or signs of other bleeding No evidence of a tumor invasion of any major blood vessel No trauma with increased risk of lifethreatening bleeding or history of severe head trauma or intracranial surgery within two months of study entry Surgery/Procedures No major surgery or open biopsy within 28 days before drug infusion or evidence of active bleeding postoperatively No plan for any major surgery during treatment period No presence or requirement of an epidural catheter or lumbar puncture within 48 hours prior to each dose of study treatment No anticipation of receiving an epidural catheter or a lumbar puncture within 48 hours after each dose of study treatment Excluded Medications or Treatment Regimens Unfractionated heparin of &gt; 15,000 units/day within 8 hours prior to each dose of study treatment Lowmolecular weight heparin at a higher dose than recommended for prophylactic used or required within 20 hours prior to each dose of study treatment Warfarin used or required within 48 hours prior to each dose of study treatment and the prothrombin time (INR) exceeded the upper limit of normal range Direct thrombin inhibitors or Xa inhibitors Acetylsalicylic acid used or required within 72 hours prior to each dose of study treatment Clopidogrel bisulfate used or required within 48 hours prior to each dose of study treatment Anticipated requirement for antiplatelet or anticoagulant agents excluding nonaspirin NSAID within 48 hours following study treatment infusion Other No active systemic infection requiring parenteral antibiotic therapy No history of or presence of a CNS disease No history of allergic reactions to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition Not HIV positive No women who are pregnant or nursing A negative serum pregnancy test if female Patients, both females and males, with reproductive potential must agree to use effective contraceptive measures for the duration of the study No history of significant renal, endocrinologic, metabolic, immunologic or hepatic disease No evidence of psychiatric illness/social situations Other illness that in the opinion of the investigator would exclude the patient from participating Must provide informed consent and HIPAA authorization and comply with protocolspecified procedures and followup evaluations</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>tissue factor</keyword>
	<keyword>solid tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>ovarian cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreatic cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>head and neck cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>soft-tissue sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic</keyword>
	<keyword>gemcitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>anti-tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>venous thromboembolism</keyword>
</DOC>