<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="29042">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02728648</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20162-2143</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02728648</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Population Pharmacokinetic-Pharmacodynamic Study of Intravenous Oxycodone in Children</brief_title>
  <official_title>Population Pharmacokinetic-Pharmacodynamic Study of Intravenous Oxycodone in Children</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Malaya</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Malaya</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Oxycodone has been in clinical use for decades. It is an effective alternative to morphine
      for moderate to severe acute or chronic pain and has been found to improve quality of life.
      The drug has been used parenterally or orally as perioperative analgesia or for cancer pain
      relief (Kalso 2005). Despite of its long clinical experience, prescribing errors and misuse
      may lead to addiction and accidental overdose (Berling et al. 2013, Boyle and Dosenbaum
      2014). Currently, little is known about the pharmacokinetic properties of intravenous
      oxycodone among paediatric patients in this region even though the drug has been used in
      children in other countries such as Finland. Therefore, a pharmacokinetic-pharmacodynamic
      study of oxycodone among Malaysian pediatric patients is warranted.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Oxycodone (14-hydroxy-7,8 dihydrocodeinone) is a strong, semisynthetic thebaine derivative
      µ-opioid receptor agonist. This drug is an effective alternative to morphine for
      moderate-to-severe pain. Oxycodone has been used parenterally or orally for perioperative
      analgesia or for cancer pain relief. The drug has a longer analgesic action than morphine.
      In terms of analgesic potency, intravenous oxycodone is about 1.6 times

      The adverse effects of oxycodone are mostly similar to those of other opioids. Oxycodone,
      however, does not cause histamine release. The drug induces less nausea and vomiting, less
      sedating, and less central nervous system excitatory effects than morphine (Kalso et
      al.1991).

      A large between subject variability in pharmacokinetic properties of oxycodone has been
      observed. The variability could be attributed to the difference body size and age-related
      difference in drug elimination organ system function. A 2-compatment first-order open model
      describes oxycodone pharmacokinetics in Finnish children (age 5.4±2.1 years) after an
      intravenous bolus dose of 0.1 mg kg-1 for post ophthalmic surgery pain relief (Olkkola et
      al. 1994). The authors reported a mean clearance (CL) and the steady state volume of
      distribution (Vss) of oxycodone 15.2 mL min-1 kg-1 (0.912 L h-1 kg-1) and 2.1 L kg-1
      respectively. A greater ventilator depression than comparable analgesic doses of other
      opioids were also observed. A pharmacokinetic study (Poyhia et al. 1991) carried out in 9
      young Finnish adult surgical patients reveals a clearance of 0.78 L min-1 (46.8 L h-1) and a
      volume of distribution (V) of 2.60 L kg-1. The mean AUC( t=0,12) ratio of noroxycodone (main
      metabolite) to oxycodone is 0.33. In a study on 69 Japanese adults (mean age 66 years, mean
      weight 52.8 kg) receiving intravenous oxycodone for cancer pain relief, a one-compartment
      first-order open model describes the pharmacokinetics of oxycodone. The mean CL and volume
      of distribution (V) are 24.6 L h-1 and 214 L or 4.053 L kg-1 (Kokubun et al. 2014).

      Often the drug concentrations in saliva reflect free drug concentrations in the plasma.
      Moreover, saliva can be collected rapidly and easily. Therefore saliva may be an alternative
      body fluid to study the exposure of drug in the body especially in young children.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clearance (CL) of IV oxycodone</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Volume of distribution of IV oxycodoen</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Emax of IV oxycodone</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ED 50 of IV oxycodone</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation of oxycodone concentration in oral fluid and oxycodone concentration in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Open label IV Oxycodone 0.1 mg/kg Bolus Pharmacokinetic-Pharmacodynamic Study</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oxycodone</intervention_name>
    <description>Pain Management</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>OxyNorm</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Aged between 3 to 17 years

          -  Generally healthy as documented by medical history (ASA 1-II)

          -  Opioid-naïve

          -  Patient is scheduled for a surgical procedure/procedures that is/are expected to
             require an analgesia with an opiate level medication.

          -  Patient who will remain hospitalized for at least 24 hours after dosing with the
             study drug.

          -  A negative urine pregnancy test at screening for females of childbearing potential

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patient is a lactating or breastfeeding female

          -  Patient has known allergy to oxycodone or any ingredient in oxycodone dosage form.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sook Hui Chaw, M.Med</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Malaya</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sook Hui Chaw, M.Med</last_name>
    <phone>03-79492052</phone>
    <email>sh_chaw@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 30, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 25, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Malaya</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Chaw Sook Hui</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pain Management</keyword>
  <keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
  <keyword>Pharmacodynamics</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Oxycodone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
