<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00359658</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is first to improve or save renal function and second to decrease cardiac risk factors by optimising the immunosuppressive regimen by withdrawing steroids and reducing the Cyclosporine A dose. The concomitant administration of Mycophenolatmofetile, an effective immunosuppressive agent, will minimize the risk of acute rejection episodes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Withdrawal of Steroids, Cyclosporine A Dose Reduction and Switch to Mycophenolatmofetile After Heart Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The decrease of quality of life in patients after heart transplantation in the long-term is determined by an increasing incidence of transplant vasculopathy and by immunosuppression-related side effects. Calcineurin inhibitors are associated with chronic nephrotoxicity, while long-term administration of steroids results in an increased incidence of cardiovascular risk factors (e.g. hypertension, lipometabolic disorders, steroid induced diabetes, adipositas)and therefore, carries the potential of graft disfunction.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Current immunosuppressive regimen: Cyclosporine A and corticosteroids for at least six month Heart transplantation above 3 years dated back Serum creatinine &lt; 3,5 mg/dl (310 µmol/l) and BUN &lt; 150 mg/dl Cyclosporine A blood level between 50 and 250 ng/ml during the last 12 month Carcinoma within the last 3 years Acute rejection episodes during the last 6 month Infection requiring therapeutic intervention Hepatitis B, Hepatitis C or HIV infection WBC &lt; 3000/µl, haemoglobin &lt; 9g/dl, platelets &lt; 70.000/µl Florid gastrointestinal ulcer Haemodialysis within the last 4 weeks before study entry Pregnancy / lactation Administration of other immunosuppressive agents than prescribed Mycophenolatmofetile incompatibility</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cyclosporine</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucocorticoids</keyword>
	<keyword>renal insufficiency, chronic</keyword>
	<keyword>long-term care</keyword>
</DOC>