<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00451594</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To determine the long term effects of pulse high dose dexamethasone and conventional dose prednisolone in treatment of adult patients with ITP.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>High Dose Dexamethasone Vs. Conventional Dose Prednisolone in Adult ITP</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients will be randomized to one of two study arms: dexamethasone 40 mg po daily for 4 consecutive days. If the platelet count drops below 30X109/L after response within 6 months, another four-day course of dexamethasone will be given, followed by 15 mg of prednisone daily, with gradual tapering (Arm 1). Prednisone 1 mg/kg po daily for 4-8 weeks, the drug is then decreased slowly over another few weeks (Arm 2).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Purpura, Thrombocytopenic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Purpura</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Purpura, Thrombocytopenic, Idiopathic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria : a true thrombocytopenia on blood smear adequate megakaryopoiesis on bone marrow examination the absence of clinically apparent associated conditions or cause of thrombocytopenia Age over 16 years A platelet count of less than 30x109/L Exclusion criteria : previous treatment for ITP. other causes of thrombocytopenia such as HIV infection, lymphproliferative disease, liver disease, or definite SLE. Patients with life threatening bleeding and pregnant women should be excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>ITP</keyword>
</DOC>