<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00451035</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the efficacy and safety of LBH589B in adult patients with chronic phase chronic myeloid leukemia with resistant disease following treatment with at least two BCR-ABL tyrosine kinase inhibitors</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of LBH589 in Adult Patients With Refractory Chronic Myeloid Leukemia (CML) in Chronic Phase</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelogenous, Chronic, BCR-ABL Positive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Chronic-Phase</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Panobinostat</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Male or female patients aged ≥ 18 years old Diagnosis of Philadelphia chromosome positive, chronic phase chronic myeloid leukemia Prior treatment with at least two BCRABL tyrosine kinase inhibitors with demonstrated resistance to the most recent kinase inhibitor therapy. Patients with a history of intolerance to one BCRABL kinase inhibitors will be considered eligible to enter the study if they demonstrate resistance to their most recent BCRABL kinase inhibitor. Patients who are intolerant of at least 2 BCRABL kinase inhibitors will be considered eligible to enter this study if they also demonstrate resistance to or intolerance of interferonalpha (IFNα) by the same criteria defined above. Patients must have adequate laboratory values Baseline measurement of left ventricular ejection fraction [assessment of the hearts ability to pump effectively] Assessment of patients ability to perform every day activities. Assessment by the ECOG [Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group] Performance Status Exclusion criteria: A candidate for hematopoietic stem cell transplantation Prior therapy with certain medications Patients with a prior history of accelerated phase or blast crisis CML Impaired cardiac function or clinically significant cardiac diseases Concomitant use of certain medications Impairment of GI function or GI disease Patients with unresolved diarrhea Patients who have received chemotherapy, any investigational drugs or undergone major surgery &lt; 4 weeks prior to starting study drug or who have not recovered from side effects of such therapy Patients who have received a BCRABL tyrosinekinase inhibitor within 1 week of first treatment with LBH589 Women who are pregnant or breast feeding or women of childbearing potential not using an effective method of birth control Male patients whose sexual partners are women of child bearing potential not using effective birth control Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Refractory Chronic Myeloid Leukemia in Chronic Phase</keyword>
	<keyword>adults</keyword>
	<keyword>oral LBH589</keyword>
</DOC>