<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00451919</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sickle cell disease is an inherited blood disorder that affects red blood cells (RBCs). People with sickle cell disease frequently experience anemia, or a low number of RBCs. RBCs are responsible for carrying oxygen to the brain and other body tissues that need oxygen to function properly. The purpose of this study is to determine what changes, which were possibly caused by anemia, exist in the brains of individuals with sickle cell disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Link Between Anemia and Deficits in Memory and Attention in Individuals With Sickle Cell Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The role of RBCs is to carry oxygen from the lungs to the brain and other body tissues. Individuals with anemia have unusually low numbers of RBCs. They also often have difficulty concentrating and remembering information, which is likely caused by a reduced oxygen supply to the brain. Previous research has shown that correcting anemia in patients without sickle cell disease improved their memory and attention. The purpose of this study is to examine any abnormal changes in the brains of individuals with sickle cell disease and to determine whether these changes are related to reduced memory and attention capabilities. Participants will attend one study visit. During this visit, a brain magnetic resonance image (MRI) will be performed while participants complete neuropsychological tests that measure memory, attention, and organizational ability. There will be no follow-up visits. The study completion date listed in this record was obtained from the "End Date" entered in the Protocol Registration and Results System (PRS) record.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of sickle cell disease Pregnancy Claustrophobia Mass lesion (e.g., meningioma, cyst, or spinal block) Need for life support constant monitoring Any unstable condition that is likely to require resuscitation Presence of a pacemaker or other ironcontaining magnetic substances in the body</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuropsychology</keyword>
</DOC>