<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00451763</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Idiopathic Macular Telangiectasia is characterized by incompetent and dilated retinal capillaries in the foveolar region of unknown cause for retinal telangiectasia. In Idiopathic Macular Telangiectasia, proliferative changes occur in the deep retinal capillary network, leading to intraretinal neovascularization that, unlike in age-related macular degeneration, seems to be retinal rather than choroidal in origin. Before the hemorrhagic and fibrotic state, these vessels may lead to exudation and decrease in the visual acuity. Long-term visual prognosis in patients with this complication may be poor and treatment with laser photocoagulation is unproven. Although newly reported treatment, by photodynamic therapy for neovascular membrane associated with Idiopathic Macular Telangiectasia, may show vision and angiographic stability in a few cases, the improvement may be transient. VEGF has been implicated as the major angiogenic stimulus responsible for neovascularization in AMD, ensuing specific anti-VEGF treatment in these cases. The purpose of the study is to evaluate intravitreal injection of bevacizumab (1.25mg/0.05ml) in the treatment of Idiopathic Macular Telangiectasia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intravitreal Bevacizumab for Idiopathic Macular Telangiectasia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Telangiectasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients with idiopathic macular telangiectasia patient consent heart attack or cerebrovascular attack previous treatment for others retinopathy media opacities that preclude visualization of the fundus inability to understands the implications of the protocol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fovea centralis/pathology</keyword>
	<keyword>Fundus oculi</keyword>
	<keyword>Retinal neovascularization</keyword>
	<keyword>Telangiectasis/diagnosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Tomography, optical coherence</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitreous Body/drug effects</keyword>
</DOC>