<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT00552851</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>The purpose study evaluate change leave ventricular mass cardiac function patient active acromegaly treatment growth hormone receptor antagonist pegvisomant one year .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Changes Left Ventricular Mass Cardiac Function Patients With Active Acromegaly During Treatment With Growth Hormone Receptor Antagonist Pegvisomant</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acromegaly</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertrophy , Left Ventricular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Active acromegaly adult subject ( ≥ 18 year ) surgery and/or radiation therapy elevate IGF1 level despite treatment somatostatin analogue dopamine agonist Pegvisomant therapy indicate ( i. e. patient inadequate response surgery and/or radiation therapy and/or medical therapy , therapy appropriate ) Evidence leave ventricular hypertrophy ( inferolateral wall thickness ≥ 12 mm assess echocardiography ) Evidence impair diastolic function ( ≥ stage 2 assessed echocardiography ) Evidence systolic dysfunction ( Ejection fraction &lt; 50 % assessed echocardiography ) Stable medication arterial hypertension heart failure 3 month Written inform consent . Pregnancy lactation period Previous therapy Pegvisomant Suspected known hypersensitivity drug component Contraindications MRI History malignancy last 5 year Suspected known drug alcohol abuse Patients neither able self administer study medication daily basis caregiver administer study medication patient daily basis Any condition opinion investigator make patient unsuitable inclusion Participation another clinical trial Pituitary adenoma distance optic chiasm &lt; 3 mm Any drug treatment acromegaly ( e.g . dopamine agonist , Somatostatin analogues ) would necessary study patient apply radiotherapy Instable heart insufficiency classify NYHA IV . Severe renal insufficiency , liver transplantation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>acromegaly</keyword>
	<keyword>heart failure</keyword>
	<keyword>hypertrophy</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiomegaly</keyword>
</DOC>