<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02662751</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to compare two post-stroke/TIA (transient ischemic attack) imaging strategies in terms of the number of clinically important (i.e. requiring specific treatment according to current recommendations) lesions detected. The first strategy is the current/usual strategy in each participating centre and the second strategy consists in starting the post-stroke/TIA imaging assessment by a whole-body, low-dose angiography and subsequently resorting to elements of the usual strategy if required.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Performing a Low-dose, Whole-body Angiography as the First Element of an Imaging Assessment Following Stroke / TIA</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The secondary objectives are: A. To compare the patient pathways between the two arms in terms of time to diagnosis, and duration of hospitalization. B. To compare the consumption of imaging exams (number and type) and total body irradiation between the two arms. C. To compare the diagnostic efficiency between the two arms in terms of detection of predefined lesions, and performance ratios. D. To study the thickness of the left atrial wall as a risk factor for permanent atrial fibrillation. E. To compare the distribution of suspected neoplasms between the two groups, as well as the number of detected incidentalomas. F. To compare the survival and the incidence of new cardiovascular events between the two arms at 12 months and 36 months. G. To compare the quality of life between the two arms at 12 months and 36 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemic Attack, Transient</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient was informed about the implementation of the study, its objectives, constraints and patient rights The patient has given free and informed consent and signed the consent Patient affiliated with or beneficiary of a health insurance plan Patient available for 36 months of followup The patient has had a stroke (within the past 10 days, diagnosis confirmed by MRI with a diffusion sequence) or transient ischemic attack (within the past 10 days, ABCD2 score greater than 3) without haemorrhage The patient is currently participating in or has participated in another biomedical research study within the past three months or is currently in an exclusion period determined by a previous study. Patient under guardianship or judicial protection Refusal to sign the consent Inability to correctly inform the patient or his/her trusted person about the study The patient is pregnant, parturient, or breastfeeding The patient has a contraindication for a treatment used in this study Known allergy to contrast medium or severe allergy to iodine Known active malignancy or history of cancer treatment The patient has already undergone a full body scanner in the previous three months Renal failure with creatinine clearance below 60 ml / min Monoclonal immunoglobulin History of severe symptomatic cardiovascular event (myocardial infarction, aortic dissection, mesenteric ischemia, renal ischemia) Emergency situations that hamper the planned course of the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>