<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01997099</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to describe the home healthcare organization ambulatory infusion pump programming workflow and the process that was followed to introduce the new CADD®-Solis VIP System to each home healthcare organization or facility. In addition, this study will characterize the overall clinician (Phase 1) and patient (Phase 2) ease of use and satisfaction with the CADD®-Solis VIP System.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Workflow and Satisfaction Study Evaluating the Implementation of a New "Smart" Ambulatory Infusion System</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, multi-center, non-randomized, post-market study conducted within the United States. There will be two independent components (Phases) to this study. Phase 1 will involve data collection to describe the home infusion pump programming workflow and the process that was used to introduce the new CADD®-Solis VIP System to each home healthcare organization. This phase is further broken down into data collection consisting of four parts: drug protocol library creation and development within the CADD™ Solis Medication Safety Software Administrator, pump programming, home care implementation, and overall workflow and new smart pump implementation. Phase 2 will involve data collection from patients that receive a prescription requiring use of the CADD®-Solis VIP pump.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diazepam</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Phase 1 Part 1: Licensed clinicians that would be responsible for protocol library creation at the center Part 2: Individuals that are responsible for ambulatory infusion pump programming per the organization's standard operating procedure Part 3: Licensed clinicians that are responsible for performing the pump setup and implementation activities within the home setting Part 4: Center personnel that are involved in the CADD®Solis VIP System implementation process Individuals that are unwilling or unable to answer questions as required by the protocol Phase 2 Patients 18 years of age or older Patients prescribed a home infusion requiring use of the CADD®Solis VIP pump Patients with infusions prescribed for a minimum duration of five (5) days Patient or patient's personal caregiver on behalf of the patient is willing and able to comply with the data collection requirements Patient is willing and able to provide informed consent for study participation Patient is currently enrolled or plans to enroll in a concurrent study that may confound the results of this study Based upon a clinician's opinion, the patient has health conditions or a psychological/cognitive status that would preclude proper participation in the study and does not have a personal caregiver available to perform study activities on behalf of the patient Previous use or experience with the CADD®Solis VIP pump</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug Library</keyword>
	<keyword>Ambulatory Infusion Pump</keyword>
	<keyword>Medication Safety Software</keyword>
	<keyword>CADD®-Solis VIP</keyword>
	<keyword>Pump Programming</keyword>
	<keyword>Home Infusion Workflow</keyword>
</DOC>