<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01997411</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to assess how glucagon administered as a puff into the nose (AMG504-1) works in children and adolescents compared with commercially-available glucagon given by injection. In addition, the safety and tolerability of glucagon given as a puff into the nose was evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of Intranasal Glucagon in Children and Adolescents With Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Glucagon, the treatment of choice for severe hypoglycemia outside of the hospital setting, is currently available only as a powder that must be mixed with a diluent immediately prior to administration by injection. Although this is a very simple procedure for insulin-using individuals, subjects experiencing severe hypoglycemia cannot inject themselves with glucagon because of the disabling effects of severe neuroglycopenia. For any non-medical person who is confronted with an emergency situation in which a patient with diabetes is in a hypoglycemic coma or suffering hypoglycemia-related convulsions, reconstitution and injection of the current injectable glucagon is a complex and daunting procedure. When used at the recommended dose of 1 mg by injection, glucagon often causes a substantial, although transient, hyperglycemia that is often accompanied by nausea and vomiting. The data generated to date with AMG504-1 suggest the resulting glucagon pharmacokinetics (PK), although less than that observed with injected glucagon, results in a therapeutic blood glucose increment with a very low incidence of gastrointestinal adverse effects. Caregivers of children and adolescents with type 1 diabetes are called upon to treat episodes of severe hypoglycemia and may want to use AMG504-1. This study was conducted to permit determination of appropriate dose level(s) for pediatric use based on the safety observations and results of glucagon and glucose assays. Each participant 12.0 to less than 17.0 years of age underwent two visits in random order and received AMG504-1 during one visit and commercially available glucagon (GlucaGen, Novo Nordisk) by IM injection during the other visit. Participants 4.0 to less than 12.0 years were randomly assigned to have either 1 visit with commercially available glucagon (GlucaGen, Novo Nordisk) by IM injection OR to have 2 visits with a 2.0 mg dose of AMG504-1 administered during one visit and a 3.0 mg dose of AMG504-1 administered during the other visit. For those randomized to complete two research dosing visits, the dose of intranasal glucagon given during each visit was masked to the participant and study personnel. Each dosing visit consisted of reducing the plasma glucose level to about 80 mg/dL by increasing the basal insulin infusion rate on the insulin pump or by an intravenous (IV) infusion of regular insulin diluted in normal saline. The insulin infusion was stopped once the plasma glucose was &lt;80 mg/dL. Five minutes after stopping the insulin infusion, participants were treated with either glucagon given intranasally (either 2.0 mg or 3.0 mg for participants 4.0 to less than 12.0 years of age or 3.0 mg for those 12.0 to less than 17.0 years of age) or by intramuscular (IM) injection (1 mg constituted in 1 mL of diluting solution for those 55 lbs or more and 0.5 mg constituted in 1 mL of diluting solution for those who weigh less than 55 lbs) in the quadriceps muscle of the leg. Blood glucose levels and adverse events were carefully monitored for 90 minutes post-dosing. After a wash-out period of 7 days or more, participants 12.0 to less than 17.0 years of age returned to the clinic and the procedure repeated with each participant crossed over to the other treatment. Participants 4.0 to less than 12.0 years assigned to have 2 dosing visits returned to clinic and repeated the procedure with a different dose of intranasal glucagon given. Participants 4.0 to less than 12.0 years assigned to a single dosing visit did not return for a second dosing visit.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon-Like Peptide 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>To be eligible, the following inclusion criteria were met: 1. History of type 1 diabetes and receiving daily insulin therapy from the time of diagnosis for at least 12 months. 2. At least 4.0 years of age and less than 17.0 years. 3. Weighed at least: 13 kg (28.6 lbs) for centers that were allowed to reinfuse blood and Institutional Review Board (IRB) guidelines allowed for 3.5 mL/kg of blood to be collected 15.1 kg (33.2 lbs) for centers that were allowed to reinfuse blood and IRB guidelines allowed for 3.0 mL/kg of blood to be collected 19 kg (41.8 lbs) for centers that were not allowed to reinfuse blood and IRB guidelines allowed for 3.5 mL/kg of blood to be collected 22.1 kg (48.6 lbs) for centers that were not allowed to reinfuse blood and IRB guidelines allowed for 3.0 mL/kg of blood to be collected 4. Females must have met one of the following criteria: 1. Of childbearing potential but agreed to use an accepted contraceptive regimen as described in the study procedure manual throughout the entire duration of the study (from the screening visit until study completion). or 2. Of nonchildbearing potential, defined as a female who had a hysterectomy or tubal ligation, was clinically considered infertile or had not yet reached menarche. 5. In good general health with no conditions that could have influenced the outcome of the trial, and in the judgment of the Investigator was a good candidate for the study based on review of available medical history, physical examination and clinical laboratory evaluations. 6. Willingness to adhere to the protocol requirements An individual was not eligible if any of the following exclusion criteria were present: 1. 1. Females who were pregnant according to a positive urine pregnancy test, actively attempting to get pregnant, or were lactating. 2. History of hypersensitivity to glucagon or any related products or severe hypersensitivity reactions (such as angioedema) to any drugs. 3. Presence of cardiovascular, gastrointestinal, liver or kidney disease, or any other conditions which in the judgment of the investigator could have interfered with the absorption, distribution, metabolism or excretion of drugs or could potentiate or predispose to undesired effects. 4. History of pheochromocytoma (i.e. adrenal gland tumor) or insulinoma. 5. History of an episode of severe hypoglycemia (as defined by an episode that required third party assistance for treatment) in the 1 month prior to enrolling in the study. 6. Use of daily systemic betablocker, indomethacin, warfarin or anticholinergic drugs. 7. History of epilepsy or seizure disorder. 8. Use of an Investigational Product in another clinical trial within the past 30 days 9. Blood donation in 3 months prior to first glucagon dosing visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucagon</keyword>
</DOC>