<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01950624</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objective: The development of a patient registry for Down syndrome (DS) was identified as a priority in the 2007 Down Syndrome Research Plan. Under the auspices of the Down Syndrome Consortium, founded in 2011 as a public-private partnership between the NIH and DS advocacy organizations, NICHD awarded a contract in 2012 to create a patient-focused online registry to facilitate research participation by individuals with DS. Two advisory boards, composed of advocates, family members, clinicians, researchers, and other relevant parties, have been involved in the development of the registry materials. Study Population: Individuals with DS (including those with mosaic DS and partial trisomy 21) Design: DS-Connect (TM) is an online survey tool designed to collect demographic data and health information from individuals with DS. Outcome measures: The purposes of DS-Connect (TM) are: 1. To identify the various phenotypic manifestations of DS. 2. To identify individuals with DS who may be eligible for research studies or new clinical trials, based on specific information about their diagnosis and health history.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>DS-Connect {TM}: The Down Syndrome Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objective: The development of a patient registry for Down syndrome (DS) was identified as a priority in the 2007 Down Syndrome Research Plan. Under the auspices of the Down Syndrome Consortium, founded in 2011 as a public-private partnership between the NIH and DS advocacy organizations, NICHD awarded a contract in 2012 to create a patient-focused online registry to facilitate research participation by individuals with DS. Two advisory boards, composed of advocates, family members, clinicians, researchers, and other relevant parties, have been involved in the development of the registry materials. Study Population: Individuals with DS (including those with mosaic DS and partial trisomy 21) Design: DS-Connect (TM) is an online survey tool designed to collect demographic data and health information from individuals with DS. Outcome measures: The purposes of DS-Connect (TM) are: 1. To identify the various phenotypic manifestations of DS. 2. To identify individuals with DS who may be eligible for research studies or new clinical trials, based on specific information about their diagnosis and health history.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Down Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Adults (at least 18 years of age) with a diagnosis of DS (including mosaic DS or partial trisomy 21) who are capable of providing consent to participate, or for whom a legally authorized representative (LAR) may give permission on behalf of the individual to participate. Adults with DS who cannot consent for themselves but can provide assent would need to provide assent to their LAR. Children (up to age 18 years of age) with a diagnosis of DS. Parents/guardians may enter registry information and give permission to participate on behalf of their child; if the child is over 7 years of age and able to provide assent, they must do so. (Note: Once a child has reached age 18, he or she will be prompted to reenroll into the registry as an adult, if he/she is able to provide informed consent or with the consent of his/her LAR if unable to reenroll themselves.) Children with DS (between the ages of 7 and 18 years) will be asked to provide their assent to register. No individuals with DS will be excluded from taking part in DSConnect based on age, race, ethnicity, or gender. EXCLUSION CRITERIA: A person who does not have a diagnosis of DS (or mosaic DS or partial trisomy 21) Adults with DS who are not capable of providing informed consent or assent to participate and do not have a Legally Authorized Representative who can do so. In the case where an adults with DS is able to provide assent but does not do so, that adult will be excluded. A participant, parent, and/or LAR who cannot provide consent or does not read or understand a language that is available for the registry, either English or Spanish. A child with DS (between the ages of 7 and 18 years) who is capable of providing assent but does not do so. A child under the age of 18 years whose parents share joint custody and one parent indicates that they do not consent to the child s participation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 27, 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Patient Registry</keyword>
	<keyword>Down Syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>