<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01950975</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The principal result expected is the discovery of inframicroscopic chromosomal rearrangements in regions of the genome not yet known to be involved, or mutations in known candidate genes; The identification of such a mosaic rearrangement in an affected infant would lead to improved genetic counselling. Indeed, as this mosaicism is a consequence of a genetic event occurring at an early stage of embryogenesis, it would be possible to confirm the sporadic nature of the observed disorder and therefore to predict a very low or even negligible risk of recurrence for the couple concerned. For the affected infant, the risk for his/her own offspring will be assessed according to the nature of the genetic anomaly discovered. For medical practice, investigators hope that this study will lead to a clearer definition of the screening modalities for mosaicism in the disorders concerned. In particular, they hope to determine whether or not it is possible to dispense with a skin biopsy, which is more invasive than a blood sample.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Screening for Chromosomal Microarrangements by CGH-array in Developmental Anomalies of the Skin Suggestive of Mosaicism.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Congenital Abnormalities</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Skin Manifestations</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Persons who have provided written informed consent Lower age limit: infant born at more than 37 WA Sporadic disorder Patients presenting at least two skin criteria, or one skin criterion and one nonskin criterion Skin criteria: 1 extensive epidermal or sebaceous naevus, 2 Extensive "segmental" haemangioma, 3 Flat angioma or extensive complex vascular malformation, 4Pigmentary disorders with patterns suggesting mosaicism (Blaschko lines) Nonskin criteria: Cerebral, ocular, cardiac or genitourinary malformation, asymmetric body, segmental hypertrophy of a limb, spinal dysraphism (only when associated with haemangioma) Persons not covered by the national health insurance scheme Mendelian disorders: CMAVM syndrome, glomangiomatosis, Cowden or Bannayan syndrome, type 1 neurofibromatosis, incontinentia pigmenti, CHILD syndrome, Happletype chondrodysplasia punctata Mendelian mosaic disorders: epidermal or epidermolytic, comedo or dyskeratotic nevus. Family history of one of these disorders Suspicion or an autosomal dominant disease Patient and/or parent under guardianship or ward of court</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>37 Weeks</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>