<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01559831</DOC>
	<brief_summary>IC51-319 is a single-arm, open-label study that investigates immune responses in subjects undergoing revaccination after receiving the subpotent batch of IXIARO JEV09L37 during primary immunization.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immune Response in IXIARO Batch JEV09L37 Recipients Before and After Revaccination</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>IC51-319 is a single-arm, open-label study that investigates immune responses in subjects undergoing revaccination after receiving the subpotent batch of IXIARO JEV09L37 during primary immunization. A total of up to 50 subjects having received primary immunization of IXIARO batch JEV09L37 and who have not yet been revaccinated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Encephalitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Encephalitis, Japanese</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects 18 years or older having received IXIARO batch JEV09L37 during primary immunization In female subjects, either childbearing potential terminated by surgery or 1 year postmenopausal, or a negative urine pregnancy test during screening and the willingness not to become pregnant during the entire study period by practicing reliable methods of contraception Written informed consent obtained from the subject prior to any studyrelated procedures Vaccination against Yellow fever, Dengue Fever, West Nile Fever or TBE or vaccination with any JE vaccine since primary immunization with IXIARO JEC09L37 Clinical manifestation of any flavivirus infection since primary immunization with IXIARO JEC09L37 Acute febrile infections or exacerbation of chronic infection on the day of IXIARO vaccination Pregnancy, lactation or unreliable contraception in female subjects with childbearing potential and unreliable contraception in male subjects. Use of any other investigational or nonregistered drug within 30 days prior to the first vaccination with IXIARO Visit 1 and during the study period Any condition which might interfere with study objectives or would limit the subject's ability to complete the study in the opinion of the investigator Persons who are committed to an institution At Day 0, upcoming scheduled travel to a JE endemic region</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Japanese Encephalitis</keyword>
	<keyword>IXIARO</keyword>
	<keyword>Japanese Encephalitis Vaccine</keyword>
</DOC>