<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01308060</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This double-blind study has two parts for each subject (same population): Part A: initial treatment in CL (placebo-controlled): - To assess the efficacy, safety and duration of effect of Azzalure® compared to placebo in the improvement of moderate to severe Lateral Canthal Lines. - To assess the subjects' level of satisfaction with the appearance their Lateral Canthal Lines compared to placebo. Part B: repeated treatment in CL with or without GL (active treatment, up to 1 year): - To assess safety of Azzalure® following repeated administration in the improvement of moderate to severe Lateral Canthal Lines. - To assess the safety of Azzalure® when used concomitantly for improvement of moderate to severe Lateral Canthal Lines and Glabellar Lines. - To assess the subjects' level of satisfaction with the appearance their Lateral Canthal Lines.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Multi-Center Study Of CD07743 for the Improvement of Lateral Canthal Lines (CROW'S FEET)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins, Type A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>incobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>abobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>onabotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subjects, 18 to 65 years of age (Screening visit), Moderate or severe (grade 2 or 3, Hund 2006) Lateral Canthal Lines "at maximum smile" determined by investigator at screening and baseline Mild to severe (grade 1, 2 or 3, Hund 2006) Lateral Canthal Lines "at rest" determined by investigator at screening and baseline The subject is a female of childbearing potential and has a negative urine pregnancy test (UPT) at screening and baseline Subjects who are not satisfied with their appearance at screening and baseline The subject is willing and able to comply with the requirements of the protocol and agree to adhere to the visit schedule, concomitant therapy prohibitions and must be compliant to the study instruction. The subject agrees to participate in the study, verified by dating and signing an approved written Informed Consent Form (ICF) and Photography Consent Form (PCF) (selected sites only if applicable) at the enrolment visit before any study procedures at screening Any prior surgery affecting the orbicularis oculi muscle, prior blepharoplasty or brow lift, or any prior cosmetic procedures or scars that may interfere with the evaluation of the investigator. Previous insertion of any permanent, semipermanent or biodegradable material in the periorbital region or facial treatment with augmentation material (e.g. silicon injections, collagen type implants, hyaluronic acid, lactic acid, etc.) within 12 months prior to screening. Any prior treatment with botulinum toxin (of any serotype) Previous treatment with lasers for skin resurfacing (e.g. CO2laser) or treatment with deep chemical peels and any other esthetic or dermatologic treatments or procedures in any area of the face within 12 months prior to screening. Any planned facial cosmetic surgery or procedures during the study period. Presence of any bleeding disorders Pregnant or lactating women or women who are planning pregnancy during the study. Known hypersensitivity to any of the test materials or related compounds.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Canthal lines</keyword>
</DOC>