<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02878850</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to learn more about how participants heal from acute spinal cord injury.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Targeted Blood Pressures in Participants With Acute Spinal Cord Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this study, the investigators will learn about the effect of targeted blood pressure management (TPM) on participants healing from acute spinal cord injury. The investigators want to learn: The effect of two types of TPM on long term motor and sensory outcomes. The effect of two types of TPM on long-term pain and functional independence outcomes. How safe TPM is for participants.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Acute traumatic SCI involving neurological levels as defined by the ASIA neurological examination between C0 and T8 (tetraplegia) and resulting in new onset neurological deficits consistent with an ASIA motor assessment of level A or B. 2. Subject or their legal representative has signed the informed consent. 3. Subject is 18 years of age or older. 1. Penetrating SCI injury. 2. Isolated cauda equine syndrome or injury at bony level Th9 or below. 3. Central cord syndrome, as determined by the primary admitting team. 4. History of demyelinating disease or central nervous system autoimmune disorder. 5. History within the past six months and/or physical findings on admission of decompensated congestive heart failure (NYHA functional class III or IV, or objective class C or D). 6. Acute, evolving or recent (30 days) myocardial infarction. 7. Chronic renal failure requiring dialysis. 8. Suspected or confirmed pregnancy. 9. Severe terminal disease with life expectancy less than 6 months. 10. Severe traumatic brain injury at presentation (GCS ≤8). 11. A condition that would preclude the performance of an accurate neurological exam due to a prior diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease, stroke, degenerative condition, cerebral tumor, or mental retardation. 12. NonEnglish or NonSpanish Speaking. 13. Refusal of consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>