<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02878655</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The nodal involvement in squamous cell carcinomas of the upper aerodigestive tract (VADS) is one of the main factors of poor prognosis, justifying the surgical management of neck dissection as a reference treatment. Under the influence of the American Hayes Martin, it was considered until the 1960s that "over the intervention was, the greater the chance of recovery was". But has since been developed by the Argentine Osvaldo Suarez the concept of functional course, which consists of resection of lymph node tissue while retaining the main structures (muscles, nerves, vessels), as opposed to the recess radical which is reserved for the invasive metastasis. In addition to these notions, our job is to evaluate the quality of life of patients with SCCHN, N0 clinical and radiological, enjoying a functional neck dissection including IIb sector to support the approach which would be to stop the systematic inclusion of this territory.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Overall Quality of Life After the Neck Dissection Retro-spinal Sector (IIb), in Squamous Cell Carcinomas Clinical and Radiological N0 VADS</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Patient with SCCHN histologically proven N0 clinical and radiological Neoplastic Location: oral cavity, oropharynx, hypopharynx, larynx Patient candidate for a neck dissection fonctonnel Life expectancy&gt; 3 months Stable patient not exhibiting at the time of recurrence sign of examination or other scalable neoplasia Age over 18 ans Patient was informed of the study Patient fluent French Patients with a history of malignancy, outside a basal cell cancer or cancer of the neck treated and cured Patient has at the time of examination of recurrence of signs or other scalable neoplasia Uncontrolled Infectious diseases Neoadjuvant radiotherapy Patient nursing or pregnant or lack of contraception during their reproductive Intercurrent pathology involving lifethreatening Any medical or psychological condition associated that could compromise the patient's ability to participate in the study Inability to submit to medical followup study for geographical, social or psychic</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>N0 clinical and radiological</keyword>
	<keyword>dissection IIb sector</keyword>
</DOC>