<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02903264</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluated the periodontal condition of gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) patients and a healthy non-pregnant control group. For the GDM group all medical data were recorded, including obesity/insulin resistance indicators.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gestational Diabetes Mellitus, Obesity and Periodontal Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Gestational diabetes mellitus is associated to a worse periodontal condition. Many patients with these two diseases are also obese. After delivery, some patients maintain the pre-pregnancy obesity status and this condition is also associated to periodontal disease. The mechanisms involved in the relationship of all these medical and periodontal conditions are not clear.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes, Gestational</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Periodontal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gingival Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for GDM group was pregnant women with diagnosis of GDM based on glucose determination described in a previous study (19) and under medical treatment of an endocrinologist and the presence of at least one tooth per sextant. Inclusion criteria for control group were absence of periodontal disease, mean age similar to test group and presence of at least one tooth per sextant. The exclusion criteria for GDM group were pregnant women without diagnosis of diabetes, age below 18 years or higher than 42 years, and the presence of other systemic diseases. In control group, women were excluded if they were pregnant, had diabetes or other systemic disease and age below 18 years or higher than 42 years.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>42 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gestational Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Periodontal Disease</keyword>
</DOC>