<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="129653">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01414244</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>11-271</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01414244</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Glutamine for the Treatment of Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome</brief_title>
  <acronym>AT005291</acronym>
  <official_title>Randomized, Placebo-Controlled Trial of Glutamine for the Treatment of Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is a common gastrointestinal disorder that is estimated to
      affect 20% of the US population. IBS patients have significantly decreased quality of life
      and utilize large amounts of health care resources. IBS patients suffer from chronic
      abdominal pain associated with diarrhea, constipation, and/or bloating. Several recent
      studies have shown that diarrhea-predominant IBS (D-IBS) patients have increased intestinal
      permeability that may lead to chronic gastrointestinal symptoms.

      Previously, it has been well established that deficiencies in glutamine may lead to
      increased membrane permeability and supplementation with glutamine can restore intestinal
      membrane permeability. The investigators hypothesize that oral glutamine supplementation
      will improve the IBS Symptom Severity Scale and restore intestinal membrane permeability in
      diarrhea-predominant IBS patients. The investigators propose to conduct a randomized,
      double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial studying glutamine compared to placebo for 8
      weeks in 100 diarrhea-predominant IBS patients. This will lead to the following specific
      aims: Specific Aim 1: To determine if oral glutamine supplementation will improve the IBS
      Symptom Severity Scale in IBS patients. To accomplish this aim, the investigators will
      measure the change in the IBS Symptom Severity Scale following treatment with either oral
      glutamine supplementation or placebo. The primary outcome measure will be an improvement or
      clinically significant response to treatment of ≥50 from the baseline score on the IBS
      Symptom Severity Scale. Specific Aim 2: To determine if oral glutamine supplementation will
      restore intestinal permeability in IBS patients. To accomplish this aim, the investigators
      will measure the change in the intestinal permeability following treatment with either oral
      glutamine supplementation or placebo.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Abstract Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is a common gastrointestinal disorder that is
      estimated to affect 20% of the US population. IBS patients have significantly decreased
      quality of life and utilize large amounts of health care resources. IBS patients suffer from
      chronic abdominal pain associated with diarrhea, constipation, and/or bloating. Several
      mechanisms that may lead to IBS have been proposed including: alterations in receptors and
      neuropeptides, bacterial overgrowth and altered microbiota, altered intestinal transit,
      anxiety and depressive symptoms, and increased intestinal membrane permeability. Several
      recent studies have shown that diarrhea-predominant IBS (D-IBS) patients have increased
      intestinal permeability that may lead to chronic gastrointestinal symptoms.

      Our laboratory recently evaluated diarrhea-predominant IBS patients and reported that they
      have increased membrane permeability. The investigators now have obtained preliminary
      evidence that oral glutamine supplementation restores membrane permeability and improves
      chronic gastrointestinal symptoms in these IBS patients. Previously, it has been well
      established that deficiencies in glutamine may lead to increased membrane permeability and
      supplementation with glutamine can restore intestinal membrane permeability. There are no
      published studies to date to support the use of glutamine for Irritable Bowel Syndrome.
      However, given our preliminary data and the mechanisms of action of glutamine on the
      gastrointestinal tract, research testing whether oral glutamine is an effective therapy in
      Irritable Bowel Syndrome is definitely needed.

      Based on these new findings, the investigators hypothesize that oral glutamine
      supplementation will improve the IBS Symptom Severity Scale and restore intestinal membrane
      permeability in diarrhea-predominant IBS patients. The investigators propose to conduct a
      randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial studying glutamine 10 g po tid
      compared to placebo 10 g po tid for 8 weeks in 100 diarrhea-predominant IBS patients. The
      IBS Symptom Severity Scale and intestinal membrane permeability will be measured at
      baseline, 2, 4, 6, and at 8 weeks. The results of this study will lead to the following
      specific aims:

      Specific Aim 1: To determine if oral glutamine supplementation will improve the IBS Symptom
      Severity Scale in IBS patients. To accomplish this aim, the investigators will measure the
      change in the IBS Symptom Severity Scale following treatment with either oral glutamine
      supplementation or placebo. The primary outcome measure will be an improvement of ≥50 from
      the baseline score on the IBS Symptom Severity Scale. This constitutes a clinically
      significant response to treatment.

      Hypothesis 1. IBS patients will have an improvement of ≥50 on the IBS Symptom Severity Scale
      following oral glutamine supplementation compared to placebo.

      Specific Aim 2: To determine if oral glutamine supplementation will restore intestinal
      membrane permeability in IBS patients. To accomplish this aim, the investigators will
      measure the change in the intestinal membrane permeability following treatment with either
      oral glutamine supplementation or placebo.

      Hypothesis 2a. Oral glutamine supplementation will restore intestinal membrane permeability
      in IBS patients compared to placebo.

      Hypothesis 2b. Improvement in the IBS Symptom Severity Scale is correlated with restoration
      of intestinal membrane permeability following oral glutamine compared to placebo.

      Layman Statement: Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is a common gastrointestinal disorder
      characterized by chronic abdominal pain associated with an alteration in bowel habits with
      diarrhea and/or constipation. IBS patients with diarrhea have been shown to have a &quot;leaky
      gut&quot; in which bacteria and toxins may penetrate the gut wall, termed increased membrane
      permeability. The current proposal will investigate oral glutamine supplementation as a
      treatment of symptoms and &quot;leaky gut&quot; in diarrhea-predominant IBS patients.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>November 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the Irritable Bowel Symptom Severity Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and at 2, 4, 6, and 8 weeks following therapy</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measure will be a change in the Irritable Bowel Symptom Severity Scale from baseline to 2, 4, 6, and 8 weeks following therapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Intestinal Permeability</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline and 2, 4, 6, and 8 weeks following therapy</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary outcome measure will be a change in intestinal permeability from base to 2, 4, 6, and 8 weeks following therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Glutamine supplementation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Glutamine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Whey protein powder</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Glutamine Supplementation</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral Glutamine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Glutamine supplementation</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>L-Glutamine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral Placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>sugar pill</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Glutamine</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Glutamine supplementation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  men and women age 18-72 years old that meet the Rome III criteria for
             diarrhea-predominant IBS (D-IBS) for at least 1 year prior to study

          -  increased intestinal membrane permeability on Lactulose/Mannitol permeability test

          -  score between 37 and 110 on the Functional Bowel Disorder Severity Index (FBDSI)

          -  able and willing to cooperate with the study

          -  *absence of alcohol ingestion for 2 weeks prior to inclusion into study and
             throughout the study duration

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  current participation in another research protocol or unable to give informed consent

          -  women with a positive urine pregnancy test or breastfeeding

          -  history of inflammatory bowel disease, lactose intolerance, and/or celiac sprue

          -  + hydrogen breath test for bacterial overgrowth

          -  + antiendomysial antibody titer

          -  use of nonsteroidal antinflammatory drug(NSAIDs) 2 weeks before or during the study

          -  known allergy to glutamine

          -  abdominal surgery except for removal of gallbladder, uterus, or appendix &gt;6 months
             prior to entry into the study

          -  Beck Depression Inventory score of ≥30, State Trait Anxiety Inventory ≥53.

          -  Abnormal blood urea nitrogen(BUN) and/or creatinine
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>72 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>QiQi Zhou</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Texas, Galveston</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>QiQi Zhou, M.D., Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>614-271-7118</phone>
    <email>qiqi06@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Medical Branch</name>
      <address>
        <city>Galveston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77550</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>QiQi Zhou, M.D., Ph.D.</last_name>
      <phone>614-271-7118</phone>
      <email>qiqi06@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 12, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 29, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
