<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01522287</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this project is to improve access to effective treatments for obsessive compulsive disorder (OCD) through the use of web-based cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) treatment. There intervention involves both a computer program (BT Steps) and human interaction via telephone. The investigators will test the efficacy and feasibility of computer therapy alone (n=35), computer plus a non-therapist coach (n=35), and computer plus a CBT therapist coach (n=35</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Computer Assisted Cognitive Behavior Therapy for Obsessive Compulsive Disorder: A Comprehensive Stepped-Care Approach</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The need for evidence-based mental health treatments i.e., 'treatment based on the best available science or research evidence‟1, has been stressed from scientific, ethical, and marketing perspectives. While empirical evidence supports both the efficacy and effectiveness of cognitive behavior therapy (CBT) for Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder (OCD), demand for clinicians trained in these approaches far exceeds supply. New technologies provide the opportunity to facilitate access to this specialized treatment. A growing body of research has found that web-based self-administered psychotherapy is highly effective, cost-efficient, and can achieve clinical improvements similar to those obtained with clinician administered therapy. The long-term goal of this project is to improve clinical and occupational functioning and decrease disability associated with OCD by improving access to effective treatments through the use of web-based CBT treatment. The intervention involves a computer program (BT STEPS) and human interaction via telephone. The inclusion of human interaction for coaching and encouragement has been found to significantly increase compliance and success rates in computerized self-help. Whether treatment outcomes differ when this coaching is done by a therapist versus when done by a trained non-therapist has not been studied. This is the first program to examine a hybrid model involving different levels of remote clinician coaching in combination with an on-line self-help tutorial. In Phase I the investigators will test the efficacy and feasibility of computer therapy alone (n=35), computer plus nontherapist coach (n=35) and computer plus CBT therapist coach. In phase II the investigators will do a fully powered study comparing our model to traditional face-to-face therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Behavior</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 or above Have clinically significant OCD YBOCS score of 1632 Significant comorbid depression Serious suicide risk Psychosis or psychotic disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obsessive Compulsive Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Computer Assisted Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive Behavior Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>