<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01522404</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out if atomoxetine causes a change in the biologic markers (substances that may indicate the presence of a disease) in the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) of participants diagnosed with Mild Cognitive Impairment (MCI). In this research study, the spinal fluid of subjects with MCI who take atomoxetine will be compared to spinal fluid of those who take capsules containing inactive material, also known as placebo. At the six-month timepoint, subjects who were taking placebo during the first six months will be placed on active study medication, and those who received active study medication will be reassigned to placebo. After completion of the study, subjects will be able to receive open-label atomoxetine. This study will also evaluate if the drug is safe and well-tolerated. Additionally, information will be gathered to identify the dose of atomoxetine that is most beneficial, and how taking this medication affects thinking and behavior, as well as imaging and blood biomarkers. The results of this research will help determine if atomoxetine alters signs of inflammation and other biomarkers associated with Alzheimer's disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Atomoxetine in Mild Cognitive Impairment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atomoxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Subjective memory concern per subject, study partner or clinician Clinician diagnosis of amnestic MCI; single or multidomain Abnormal memory per Logical Memory subscale from Wechsler Memory ScaleRevised MMSE score 2430 inclusive. Exceptions considered for &lt;8 yrs.education Clinical Dementia Rating 0.5. Memory Box score must be &gt;=0.5 General cognition &amp; functional performance preserved Cholinesterase inhibitors &amp; memantine, if stable x12 wks. Stability of medications x4 wks. May washout from psychoactive medication x4 wks. Geriatric Depression Scale ≤6 Male/female outpatients aged 5090 (inclusive) Study partner has regular contact w/ subject, can provide reliable assessment of subject's level of function, &amp; can be available for all visits, either in person or by telephone, throughout trial Visual &amp; auditory acuity adequate for testing Good general health Women of childbearing potential willing to use medically acceptable birth control or practice abstinence throughout trial Modified Rosen Hachinski ≤4 Completed 6th grade or has good work history Fluent in English Able to understand nature of study. Must provide written informed consent prior to conduct of any study procedures Willing to undergo repeated MRIs &amp; PET scans Agrees to APOE, CYP2D6 &amp; biomarker testing Agrees to 3 lumbar punctures over course of study Exclusion Significant neurologic disease other than MCI Screening/baseline MRI scan w/ evidence of infection, large vessel infarction or other focal structural lesion that could account for memory deficits. Subjects w/ multiple lacunes or lacunes in a critical memory structure Contraindication to MRI (pacemakers, aneurysm clips, artificial heart valves, ear implants, metal fragments or foreign objects in the eyes, skin or body, or excessive weight) Clinically significant suicide risk, based on MD's judgment per structured clinician interview. Suicide attempt within past yr. Major depression, bipolar disorder within past yr., or history of schizophrenia. Psychotic features, agitation or behavioral problems within last 3 mos. History of alcohol or substance abuse/dependence within past 2 yrs. Allergic to atomoxetine Uncontrolled medical condition that may preclude completion of study, or medical condition which would represent contraindication to atomoxetine (e.g. hepatic insufficiency, untreated hypertension, untreated cardiovascular or cerebrovascular disease) Known serious cardiac problems. History of narrow angle glaucoma. History of pheochromocytoma Clinically significant abnormal findings on screening lab tests or exam. Abnormalities in Vitamin B12 level, TFTs or LFTs that may interfere w/ study. Low Vitamin B12 level (unless homocysteine &amp; methylmalonic acid indicate no clinical significance) Slow metabolizer of atomoxetine Women who are pregnant or lactating, or plan to become pregnant during study Behavioral symptoms requiring current use of neuroleptics, chronic anxiolytics, sedative hypnotics Current use of warfarin Inability to obtain initial Cerebrospinal fluid sample Use within 60 days of a monoamine oxidase inhibitor or potent CYP2D6 inhibitor Current use of antipsychotics or the following antidepressant medications: duloxetine, venlafaxine, desvenlafaxine, imipramine, amitryptiline Current participation in another clinical trial. Current/recent participation in procedures involving radioactive agents such that total radiation dose exposure to subject in any given year &gt; limits of annual &amp; total dose commitment set forth in US CFR Title 21 Section 361.1 Cerebrospinal fluid profile inconsistent with underlying AD pathology Reasonable likelihood for noncompliance w/ protocol or any other reason, in opinion of investigator Exceptions may be considered on individual basis at discretion of protocol director</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mild Cognitive Impairment</keyword>
	<keyword>Memory Loss</keyword>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's Disease</keyword>
</DOC>