<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01522001</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cardiac rehabilitation is an individual adapted multidisciplinary intervention for people suffering from Heart Disease. It involves; - Dietary counseling, - Exercise training, - Psychosocial support, - Physician - smoking cessation - Patient education The purpose is quick and complete recovery and to reduce the chance of recurrence. In Denmark people admitted with Acute Cardiac Disease is referred to a course of hospital based cardiac rehabilitation at discharge. The Danish Municipal Reform of 2007 changed the responsibility of rehabilitation from the Regions, who runs the hospitals, to the municipalities. Shared care is in this setting that elements of treatment are completed different places in Health Care. The aim of this study is: - to establish a shared care model for Cardiac rehabilitation following admission with Acute Coronary Syndrome and - to compare this model to the existing hospital based cardiac rehabilitation after admission with Acute Coronary Syndrome. Primary outcome is participation in cardiac rehabilitation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Shared Care Rehabilitation After Acute Coronary Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Admission with Acute Coronary Syndrome Resident in district of Department of Cardiology, Aarhus University Hospital, Silkeborg or Viborg Hospital, part of the "Hospitalsenheden Midt" Viborg, Silkeborg, Skive, Hammel. Accept both models of cardiac rehabilitation written informed consent Resident outside the district of Department of Cardiology, Aarhus University Hospital, Viborg Hospital or Silkeborg Hospital, part of "Hospitalsenheden Midt" (Viborg, Silkeborg, Skive, Hammel). Age 80 years or older Heart Failure (Ejection Fraction less than 40%) Severe Comorbidity Resuscitated and need of support from ergotherapist after discharge.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute Coronary Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Myocardial Ischemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Shared Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Community</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac Rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Hospital</keyword>
</DOC>