<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01957410</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate if somatosensory evoked potentials (SEPs) and motor evoked potentials (MEPs) obtained with electroencephalography (EEG) and electromyography (EMG) can be used to detect changes in cortical plasticity in responders to a single IV infusion of ketamine as compared to non-responders.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Investigate Evoked Potentials as Markers of Ketamine-induced Cortical Plasticity in Patients With Major Depressive Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will be conducted in patients with Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) and divided into 2 sequential cohorts. Cohort 1 will be conducted in 12 patients at a single center. For each patient, there will be up to 4 sequential phases: a screening phase of up to 6 weeks, an open-label treatment phase of up to 4 weeks, an optional open-label treatment phase of up to 1 week, and a follow-up phase of up to 1 week (if applicable). Cohort 2 will be conducted in 20 patients and will be a multicenter, double-blind (neither physician nor patient knows the treatment that the patient receives), randomized (the study drug is assigned by chance), placebo-controlled (an inactive substance that is compared with a drug to test whether the drug has a real effect in a clinical trial) design. For each patient, there will be up to 4 sequential phases: a screening phase of up to 6 weeks, a double-blind treatment phase of up to 4 weeks, an optional open-label treatment phase of up to 1 week, and a follow-up phase of up to 1 week (if applicable). The total study duration for each patient will be maximally about 12 weeks. Participant safety will be monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient must be medically stable Patient must meet Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders Fourth Edition (DSMIV) diagnostic criteria for Major Depressive Disorder (MDD), without psychotic features, based upon clinical assessment and confirmed by the Mini International Psychiatric Interview (MINI) Patient must have had an inadequate response to at least 2 antidepressants, one of which is in the current episode of depression Patient must have an Inventory of Depressive Symptomatology 30item Clinicianrated (IDSC30) total score ≥ 34 at Screening and Day 1 Women must be postmenopausal, surgically sterile, or, if heterosexually active, practicing a highly effective method of birth control Men who are heterosexually active with a woman of childbearing potential must agree to use a double barrier method of birth control and to not donate sperm during the study and for 3 months after receiving the last dose of study drug Patient has current signs and/or symptoms of liver or renal insufficiency; significant cardiac, vascular, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, endocrine, neurologic, hematologic, rheumatologic, or metabolic disturbances Patient has a primary DSMIV diagnosis of current (active) generalized anxiety disorder (GAD), panic disorder, obsessive compulsive disorder (OCD), posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD), anorexia nervosa, or bulimia nervosa Patient has a current diagnosis of bipolar disorder, mental retardation, or cluster b personality disorder (e.g., borderline personality disorders, antisocial personality disorder, etc) Patient has a current or prior diagnosis of a psychotic disorder or MDD with psychosis Patient has not responded to treatment with electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) in the current episode of depression Patient has suicidal ideation with intent to act, or has homicidal ideation/intent, during Screening phase per Investigator's clinical judgment Patient has any significant primary sleep disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Major Depressive Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Ketamine</keyword>
	<keyword>Evoked potentials</keyword>
	<keyword>Somatosensory evoked potentials</keyword>
	<keyword>Motor evoked potentials</keyword>
	<keyword>Cortical plasticity</keyword>
</DOC>