<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01957176</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will provide continued access to treatment with eltrombopag for subjects who are currently participating in a GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) sponsored investigational study of eltrombopag (parent study) and to collect long term safety data.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Rollover Study to Provide Continued Treatment With Eltrombopag</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Thrombocytopenia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent has been obtained from the subject (or subject's legally acceptable representative) prior to performance of any studyspecific procedure. The subject is participating in a GSK sponsored investigational study of eltrombopag (parent study) within the past 28 days and is receiving clinical benefit without unacceptable toxicity as determined by the investigator. Subjects with a QTc &lt;450 millisecond (msec) or &lt;480 msec for subjects with bundle branch block. The QTc is the QT interval corrected for heart rate according to either Bazett's formula (QTcB), Fridericia's formula (QTcF) or another method, machine or manual overread. For subject eligibility and withdrawal QTcF will be used. For purposes of data analysis, QTcF will be used. The QTc should be based on single or averaged QTc values of triplicate electrocardiograms (ECGs) obtained over a brief recording period. Women must be either of nonchild bearing potential or women with childbearing potential and men with reproductive potential must be willing to practice acceptable methods of birth control during the study. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test within 14 days of the first dose of study treatment and agree to use effective contraception, during the study and for 4 weeks following the last dose of study treatment. Men with a female partner of childbearing potential must have either had a prior vasectomy or agree to use effective contraception from time of first dose until 16 weeks after the last dose of study treatment. In France, a subject will be eligible for inclusion in this study only if either affiliated to, or a beneficiary of, a social security category. Permanent discontinuation of eltrombopag in the parent study based upon the study treatment discontinuation or study withdrawal criteria from the parent study. Subjects who permanently discontinued treatment because they completed all study related treatments remain eligible. The subject is pregnant or a lactating female. Any serious and/or unstable preexisting medical, psychiatric disorder or other conditions at the time of transition to this study that could interfere with subject's safety, obtaining informed consent or compliance with the study procedures, in the opinion of the investigator or GSK Medical Monitor. French subjects: The French subject has participated in any study using an investigational drug during the previous 30 days, with the exception of eltrombopag, in the parent study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>myelodysplastic syndromes</keyword>
	<keyword>thrombocytopenia</keyword>
	<keyword>acute myeloid leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>, idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura</keyword>
	<keyword>Eltrombopag</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatrics</keyword>
</DOC>