<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00833248</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this phase 3B trial was to see how well a new trial drug (degarelix) works in terms of reducing the size of the prostate volume in prostate cancer patients who were scheduled to undergo subsequent radiotherapy for treatment of their prostate cancer. Prior to receiving radiotherapy, it is recommended that patients with intermediate to high risk prostate cancer are pre-treated with hormone therapy (so-called neoadjuvant therapy) which is known to reduce the size of the prostate and thereby decrease the required radiation field and enable a more safe and effective treatment. In this trial, participants were randomly selected (like flipping a coin) to receive either degarelix given alone or a standard hormone therapy (combination of goserelin and bicalutamide. The treatment was given for three months and the prostate size was measured by ultra sound at the beginning and at the end of the trial. The participants were required to come to the clinic for 5 or 6 visits during the three months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neoadjuvant Study Investigating Degarelix in Patients Suffering From Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Goserelin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bicalutamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Androgen Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient has given written informed consent before any trialrelated activity is performed. Has a confirmed prostate cancer in which this type of treatment is needed. Previous treatment for prostate cancer Previous transurethral resection of the prostate Patients who are lymph node positive or have other metastatic disease Use of urethral catheter Current treatment with a 5alpha reductase inhibitor or αadrenoceptor antagonist. History of severe untreated asthma, anaphylactic reactions, or severe urticaria and/or angioedema. Hypersensitivity towards any component of the investigational product Other previous cancers within the last five years with the exception of prostate cancer and some types of skin cancer. Certain risk factors for abnormal heart rhythms/QT prolongation (corrected QT interval over 450 msec., Torsades de Pointes or use of certain medications with potential risk) Clinical disorders other than prostate cancer including but not limited to renal, haematological, gastrointestinal, endocrine, cardiac, neurological, psychiatric disease, alcohol or drug abuse or other conditionals as judged by the investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>