<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02332616</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates the pathophysiological effects of a single dose of methylprednisolone administered prior to total knee-arthroplasty surgery. The investigators examine the effect on complement activation. Half of participants will receive intravenous Solu-Medrol 125 mg, while the other half will receive placebo. The investigators hypothesize that the group receiving methylprednisolone will experience beneficial inhibition of the undesirable parts of the complement activation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Methylprednisolone on Complement Activation in Patients Undergoing Total Knee-arthroplasty</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The anti-inflammatory effects of glucocorticoids are well known. The beneficial effects on postoperative pain, postoperative nausea and vomiting are well-documented. Anaesthesia and surgery are associated with a dramatic increase in the inflammatory response. The complement system participates in the disposal of products due to inflammatory damage. The complement activation generates proinflammatory mediators which amplifies the tissue damage and the inflammation. Glucocorticoid administration prior to surgery is thought to effectively reduce the inflammatory response and the activation of the complement system. The effect of glucocorticoids on specific complement markers after surgery is unknown and calls for further investigation. This study is embedded in a primary study registrated as: NCT02319343 For further details please view the EudraCT registration: EudraCT nr.: 2014-003395-23</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Joint Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Complement System Proteins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Osteoarthrosis Undergoing total unilateral kneearthroplasty surgery Speak and understand Danish Have given informed consent Revision, bilateral or uni chamber kneearthroplasty surgery General anaesthesia Allergy or intolerance towards Methylprednisolone Local or systemic infection Permanent systemic treatment with steroids within 30 days preoperatively Insulindependent diabetes Active treatment of ulcer within 3 months preoperatively Cancer disease Autoimmune disease incl. rheumatoid arthritis Pregnant or breast feeding women Menopause &lt;1 year</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Glucocorticoid</keyword>
	<keyword>Complement activation</keyword>
	<keyword>Knee arthroplasty, total</keyword>
</DOC>