<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00102050</DOC>
	<brief_summary>NM-702 oral tablets are being developed for the treatment of Intermittent Claudication, a primary early stage indication of peripheral arterial disease (PAD). This trial is designed to assess the safety and efficacy of 4 mg and/or 8 mg NM-702 taken twice a day (BID) for 24 weeks to see if it improves peak walking time (PWT) more than placebo for the treatment of Intermittent Claudication.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of NM-702 Tablets for the Treatment of Intermittent Claudication</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>NM-702 oral tablets are being developed for the treatment of Intermittent Claudication, a primary early stage indication of peripheral arterial disease (PAD). This trial is designed to assess the safety and efficacy of 4 mg and/or 8 mg NM-702 BID for 24 weeks to see if it improves peak walking time (PWT) more than placebo for the treatment of Intermittent Claudication.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intermittent Claudication</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phosphodiesterase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Stable, symptomatic, intermittent claudication due to occlusive atherosclerotic disease of the lower extremities Median treadmill peak walking time between 90 and 600 seconds Symptoms of limb threatening ischemia (ischemic rest pain, ischemic ulceration and/or gangrene) Clinically significant pulmonary, neurological or skeletal dysfunction (e.g., lumbar canal stenosis, emphysema, uncontrolled angina, multiple sclerosis, or gait altering amputation) that would directly interfere or limit exercise testing Subjects who have had, or will require, a peripheral revascularization procedure within 12 weeks prior to or following treatment initiation. A resting blood pressure greater than 150/100 and other clinically significant results.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>NM-702 tablets</keyword>
	<keyword>intermittent claudication</keyword>
	<keyword>peripheral</keyword>
	<keyword>arterial</keyword>
	<keyword>vascular</keyword>
	<keyword>peripheral arterial disease</keyword>
</DOC>