<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00266929</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the safety and effectiveness of surgical versus conservative management of type II odontoid fractures among patients &gt; 64 years of age. Of secondary interest is to determine if there are differences in outcomes between anterior screw fixation and posterior fusion of these fractures.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Type II Odontoid Fractures Among the Elderly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Hypotheses are as follows: - Patients receiving surgical management will exhibit better disease specific health and general health related quality of life measures compared to those managed conservatively. - The rate of radiographic bony fusion will be greater among elderly patients receiving surgical fixation compared to patients receiving conservative management. - The rate of non union will be greater in the conservative group compared to the surgical group. - The complication rate will be higher in the surgical group due to the nature of the intervention though the rate of severe and serious complications will be low.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neck Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All new type II odontoid fractures including those in which the fracture line crosses into the body of C2 Age &gt; 64 Stable and unstable fractures &lt; 3 months postinjury No previous treatment for an odontoid fracture Pathological fractures unrelated to osteoporosis Severe dementia or severe mental health problems Participation in other trials or unlikely to attend followups</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>64 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>odontoid fx</keyword>
	<keyword>surgical intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>conservative treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>nonunion</keyword>
	<keyword>odontoid fractures</keyword>
	<keyword>surgical treatment</keyword>
</DOC>