<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00266565</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Toxicity of anti-IL-5</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Anti-Interleukin-5 (IL-5) Study for Hypereosinophilic Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of the study is to assess the toxicity of anti-IL-5, and to see whether it lowers peripheral blood eosinophils and/or tissue and whether it has a steroid and/or interferon sparing effect.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophagitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastroenteritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eosinophilic Esophagitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Churg-Strauss Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypereosinophilic Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Enteritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eosinophilia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastritis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adequate renal, cardiac, and hepatic function Not pregnant or breastfeeding A diagnosis of hypereosinophilic syndrome such as: Idiopathic hypereosinophilic syndrome; Eosinophilia myalgia syndrome; Eosinophilic gastroenteritis; ChurgStrauss syndrome; Eosinophilic cellulitis; Benign hypereosinophilia; or Eosinophilic esophagitis. Maintained on, or in need of, the following: glucocorticoids, interferon, methotrexate, hydroxyurea, cytoxan, 6mercaptopurine, or vincristine Blood eosinophil counts greater than 750 cells/mcl Creatinine &gt; 3 X upper limit for age AST &gt; 5 X upper limit for age Platelet count &lt; 50,000/mm3 Cardiac function: 1. NYHA class IIIb or IV (patients with shortness of breath or fatigue with mild exertion or at rest); 2. Patients with symptomatic supraventricular or ventricular arrythmias requiring treatment; 3. Patients requiring IV heart failure medications; 4. Angina or acute myocardial infarction History of renal, hepatic, endocrine, oncologic, cardiovascular disease, or any other condition which, in the opinion of the Investigator, would jeopardize the safety of the patient or impact on the validity of the study results History of allergic or adverse response to previous antibody type therapy History of allergic or adverse response to antiIL5 therapy Evidence of, or history of, a parasitic infection (within past 1 year) Participation in a previous clinical trial involving an investigational agent within 30 days prior to study initiation Receipt of antiIL5 therapy in the past Blood donation of 450 ml (1 pint) or more within 30 days prior to study initiation Abnormal or unusual diet or substantial changes in eating habits within 30 days prior to, or during, the study. Patients who do not have eosinophil levels &gt; 750 cells/mcl after the runin period. Patients who have only eosinophilic infiltration of tissue are eligible if they do not develop an eosinophil level &gt; 750 cells/mcl, assuming that they meet all other eligibility requirements. Positive serum pregnancy test Breastfeeding Unable to use effective birth control methods for duration of study Unable or unwilling to give voluntary informed consent/assent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>