<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00344760</DOC>
	<brief_summary>We hypothesize that using a potent antiretroviral such as Enfuvirtide during the induction phase of HAART therapy will lead to faster clearance of virus and infected cells, and lower number of minority variant HIV-1 strains.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate of the Efficacy of Enfuvirtide During the Induction Phase of Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an 48 week Phase 4, open label, randomized, prospective, pilot proof of concept study to evaluate the use of Enfuvirtide in an induction/maintenance treatment model. Patients meeting inclusion criteria will be stratified into two groups according to HIV-1 RNA viral loads (less than 300,000 copies/ml and greater than 300,000 copies/ml). Thereafter, patients will be block randomized (the size of each block will be two patients) into one of two treatment arms. All patients will receive Efavirenz 600mg once a day, Lamivudine 300 mg once a day, and Tenofovir 300mg once a day. After randomization, one half of the patients will receive no additional treatment, while the other half will receive Enfuvirtide 90mg sq BID until the viral load is &lt;50 x 2 consecutive visits or 12 weeks (whichever comes first).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Efavirenz</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lamivudine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Enfuvirtide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age: 18 to 70 years of age. 2. Sex: Male or Female. 3. Documented HIV1 seropositive by Western Blot, Elisa, or HIV1 viral load. 4. Naïve to HAART. 5. Viral load &gt;100,000c/ml. 6. CD4&lt;200c/ml. 7. Volunteers must be willing and able to provide written informed consent to participate in the study. 8. Available for at least 48 weeks of followup. 1. Volunteers with an acute and clinically significant medical event as determined by the investigator to result in a life expectancy less then 12 months despite ART. 2. Volunteers with current psychiatric illness, alcohol abuse or illicit drug use that in the opinion of the Principal Investigator may interfere with patient's ability to comply with protocol requirements. 3. Renal insufficiency (Estimated Creatinine clearance of &lt;60ml/min.) 4. Patients with malabsorption or severe chronic diarrhea for more than 30 days. 5. Inability to consume adequate oral intake (defined as inability to eat at least 1 meal per day). 6. Current treatment for malignancy other than basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix. 7. Any other medical condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, might interfere with completion of the study or evaluation of the results. 8. Pregnancy or breastfeeding 9. In a female capable of child bearing, unwillingness to use effective barrier contraception or abstinence 10. Patient who is currently receiving an experimental medication.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>