<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02259543</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to investigate the effects of the application of a citric acid + tetracycline gel solution during 90 or 180 seconds compared to no conditioning in the outcomes of treatment of Miller's class I or II recession defects by subepithelial connective tissue graft.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Root Biomodification With Citric Acid and Tetracycline Improves the Outcomes of Root Coverage</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Adult patients showing Miller's class I or II recession defects requiring root coverage were recruited to participate in the study. All patients were submitted to non surgical periodontal therapy consisting of scaling and root planing, prophylaxis, and oral hygiene instruction in order to reduce/eliminate gingival inflammation. After that, patients were randomly allocated to three different treatment groups based on root conditioning: G0- no conditioning; G90- root conditioning for 90 seconds; G180- root conditioning for 180 seconds. Allocation was defined by a software. Root coverage was performed by subepithelial connective tissue graft (SCTG) in all treated sites by the same operator, who performed the indicated root treatment. Periodontal parameters were investigated at baseline and at 1, 3, 6 and 12 months post-operatively by a blinded trained expertise different from operator and included: pocket depth, recession height, clinical attachment level, width of keratinized gingiva, sulcular bleeding index and plaque index. Hypersensitivity at recession sites was also investigated at baseline and at 7 days, 14 days, 1, 3, 6 and 12 months after treatment according to visual analogic scale (VAS).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Gingival Recession</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tetracycline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citric Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>presence of Miller's class I or II recession extending 25 mm apical to CEJ requiring root coverage for the following reasons: esthetics, progression of recession or hypersensitivity. smokers; pregnants; routine use of anticonvulsants, antihypertensive or cyclosporine; uncontrolled systemic diseases (e.g.: diabetes mellitus); systemic conditions that requires antibiotic prophylaxis (e.g.: history of bacterial endocarditis; rheumatoid arthritis; prosthetic valves); antibiotics, steroidal or nonsteroidal antiinflammatory intake in the 6month previous period.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>gingival recession</keyword>
	<keyword>soft tissue</keyword>
	<keyword>root biomodification</keyword>
	<keyword>root coverage</keyword>
	<keyword>citric acid</keyword>
	<keyword>tetracycline</keyword>
</DOC>