<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00445328</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the efficacy and safety of dalteparin vs unfractionated heparin for the prevention of VTE (Venous Thromboembolism) in hospitalized acutely ill medical patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dalteparin vs Unfractionated Heparin For The Prevention Of Venous Thromboembolism (VTE) In Hospitalized Acutely Ill Medical Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study was prematurely discontinued due to delay in overall study start-up and inability to meet pre-defined protocol recruitment milestones on June 30th, 2008. There were no safety concerns regarding the study in the decision to terminate the trial.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium heparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dalteparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heparin, Low-Molecular-Weight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged greater than or equal to 18 years Acute medical condition with a projected hospitalization of greater than or equal to 4 days and had less than or equal to 3 days of prior immobilization for more than two thirds of the day Acute congestive heart failure Class IIIIV per NHYA/ Acute respiratory failure not requiring mechanical ventilation or Both Acute infection without septic shock/ Acute episode of inflammatory bowel disease/ Acute rheumatologic disorders/ Acute lumbar pain or sciatica or vertebral compression with at least one risk factor for VTE Contraindications to use of anticoagulants Active bleeding or abnormal coagulation tests Recent (less than 1 month) head injury, hemorrhagic stroke, cerebral tumor or intracranial aneurysm or ischemic stroke within the last month. Major surgical or invasive procedure within the last month resulting in ongoing convalescence Lumbar or spinal puncture within last 48 hours S creatinine levels more than 2 On inotropic agents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>hospitalised acutely medically ill patients; Venous Thromboembolism, Infection, Inflammatory Bowel Diseases, Heart Failure, Congestive, Sciatica</keyword>
</DOC>