<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00989924</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the correlation among magnetocardiography (MCG) patterns and various known cardiovascular risk factors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Research on the Correlation Among Magnetocardiography Patterns and Known Cardiovascular Risk Factors in Diabetic Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>It is well understood that diabetes mellitus (DM) causes various micro- and macrovascular complications. Among them, coronary heart diseases (CHDs) claim most mortality, and diabetes has been considered as "CHD equivalent". Furthermore, the risk of CHD has been noticed to increase in the pre-diabetic stage, suggesting the development of CHD may start in a rather early stage of the disease. Thus, early detection of CHD in diabetic patients seems to be important. However, currently exam methods for CHD in diabetic patients seemed to have their limitations. Developed in the 1960s, magnetocardiography (MCG) is designed to detect the weak magnetic field generated by the electrical activity of the heart, and has been used widely in the study of fetal cardiac electrophysiology, arrhythmia and ischemic heart disease. However, the MCG pattern in diabetic patients is not fully understood. The aim of the study is to clarify the correlation among various cardiovascular risk factors and MCG pattern in diabetic patients. And, according to the results of the study, we'll evaluate the potentiality of MCG in early diagnosis of CHD in diabetic patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clear consciousness Met the diagnostic criteria of DM published by the American Diabetes Association in 2009 not suitable for MCG exam (ex. with pacemaker implantation or indwelling metallic device)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary heart disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Magnetocardiography</keyword>
</DOC>