<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00989014</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized, double-blind, parallel-group, vehicle-controlled, dose-finding study to investigate the pharmacodynamics and the safety of three dosages of CD07805/47 topical gel (0.07%, 0.18%, and 0.50%), after a single application in subjects with a clinical diagnosis of stable moderate to severe erythematotelangiectatic rosacea. Subjects will be randomized in a 1:1:1:1 ratio to receive either one of three CD07805/47 topical gel concentrations (0.07%, 0.18%, or 0.50%) or Vehicle Gel. All subjects will be treated with a single application (once daily dosing for one day) of study medication.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose-Finding Study of CD07805/47 Topical Gel in Subjects With Erythematotelangiectatic Rosacea</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rosacea</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female who is at least 18 years of age. Clinical diagnosis of stable moderate to severe erythematotelangiectatic rosacea. CEA (clinician's erythema assessment) score greater than or equal to 3 at Screening and on Treatment visit at baseline. PSA (patient self assessment) score of greater than or equal to 3 at Screening and on Treatment visit at baseline. Presence of 2 or fewer inflammatory facial lesions. History of Raynaud's Syndrome, glaucoma, orthostatic hypotension, thromboangiitis obliterans, cerebral or coronary insufficiency, or depression. History of refractive surgery such as photorefractive keratectomy. The subject is being treated with monoamine oxidase (MAO) inhibitor, antidepressants, barbiturates, opiates, sedatives, systemic anesthetics, alphaagonists, beta blockers, antihypertensive agents, cardiac glycosides, or systemic anticoagulants. The subject is currently enrolled in an investigational drug or device study or participated in such a study in the past 3 months prior to enrollment and is still in the exclusion period on the day of the Treatment visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Erythematotelangiectatic</keyword>
	<keyword>Rosacea</keyword>
</DOC>