<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00989430</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study with a randomized controlled design is to examine the effects of prism adaptation treatment on two visual-spatial recovery components. After a stroke, an "internal GPS", locating where objects or people lie in a particular area of space, may be impaired. Alternately, a stroke may impair precise visual-spatial hand and body aiming movements. The research team wishes to discover whether prism adaptation treatment (two weeks of daily 20-min sessions of goal-directed movement with prism goggles) affects visual-spatial where or aiming errors selectively after stroke. This research represents one of the first attempts to apply what we know about the brain from neuroscience research, to modern clinical rehabilitation practices.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prism Adaptation Therapy for Spatial Neglect</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this research study with a randomized controlled design is to examine the effects of prism adaptation treatment on two visual-spatial recovery components. After a stroke, an "internal GPS", locating where objects or people lie in a particular area of space, may be impaired. Alternately, a stroke may impair precise visual-spatial hand and body aiming movements. The research team wishes to discover whether prism adaptation treatment (two weeks of daily 20-min sessions of goal-directed movement with prism goggles) affects visual-spatial where or aiming errors selectively after stroke. This research represents one of the first attempts to apply what we know about the brain from neuroscience research, to modern clinical rehabilitation practices.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Perceptual Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The subject is 18 to 100 years of age, inclusive. The subject has had a stroke on the right side of the brain. The subject is able to give Informed consent. The subject has a spatial neglect (if known). The subject is able and willing to comply with the study protocol, including availability for all scheduled clinic visits. The subject has or had a serious brain condition other than stroke.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>CVA</keyword>
	<keyword>cerebrovascular accident</keyword>
	<keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
</DOC>