<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03092804</DOC>
	<brief_summary>With the advent of the aging society, dementia becomes the focus of common people. As for the neurodegeneration dementia, no disease modifying treatments have been discovered. Idiopathic normal pressure hydrocephalus (iNPH) is considered as one of reversible dementia, which can be hint by the surgery. In addition, dementia of iNPH is the typical subcortical dementia. Therefore exploring the pathogenic mechanism is conducive to the early diagnosis and treatment. This research is to monitor the changing of iNPHGS, cognitive function, walking ability as well as brain construction imaging and neural network before and after ventriculo-peritoneal shunting in order to demonstrate the pathogenesis of triads. In the process, the supplementary test, for instance, CSF tap test, will be validated the predictive value.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Brain Structure and Neural Network Changing the Before and After Ventriculo-peritoneal Shunting in the Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hydrocephalus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrocephalus, Normal Pressure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ncluded will be subjects with a probable diagnosis of NPH. The diagnosis will be based primarily on presence of gait impairment plus at least one other impairment in urinary symptoms, cognition impairment or both. 1. Are 50 years old or older 2. Patients who understand the study protocol 3. Patients who meet the criteria for NPH 1. A typical personal history 2. A typical brain imaging on head CT or MRI 3. Normal LP findings excluding other conditions 4. Exclusion of other conditions causing the symptomatology 1. Patients below the age of 50 years. 2. Patients who underwent shunt surgery before</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Shunting</keyword>
	<keyword>Brain constructure</keyword>
	<keyword>Neural network</keyword>
</DOC>