<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02544698</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates the safety of Pneumococcal 13-valent Conjugate Vaccine in Healthy People Aged 2 Months and Older.120 Subjects will be equally divided into 4 groups,including 18 years and older,2-5 years old, 2 months old and 3 months old. Subjects aged 18 years and 2-5 years old will receive one dose of PCV13 vaccine,while subjects aged 2 and 3 months will receive 3 doses of PCV13 vaccine,injected at 2, 4, 6 months or 3、4、5 months respectively.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of Pneumococcal 13-valent Conjugate Vaccine in Healthy People Aged 2 Months and Older</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Healthy babies with health conditions confirmed according to medical history, medical examination and judgment of researchers; 2. Satisfy the age requirements of the clinical trial.(children from 2 months to 5 years old and adults over the age of 18); 3. Parents or guardians of the subjects must provide informed consent forms with personally signature and date; 4. Parents or guardians of the subjects have been informed of all aspects of the research; 5. Subjects or guardians can obey the requirements of the clinical research; 6. No pneumococcal vaccine inoculation history, no other preventive vaccination within 7 days; 7. Axillary temperature below 37℃ 1. People with pneumococcal vaccine inoculation history, no matter experimentally or already on the market; 2. People has allergic reaction to any drugs, vaccine or vaccinerelated components previously; 3. People has allergic reaction to 13vPnC, 7vPnC or other complexes associated with the drug, known or suspected; 4. People has hemorrhagic physical constitution or diseases that prolong bleeding time, intramuscular injection taboo; 5. People has immune deficiency or immune function inhibition, known or suspected; 6. People has irritability, convulsions, epilepsy, brain diseases and mental history or family history; 7. People has cultureconfirmed invasive diseases caused by streptococcus pneumoniae history; 8. People has serious congenital malformations or serious chronic diseases that are known, people with congenital deformities, stunted or has a clinical diagnosis of serious chronic diseases (such as Down syndrome, diabetes, sickle cell anemia or nerve disorders, GuillainBarre syndrome); 9. People suffers from these diseases: respiratory diseases, acute or chronic active stage of infection, severe cardiovascular disease, kidney and liver diseases, malignant tumors, skin diseases, babies with HIV infected mothers(inspection report is available); 10. People with vaccinationrelated contraindications that other researchers believe; 11. People take part in other clinical trials while taking part in this clinical trial or 28 days before this clinical trial. People who participate in purely observational studies are acceptable; 12. People received blood products or intravenous immunoglobulin. People who was inoculated Hepatitis B immunoglobulin can be acceptable.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
</DOC>