<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02975648</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the effect of an educational model, which includes cardiac rehabilitation with emphasis on physical activity and telephone reinforcement, with the usual management of individuals undergoing to intervention coronary percutaneous, in relation to physical activity six months after discharge.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Education Model for Cardiac Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Randomized controlled trial (RCT) at a public teaching hospital, which has specialized care for CAD in Ribeirão Preto, state of São Paulo, Brazil. The intervention group will receive usual care and an educational programme and the control group will receive only usual care. One of the researchers will perform the first interview (baseline). A researcher (who will not have contact with the patients) will generate the random allocation in Graphpad software, concealing it from the investigators in sequentially numbered, sealed, opaque envelopes. The same researcher who carried out the interview will open the envelope to allocate the participants to either intervention or control group. The educational programme consists of four booklets entitled 1. Percutaneous Transluminal Coronary Angioplasty, 2. Going home after your coronary angioplasty, 3. How to take care of your heart and your health, and 4. How to practice physical activities. The educational programme includes the telephone follow-up that consists in three calls to motivate the participants and clarify doubts. The booklets will be offered to the participants by a researcher (who will not participate in the interviews) face to face, who will explain the content step by step.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arteriosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients (18 years or more) of both sexes Being submitted to the first percutaneous coronary intervention Having a properly functioning residential phone line No cognitive conditions to participate (evaluated by the ability to inform the day of the week, the month, and the place where is) Who do not present clinical or physical conditions to respond to the questionnaires (individuals with dyspnea and / or mental confusion) Who report difficulties to talk over the telephone (auditory deficit) Who have sequelae that may influence the activities of daily living (limb amputation or paralysis) Having contraindication to physical exercises prescribed by the physician, and who are already participating in some cardiac rehabilitation program with supervision</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>