<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02975024</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Apply the LSCI for follow-up the postoperative microcirculation after surgical procedures to enlarge keratinized gingiva in order to characterize the kinetics of the blood flow changes during wound healing in human subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Blood Flow Analysis of the Human Mucosa After Vestibuloplasty Procedures</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Vestibuloplasty is the common name of those procedures designed to widen the zone of attached gingiva. The apically repositioned split thickness flap with a xenogeneic collagen matrix or with a combination of strip gingival graft and a xenogeneic collagen matrix are frequently used surgical techniques, however no data are available, how these graft tissues affect the microcirculation of the healing gingiva. LSCI is a non-invasive, two dimensional method to evaluate microcirculation of different tissues. This new method let us monitor the entire surgical area real-time during the healing period. The aim of the present study is to define blood flow patterns, which might characterize the wound healing of such surgical procedures during the first 6 months of healing in order to facilitate treatment.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Ages Eligible for Study: 18 Years to 45 Years Genders Eligible for Study: Both Accepts Healthy Volunteers: Yes • clinical diagnosis of inadequate width of keratinized gingiva at the mandibular front region pregnancy heavy smoking general diseases taking medications or having treatments which have an effect on mucosal healing in general (e.g. steroids, antiinflammatory drugs) taking any other medications in the last three months (except contraceptives)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>mandibular vestibuloplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>wound healing</keyword>
	<keyword>microcirculation</keyword>
	<keyword>Laser Speckle Contrast Imager</keyword>
	<keyword>Mucograft</keyword>
	<keyword>strip gingival graft</keyword>
</DOC>