<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01198574</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Anemia and vitamin A deficiency (VAD) are major nutritional problems in the world and also in Myanmar. Both nutrient deficiencies result from interaction of several causal factors, and a better understanding of the etiology to interpret the prevalence and to formulate appropriate measures to reduce these deficiencies is necessary. There is a growing concern on the role of sub-clinical inflammation on the nutritional status indicators during the nutritional status assessment. However, there is lack of information on the role of inflammation on the iron supplementation. The adolescent period is a window of opportunity to improve the preconceptional iron status of the girls and recently gained much attention. The purpose of the study is to understand the role of inflammation on iron and vitamin A status during iron and vitamin A supplementation. The findings will show the extent to which iron supplementation has been hampered by inflammation and to formulate the necessary measures to overcome the interference.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sub-clinical Inflammation and Iron Supplementation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ferrous fumarate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinol palmitate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin B Complex</mesh_term>
	<criteria>adolescent girls (age 1219 years) already experienced menarche anemic girls (Hb&lt;120 g/L) no known illness (apparently healthy) free from haemoglobinopathy No regular consumption of iron and vitamin A supplement during the last 3 months subjects with chronic illness subjects with severe anaemia who do not give the consents</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>iron supplementation</keyword>
	<keyword>sub-clinical inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>adolescents</keyword>
</DOC>