<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01198626</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the efficacy, safety and tolerability of JNJ-32729463 compared to moxifloxacin for the treatment of subjects requiring hospitalization for Community-Acquired Bacterial Pneumonia (CABP).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Study of JNJ-32729463 Compared With Moxifloxacin for the Treatment of Subjects Requiring Hospitalization for Community-Acquired Bacterial Pneumonia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia, Bacterial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Moxifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluoroquinolones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Norgestimate, ethinyl estradiol drug combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>women of childbearing potential must agree to use an acceptable method of birth control clinical diagnosis of community acquired bacterial pneumonia (CABP) PORT score of II or greater able to generate an adequate sputum specimen chest xray showing presence of new infiltrates in a lobar or multilobar distribution characteristic of bacterial pneumonia history of tendon damage/disorders due to quinolone therapy uncorrected hypokalemia history of myasthenia gravis intubated at the time of consent OR subject is a candidate for enrollment into the openlabel S. aureus arm and has been intubated greater than 12 hours prior to randomization mild CABP with a PORT score of less than II viral, fungal, mycobacterial, or atypical pneumonia as a primary diagnosis pneumonia suspected to be secondary to aspiration primary, solitary lung abscess healthcareassociated pneumonia, hospitalacquired pneumonia, or ventilatorassociated pneumonia known bronchial obstruction or a history of postobstructive pneumonia. primary lung cancer or another malignancy metastatic to the lungs cystic fibrosis, known or suspected Pneumocystis jiroveci (carinii) pneumonia, or known or suspected active tuberculosis infection that necessitates the use of a concomitant antibacterial agent in addition to study medication systemic antibiotics within the last 96 hours before randomization, with exceptions hospitalized for greater than 72 hours for any reason 30 days before randomization (excluding the 24 hour period before enrollment). history of a serious hypersensitivity reaction to any quinolone including moxifloxacin. female and pregnant, breastfeeding, or may be pregnant. Other protocolspecific eligibility criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>community-acquired bacterial pneumonia</keyword>
	<keyword>CABP</keyword>
	<keyword>CAP</keyword>
	<keyword>pneumonia</keyword>
	<keyword>pneumonia, bacterial</keyword>
	<keyword>bacterial infections</keyword>
	<keyword>anti-bacterial agents</keyword>
	<keyword>anti-infective agents</keyword>
	<keyword>lung disease, interstitial</keyword>
	<keyword>respiratory tract diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>respiratory tract infections</keyword>
	<keyword>community-acquired infections</keyword>
</DOC>