<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02027922</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is to compare the prophylactic and therapeutic clinical effectiveness of two fluoride varnishes in children at high caries risk. It was hypothesized, the use of Fluor Protector S (I) fluoride varnish in children with deciduous teeth at high risk of caries (P) reduces caries and the activity/remineralisation of carious enamel spots (transformation of White Spot Lesion into D (decay)) (O), similarly to what occurs after the use of Duraphat varnish (C).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Effectiveness of Various Professionally Applied Fluoride Prophylaxes in Groups at High Risk</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is to compare the prophylactic and therapeutic clinical effectiveness of two fluoride varnishes in children at high caries risk. It was hypothesized, the use of Fluor Protector S (I) fluoride varnish in children with deciduous teeth at high risk of caries (P) reduces caries and the activity/remineralisation of carious enamel spots (transformation of White Spot Lesion into D (decay)) (O), similarly to what occurs after the use of Duraphat varnish (C). The question set bases on a Caries Assessment by Risk Management system basing on the occurrence of major caries causative agents (biological and medical), and also of the protective/preventive ones. Questions related to the social and economical status will be left out because of the difficulty of getting them answered honestly. Teeth will be scored according to International Caries Detection System II classification, and oral hygiene according to the Greene and Vermillion simplified Oral Hygiene Index (OHI-S) (1964). Children and their parents/guardians will receive hygienic, dietary and prophylactic guidelines.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dental Caries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sodium fluoride topical preparation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sodium Fluoride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorides</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorides, Topical</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Listerine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>generally healthy children aged 35 years high risk of caries parent/legal guardian consent for participation in research study chronic diseases or medication in medical history planned change of residence within a year aged &lt;3, &gt;5 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>white spot lesion</keyword>
	<keyword>caries</keyword>
</DOC>