<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02913963</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to demonstrate that the application of Kinesio Taping on a myofascial trigger point in the trapezius muscle able to cause a decrease of the trigger point pain and an increase of the cervical range of motion in asymptomatic subjects</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Changes on Pain and Range of Motion by the Use of Kinesio Taping in Subjects With Myofascial Trigger Point</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The use of Kinesio Taping has become very popular for the treatment of many musculoskeletal disorders in recent decades. Of the six variants of application that has the Kinesio Taping, the space correction technique is suggested for pain management. The increased space achieved with this variant decreases the pressure Kinesio Taping by raising the skin directly over the treatment area, reducing chemical irritation receptors and therefore pain. The aim of this study is to demonstrate that the application of this variant of Kinesio Taping on a myofascial trigger point in the trapezius muscle able to cause a decrease of the pain and an increase of the cervical range of motion in asymptomatic subjects. For this, the pressure pain threshold will be measured with a algometer on the trigger point and the range of motion with a cervical goniometer.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Mobility Limitation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myofascial Pain Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Agree to participate in the study (signed informed consent) Presence of latent myofascial trigger point in upper trapezius. Subjects in which not clearly identified myofascial trigger point in the upper trapezius . Subjects who suffer or have suffered pathologies of upper limb deformities or orthopedic injuries that can alter static and biomechanics of shoulder and neck. Subjects who suffer or have suffered rheumatic or neurological disease or chronic shoulder pain and/or neck Subjects diagnosed with fibromyalgia, myelopathy or radiculopathy. Subjects suffering from any psychiatric disorder (such as anxiety or depression). Subjects who have suffered posttraumatic alteration (whiplash type) or cervical surgery. Pregnancy risk of abortion. Have used analgesics in the 48 hours before participating in the study Subjects presenting any contraindications to the application of Kinesio Taping. Know the Kinesio Taping technique applied in the study. Be receiving physical therapy for any shoulder or neck pathology.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>