<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02413606</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: It has often been hypothesized that the frequency of follow-up for patients with early-stage endometrial cancer could be decreased. However, studies evaluating effects of a reduced follow-up schedule among this patient group are lacking. Objective: Assess patient satisfaction and cost-effectiveness of a less frequent follow-up schedule compared to the schedule according to the Dutch guideline. Study design: Dutch multicentre randomized controlled trial with a 5 year follow-up. Patients (n=282) are randomized in an intervention group with 4 follow-up visits during 3 years, and a control group with 10-13 follow-up visits during 5 years, according to the Dutch guideline. Patients are asked to fill out a questionnaire at baseline, 6, 12, 36 and 60 months. Patient inclusion will take two years (if 60% of the patients participate). Outcomes: Primary: Patient satisfaction with follow-up care and cost-effectiveness. Secondary: health care use, adherence to schedule, health-related quality of life, fear of recurrence, anxiety and depression, information provision, recurrence, survival Patients: Stage 1A and 1B low-risk endometrial cancer patients, for whom adjuvant radiotherapy is not indicated Statistics: linear regression analyses to assess differences in patient satisfaction with follow-up care between intervention and control group adjusted for potential pre-defined confounders. Expected results: Patients in the intervention arm have a similar satisfaction with follow-up care and overall outcomes, but lower health care use and costs than patients in the control arm. No effects are expected on QALY differences (losses) and satisfaction, but the reduced schedule is expected to save 144.000 per year in the Netherlands.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ENdometrial Cancer SURvivors' Follow-up carE (ENSURE): Less is More?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients with Endometrioïd type endometrial carcinoma with stage 1 (FIGO, 2009) disease, with the following combination of stage, age and grade: Stage 1A, any age, grade 1 or 2; Stage 1B, &lt; 60 years, grade 1 or 2 without LVSI; 2. Written informed consent; 3. Sufficient oral and written command of the Dutch language. 1. Any other stage and type of endometrial carcinoma 2. Histological types papillary serous carcinoma or clear cell carcinoma 3. Uterine sarcoma (including carcinosarcoma) 4. Radiotherapy for current endometrial carcinoma 5. Previous malignancy (except for nonmelanomatous skin cancer) &lt; 5 yrs 6. Confirmed Lynch syndrome 7. Previous pelvic radiotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>follow up care</keyword>
	<keyword>satisfaction with care</keyword>
</DOC>