<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02413138</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The trial will consist of three stages: 1) a 30 day Phase 2 PK and PD evaluation of somavaratan, 2) an optional Phase 2 Extension and 3) a 12 month Phase 3 safety and efficacy stage. Upon completion of the PK/PD stage, the PK/PD profiles for the GHD children in this study will be compared to the PK/PD profiles for the GHD children treated in the Western study Phase 1b/2a study (Protocol 12VR2) and identify the somavaratan dose to be used in the Phase 3 stage in Japan. The Phase 3 stage will continue dosing for 12 months to obtain safety and efficacy data on 48 subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Versartis Trial in Pre-pubertal Japanese Children With Growth Hormone Deficiency (GHD) to Assess Long-Acting Growth Hormone (Somavaratan, VRS-317)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The trial will consist of three stages: 1) a 30 day Phase 2 PK and PD evaluation of somavaratan, 2) an optional Phase 2 Extension and 3) a 12 month Phase 3 safety and efficacy stage. The study is a randomized, multi-center, open label study. The primary endpoint is height velocity at 12 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Endocrine System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dwarfism, Pituitary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Growth Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronological Age ≥ 3.0 years and ≤ 9.0 years (girls) or ≤ 10.0 years (boys) Prepubertal status Diagnosis of GHD as documented by two or more GH stimulation test results Height SD score ≤ 2.0 at screening Weight for Stature ≥ 10th percentile IGFI SD score ≤ 1.0 at screening Delayed bone age Prior treatment with any growth promoting agent History of, or current, significant disease Chromosomal aneuploidy, significant gene mutations (other than those that cause GHD) or confirmed diagnosis of a named syndrome Birth weight and/or birth length less than 5th percentile for gestational age A diagnosis of Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder Daily use of antiinflammatory doses of glucocorticoid Prior history of leukemia, lymphoma, sarcoma or cancer Ocular findings suggestive of increased intracranial pressure and/or retinopathy at screening Significant spinal abnormalities including scoliosis, kyphosis and spina bifida variants Significant abnormality in screening laboratory studies</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>GHD</keyword>
</DOC>