<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01186094</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized study is a multi-center, randomized, study to compare the efficacy of sirolimus (Cypher) versus zotarolimus-eluting stent (Endeavor Resolute) implantation for long coronary lesions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Percutaneous Treatment of LONG Native Coronary Lesions With Drug-Eluting Stent-IV: (LONG-DES-IV)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Following angiography, patients with significant diameter stenosis &gt;50% and lesion length (&gt; 25mm) requiring single or multiple long-stent placement (total stent length&gt;28mm) by visual estimation and eligible for LONG-DES IV trial inclusion and exclusion criteria will be randomized 1:1 to a) CYPHER and b) ENDEAVOR RESOLUTE stent by the stratified randomization method.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient must be at least 18 years of age. Significant native coronary artery stenosis (&gt;50% by visual estimate) with lesion length of more than 25mm, which requiring single or multiple long stent placement (&gt;=28mm) Patients with silent ischemia, stable or unstable angina pectoris, ad NonSTelevation myocardial infarction The patient or guardian agrees to the study protocol and the schedule of clinical and angiographic followup, and provides informed, written consent, as approved by the appropriate Institutional Review Board/Ethical Committee of the respective clinical site. Any contraindication to any of the following medications: aspirin, heparin, clopidogrel, stainless steel, contrast agents, sirolimus, or everolimus. An elective surgical procedure is planned that would necessitate interruption of antiplatelet drugs during the first 6 months post enrollment. Acute STsegmentelevation MI or cardiogenic shock Terminal illness with life expectancy &lt;1 year Patients who are actively participating in another drug or device investigational study, which have not completed the primary endpoint followup period. Instent restenosis at target vessel (either bare metal stent or drugeluting stent segment, nontarget vessel ISR is permitted) Patients with EF&lt;30%. Serum creatinine level &gt;=3.0mg/dL or dependence on dialysis. Patients with left main stem stenosis (&gt;50% by visual estimate).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Stent</keyword>
</DOC>