<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00499252</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II trial is studying the side effects and how well paclitaxel albumin-stabilized nanoparticle formulation works in treating patients with recurrent or persistent ovarian epithelial cancer, fallopian tube cancer, or primary peritoneal cancer. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as paclitaxel albumin-stabilized nanoparticle formulation, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Paclitaxel Albumin-Stabilized Nanoparticle Formulation in Treating Patients With Recurrent or Persistent Ovarian Epithelial Cancer, Fallopian Tube Cancer, or Primary Peritoneal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the antitumor activity of paclitaxel albumin-stabilized nanoparticle formulation (Abraxane®), in terms of frequency and duration of objective response, in patients with persistent or recurrent platinum-resistant ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, or primary peritoneal cancer. II. Determine the toxicity of this drug in these patients. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the duration of progression-free survival and overall survival of patients treated with this drug. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients receive paclitaxel albumin-stabilized nanoparticle formulation (Abraxane®) IV over 30 minutes on days 1, 8, and 15. Treatment repeats every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 3 months for 2 years and then every 6 months for 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed diagnosis of 1 of the following: Ovarian epithelial cancer Fallopian tube cancer Primary peritoneal carcinoma Recurrent or persistent disease Must have received 1 prior platinumbased chemotherapy regimen containing carboplatin, cisplatin, or another organoplatinum compound for management of primary disease Initial treatment may have included intraperitoneal therapy, highdose therapy, consolidation therapy, or extended therapy administered after a surgical or nonsurgical assessment Patients who have not received prior paclitaxelbased chemotherapy must receive a second regimen that includes paclitaxel or docetaxel Platinumresistant or refractory disease, defined by 1 of the following: Treatmentfree interval of &lt; 6 months after completion of platinumbased therapy Persistent disease at completion of primary platinumbased therapy Progressive disease during platinumbased therapy Paclitaxelresistant disease, defined as having had a treatmentfree interval &lt; 6 months or shown disease progression during paclitaxelbased therapy Patients who have not received prior paclitaxelbased chemotherapy must receive a second regimen that includes paclitaxel or docetaxel Measurable disease, defined as ≥ 1 unidimensionally measurable lesion ≥ 20 mm by conventional techniques or ≥ 10 mm by spiral CT scan Must have ≥ 1 target lesion that can be used to assess response Tumors within a previously irradiated field are designated as nontarget lesions unless progression is documented or biopsy confirms persistence ≥ 90 days after completion of radiotherapy Not a candidate for a higher priority GOG protocol GOG performance status 02 ANC ≥ 1,500/mm³ Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm³ Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL Creatinine ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) Bilirubin normal SGOT ≤ 2.5 times ULN Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2.5 times ULN No active infection requiring antibiotics No sensory or motor neuropathy &gt; grade 1 Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception PT INR ≤ 1.5 or inrange INR 23 (if patient is on a stable dose of therapeutic warfarin) PTT &lt; 1.2 times control No concurrent serious medical or psychiatric illness, including serious active infection No uncontrolled hypertension (i.e., blood pressure ≥ 150/100 mm Hg) No uncompensated congestive heart failure or symptomatic coronary artery disease No myocardial infarction within the past 6 months No active bleeding No other invasive malignancies within the past 5 years except for nonmelanoma skin cancer No history of allergic reactions attributed to chemical or biological composition to paclitaxel or other study agents No concurrent amifostine or other protective reagents Recovered from prior surgery, radiotherapy, or chemotherapy No prior paclitaxel albuminstabilized nanoparticle formulation (Abraxane®) No prior cancer treatment that would preclude study therapy No additional prior cytotoxic chemotherapy for management of recurrent or persistent disease, including retreatment with initial chemotherapy regimens One additional prior noncytotoxic regimen (i.e., monoclonal antibodies, cytokines, or small molecule inhibitors of signal transduction) for management of recurrent or persistent disease allowed At least 1 week since prior hormonal therapy directed at the malignant tumor Concurrent hormone replacement therapy allowed At least 3 weeks since other prior therapy directed at the malignant tumor, including biologic therapy, immunologic agents, or radiotherapy More than 5 years since prior chemotherapy for any other portion of the abdominal cavity or pelvis, unless for treatment of ovarian, primary peritoneal, or fallopian tube cancer Prior adjuvant chemotherapy for localized breast cancer allowed provided it was completed &gt; 3 years ago and patient remains free of recurrent or metastatic disease More than 5 years since prior radiotherapy to any other portion of the abdominal cavity or pelvis, unless for treatment of ovarian, primary peritoneal, or fallopian tube cancer Prior radiotherapy for localized breast cancer, cancer of the head and neck, or skin cancer allowed provided it was completed &gt; 3 years ago and patient remains free of recurrent or metastatic disease No prior radiotherapy to &gt; 25% of marrowbearing areas</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>