<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00499317</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic Prostatitis/Chronic Pelvic Pain Syndrome (CP/CPPS) is a condition with several causes of which some remain unknown. It is believed that some types of CP may be genetic and passed down (or inherited) from one generation to the next. In this study, we are collecting genetic material and medical information to try to determine if there are genetic factors may play a role in CP/CPPS. We will be collecting DNA (from Saliva) and urine from each participant. Individuals and families with CP/CPPS will be enrolled. Family members of an individual with CP/CPPS are eligible whether or not they also experience CP/CPPS symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Genetic Study of Chronic Prostatitis/Chronic Pelvic Pain Syndrome (CP/CPPS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To further describe the phenotype of chronic prostatitis/chronic pelvic pain syndrome (CP/CPPS) and to correlate the phenotypic information with the genotypic findings utilizing linkage analysis and candidate gene studies. A North American cohort and a Bulgarian cohort will be recruited. Each individual participant will be required to give a DNA sample (via Saliva) and a urine sample. All samples will be stored.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pelvic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystitis, Interstitial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have symptoms for at least 3 months within the preceding 6 months: Pain in the pelvic area Urinary frequency and/or Urinary urgency and/or Sexual dysfunction (erectile dysfunction) Have CP/CPPS, IC, PBS, or BFS Be willing to provide a saliva and urine sample Agree to complete several brief questionnaires Family member of someone with CP/CPPS, PBS, IC or BFS Live in the USA or Canada Major structural/anatomical urinary tract abnormalities Underlying inborn or congenital conditions which affect the urinary tract Surgery/chemotherapy in the pelvic area</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Urgency</keyword>
	<keyword>Frequency</keyword>
	<keyword>Pelvic pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Sexual dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Erectile dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Painful intercourse</keyword>
</DOC>