<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00902603</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Ventavis® (iloprost) Registry is a multicenter, observational, U.S.-based study that longitudinally follows patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) who have been receiving therapy with Ventavis® for at least 3 months. Patients diagnosed with WHO Group I PAH who are on a stable regimen of commercial Ventavis® will be followed for a maximum of 2 years from the time of enrollment. Data will be collected via patient interview and review of the medical record. Quarterly data collection will include capture of medications and Ventavis® adherence data.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ventavis® Registry Protocol</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Ventavis® (iloprost) Registry is a multicenter, observational, U.S.-based study that longitudinally follows patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) who have been receiving therapy with Ventavis® for at least 3 months. Patients diagnosed with WHO Group I PAH and who are on a stable regimen of commercial Ventavis® will be followed for a maximum of 2 years from the time of enrollment. All data will be collected via patient interview and/or review of the medical record, as well as from I-neb® downloads using INSIGHT software. Adherence with Ventavis® will be compared before and after targeted instruction on inhalation techniques by a respiratory therapist or designee, as well as before and after participation in PAH patient support groups (if applicable). Quarterly data collection will include capture of PAH and non-PAH medications and Ventavis® adherence data; Ventavis® adherence data will also be collected one month after study entry.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Familial Primary Pulmonary Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iloprost</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Have a current diagnosis of WHO Group I PAH 2. Have initiated therapy with commercial Ventavis® administered via portable nebulizer at least 3 months prior to study enrollment, either with commercial product or from participation in Actelion's Clinical Study AC063A302 3. Age &gt; or = 18 years old at the time of enrollment 1. Meet the criteria for inclusion into WHO Groups II, III, IV or V PAH 2. Are not currently on commercial Ventavis® 3. Have initiated therapy with commercial Ventavis® administered via portable nebulizer less than 3 months prior to study enrollment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>pulmonary arterial hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Ventavis®</keyword>
	<keyword>iloprost</keyword>
</DOC>