<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01598857</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate efficacy, safety and tolerability of blisibimod when taken with methotrexate in the induction of remission in ANCA-Associated Small Vessel Vasculitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>BIANCA-SC: A Study of the Efficacy, Safety, and Tolerability of Blisibimod in Addition to Methotrexate During Induction of Remission in Subjects With ANCA-Associated Small Vessel Vasculitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vasculitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Systemic Vasculitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Granulomatosis with Polyangiitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Microscopic Polyangiitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. 18 years of age or older (male or female). 2. Granulomatosis with polyangiitis (GPA, or Wegener's granulomatosis) or microscopic polyangiitis (MPA) according to the definitions of the American College of Rheumatology and Chapel Hill Consensus Conference. 3. Active GPA or MPA disease at screening. 4. Positive for either PR3ANCA or MPOANCA at screening. 5. Subject willing to initiate corticosteroids and methotrexate (MTX) if not already on corticosteroids and/or MTX at baseline. 6. Clinical intention to prescribe MTX therapy for treatment of GPA or MPA. 1. Diagnosed with Churg Strauss syndrome. 2. Severe GPA or MPA disease that would conventionally be treated with cyclophosphamide. 3. Nursing or pregnant. 4. Active systemic infection or deepspace infection. 5. Active hepatitis B, active hepatitis C or a documented history of HIV, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C. 6. Liver disease. 7. History of documented antiglomerular basement membrane (GBM) disease. 8. Malignancy within the past 5 years. 9. History of active tuberculosis (TB) or history of TB infection. 10. Anemia, neutropenia, or thrombocytopenia. 11. Serum creatinine level greater than 2.5 mg/dL. 12. Prior administration of a Bcell modulating therapy other than rituximab. 13. Subject has not yet completed at least 3 months or 5 halflives (whichever is longer) since ending other investigational study. 14. History of congenital immunodeficiency.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>granulomatosis with polyangiitis</keyword>
	<keyword>microscopic polyangiitis</keyword>
	<keyword>anti-neutrophil cytoplasmic antibodies</keyword>
	<keyword>ANCA-associated vasculitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Wegener Granulomatosis</keyword>
</DOC>