<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01992146</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Recent studies have focused on the role of endogenous opioids on central sensitization. Central sensitization is known to be impaired or altered in chronic pain conditions, as fibromyalgia or chronic tension headache. Animal studies have shown reinstatement of mechanical hypersensitivity following naloxone administration after resolution of an injury. This suggests latent sensitization. In the present study, investigators hypothesize that a high-dose target-controlled naloxone infusion (total dose: 3.25 mg/kg) can reinstate pain and hyperalgesia 6-8 weeks after a unilateral primary open groin hernia repair procedure. Investigators aim to show that latent sensitization is present in humans and is modulated by endogenous opioids.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of High-dose Naloxone Infusion on Pain and Hyperalgesia in Patients Following Groin-Hernia Repair.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hernia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperalgesia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polystyrene sulfonic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Naloxone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years and ≤ 65 years Signed informed consent Patients submitted to unilateral, primary inguinal, open herniotomy 68 weeks prior to study start. Open operating procedure a.m. Lichtenstein. Urin sample without traces of opioids (morphine, methadon, buprenorphine, codeine, tramadol, ketobemidone, oxycodone, hydromorphine, dextromethorphan) ASA III Body mass index (BMI): 18 &lt; BMI &lt; 30 Volunteers , who do not speak or understand Danish Patients, who cannot cooperate with the investigation Patients who have had previous surgery in the groin region Patients with pain at rest &gt; 3 (NRS) Activityrelated pain in the surgical field &gt; 5 Allergic reaction against morphine or other opioids (including naloxone), Abuse of alcohol or drugs according to investigator's evaluation Use of psychotropic drugs (exception of SSRI) Neurologic or psychiatric disease Chronic pain condition Regular use of analgesic drugs Skin lesions and tattoos in the assessment areas Nerve lesions in the assessment sites (for instance, after trauma, disc herniation, etc.) Use of prescription drugs 1 week before the trial Use of overthecounter drugs 48 hours before the trial</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>central sensitization</keyword>
	<keyword>endogenous opioids</keyword>
	<keyword>humans</keyword>
	<keyword>latent sensitization</keyword>
	<keyword>naloxone</keyword>
	<keyword>open groin hernia repair</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>randomized controlled trial</keyword>
	<keyword>secondary hyperalgesia</keyword>
	<keyword>target-controlled infusion</keyword>
</DOC>