<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01992861</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial studies magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and positron emission tomography (PET) imaging in predictive treatment response in patients with stage IB-IVA cervical cancer. MRI is a procedure in which radio waves and a powerful magnet linked to a computer are used to create detailed pictures of areas inside the body. PET is a procedure in which a small amount of radioactive glucose (sugar) is injected into a vein, and a scanner is used to make detailed, computerized pictures of areas inside the body where the glucose is taken up. Comparing results of diagnostic procedures, such as MRI and PET, done before, during and after radiation and chemotherapy may help doctors predict a patient's response to treatment and help plan the best treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>MRI and PET Imaging in Predicting Treatment Response in Patients With Stage IB-IVA Cervical Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the value of MRI and PET as a non-invasive predictive assay for therapy outcome in cervical cancer. OUTLINE: Patients undergo radiation therapy and receive chemotherapy per standard of care. Patients undergo dynamic contrast-enhanced (DCE) MRI, diffusion-weighted (DW) MRI, and magnetic resonance (MR) spectroscopy at baseline, 2-2.5 weeks, 4-5 weeks, and 1 month following radiation therapy completion, and fludeoxyglucose F 18 (FDG) PET/computed tomography (CT) at baseline, 2-2.5 weeks, and 4-5 weeks. After completion of study, patients are followed up at least every 3-6 months for 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Adenosquamous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorodeoxyglucose F18</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have histologically confirmed stage IB2IVA epithelial carcinoma of the cervix, including squamous cell, adeno, and undifferentiated carcinoma, and excluding small cell/neuroendocrine carcinoma, who will undergo radiation therapy for cervical cancer with curative intent Surgical staging with retroperitoneal staging and lymphadenectomy is permitted Patients who will undergo standard radiation therapy with concurrent cisplatinbased chemotherapy for cervical cancer Patients with no prior radiation therapy to the pelvis Patients with no contraindications to magnetic resonance (MR) imaging Patients must have adequate renal function: glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &gt; 30 mL/min/1.73 m^2; for the testretest substudy MRI, patients must have a GFR of &gt; 60 mL/min/1.73m^2 Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document Patients with small cell/neuroendocrine cervical carcinoma Patients who have received any prior pelvic radiation therapy in the area of the tumor that precludes the delivery of a curative dose of pelvic radiation Medical contraindication to MR imaging (e.g. pacemakers, metallic implants, aneurysm clips, known contrast allergy to gadolinium contrast, pregnancy, nursing mothers, weight greater than 350 pounds, GFR &lt; 30) Major medical or psychiatric illness that, in the investigator's opinion, would prevent completion of treatment, completion of the study protocol, or interfere with followup Life expectancy of less than 6 months</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>