<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01280383</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Neurally adjusted ventilatory assist (NAVA) is a new concept of mechanical ventilation. NAVA delivers assistance to spontaneous breathing based on the detection of the electrical activity of the diaphragm. The investigators will study the effects of non-invasive NAVA on respiratory muscle unloading critically ill patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Non-invasive Neurally Adjusted Ventilatory Assist</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To assess the effects of non-invasive NAVA on respiratory muscle unloading in critically ill patients</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 85 years History of chronic obstructive lung disease Invasive mechanical ventilation for more than 12 hours Planned extubation according to the weaning protocol of our clinic Informed consent obtained from a next of kin Enrollment approval from a neutral physician neither participating in the study nor in the clinical treatment of the patient Tracheostomy Facial or cranial trauma or surgery Oral, esophageal, diaphragmatic or gastric trauma or surgery Contraindication to insertion of a nasogastric tube (e. g. malformation, esophageal varices, esophageal perforation or rupture, Zenkers diverticulum, severe bleeding disorder) Uncooperative state and combativeness not responding to low levels of sedatives Neurological disease possibly influencing the brainstem respiratory centre, such as but not limited to: intracerebral, subarachnoidal or subdural hemorrhage, cerebral infarction, possible hypoxic encephalopathy Next of kin refuses informed consent Pregnancy. In female patients between 18 and 60 years of age, a pregnancy test will be performed.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>non-invasive ventilation</keyword>
	<keyword>diaphragm</keyword>
	<keyword>electrical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>neurally adjusted ventilatory assist</keyword>
	<keyword>critically ill patients</keyword>
</DOC>