<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01280877</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Aim is to validate that non-invasive brain stimulation can increase cortical excitability in the visual system. The investigators assess if transcranial alternating current stimulation (tACS) can improve visual field size in patients with optic nerve damage. Hypothesis: tACS would improve visual functions within the defective visual field (primary outcome measure).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Paraorbital-Occipital Alternating Current Stimulation Therapy for Optic Neuropathy (MCT_optnerve)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In addition, the correlation between the brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) or other plasticity markers are correlated to the improvement of the visual field after stimulation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Optic Nerve Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Optic Nerve Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients with optic nerve lesion stable visual field defect with residual vision lesion age at least 6 months age at least 18 years no completely blindness, residual vision still existent electric or electronic implants, e.g. heart pacemaker any metal artefacts in head and truncus epilepsy autoimmune diseases in acute stage mental diseases, e.g. schizophrenia etc. unstable diabetes, diabetes causing diabetic retinopathy addiction high blood pressure (max. 160/100 mmHg) instable or high level of intraocular pressure (i.e. &gt; 27 mmHg) retinitis pigmentosa pathological nystagmus presence of an unoperated tumor anywhere in the body pregnant or breastfeeding women photo sensibility Fundus hypertonicus acute conjunctivitis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>optic neuropathy</keyword>
	<keyword>visual field</keyword>
	<keyword>electric stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>alternating current</keyword>
	<keyword>perimetry</keyword>
</DOC>