<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00132925</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purposes of this study are: - To demonstrate the efficacy of once daily administration of Nasacort AQ 110 µg compared with placebo in children 2-5 years of age with perennial allergic rhinitis; and - To assess the safety of Nasacort AQ 110 µg in children 2-5 years of age.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Efficacy and Safety Evaluation of Nasacort AQ in Children Ages 2-5 Years With Perennial Allergic Rhinitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic, Perennial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone hexacetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone Acetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone diacetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects will be male or female children ages 25 years with a history of at least 1 year of perennial allergic rhinitis (PAR) with or without seasonal allergic rhinitis (SAR) characterized by nasal stuffiness, nasal discharge, sneezing, nasal itching, and total eye symptoms, and verified by positive skin test or radioallergosorbent test (RAST) to perennial allergen that is present in the subject's environment (documented historical testing performed during the past year will be accepted). Subjects (assisted by a parent/guardian/care provider) must meet an aggregate symptom score of at least 18 (out of a possible 36) for nasal stuffiness, nasal discharge and sneezing for both the reflective (previous 24 hours) and instantaneous symptom scores recorded in the morning Subjects must not have clinically relevant disease other than allergic rhinitis or have clinically relevant deviations from normal on a physical examination. Subjects must not have been recently exposed to rhinitis medications prior to screening Subjects must have no history of hypersensitivity to glucocorticoids or to any excipients of the formulation Subjects undergoing cosyntropin stimulation test must have a morning (8 AM ± 1 hour) prestimulation serum cortisol level ≥ 5 µg/dL and 30 minutes poststimulation serum cortisol level ≥ 18 µg/dL at screening Subjects presenting with any of the following will not be included in the study: Asthma, requiring chronic use of inhaled or systemic corticosteroids in the previous 6 months; upper respiratory tract infection or sinus infection requiring antibiotic therapy within 2 weeks prior to screening or viral upper respiratory tract infection within 7 days of screening. Nasal polyps, deviated septum, or nasal/facial anatomic abnormalities that interfere with symptom evaluation and/or use of intranasal corticosteroids Treatment with more than 2 courses of systemic corticosteroids (each course not exceeding 14 days) within 1 year of screening Use of intranasal or ocular corticosteroids within 2 weeks of screening Use of oral, inhaled, or intravenous corticosteroids within 1 month of screening Use of intramuscular or intraarticular corticosteroids within 3 months of screening Use of high potency dermatological corticosteroids within 1 month of screening Use of oral leukotriene modifiers within 1 week of screening Use of nasal or oral antihistamines or oral or nasal decongestants within 3 days of screening Current or history of cataract or glaucoma Treatment with any investigational product or use of an investigational device within 1 month of screening Immunotherapy, with the exception of a stable maintenance schedule, for at least 1 month prior to screening History of hypersensitivity to glucocorticoids or to any excipients of the formulation Subject is the investigator or any subinvestigator, research assistant, pharmacist, study coordinator, or other staff or relative thereof directly involved in the conduct of the protocol. Any waiver of these inclusion and exclusion criteria must be approved by the investigator and the sponsor on a casebycase basis prior to enrolling the subject. This must be documented by both the sponsor and the investigator. No subject will be allowed to enroll in this study more than once.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>allergic rhinitis</keyword>
</DOC>