<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00733161</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the effect of passive exercise on systemic endothelial function in elderly patients with chronic heart failure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Passive Exercise on Systemic Endothelial Function in Elderly Patients With Chronic Heart Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Endothelial function is known to be impaired in patients with chronic heart failure (CHF) and impaired endothelial function has been reported to be associated with an increased mortality risk in those subjects. Although systemic exercise training has been demonstrated to improve endothelial dysfunction in patients with CHF, elderly patients with severely impaired exercise capacity could not engaged in usual exercise training using ordinal ergometer. Those patients are able to join stretching or very light resistance training. On the other hand, passive pedaling using strength ergometer has been reported to be useful in patients with severely impaired exercise capacity, but the safety and the efficacy of passive pedaling on endothelial function in old patients with CHF has not been previously reported.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of chronic heart failure Elderly patients aged ≧65 years Patients with severely reduced exercise capacity and cannot continue exercise with usual cycling ergometer for 5 minutes Unstable hemodynamic status (uncontrolled arrhythmia, uncontrolled congestion, uncontrolled hypertension) Active infectious disease Malignancy Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease Dialysis Severe aortic valve disease With any hip, knee, ankle joint pain Hemiplegia Current smoker</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>passive leg exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>congestive heart failure</keyword>
	<keyword>endothelium-derived factors</keyword>
	<keyword>elderly</keyword>
</DOC>