<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00733070</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A multicenter multinational study to evaluate the safety and efficacy of the CiTop™ ExPander™ Guidewire for crossing chronic total occlusion in Coronary arteries.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of the CiTop™ ExPander™ Guidewire for Crossing Chronic Total Occlusions in Coronary Arteries</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>1. Informed consent obtained prior to any trial activities. 2. Patients, male or female between 21 and 80 years of age, with no significant comorbidities (see exclusion criteria). 3. Patient has an angiographic documented Chronic Total Occlusion showing distal TIMI flow 0 to 1. 1. Patient unable to give informed consent. 2. Current participation in another study with any investigational drug or device. 3. Factors making followup and/or repeat angiography difficult or unlikely. 4. Contraindication to emergency artery by pass surgery. 5. Lack of surgical backup. 6. Contraindication to treatment with Aspirin, or Clopidogrel and/or Heparin. 7. Lesion &gt; 40mm in length (both calcified lesion and adjacent thrombus). 8. Treated vessel referenced diameter less than 2.5 mm. 9. Visualization of the distal lumen less than the Rentrop Classification Grade 2 collateralization. 10. Nonvisible entry point of target lesion. 11. Totally occluded bypass graft as target vessel. 12. Acute MI less than 1 week before procedure. 13. Patient has significant LV dysfunction, 35% LVEF or less. 14. Patient with cancer or other sever chronic disease with life expectance of 2 years. 15. Patient has chronic renal failure with serum creatinine ≥2. 16. Hemoglobin ≤11. 17. Patient is known or suspected not to tolerate the contrast agent. 18. Morbid Obesity (BMI &gt; 40). 19. Drug abuse or alcoholism. 20. Patients under custodial care. 21. Pregnant women or women with childbearing potential with a positive pregnancy test at the time of procedure.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>CTO</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Total Occlusion</keyword>
	<keyword>Revascularization</keyword>
</DOC>