<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02327533</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study, the investigators evaluated molecular biomarkers which play a role in the development of generalized aggressive periodontitis (GAgP) using gingival tissue samples through omics-based whole-genome transcriptomic while using healthy individuals as background controls.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gene Expression Profiles in Generalized Aggressive Periodontitis: A Gene Network-based Microarray Analysis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Aggressive periodontitis (AgP) is an inflammatory periodontal disease which is complex, multifactorial, and destructive. Progression and severity of the disease depend on interacting risk factors such as: immunological, microbiological, environmental, and genetic factors, as well as age, sex, and race.Some patients are genetically predisposed to AgP; they have immunological abnormalities, which are thought to be under genetic control. However, high susceptibility for periodontal destruction and the relationship between inflammatory changes, and genetic factors remain unclear. Gene expression profiling is a powerful means of generating comprehensive genome-level data sets on diseases such as cancer, asthma, rheumatoid disorders and periodontitis, and provides significant insight information for these diseases. Gene expression profiling may provide an evidence for involving genes in the pathogenesis of AgP and generate further information other than clinical signs and symptoms of AgP. The aim of this study was to identify gene-expression patterns of patients with generalized aggressive periodontitis by whole-transcriptome gene-expression analyses.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aggression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aggressive Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The periodontal diagnosis of subjects with GAgP was established on the basis of clinical and radiographic criteria and was defined by the 1999 International World Workshop for a Classification of Periodontal Diseases and Conditions.(Lang et al., 1999) Patients were included if they were between 18 and 35 years of age and otherwise healthy. The bone loss estimation was radiographically performed in each patient for the assessment of the extent and severity of alveolar bone loss. Subjects were excluded if they had any known systemic diseases or conditions that can/could influence the periodontal status (cancer, cardiovascular and respiratory diseases), any history of hepatitis and/or HIV infection, immunosuppressive chemotherapy, current pregnancy, planning a pregnancy or lactation, requirement for antibiotic prophylaxis, oral diseases other than GAgP, ongoing orthodontic therapy, a history of antibiotic therapy, or periodontal treatment within the preceding six months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>generalized aggressive periodontitis</keyword>
	<keyword>microarray analysis</keyword>
</DOC>