<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02743923</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether carboplatin-paclitaxel-bevacizumab results in a prolonged progression free survival compared to cisplatin-pemetrexed as first line treatment in patients with KRAS mutated non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cisplatin-Pemetrexed Compared With Carboplatin-Paclitaxel-Bevacizumab in KRAS Mutated Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>KRAS mutations occur in 30% of patients with non-small cell lung cancer, especially adenocarcinoma. For long time KRAS mutation has been related with poor prognosis and poor response to chemotherapy. Recent data however show that this is both not true. It seems that response, progression free survival and overall survival is similar in KRAS mutated. Until now no specific targeted therapy is available for KRAS mutated NSCLC patients. Optimization of treatment in advanced NSCLC patients with a KRAS mutation could also be achieved by selecting the best available chemotherapy treatment. Two standard chemotherapy schemes are frequently used and FDA and EMA approved as first line treatment for patients with adenocarcinoma: cisplatin-pemetrexed and carboplatin-paclitaxel-bevacizumab. The aim of this randomized phase III study is to compare two standard treatment regimens in patients with KRAS mutated, advanced stage NSCLC and the hypothesis is that bevacizumab with chemotherapy improves outcomes compared to chemotherapy alone as first line treatment. Furthermore the outcome for the different KRAS mutations will be studied. Treatment with one of the two following chemotherapy combinations according to the label: carboplatin-paclitaxel-bevacizumab or cisplatin-pemetrexed q3wks for up to six cycles. Continuation maintenance with bevacizumab and pemetrexed is allowed until progression. Blood and archival tissue will be optionally collected for translational research. This may help to identify subgroups of patients who are likely better treated with a specific treatment regimen.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Histologically or cytologically confirmed (nonsquamous) NSCLC incurable locally advanced or metastatic (stage IIIB and stage IV) disease. 2. Documented KRAS mutation 3. Chemotherapynaive NSCLC patients. Adjuvant chemotherapy or chemoradiotherapy is allowed when given &gt; 1 year for study entry. 4. At least one unidimensionally measurable lesion meeting RECIST1.1. 5. ECOG PS 02 6. Age ≥ 18 years 7. Adequate organ function, including: Adequate bone marrow reserve: ANC ≥ 1.5 x 109/L, platelets ≥ 100 x 109/L. Hepatic: bilirubin ≤1.5 x ULN, AP, ALT, AST ≤ 3.0 x ULN AP, ALT, and AST ≤5 xULN is acceptable if the liver has tumor involvement Renal: calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 60 ml/min based on the CockroftGault formula. Urine protein (dipstick) &lt; 2 +; when ≥ 2 +: 24 hours urine protein ≤ 1 gr. 8. Signed informed consent 9. Male and female patients with reproductive potential must use an approved contraceptive method, if appropriate. Female patients with childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test within 7 days prior to study enrollment. 1. Pregnant or lactating women 2. Clinically significant (i.e. active) cardiovascular disease: congestive heart failure &gt;NYHA class 2; CVA or myocardial infarction &lt; 6 months prior to study entry; uncontrolled hypertension (blood pressure systolic &gt; 150 mmHg and/or diastolic &gt; 100 mmHg) 3. History of hemoptysis ≥ grade 2 (bright red blood of at least 2,5 ml in the last 3 months) 4. Evidence of tumor invading major blood vessels on imaging (i.e. superior vena cava or pulmonary artery) 5. Patients with evidence or history of bleeding diathesis 6. Nonhealing wound or ulcer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>