<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02743338</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study includes two consecutive sub-trials. Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT) is treatment of choice for Insomnia. One of the most important treatment Components in CBT for insomnia (CBT-i) is Sleep Restriction (SR), but lately, adverse effects related to SR have been reported. A treatment method with similarities to SR is Sleep Compression (SC). SC is not as well studied as SR, but appears to have similar effects to SR but without the adverse effects. The first sub-trial thus aims at directly comparing SR and SC. The second sub-trial aims at evaluating any additional effects of CBT-i components given as an add-on treatment to a randomized selection of half participants in each original treatment arm.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CompRest - a Comparison Between Sleep Compression and Sleep Restriction for Treating Insomnia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical level of Insomnia (more than 10 on ISI) Meets criteria for Insomnia Disorder according to DSMV Sufficient language skills Having access to Internet to fill out forms and participating in treatment Not foresee obstacles to participating in treatment during the coming 20 weeks, or participating in measurements during the coming year. Sleep disorders requiring other treatment High consumption of alcohol/drugs that affect sleep Somatic or psychiatric conditions counterindicative of treatments given in the study, requiring acute care, or with symptoms and level of functioning affecting the ability to participate in the treatment programs. Working (night) shifts Ongoing psychological treatment for Insomnia with sleep restriction or sleep compression as a treatment component also previous such treatment can be excluding Use of sleep medication in such a way that may hinder the implementation of the methods in this treatment Pretreatment measurements not finished within the given timeframe.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sleep Restriction</keyword>
	<keyword>Sleep Compression</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>