<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02743065</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this multicenter registry is to gather the safety, efficacy and survival data in advanced HCC patients treated with HepaSphere in China in order to evaluate the application of HepaSphere deTACE in treating advanced HCC patients</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>HepaSphere Chemoembolization in Advanced HCC Patients: Safety &amp; Efficacy Registry in China</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 18 or older 2. Patient has signed informed consent 3. Patient must have a diagnosis of hepatocellular cancer by at least one of the following method: 1. Histological confirmation 2. Classic imaging characteristics of HCC: Early enhancement (Arterial hypervascularity) and Venous or Delayed phase washout in multidetector contrast enhanced computed tomography (CT) scan / dynamic contrastenhanced magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) imaging. Either CT/ MRI shows at least one solid liver lesion ≥ 2 cm with the above described imaging characteristics of HCC. In case of liver lesion between 1 and 2 cm, both CT and MRI imaging have to be performed in order to confirm the imaging characteristics of HCC. 4. At time of study entry. 1. Patients not suitable for ablation due to lesion location may be enrolled 2. Patients with HCC recurrence but not suitable for resection or ablation maybe enrolled 5. Patient MUST be with BCLC stage C and meet the following criteria: Stage ChildPugh A or B AND Performance status ECOG ≤ 2 WITH Vascular Invasion or WITHOUT Vascular invasion 6. Patient has a life expectancy of at least 6 months 1. Current or previous treatment with chemo or radiation therapy or sorafenib 2. Previous treatment of transarterial chemoembolization (TACE) 3. Patients with current or history of any other cancer except nonmelanomatous skin cancer 4. Female patients who are pregnant, breastfeeding, or premenopausal and not using an effective method of contraceptive 5. Performance status ECOG &gt; 2 6. ChildPugh Class C 7. Occlusive tumor thrombus to the main portal trunk 8. Active gastrointestinal bleeding 9. Evidence of uncorrectable bleeding diathesis 10. ExtraHepatic spread of the HCC 11. &gt;50% tumor involvement of the liver 12. Infiltrative HCC 13. Encephalopathy not adequately controlled medically 14. Presence of ascites not controlled medically 15. Any contraindication for MRI/ CT (eg. metallic implants) 16. Allergy to contrast media that cannot be managed with prophylaxis 17. Any contraindication to arteriography 18. Any contraindication for doxorubicin administration</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HepaSphere</keyword>
</DOC>