<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01635491</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to describe gastrointestinal motility and transit times in healthy subjects by using Motilis 3D-Transit and to compare the total gastrointestinal transit time (GITT) to GITT obtained using radioopaque markers. The investigators end points are to measure the transit times through different segments of the gastrointestinal canal,e.g. gastric emptying, small intestine, total GITT. The study is descriptive and is designed to test and evaluate the usefulness of the Motilis 3D-Transit system. The investigators hypothesize, that with the system transit times through different segments of the gastrointestinal canal can be measured. The design is made for evaluating the transit times, the inter-subject reproducibility and comparison with gold standard for colonic transit time measurement. The investigators have chosen to include 20 healthy volunteers.The study is descriptive and therefore power calculation is not needed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gastrointestinal Transit Times and Motility in Healthy Volunteers Obtained by Motilis-3D-transit</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Healthy Volunteer Signed informed consent obtained Fasted since midnight Subject has known GI related symptoms complaints or GI diseases, including swallowing disorders Subject has cancer or other life threatening diseases or conditions Subject is pregnant Subject has undergone abdominal surgery Subject has abdominal diameter &gt;140cm? Drug abuse or alcoholism Subject's bowel movements are irregular Subject has known cardiovascular or pulmonary diseases Participation in any clinical study within the last 30 days Subject has cardiac pacemaker or infusion pump or any other implanted or portable electromechanical medical device. Subject takes any medication affecting GI motility Subject having MRI within the next four weeks</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gastrointestinal Motility</keyword>
	<keyword>Transit time</keyword>
</DOC>