<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01635933</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to evaluate the overall comfort of AIR OPTIX® COLORS compared to FRESHLOOK® COLORBLENDS in habitual wearers of the FRESHLOOK® COLORBLENDS .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Comparison of AIR OPTIX® COLORS Versus FRESHLOOK® COLORBLENDS</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Myopia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Able and willing to sign the Informed Consent document. If under legal age of consent, legally authorized representative must sign also Informed Consent document. Able to achieve visual acuity of at least 20/30 (Snellen) in each eye at distance with contact lenses and best corrected visual acuity (BCVA) ≥ 20/25 in each eye. Manifest cylinder less than or equal to 0.75 diopters (within the previous year) in each eye. Successful wear of FRESHLOOK® COLORBLENDS spherical soft contact lenses in both eyes (in the protocolspecified colors) during the past three months for a minimum of 5 days per week and 8 hours per day. History of at least 5 days of successful use with both lenses (minimum of 8 hours/day) of one of the protocolspecified lens care solutions/multipurpose solutions (MPS). Other protocolspecified inclusion criteria may apply. Any ocular or systemic medical condition that may, in the opinion of the investigator, preclude safe administration of the test articles or affect the results of this study. Wears habitual lenses in an extended wear modality (sleeping in lenses overnight / not removing lenses on a daily basis). Monovision, monocular (only one eye with functional vision) or fit with only one lens. History of intolerance or hypersensitivity to any component of the test articles. Use of any overthecounter or prescribed topical ocular medications within the previous 7 days (excluding rewetting drops). Moderate or severe corneal edema, corneal vascularization, corneal staining, injection, tarsal abnormalities, "other" complications; and any corneal infiltrates. Current or history of ocular infection, severe inflammation, or disease within previous 6 months. Any systemic disease (including allergies, respiratory infections or colds) that may affect the eye or be exacerbated by use of contact lenses or contact lens solutions. Participation in any investigational clinical study within previous 30 days. Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>contact lenses</keyword>
	<keyword>color contact lenses</keyword>
	<keyword>myopia</keyword>
</DOC>