<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01635036</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate that the Eeva™ System is compatible with the Eeva 12-well Dish.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Eeva 12-well Dish Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is designed to demonstrate that the Eeva System Software successfully tracks the embryo images and identifies the timing of key developmental events using the Eeva 12-well Dish. This is a prospective, observational, blinded, single arm, nonrandomized, single center clinical study. Images of developing embryos and Eeva predictions will be blinded to embryologists and physicians</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women undergoing fresh in vitro fertilization treatment using their own eggs or donor eggs. Subject is at least 18 years of age. Subject has basal antral follicle count (BAFC) ≥ 12 prior to stimulation cycle. Subjects has basal FSH &lt; 11 IU Fertilization using only ejaculated sperm (fresh or frozen) no surgically removed sperm. Subject has at least 8 normally fertilized eggs (2PN) Willing to have all 2PN embryos monitored by Eeva Willing to comply with study protocol and procedures and able to speak English. Willing to provide written informed consent. Reinseminated eggs. History of cancer. Gestational carriers. Planned preimplantation genetic diagnosis or preimplantation genetic screening. Previously enrolled in this study Concurrent participation in another clinical study. Any other reason the Investigator believes the subject should not participate in the clinical study.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>in vitro fertilization</keyword>
	<keyword>assisted reproduction techniques</keyword>
	<keyword>noninvasive imaging of embryos</keyword>
	<keyword>time lapse imaging of embryos</keyword>
	<keyword>traditional morphological grading of embryos</keyword>
	<keyword>prediction of blastocyst formation</keyword>
	<keyword>infertility</keyword>
	<keyword>male factor female factor</keyword>
	<keyword>embryo viability</keyword>
</DOC>