<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02895191</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Compared with placebo, evaluate the effects and safety of Ulinastatin added to conventional treatment for ARDS; Evaluate the dose response relationship of Ulinastatin for ARDS.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Safety and Dose Response Relationship of Ulinastatin for Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome(ARDS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After signed off the informed consent form by patient or surrogate, and after completing the screening phase, the patients who fulfill the inclusion and exclusion criteria will be randomized 1:1:1:1 to the 4 study arms. All the Patients will receive the study treatment drugs for 7 to 14 days. Use Day 28 of last patient as a cut-off day, Collect the follow up visit data on both Day 28 and Day 90 of other patients．</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinastatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trypsin Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Have provided signed written informed consent form (ICF) from the patient or the patient's legal representative; 2. Male or Female patients ≥18 years of age; 3. ARDS defined with using 2012 Berlin Criteria; 4. ARDS diagnosed ≤72 hours, and patients should be mechanically ventilated (invasive and or noninvasive mechanical ventilation); 5)100mmhg &lt; PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 250mmhg with CPAP/PEEP≥5 cmH2O. 1. Patient with known hypersensitivity to Ulinastatin/adjuvant or patient with allergic constitution; 2. Presence or 2 or more extrapulmonary failing organs failure according to SOFA； 3. Cardiogenic pulmonary edema , and the cardiogenic pulmonary edema is as the only or primary reason for respiratory failure； 4. Patients with severe fungal infection and or septic shock; 5. ARDS caused by burning, drowning, poisoning; 6. Presence of severe chronic liver diseases (ChildPugh score 1215)，or severe chronic respiratory disease with a PaCO2 &gt; 50 mmHg or the use of home oxygen;</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>