<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02895048</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The effects of Cardiac Contractility Modulation (CCM) treatment are observed in patients with heart failure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of CCM-therapy in Patients With Heart Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The OPTIMIZER III System is indicated for use in patients greater than 18 years of age with symptomatic heart failure due to left ventricular systolic dysfunction despite appropriate medical therapy. The study will gather additional data on the effect of CCM treatment with the objective of determining the impact of CCM on the composite of heart failure hospitalizations and mortality in the low ejection fraction (EF &lt; 35%) and mildly reduced ejection fraction (35 ≤ EF ≤ 45) heart failure population. The study will also assess the impact of CCM on exercise tolerance (six minute hall walk test, 6 Minute Walk Test) and quality of life (Minnesota Living With Heart Failure Questionnaire, MLWHFQ) in these same populations.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria (treatment group): Any subject who receives an OPTIMIZER system implant and provides informed consent Exclusion Criteria (treatment group): Inclusion Criteria (control group): Symptomatic heart failure (NYHA Class 2, 3 or 4) despite receiving optimal medical therapy with doses of medications that are stable (no more than 50 % variation) for at least 7 days. EF ≤ 45% Signed informed consent Exclusion Criteria (control group): Heart failure due to a potentially correctible cause ( e. g. valvular disease, congenital disease) Idiopathic hypertrophic cardiomyopathy, restrictive or constrictive cardiomyopathy, or heart failure on the basis of a known inflammatory or infiltrative disease (e. g. amyloidosis, sarcoidosis) or constrictive disease Active ischemia or exercise tolerance limited by angina Hospitalizations for heart failure which required the use of inotropic support within 14 days of enrollment Chronic (permanent or persistent) atrial fibrillation or atrial flutter Scheduled for a CABG or a PCI procedure, or has undergone a CABG procedure within 90 days or a PCI procedure within 30 days of enrollment Myocardial infarction within 90 days of enrollment Hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis Prior heart transplant Participating in another study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>