<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02895841</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to learn more about the ways in which mobile technology can be integrated into inpatient care to help better track pain levels using mobile technology of patients with sickle cell disease, oncology patients, and bone marrow transplant patients. The study will assess whether or not daily mobile monitoring with wearable accelerometers (devices that detect movement as well as heart-rate) to monitor and manage medical treatments can have a lasting positive impact on outcomes in patients with chronic diseases. The investigator hopes to learn more about the ways in which mobile technology can be integrated into inpatient care. Specifically, the investigator is looking to help patients better track their pain, use wearable technology to track physiological measures (for example, heart rate, sleep quantity and quality), and integrate these data points into the medical care of patients by providing the information to providers. This study will first gather information regarding the feasibility and acceptability of the use of technology on the inpatient unit. This will help the study team to refine the technology of the mobile app and logistics of integration. Following this, the investigator will complete a second phase of the study, during which select patients will pilot the intervention. This will be followed by the third and final phase, during which patients will be randomly assigned to the active intervention or standard of care. This phase approach will enable the study team to refine the intervention, relying on the feedback from patients and providers, and subsequently test its utility compared to standard of care through random assignment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Patient-Empowered Mobile Technology in Hospitalized Patients (TRU-PAIN)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigator hopes to learn more about the ways in which mobile technology can be integrated into inpatient care. Specifically, the investigator is looking to help patients better track their pain, use wearable technology to track physiological measures (for example, heart rate, sleep quantity and quality), and integrate these data points into the medical care of patients by providing the information to providers. This study will first gather information regarding the feasibility and acceptability of the use of technology on the inpatient unit. This will help the study team to refine the technology of the mobile app and logistics of integration. Following this, the investigator will complete a second phase of the study, during which select patients will pilot the intervention. This will be followed by the third and final phase, during which patients will be randomly assigned to the active intervention or standard of care. This phase approach will enable the study team to refine the intervention, relying on the feedback from patients and providers, and subsequently test its utility compared to standard of care through random assignment.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Any patient 880 years old with a past medical history for a chronic disease (such as sickle cell disease), cancer (solid tumor, lymphoma, brain tumor), or currently undergoing bone marrow transplant Currently admitted to the hospital Have a current diagnosis which includes pain for which they are being treated Must be enrolled within 48 hours of admission Due to the possibility of a choking hazard, only patients who are at least 8 years of age will be enrolled in the study Patients in the Intensive Care Units will not be eligible Must be able to understand and operate the mobile device independently; therefore the investigators will exclude those the provider team considers unable to do so</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>oncology</keyword>
	<keyword>bone marrow transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>sickle cell disease</keyword>
</DOC>