<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02895334</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will conduct an initial clinical evaluation of this support program to examine its impact on reducing caregiver stress, increasing confidence in daily feeding, and improving weight-for-age growth percentiles in infants with Congenital Heart Disease (CHD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>MyHeartBaby: An Initial Evaluation of the MyHeartBaby Psychosocial Telemedicine Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Caregivers of infants with CHD are at high-risk of anxiety and distress due to the complex daily caregiving demands. Previous research has demonstrated decreased parental stress and more optimal infant developmental outcomes with a psychosocial intervention delivered to caregivers of infants with CHD prior to hospital discharge as well as reduced healthcare use in caregivers who received medical video-consultations during the interstage surgical palliation period. This study will implement a telemedicine intervention program (MyHeartBaby) to support caregivers remotely in the daily care and adjustment to having an infant with chronic medical needs. The program is delivered via video chat over the Internet and caregivers will complete questionnaires about general family information, stress, and feeding their infant.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Defects, Congenital</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Caregiver's infant is less than 45 days of age at time of study enrollment. Caregiver of infant with highrisk, shunt dependent physiology (one or twoventricle circulation) having just received neonatal surgery for CHD. English is a primary language for caregiver of infant. Caregiver's infant is greater than 45 days of age at time of study enrollment. Not a caregiver of infant with highrisk, shunt dependent physiology having just received neonatal surgery for CHD. English is not a primary language for caregiver of infant.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>CHD</keyword>
	<keyword>Congenital Heart Disease</keyword>
</DOC>