<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02895607</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Care in ambulatory surgery (CA) is growing in France, despite lagging behind other countries in North or US Europe. Arthroscopic knee surgery is a minimally invasive surgery eligible for CA. Currently 71.8% of knee arthroscopy are made in this context. However ligamentoplasties anterior cruciate are still carried out predominantly in conventional hospitalization (HC) with a median of 3 to 5.5 days of stay. Two recent prospective studies French single-operator shows the feasibility of reconstruction of the anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) in ambulatory: no serious events were recorded, the risks are comparable to those of a HC. However, this support requires a structure and a coordinated network between different medical and paramedical (surgeons, anesthetists, nurse frame, City nurse, doctor, physiotherapist). The objective of the study is to evaluate (i.e. EPP or "feasibility") ACL reconstruction in CA in hospitals, multi-operator.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Outpatient Surgery in the Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstructions With Hamstring Hospital</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>II. objectives at. primary objective Rating (or "feasibility") of a management protocol HDJ of ACL reconstruction in a hospital structure on a multi-operator series. Evaluation criteria (absence of EG)? b. secondary objectives i. Evaluation of the acceptance rates of ambulatory care patients eligible ii. Evaluation of the rate and type of complication in our series iii. Evaluation of early postoperative results (postoperative pain, analgesic consumption, sleep, satisfaction) IV. Methodology and duration of the research This is a consecutive series single-center multi-operator prospective regarding the evaluation of surgical practice cited in goal. The inclusion of patients will take place over a period of 4 months. The management of ACL reconstruction in outpatient will be proposed in consultation with the surgeon. After an explanation of the course of treatment a fact sheet on the protocol will be provided to the patient and his doctor to the patient to decide its support AC or HC. Clinical data will be collected by telephone the first 4 days and in consultation with J45. The revision sheet is provided. Patients are aware of the use of their data for medical research through oral information provided by the doctor at the signing by the patient's consent related to the surgery. The data collected as part of the research are anonymous and unidentifiable (for each subject is assigned a number); the name of the surgeon is also anonymized.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Isolated ACL tear DIDT first arthroscopic reconstruction in Age over 60 years ASA score greater than 2 Geographical remoteness Social isolation medical condition requiring supervision by HC (phlebitis history, coagulation disorders ...) psychiatric pathology</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>