<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02401542</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1b/2, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter, parallel-group study of B-701 plus docetaxel versus placebo plus docetaxel in the treatment of locally advanced or metastatic urothelial cell carcinoma in subjects who have relapsed after, or are refractory to standard therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 1b/2 Study of B-701 in Treatment of Locally Advanced or Metastatic Urothelial Cell Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 1b/2, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter, parallel-group, efficacy and safety study of B-701 plus docetaxel versus placebo plus docetaxel in the treatment of subjects with Stage IV, locally advanced or metastatic UCC who have relapsed after, or are refractory to at least one prior line of chemotherapy. This study is divided into 2 phases: Lead-In Phase and Randomized Phase; and the Lead-In Phase is divided into 3 cohorts. In Cohorts 1 and 2, all subjects will receive both B-701 plus docetaxel. In Cohort 3, all subjects will receive B-701 only.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urologic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Provide tumor tissue obtained within 18 months of enrollment of suitable quality and quantity and to demonstrate FGFR3 positive tumor by IHC. For subjects participating in the Randomized Phase only, if suitable archival tissue is unavailable, then a core biopsy of tumor tissue (metastatic or primary) must be obtained prior to randomization Stage IV, locally advanced or metastatic urothelial bladder cancer or transitional cell carcinoma arising in another location of the urinary tract, including urethra, ureter, and renal pelvis Relapsed after or are refractory to one or two prior lines of chemotherapy which have not included a taxane platinum agent, as long as a platinum agent is not contraindicated for the subject (i.e., if a platinum agent is contraindicated for a subject, the one or two prior regimen need not have included a platinum agent) Measurable disease according to RECIST v1.1 criteria ≥ 18 years old ECOG 0 or 1 Main Prior anticancer therapy within 4 weeks prior to Cycle 1, Day 1 Weight &gt; 100kg Clinically significant comorbid medical conditions or lab abnormalities</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Urothelial Cell Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>UCC</keyword>
	<keyword>bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>B-701</keyword>
	<keyword>FGFR3</keyword>
	<keyword>invasive bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>targeted therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Transitional Cell Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>TCC</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase 2</keyword>
	<keyword>second line therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>monoclonal antibody</keyword>
	<keyword>docetaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>combination therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase 1</keyword>
</DOC>