<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02401633</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Out-of-hospital cardiac arrest (OHCA) is one of the leading causes of mortality in the industrialized world. Bystander CPR before arrival of the Emergency Medical Service (EMS) is a positive predictor of survival. During the last decade, the best form of bystander CPR has been debated. Chest Compression Only CPR (CO-CPR) has been advocated as a preferable method in situations where the bystander has no previous knowledge in CPR, both because its believed to be equally efficient but also a simplified form of CPR that could lead to a higher incidence of bystander-CPR. The purpose of this study is to perform av run-in period with focus on safety and feasibility prior to the launch of a larger randomized trial which has a primary end-point of survival. This study will compare OHCA with standard CPR (S-CPR; chest compressions and rescue breaths in a 30:2 fashion) compared to CO-CPR.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Compression Only-CPR Versus Standard-CPR - the Run-in Phase</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Witnessed cases of OHCA with a non-asphyctic aetiology will be the principal study population. According to current guidelines an unresponsive patient with no or agonal breathing is treated as a suspected case of OHCA at the dispatch centre. These cases are eligible for screening for inclusion. If the case is witnessed, the bystander has previous knowledge in CPR and no exclusion criteria are present, the case can be included in the study. If included, it will be randomly assigned to either CO-CPR (intervention) or S-CPR (control). The intervention consists of instructions from a dispatcher at the dispatch centre to bystanders and first responders to perform either CO-CPR (intervention) or S-CPR (control). Instructions to bystanders on how to perform CO-CPR emphasizes continuous chest compressions without interruptions or rescue breaths. The instructions on how to perform S-CPR in the control group include information on giving chest compressions and rescue breaths in a 30:2 ratio (like current CPR recommendation state). Please se Appendix a) for detailed instructions to both groups. If first responders equipped with an automated external defibrillator arrive prior to EMS they will carry on with CPR in accordance with initial allocation. The intervention continues until arrival of the EMS at the patient's side.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Out-of-Hospital Cardiac Arrest</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Unconsciousness with no, abnormal or agonal breathing (suspected OHCA) The suspected OHCA is witnessed (seen or heard) Bystander has previous training in CPR Age 18 or younger Collapse is not witnessed Bystander has never been trained in CPR (these bystanders should be instructed to administer COCPR in accordance to guidelines). Obvious asphyxia, i.e. drowning, strangulation, hanging Obvious intoxication or drug overdose Pregnancy Obvious pregnancy Trauma Bystander is unwilling to participate or to perform CPR</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cardio-Pulmonary-Resuscitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Advanced Cardiac Life Support</keyword>
	<keyword>Compression-Only CPR</keyword>
	<keyword>Chest compression CPR</keyword>
</DOC>