<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00992186</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the safety and effectiveness of the study drug carlumab in participants with metastatic castrate-resistant prostate cancer (cancer of the gland that makes fluid that aids movement of sperm).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of the Safety and Efficacy of Single-agent Carlumab (an Anti-Chemokine Ligand 2 [CCL2]) in Participants With Metastatic Castrate-Resistant Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label (all people know the identity of the intervention), multicenter trial (conducted in more than one center) in participants with metastatic castrate-resistant prostate cancer. The trial consists of 3 phases: screening period, treatment period of approximately 4 months, and a follow-up period (Week 1, 4, 8 and 12 after the last dose) of up to 12 weeks after the administration of last dose. The participants will receive carlumab at the dose of 15 milligram/kilogram (mg/kg) by intravenous (into a vein) infusion (a fluid or a medicine delivered into a vein by way of a needle) at a constant rate over a 90 minute period once every 2 weeks until disease progression. Efficacy of the participants will be primarily evaluated by composite response. Participants' safety will be monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histological documentation of adenocarcinoma of the prostate Received at least 1 but no more than 2 prior docetaxelbased chemotherapy regimens and had disease progression following the last therapy Serum prostate specific antigen (PSA) greater than or equal to 5.0 nanogram/milliliter (ng/ml) within 4 weeks prior to the first dose of study agent Orchiectomy (surgery to remove one or both testicles) or testosterone less than 50 nanogram/deciliter by means of pharmacological/chemical castration within 4 weeks prior to the first dose of study agent At least 6 weeks from prior docetaxel chemotherapy regimen to first dose of study agent Experience a hormonal treatment withdrawal response (including a lowering of PSA that was previously rising or symptomatic improvement) Known or symptomatic Central Nervous System metastases Residual toxicities resulting from previous therapy that are Grade 2 or more (except for alopecia) Known allergies, hypersensitivity, or intolerance to carlumab or its excipients or clinically significant reactions to chimeric or human proteins Vaccinated with live, attenuated vaccines within 4 weeks prior to the first dose of study agent</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Infusion</keyword>
	<keyword>Carlumab</keyword>
	<keyword>CNTO 888</keyword>
</DOC>