<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02991898</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a single center pilot study of a non-myeloablative umbilical cord blood transplant for the treatment of a hematological malignancy with a single infusion of T regulatory (Treg) given shortly after umbilical cord blood transplantation and supported with ultra-low dose (ULD) IL-2 for 4 weeks. The goal of the study is to demonstrate the feasibility and safety of giving ULD IL-2 to support in vivo Treg survival and help with the design of future larger scale studies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treg Cell With IL-2 to Suppress aGVHD Umbilical Cord Blood Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Disease Criteria: Acute Leukemias: Must be in remission by morphology (≤5% blasts). . Also a small percentage of blasts that is equivocal between marrow regeneration versus early relapse are acceptable provided there are no associated cytogenetic markers consistent with relapse. Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia (ALL) second or greater CR; CR1 unable to tolerate consolidation chemotherapy due to chemotherapyrelated toxicities; CR1 highrisk ALL. High risk ALL is defined as having one of the following: Evidence of high risk cytogenetics such as t(9;22), t(1;19), t(4;11), other MLL rearrangements, IKZF1 30 years of age or older at diagnosis White blood cell counts of greater than 30,000/mcL (BALL) or greater than 100,000/mcL (TALL) at diagnosis CNS leukemia involvement during the course of disease Slow cytologic response (&gt;10% lymphoblasts in bone marrow on Day 14 of induction therapy) Evidence of persistent immonophenotypic or molecular minimal residual disease (MRD) at the end of induction and consolidation therapy Acute Myelogenous Leukemia (AML) and related precursor neoplasms: 2nd or greater complete remission (CR); first complete remission (CR1) in patients &gt; 60 years old; CR1 in ≤ 60 years old that is NOT considered as favorablerisk. Favorable risk is defined as having one of the following: t(8,21) without cKIT mutation inv(16) or t(16;16) without cKIT mutation Normal karyotype with mutated NPM1 and wild type FLTITD Normal karyotype with double mutated CEBPA Acute prolymphocytic leukemia (APL) in first molecular remission at end of consolidation Biphenotypic/Undifferentiated/Prolymphocytic Leukemias in first or subsequent CR, adult Tcell leukemia/lymphoma in first or subsequent CR Burkitt's Lymphoma in CR2 or subsequent CR Natural Killer Cell Malignancies Chronic Myelogenous Leukemia: all types except refractory blast crisis. Chronic phase patients must have failed at least two different tyrosinekinase inhibitors (TKIs), or been intolerant to all available TKIs or have T315I mutation. Myelodysplastic Syndrome: IPSS INT2 or High Risk; RIPSS High or Very High; WHO classification: RAEB1, RAEB2; Severe Cytopenias: ANC &lt; 0.8, Anemia or thrombocytopenia requiring transfusion; Poor or very poor risk cytogenetics based on IPSS or RIPSS definitions; therapyrelated MDS. Blasts must be &lt; 5% by bone marrow aspirate morphology. If ≥5% blasts, patient requires chemotherapy for cytoreduction to &lt;5% blasts prior to transplantation. LargeCell Lymphoma, Hodgkin Lymphoma and Multiple Myeloma with chemotherapy sensitive disease that has failed or patients who are ineligible for an autologous transplant. Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia/Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma (CLL/SLL), Marginal Zone BCell Lymphoma, Follicular Lymphoma, which have progressed within 12 months of achieving a partial or complete remission. Patients who had remissions lasting &gt; 12 months are eligible after at least two prior therapies. Patients with bulky disease should be considered for debulking chemotherapy before transplant. Patients with refractory disease are eligible, unless has bulky disease and an estimated tumor doubling time of less than one month. Lymphoplasmacytic Lymphoma, MantleCell Lymphoma, Prolymphocytic Leukemia are eligible after initial therapy if chemotherapy sensitive. Patients must have undergone an autologous transplant ≤ 12 months prior to transplant on this study or have received multiagent or immunosuppressive chemotherapy within 3 months of the preparative regimen. Must be ≥18, but &lt; 70 years of age with no available medically suitable 7/8 or 8/8 HLA matched sibling donor, considering HLA A, B, C and DRB1 patients ≥ 70 and ≤ 75 years of age may be eligible if they have a CoMorbidity score ≤ 2 . (http://www.qxmd.com/calculateonline/hematology/hctci) UCB unit(s) composing the graft will be selected according to the current University of Minnesota umbilical cord blood graft selection algorithm a 3rd cord blood unit to be used as the source to manufacture the Treg product. This UCB unit must be matched at 46/6 to the patient, considering HLAA, B at the antigen level and DRB1 at the allele level. Karnofsky performance status of ≥ 70% Adequate organ function defined as: Renal: creatinine ≤ 2.0 mg/dL, if &gt; 1.2 mg/dL must have eGFR of ≥ 40 Hepatic: bilirubin, AST/ALT, ALP ≤ 5 x upper limit of normal, Pulmonary function: DLCO, FEV1, FVC ≥ 40% predicted, and absence of O^2 requirements Cardiac: Absence of decompensated congestive heart failure, or uncontrolled arrhythmia and left ventricular ejection fraction ≥ 40%. Sexually active females of childbearing potential and males with partners of childbearing potential must agree Voluntary written informed consent signed Untreated active infection History of HIV infection Pregnant or breast feeding. The agents used in this study may be teratogenic to a fetus and there is no information on the excretion of agentsinto breast milk. Females of childbearing potential must have a blood test or urine study within 14 days prior to registration to rule out pregnancy Prior allogeneic transplantation Less than 3 months from myeloablative conditioning for autologous transplantation (if applicable) Evidence of progressive disease by imaging modalities or biopsy persistent PET activity, though possibly related to lymphoma, is not an exclusion criterion in the absence of CT changes indicating progression. CML in blast crisis Large cell lymphoma, mantle cell lymphoma and Hodgkin disease that is progressing on salvage therapy. Active central nervous system malignancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute Leukemias</keyword>
	<keyword>Burkitt's Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Natural Killer Cell Malignancies</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Myelogenous Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Myelodysplastic Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Large-Cell Lymphoma, Hodgkin Lymphoma, and Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia/Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma, Marginal Zone B-Cell Lymphoma, Follicular Lymphoma:</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphoplasmacytic Lymphoma, Mantle-Cell Lymphoma Prolymphocytic Leukemia</keyword>
</DOC>