<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02991352</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Treatment of vascular malformations requires the placement of a needle within anatomically non well defined, pathological vessels, which may be as small as 1 mm, with the current state of the art relying exclusively on two dimensional fluoroscopy images for guidance. The investigators hypothesize that the combination of stereotactic image guidance with existing targeting methods will result in faster and more reproducible needle placements.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Stereotactic MRI Based Image Guidance for the Treatment of Vascular Malformations - a Pilot Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This prospective study aims to investigate the feasibility of the utilization of stereotactic image guidance technology for the needle based percutaneous treatment of peripheral vascular malformations. The specific device to be utilized is the CAS-One IR system, CE marked for use with needle based procedures in combination with medical image data including MRI data, as required by this study. Utilizing feedback from the stereotactic image guidance system, the interventionalist will attempt to place the needle within the malformation. The position and orientation of the needle relative to the anatomy will be displayed on 2D slices from the MRI, as well as relative to a 3D volume rendering of the patient anatomy constructed from MRI data. The position of the needle relative to the desired position within the malformation will be evaluated utilizing fluoroscopy. If necessary the position of the needle will be adjusted, this adjustment can be performed utilizing navigated feedback or standard fluoroscopy feedback at the discretion of the physician. The final position of the needle will be confirmed on intra-operative DSA imaging and the sclerosant will be applied according to standard clinical protocols. This single-centre pilot study will involve a total of 10 patients suffering from peripheral vascular malformations. Only non-emergency adult patients will be considered for inclusion in this trial. Inclusion will be at the discretion of the treating physician and patient. As the study is designed as a pilot trial, no comparator is considered and no blinding performed. The trial will be performed over a period of nine months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Congenital Abnormalities</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Malformations</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with venous or mixed venouslymphatic malformation Patients which are regular scheduled for a percutaneous treatment of a vascular malformation Informed Consent as documented by signature Age &lt; 18 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vascular Malformations</keyword>
	<keyword>Image Guidance</keyword>
</DOC>