<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02286518</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of TAK-114 following single and multiple ascending oral doses in healthy Japanese male participants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TAK-114 Single- and Multiple-Dose Phase 1 Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase 1, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, single and multiple oral dose study in healthy Caucasian and Japanese male participants. The study is composed of three parts, Single-dose Ascending Part, Food Effect Part and Multiple-dose Ascending Part. Single-dose Ascending Part and Multiple-dose Ascending Part are designed as a randomized, double-blind or open-label, placebo-controlled, sequential-cohort, ascending single or multiple oral dose study of TAK-114 or matched placebo. The Food Effect Part is designed as a randomized, open-label, 2-period crossover study of a single dose of TAK-114.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Healthy Japanese participants: Must be willing to provide written informed consent and in the investigator's opinion able to comply with the study protocol. Is aged 20 to 45 years, inclusive. Weighs at least 50 kilogram (kg) and have a body mass index (BMI) between 18.5 and 25.0 kilogram per square meter (kg/m^2). Healthy Caucasian participants: Must be willing to provide written informed consent and in the investigator's opinion able to comply with the study protocol. Is aged 20 to 45 years, inclusive; are of Caucasian descent (born to Caucasian parents and grandparents and has lived outside original country for less than 5 years) and maintains their original diet and lifestyle. Weighs at least 50 kg and have a body mass index between 18.5 and 30.0 kg/m2. • Participants have a known hypersensitivity to any component of the formulation of TAK114 or any herb medicine or supplement related to Indigo naturalis.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>