<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02558829</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Macimorelin-GHST (growth hormone stimulation test) will be compared with the ITT (insulin tolerance test) in an open-label, randomized, 2-way crossover Trial. The trial will include subjects suspected to have adult growth hormone deficiency (AGHD) and a group of healthy control subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Validation of Macimorelin as a Test for Adult Growth Hormone Deficiency</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Trial subjects will be assigned to groups of descending likelihood of having AGHD: Group A, B, C: High, intermediate, and low likelihood of GHD, respectively; Group D: Healthy control subjects matching Group A subjects . The sequential order of the GHSTs for suspected AGHD subjects (Group A-C) will be determined by stratified randomization; healthy control subjects (Group D) will be tested in the same sequence as the matched Group A subjects. Serum concentrations of GH will be measured at pre-defined time points before and after GHST with macimorelin or insulin. A peak GH value below the GHST-specific cut-off value will be considered 'test positive'. The ITT will be considered as comparator (non-reference standard) to assess positive and negative agreement of both GHSTs, based on the predefined cut-off values.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Endocrine System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dwarfism, Pituitary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Septo-Optic Dysplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Suspected growth hormone deficiency (GHD), based on either of the following: structural hypothalamic or pituitary disease, or surgery or irradiation in these areas, or head trauma as an adult, or evidence of other pituitary hormone deficiencies, or idiopathic childhood onset GHD (without known hypothalamic or pituitary lesion or injury). Healthy* control subjects, matching a 'high likelihood GHD' subjects GH therapy within 1 month prior to anticipated first GHST within this trial (within 3 months in case of longacting GH formulation). GHST within 7 days prior to the anticipated first test day within the trial. Subjects that are not euthyroid, or subjects who had a change in thyroid therapy within 8 weeks prior to anticipated first test day within the trial. Untreated hypogonadism or not on a stable substitution treatment within 30 days prior to anticipated first test day within the trial. Treatment with drugs directly affecting the pituitary secretion of somatotropin (e.g. somatostatin analogues, clonidine, levodopa, and dopamine agonists) or provoking the release of somatostatin; antimuscarinic agents (atropine). Concomitant use of a CYP3A4 inducer (e.g., carbamazepine, phenobarbital, phenytoin, pioglitazone, rifabutin, rifampin, St. John's Wort). Medical history of ongoing clinically symptomatic severe psychiatric disorders. Parkinson's disease. Cushing disease or patients on supraphysiologic glucocorticoid therapy within 30 days prior to the anticipated first test day within the trial. Type 1 diabetes or untreated or poorly controlled Type 2 diabetes, as defined by HbA1c &gt; 8%. Body mass index (BMI) ≥ 40.0 kg/m2. Participation in a trial with any investigational drug within 30 days prior to trial entry. Vigorous physical exercise within 24 hours prior to each GHST within this trial. Known hypersensitivity to macimorelin or insulin, or any of the constituents of either preparation. Clinically significant cardiovascular or cerebrovascular disease. Prolonged ECG QT interval, defined as QTc &gt; 500 msec. Concomitant treatment with any drugs that might prolong QT/QTc. Elevation of laboratory parameters indicating hepatic or renal dysfunction or damage (ASAT, ALAT &gt; 2.5 x ULN; GGT, creatinine, or bilirubin &gt; 1.5x ULN). Medical history of seizure disorders. Known immunosuppression. Current active malignancy other than nonmelanoma skin cancer. Breastfeeding or positive urine pregnancy test (for women of childbearing potential only). Women of childbearing age without contraception, such as hormonal contraception or use of condom and spermicides or use of diaphragm and spermicides or Intra Uterine Device (IUD). Lack of ability or willingness to give informed consent. Anticipated nonavailability for trial visits/procedures.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Adult Growth Hormone Deficiency</keyword>
</DOC>