<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02558881</DOC>
	<brief_summary>France is among the countries with a high incidence of colorectal cancer. The prognosis associated with colorectal cancer is related to the development stage of the disease at diagnosis. Thus, when the cancer is detected and treated at an early stage, the survival rate at 5 years was 90%. It is therefore a major issue of screening is widespread in France since the end of 2008. This screening is based on a two step strategy: 1) the occult blood in the stool (FOBT) and if positive 2) the realization of an optical colonoscopy examination currently regarded as the evaluation procedure colon reference. But as part of this organized screening, 13% of those with a positive FOBT ultimately refuse to have an optical colonoscopy. Under the refusal, virtual colonoscopy may be proposed as an alternative according to the recommendations of the National Health Authority in 2010. But it has never been assessed as part of organized screening. Similarly another alternative is recently developed colic capsule that benefits of development in recent years of the capsule for the small intestine which has become the gold standard for diagnosis of most diseases of the small intestine (bleeding occult, diagnosis of unknown colitis...). Therefore the study proposes virtual colonoscopy or colon capsule for people with a positive FOBT as part of organized screening and did not realize optical colonoscopy after the usual procedure and complete recovery. This study aims to answer the question of the place of colic capsule as part of organized screening. An economic component is integrated to assess, in terms of health insurance, the cost associated with these two exams, and compare them to the cost of optical colonoscopy. The proposed study is an observational study of impact of an alternative screening strategy for colorectal cancer whose primary objective is to compare the rate of acceptance of virtual colonoscopy and colon capsule in patients refusing optical colonoscopy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Colon Capsule Versus Virtual Colonoscopy for Colorectal Cancer Screening</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with a positive FOBT at screening organized colorectal cancer, patients who have not achieved optical colonoscopy and who received the usual procedure and complete recovery</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>screening</keyword>
	<keyword>colorectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>colon capsule</keyword>
	<keyword>virtual colonoscopy</keyword>
</DOC>