<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02558582</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Pulmonary Hypertension (PH) is a serious disease with a dismal prognosis when left untreated. Advances in medical therapy have improved survival according to recent registries and systematic reviews, but are associated with high healthcare costs. Earlier studies in Heidelberg, Germany showed good evidence for the effect of exercise training on improving exercise performance, quality of life and pulmonary hemodynamics in patients with pulmonary hypertension. The main objectives of the present project are: 1. to investigate the quality of the implementation of a standardized 3 week in-hospital exercise training program on markers of outcome and disease severity in PH-patients in Switzerland immediately after training and after 3 and 12 month. 2. to look whether training with hyperoxia vs. standard care might be more effective. This is a multicentre, randomized parallel-group trial where the intervention rehabilitation is delayed in one group so that they can serve as standard care controls for the others. In a nested single-centre randomized-controlled trial patent will additionally be randomized to receive either usual rehabilitation (UR) or rehabilitation with standardized supplemental oxygen therapy (SSOT) during nights and ergometer training. Patients will receive a PH specific rehabilitation program during 3 weeks followed by an instructed home-based training program for 12 weeks. Patients who are not already under long-term oxygen therapy (LTOT) due to daytime hypoxemia will additionally be randomized to receive standardized supplemental oxygen therapy (SSOT) during training and nights upon written informed consent.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Exercise Training in Patients With Pulmonary Hypertension</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
	<criteria>WHO functional class IIIV PH diagnosed by right heart catheter showing: Baseline mean pulmonary arterial pressure (mPAP) ≥ 25 mmHg Baseline pulmonary vascular resistance (PVR) &gt; 240 dyn x s x cm5 Baseline pulmonary capillary wedge pressure (PCWP) ≤ 15 mm Hg Patients receiving maximal PH therapy including intensified treatment with diuretics and who have been stable for 2 months before entering the study PH target therapy should not be expected to change during the entire 15week study period Negative pregnancy test (βHCG) at the start of the trial Able to understand and willing to sign the Informed Consent Form PH due to significant left heart disease (Wedge ≥ 15mmHg) or lung disease (FEV1 ≤ 60% predicted) Pregnancy at study onset Walking disability Any change in diseasetargeted therapy within the last 2 months Any subject who is scheduled to receive another investigational drug during the course of this study Any other relevant concomitant disease Systolic blood pressure &lt; 85 mmHg History or suspicion of inability to cooperate adequately</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pulmonary arterial hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Oxygen</keyword>
</DOC>