<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02558023</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to demonstrate that urapidil is not inferior to nicardipine for the treatment of hypertension associated with preeclampsia (PE) and that it is better tolerated. - efficacy endpoint : mean arterial blood pressure corrected to 100-120 mmHg after 120 min of study drug administration. - safety endpoints : clinical and biological observation for any side effect. All infants will be observed in the neonatology unit (during 48h). Pharmacokinetic study included to study : - transplacental transfer, - transfer in breast milk, - and neonatal elimination (premature babies of mothers treated with urapidil (less than 33 WG))</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Treatment of Hypertension Associated With Severe Preeclampsia (PE). A Trial of Urapidil Versus Nicardipine</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urapidil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nicardipine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Benzocaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients Singleton pregnancy Patients with remaining hypertension despite an oral treatment for who an iv antihypertensive treatment is indicated Patient with PE, as defined by : Systolic Blood Pressure (BP) ≥ 140 mmHg and/or Diastolic BP ≥ 90 mmHg, after the 20th week of amenorrhea, without chronic hypertension, AND Proteinuria &gt; 300 mg.day1 or &gt; 2 crosses(++) on an urinary dipstick, OR Patient with severe Pregnancy Induced Hypertension (PIH), as defined by : Systolic BP ≥ 160 mmHg and/or Diastolic BP ≥110 mmHg, after the 20th week of amenorrhea, without chronic hypertension, Written informed consent signed and dated by both investigator and patient, Valid social security affiliation Known allergy to study drugs Contraindication to the study drugs: stenosis of the aortic isthmus, arteriovenous shunt, coarctation of the aorta, unstable angina, compensatory hypertension, myocardial infarction &lt; 8 days. Eclampsia Person with difficulty understanding information Person with diminished responsibility, Ongoing intravenous antihypertensive treatment, No pressure cuff adapted to the morphology of the arms of the patients Concomitant use of 5 phosphodiesterase inhibitors Participation in a clinical trial within 6 months prior to inclusion</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>PRE-ECLAMPSIA</keyword>
	<keyword>URAPIDIL</keyword>
	<keyword>NICARDIPINE</keyword>
</DOC>