<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02558868</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a randomized, open-label, controlled study that will compare the efficacy of oxaliplatin in combination with irinotecan to irinotecan alone as second-line treatment for patients with gemcitabine and S-1 refractory pancreatic cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Second-Line Oxaliplatin and Irinotecan Versus Irinotecan Alone for Gemcitabine and S-1 Refractory Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with histologically confirmed advanced pancreatic cancer who had experienced progression during firstline gemcitabine and S1 were eligible for enrollment on this openlabel, randomized study. Additional inclusion criteria were age 18 years or older Measurable reference cancer site(s) confirmed with computed tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) Karnofsky performance status (KPS) of at least 70% Adequate renal function, defined as creatinine clearance greater than 30 mL/min) Adequate hepatic function, defined asALT and AST less than 2.5× upper limit of normal or, with liver metastases, less than 5_ upper limit of normal Adequate bone marrow function, defined as platelets greater than 100×10E9/L and WBC greater than 3.5×10E9/L. The presence of any severe concomitant disease that could interrupt the planned treatment; intractable pain Hypersensitivity to study drugs Serious cardiovascular disease (eg, unstable coronary artery disease or myocardial infarction within 4 weeks of study start) National Cancer Institute CommonToxicity Criteria (NCICTC) grade 3 or 4 sensory or motor neuropathy Prior or concurrent malignancy (other than pancreatic cancer) Female, pregnancy or breastfeeding.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>