<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02828462</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The emergence of oral delivery in cancer therapeutics is expected to result in an increased need for better coordination between all treatment stakeholders, mainly to ensure adequate treatment delivery to the patient. There is significant interest in the nurse navigation program's potential to improve transitions of care by improving communication between treatment stakeholders and by providing personalized organizational assistance to patients. The use of health information technology is another strategy aimed at improving cancer care coordination that can be combined with the NN program to improve remote patient follow-up. However, the potential of these two strategies combined to improve oral treatment delivery is limited by a lack of rigorous evidence of actual impact. The investigators are conducting a large scale randomized controlled trial designed to assess the impact of a navigation program denoted CAPRI that is based on two Nurse Navigators and a web portal ensuring coordination between community and hospital as well as between patients and navigators, versus routine delivery of oral anticancer therapy. The primary research aim is to assess the impact of the program on treatment delivery for patients with metastatic cancer, as measured by Relative Dose Intensity. The trial involves a number of other outcomes, including toxic side effects, patient quality of life and patient experience . An economic evaluation adopting a societal perspective will be conducted, in order to estimate those health care resources' used. A parallel process evaluation will be conducted to describe implementation of the intervention</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of a Monitoring Device for Patients With Cancer Treated Using Oral Therapeutics</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coal Tar</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients (male or female) aged &gt; 18 years Life expectancy &gt; 6 months Patients with metastatic cancer or hematological malignancy being treated at Gustave Roussy Patients with oral therapy (cytotoxic or targeted therapies) Patients starting therapy Patients living in France Patients affiliated to a social security system or equivalent OMS score from 0 to 2 at the time of inclusion Signed inform consent Patients able to follow protocol Patients being treated with hormonotherapy only Patients enrolled in a clinical trial Patients beneficiary of a treatment under Temporary Use Authorisation Not French speaking patients Patients deprived of liberty Patients with no internet access or telephone line</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>