<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02828683</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to demonstrate the safety and efficacy of the TCD-10023 (Ultimaster) sirolimus eluting stent in patients with acute ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI), by proving superiority with respect to in-stent late loss at 6 months to the Kaname bare metal stent and non-inferiority with respect to Target Vessel Failure (TVF) at 12 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of TCD-10023 (Ultimaster) Drug-eluting Stent in STEMI Patients - MASTER Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>MASTER is prospective, randomized (3:1), single blind, controlled, superiority (efficacy) and non-inferiority (safety and efficacy), multi center, two-arm trial of TCD-10023 (Ultimaster) drug eluting stent (test) and Kaname bare metal stent (comparator). Patients will be followed at 30 days, 6, and 12 months post-procedure and annually for 3 years. 500 patients with clinical follow up will be randomized in 3:1 ratio (375 in TCD-10023 arm and 125 in Kaname arm). Among them, 100 patients will be randomized in the same, 3:1 ratio, to angiographic follow up at 6 months in preselected hospitals (75 in TCD-10023 and 25 in Kaname arm)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age equal or more than 18 years Chest pain &gt; 20 minutes Primary PCI &lt;24h from symptoms onset STsegment elevation of &gt; 1 mm in &gt; 2 contiguous leads, or (presumably new) left bundle branch block, or true posterior MI with ST depression of &gt; 1 mm in &gt; 2 contiguous anterior leads Presence of at least one acute infarct artery target vessel with one or more coronary artery stenoses in a native coronary artery from 2.54.0 mm in diameter that can be covered with one or multiple stents Signed informed consent Female of childbearing potential (age &lt; 50 and last menstruation within the last 12 months), who did not underwent tubal ligation, ovariectomy or hysterectomy Known intolerance to aspirin, clopidogrel, heparin, bivalirudin, cobalt, chromium, nickel, sirolimus or contrast material Currently participating in another trial before reaching primary endpoint Mechanical complication of acute myocardial infarction (e.g. cardiogenic shock…) Acute myocardial infarction secondary to stent thrombosis Previously stented infarction related artery (IRA) Planned surgery within 6 months of PCI unless dual antiplatelet therapy is maintained throughout the perisurgical period Patients with noncardiac comorbid conditions with life expectancy&lt; 1 year or that may result in protocol noncompliance History of bleeding diathesis or known coagulopathy Use of oral anticoagulants</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>DES</keyword>
	<keyword>PCI</keyword>
	<keyword>STEMI</keyword>
	<keyword>Interventional Cardiology</keyword>
</DOC>