<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01063361</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Healthy individuals with type 2 diabetes will receive intensive counseling on food selection to improve glucose control using either high cereal fiber dietary strategies or low glycemic index foods emphasizing dried legumes and their products. The treatments will last 3 months with bloods taken for HbA1c, glucose and blood lipids. If the study shows a benefit for either or both diets, then use of high fiber and/or low glycemic index foods in the diet may provide another potential way to improve glucose control and lower cholesterol levels in non-insulin dependent diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Low Glycemic Index Diets (With Pulses) in Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and women with type 2 diabetes who are treated with oral hypoglycemic agents at a stable dose for at least 8 weeks have a HbA1c in the range of 6.5% to 8.5% at screening and at the visit prior to randomization have diabetes diagnosed &gt;6 months have maintained stable weight for 2 months (within 3%) have a valid OHIP card and a family physician if prescribed lipid medication, have taken a stable dose for at least 2 weeks if prescribed blood pressure medication, have taken a stable dose for at least 1 week can keep written food records, with the use of a digital scale Individuals who take insulin take steroids have GI disease (gastroparesis, celiac disease, ulcerative colitis, Crohn's Disease, IBS) have had a major cardiovascular event (stroke or myocardial infarction) in the past 6 months take warfarin (Coumadin) have had major surgery in the past 6 months have a major debilitating disorder have clinically significant liver disease (AST or ALT &gt; 130 U/L), excluding NAFL or NASH have hepatitis B or C have renal failure (high creatinine &gt; 150 mmol/L) have serum triglycerides ≥ 6.0 mmol/L have a history of cancer, except nonmelanoma skin cancer (basal cell, squamous cell) have food allergies to study food components have elevated blood pressure (&gt; 145/90) unless approved by GP have acute or chronic infections (bacterial or viral) have chronic inflammatory diseases (e.g. rheumatoid arthritis, lupus; ulcerative colitis) have other conditions which in the opinion of any of the investigators would make them unsuitable for the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>