<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00358982</DOC>
	<brief_summary>MGCD0103 is an experimental drug that belongs to a class of drugs known as the histone deacetylase inhibitors, which may restore normal control in cancer cells by affecting the genes and proteins that are being made. Laboratory tests show that this new investigational anti-cancer drug can slow down the growth of human cancer cells in mice; two clinical research studies are currently being performed in humans with cancer and a similar study is being performed in patients with the same disease. The purpose of this study is to find out what effect the experimental drug MGCD0103 has on patients with relapsed and refractory Hodgkin's lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of MGCD0103 (MG-0103) in Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Hodgkin's Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mocetinostat</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pathologic confirmation of relapsed or refractory classical Hodgkin's lymphoma. The patient has at least one site of measurable disease (≥ 2.0 cm) as measured by conventional techniques such as CT or MRI. Prior treatment: there is no limit to number of prior therapies. Patients who had prior allogeneic stem cell transplants and do not have evidence of graft versus host disease and are not receiving immunosuppressive agents are eligible if they meet all other inclusion criteria. ECOG performance status of 0 or 1. Aged 18 years or older (no safety data yet for ages &lt; 18). Laboratory requirements (must be done within 7 days prior to study initiation). Patients with another active cancer (excluding basal cell carcinoma or cervical intraepithelial neoplasia [CIN/cervical in situ] or melanoma in situ). Prior history of cancer is allowed, as long as there is no active disease. Pregnant or lactating women. Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must have a negative serum pregnancy test documented within 7 days prior to start of study drug. WOCBP and men whose partners are WOCBP must use an acceptable method of contraception while enrolled in this study, and for a period of 3 months following study drug treatment. Patients with uncontrolled intercurrent illness, active or uncontrolled infections, or a fever &gt; 38.5°C (not due to tumor fever) on the day of scheduled dosing.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Relapsed or Refractory Hodgkin's Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase II</keyword>
</DOC>