<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01014143</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Clinical research study to determine the anti-plaque efficacy of commerical dentifrices and an oral rinse.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluating Commercial Anti-Plaque Products and Oral Rinse</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This clinical research study was to train new examiners for short term plaque clinical methodologies.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dental Plaque</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorhexidine gluconate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorhexidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triclosan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorides</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female volunteers at least 18 years of age. Good general health. Must sign informed consent form. Minimum of 20 natural uncrowned teeth (excluding third molars) must be present. No history of allergy to personal care consumer products, or their ingredients, relevant to any ingredient in the test products as determined by the dental/medical professional monitoring the study. Subjects unable or unwilling to sign the informed consent form. Medical condition which requires premedication prior to dental visits/procedures. Moderate or advanced periodontal disease or heavy dental tartar (calculus). Two or more decayed untreated dental sites at screening. Other disease of the hard or soft oral tissues. Impaired salivary function (e.g. Sjogren's syndrome or head and neck irradiation). Use of medications that are currently affect salivary function. Use of antibiotics or antimicrobial drugs within 30 days prior to study visit #1. Allergy to chlorhexidine. Pregnant or nursing women. Participation in any other clinical study within 1 week prior to enrollment into this study. Use of tobacco products. Subjects who must receive dental treatment during the study dates. Current use of Antibiotics for premedication for dental treatment or for any other purpose. Presence of an orthodontic appliance that interferes with plaque scoring. History of allergy to common dentifrice ingredients. Immune compromised individuals (HIV, AIDS, immuno suppressive drug therapy).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>23 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>81 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>