<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00397098</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of SR58611A (350 mg BID) compared to placebo in the prevention of relapse of anxiety, in patients with Generalized Anxiety Disorder improved after 12 weeks of treatment with SR58611A. The primary objective is to evaluate the efficacy of SR58611A 350mg BID compared to placebo over a 24 to 52-week treatment period. The secondary objective is to assess the safety and tolerability of SR58611A in patients with GAD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prevention of Relapse Study of SR58611A in Improved Patients With Generalized Anxiety Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amibegron</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For entry into the open phase: Patients suffering from generalized anxiety disorder, according to Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSMIVTR) criteria and assessed with the Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI) plus Generalized Anxiety Disorder (GAD) module. With a total score on the 14item Hamilton Anxiety Rating Scale (HAMA) &gt; 20 at V1(D4) and V2 (D1). For entry into the doubleblind randomized phase: Improved patients with HAMA score &lt; 11 at V7 (W12). Inpatients. Patients with a diagnosis of Major Depressive Disorder (DSM IVTR) within 6 months of screening. Patients with a MADRS total score &gt; 18 at screening or baseline. Patients at immediate risk for suicidal behaviour. Patients with other current (within 6 months) anxiety disorder according to the MINI Patients with a lifetime history according to the MINI of: Bipolar disorder, Psychotic disorder, Antisocial personality disorder. Patients with a current history according to the MINI of: Anorexia nervosa or bulimia nervosa in the past 6 months, Alcohol or substance dependence or abuse in the past 12 months, except nicotine or caffeine dependence. The investigator will evaluate whether there are other reasons why a patient may not participate.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anxiety disorders, Relapse prevention</keyword>
</DOC>