<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00397046</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the tolerability and safety of HKI-272, and to determine the maximum dose that can safety be given. The secondary purpose of this study is to determine how the body uses and gets rid of HKI-272 and to assess whether HKI-272 is effective for the treatment of advanced solid tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Of The Safety And Tolerability Of HKI-272 Administered Orally To Japanese Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase 1 open-label sequential-group study of ascending single and multiple oral doses administered to subjects with advanced solid tumors. Each subject will participate in only 1 dose group and will receive a single dose of test article, followed by a 1-week observation period, and then will receive the test article administered once-daily by mouth in cycles consisting of 28 days. Subjects will be enrolled in groups of 3 to 6. Adverse events and dose-limiting toxicities will be assessed from the first single dose.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria 1. Diagnosis of metastatic or advanced cancer that has failed standard effective therapy 2. Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks and adequate performance status 3. Adequate bone marrow, kidney and liver function 4. Willingness of male and female subjects who are not surgically sterile or postmenopausal to use adequate methods of birth control Exclusion Criteria 1. Any anticancer chemotherapy, radiotherapy immunotherapy or investigational agents within 4 weeks of first dose of HKI272 2. Inadequate cardiac function 3. Surgery within 2 weeks of first dose of HKI272 4. Active central nervous system metastases (i.e., symptomatic, required use of corticosteroids and/or progressive growth) 5. Significant gastrointestinal disorder with diarrhea as a major symptom 6. Pregnant or breast feeding women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Advanced Malignant Solid Tumors</keyword>
</DOC>