<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="129832">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01411839</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>35279-C</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R34MH084674</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01411839</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Depression and ART Adherence in HIV+ Latinos</brief_title>
  <official_title>Addressing Depression and ART Adherence in HIV+ Latinos on the U.S.-Mexico Border</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Washington</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Texas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Washington</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The current HIV treatment adherence project was designed to adapt culturally and then pilot
      test an empirically supported cognitive-behavioral therapy program for adherence and
      symptoms of depression (CBT-AD)with HIV+ Latinos living on the U.S.-Mexico Border.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Additionally, the investigators will assess the feasibility and efficacy of a novel
      medication monitoring and reminder system (MedSignals®) in the form of an electronic pillbox
      with monitoring and reminding functions that is available in a Spanish-language version. Our
      hypotheses are grounded in a conceptual model proposing that the CBT-AD intervention will
      improve problem-solving ability and decrease depressive symptomatology, which will directly
      improve biomedical outcomes of HIV-1 RNA viral load and CD4 as well as indirectly improve
      biomedical outcomes through increased motivation, improved memory, and better medication
      adherence. Evaluating and implementing generalizable and sustainable mental health and
      adherence interventions such as the ones proposed are urgently needed in the region to
      improve HIV treatment outcomes and thwart the development and transmission of drug resistant
      virus.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>July 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single Blind (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Montgomery-Asberg Depression Rating Scale (MADRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes in depression ratings at two time points: From baseline to 6 and 9 month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The MADRS is a 10-item clinician administered scripted rating scale of depressive symptoms. The scale was develop to capture current depressive symptoms within the past seven days. The areas covered include: apparant and reported sadness, inner tension, reduced sleep and appetite, concentration difficulties, lassitude, inability to feel, pessimistic and suicidal thoughts. Both control and treatment conditions are interviewed with the MADRS at baseline and at 6 and 9 month follow-ups for any changes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Self-Report Adherence</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes in self-reported adherence from baseline through 9 months</time_frame>
    <description>From the Visual Analogue Scale or brief items</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MedSignals Electronic Pill-box for Adherence</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes in adherence at two-time points: from baseline to 6 and 9 month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The MedSignals electronic pill-box is a elecontric storage bin that allows participants to store medications. In the treatment condition, the pill-box provides audio commands to alarm participants of their dosing regimen. The pill-box stores adherence information (time, number of openings). In the control condition, the pill-box does not alarm participants. The pill-box serves as a storage bin for the control condition and stores adherence data. All data is then uploaded onto an online database for investigators.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Depressive Symptoms</condition>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy (CBT-AD)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>CBT intervention for adherence and depression in a sample of HIV+ Latinos. The intervention is designed for issues of non-adherence and depressive symptomatology. Therapy intervention involves 10-weekly or biweekly sessions, with 2 booster session.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control-Standard Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Those randomized to the control condition are not involved in the CBT-AD therapy intervention. They receive standard care as usual. A letter is sent to their medical provider indicating that mild symptoms of depression were detected. The participants in the control arm are followed and matched to a participant in the intervention arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy AD</intervention_name>
    <description>Therapeutic intervention, one-on-one and face-to-fact, over multiple sessions</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy (CBT-AD)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CBT-AD</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  HIV+ participants (a) currently receiving HIV care at La Fe CARE Center (study site);

          -  18 years of age or older;

          -  Latino (i.e., self-identified as being of Mexican heritage);

          -  English- or Spanish-speaking

          -  capable of giving informed consent;

          -  currently on a prescribed antiretroviral regimen;

          -  suboptimally adherent (i.e., demonstrated either by a VL load taken in the last 12
             months that is above the undetectable threshold of 50 mL copies or self-reporting a
             missed dose in the last two weeks);

          -  exhibiting some depressive symptomatology (i.e., scoring on the Beck Depression
             Inventory-1A 10 or above), and (i) male or female (including transgender
             Female-to-Male and Male-To-Female.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  actively psychotic or so cognitively impaired that they cannot participate,

          -  so physically ill as to be unable to come to the clinic to participate in the
             intervention, OR

          -  Report The use of crack, cocaine, heroin, OR methamphetamines to any extent in the
             past 40 days.

          -  Those who are planning on being away from the area for any extended period during the
             study (as in the case of seasonal workers) or whom

          -  have household members already enrolled in the study will also be excluded. We did
             choose to restrict study eligibility to individuals of Mexican descent.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jane M Simoni, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Washington</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centro de Salud Familiar La Fe CARE Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>El Paso</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>79925</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2011</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>August 23, 2011</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 25, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Jane M. Simoni, Ph.D.</name_title>
    <organization>University of Washington</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Latinos</keyword>
  <keyword>Adherence</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV/AIDS</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
