<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02585180</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Many studies provide evidence for the benefit of lower respiratory tract surveillance, mostly by culture of endotracheal secretions, to predict bacterial pathogens (especially multi-drugs resistant pathogens) involved in VAP. The DEMETER study (NCT02515617) assessing the medico-economical impact of the subglottic secretions drainage (SSD) provides the opportunity to evaluate the accuracy of the subglottic secretions culture surveillance to predict pathogens involved in VAP (in comparison with the concomitant endotracheal secretions surveillance). These subglottic and tracheal secretions culture surveillance will be masked to the investigators of the DEMETER Study. This ancillary study will be performed in 14 centers participating to the DEMETER study</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Subglottic Secretions Surveillance to Predict Bacterial Pathogens Involved in Ventilator-associated Pneumonia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia, Ventilator-Associated</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age over 18 years Invasive mechanical ventilation delivered via an endotracheal tube and expected to be required more than 24 hours Intubation performed in units in which the specific endotracheal tube allowing the subglottic secretions drainage will be available during the SSD period of the trial Information delivered Previous inclusion in the study Patients moribund at the Intensive Care Unit admission Pregnant, parturient or breastfeeding woman Patient hospitalized without consent and/or deprived of liberty by court's decision Patient under guardianship or curators Lack of social insurance Concomitant inclusion in a trial on VAP prevention Patient with no comprehension of the French language</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ventilator-associated pneumonia</keyword>
	<keyword>Surveillance</keyword>
	<keyword>Subglottic-secretions</keyword>
	<keyword>Critically ill patients</keyword>
	<keyword>Prevention</keyword>
</DOC>