<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01279577</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will run in centers in Germany, Denmark, Austria, Czech Republic, and Switzerland, only. This proof-of-concept study aims to evaluate the efficacy of three doses of oral TSO suspension vs. placebo for the induction of remission in Crohn's disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trichuris Suis Ova (TSO) Suspension Versus Placebo in Active Crohn's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Major Signed informed consent, Man or woman between 18 and 75 years of age, Established diagnosis of Crohn's disease (CD) since at least 3 months prior to screening confirmed by endoscopic and histological, or endoscopic and radiological criteria, Negative pregnancy test in females of childbearing potential. Major Bowel surgery within the last 3 months prior to baseline, Resection of more than 50 cm of the ileum, Ileostomy or colostomy, Septic complications, Evidence of infectious diarrhoea (i.e., pathogenic bacteria or Clostridium difficile toxin in stool culture), Abscess, perforation, fistulas, or perianal lesions, Immediate surgery required (e.g., major stenosis, serious bleeding, peritonitis, ileus), Clinical signs of stricturing disease, Parenteral or tube feeding, Abnormal hepatic function (ALT or ALP &gt; 2.5 x upper limit of normal [ULN] at screening), liver cirrhosis, or portal hypertension, Abnormal renal function (Cystatin C &gt; ULN) at screening, Any severe concomitant cardiovascular, renal, endocrine, or psychiatric disorder, which in the opinion of the investigator might have an influence on the patient's compliance or the interpretation of the results, Any condition associated with significant immunosuppression, Active malignancy or treatment with anticancer drugs during the last 5 years. Existing or intended pregnancy or breastfeeding, Participation in another clinical trial within the last 30 days, simultaneous participation in another clinical trial, or previous participation in this trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Crohn´s disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Trichuris suis</keyword>
	<keyword>randomized</keyword>
	<keyword>placebo</keyword>
	<keyword>induction of remission</keyword>
	<keyword>porcine whipworm</keyword>
</DOC>