<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01279876</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether melatonin is effective in the treatment of relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis patients as a supplement to the main disease-modifying drugs.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Melatonin in Relapsing-Remitting Multiple Sclerosis Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Multiple sclerosis is an autoimmune chronic demyelinating disorder of the central nervous system, and the major cause of disability in the youngsters all over the world, still with no definitely known etiology and treatment. Melatonin is a hormone secreted by pineal gland famous for its role in circadian rhythm regulation, and with known antioxidant effects. It was shown that melatonin is lower in multiple sclerosis patients in the relapse phase in comparison to other diseases and is correlated with the Multiple Sclerosis Functional Composite score of the patients. Melatonin is also suggested to have an immunomodulatory role. Therefore, we hypothesize that melatonin can be effective in the treatment of relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis, Relapsing-Remitting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Melatonin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>definite diagnosis of relapsingremitting multiple sclerosis EDSS &lt;=5 at least 6months consumption of interferon beta 1a illiteracy evidence of Nystagmus or visual acuity lower than 5/10 in each of the eyes relapse in the last 3 months pregnancy or deciding to become pregnant during the following year regulatory consumption of warfarin, nifedipine, nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), betablockers, fluvoxamine, isoniazide, progestin history of epilepsy, stroke, major depression, endocrine, hepatic, hematologic, and nephrologic diseases</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>