<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02339194</DOC>
	<brief_summary>BACKGROUND: The literature has shown that simplified methods for complete denture fabrication can be as effective as the traditional techniques, but with less expenditure of time and resources, without prejudice to the patients. However, the effectiveness of these simplified methods for patients with more complex medical conditions haven't been deeply explored. OBJECTIVES: To evaluate the effectiveness of a proposed simplified method for complete dentures fabrication for patients with severely resorbed mandibular alveolar bones. METHOD: edentulous patients requesting treatment with bimaxillary complete dentures in a university clinic will be rehabilitated following a simplified technical proposal, being divided randomly into two groups according to the mandibular arch molding technique. In group A, a single impression with alginate through pre-fabricated trays will be performed, while patients allocated in group B will receive a second molding with a more complex technique. After 3 and 6 months, besides important clinical parameters, it will be investigated aspects related to patient's perceptions about the success of treatment. The study will be conducted with a minimum of 30 participants per group, and comparisons between the two groups will be made by means of tests suitable for distribution of data.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Application of a Simplified Method of Complete Denture Fabrication for Severely Resorbed Mandibular Ridges</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Mouth, Edentulous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Jaw, Edentulous</mesh_term>
	<criteria>complete edentulism for at least one year; desire to receive a pair of new conventional complete dentures mental receptiveness; good understanding of spoken Portuguese disorders of the masticatory system; pathological changes of residual ridges; debilitating systemic diseases.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>complete denture</keyword>
	<keyword>quality of life</keyword>
	<keyword>patient satisfaction</keyword>
</DOC>