<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02339415</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effects of pharmacologic FXa inhibition (via edoxaban 30 mg daily) on inflammation, as reflected in plasma Interleukin-6 levels.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Targeted Anticoagulation Therapy to Reduce Inflammation and Cellular Activation in Long-term HIV Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Edoxaban</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria HIV infection (verified by previous positive antibody or detectable HIV RNA level) Age ≥18 years Receiving continuous ART for ≥2 years (regimen changes &gt;3 months prior to enrollment are acceptable) HIV RNA level ≤200 copies/mL for ≥1 year (1 measure ≥200 allowed if also &lt;500 and preceded and followed by one or more values ≤200 copies/mL) Ddimer level ≥100 mg/L (or ng/mL) at screening (or within the prior month) Estimated creatinine clearance ≥50 mL/min Body weight ≥60kg Do not anticipate starting (or stopping) statin or aspirin therapy during the study For women of child bearing potential, agrees to use a reliable form of birth control Exclusion Criteria Pregnancy or breast feeding A contraindication to taking edoxaban A clinical indication for anticoagulation therapy (e.g., atrial fibrillation or Deep Vein Thrombosis/PE) Treatment with antiplatelet, anticoagulation, or immunemodulatory drugs currently or within the past 6 months; prior selflimited treatment with aspirin (i.e., not daily use) is not itself an exclusion. Grade ≥1 hematology lab abnormality for INR (&gt;1.1 x ULN), hemoglobin (&lt;10.0 g/L), platelets (&lt;100,000 cells/μL), and WBC (2,500 cells/mm3) Grade ≥2 lab abnormality for chemistries (BMP) or liver panel Alcohol or illicit drug abuse/dependency within the prior year History of prior myocardial infarction or unstable atherosclerotic disease History of prior stroke or transient ischemic attack (TIA) History of active gastrointestinal ulcer or bleeding disorder within the prior year Intent to have surgery during the study period (12 months) Hepatitis C treatments (e.g., interferon, ribavirin, protease inhibitors) within the past 6 months Cirrhosis or hepatic impairment (e.g., ChildPugh class B or C). Seizure disorder Previous/current CNS space occupying lesion (e.g., Toxoplasmosis, mTB) with persistent abnormalities on CNS imaging after completion of treatment. Surgical or invasive procedure anticipated during study period. Invasive cancer in the prior year or receiving cancer treatment (not including carcinomainsitu or basal cell cancer of the skin) Rheumatologic or inflammatory disease, systemic in nature (e.g., systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, vasculitis, sarcoidosis, Crohn's disease) Assessment by the clinical investigator that enrollment into the study could entail excess risk to the participant, beyond what is intended or expected.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>