<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00127218</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the added benefits of increased high-density lipoprotein (HDL) cholesterol serum levels over and above those achieved by lipid lowering therapy guided by current guidelines, in older individuals with cardiovascular disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>High-Density Lipoprotein (HDL) Cholesterol Increased Plaque Stabilization in the Elderly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The hypothesis being tested is that the current standard lipid lowering therapy, combined with a 20 percent or greater increase in serum HDL induced by long-acting niacin, reduces plaque size in older individuals with cardiovascular disease. The specific aims of testing this hypothesis are: 1. to determine the effects of statin plus placebo vs. statin plus niacin therapy on plaque size and composition, 2. to determine whether alterations of inflammatory markers of atherosclerosis induced by lipid lowering therapy parallel alterations of plaque architecture and composition in older patients with cardiovascular disease, 3. to determine the effects of these interventions on the incidence of cardiovascular and cerebrovascular events. The results of the trial will be directly applicable to developing strategies for plaque stabilization in the elderly who suffer the most from the severe complications of advanced cardiovascular atherosclerosis. A total of 144 participants aged 65 and older with cardiovascular or cerebrovascular disease will be recruited. Participants will be randomized to receive either statin plus niacin or statin plus a placebo for 18 months. Participants will be provided a prescription for fluvastatin 80 mg to be taken on a daily basis, or they may continue their ongoing or any other cholesterol-lowering drugs such as pravastatin 80 mg daily, simvastatin 20 mg daily, atorvastatin up to 20 mg daily or rosuvastatin up to 20 mg daily. Ten visits are expected, initially every 4 weeks for dose adjustment. Then visits will be every 6 months; MRI, Inflammatory Markers tests, and other lab tests will be done at baseline and the visits at months 6, 12, and 18.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atorvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pravastatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Simvastatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rosuvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluvastatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Niacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Niacinamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nicotinic Acids</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged 65 or older Documented clinical cardiovascular or cerebrovascular disease due to atherosclerosis Candidate for lipid lowering therapy; no contraindication to fluvastatin, niacin or aspirin therapy Lowdensity lipoprotein (LDL) cholesterol below 150 mg/dl if untreated or below 125 mg/dl on statin monotherapy Willing to discontinue present therapy if private physician agrees with enrollment Eligible to undergo transesophageal magnetic resonance imaging (MRI); no contraindications to GadoliniumDTPA, the contrast agent used Willing to sign Informed Consent Ineligibility for MRI procedure due to pacemaker, metal implants, or other ferromagnetic devices Claustrophobia Previously documented esophageal disease which would preclude transesophageal MRI LDLC greater than 150 mg/dl off lipid lowering therapy or daily statin therapy requiring doses greater than 20 mg of atorvastatin, 20 mg of simvastatin, 80 mg of lovastatin, 80 mg of pravastatin, 80 mg of extended release fluvastatin, or 20 mg of rosuvastatin Contraindication or allergy to statins or aspirin Current use of or known intolerance or allergy to Niaspan (a longacting niacin) Allergy or intolerance to GadoliniumDTPA (MRI contrast agent) Liver or kidney failure defined clinically and by laboratory data Mental, neurologic or social condition preventing understanding of the rationale, procedures, risks and potential benefits associated with the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>atherosclerotic plaque</keyword>
	<keyword>MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>inflammatory markers</keyword>
	<keyword>statins</keyword>
</DOC>