<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02192866</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Food allergies are now a major problem. These experiments involve getting blood from people with food allergies and from people without food allergies. The blood collected will be used to answer questions and find information about peanut and other food allergies. Samples will come from: - People signed up by the investigators at the University of Colorado Denver - University of North Carolina and Massachusetts General Hospital where people have been treated for peanut allergies - University of North Carolina, Massachusetts General Hospital, National Jewish Health and The Children's Hospital in Denver where people have taken part or will take part in clinically indicated oral food challenges. Blood and health histories from the University of North Carolina, Massachusetts General Hospital, National Jewish Health, and The Children's Hospital will not have personal information linked. The specific aims of this experiment are: 1. Come up with a lab test that will predict how bad an allergic reaction will be to peanuts. 2. Find out what part of a peanut causes allergic reactions. 3. Come up with preventions that can block peanut allergies. 4. Find the strongest proteins in walnuts.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Blood Samples for the Study of Peanut, Tree Nut and Other Food Allergies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Food Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peanut Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nut Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>This protocol is to draw blood for a variety of related studies of food allergy. For this reason, we will list each group of subjects and the inclusion criteria for that group. 1. Deidentified sera or plasma from patients who have undergone Oral ImmunoTherapy (OIT) for peanut allergy. These samples already exist. Inclusion criteria for the current study is that the patients have been enrolled in a controlled trial of OIT for peanuts and had at least one oral challenge. Age 175. 2. Deidentified samples from patients who are undergoing clinically indicated food challenges for peanut allergy. Inclusion criteria are a) concern regarding possible allergy to peanuts, b) age 175, c) plan to undergo a clinically indicated challenge with peanuts. 3. Patients with peanut allergy. Inclusion criteria are a) excellent history of a systemic reaction to peanuts, b) age 675. 4. Patients with other food allergies (especially tree nuts). Inclusion criteria are a) excellent history of a systemic reaction to tree nuts or other foods, b) age 675. 5. Normal controls. Inclusion criteria are a) no known food allergies, b) recent ingestion of peanuts without difficulty, and c) age 675. 1. Any known significant medical or psychiatric diagnosis 2. Use of an investigational drug within 30 days 3. Use of omalizumab (antiIgE; Xolair) within 6 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>