<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02192489</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics and preliminary efficacy of oral CC-220 in adult subjects with chronic cutaneous sarcoidosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 2 Study With CC-220 in Skin Sarcoidosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 2a, multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, sequential, dose-ascending, safety and tolerability study in subjects with chronic cutaneous sarcoidosis. Two dose cohorts of CC-220 (Cohort 1: 0.3 mg by mouth (PO) every day (QD) or matching placebo and Cohort 2: 0.6 mg PO QD or matching placebo) will be evaluated using a sequential, dose-ascending design</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoidosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males or females aged ≥ 18 years at the time of consent. Have chronic cutaneous sacrcoidosis (CCS) prior to consent Have active cutaneous sarcoidosis lesion(s) at screening Forced vital capacity of ≥ 45% of predicted normal value at screening. Estimated Glomerular Filtration Rate (eGFR) ≥ 60 mL/min. Females of childbearing potential must have negative pregnancy tests prior to starting study therapy and agree to either commit to true abstinence or use effective contraception. Male subjects must practice true abstinence or agree to use a condom even if he has undergone a successful vasectomy Positive tuberculosis test at screening. History of inadequately treated tuberculosis History of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) and/or Common Variable Immunodeficiency Disease. History of alcohol or drug abuse History or current peripheral neuropathy Current uveitis or any other clinically significant ophthalmological finding Currently require therapy for precapillary pulmonary hypertension.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Cutaneous Sarcoidosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Cutaneous Sarcoidosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Sarcoidosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Sarcoidosis</keyword>
</DOC>