<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02192047</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators hypothesized that there will be a significant difference between the effects of trans-free palm-, interesterified palm- and interesterified soybean oil blend on cardiovascular disease, inflammation, insulin resistance and obesity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chronic Effects of Natural and Interesterified Fats Margarine on Insulin Sensitivity and Selected Markers of Cardiovascular Diseases (CVD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Human volunteers will be conditioned for a 8 wk intervention on 3 different test diets providing 30 % energy as fat, 15% energy as protein and 55% energy as carbohydrate according to parallel designed sequences. The test fats used for this study are palm oil, chemically interesterified palm oil and chemically interesterified fully hydrogenated soybean oil and soft oil blend in the form of margarine. Volunteers will be restricted to follow the dietary guidelines throughout the study. Blood collection sessions will held before and after every diet intervention. Outcome measures of the study are serum lipid profile, markers of inflammation, markers of obesity and insulin resistance.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult males and females, aged 2060 yr Staff and students of International Medical University, IMU/ Staff of Malaysian Palm Oil Board, MPOB to facilitate centralized consumption of the test fats/snacks BMI 21 30 kg/m2 Abnomal liver function test (elevated transaminases alanine aminotransferase,ALT; aspartate aminotransferase,AST))/ abnormal kidney function test (elevated plasma creatinine) History of type 2 diabetes mellitus, cancer, stomach ulcers, drug abuse or alcoholism Smokers On lipid/blood pressure lowering medication/supplements Blood pressure&gt;140/90 mmHg Fasting total cholesterol &gt; 6.5 mmol/L Fasting TAG &gt; 2.0 mmol/L Candidates who are going abroad during the planned schedule for the dietary intervention</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>