<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01382875</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Fragility fractures are one of the commonest injuries among elderly people in Hong Kong and account for 12% of the disease burden in elderly aged 65 or above. A good management healthcare program and training helps elderly to restore full functional level and prevent re-fracture in the following 2 years after primary fracture, but Hong Kong lacks of such program. Some reports from other countries pointed out a well-organized multi-disciplinary management programs are cost-effective to identify and treat osteoporosis, reduce the fracture rate, improve quality of life and raise awareness of fragility fracture. This study aims to compare the cost-effectiveness of multi-disciplinary management program with conventional care controls. The clinical effectiveness outcomes (re-fracture rate, fall rate, mortality, mobility, quality of life and specialist follow-up time) of the fragility hip fracture patients in New Territories East receiving the proposed management program will be compared with those from Kowloon Central with usual care as controls. The findings will provide useful data for the policy maker to evaluate the current clinical service for fragility fracture patients and consider the implementation of new multi-disciplinary management program into our healthcare system.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Comparison of Comprehensive Multi-disciplinary Program and Conventional Care Program on Fragility Fracture Elderly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Fragility hip fracture patients within age 6590 Taking medication affecting bone metabolism or intensive exercise training; Those living in old age homes or anyone who is not able to comply with our program</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multi-disciplinary management program</keyword>
	<keyword>Conventional care program</keyword>
	<keyword>Balance Ability</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
</DOC>