<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00765310</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see if a dietary supplement, R-alpha lipoic acid, is able to reduce risk factors such as body weight and high blood cholesterol levels in overweight or obese participants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lipoic Acid and Prevention of Heart Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to see if a dietary supplement, R-alpha lipoic acid, is able to reduce risk factors such as body weight and high blood cholesterol levels in overweight or obese participants. Recruitment will be in the Portland, Oregon area.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thioctic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1860 Overweight (BMI, 25.029.9 kg/m2) or obese (BMI, &gt;30 kg/m2); Elevated plasma triglycerides (100400 mg/dl); Weight stable for the last three months and at lifetime maximum; Exercise limited to 30 minutes 3 times a week or less; HsCRP level at baseline of ≤ 10 mg/L; Consuming ≤ 2 alcoholic drinks per day; Exclusion criteria: Pregnant, breastfeeding, or planning to become pregnant before the end of the study. Having had acute medical conditions, such as hospitalizations or surgeries, at least three months prior to entry into the study Diagnosed as having diabetes (fasting glucose &lt;125 mg/dl for entry), cardiovascular disease, congestive heart failure, angina, thyroid disorders, cancer, inflammatory disorders or renal, hepatic, or hematological abnormalities; Currently taking lipidlowering drugs, antihypertensive drugs, insulin , or oral hypoglycemic agents, antiinflammatory drugs, weight loss medications, or hormone replacement therapy; On an extreme diet and not maintaining a prudent diet; Currently taking vitamin or antioxidant supplements, including Ralpha lipoic acid, except standard multivitamin/mineral supplements containing not more than the Daily Value (DV) of the vitamins and minerals; Smoking within the last three months;</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>atherosclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>lipoic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>thioctic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>triglycerides</keyword>
	<keyword>overweight</keyword>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>oxidative stress</keyword>
	<keyword>inflammation</keyword>
</DOC>