<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00765063</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this 6 month open-label extension trial is to evaluate long-term safety and tolerability of dalteparin in treatment of chronic neuroischaemic foot ulcers in diabetic patients with peripheral arterial occlusive disease (PAOD) and peripheral neuropathy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect Of Fragmin In The Treatment Of Neuroischaemic Foot Ulcers In Diabetic Patients (A6301086)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Foot</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Foot Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arterial Occlusive Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dalteparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heparin, Low-Molecular-Weight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must have completed the 6 month study duration in the A6301083 study. Subjects must have a positive ulcer treatment response, defined as a reduction in the study ulcer area size (ie, ulcer area reduction &gt;0%) at Visit 8 (EOT Visit) from baseline in the A6301083 study. All ulcers must have an ulcer staging of 1C, 2C, 1D or 2D according to the University of Texas wound classification system Subjects who have the following: Intact skin healing (defined as 100% reduction in ulcer surface area with full epithelialisation at or prior to the EOT visit in the A6301083 study). A study ulcer area at Visit 8 (EOT visit) which is greater or equal to the baseline ulcer area (ie, ulcer area increase ≥0%) in the A6301083 study. Subjects with an ulcer grading of 0 or 3 or staging of A or B according to the University of Texas wound classification system. Subjects with a known bleeding disorder or evidence of active bleeding. Subjects who are on dialysis. Subjects who where found to be major protocol violators in A6301083 study. Subjects who did not complete the 6 month study period of the A6301083 study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetic Foot Ulcers Neuroischaemic</keyword>
</DOC>