<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00765765</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as ixabepilone, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Hydroxychloroquine may help ixabepilone work better by making tumor cells more sensitive to the drug. PURPOSE: This phase I/II trial is studying the side effects and best dose of ixabepilone given together with hydroxychloroquine and to see how well they work in treating patients with metastatic breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ixabepilone and Hydroxychloroquine in Treating Patients With Metastatic Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - The primary objective of this study is to assess the antitumor activity, measured by tumor response rate, in patients who receive this regimen as a third-line treatment. (Phase II) Secondary - To measure the duration of response for responding patients. - To measure the time to progressive disease. - To measure survival time. - To characterize the quantitative and qualitative toxicities of this regimen in these patients. - To develop pharmacodynamic markers for autophagy detection in patient specimens. - To characterize the effects of hydroxychloroquine on autophagy in patients in vivo. - To investigate whether the estrogen receptor, progesterone receptor, and/or HER2 status of breast tumors correlates with treatment response. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter, phase I dose-escalation study of ixabepilone followed by a phase II study. During the first course, patients receive ixabepilone IV over 3 hours on day 1 and oral hydroxychloroquine twice daily on days 3-21. On all subsequent courses, patients receive ixabepilone IV over 3 hours on day 1 and oral hydroxychloroquine twice daily on days 1-21. Treatment repeats every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study therapy, patients are followed every 6 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxychloroquine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epothilones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed breast cancer Histologic or cytologic elements can be established on metastatic tumor aspirate or biopsy Metastatic disease Measurable disease according to RECIST criteria Must have received 2 prior chemotherapy regimens for metastatic breast cancer Anthracyclineresistant (or treated with minimum cumulative doxorubicin dose of 240 mg/m^2 or epirubicin dose of 360 mg/m^2) and taxaneresistant disease Anthracycline resistance is defined as progression while on therapy or within 6 months in the adjuvant/neoadjuvant setting or 3 months in the metastatic setting Taxane resistance is defined as progression while on therapy or within 12 months in the adjuvant/neoadjuvant setting or 4 months in the metastatic setting Hormone receptor status known No known CNS metastases or previously treated and now stable CNS metastases PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Menopausal status not specified ECOG performance status 02 ANC ≥ 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL Total bilirubin ≤ upper limit of normal (ULN) If patient has Gilbert's disease, then patient must have isolated hyperbilirubinemia (e.g., no other liver function test abnormality), with maximum bilirubin ≤ 2 times ULN AST and ALT ≤ 2.5 times ULN, independently of liver metastases Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2.5 times ULN Creatinine ≤ 1.5 times ULN OR calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 60 mL/min Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception No other active malignancy History of basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix within the past 3 years allowed provided patient has been treated with curative intent History of prior malignancy allowed provided patient has been treated with curative intent and has been disease free &gt; 3 years None of the following conditions within the past 6 months: Myocardial infarction Stroke Symptomatic peripheral vascular disease No unstable angina or NYHA class IIIV congestive heart failure No history of psoriasis or porphyria No history of hypersensitivity to 4aminoquinoline compound No retinal or visual field changes from prior 4aminoquinolinecompound use No history of G6PD deficiency No GI pathology that would interfere with drug bioavailability No motor or sensory neuropathy ≥ grade 2 (NCI CTCAE) at study entry No serious uncontrolled medical disorder or active infection at study entry No rheumatoid arthritis or systemic lupus erythematosus requiring active treatment No history of HIV No history of any condition (social or medical) that, in the opinion of the investigator, might interfere with the patient's ability to comply with the protocol or pose additional or unacceptable risk to the patient PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics Prior radiation to tumor sites allowed provided: Radiation was completed ≥ 3 weeks prior to study treatment All radiationrelated toxicities have resolved to ≤ grade 1 No more than 3 prior chemotherapy regimens in the metastatic setting No prior ixabepilone or another epothilone No concurrent highly active antiretroviral therapy No other concurrent hydroxychloroquine for treatment or prophylaxis of malaria No other concurrent anticancer investigational or commercial agents or therapies</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IV breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>male breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>