<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00765726</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to collect safety information associated with the use of Xyntha in a usual care setting. Upon meeting eligibility criteria, patients will be required to have approximately 5 study visits over a 2 year period. Procedures completed throughout the study include collection of vital signs, physical exams, and laboratory assessments. Patients will be required to complete an infusion log for each Xyntha infusion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Evaluating The Safety Of Xyntha In Usual Care Settings</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study was terminated on May 12, 2011 due to poor enrollment prospects and the study's similarity to another ongoing trial with ReFacto AF. The termination of this study has no impact on subject safety or well being. The decision to terminate the trial was not based on any safety concerns.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Factor VIII</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male patients 12 years of age and older. Patients transitioned to Xyntha from other recombinant or plasmaderived FVIII replacement products. Treatment history of 150 or greater exposure days to any FVIII products prior to Enrollment visit. Negative inhibitor at screening or documentation of negative inhibitor titer within 6 weeks or less prior to study entry except for patients entering the study on immune tolerance induction therapy. Bleeding disorder other than hemophilia A. Inhibitor titer greater than or equal to 0.6 BU during screening except for patients on immune tolerance induction therapy. Immunomodulatory therapy during screening period. Known hypersensitivity to hamster protein.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>hemophilia</keyword>
	<keyword>hemophilia A</keyword>
	<keyword>ReFacto</keyword>
	<keyword>Xyntha</keyword>
	<keyword>moroctocog alfa</keyword>
	<keyword>bleeding disorder</keyword>
</DOC>