<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00066482</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Combining more than one drug may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: Phase I trial to study the effect on the body of combining cyclophosphamide with cisplatin, etoposide, and bleomycin in treating children who have newly diagnosed malignant germ cell tumors that are not in the brain and gonads.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination Chemotherapy in Treating Children With Newly Diagnosed Malignant Germ Cell Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the maximum tolerated dose and toxicity profile of cyclophosphamide in combination with bleomycin, etoposide, and cisplatin in pediatric patients with newly diagnosed high-risk extracranial, extragonadal malignant germ cell tumors. - Determine the response rate in patients treated with this regimen. OUTLINE: This is a pilot, multicenter, dose-escalation study of cyclophosphamide. - Induction therapy: Patients receive bleomycin IV over 10-20 minutes on day 1, etoposide IV over 1 hour and cisplatin IV over 4 hours on days 1-5, and cyclophosphamide IV over 1 hour on day 1. Patients also receive filgrastim (G-CSF) subcutaneously once daily beginning on day 6 and continuing until blood counts recover. Treatment repeats every 21 days for 4 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Cohorts of 6 patients receive escalating doses of cyclophosphamide until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose preceding that at which 2 of 6 patients experience dose-limiting toxicity. Patients are evaluated after 4 courses of therapy. Patients with partial response or stable disease undergo second-look surgery, receive 2 more courses of induction therapy, and are then re-evaluated. Patients who do not achieve complete response (CR) after a total of 6 courses may undergo a third surgery. Patients who still have tumor that cannot be removed are removed from study therapy. Patients who achieve a CR at anytime are followed. Patients are followed monthly for 1 year, every 6 months for 1 year, and then annually for 3 years. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 6-18 patients will be accrued for this study within 1.3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Germ Cell and Embryonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bleomycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenograstim</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mesna</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed newly diagnosed extracranial germ cell tumors, including 1 of the following types: Yolk sac carcinoma (endodermal sinus tumor) Embryonal carcinoma Choriocarcinoma Teratoma with mixed malignant elements (malignant teratoma) Highrisk disease, defined as stage III or IV extragonadal germ cell tumors Must be enrolled on study within 21 days of diagnostic surgical procedure PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 21 and under (at original diagnosis) Performance status ECOG 02 Karnofsky 50100% (in patients over 16 years of age) Lansky 50100% (in patients 16 years of age and under) Life expectancy At least 2 months Hematopoietic Absolute neutrophil count at least 1,000/mm^3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm^3 (transfusion independent) Hemoglobin at least 10.0 g/dL (transfusion allowed) Hepatic Not specified Renal Creatinine clearance or radioisotope glomerular filtration rate at least 70 mL/min OR Creatinine based on age as follows: No greater than 0.8 mg/dL (5 years and under) No greater than 1.0 mg/dL (610 years) No greater than 1.2 mg/dL (1115 years) No greater than 1.5 mg/dL (over 15 years) Pulmonary FEV_1/FVC greater than 60% OR Children who are uncooperative must meet all of the following criteria: No dyspnea at rest No exercise intolerance Pulse oximetry greater than 94% Other Not pregnant or nursing Fertile patients must use effective contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy Not specified Chemotherapy No prior chemotherapy Endocrine therapy Not specified Radiotherapy No prior radiotherapy Surgery See Disease Characteristics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>childhood teratoma</keyword>
	<keyword>childhood extragonadal germ cell tumor</keyword>
</DOC>