<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00066222</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Radiation therapy uses high-energy x-rays to damage tumor cells. Combining more than one chemotherapy drug with radiation therapy may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well giving cisplatin and etoposide together with radiation therapy works in treating patients with limited-stage small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cisplatin, Etoposide, and Radiation Therapy in Treating Patients With Limited-Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the response rate of patients with limited stage small cell lung cancer treated with cisplatin and etoposide combined with accelerated high-dose thoracic radiotherapy. - Determine the progression-free and overall survival in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the qualitative and quantitative toxicity and reversibility of toxicity of this regimen in these patients. OUTLINE: Patients undergo radiotherapy once daily 5 days a week for approximately 3 weeks and then twice daily 5 days a week for approximately 2 weeks (a total of 9 treatment days during the final 2-week treatment period). Beginning on the first day of radiotherapy, patients receive cisplatin IV over 2 hours and etoposide IV over 1 hour on day 1 and oral etoposide once daily on days 2 and 3. Chemotherapy repeats every 3 weeks for up to 4 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients are followed every 3 months for 1 year, every 6 months for 2 years, and then annually thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 71 patients will be accrued for this study within 18 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed small cell carcinoma of the lung by fine needle aspiration biopsy or two positive sputa Must have limited disease Stage I, II, IIIA, or IIIB Confined to 1 hemithorax, but excluding the following: T4 tumor based on malignant pleural effusion N3 disease based on contralateral hilar or contralateral supraclavicular involvement No pericardial or pleural effusions on chest xray (regardless of cytology) Measurable or evaluable disease Tumor must be able to be encompassed by limited radiotherapy fields without significantly compromising pulmonary function No prior complete tumor resection PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 18 to 100 Performance status Zubrod 01 Life expectancy Not specified Hematopoietic Absolute granulocyte count at least 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count at least 150,000/mm^3 Hepatic Bilirubin no greater than 1.5 mg/dL Renal Creatinine no greater than 1.5 mg/dL Cardiovascular No myocardial infarction within the past 6 months No symptomatic heart disease Pulmonary No chronic obstructive pulmonary disease with Forced Expiratory Volume (FEV)1 no greater than 0.8 liter No uncontrolled bronchospasm in the unaffected lung Other Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception Available for followup No other malignancy within the past 2 years except curatively treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer or noninvasive in situ malignancies No other concurrent serious medical illness No uncontrolled psychiatric illness No chronic alcohol or drug abuse PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy Not specified Chemotherapy No prior chemotherapy Endocrine therapy Not specified Radiotherapy No prior radiotherapy to the chest or other area containing a large amount of bone marrow (e.g., more than 75% of pelvic bone) Surgery See Disease Characteristics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>limited stage small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>