<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02670525</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research study is seeking to gain new knowledge about Recurrent, Refractory, or High Risk Leukemias in children and young adults. This study is evaluating the use of specialized testing called leukemia profiling. Once the profiling is performed, the results are evaluated by an expert panel of physicians, scientists and pharmacists. This may result in a recommendation for a specific cancer therapy or a clinical trial called matched targeted therapy (MTT). The results of the leukemia profiling and, if applicable, the MTT recommendation will be communicated to the participant's primary oncologist.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Matched Targeted Therapy For High-Risk Leukemias</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will determine whether it is possible to use profiling results and determine a matched targeted therapy for patients with leukemia. It will describe the range of mutations found in patients with leukemia with this type of profiling, and describe the clinical outcomes of patients who receive a matched targeted therapy. Our tissues and organs are made up of cells. Cancer occurs when the molecules that normally control cell growth are damaged. The damage results in unchecked cell growth which causes a tumor, a collection of cancer cells. The damage is referred to as an alteration. There are different types of cancer-causing alterations. Genes are the part of cells that contain the instructions which tell our cells how to make the right proteins to grow and work. Genes are composed of DNA letters that spell out these instructions. By participating in this study, the participant's leukemia cells will be tested for cancer causing alterations. This testing is called leukemia profiling. The leukemia profiling will be performed using bone marrow or blood that has already been obtained during a clinical test. Alternately, the profiling may be done on leukemia cells that are planned to be obtained as part of routine clinical care.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≤ 30 years at study entry Diagnosis: Patients will be enrolled in one of the two cohorts based on diagnosis: Cohort 1: Relapsed/refractory leukemia Acute lymphoblastic leukemia, first or greater relapse Acute myeloid leukemia, first or greater relapse Leukemia refractory to induction chemotherapy Other recurrent leukemia Cohort 2: New diagnosis Acute myeloid leukemia, new diagnosis (excluding acute promyelocytic leukemia (APL)) New diagnosis infant MLLrearranged ALL or low hypodiploid (&lt;40 chromosomes) ALL Rare leukemia e.g., JMML, leukemia of ambiguous lineage Secondary leukemia Pathologic Criteria Histologic confirmation of leukemia at the time of diagnosis or recurrence Specimen Samples Sufficient leukemia specimen available for profiling from diagnosis or recurrence OR bone marrow aspirate/blood draw/pheresis/other fresh sample of patient leukemia cells planned for clinical care anticipated to allow collection of minimum specimen for testing. Insufficient leukemia specimen available for profiling from diagnosis or recurrence; or bone marrow evaluation/blood draw/other leukemia cell sample NOT planned to be obtained for clinical care; or peripheral blast percentage &lt;20% AND clinical blood draw not planned.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Recurrent, Refractory, or High Risk Leukemias</keyword>
	<keyword>Matched targeted therapy</keyword>
</DOC>