<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02477202</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Combination-type oral contraceptives (COCs) have been shown to significantly reduce the risk of invasive epithelial ovarian cancer (IEOC); this protective effect may be achieved to a large extent through COCs ability to reduce cell proliferation in the fallopian tube fimbriae (FTF). The progestin-releasing Mirena® intra-uterine device (IUD) is an increasingly popular method of contraception, but it is not known if its use will reduce a woman's risk of IEOC. Mirena® use does not block ovulation in most women but it may release sufficient progestin to also reduce cell proliferation in the FTF. This study aims to evaluate the effects of the Mirena® IUD on cell proliferation in the FTF as a possible biomarker of protection against IEOC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mirena® IUD's Effect on Fallopian Tube Fimbriae and Ovarian Cortical Inclusion Cyst Cell Proliferation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Glandular and Epithelial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levonorgestrel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women between 35 and 50 years of age (inclusive) Women who will be scheduled to undergo an RRSO or RRs Women who will have at least one fallopian tube removed for riskreducing reasons (with or without removal of ovar(ies)) Women who are willing to have a Mirena® IUD inserted at least prior to riskreducing surgery or who already have the Mirena® in place Women using nonhormonal forms of contraception (Note: If a copper IUD is being used, the IUD must be removed prior to or at time of Mirena insertion.) Any medical contraindication to use of a Mirena® IUD, including: Pregnancy (a pregnancy test is required prior to study entry) Known uterine anomaly that distorts the shape of the uterine cavity Acute pelvic inflammatory disease Postpartum endometritis or endometrial infection Known or suspected uterine or cervical neoplasia Known history or suspected breast cancer or other progestinsensitive cancer Uterine bleeding of unknown etiology. Untreated acute cervicitis, vaginitis, or other lower genital tract infections Acute liver disease or liver tumor (benign or malignant) Use of tamoxifen, raloxifene, or chemotherapy within the previous 6 months Positive pregnancy test Breastfeeding Use of a copper IUD if the patient is not willing to have it removed prior to surgery and replaced with a Mirena® IUD</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mirena® IUD's</keyword>
	<keyword>Women</keyword>
	<keyword>risk-reducing salpingo-oophorectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>risk-reducing salpingectomy</keyword>
</DOC>