<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02381054</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see if the Italian language version of a questionnaire about symptoms that patients may have during cancer treatment is understandable to Italian speaking patients. The questionnaire is called the PRO-CTCAE, and was originally developed at the U.S. National Cancer Institute to help get information about patients' symptoms directly from the patients themselves. The Italian version of the questionnaire will be used in future studies to gain a better understanding of patient symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Translation, Cross-cultural Adaptation and Validation of PRO-CTCAE for Italian-speaking Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will be conducted in two steps. The first is the Italian translation and cross cultural adaptation of the original US NCI's version of the PRO-CTCAE questionnaire. The questionnaire will be translated and administered to a sample of 96 Italian patients. The second step is the validation of the Italian language version of the PRO-CTCAE questionnaire that was developed in the first step, and in this phase 300 Italian patients will be enrolled.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Eligibility Criteria for crosscultural adaption phase: Inclusion criteria: patients receiving (or who have received within 6 months) chemotherapy or radiotherapy with curative or palliative intent for an advanced cancer at one of the study sites ≥18 years of age able to speak and understand Italian providing written informed consent Exclusion criteria: • Patients judged unable to report on their symptoms from the last seven days due to cognitive impairment. Eligibility Criteria for Validation phase: ≥18 years of age. Patient is able and agrees to return to clinic the following day. Patient is actively receiving treatment for cancer diagnosis Disease and treatment matching 1 of the 6 following cohorts: Cohort Breast: Breast cancer patients who are still on treatment and have already received at least one cycle of adjuvant chemotherapy Cohort Lymphoma/Myeloma: Lymphoma/myeloma patients who are still on treatment and have already received at least one cycle of chemotherapy. Cohort Prostate/Bladder: Metastatic prostate or bladder cancer patients who are still on treatment and have already received at least one cycle of chemotherapy. Cohort Lung: Metastatic lung cancer patients EITHER: who are still on treatment and have already received at least one cycle of chemotherapy or biotherapy (eg. EGFRTKI) ; OR: who have received daily radiation therapy lasting at least 28 days (concurrent chemotherapy is allowed and radiation therapy should have ended not more than 4 weeks before) Cohort Colorectal: Metastatic colorectal cancer patients who are still on treatment and have already received at least one cycle of chemotherapy (with or without associated biologic agents) Cohort Head/Neck/Gastroesophageal: Head/neck/gastroesophageal cancer patients who who have received daily radiation therapy lasting at least 28 days (concurrent chemotherapy is allowed and radiation therapy should have ended not more than 4 weeks before) Able to complete questionnaire by themselves or with assistance. Providing informed written consent. Able to speak and understand Italian Clinically significant cognitive or memory impairment in the opinion of clinical or research staff. Other important acute medical conditions.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Patient reported outcomes</keyword>
</DOC>