<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02931734</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is through a randomized clinical trial, double blind, splith-mouth, evaluate the various types of protocols and clinical efficacy in the reduction or even elimination of dentinal hypersensitivity by the agents Desensibilize KF - FGM Dental Products, Clinpro - 3M Company, Minnesota - USA, Photon Laser III - DMC, Brazil, Desensibilize KF and laser, Desensibilize KF and Clinpro, laser and Clinpro and the association of all products. Data will be collected, tabulated and submitted to statistical analysis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of Different Protocols for Cervical Dentin Hypersensitivity Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cervical dentin hypersensitivity is a painful condition and is a clinical challenge due to different treatment strategies available. The aim of this study is through a randomized clinical trial, double blind, splith-mouth, evaluate the various types of protocols and clinical efficacy in the reduction or even elimination of dentinal hypersensitivity. A hundred forty teeth of healthy patients of both sexes were selected. Visual Analog Scale was used pain (VAS) to measure the intensity of the patient's pain. The teeth will be randomly divided into 7 different groups according to the desensitization treatment under study: Desensibilize KF - FGM Dental Products, Clinpro - 3M Company, Minnesota - USA, Photon Laser III - DMC, Brazil, Desensibilize KF and laser, Desensibilize KF and Clinpro, laser and Clinpro and the association of all products. Data will be collected, tabulated and submitted to statistical analysis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dentin Sensitivity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>presence of dentin exposure lesions with clinical diagnosis of moderate or severe tooth sensitivity good oral hygiene. cavities, presence of periodontal disease and or parafunctional habits, cracks or enamel fractures, extensive or unsatisfactory restorations, recent restorations involving the labial surface, dentures, orthodontics.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>