<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02931071</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Fanconi anemia (FA) is a congenital disease characterized by bone marrow failure and increased incidence of malignant tumors. The Project pursue the optimization of the collection of hematopoietic progenitor cells for later use in another clinical trial entitled "Clinical Trial Phase I/II to evaluate the safety and efficacy of the infusion of autologous CD34+ cells mobilized with mozobil and filgrastim, and transduced with a lentiviral vector carrying the FANCA gene (Orphan Drug) for patients with Fanconi Anemia Subtype A ". The objectives of this study are, therefore, to assess the safety and efficacy of CD34+ cells mobilization with mozobil and filgrastim, which is postulated the most efficient for the collection of CD34+ cells from FA patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Phase II Trial to Evaluate CD34+ Cells Mobilization and Collection in Patients With Fanconi Anemia for Subsequent Transduction With a Lentiviral Vector Carring FANCA Gene. FANCOSTEM-1</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fanconi Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fanconi Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>JM 3100</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenograstim</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female &gt; 1 year diagnosed of Fanconi's anemia confirmed by instability chromosomal test with diepoxybutane or mitomycin C At least one of the following parameters must be higher than these values: Hemoglobin:8,0 g/dL; neutrophils: 750/mm3; platelets: 30.000/mm3 Lansky index&gt; 60%. Left ventricular ejection fraction &gt;50%. To grant informed consent in agreement with current law norms Women in childbearing age must obtain a negative result in the pregnancy test in serum or urine in the visit of selection and accept the use of suitable contraceptive methods since at least 14 days prior to the first dose of mobilizing treatment until the 14 days following the last Evidence of myelodysplastic syndromes or leukemia, or cytogenetic abnormalities predicted of these syndromes in bone marrow aspiration. Cytogenetic analyses performed 2 months before starting study are accepted Patients with active infection process or any other underlaying severe medical process Severe Functional alteration of organs (hepatic, renal, respiratory)(?3), according to National Cancer Institute (NCI CTCAE v3) criteria Haematopoietic transplant Any disease or concomitant process that is not compatible with the study as per investigator opinion Patients not elegible because of an psicosocial evaluation Patients that received transfusional support during the last 3 months. Pregnant or breastfeeding women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>