<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02701166</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Randomized double blind placebo controlled trial to evaluate the antipruritic effect of bezafibrate in patients with moderate to severe cholestatic itch.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Bezafibrate on Cholestatic Itch</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cholangitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholangitis, Sclerosing</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bezafibrate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>diagnosis of primary biliary cholangitis or primary/secondary sclerosing cholangitis as defined by EASL clinical practice guidelines of cholestasis 2009; itch without primary dermatologic abnormalities and with an intensity score of ≥ 5.0 cm on a scale from 0.0 cm (no itch) to 10.0 cm (worst itch possible), scored twice in the week before inclusion. Concomitant guidelinerecommended as well as experimental antipruritic therapy, e.g. rifampicin, opioidreceptor antagonists (naltrexon, naloxone), serotoninreuptake inhibitors (sertraline), ondansetron, phenobarbital, propofol, lidocaine, dronabinol, butorphanol, internal or external biliary drainage, extracorporeal albumin dialysis, ultravioletB phototherapy; NB. Topical menthol containing agents are allowed, as well as bile salt sequestrants (colesevelam, cholestyramin) as long as taken at least 4 hours before or after intake of the study medication. Incidental use of these agents should be noted by patients in the diary, structural use should be noted on the CRF (section comedication); Pregnancy, women of childbearing potential not using contraception, breast feeding; Cholestasis due to obstruction that requires invasive desobstructive treatment within the time scope of the study (5 weeks), such as endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreaticography (ERCP) or surgical removal of a tumor compressing the bile duct; Use of opiates; Renal insufficiency (creatinine clearance &lt;60mL/min).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pruritus</keyword>
	<keyword>itch</keyword>
	<keyword>cholestasis</keyword>
</DOC>