<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03064243</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Apatinib is a kind of innovative medicines approved by China Food and Drug Administration（CFDA）, which was researched by Jiangsu Hengrui Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Apatinib is a kinase inhibitor of receptor tyrosine with VEGFR2. The protocol is to explore Apatinib for the effectiveness of advanced soft tissue sarcoma and safety.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase II Study of Apatinib in STS Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed informed consent. Histologically proven advanced soft tissue sarcoma, At least one measurable lesion. Including: Synovial sarcoma, leiomyosarcoma, Alveolar soft part sarcoma, Undifferentiated pleomorphic sarcoma / malignant fibrous histiocytoma, Liposarcoma, Fibrosarcoma, Clear cell sarcoma, Epithelioid sarcoma, Angiosarcoma, Spindle cell sarcoma, rhabdomyosarcoma treated by chemotherapy, Ewing's sarcoma of soft tissue/Primitive neuroectodermal tumor. Excluding: Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor, chondrosarcoma, Dermatofibrosarcoma protuberans, Gastrointestinal stromal tumor, Inflammatory myofibroblastic sarcoma, Malignant mesothelioma. Must have evidence of unresectable residual disease. In the last 6 months, at least one chemotherapy regimen (including anthracyclines) was used in patients who failed or were unable to tolerate treatment. ECOG ps≤2. Life expectancy: more than 3 months. Prior aptinib less than 2 weeks and at least 1 month since prior aptinib；at least 1 month since prior inhibitor of mTOR or EGFR pathway. Not pregnant or nursing；Fertile patients must use effective contraception. Hematopoietic HB≥90g/L Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 80,000/mm^3 Uncontrollable hypertension; Has influence of oral drugs; Patients with high risk of gastrointestinal blooding; INR&gt;1.5×ULN，APTT&gt;1.5×ULN; Allergic to any ingredient of this product; Less than 1 month since last major surgery; Brain metastases; With the second cancer.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>