<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03064932</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a randomized 3-period crossover, controlled feeding study designed to evaluate the effects of the most commonly consumed spices in the U.S. on CVD risk factors, inflammation &amp; immune function, and diet satisfaction in participants at risk for CVD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of a Spice Blend on Cardiovascular Risk Factors and Diet Satisfaction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A 3-period randomized crossover controlled-feeding study will be conducted. Participants will be randomly assigned to receive each 4-week treatment (diet) in random order. Each test diet period will be separated by a standard 4-week compliance break. Data collection will be conducted across at baseline (start of study) and the end of each diet period to assess the effects of chronic spice consumption on selected cardiovascular endpoints.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>overweight or obese (2535kg/m2) nonsmoking male or female waist circumference &gt;= 94cm for men and &gt;=80cm for women at least one other of the following: LDL cholesterol &gt;130mg/dL; CRP &gt;1mg/L; triglycerides &gt;=150mg/dL; HDL &lt;40mg/dL for men or &lt;50mg/dL for women; systolic blood pressure &gt;= 130mmHg or diastolic &gt;= 85mmHg; fasting glucose &gt;=100mg/dL diabetes (fasting glucose &gt;126mg/dL) hypertension (systolic blood pressure &gt;160mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;100mmHg) prescribed antihypertensive or glucose lowering drugs established cardiovascular disease, stroke, diabetes, liver, kidney or autoimmune disease use of cholesterol/lipid lowering medication or supplementation (psyllium, fish oil, soy lecithin, phytoestrogens) and botanicals pregnancy or lactation weight loss of &gt;=10% of body weight within the 6 months prior to enrolling in the study vegetarianism</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>