<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03064516</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objective: To evaluate the immediate and mediate outcomes of endocrowns and onlay ceramic restorations with glass fiber pin in endodontically treated teeth. Material and methods: A randomized controlled clinical trial, a double-blind (patient and examiner) is conducted by two trained and calibrated operators who perform all restorative procedures. The restorations are evaluated longitudinally by a blind and calibrated examiner using the USPHS. A total of 34 patients will be randomly assigned to each group for a total of 68 patients. The randomization sequence will be generated (www.sealedenvelope.com) and to ensure the confidentiality of the allocation, this will be used opaque, sealed and numbered envelopes in series. These will be kept with an independent researcher for the moment of inclusion of the subjects. In the group of onlays, the teeth receive a fiberglass pin in the main root canal and composite resin filling. In the group of endocrown, only the restoration fill the pulp chamber. The parts are milled in IPS e-max CAD (Ivoclar Vivadent) and cemented with the Multilink cementation system (Ivoclar Vivadent). The immediate clinical (focused in restoration and patient) and mediate (radiographic and clinical) outcomes will be compared between the groups. Survival and success rates will be defined in 6, 12 and 24 months. Survival will be established by Kaplan-Meier survival curve and log-rank can be conducted to identify as variables associated with as failures over time. Multivariate analysis with the Cox regression models will be condutcted for the determination of failure predictors. For all analyzes, the significance value will be adjusted to 5%.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Endocrowns vs.Ceramic Onlays Used in Endodontically Treated Teeth- Randomized Clinical Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Tooth, Nonvital</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Presence of molars or pre molars with endodontic treatment with at least 1 face (buccal or lingual) or 1 cusp with adequate thickness of 3 mm; 2. Presence of opposing teeth and normal occlusion; 3. Supragingival margin after preparation; 4. Volunteers with good oral hygiene (no active caries, gingivitis, periodontal disease or any other disease in the soft or hard tissues of the oral cavity); 5. The selected teeth should not present restorations, cracks, hypoplasias or caries lesions in the adjacent remaining faces; 6. Not being in orthodontic treatment; 7. Be at least 18 years old. 1. Patients will be excluded with special needs, using orthodontics devices and / or systemic diseases which may affect the oral cavity; 2. Teeth that undergo radiographic or clinical examination with painful symptomatology, unsatisfactory endodontic treatment, mobility, presence of abscess or fistula next to the tooth, teeth with restorations, sealants or enamel formation defects or signs of periapical alteration will also be excluded; 4) Volunteers smokers and pregnant women; 5) Volunteers without agenda compatible with the research schedule.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>