<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02221687</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to demonstrate that a synbiotic formula, fed for the duration of the first year of life (infant and follow-on formula) reduces the incidence rate of episodes of infectious diarrhea in infants during the first year of life compared to a standard infant formula.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Combiotic-Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Healthy term infants Female or male gender Gestational age between 37 and 41 weeks completed (= 41 weeks + 6 days) Age at time of V1 visit : 4 +/ 7 days Birth weight between 2500 ans 4200g, with regular weight gain (≥ 150g / week) Two legal representatives (parent(s) / guardian(s)) who are capable of and willing to comply with the protocol and have signed the informed consent in accordance with legal requirements. at least one of the legal representatives is affiliated to with a social security scheme. Additionnaly , criteria of inclusion in one of the formulafed groups or in the breastfed group, respectively, are the following: To be included in one of the formula arm, infants will have to be exclusively formulafed (no breast milk meal) at the time of V1 visit (randomization). or To be included in the breastfeeding arm, infants will have to be exclusively breastfed (no more than one formula meal per day) at V1 visit (randomization) and its mother will have to be willing to pursue exclusive breastfeeding at least until the infant will be 4month old. Intensive care during at least the first 14 days of life Neonatal health problems, such as: respiratory distress, asphyxia, hypoglycemia, sepsis, NEC (necrotizing enterocolitis),... Clinical evidence of chronic illness or gastrointestinal disorders such as : GER (Gastrooesophageal Reflux), gastroenteritis,... Known metabolic disorders, such as diabetes, lactose intolerance,.... Known immune deficiency Subjects recommended to receive formula with hydrolized protein (e.g. children with allergy risk) Subject under oral antibiotic treatment at V1 visit Participation in another biomedical study Whose legal representatives have psychological or linguistic incapability to sign the informed consent form Reasons to presume that parents are unable to meet the study plan requirements (e.g. impossibility to contact study representatives in case of emergency, drug addiction etc)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>5 Weeks</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>synbiotic formula</keyword>
	<keyword>infant formula</keyword>
	<keyword>diarrhea</keyword>
</DOC>