<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02221440</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Supplementary oxygen is routinely administered to patients, even those with adequate oxygen saturations, in the belief that it increases oxygen delivery. However, oxygen delivery depends not just on arterial oxygen content but also on perfusion. Maternal oxygen administration has been used in an attempt to lessen fetal distress by increasing the available oxygen from the mother. However, the effect of supplemental maternal oxygen therapy on fetal acid base status has been debated for more than seven decades. Hypothesis: Prophylactic maternal low flow nasal oxygen administration during the second stage of labor can relieve fetal distress.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Maternal Oxygen Administration for Fetal Distress</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A report from the cochran library (Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012 Dec 12;12:CD000136.): Too little evidence to show whether oxygen administration to the woman during labour is beneficial to the baby. Some babies show signs of distress, such as unusual heart rates or the passing of a bowel motion (meconium) during their mother's labour. This may be caused by a lack of oxygen passing from the woman to the baby through the placenta. Sometimes, women may be encouraged to breathe extra oxygen through a facemask (oxygen administration) to increase the oxygen available to the unborn baby. A review of two trials found too little evidence to show whether oxygen administration to the woman during the second stage of labour is beneficial to the baby. No trials of oxygen administration when the baby is showing signs of distress were found. Further research is needed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fetal Distress</mesh_term>
	<criteria>at term singleton primigraida cephalic presentation spontaneous or induced labor normal labor normal FHR tracings in the first stage at the onset of second stage respiratory disease cardiovascular disease diabetes mellitus or insulintreated gestational diabetes mellitus hypertension or preeclampsia oligohydramnios fetal growth restriction placental abruption anemia disorders in oxygen saturations received oxygen therapy in the first stage</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>