<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02221505</DOC>
	<brief_summary>LOP628 is an antibody-drug conjugate (ADC) consisting of an anti-cKit humanized IgG1/κ antibody conjugated to a maytansine payload via a non-cleavable linker. LOP628 provides an opportunity to target cKit overexpressing tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 1 Study of LOP628 in Adult Patients With cKit-positive Solid Tumors and Acute Myeloid Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For patients with solid tumors: documented cKitpositive neoplasms Patient must have progressive disease as defined by any of the following: SCLC: patient has progressed after at least 1 prior therapy GIST : patient has relapsed or has refractory disease, and no further approved effective therapeutic option exists Patients with other cKitpositive solid tumors: patient has progressed after at least one prior line of therapy and no further approved effective therapeutic option exists Patient has measurable disease as per RECIST v1.1 criteria For patients with AML: documented cKitpositive acute myelogenous leukemia Consent to newly obtained bone marrow aspirate Patient must have progressive disease defined as relapsed or refractory nonPML AML following standard therapy or for whom no effective therapy exists. Blast count &lt; 50,000/mm3 For patients with solid tumors: Patient has central nervous system (CNS) metastatic involvement unless the CNS metastases have been previously treated and the patient is clinically stable and on a stable dose of corticosteroids for at least 4 weeks prior to enrollment. Patient has the presence of other clinically significant hematologic, cardiac, respiratory, gastrointestinal, renal, hepatic or neurological conditions. Patient has a history of serious allergic reactions, which in the opinion of the investigator may pose an increased risk of serious infusion reactions Patient has been previously treated with cKit directed antibodies Pregnant or nursing women For patients with AML: Patient has received prior allogeneic bone marrow transplant (BMT). Patient has the presence of other clinically significant cardiac, respiratory, gastrointestinal, renal, hepatic or neurological disease Patient has a history of serious allergic reactions, which in the opinion of the investigator may pose an increased risk of serious infusion reactions Patient has been previously treated with cKit directed antibodies Pregnant or nursing women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>LOP628,</keyword>
	<keyword>cKit,</keyword>
	<keyword>ADC,</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibody drug conjugates,</keyword>
	<keyword>maytansine</keyword>
</DOC>