<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02221986</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The results of the present RCT study will add to the growing body of literature investigating the potential role of exercise as a supportive therapeutic intervention for patient with glioma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Interdisciplinary Specialised Rehabilitation Among Glioma Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Gliomas are the most frequent primary neoplasm in the CNS and according to the World Health Organization histologically categorized into low-grade glioma (LGG) (WHO grades I/II) or high-grade glioma (HGG) (WHO grades III/IV). Gliomas are among the biggest challenges within the field of neuro-rehabilitation and oncology, and optimising treatment by improving QoL, function and cognition is of major clinical importance in this population. Because the majority of patients cannot be cured, clinical cancer research traditionally have focused on prolonging survival, exposing relapse or optimising the response to the medical treatment. Today there is a general consensus that health-related quality of life (HRQoL) is important in the evaluation of new treatments. However, research in HRQoL among patients with gliomas is scarce compared to the other categories of patients with tumors. In recent years have exercise become an important part of cancer treatment. The effects is well documented in studies among other cancer patients than gliomas and includes improvements of quality of life, physical function, reduce fatigue and thereby supports daily activities among cancer patients'. Inpatient rehabilitation studies among glioma patients have also indicated improved HRQoL and functional measurements such as activity of daily life, mobility and cognition. Despite of this rehabilitation efforts is still not emphasized in this population and recent literature concludes that there are no well-designed clinical studies examining the effect of multidisciplinary rehabilitation among Glioma patients. This study is the first to investigate the effect of an intensive specialised interdisciplinary outpatient rehabilitation program among gliomas patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of primary glioma (WHO grades IIV) Age ≥ 18 Reference with diagnosis or treatment at Odense University Hospital Karnofsky performance score (KPS) ≥70 Ability to understand Danish. Pregnancy Known psychiatric diagnosis or substance abuse Heart problems excluding intense exercise (NYHA group III and IV) Pronounced impressive/expressive aphasia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Interdisciplinary rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurooncology</keyword>
	<keyword>Physiotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Occupational therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurorehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Glioma</keyword>
</DOC>