<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02221882</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety of a study drug known as LY3164530 in participants with cancer that is advanced and/or has spread to another part(s) of the body.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of LY3164530 in Participants With Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Have advanced or metastatic cancer and be an appropriate candidate for experimental therapy. Have adequate organ function. Prior Treatments: Systemic treatments: Must have discontinued previous systemic treatments for cancer and recovered from the acute effects of therapy. Participants must have discontinued: Cytotoxic therapies or targeted agents that are small molecule inhibitors for 5 halflives or at least 28 days. MitomycinC or nitrosourea therapy for at least 42 days and biologic agents for at least 28 days. Radiation therapy and surgery must be completed 4 weeks prior to therapy, except for limited field radiation therapy, which must be completed 2 weeks before therapy. If participant is of reproductive potential, must agree to use medically approved contraceptive precautions during the study and for three months following the last dose of study drug. If the participant is a female of childbearing potential, must have had a negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 14 days of the first dose of study drug and must not be breast feeding. Must not have taken an unapproved drug as treatment for any indication within the last 28 days prior to starting study treatment. Must not have an active symptomatic fungal, bacterial or viral infection, including human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or Hepatitis A, B, or C. Must not have a serious preexisting medical conditions or concomitant disorders. Must not have leukemia. Must not have QT interval of &gt;470 millisecond. Must not have a serious cardiac condition, such as congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, or heart attack within the last 3 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>