<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01977326</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this randomised controlled trial (RCT) is to determine the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of a task sharing counseling intervention for maternal depression in South Africa(i.e. provided by non-specialist health workers)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Task Sharing Counseling Intervention by Community Health Workers for Prenatal Depression in South Africa</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Specific Objectives: 1. To determine the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of task sharing care to community health workers (CHWs), compared to enhanced usual care in South Africa, on both primary outcome measures (severity of prenatal maternal depression symptoms) and on a series of secondary outcome measures (functional status, health care utilization, social support and postnatal infant growth). 2. To examine factors influencing the implementation of the task sharing intervention and future scale up, by assessing feasibility, sustainability, quality, and safety, and by qualitative exploration of the experience of task sharing from the perspectives of both CHWs and patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression, Postpartum</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Women attending antenatal clinics at the Michael Mapongwana Community Health Centre in Khayelitsha, presenting for their first booking appointment, no later than 28 weeks gestation 2. Living in Khayelitsha 3. 18 years or older 4. Screen positive for depression with a cut off of 13 or more on the EPDS 5. Able to give informed consent Require urgent medical attention or have severe mental health problems, defined as a diagnosis of schizophrenia, bipolar mood disorder, or currently experiencing an episode of psychosis. Women who do not speak isiXhosa as a first language</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>task sharing</keyword>
	<keyword>task shifting</keyword>
	<keyword>prenatal depression</keyword>
	<keyword>counselling</keyword>
	<keyword>lay health workers</keyword>
</DOC>