<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01977183</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical trial is to study the effects of potato resistant starch on the microbiota (microorganisms or bacteria) and short chain fatty acids levels of the gut. Levels will be measured and compared between elderly adults and in pre-elderly, adults from the general public. A correlation between the use of potato resistant starch and specific clinical and quality of life endpoints between elderly adults and in pre-elderly, adults from the general public will be studied. Hypothesis 1: The investigator hypothesizes that the microbiome in elderly adults (≥70 years) is less diverse and more prone to imbalance compared to adults (30-50 years) from the general population and that this imbalance of the gut microflora in the elderly adults is partially related to inadequate RS in their diet. Hypothesis 2: The investigator hypothesizes that ingestion of potato resistant starch of food grade quality (MSPrebiotic) will stabilize the gut microbiome (i.e. high Firmicutes/Bacteroides ratio)in LTC residents (i.e. similar to that of adults from the general population), thereby improving gut health and reducing the risk of diarrhea and/or gut infection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of MSPrebiotic on Gut Health in the Elderly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To assess the impact on the potato resistant starch on the microbiota, pyrosequencing will be performed on stool samples to determine the original composition and assess any changes over the study period. In addition the impact of the potato resistant starch on inflammatory markers will be assess through blood samples collected over the study period.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Ability to provide written informed consent Willing to provide stool and blood specimens 5 times over the 14 week study period Subjects ≥ 70 years of age Subjects 3050 years of age Pregnancy Crohn's disease or any other inflammatory bowel disease Individuals with Lupus, or on cancer chemotherapy Prediabetes or Diabetes Thyroid disease Renal disease Hepatic disease Previous gastrointestinal surgery (intestinal resection, gastric bypass, colorectal surgery) Subjects on probiotic Subjects on antibiotics at time of recruitment or on antibiotics within the previous five weeks Individuals experiencing dysphagia Subjects using additional fiber supplements Subjects on digestants, emetics and antiemetics, medications for acid peptic disease and antacids.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>gastrointestinal</keyword>
	<keyword>microbiome</keyword>
	<keyword>prebiotic</keyword>
	<keyword>starch</keyword>
</DOC>