<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="34656">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02655419</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D4910C00009</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02655419</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Determine the PK and Safety and Tolerability of ATM-AVI for the Treatment of cIAIs in Hospitalized Adults</brief_title>
  <acronym>REJUVENATE</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase IIa Prospective, Open-label, Multicenter Study to Determine the Pharmacokinetics (PK) and Safety and Tolerability of Astreonam-avibactam (ATM-AVI) for the Treatment of Complicated Intra-Abdominal Infections (cIAIs) in Hospitalized Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Clinical Trial Centre, Cologne, CTCC, Germany</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Universitätsklinikum Köln, UKK, Germany</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Medical Centre Utrecht, UMCU, the Netherlands</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Servicio Andaluz de Salud, SAS, Spain</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Limoges, CHUL, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institute National de la Santé et de la Recherche Médicale, INSERM, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AstraZeneca</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Determine the PK and safety and tolerability of aztreonam-avibactam (ATM-AVI) in the
      treatment of hospitalized adults with cIAI
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A Phase IIa prospective, open-label, multicenter study to determine the pharmacokinetics
      (PK) and safety and tolerability of aztreonam-avibactam (ATM-AVI) for the treatment of
      complicated Intra-Abdominal Infections (cIAIs) in hospitalized adults
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 19, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 24, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 24, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>No masking</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Concentrations of ATM and AVI in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>sample collected at day 1 and day 4</time_frame>
    <description>Sparse sampling will be taken from all patients at Day 1; intensive sampling will be taken from first 25 patients on Day 4 and remaining 15 patients take sparse sampling.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of ATM-AVI PK profile in terms of Cmax</measure>
    <time_frame>sample collected at day 4</time_frame>
    <description>For patient undergoing intensive sampling on Day 4 .</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of ATM-AVI PK profile in terms of tmax</measure>
    <time_frame>sample collected at day 4</time_frame>
    <description>For patient undergoing intensive sampling on Day 4.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of ATM-AVI PK profile in terms of AUC(0-6)</measure>
    <time_frame>sample collected at day 4</time_frame>
    <description>For patient undergoing intensive sampling on Day 4.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of ATM-AVI PK profile in terms of AUC(0-last)</measure>
    <time_frame>sample collected at day 4</time_frame>
    <description>For patient undergoing intensive sampling on Day 4.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of ATM-AVI PK profile in terms of tlast</measure>
    <time_frame>sample collected at day 4</time_frame>
    <description>For patient undergoing intensive sampling on Day 4.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of ATM-AVI PK profile in terms of t1/2</measure>
    <time_frame>sample collected at day 4</time_frame>
    <description>For patient undergoing intensive sampling on Day 4.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of ATM-AVI PK profile in terms of Vss</measure>
    <time_frame>sample collected at day 4</time_frame>
    <description>For patient undergoing intensive sampling on Day 4.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of ATM-AVI PK profile in terms of Vz</measure>
    <time_frame>sample collected at day 4</time_frame>
    <description>For patient undergoing intensive sampling on Day 4.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of ATM-AVI PK profile in terms of CL</measure>
    <time_frame>sample collected at day 4</time_frame>
    <description>For patient undergoing intensive sampling on Day 4.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of safety in terms of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>from screening to last visit (about 35 +/-3day)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of safety profile in terms of physical examination</measure>
    <time_frame>from screening to last visit (about 35 +/-3day)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of safety profile in terms of vital signs</measure>
    <time_frame>from screening to last visit (about 35 +/-3day)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of safety profile in terms of ECG</measure>
    <time_frame>from screening to last visit (about 35 +/-3day)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of safety profile in terms of laboratory assessments</measure>
    <time_frame>from screening to last visit (about 35 +/-3day)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients with clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>at TOC (test of cure) visit, day 22-28</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with clinical cure at TOC (day 22-28). Clinical Response will be assessed as 'Cure', based on resolution or significant improvement of signs and symptoms of cIAI such that no further antimicrobial therapy, drainage or surgical intervention is necessary and the patient does not meet any criteria for 'Failure' (death related to cIAI, received treatment with additional antibiotics for ongoing cIAI, evidence of persisting or recurrent infection at surgical re-intervention, or post-operative wound infection) or 'Indeterminate' (study data not available for evaluation of efficacy for any reason, including 'lost to follow up' or 'assessment not undertaken').</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation of derived PK parameters and clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>at TOC (test of cure) visit (Day 22-28)</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Response will be assessed as 'Cure', based on resolution or significant improvement of signs and symptoms of cIAI such that no further antimicrobial therapy, drainage or surgical intervention is necessary and the patient does not meet any criteria for 'Failure' (death related to cIAI, received treatment with additional antibiotics for ongoing cIAI, evidence of persisting or recurrent infection at surgical re-intervention, or post-operative wound infection) or 'Indeterminate' (study data not available for evaluation of efficacy for any reason, including 'lost to follow up' or 'assessment not undertaken').
The relationship between exposure to ATM-AVI and efficacy (clinical cure) will be explored graphically.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Complicated Intra-Abdominal Infections (cIAIs)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ATM-AVI</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>ATM plus AVI treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ATM-AVI</intervention_name>
    <description>For patients with normal renal function or mild renal impairement: 6500mg ATM/1777mg AVI on day 1 followed by daily dose of 6000mg ATM/1640mg AVI</description>
    <arm_group_label>ATM-AVI</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Metronidazole</intervention_name>
    <description>Metronidazole 500mg infused over 1 hour every 8 hours</description>
    <arm_group_label>ATM-AVI</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ATM-AVI</intervention_name>
    <description>For patients with normal renal function or mild renal impairement: 6500mgATM/2167mg AVI on day 1 followed by daily dose of 6000mg ATM/2000mg AVI</description>
    <arm_group_label>ATM-AVI</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ATM-AVI</intervention_name>
    <description>For patients with moderate renal impairment: 4250mg ATM/1417mg AVI on day 1 followed by daily dose of 3000mg ATM/1000mg AVI</description>
    <arm_group_label>ATM-AVI</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ATM-AVI</intervention_name>
    <description>For patients with moderate renal impairement: 4250mg ATM/1162AVI on day 1 followed by daily dose of 3000mg ATM/820mg AVI</description>
    <arm_group_label>ATM-AVI</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Provision of informed consent prior to any study-specific procedures.

          2. Male or female from 18 to 90 years of age inclusive.

          3. Female patients are authorized to participate in this clinical study if criteria
             concerning pregnancy avoidance stated in the protocol are met

          4. Diagnosis of cIAI

             EITHER:

             Intra-operative/postoperative enrolment with visual confirmation (presence of pus
             within the abdominal cavity) of an intra-abdominal infection associated with
             peritonitis. Surgical intervention includes open laparotomy, percutaneous drainage of
             an abscess, or laparoscopic surgery. Specimens from the surgical intervention must be
             sent for culture. Patients who undergo a surgical procedure with complete fascial
             closure are appropriate for the trial. The skin incision may be left open for
             purposes of wound management as long as complete fascial closure is accomplished. The
             patient has at least 1 of the following diagnosed during the surgical intervention:

               1. Cholecystitis with gangrenous rupture or perforation or progression of the
                  infection beyond the gallbladder wall

               2. Diverticular disease with perforation or abscess

               3. Appendiceal perforation or peri-appendiceal abscess

               4. Acute gastric or duodenal perforations, only if operated on &gt;24 hours after
                  diagnosis

               5. Traumatic perforation of the intestines, only if operated on &gt;12 hours after
                  diagnosis (f) Secondary peritonitis (but not spontaneous bacterial peritonitis
                  associated with cirrhosis and chronic ascites)

             (g) Intra abdominal abscess (including of liver or spleen provided that there is
             extension beyond the organ with evidence of intraperitoneal involvement) OR
             Preoperative enrollment where the following clinical criteria are met with
             confirmation of infection by surgical intervention within 24 hours of entry:

               1. Requirement for surgical intervention, defined per protocol as open laparotomy,
                  percutaneous drainage of an abscess, or laparoscopic surgery

               2. Evidence of systemic inflammatory response, with at least one of the following:

                    -  Fever (defined as body temperature &gt;38°C) or hypothermia with a core body
                       temperature &lt;35°C

                    -  Elevated white blood cells (&gt;12000 cells/μL)

                    -  Systolic blood pressure &lt;90 mmHg or mean arterial pressure &lt;70 mmHg, or a
                       systolic blood pressure decrease of &gt;40 mmHg Increased heart rate ( &gt;90
                       bpm) and respiratory rate (&gt;20 breaths/min)

                    -  Hypoxemia (defined as oxygen saturation &lt; 95% by pulse oximetry)

                    -  Altered mental status.

               3. Physical findings consistent with intra-abdominal infection, such as:

                    -  Abdominal pain and/or tenderness, with or without rebound

                    -  Localized or diffuse abdominal wall rigidity

                    -  Abdominal mass.

               4. Supportive radiologic imaging findings of intra-abdominal infection such as
                  perforated intraperitoneal abscess detected on computed tomography scan,
                  magnetic resonance image, or ultrasound.

               5. Specimens from the surgical intervention will be sent for culture for isolation
                  of both aerobic and anaerobic bacteria.

          5. Patients who failed prior antibacterial treatment for their current cIAI can be
             enrolled but must:

               -  Have a known or suspected pathogen causing cIAI that is resistant to the prior
                  therapy while assuming the organism is known to be sensitive to ATM-AVI.

               -  Require surgical intervention.

          6. Patient must have or will have a surgical intervention within 24 hours (before or
             after) the administration of the first dose of study drug

        Exclusion criteria:

          1. Involvement in the planning and/or conduct of the study

          2. Patient has been previously enrolled in this study, previously treated with ATM-AVI
             or previously participated in an investigation study containing AVI

          3. Patient has participated or intends to participate in any other clinical study that
             involves the administration of an investigational medication at the time of
             presentation, during the course of the study, or during the 30 days prior to study
             start.

          4. Patient has a history of serious allergy, hypersensitivity (eg, anaphylaxis), or any
             serious reaction to aztreonam, carbapenem, monobactam or other β-lactam antibiotics,
             avibactam, nitroimidazoles or metronidazole, or any of the excipients of the
             respective (investigational) medicinal products to be administered during the study

          5. Patient has a diagnosis of abdominal wall abscess; small bowel obstruction or
             ischemic bowel disease without perforation; traumatic bowel perforation with surgery
             within 12 hours of diagnosis; perforation of gastroduodenal ulcer with surgery within
             24 hours of diagnosis (these are considered situations of peritoneal soiling before
             infection has become established); another intra-abdominal process in which the
             primary etiology is not likely to be infectious

          6. Patient has a simple cholecystitis, gangrenous cholecystitis without rupture, simple
             appendicitis, acute suppurative cholangitis, infected necrotizing pancreatitis,
             pancreatic abscess or ischaemic/necrotic intestine without perforation

          7. Patient has a cIAI managed by staged abdominal repair (STAR), open abdomen technique
             or any situation where infection source control is not likely to be achieved or in
             whom the abdomen is left open, particularly those for whom re-operation is planned,
             or those unlikely to solely respond to antimicrobial therapy

          8. At screening, if it is known the patient has an infection due to a pathogen that is
             unlikely to respond to ATM-AVI plus metronidazole treatment

          9. Patient has a rapidly progressive (expected to die in &lt;30 days) or terminal illness,
             including acute hepatic failure, respiratory failure or septic shock with a high risk
             of mortality due to other causes than cIAI

         10. Patient has received systemic antibacterial agents within the 72- hour period prior
             to study entry, unless either of the following pertains:

               1. Patient has a new infection (not considered a treatment failure) and the
                  following is met:

                  - Patient received no more than 24 hours within the 72 hour period prior to
                  study entry

               2. Patient is considered to have failed the previous treatment regimen

         11. Patient has a concurrent infection that may interfere with the evaluation of clinical
             cure for the study therapy

         12. Patient needs effective concomitant systemic antibacterials (oral, IV, or
             intramuscular) or antifungals in addition to the investigational product and
             metronidazole

         13. Patient has creatinine clearance ≤50 ml/min. Note: following review of PK and safety
             data from the first 10 enrolled patients, and the confirmation of a provisional dose
             schedule, patients with a creatinine clearance of 31 - 50 mL/min may be included.

         14. Patient has had acute hepatitis in the prior 6 months, chronic hepatitis, cirrhosis
             (any Child-Pugh class), acute hepatic failure, or acute decompensation of chronic
             hepatic failure

         15. Presence of hepatic disease as indicated by aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or
             alanine transaminase (ALT) &gt;3 × upper limit of normal (ULN) at Screening. Patients
             with AST and/or ALT &gt;3 × ULN and &lt; 5 × ULN are eligible if these elevations are
             acute, not accompanied by a total bilirubin ≥ 2xULN and documented by the
             investigator as being directly related to the infectious process being treated

         16. Patient has a total bilirubin &gt;3 × ULN, unless isolated hyperbilirubinemia is
             directly related to the acute infection or due to known Gilbert's disease

         17. Alkaline phosphatase (ALP) &gt;3 × ULN. Patients with values &gt;3 × ULN and &lt;5 x ULN are
             eligible if this value is acute and directly related to the infectious process being
             treated.

         18. Patients with an immunocompromising illness

         19. Known active Clostridium difficile associated diarrhoea

         20. Any other condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, may confound the
             results of the study or pose additional risks

         21. Patient with a do not resuscitate order

         22. Patient has an absolute neutrophil count &lt;1000/μL

         23. Patient has a hematocrit &lt;25% or hemoglobin &lt;8 gm/dL.

         24. Patient has a platelet count &lt;75,000/μL. Patients with a platelet as low as 50,000
             /μL are permitted if the reduction is historically stable

         25. Patient is currently receiving treatment with probenecid.

         26. Patient is pregnant or breastfeeding or if of child bearing potential,

         27. Patient is unlikely to comply with protocol,

         28. Patient is currently receiving anti-convulsant therapy to prevent recurrence of a
             past history of seizures.

         29. Patient has a prior liver, pancreas or small-bowel transplant.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Oliver Cornely, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, University of Cologne</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jose Miguel Cisneros Herreros, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital Unversitario Virgen Del Rocio y Virgen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Deborah Postil, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CHU Limoges</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>AstraZeneca Clinical Study Information Center</last_name>
    <phone>1-877-240-9479</phone>
    <email>information.center@astrazeneca.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amiens Cedex 1</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Angoulême</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clermont-ferrand</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lille Cedex</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Limoges</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Poitiers</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bonn</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Freiburg</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Köln</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lübeck</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>München</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Regensburg</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barakaldo</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cordoba</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palma de Mallorca</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Terrassa</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zaragoza</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 20, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 1, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cIAIs in hospitalized adults</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Intraabdominal Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Metronidazole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
