<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01785615</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Little is known regarding the association of individual components of the metabolic syndrome (MBS) and prothrombotic, inflammatory and preclinical cardiac structural and functional markers in women with this syndrome. Less is known about adequate treatment as the pathological mechanism of this syndrome is not well understood. The purpose of this study is two fold; 1. To determine basic differences in biochemical and cardiovascular structural markers in women with and those without MBS and their association with the individual components of MBS. 2. To determine the impact of atorvastatin to lower the risk factors of Metabolic Syndrome. Atorvastatin is one of the most effective drugs approved by the United States Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for the treatment of high cholesterol. It belongs to a class of drugs called statins and its role in primary prevention is still unclear. Thus this population seems to be an ideal group that may benefit from this intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prothrombotic Inflammatory Markers in Women With Metabolic Syndrome - Effect of Atorvastatin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The first phase of the study is an observational phase as previously described. The second phase was a prospective evaluation of the effect of a well known "statin" drug (Liptor) on different biochemical factors measured in the blood. The eligible study participants had blood work done upon enrollment and if criteria was met(according to the Adult Treatment Panel III), they were given dietary counseling (NYHA - New York Heart Association Step 1 diet) as a lead in phase. Lab work was repeated at 3 weeks to evaluate the impact of the diet and if participant's profile still met criteria for MBS,randomization for either atorvastatin (Liptor) 80mg or placebo (sugar pill) for 12 weeks took place.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atorvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women between the ages of 1875 with Metabolic syndrome Abdominal circumference &gt; 35 in Hypertriglyceridemia &gt; 150mg/dl HDL &lt;50 Blood Pressure &gt;130/85 Fasting Glucose &gt;100 Pregnant or planning to become pregnant in the next 612 months Receiving lipidlowing drugs Obstructive hepatobiliary disease or serious hepatic disease Diabetes, cardiovascular disease (CVD), hypothyroidism, active infection, cancer, recent surgery Fulfill criteria to receive statin based on LDL levels, risk factors, and Framingham risk scoring outlined on ATP111/NCEP 111 recommendations Documented allergic reaction to statin in past unexplained elevation in creatinine kinase levels &gt; 3 times upper limit</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>metabolic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>atorvastatin</keyword>
	<keyword>women</keyword>
</DOC>