<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01785849</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to assess the efficacy and safety of etelcalcetide compared with placebo in the treatment of SHPT in patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) receiving hemodialysis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Etelcalcetide (AMG 416) in the Treatment of Secondary Hyperparathyroidism (SHPT) in Patients With Chronic Kidney Disease on Hemodialysis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperparathyroidism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperparathyroidism, Secondary</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject understands the study procedures and agrees to participate in the study by giving written informed consent. Subject is 18 years of age or older. Subject must be receiving hemodialysis 3 times weekly for at least 3 months Subject agrees to not participate in another study of an investigational agent during the study. Other Inclusion Criteria may apply Currently receiving treatment in another investigational device or drug study, or ended treatment on another investigational device or drug study(s) within 8 weeks prior to screening. Other investigational procedures while participating in this study are excluded. Anticipated or scheduled parathyroidectomy during the study period. Subject has received a parathyroidectomy within 3 months prior to dosing. Anticipated or scheduled kidney transplant during the study period. Subject has known sensitivity to any of the products or components to be administered during dosing. Subject has participated in a prior clinical trial of AMG 416 (also referred to as KAI4169). Subject has received cinacalcet within the 4 weeks prior to screening labs (treatment with cinacalcet is prohibited during the study). Subject has an unstable medical condition based on medical history, physical examination, and routine laboratory tests, or is otherwise unstable in the judgment of the Investigator. Other Exclusion Criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Secondary Hyperparathyroidism (SHPT), chronic kidney disease (CKD), hemodialysis, parathyroid hormone (PTH), hypocalcemia, bone and mineral metabolism</keyword>
</DOC>