<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00811382</DOC>
	<brief_summary>EffecT is a prospective, randomized multicenter study to assess whether management of atrial fibrillation (AF) as well as the early optimization of cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) via Home Monitoring decreases mortality and morbidity compared to conventional treatment in subjects with a standard indication for CRT with Implantable Cardioverter Defibrillator (ICD) backup and AF.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical effecT of Heart Failure Management Via Home Monitoring With a Focus on Atrial Fibrillation (effecT)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>EffecT is a prospective, randomized multicenter study to assess whether management of atrial fibrillation as well as the early optimization of cardiac resynchronization therapy via Home Monitoring decreases mortality and morbidity compared to conventional treatment in subjects with a standard indication for CRT with Implantable Cardioverter Defibrillator backup (CRT-ICD) and paroxysmal or persistent AF. 300 patients with a documented history of AF will be enrolled and randomized 1:1 to standard patient management or AF management and early optimization of CRT via Home Monitoring. The patient outcome regarding days lost due to cardiovascular mortality, cardiovascular hospitalization and inappropriate ICD therapy will be documented during an observational period of 1 year. Another 300 patients undergoing CRT-ICD implantation without a history of AF will undergo an AF evaluation during the first three months of CRT. If a patient shows an AF episode during this period, he is eligible for study inclusion. If no AF episode occurs during AF evaluation, the patient be treated as screening failure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Indication for CRT with ICDbackup Paroxysmal or persistent AF Optimized HFrelated medication Permanent AF Contraindication for anticoagulation Stroke within the last 6 weeks Acute coronary syndrome within the last 2 months Cardiac surgery within the last 2 months Acute myocarditis Severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) Planned cardiac surgery or interventional measures within the coming 3 months Dialysis dependency Life expectancy &lt; 12 months Insufficient GSM (Global System for Mobile Communication)/GPRS (General Packet Radio Service)network coverage Previously implanted unipolar right atrial lead Previously implanted right atrial lead with tipring distance &gt; 11 mm</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>CRT</keyword>
	<keyword>therapy of AF</keyword>
	<keyword>telecardiology</keyword>
	<keyword>home monitoring</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiovascular hospitalization</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiovascular mortality</keyword>
</DOC>