<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00811265</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluate the safety, compatibility and imaging quality of the ExAblate MRgFUS system.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Evaluation of ExAblate MRgFUS for Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of this study is to evaluate safety, compatibility and imaging quality of the ExAblate MRgFUS system for prostate cancer, under simulated use conditions. No acoustic energy will be delivered and no focused ultrasound therapy will be performed. This is an imaging only study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age of patients: up to 75 years. Men scheduled for radical prostatectomy due to prostate cancer. Patients who are able and willing to give consent and able to attend all study visits. Contraindications to MRI including: claustrophobia, weight over 120 kg, implanted ferromagnetic materials or foreign objects, and known intolerance to the MRI contrast agent (e.g. Gadolinium or Magnevist) Severely abnormal coagulation (INR&gt;1.5) Patients with unstable cardiac status including: unstable angina pectoris on medication, patients with documented myocardial infarction within six months of protocol entry, congestive heart failure requiring medication (other than diuretic), patients on antiarrhythmic drugs, severe hypertension (diastolic BP &gt; 100 on medication), and patients with cardiac pacemakers Severe cerebrovascular disease (multiple CVA or CVA within 6 months) Individuals who are not able or willing to tolerate the required prolonged stationary supine position during imaging (approximately 1 hrs.) Any rectal pathology preventing probe insertion, (as active proctitis, ulcerative colitis, fissure ani, diverticulitis, previous rectal surgery, IBD, etc…) Any spinal pathology that prohibits maintaining supine position for more then an hour Any previous radiation to the pelvis.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ExAblate MRgFUS</keyword>
	<keyword>Focused ultrasound</keyword>
	<keyword>Magnetic resonance imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Radical prostatectomy candidate</keyword>
</DOC>