<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02305914</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a follow-up study focusing on long-term complications of acute pancreatitis. The primary purposes include: 1. To assess the incidence of type 2 diabetes mellitus（2-DM）,impaired glucose tolerance, metabolic abnormalities of blood lipids after acute pancreatitis. 2. To observe the possible long-term clinical outcomes after acute pancreatitis attack, which may include: chronic pancreatitis, pancreatic cancer, pancreatogenic portal hypertension, autoimmune pancreatitis et al. 3. To evaluate the long-term influence of acute lung injury(PaO2/FiO2&lt;200,FiO2 means fraction of inspiration O2) in AP patients during ICU stay on life qualities of the patients; 4. To observe the prognosis of the local complications of acute pancreatitis(AP) patients; it might be helpful to find the most effective and targeted interventions aiming at different phases after AP attack.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Follow-up Study of Complications of Acute Pancreatitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Currently，follow-up study is limited on glucose intolerance and life quality assessment. However, it has been shown that AP is associated to some extent with other diseases such as chronic pancreatitis, pancreatic cancer, pancreatogenic portal hypertension and autoimmune pancreatitis; In addition, for patients who have severe lung injury following AP, especially with PaO2/FiO2&lt;200 during ICU stay, the long term prognosis remains unclear. Thus, a large sample follow-up study is essential for elucidating the possible long-term complications. Prior to follow up study, the investigators performed baseline analysis of AP patient data from the database of the First Affiliated Hospital of Nanchang University. It is estimated that 1300 patients will be interviewed over telephone and 600 patients in the outpatient department. The content of the follow-up includes: questionnaire (the MOS[medical outcome study] item short from health survey, SF[short form]-36) ; lab testing(complete blood count, blood chemistry such as liver and kidney function, C-reaction protein(CRP), AMY, fasting blood-glucose，1 and 2 hour postprandial blood glucose,C-peptide, blood lipids, FE-1) and CT scan. For patients who have severe lung injuries during ICU stay, pulmonary function test, Blood gas analysis and chest CT will be performed. After screening, the patients with chronic pancreatitis(CP), pancreatic cancer(PC), post Pancreatogenic portal hypertension（PPH） or autoimmune pancreatitis(AIP）will be hospitalized for further therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension, Portal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of acute pancreatitis from our hospital Must be signed the informed consent Failed to complete the questionnaire survey and the followup examination</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>acute pancreatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic pancreatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreatic cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreatic disease-associated portal hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>autoimmune pancreatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>PaO2/FiO2＜200</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>blood lipid</keyword>
	<keyword>local complications</keyword>
	<keyword>quality of life</keyword>
</DOC>