<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02886884</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a 10 subject trial to demonstrate the safety of allogeneic hMSCs administered via infusion therapy for diabetic subjects with endothelial dysfunction.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Allogeneic Mesenchymal Human Stem Cells Infusion Therapy for Endothelial DySfunctiOn in Diabetic Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Sixteen (16) diabetic subject with endothelial dysfunction will be scheduled to undergo a peripheral intravenous infusion after meeting all inclusion/exclusion criteria at baseline. Three (3) subjects will be treated with 20 million (2 x 10^7) allogeneic hMSC's and thirteen (13) subjects will be treated with 100 million (100 x 10^6) allogeneic hMSC's Follow up: Subjects will be followed at 3, 7, 14 and 28 days post-infusion to complete all safety and efficacy assessments and at 6 and 12 months post-infusion to complete safety assessments.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Be ≥ 21 and &lt;80 years of age. Provide written informed consent. Have endothelial dysfunction defined by impaired flowmediated vasodilation (FMD &lt;7%). Been treated with appropriate medical therapy for ischemic heart disease, including aspirin, betablockers, angiotensin converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitors / Angiotensin II receptor blockers (ARBs) and statins as tolerated by the subject. Have an ejection fraction &gt; 45% by gated blood pool scan, two dimensional echocardiogram, cardiac MRI, cardiac CT or left ventriculogram within the prior 3 months. Have Diabetes mellitus type 2 documented by hemoglobin adult type 1 component (A1C) &gt; 7% or on medical therapy for diabetes. Females of childbearing potential must use two forms of birth control for the duration of the study. Female subjects must undergo a blood or urine pregnancy test at screening and within 36 hours prior to infusion. In order to participate in this study, a subject Must Not: Be younger than 21 years or older than 80 years of age. Have a baseline glomerular filtration rate &lt;50 ml/min 1.73m^2 estimated using the Modification of Diet in renal disease (MDRD) formula. Have poorly controlled blood glucose levels with hemoglobin A1C &gt; 8.5%. Have a history of proliferative retinopathy or severe neuropathy requiring medical treatment. Have an indication for surgical standardofcare (including valve surgery, placement of leftventricular assist device) or percutaneous intervention for the treatment of valvular heart disease (including valvuloplasty). Known hypersensitivity or contraindication to aspirin; both heparin and bivalirudin; all available P2Y12 inhibitors (clopidogrel, prasugrel, and ticagrelor); or any zotarolimus, cobalt, chromium, nickel, tungsten, acrylic, or fluoro polymers; or hypersensitivity to contrast media that cannot be adequately premedicated. Have a hematologic abnormality as evidenced by hematocrit &lt; 25%, white blood cell &lt; 2,500/ul or platelet values &lt; 100,000/ul without another explanation. Have liver dysfunction, as evidenced by enzymes (AST and ALT) greater than two times the upper limit of normal. Have a bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy (INR &gt; 1.3), cannot be withdrawn from anticoagulation therapy, require Coumadin therapy, or will refuse blood transfusions. Have Lymphadenectomy or Lymph node dissection in the right arm. Be an organ transplant recipient or have a history of organ or cell transplant rejection. Have a clinical history of malignancy within the past 5 years (i.e., subjects with prior malignancy must be disease free for 5 years), except curatively treated basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma, or cervical carcinoma. Have a condition that limits lifespan to &lt; 1 year. Have a history of drug or alcohol abuse within the past 24 months. Be on chronic therapy with immunosuppressant medication, such as corticosteroids or Tumor Necrosis Factor alpha (TNFα) antagonists. Be serum positive for HIV, hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) or viremic hepatitis C. Be currently participating (or participated within the previous 30 days) in an investigational therapeutic or device trial. Be pregnant, nursing, or of childbearing potential while not practicing effective contraceptive methods. Any other condition that in the judgment of the Investigator would be a contraindication to enrollment or followup.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Endothelial dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Stem cells</keyword>
</DOC>