<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02886637</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the present study is to evaluate the effects of immune function on prognositic outcome in critical ill patients with Acinetobacter baumannii infection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Immune Function on Prognositic Outcome in Critical Ill Patients With Acinetobacter Baumannii Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single-center, observational study. Patients with Acinetobacter baumannii infection in the intensive care unit of Zhongda Hospital were enrolled. We recorded the data of age, ICU admission diagnosis, underlying diseases, APACHE II score and infection site. Body temperature, heart rate, white blood cell counts, procalcitonin, C-reactive protein, SOFA score and the level of CD4+, CD8+, Th1, Th2 and HLA-DR in the blood measured by flow cytometry on the D1, D3 and D7 were also recorded.We can get the results of the change of immune function of critical ill patients after Acinetobacter baumannii infection. After compare the patients who die of survive at 28 day after infection, we can get the results of the relationship between the immune function and the outcome. We also can calculate the effect immune function on prognositic mortality in patients with Acinetobacter baumannii infection.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients admitted to ICU Infection with Acinetobacter baumannii Agree to participate the study Age less than 16 years old or older than 80 years old pregnancy immunosuppression patients which include 1. therapy 0.5mg/kg/day of prednisoneover(equivalent dose of other glucocorticoids) for at least 1 month within recent 3 month 2. Cancer chemotherapy within recent 3 month 3. Receive immunosuppression treatment because of solid organ transplant or Autoimmune diseases 4. allogeneic bone marrow transplantation or allogeneic haematopoietic stem cell transplantation. 5. HIV infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>A baumannii infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunosuppression</keyword>
	<keyword>prognosis</keyword>
	<keyword>immune function</keyword>
</DOC>