<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00480077</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The DOT-HF trial is an international, prospective, multi-center, randomized, controlled trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Diagnostic Outcome Trial in Heart Failure (DOT-HF Trial)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study was designed with a Control Arm in order to adequately study the effect of early intervention triggered by the OptiVol® Alert and/or SentryCheck™ Monitor/PatientLook™ Indicator and evaluation using OptiVol® Fluid Status Monitoring with Cardiac Compass. OptiVol® Fluid Status Monitoring with Cardiac Compass features are available in the per Clinical Investigational Plan specified Medtronic products (CRT, CRT-D and ICD devices)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects of both genders with mild to severe HF as defined as NHYA Class II to IV who also have an indication for device implant according to ESC/AHA guidelines as well as having a HF hospitalization or Emergency Department visit necessitating therapy within the past 12 months and who meet all inclusion criteria and no exclusion criteria, are eligible for this study. Subject is post heart transplant or actively listed on the transplant list and reasonable probability (as defined by investigator) of undergoing transplantation in the next year Subject received a coronary artery bypass graft or valve surgery in last 90 days Subject with a myocardial infarction (MI) in the last 40 days. Subject's life expectancy is less than one year in the opinion of the physician Subject has severe Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD), as determined by physician and documented in medical records Subject is listed for valve replacement/valve repair Subject has severe, primary pulmonary hypertension as determined by physician and documented in medical records Subject with serum creatinine ≥ 2.5 mg/dL measured within 14 days prior to enrolment Subject on chronic renal dialysis Subject on continuous or uninterrupted (≥ 2 stable infusions per week) infusion (inotropic) therapy for HF Subject has complex and uncorrected Congenital Heart Disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Heart Failure, randomized, OptiVol® Fluid status monitoring</keyword>
</DOC>