<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="114288">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01615367</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>K23MH091182-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01615367</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Nutrition, Exercise, and Wellness Treatment (NEW Tx) for Bipolar Disorder</brief_title>
  <acronym>NEW Tx</acronym>
  <official_title>Nutrition, Exercise, and Wellness Treatment (NEW Tx) for Bipolar Disorder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cardiovascular disease (CVD) is the leading cause of morbidity and mortality in bipolar
      disorder, yet no empirically validated psychosocial interventions to manage risk factors for
      CVD in BD have been developed. The purpose of this study is to develop and test the
      feasibility of an integrated treatment to decrease CVD risk factors, while exploring whether
      the intervention improves overall functioning and mood symptoms. The designed treatment
      integrates theories on Nutrition strategies, Exercise interventions, and Wellness Treatment
      (NEW Tx) to address risk factors for CVD that co-occur with bipolar disorder. NEW Tx
      includes novel intervention strategies in each of these three modules, as well as modified
      and tailored empirically-supported strategies for bipolar disorder. The primary hypotheses
      are that NEW Tx will be feasible to deliver, acceptable to this population, and associated
      with improvements in CVD risk factors (i.e., waist circumference). Exploratory analyses will
      examine predictors of treatment response and the effect of NEW Tx on mood symptoms and
      overall functioning.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of the Nutrition, Exercise, and Wellness Treatment (NEW Tx) research is to
      develop and test the feasibility and acceptance of a theoretically integrated treatment to
      address the impact of medical comorbidity of individuals with bipolar disorder (BD), while
      exploring its efficacy, whether it improves overall functioning and symptoms, as well as
      examine a potential moderator and mediator of treatment response.

      A.Primary Aims

      Aim 1: Feasibility and Acceptance of NEW Tx in the Nonrandomized Trial.

      Hypothesis 1a: A preliminary study of whether NEW Tx will be feasible with regards to
      recruitment, retention, blinded assessments, and therapist adherence to NEW Tx.

      Hypothesis 1b: Participants will report high satisfaction with the treatment and
      acceptability over the study duration in a nonrandomized trial.

      Aim 2: Feasibility and Acceptance of NEW Tx and its Evaluation in the Randomized Pilot
      Trial.

      Hypothesis 2a: A pilot study of whether NEW Tx will be feasible with regards to recruitment,
      randomization, retention, blinded assessments, and therapist adherence to NEW Tx.

      Hypothesis 2b: Participants will report high satisfaction with the treatment and
      acceptability over the study duration in the randomized pilot trial.

      B. Exploratory Aims

      Aim 3a: Reducing Medical Burden in the Randomized Pilot Trial. Pilot test the efficacy of
      NEW Tx in improving medical burden using the Framingham Risk Score (FRS).

      Hypothesis 3a: Over the course of 20-weeks (18 sessions) the NEW Tx group will have a lower
      FRS compared to treatment as usual (TAU) in the randomized pilot trial.

      Aim 3b: Symptoms and Functioning in the Randomized Pilot Trial. Examine the efficacy of NEW
      Tx in improving functioning and symptoms of BD.

      Hypothesis 3b: Over the course of 20-weeks (18 sessions) the NEW Tx group will improved
      functioning and mood symptoms compared to TAU in the randomized pilot trial.

      Aim 3c: Moderator and Mediator of NEW Tx in the Randomized Pilot Trial. Investigate a
      potential moderator and mediator of treatment response.

      Hypothesis 3c.1: Individuals with higher baseline Body Mass Index (BMI) &gt; 30 will moderate
      the between treatment effect size for medical burden (FRS) in the randomized pilot trial,
      such that of NEW Tx will have lower FRSs.

      Hypothesis 3c.2: Mastery of the diet and exercise modules of NEW Tx will mediate the
      association of NEW Tx and improvement in medical burden (FRS).
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single Blind (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>NEW Tx Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>NEW Tx Scale is a 10-item scale to asses participants' expectations of NEW Tx at Baseline and their acceptability of NEW Tx at Week 10 and Week 20. This scale also includes a comments section to solicit unstructured feedback from participants on NEW Tx.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Client Satisfaction Questionnaire-8</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Client Satisfaction Questionnaire-8 is a reliable and valid self-report of participants' acceptability of treatment. This is an assessment of client/patient satisfaction with their care and perceived quality and tolerability of NEW Tx.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Framingham Risk Score</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Framingham Risk Score (FRS) will be used to estimate medical burden as it is designed to estimate risk in adults (age &gt; 20) to predict 10-year risk for myocardial infarction and coronary death. The FRS is calculated based on six indices: age, gender, total cholesterol, HDL cholesterol, smoker (Y/N), systolic blood pressure, and medications to treat high blood pressure (Y/N).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>LIFE- Range of Impaired Functioning Tool</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>LIFE- Range of Impaired Functioning Tool assesses the extent to which medical burden has impacted current functioning.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Montgomery Asberg Depression Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Montgomery Asberg Depression Rating Scale is a 10-item clinician-rated measure of depression that assesses the presence and severity of patient's current depressive symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Young Mania Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>20 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Young Mania Rating Scale is an 11-item, clinician-rated measure that assesses the presence and severity of patient's current symptoms of mania.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">39</enrollment>
  <condition>Bipolar Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NEW Tx</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>25 people will be randomized to NEW Tx, a weekly individualized psychotherapy. Therapy is 20 weeks long.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual (TAU)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>25 people will be randomized to TAU and will meet with their psychiatrist as often as clinically needed over the 20 week study duration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nutrition, Exercise, and Wellness (NEW) psychotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>NEW Tx is a flexible modular treatment such that modules are selected based on the needs of the individual to increase its generalizability across patients, settings, and providers as well as its acceptability to patients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NEW Tx</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Typically consists of at least one FDA-approved mood stabilizer</intervention_name>
    <description>Pharmacotherapy will be conducted by experts in BD treatment and will follow the empirically-supported treatment algorithm for BD that has been developed and recently revised. The foundation of TAU is to maintain treatment with at least one Food and Drug Administration approved mood stabilizer. For TAU, medication and dosage changes are allowed as needed as long as the change is recommended based on the guidelines and participants remain on a mood stabilizer.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual (TAU)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Diagnosis of Bipolar Disorder (Type I or II), which is the primary focus of treatment

          -  Ability to give informed consent

          -  Currently ill (CGI-BP ≥ 3)

          -  Age &gt; 18 years and &lt; 65 years

          -  Overweight individuals (BMI &gt; 25)

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Unwilling/unable to comply with study procedures

          -  Endorsed item, confirmed by patient's physician, on the PAR-Q

          -  Euthymic (CGI-BP &lt; 3)

          -  Diagnosis of an eating disorder (e.g., anorexia nervosa, bulimia nervosa) in the past
             month

          -  Diagnosis of substance dependence in the past month

          -  Active suicidality (MADRS item 9 score &gt; 4)

          -  Pregnant (as analyzed by a urine pregnancy test)

          -  Currently receiving another psychosocial treatment

          -  Exercising regularly (i.e., 5 days per week for 30 min)

          -  Neurologic disorder or history of head trauma

          -  Contraindications to exercise or diet interventions (e.g., co-morbid nutritional and
             metabolic diseases, physical injuries)
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>September 15, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 31, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Louisa Grandin Sylvia</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Instructor of Psychiatry</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bipolar disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Nutrition</keyword>
  <keyword>Exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>Symptoms</keyword>
  <keyword>Functioning</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
