<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01590992</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether psychotherapy (based on exposure techniques) is effective in the treatment of functional somatic symptoms (FSS)/Somatoform Disorders (as exemplified here in subjects with globus sensations in the throat).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Globus Sensations With Psychotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Functional somatic symptoms (FSS) and somatoform disorders are characterized by the presence of medically unexplained symptoms. They are among the most prevalent disorders in the general medical setting, leading to individual suffering and having huge impact on public health alike. Unfortunately, many patients still remain untreated and not all patients get better, even when receiving currently proposed treatments. The aim of the present project is twofold: First, we want to improve the understanding of risk factors and psychobiological processes leading to the development of FSS. Second, we will explore and evaluate new ways of treating subjects with FSS. Within the project, we will examine subjects with globus sensations in the throat, a very common und impairing form of FSS. The proposed study i) may provide insight into the development of FSS, thereby improving our way by which we recognize and diagnose subjects with FSS, and ii) may help fostering our understanding of how to better treat subjects suffering from FSS.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Somatoform Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Conversion Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Sufficient spoken and written knowledge of German Presence of globus sensations and somatoform disorder Clinically significant impairment Current (past 12 months) severe chronic physical illnesses, especially neurological, endocrine or metabolic diseases Current (past 12 months) substance dependence or eating disorder Lifetime history of psychotic disorder or bipolar disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Somatoform disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Functional Somatic Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Functional Somatic Symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>Somatic Symptom Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>globus sensation</keyword>
	<keyword>globus pharynges</keyword>
	<keyword>globus hystericus</keyword>
</DOC>