<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01590654</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Dose cohorts may be dosed with one of up to 4 possible total weekly doses (0.3 mg, 1 mg, 2 mg, 4 mg). Dose escalation or repetition will be governed by pre-specified safety and activity rules. Subjects will be confined on days 1-3 and/or days 8-10. Follow-up visits are required periodically through day 43. Subjects with sustained reductions in HbsAg will be requested to return for additional follow-up follow-up visits at 3 and 6 months post last dose. Study procedures involve blood draws for pharmacokinetic, pharmacodynamic, virologic, and safety assessments</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Evaluating GS-9620 in Virologically Suppressed Subjects With Chronic Hepatitis B Virus Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronic HBV infection for ≥ 6 months Currently on treatment with at least 1 HBV approved oral drug (i.e. lamivudine, telbivudine, entecavir, adefovir, tenofovir) ≥ 3 months prior to screening HBsAg ≥ 250 IU/mL HBV DNA at below the level of quantitation (BLQ; to be confirmed at screening) Absence of extensive bridging fibrosis (Metavir 3 or greater)or cirrhosis Creatinine clearance ≥ 70 mL/min Coinfection with hepatitis C virus (HCV), hepatitis D virus (HDV), or HIV History of Gilberts disease Laboratory parameters not within defined thresholds for leukopenia, neutropenia, anemia, thrombocytopenia, thyroidstimulating hormone (TSH), or other evidence of hepatic decompensation Diagnosis of autoimmune disease, poorly controlled diabetes mellitus, significant psychiatric illness, severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), malignancy, hemoglobinopathy, retinal disease, or patients who are immunosuppressed Evidence of hepatocellular carcinoma</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis B</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis B Virus</keyword>
	<keyword>HBV</keyword>
	<keyword>GS-9620</keyword>
	<keyword>Toll-like receptor (TLR)-7 Agonist</keyword>
</DOC>