<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="175374">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00812708</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>02-06-072</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00812708</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Morcher Artificial Iris Devices to Treat Light and Glare Sensitivity in Partial or Complete Aniridia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Compassionate Use Study of Morcher Artificial Iris Devices to Treat Light and Glare Sensitivity in Partial or Complete Aniridia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, Los Angeles</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Los Angeles</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the safety and effectiveness of Morcher artificial
      iris devices in the treatment of congenital and acquired aniridia.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Congenital aniridia is a rare genetic condition that results in the abnormal development of
      the iris (colored part) of the eye. This genetically inherited disorder occurs in
      approximately 1/60,000 to 1/100,000 births. Severe cases can result in the complete absence
      of the iris and the muscles that open and close the pupil. Mild cases can result in a
      thinner iris with a normal pupil. About half of the people with this condition also develop
      early cataracts that need to be removed in their 20's or 30's. Most have glaucoma, which is
      difficult to control. Vision is usually decreased by significant glare because the iris is
      not present to control the amount of light entering the eye. Vision can also be limited
      because of the presents of cataracts, glaucoma, and a condition called nystagmus in which
      there are uncontrollable jerking eye movements. The only treatment for aniridia is the use
      of colored glasses or contact lenses with images of an iris painted on them to reduce the
      amount of light entering the eye.

      Acquired aniridia is more common than congenital aniridia. Acquired aniridia may be partial
      or complete and may be caused by trauma or surgery. Often the cornea, lens, and/or retina
      are affected simultaneously, resulting in severe visual disability.

      Morcher GmbH, a German company, manufactures the iris diaphragms. Their web site is
      http://www.morcher.com. Morcher artificial iris devices are designed to reduce the
      significant light and glare sensitivity that patients experience with aniridia. These
      devices have been used in Europe for over 20 years. They hold the European CE mark of
      conformity and have been certified through the Active Implantable Medical Device Directive
      (AIMDD) since 1994.

      Implantation of a Morcher iris diaphragm is performed in association with other standard of
      care surgical procedures, which include cataract surgery with intraocular lens (IOL)
      implantation, IOL exchange, and/or anterior vitrectomy. These procedures are performed in an
      operating room under local or general anesthesia. The IOL and the iris diaphragm are placed
      into the eye through an incision in the cornea. The IOL is placed in the eye behind the
      normal position of the iris, inside the lens capsule if it remains following cataract
      removal. The iris diaphragm is placed in front of the IOL. In some cases a single-piece iris
      reconstruction lens containing an artificial iris and lens is implanted. If the capsule can
      not support an IOL and iris implant, they are sutured in place through the sclera, the white
      part of the eye. Two different medication eye drops are used for 4 to 6 weeks following
      surgery. Patients are required to return for 5 postoperative visits at intervals of 1 day, 2
      weeks, 3, 6, and 12 months. Standard testing occurs at each of these visits and require
      approximately 1 to 2 hours of the patient's time. Color photographs of the eye and
      endothelial cell counts are obtained preoperatively and 3 months postoperatively. If
      required, the same procedure for the other eye may be performed 6 months after first eye
      surgery.

      61 patients have been enrolled as of August 2012.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2030</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in best-corrected glare visual acuity (BCGVA) at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical glare test to test glare sensitivity on visual acuity. An improvement of 2 lines or better on the Snellen eye chart under glare conditions is considered a positive outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction of 15% or more of the central endothelial cell density is considered an adverse safety event</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Endothelial cell count to measure cell density at 3 months post-operative status</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Need to explant or exchange the Morcher Iris Diaphragm</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA) at 2 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Visual Acuity test under non glare conditions for patients who undergo simultaneous cataract surgery. A 2-line improvement on the Snellen eye chart is considered a positive response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA) at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual Acuity test under non-glare conditions for patients who undergo simultaneous cataract surgery. A 2-line improvement on the Snellen eye chart is considered a positive response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA) at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual Acuity test under non glare conditions for patients who undergo simultaneous cataract surgery. A 2-line improvement on the Snellen eye chart is considered a positive response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA) at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual Acuity test under non glare conditions for patients who undergo simultaneous cataract surgery. A 2-line improvement on the Snellen eye chart is considered a positive response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in best-corrected glare visual acuity (BCGVA) at 2 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical glare test to test glare sensitivity on visual acuity. An improvement of 2 lines or better on the Snellen eye chart under glare test conditions is considered a positive outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in best-corrected glare visual acuity (BCGVA) at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical glare test to test glare sensitivity on visual acuity. An improvement of 2 lines or better on the Snellen eye chart under glare test conditions is considered a positive outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in best-corrected glare visual acuity (BCGVA) at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical glare test to test glare sensitivity on visual acuity. An improvement of 2 lines or better on the Snellen eye chart under glare conditions is considered a positive outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">72</enrollment>
  <condition>Aniridia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Morcher artificial iris implantation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A Morcher artificial iris will be implanted inside the eye. Reduction in glare sensitivity and other outcomes will be measured.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>Surgical implantation of Morcher iris device(s)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Morcher artificial iris implantation</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Morcher modified capsule tension rings (models 96F and 50F)</other_name>
    <other_name>Morcher iris reconstruction lens (model 67B)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patient must be 18 years old and have partial or complete aniridia

          -  Be willing and able to comply with all follow-up requirements

          -  Must have increased light and/or glare sensitivity or complete aniridia

          -  Patients may be phakic, aphakic, or pseudophakic

          -  Phakic patients will require simultaneous cataract surgery

          -  Aphakic patients will require secondary IOL implantation

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  The presence of any ocular condition that may cause complications from the surgical
             procedure

          -  Active ocular infection or inflammation

          -  Patients with allergies to operative and/or postoperative medications

          -  Pregnant or lactating women

          -  Persons who, in the determination of the investigator, are not competent to
             understand the procedure or the actions asked of them as research subjects
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kevin M Miller, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, Los Angeles</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jules Stein Eye Institute, UCLA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90095-7002</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://bmctoday.net/advancedocularcare/2010/12/article.asp?f=iris-prosthetics</url>
    <description>Related article: Iris Prosthetics. Advanced Ocular Care. December 2010</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://bmctoday.net/crstoday/2012/01/article.asp?f=cataract-and-lost-iris-tissue-after-trauma</url>
    <description>Related article: Cataract and lost iris tissue after trauma. Cataract &amp; Refractive Surgery Today. January 2012</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Olson MD, Masket S, Miller KM. Interim results of a compassionate-use clinical trial of Morcher iris diaphragm implantation: report 1. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2008 Oct;34(10):1674-80. doi: 10.1016/j.jcrs.2008.05.048.</citation>
    <PMID>18812117</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chung MY, Miller KM, Weissman BA. Morcher iris reconstruction lens and rigid contact lens for traumatic aniridia. Eye Contact Lens. 2009 Mar;35(2):108-10. doi: 10.1097/ICL.0b013e318199b00b.</citation>
    <PMID>19265334</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 26, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 19, 2008</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, Los Angeles</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kevin M. Miller, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Kolokotrones Professor of Clinical Ophthalmology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>aniridia</keyword>
  <keyword>Morcher iris diaphragms</keyword>
  <keyword>modified capsule tension ring</keyword>
  <keyword>artificial iris</keyword>
  <keyword>iris reconstruction lens</keyword>
  <keyword>glare sensitivity</keyword>
  <keyword>photophobia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aniridia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
