<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01105559</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the long term immunogenicity produced in children by the investigational hexavalent vaccine (DTaP-IPV-Hep B-PRP-T) given in Study A3L15 (NCT 00362336). Primary Objective: To describe the antibody long term persistence at 3.5 and 4.5 years of age following a 3 dose primary series vaccination of either DTaP-IPV-Hep B-PRP-T or CombAct-Hib™ + Oral poliovirus vaccine (OPV) + Engerix™ B vaccination at 6, 10 and 14 weeks of age and a booster vaccination of DTaP-IPV-Hep B-PRP-T or CombAct-Hib™ + OPV at 15-18 months</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Antibody Persistence in Healthy Children After Primary and Booster DTaP-IPV-Hep B-PRP-T Vaccine or Control Vaccine</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All participants must have received the primary series of vaccinations and a booster vaccination in Study A3L15 (NCT 00362336). Participants will receive no vaccination in this study but will undergo immunologic assessments at 3.5 and 4.5 years of age.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tetanus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diphtheria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Poliomyelitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Whooping Cough</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria : Aged 3 years and a half on the day of inclusion (42 months ± 60 days) Informed consent form signed by a parent or other legally acceptable representative and by an independent witness if the parent or other legal guardian is illiterate. Subject and parent/ legally acceptable representative able to attend the scheduled visits and to comply with all trial procedures. Receipt of primary vaccination with 3 doses of either DTaPIPVHep BPRPT or CombActHib™ + Oral poliovirus vaccine (OPV) + Engerix™ B and a booster dose of either DTaPIPVHep BPRPT or CombActHib™+ OPV. Exclusion Criteria : Participation in another clinical trial investigating a vaccine, drug, medical device, or a medical procedure in the 4 weeks preceding the inclusion in the trial. Incomplete primary and booster immunization at trial A3L15. Previous confirmed clinical, serological, or microbiological diagnosis of diphtheria, tetanus, whooping cough, poliomyelitis, Haemophilus influenza b or hepatitis B after completion of A3L15 Study. Subjects known to have received diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis, Haemophilus influenza b and hepatitis B vaccination after completion of A3L15 Study. Any vaccination within 30 days preceding inclusion, except for measles or poliovirus (monovalent) containing vaccines and pandemic influenza vaccines including pandemic H1N12009 strain, which may be received at least two weeks before the subject's blood sample collection Blood or bloodderived products received at the latest 3 months before inclusion, receipts of immunosuppressant drugs within the previous 3 months. Known or suspected congenital or acquired immunodeficiency since completion of A3L15 Study. Serious chronic illness occurring after receipt of the primary and booster series (e.g. leukemia, lymphoma [Tor B cells], Crohn's disease). Known or suspected subject seroconversion for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or hepatitis C seropositivity since completion of A3L15 Study. Febrile (temperature ≥ 38.0°C) or acute, moderate or severe systemic illness on the day of inclusion.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>41 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>43 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diphtheria</keyword>
	<keyword>Tetanus</keyword>
	<keyword>Whooping cough</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis B</keyword>
	<keyword>Poliomyelitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Diphtheria-Tetanus-acellular Pertussis Vaccines</keyword>
</DOC>