<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00121641</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical research study is to learn whether saxagliptin (BMS-477118) is more effective than placebo as a treatment for type 2 diabetic subjects who are not sufficiently controlled with diet and exercise</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Saxagliptin Treatment in Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes Who Are Not Controlled With Diet and Exercise</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All subjects will participate in a lead-in period, and qualifying subjects will continue into a short-term randomized treatment period. Subjects who complete the short-term period will be eligible to enter the long term extension period. Also, subjects in the short-term period who have an elevated blood sugar that requires additional medication for blood sugar control will be eligible to enter the long-term treatment extension period where they will receive metformin added onto their blinded study medication. Subjects with screening hemoglobin A1c (A1C) &gt; 10.0% and ≤ 12.0%, who otherwise meet all inclusion/exclusion criteria, were eligible to enroll directly into Open-Label Treatment Cohort (Direct Enrollees) and receive open-label saxagliptin 10 mg. Those who completed the short-term period were eligible to enter into the long-term treatment extension period.Saxagliptin dose titration was not permitted.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Saxagliptin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 2 diabetes mellitus Drug naive Hemoglobin (Hb) A1c &gt;= 7.0% and &lt;= 10.0% (&gt;10% and &lt;= 12% for open label arm) Fasting Cpeptide &gt;= 1 ng/mL Body mass index &lt;= 40 kg/m2 Symptomatic poorly controlled diabetes Recent cardiac or cerebrovascular event Serum creatinine &gt;= 1.5 mg/dL for males and &gt;= 1.4 mg/dL for Women of Child Bearing Potential</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>77 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>