<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00150046</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will test the safety and efficacy of everolimus on heart transplant recipients. This study is not recruiting in the United States.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Everolimus in de Novo Heart Transplant Recipients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female cardiac recipients 1865 years of age undergoing primary heart transplantation. The graft must be functional at the time of randomization. Calculated creatinine clearance (CockroftGault) ≥ 50 mL/min at screening. Patients who have given written informed consent to participate in the study. Patients who are recipients of multiple solid organ transplants or have previously received organ transplants. Patients who received any investigational drug or who have been treated with an immunosuppressive drug or treatment within 1 month prior to randomization Patients receiving induction therapy which is not standard per local practice Patients with donor greater than 60 years and/or with known donor coronary or heart disease at the time of transplant. Donor heart cold ischemic time &gt;6 hours. Patients with Panel Reactive Antibodies &gt;20%. Patients who are recipients of ABO incompatible transplants Patients with platelet count &lt;50,000/mm3 at the evaluation before randomization. Presence of severe hypercholesterolemia (≥350 mg/dL; ≥9 mmol/L) or hypertriglyceridemia (≥750 mg/dL; ≥8.5 mmol/L) Patients with an absolute neutrophil count of ≤1,500/mm3 or white blood cell count of ≤4000/mm3 at baseline before surgery Patients with a history of significant coagulopathy or medical condition requiring long term anticoagulation after transplantation (low dose aspirin treatment is allowed) Patients who are HIVpositive or Hepatitis C (PCR+ only) or B surface antigen positive. Laboratory results obtained within 6 months prior to study entry are acceptable. Recipients of organs from donors who test positive for Hepatitis B surface antigen or Hepatitis C (PCR+ only) are excluded Patients with a known hypersensitivity to similar drugs and to the components of the formulations Patients being treated with terfenadine, astemizole, or cisapride. Patients who are treated with drugs strong inducers or inhibitors of cytochrome P450 3A4. Patients with any past (within the past 5 years) or present malignancy (other than excised basal cell carcinoma) Patients with clinically significant systemic infection Patients who are unable to take oral medication Existence of any surgical or medical condition, which in the opinion of the investigator, might significantly alter the absorption, distribution, metabolism and excretion of study medication, and/or the presence of severe diarrhea or active peptic ulcer Abnormal physical or laboratory findings of clinical significance within 2 weeks of randomization which would interfere with the objectives of the study Females of childbearing potential who are planning to become pregnant, who are pregnant and/or lactating, who are unwilling to use effective means of contraception</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Heart transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Everolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>Heart transplant recipient</keyword>
</DOC>