<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02018432</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Main adverse events of Roflumilast are weight loss, loss of appetite, insomnia, headache, diarrhea, vomiting, and nausea. Although the majority of these adverse reactions were mild or moderate. They occurred mainly at the beginning of therapy and mostly resolved with continued treatment around for two weeks according to experiences of clinicians. These adverse events occur more often in Roflumilast 500 μg than 250 μg, having negative impact on compliance of patients at the early stage of treatments. Thus, investigators aim to compare the drop-out rates between the usual dosage (Roflumilast 500 μg once daily) and the dose escalation (Roflumilast 250 μg once daily for 4 weeks and then escalating dose of 500 μg once daily).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Strategy to Improve Adherence of Roflumilast</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female older than 40 years 2. Clinical diagnosis of COPD (confirmed with a postbronchodilator forced expiratory volume in 1 s [FEV1]/forced vital capacity [FVC] ratio ≤70%) at least 4 weeks prior to the study and postbronchodilator FEV1 is 50% or less than the predicted value 3. Former smokers or current smokers with at least a 10 packyear history 4. A history of exacerbation (scheduled/unscheduled visits to primary care physicians, specialists or allied healthcare professionals, or emergency room, or hospitalization due to purulent sputum or increased sputum, or increased dyspnea) in the previous year (at least one) 5. Chronic bronchitis (cough and sputum production for at least three months within two years) 6. Able to have the signed written informed consent prior to any studyrelated procedures. 1. COPD exacerbation or respiratory infection 4 weeks prior to the baseline visit 2. Known a1antitrypsin deficiency 3. Need for longterm oxygen therapy 4. Moderate to severe liver impairment (ChildPugh B or C) 5. Severe immunological diseases (e.g. HIV infection, multiple sclerosis, lupus erythematosus, etc) 6. Severe acute infectious diseases 7. Cancers 8. Subjects being treated with immunosuppressive medicinal products (i.e.: methotrexate, azathioprine, infliximab, etanercept, or oral corticosteroids to be taken longterm) except shortterm systemic corticosteroids) 9. Latent infections such as tuberculosis, viral hepatitis, herpes viral infection and herpes zoster 10. Subjects with congestive heart failure (NYHA grades 3 and 4) 11. Subjects with a history of depression associated with suicidal ideation or behavior 12. Clinically meaningful bronchiectasis 13. Pregnancy or breast feeding, or Female subjects of childbearing potential unwilling to use effective contraception 14. Patients with known hypersensitivity to Roflumilast or rescue medication and their ingredients 15. Patients with previous Roflumilast therapy within past 3 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>