<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01986348</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label, multicenter, Phase 2 study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of oral Selinexor in patients with recurrent gliomas.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 2 Study Evaluating the Efficacy and Safety of Selinexor (KPT-330) in Patients With Recurrent Gliomas</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label, multicenter, Phase 2 study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of oral selinexor in patients with recurrent gliomas. Initially, the study included 2 arms: an exploratory Surgical Arm (Arm A) with sequential enrollment for patients who require surgery and a medical arm (Arm B) for patients who are not eligible for surgery. Enrollment in Arm B was stopped to explore alternative dosing in Protocol Versions ≥ 4.0 to potentially improve tolerability. Four arms (Arms C, D, E, and F) were added to the Medical Arm in Protocol Version 4.0. Patients in the primary population enrolled under Protocol Version 4.0 or above will be randomized to Arm C and Arm D (approximately 30 patients per arm) to explore alternative dosing to potentially improve tolerability. Patients with malignant gliomas other than glioblastoma (GBM) (Arm E; approximately 20 patients) and patients with GBM or AG that is refractory to antiangiogenic treatment (Arm F; approximately 10 patients) will be enrolled to evaluate preliminary evidence of the efficacy of Selinexor in those exploratory populations. After screening and registration/randomization in the study, patients enrolling in Arms A and E or randomized to Arm C will receive 60 mg Selinexor orally twice weekly. Patients randomized to Arm D will receive 80 mg Selinexor orally weekly. Enrollment in Arm F will not begin until the first stage results for Arms C and D are available. Dosing for Arm F will be selected based on the first stage results for Arms C and D. Patients will be treated until progression of disease or the development of unacceptable toxicities. All patients will then undergo the End of Treatment (EOT) visit.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed diagnosis, as follows: 1. Arms A, B, C, and D: Pathologically confirmed GBM (including all histologic variants) at first diagnosis with radiographic evidence of recurrent disease after treatment with radiotherapy and temozolomide; 2. Arm E: Pathologically confirmed malignant gliomas other than GBM (WHO Grade 2 or Grade 3), with radiographic evidence of recurrent disease after treatment with radiotherapy and at least one line of systemic treatment; 3. Arm F: Pathologically confirmed GBM (including all histologic variants) or AG that is refractory to antiangiogenic treatment (defined as recurrence or progression of disease per RANO criteria during prior therapy with bevacizumab or other direct VEGF/VEGFR inhibitors) with radiographic evidence of recurrent disease after treatment with radiotherapy and temozolomide; 18 years of age or older Patients enrolling in the medical arm (Arms B,C, D, E, and F) must be on a stable or decreasing dose of corticosteroids (or none) for at least 5 days prior to the baseline MRI; Measurable disease (according to RANO guidelines) Surgical arm (Arm A) must be predicted preoperatively to have sufficiently sized tumor to be resected and provide tissue samples for exploratory assessments. Markedly decreased visual acuity if attributed to other causes than GBM for Arms A, C, and D, malignant gliomas other than GBM (WHO Grade 2 or Grade 3) for Arm E, or GBM or AG that is refractory to antiangiogenic treatment for Arm F. Known active hepatitis A, B, or C Patients with coagulation problems and medically significant bleeding in the month prior to start of treatment (e.g., peptic ulcer, epistaxis, spontaneous bleeding). Prior history of DVT or PE is not exclusionary. Patients must not have significantly diseased or obstructed gastrointestinal tract, malabsorption, uncontrolled vomiting or diarrhea, or inability to swallow oral medications. Arms A, B, C, and D, only: Prior treatment with bevacizumab or other direct VEGF/ VEGFR inhibitors. For any question of the definition of a direct VEGF/VEGFR inhibitor, consult Sponsor. Arms C and D only: body surface area &lt; 1.2 m2. &lt; 24 days from prior temozolomide, &lt; 6 weeks from nitrosourea, &lt; 4 weeks from other chemotherapy or investigational agents prior to start of treatment within study. For Arm F only: &lt; 6 weeks from prior bevacizumab or other direct VEGF/VEGFR inhibitor prior to start of treatment within the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>GBM</keyword>
	<keyword>Glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>selinexor</keyword>
	<keyword>KPT-330</keyword>
	<keyword>Karyopharm</keyword>
	<keyword>brain tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>brain cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>Astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Oligodendrogliomas</keyword>
	<keyword>Oligo-astrocytomas</keyword>
</DOC>