<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01986218</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of daily doses of BMS-986115 in subjects with advanced solid tumors</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase I Ascending Multiple-Dose Study of BMS-986115 in Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>For more information regarding BMS clinical trial participation, please visit www.BMSStudyConnect.com. Subjects with a histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of solid tumors, advanced or metastatic, refractory to or relapsed from standard therapies or for which there is no known effective treatment Life expectancy of at least 3 months Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status score 01 Prior anticancer treatments are permitted (i.e., chemotherapy, radiotherapy, hormonal, or immunotherapy) At least 4 weeks must have elapsed from last dose of prior anticancer therapy and the initiation of study therapy Subjects with known or suspected brain metastases, primary brain tumors, or brain as the only site of disease Evidence of uncontrolled, active infection, requiring systemic antibacterial, antiviral or antifungal therapy ≤ 7 days prior to administration of study medication Current or recent (within 3 months of study drug administration) gastrointestinal disease such as chronic or intermittent diarrhea, or disorders that increase the risk of diarrhea, such as inflammatory bowel disease. Nonchronic conditions (e.g. infectious diarrhea) that are completely resolved for at least 2 weeks prior to starting study treatment are not exclusionary Any major surgery or gastrointestinal disease that would interfere with administration of oral medications Conditions requiring chronic systemic glucocorticoid use, such as autoimmune disease or severe asthma, excluding inhalation steroids for maintenance. Uncontrolled or significant cardiovascular disease History of medically significant thromboembolic events or bleeding diathesis within the past 6 months Inadequate bone marrow function (Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt; 1,500 cells/mm3; Platelet count &lt; 100,000 cells/mm3; Hemoglobin &lt; 9.0 g/dL) Inadequate hepatic function (Total bilirubin &gt; 1.5 times the institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) (except known Gilbert's syndrome); Alanine transaminase (ALT) or aspartate transaminase (AST) &gt; 2.5 times the institutional ULN. ALT or AST up to 3 times the institutional ULN permitted if total bilirubin is normal Uncontrolled (≥ Grade 2) hypertriglyceridemia (fasting triglycerides &gt; 300 mg/dL (3.42 mmol/L)) Inadequate renal function (Blood creatinine &gt; 1.5 times the institutional ULN) Positive blood screen for hepatitis C antibody, hepatitis B surface antigen, or Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) 1, 2 antibody</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>