<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00234169</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Hematopoietic stem cells (HSC) are used to support the administration of high dose chemotherapy for a range of human cancers. For a safe HSC transplantation, a minimum of 5 million HSC per kilogram are required. HSC are collected from the bone marrow by using drugs such as G-CSF (filgrastim) which 'mobilize' them from the bone marrow into the bloodstream. HSC are collected from the bloodstream using an apheresis machine. Between 5 and 60% of patients fail to mobilize the minimum HSC dose required for safe transplantation, and this trial is investigating a way to enhance mobilization to overcome this problem. This trial aims to determine if a new vitamin A derivative is capable of enhancing HSC mobilization when used in conjunction with G-CSF. Patients will undergo two mobilization procedures. They will be given G-CSF alone, or a combination of the study drug plus G-CSF, and their stem cells will be collected. A comparison group of patients will be given G-CSF alone for both mobilizations. Stem cells collected from patients in this trial will be frozen and stored until they are required for transplantation into that patient. At that time, patients will be monitored for how well they recover from their high dose chemotherapy and HSC transplantation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Peripheral Blood Progenitor Cells Mobilisation (PBPC) With VTP195183 Plus Granulocyte-Colony Stimulating Factor (G-CSF) Compared to Mobilisation With G-CSF Alone</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenograstim</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 1870 2. Histologically proven multiple myeloma or lymphoma 3. Intent of treating physician to proceed to high dose therapy and autologous transplantation 4. Not currently receiving thalidomide (within 1 week of commencing VTP195813 or GCSF), cytotoxic agents or high dose prednisolone or Dexamethasone (at doses greater than 15 mg prednisolone or equivalent per day) 5. Multiple myeloma patients must be taking regular bisphosphonate therapy 6. Absolute neutrophil count between 1.5 and 10 x 109/L 7. ECOG performance status ? 2 8. Life expectancy of at least 2 months 9. Written informed consent signed by patient or legally authorized representative 1. Active infection or a fever &gt; 38.2 degrees C (fever due to B symptoms in lymphoma patients will not exclude a patient) 2. Use within the previous 30 days of other vitamin A preparations within the last 30 days (including oral vitamin supplements, oral retinoids for acne or other skin disorders, bexarotene, or topical vitamin A preparations) 3. Pregnancy or breast feeding. Women of childbearing potential, admitted to the trial must take adequate measures to prevent conception (at least two different forms of contraception during the study and for at least one month after completion of study drugs) and are to undergo a pregnancy test 4. Significant nonmalignant disease including HIV infection, uncontrolled hypertension (diastolic blood pressures &gt; 115 mmHg), unstable angina 5. Known allergy to E.coliderived products 6. Current treatment with tetracycline antibiotics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>