<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00234416</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the trial is to identify the dose of gemcitabine given as a 2-hour intravenous (iv) infusion that can be administered in combination with ZD1839 250 mg once daily and a standard course (45 Grays [Gy]) of radiotherapy in patients with locally advanced, unresectable pancreatic cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>IRESSA Combined With Radiotherapy &amp; Gemcitabine as First-Line Treatment in Locally Advanced Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gefitinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed pancreatic cancer (aspiration biopsy by fine needle [PAAF] by USE or biopsy guide by ECOCT). It is mandatory the diagnostic by USE and will recommend the aspiration biopsy with this technique Tumoural volume by TAC &lt; 500 cc Aged 18 to 75 years inclusive Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) £ 1 Lifeexpectancy of more than 12 weeks Women of childbearing potential must be willing to practice reliable methods of birth control to prevent pregnancy Previous radiotherapy or chemotherapy for malignant disease Other coexisting malignancies or malignancies diagnosed within the last 5 years with the exception of basal cell carcinoma or cervical cancer in situ In the opinion of the investigator, any evidence of severe or uncontrolled systemic disease (e.g. unstable or uncompensated respiratory, cardiac, hepatic or renal disease) Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) less than 1.5 x 109/litre (L), platelets less than 100 x 109/L or haemoglobin less than 9 mg/dL; Prothrombin time (PT) less than 50%; Serum bilirubin greater than 2.5 times the upper limit of reference range (ULRR; Creatinine clearance less than 45 mL/min; ALT or AST greater than 2.5 times the ULRR Active dermatoses (e.g. psoriasis, eczema) Concomitant use of phenytoin, carbamazepine, barbiturates, rifampicin, or drugs with known corneal toxicity Known, severe hypersensitivity to ZD1839 or any of the excipients of this product</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>EGF-R</keyword>
</DOC>