<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02068170</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A prospective, observational study in a university hospital (UZ Leuven). Patients are included when they are treated with a potentional QT-prolonging drug: haloperidol for delirium, antibiotics (moxifloxacin, levofloxacin, azithromycin, clarithromycin, erythromycin, co-trimoxazole), antimycotics (ketoconazole, itraconazole, fluconazole, voriconazole), methadone, tacrolimus and oral oncolytics. An ECG is taken before the administration of the drug and 3-5 days after starting the drug to investigate the change in duration of the QTc-interval. Risk factors for developing QT-prolongation will be documented. Together with ECG2, an additional blood sample will be collected to measure the blood concentration of the drug.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Risk of QT-prolongation and Torsade de Pointes in Patients Treated With Acute Medication in a University Hospital</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Delirium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Long QT Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Torsades de Pointes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Itraconazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Voriconazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketoconazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levofloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clarithromycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin Estolate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin Ethylsuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Moxifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluoroquinolones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxyitraconazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin stearate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trimethoprim, Sulfamethoxazole Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Haloperidol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Haloperidol decanoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methadone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sunitinib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Norgestimate, ethinyl estradiol drug combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>treatment with a potentional QTprolonging drug of our list inpatient of UZ Leuven, admitted on one of the participating wards &lt; 18 years old DNRcode 3 not possible to take an ECG before the start of haloperidol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>QT-prolongation</keyword>
	<keyword>Torsade de Pointes</keyword>
	<keyword>QT-prolonging drugs</keyword>
</DOC>