<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01017354</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This project was designed to optimizing vitamin D status in prefrail seniors age 70+ living at home and prevent their functional decline. We test 3 arms of monthly vitamin D supplementation. Intermittent dosing will improve adherence and simplify vitamin D supplementation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Zurich Disability Prevention Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We propose a double-blind, randomized controlled trial to test the effectiveness of a 1. Active I (n=70): monthly high-dose vitamin D3 supplement dose (60'000 IU/month, equivalent to 2000 IU daily), 2. Active II (n=70): or a monthly standard vitamin D3 supplement dose combined with 25(OH)D (24'000 IU/month, equivalent to 800 IU daily PLUS 300 mcg 25(OH)D, equivalent to 10 mcg per day) 3. Control (n=70): compared to a standard vitamin D3 supplement dose (24'000 IU/month, equivalent to 800 IU daily) All individuals will be advised to consume calcium from natural food sources in a daily dose of 600-800 mgs a day, including milk products. Maximal intake of supplemental calcium is restricted to 250 mg per day.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcifediol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Age 70+ Fall in the last 12 months before screening (with or without a fracture) Living at home (communitydwelling) Men or women Mobile with or without walking aid have to be able to use public transportation to attend the clinical visits at the trial centre Score of at least 27 at the screening Folstein Mini Mental test + normal clock test Patient understands the study procedures, alternative treatments available and risks involved with the study, and voluntarily agrees to participate by giving a written informed consents. Patient meets the entry minimal requirements based on routine clinical laboratory safety screening tests and the Folstein mini mental status (score 27+ required) performed at the Screening Visit. Patient is willing to perform all study tests, attend all required office visits, and provide blood and urine samples. Exclusion criteria: Serum calcium adjusted for albumin of &gt; 2.6 nmol/l Pathologic fracture in the last year (except for fractures due to osteoporosis) Chemo therapy / Radiation due to cancer in the last year Treatment which has an effect on bone metabolism (e.g. bisphosphonate, PTH, calcitonin, chronic cortisone intake &gt; XYmg/day for more than XY month/years (except for inhalation and sporadic infiltration)) Oral vitamin D intake of more than 800 IU per day Unwilling to stop calcium supplementation and vitamin D supplementation during the trial (maximal calcium supplement intake 250mg/d; no additional vitamin D supplementation) Severe visual or hearing impairment Unwilling or unable to take study medication Diseases with a risk of recurrent falling (e.g. Parkinson's disease/syndrome, Hemiplegia after stroke, symptomatic stenosis of the spinal canal, polyneuropathy, epilepsy, recurring vertigo, recurring syncope) BMI &gt;= 40 Estimated creatinine clearance &lt; 15 ml/min (estimated Creatinine Clearance Cockcroft and Gault) Malabsorption syndrome (celiac diseases, inflammatory bowl disease) Diseases that may enhance serum calcium: sarcoidosis, lymphoma, primary hyperparathyroidism kidney stone in the last 10 years Abnormal indices of calcium metabolism, uncontrolled hypocalcemia. Patient heavily consumes alcohol containing products defined as greater than (&gt;) 3 drinks (beer, wine, or distilled spirits) of alcoholic beverages per day. Patient is unlikely to adhere to the study procedures, to keep appointments, or is planning to relocate during the study. Patients who are planning a stay in a "sunny" location (e.g. winter sun resort) for more than two months per year Medication which has an effect on 25hydroxyvitamin D level (e.g. certain anticonvulsants (e.g. Phenobarbital, Carbamazepin, Phenytoin)) M. Paget (Ostitis deformans) inflammatory arthritis (e.g. rheumatoid arthritis, reiter syndrome, psoriasis arthritis)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>70 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>vitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>function</keyword>
	<keyword>falls</keyword>
	<keyword>25-hydroxyvitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>disability</keyword>
</DOC>