<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01017627</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators hypothesize that the post-hospitalized patient status is characterized by subacute and reversible metabolic and hematological changes that, if addressed and treated in a timely manner, would result in a reduced risk for repeat hospitalization. Consequently, a structured quality improvement program, focused on increasing adherence to company wide anemia management policies (ie hemoglobin monitoring within the first 3-5 days post-hospitalization, followed by an appropriate EPO dose modification within the 7 days post-hospitalization), will significantly decrease the risk of hospital re-admission in the 30 days after discharge.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Adherence to Anemia Management Policy on Repeat Hospitalization in End Stage Renal Disease (ESRD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The post-hospitalization quality improvement project will be piloted across 30 Fresenius clinics. Targeted enrollment of 1500 episodes of hospitalization in which the patient returns after discharge to resume outpatient dialysis. Patient outcomes will be followed for up to 30 days from the time of discharge from hospital.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age ≥ 18 resumption of routine outpatient chronic hemodialysis within three days of discharge from hospital admission enrolled in a facilitybased anemia management program enrolled in hospice previous hospitalization within the past 30 days (ie. patients discharged from a repeat hospitalization) anticipated discharge from the outpatient dialysis facility within 30 days (ie anticipated transfer to another facility or hospice)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>ESRD</keyword>
	<keyword>Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Hospitalizations</keyword>
	<keyword>Mortality</keyword>
</DOC>