<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01527422</DOC>
	<brief_summary>We now propose to investigate the combination of CHOP-Rituxan plus PEG-Filgrastim (PEG-filgrastim) and GM-CSF. PEG-Filgrastim would be given in order to allow us to administer the chemotherapy courses every 2 weeks with the practical advantage of requiring only one dose of PEG-filgrastim instead of daily doses of G-CSF.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cyclophosphamide, Doxorubicin, Vincristine, Prednisone, Rituximab Pateinets With Aggresive NHL</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>1.1 Primary Objective: 1. To identify the ideal dose of the combination of CHOP-R with PEG-Filgrastim (Neulasta) using first a fixed dose of Neulasta and an escalating dose of GM-CSF (Leukine) up to 250 mcg. When that dose is reached, if possible, the dose of Neulasta will be increased stepwise. CHOP-R will be delivered every 14 days at a fixed standard dose with dose adjustments of PEG-Filgrastim and GM-CSF upwards and downwards according to nadir or zenith blood counts. 1.2 Secondary Objective: 2. To generate preliminary pilot data as to the effectiveness of the regimen in inducing very early remissions as measured by the CT-PET scan technique.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vincristine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenograstim</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with previously untreated aggressive nonHodgkin's Lymphoma. Aggressive histologies include follicular large cell, diffuse large cell, peripheral T cell, transformed lymphomas, Lymphoblastic lymphomas, Burkitt and Burkitt like lymphomas. Must have measurable or evaluable disease. Stage IIV patients are eligible Patients must be 18 years or older. No evidence of grade 3 or more neurosensory or neuromotor dysfunction (see appendix toxicity criteria) Written Consent HIV positive patients and those with Hepatitis B or C will be excluded from this protocol. Patients with inadequate bone marrow and organ function as defined below: Neutrophils &lt;1,000/l Platelets &lt;100,000/l Billirubin &gt;2 Creatinine &gt;2.0 or estimated CrCl &lt;30 cc/min CNS involvement by Lymphoma. Uncontrolled intercurrent disease including arrhythmias, angina pectoris, Class IIIIV Congestive heart failure (CHF symptoms on less than ordinary exertion or at rest) or active infection. Active infection or fever &gt; 38.2 degrees C unless due to lymphoma. Subject is not using adequate contraceptive precautions. Pregnancy or breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Aggressive Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>