<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01527630</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted in Japan. The aim of this trial is to investigate the bioequivalence of two formulations of biphasic insulin aspart 50 (NN-X14Mix50) in healthy Japanese subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bioequivalence of Two Formulations of Biphasic Insulin Aspart 50 in Healthy Japanese Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin degludec, insulin aspart drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Biphasic Insulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Aspart</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Long-Acting</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Considered generally healthy upon completion of medical history and physical examination, as judged by the Investigator or SubInvestigator. Body Mass Index (BMI) between 1929 kg/m^2 (inclusive) Fasting plasma glucose between 3.86.0 mmol/L (both inclusive) Clinically significant abnormal haematology, biochemistry or urinalysis screening tests, as judged by the Investigator or SubInvestigator Any serious systemic infectious disease that had occurred during the 4 weeks prior to the screening, as judged by the Investigator or SubInvestigator Any intercurrent illness that might affect blood glucose, as judged by the Investigator or SubInvestigator Hepatitis B or C, or HIV (human immunodeficiency virus) positive Subjects with a first degree relative with diabetes mellitus History of or presence of diabetes, cancer or any clinically significant cardiac, respiratory, metabolic, renal, hepatic, gastrointestinal, endocrinological, dermatological, venereal, haematologic, neurologic, or psychiatric diseases or disorder Subjects who consumed more than 28 units of alcohol per week or who had a significant history of alcoholism or drug/chemical abuse Subjects who smoked more than 5 cigarettes per day Subjects who had taken part in strenuous exercise within 7 days prior to the screening</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>