<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01527305</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of paliperidone palmitate in schizophrenic inpatients who have experienced recent exacerbation of acute schizophrenia (that is within past 4 weeks).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Effectiveness and Safety of Paliperidone Palmitate in Subjects With Acute Schizophrenia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label (all people know the identity of the intervention), prospective (looking forward using periodic observations collected predominantly following participant enrollment), non-comparative and multicenter study to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of paliperidone palmitate in acute schizophrenic participants. This study consists of a screening phase (up to 7 days), treatment phase (13 weeks), and a study completion or early withdrawal visit. Safety evaluations will include adverse events, clinical laboratory tests, concomitant medications, physical examination, and vital signs, which will be monitored throughout the study. The total duration of study participation for each participant will be approximately 13 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paliperidone Palmitate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have a current diagnosis of schizophrenia as defined by Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders Version IV (DSMIV) Must be admitted to a hospital within 4 weeks prior to Screening experiencing an acute exacerbation of schizophrenia Have a positive and negative syndrome scale (PANSS) total score of more than or equal to 60 or clinical global impressions severity (CGIS) score of more than or equal to 4 (moderately ill) at Screening Agree to protocoldefined method of contraception Must be medically stable based on physical examination, medical history, vital signs, and clinical laboratory tests performed at Screening Have a primary active DSMIV Axis I diagnosis other than schizophrenia Have evidence of clinically significant cardiovascular, renal, hepatic, gastrointestinal, neurological, endocrine, metabolic or pulmonary disease in medical history, clinical laboratory or physical examination Have a history of neuroleptic malignant syndrome Participants at risk of suicide Have received clozapine within 1 month prior to Screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Antipsychotics</keyword>
	<keyword>Paliperidone Palmitate</keyword>
	<keyword>Paliperidone</keyword>
	<keyword>Invega</keyword>
	<keyword>Sustenna</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychotic disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychosis</keyword>
</DOC>