<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02456207</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the study is to assess the pharmacokinetic (PK) similarity of SCT400 versus rituximab (MabThera®) in patients with CD20+ B-cell Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma. The secondary objective of the study is to evaluate the pharmacodynamics (PD) and safety of SCT400 versus rituximab (MabThera®), as well as the presence of human anti-chimeric antibodies (HACA).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pharmacokinetic Study Comparing SCT400 And Rituximab in Patients With B-cell Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. aged from 18 to 75 years; 2. having histologically confirmed NHL expressing CD20 antigen; 3. having obtained CR (complete remission) or CRu (uncertain complete remisson) after the prior therapy; 4. ECOG performance status of 0 to 1 5. expected survival of at least ≥ 3 months; 6. signed an informed consent form which was approved by the institutional review board of the respective medical center . 1. had received rituximab or other antiCD20(+) monoclonal antibody treatment within 1 year before enrollment; 2. having to be at least 4 weeks beyond prior anticancer therapy including corticosteroid, or have not recovered from significant toxicities of prior therapy; 3. participating in other clinical trial within 30 days before enrolment; 4. with serious hematologic dysfunction (white blood cell count of &lt;3.0×103/uL; absolute neutrophil count of &lt;1.5×103/ uL; platelet count of &lt; 75×103/uL; hemoglobin level of &lt; 8.0 g/dL); hepatic dysfunction (total bilirubin level of &gt; 1.5×ULN; aspartate amino transferase (AST) and alanine amino transferase (ALT) levels of &gt;2.5 × ULN; renal dysfunction (serum creatinine level of &gt; 1.5×ULN ); and International normalized ratio (INR) and partial thromboplastin time or activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) &gt; 1.5 × ULN (unless on therapeutic coagulation); 5. had received live vaccine within 4 weeks prior to study entry; 6. with other malignancies ; or central nervous system (CNS) lymphoma, AIDSrelated lymphoma; or active opportunistic infection, a serious nonmalignant disease; 7. seropositive for HCV antibody, or HIV antibody, or hepatitis B virus surface antigen (HBsAg). HBc antibody seropositive, but HBV DNA and HBsAg negative patients may participle following consultation with a hepatitis expert regarding monitoring and use of HBV antiviral therapy, and provided they agree to receive treatment as indicated, 8. recent major surgery (within 28 days prior to study entry ); 9. with a history of allergic reaction or protein product allergy including murine proteins; 10. pregnant or lactating or not accepted birth control methods including male patients.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>