<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02223234</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall objective of the proposed study is to test, among Canadian families, the comparative effectiveness of 2 different versions (doses) of a family-based obesity prevention intervention that is tailored to families' behavioural risk profile. To achieve this objective, we will conduct a randomized controlled trial of families with children aged 18 months- 5 years. Families will be randomized to 1 of 3 conditions: 1) Monthly emails with general health information (Attention Control), 2) Tailored weekly emails and 2 home visits with a health educator (Email +2), 3) Tailored weekly emails and 4 home visits (Email +4). The intervention will last 6 months, with follow-up at 12-months post-intervention (18 months from baseline). We will examine the impact of the intervention on the children's body composition, weight-related behaviours, and biomarkers of diabetes and cardiovascular disease risk. We hypothesize that, compared to children in the Attention Control, children in the Email +2 and Email +4 conditions will achieve: 1. a smaller increase in adiposity (primary outcome), age- and gender-specific body mass index (BMI),over a 6-month intervention period. 2. higher frequency of family meals, child's sleep duration, physical activity, and fruit and vegetable intake and lower child's sugar-sweetened beverage intake, and sedentary behaviour over a 6-month intervention period. (secondary outcomes) 3. lower diastolic blood pressure, glycosylated hemoglobin, fasting glucose, fasting insulin, Low Density Lipoprotein (LDL) cholesterol, triglycerides, C-reactive protein, trans and saturated fats, and higher High Density Lipoprotein (HDL) cholesterol over a 6-month intervention period. We further hypothesize that there will be no significant difference in these outcomes between children in the conditions with 2 (Email +2) or 4 (Email +4) home visits.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Guelph Family Health Study: Pilot Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>families who have a child aged 18 months through 5 years live the Guelph area have a parent who can respond to questionnaires in English families who plan to move during the study period children with severe health conditions (such as severe cerebral palsy) that would prohibit them from participating in study activities</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>