<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02730923</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators hypothesize that the dual inhibition of mTORC1/mTORC2 by AZD2014 combined with inhibition of aromatase enzyme by anastrozole will act synergistically and may be an interesting therapeutic option for endometrial cancer with a manageable toxicity profile. The investigators proposal is to conduct a multicenter, 2-step, randomized, Phase I/II trial to evaluate the safety and efficacy of a combination treatment associating anastrozole to AZD2014 in advanced endometrial cancer patients. The study is divided in 2 steps : - A safety run-in phase aiming to evaluate the safety of the proposed combination AZD2014 + anastrozole (Arm A) versus anastrozole alone (Arm B). No dose escalation is scheduled (doses are based on maximum tolerated dose (MTD) defined for AZD2014 and the summary of product characteristics (SPC) of anastrozole). However, dose de-escalation for AZD2014 will be applied in case of toxicity. - A two-stage randomized Phase II part aiming to evaluate the clinical benefit of the AZD2014 + anastrozole (Arm A) combination therapy versus anastrozole (Arm B).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hormone Receptor Positive endometrIal Carcinoma Treated by Dual mTORC1/mTORC2 Inhibitor and Anastrozole (VICTORIA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>TREATMENT PLAN : Following randomisation patients will receive Arm A : AZD2014 plus anastrozole or Arm B: anastrozole alone AZD2014 will be administered with an intermittent schedule i.e. 125 mg bis in die (BID) intermittent with 2 days on followed by 5 days off per week for a total weekly dose of 500 mg/week (250mg D1 and D2, 5 days off) Anastrozole will be administered at the standard dose defined in the SPC i.e. 1mg/d, per os, continuously. Both treatment will be administered until progressive disease (PD), unacceptable toxicity or willingness to stop. STATISTICS : A total of 72 patients will be randomized in the study. Safety run-in Phase on the first 9 patients randomized - As no dose escalation will be performed, the safety will be evaluated following the treatment and 8-week follow-up of the first 6 patients by the experimental association AZD2014+anastrozole (experimental arm). By similarity to a classic 3+3 design, based on binomial probabilities, there is a 90% probability of observing one or more patients with a toxicity event, if that event occurs in at least 32% of the target population. Assuming a 2:1 randomization ratio, a total of 9 patients (Arm A - Experimental: 6 patients, Arm B - Control: 3 patients) will be enrolled in this safety run-in phase and will be included in the evaluation of Phase II part. Phase II The sample size calculation was based on a Simon optimal two-stage design, with a minimum success (8-week non progression) rate considered of interest p1=60% and an uninteresting rate p0=40%. Assuming a type I error alpha of 0.05 and 80% power, 46 evaluable patients are needed in the experimental arm to reject the null hypothesis H0: p≤p0 versus the alternative hypothesis H1: p ≥ p1 in a unilateral situation (16 patients in Stage I and 30 additional patients in Stage II). With a 2:1 randomization and based on the assumption that 5% of the patients may be non-evaluable, a total of 72 patients will be included in the study : 48 patients in Arm A - experimental and 24 patients in Arm B - control). DATA ENTRY, DATA MANAGEMENT AND STUDY MONITORING All the data concerning the patients will be recorded in the electronic case report form (eCRF) throughout the study. serious adverse event (SAE) reporting will be also paper-based by e-mail and/or Fax. The sponsor will perform the study monitoring and will help the investigators to conduct the study in compliance with the clinical trial protocol, Good Clinical Practices (GCP) and local law requirements.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aromatase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anastrozole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Postmenopausal female patient at the time of consent Histologicallyconfirmed diagnosis of advanced or recurrent endometrial carcinoma, not amenable to curative treatments. Carcinosarcoma are not eligible. Documented estrogen receptor and/or progesterone receptor positive endometrial cancer. Hormone receptor positivity is defined according to routine practice at each participating site. Availability of a pretreatment tumor sample (archival formalinfixed paraffinembedded (FFPE) block or fresh biopsy if feasible) and presence of at least one biopsiable tumor lesion for ontreatment biopsy Documented disease progression after no more than one prior firstline chemotherapy regimen and/or more than 2 lines endocrine therapy in the metastatic setting Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status (PS) 0 or 1 and minimum life expectancy of 8 weeks At least one measurable lesion according to response evaluation criteria in solid tumor (RECIST 1.1) Adequate bone marrow, renal and liver function as shown by: Absolute neutrophil count &gt; 1.5 x 109/L, Platelets &gt; 100 x 109/L, Hemoglobin (Hb) &gt;9 g/dL Serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 upper limit of normal (ULN), alanine aminotransferase and aspartate aminotransferase ≤ 2.5 ULN (≤ 5 ULN in patients with liver metastases) Creatinine clearance &gt; 50 mL/min (using Cockcroft formula, or MDRD formula for patients over 65 years Appendix 3 Creatinine Clearance) Fasting serum cholesterol ≤ 300 mg/dL (7.75 mmol/L) AND fasting triglycerides ≤ 2.5 ULN (lipidlowering drugs allowed), Fasting plasma glucose ≤7 mmol/L (126 mg/dL) Recovered from prior significant treatmentrelated toxicity i.e. no persistent treatmentrelated toxicity &gt; Grade 1 as per Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v4.3, except grade 2 alopecia, grade 2 anemia but with Hb &gt;9 g/dL. Minimal washout period before the start of the study drugs for the following treatments: Any anticancer treatment approved or investigational medicinal product :&gt; 21 days Any chemotherapy, radiation therapy, androgens : &gt; 21 days (not including palliative radiotherapy at focal sites). Any monoclonal antibody therapy: &gt; 4 weeks Major surgery: &gt; 4 weeks Minor surgery (excluding tumour biopsies) &gt;14 days. Any haemopoietic growth factors (e.g., filgrastim [granulocyte colonystimulating factor (GCSF)], sargramostim [granulocytemacrophage colonystimulating factor (GMCSF)]): &gt; 14 days Vaccinated with live, attenuated vaccines : &gt; 4 weeks. Sensitive or narrow therapeutic range substrates of the drug metabolising enzymes Cytochrome P4502C8 (CYP2C8), Cytochrome P4502C9 (CYP2C9), Cytochrome P4502C19 (CYP2C19), Cytochrome P4502D6 (CYP2D6) or the drug transporters Pglycoprotein (Pgp) (multidrug resistance (MDR1)), breast cancer resistance protein (BCRP), organic aniontransporting polypeptide 1B1 (OATP1B1), organic aniontransporting polypeptide 1B3 (OATP1B3), organic cation transporter 1 (OCT1) and organic cation transporter 2 (OCT2) Potent or moderate inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4/5, Pgp (MDR1) and BCRP Restricted CYP and transporter related comedications Patient willing to follow sunlightprotection measures. Patients should be advised of the need for sunlight protection measures during administration of AZD2014, and should be advised to adopt such measures for a period of 3 months after receiving their final dose of AZD2014. Patient able and willing to provide informed consent with ability to understand and willingness for followup visits. Covered by a medical insurance Patient pretreated by a nonsteroidal aromatase inhibitor Active uncontrolled or symptomatic central nervous system metastases or spinal cord compression Clinically relevant abnormal levels of potassium or sodium. Use of any forbidden concomitant treatment during the treatment period: Any anticancer treatment (approved or investigational) not mentioned in the protocol Chronic treatment with corticosteroids or other immunosuppressive agents. Stable low dose of corticosteroids are allowed (unless contraindicated) provided that they were initiated before the last disease progression or were started at least 4 weeks prior to study treatment. Topical or inhaled corticosteroids are allowed. Potent or moderate inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4/5, Pgp (MDR1) and BCRP (see Appendix 5 Restricted CYP and transporter related comedications) Sensitive or narrow therapeutic range substrates of the drug metabolising enzymes CYP2C8, CYP2C9, CYP2C19, CYP2D6 or the drug transporters Pgp (MDR1), BCRP, OATP1B1, OATP1B3, OCT1 and OCT2 outside the wash out period and restrictions presented in Appendix 5 Restricted CYP and transporter related comedications) Patient with known hypersensitivity to anastrozole or to any of the excipients (Lactose monohydrate, Povidone, Sodium starch glycollate, Magnesium stearate, Hypromellose, Macrogol 300, Titanium dioxide) History of hypersensitivity to active or inactive excipients of AZD2014 or drugs with a similar chemical structure or class to AZD2014 History of other malignancies except for basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, in situ cervical cancer, unless they have been diseasefree for at least five years Patient who has any severe and/or uncontrolled medical conditions such as: Recent history of specific cardiovascular events, or laboratory parameters that may affect cardiac parameters including : unstable angina pectoris, symptomatic congestive heart failure, myocardial infarction ≤6 months prior to start of study drug, serious uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmia, or any other clinically significant cardiac disease; Symptomatic congestive heart failure of New York heart Association Class III or IV Mean resting corrected QT interval (QTc), calculated using Fridericia's formula, &gt; 470 msec obtained from 3 electrocardiograms (ECGs), family or personal history of long or short QT syndrome, Brugada syndrome or known history of QTc prolongation or Torsade de Pointes within 12 months of the patient entering in the study Abnormal cardiac function at baseline :left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt;50% and shortening fraction (SF) &lt;15%. Any evidence of interstitial lung disease and uncompensated respiratory conditions. Active (acute or chronic) or uncontrolled severe infection, liver disease such as cirrhosis, decompensated liver disease, and active or chronic hepatitis (i.e. quantifiable hepatitis B virus (HBVDNA) and/or positive HbsAg, quantifiable hepatitis C virus (HCVRNA)), Active, bleeding diathesis Current refractory nausea and vomiting, chronic gastrointestinal diseases, inability to swallow the formulated product or previous significant bowel resection that would preclude adequate absorption of AZD2014. Rare hereditary problems of galactose intolerance, the Lapp lactase deficiency or glucosegalactose malabsorption Type 1 and uncontrolled Type 2 diabetes Preexisting renal disease including glomerulonephritis, nephritic syndrome, Fanconi Syndrome or renal tubular acidosis.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Clinical Trials, Randomized</keyword>
	<keyword>Clinical Trial, Phase I</keyword>
	<keyword>Clinical Trial, Phase II</keyword>
	<keyword>Multicenter Trials</keyword>
	<keyword>Aromatase Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>mTOR kinase inhibitor</keyword>
</DOC>