<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02730871</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the additive intraocular pressure (IOP) lowering effect of Brinzolamide 1%/Brimonidine 0.2% (SIMBRINZA®) dosed twice daily (BID) when added to Travoprost 0.004%/Timolol 0.5% (DUOTRAV®) in subjects with open-angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of SIMBRINZA® BID as an Adjunctive to DUOTRAV®</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is divided into 2 sequential phases for a total of 5 visits. Phase I of the study is the open-labeled Screening/Eligibility Phase, which includes a Screening Visit followed by 2 Eligibility Visits. Phase II of the study is the randomized, double-masked Treatment Phase, which includes 2 on-therapy visits: Visit 4 (at Week 2) and Visit 5 (Week 6, Exit Visit).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma, Open-Angle</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ocular Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brimonidine Tartrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Travoprost</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Timolol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brinzolamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of openangle glaucoma (including pseudoexfoliation or pigment dispersion glaucoma) or ocular hypertension. Currently on treatment with Travoprost 0.004%/Timolol 0.5% prescribed as approved in the country, on evening dosing for at least 28 days prior to screening, and in the opinion of the Investigator may benefit from further IOP lowering. Mean IOP measurements at both the Eligibility 1 and Eligibility 2 visits, in at least 1 eye (the same eye(s) ≥ 21 and ≤ 28 mmHg at 9:00 while on a Travoprost 0.004%/ Timolol 0.5% solution. Able to understand and sign an informed consent form that has been approved by an Institutional Review Board/Ethics Committee. Willing and able to attend all study visits. Other protocoldefined inclusion criteria may apply. Women of childbearing potential: not postmenopausal for at least 1 year or less than 6 weeks since sterilization, currently pregnant; have a positive result on the urine pregnancy test at Screening; intend to become pregnant during the study period; breastfeeding; or not in agreement to use adequate birth control methods to prevent pregnancy throughout the study. Any form of glaucoma other than openangle glaucoma or ocular hypertension. Severe central visual field loss in either eye. Chronic, recurrent or severe inflammatory eye disease in either eye. Ocular trauma in either eye within the past 6 months prior to the Screening visit. Ocular infection or ocular inflammation in either eye within the past 3 months prior to the Screening visit. Retinal degeneration, diabetic retinopathy, or retinal detachment in either eye. Bestcorrected visual acuity score worse than 55 ETDRS letters (equivalent to approximately 20/80 Snellen, 0.60 logMAR or 0.25 decimal) in either eye. Other ocular pathology (including severe dry eye) in either eye that may, in the opinion of the Investigator, preclude the safe administration of any study medication. Intraocular surgery in either eye within the past 6 months prior to the Screening visit. Ocular laser surgery in either eye within the past 3 months prior to the Screening visit. Any other condition including severe illness which would make the subject, in the opinion of the Investigator, unsuitable for the study. Asthma, history of asthma, or severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>