<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01061996</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective Safety: assess the safety of basiliximab 40 mg, given every 4 weeks, in subjects with ulcerative colitis who completed previous basiliximab studies. Secondary Objectives: evaluate the efficacy and assess the immunogenicity of this multiple-dose maintenance regimen in this population</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Basiliximab Maintenance in Ulcerative Colitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Basiliximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Previously met eligibility criteria in the previous basiliximab UC study 2. Must have a total Mayo score at entry consistent with clinical response or clinical remission. 3. Signed a current IRB/IECapproved informed consent form 4. Females of childbearing potential must use an effective birth control method, and be willing to continue birth control during the study, and for 4 months after the last dose of study drug. 5. Females of nonchildbearing potential should be surgically sterile (bilateral tubal ligation with surgery at least 6 months before study entry, hysterectomy, or bilateral oophorectomy at least 2 months before study entry) or postmenopausal for at least 2 years. 1. Subject is severely ill, as evidenced by more than 6 episodes of loose stools, all of them bloody, during a 24hour period within the prior 7 days, concurrent with any of the following systemic features: Heart rate &gt; 90 beats/min at rest Temperature &gt; 37.8 degrees C Hemoglobin &lt; 10.5 g/dL 2. Subject is currently receiving a restricted/prohibited concomitant medication 3. Subject has undergone colectomy (total, or subtotal) 4. Subject is pregnant or breastfeeding 5. Prior noncompliance with previous study visit schedule and requirements</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ulcerative Colitis</keyword>
</DOC>