<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01061489</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Age-related cognitive decline is unavoidable. However, recent results of neuroplasticity-based research show that neuroplasticity-based training and physical activity might have the potential to decelerate or even reverse effects of aging and age-related cognitive impairments. Little is known whether these results also apply to pathological processes of aging such as mild cognitive impairment (MCI) and dementia. This multi-center study aims at investigating efficiency and feasibility of a neuroplasticity-based auditory discrimination training and a physical fitness training for patients suffering from mild cognitive impairment or mild Alzheimer's disease (Mini Mental State Examination, MMSE &gt; 19). Evaluation will include neuropsychological testing, electroencephalography (EEG) and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) measurements as well as blood and liquor analyses.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sensory-cognitive and Physical Fitness Training in Mild Cognitive Impairment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<criteria>focus: subjective and/or objective memory complaints with MMSE &gt; 19 (MCI or mild Alzheimer's Disease, with stable medication for at least 3 months) mild to moderate depression correctedtonormal hearing and vision for MRI: nonmagnetic metals inside the body right handedness preferred cognitive impairment/ dementia with MMSE &lt; 20, severe psychiatric or neurological disease (current and lifetime) physical health that does not allow physical fitness tests and trainings benzodiazepin, tricyclic antidepressants for MRI: magnetic metal inside the body, cardiac pacemaker etc. for liquor: insufficient blood coagulation, insufficient brain pressure</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>neuroplasticity</keyword>
	<keyword>Mild Cognitive Impairment (MCI)</keyword>
	<keyword>Alzheimer</keyword>
	<keyword>sensory-cognitive training</keyword>
	<keyword>physical fitness</keyword>
</DOC>