<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00387387</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will test the safety of treating colorectal cancer with a combination of drugs. The current standard treatments of FOLFOX6 or CapeOx will be give in combination with the GSK investigational drug pazopanib.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study On Pazopanib When Given With FOLFOX6 (Fluorouracil, Oxaliplatin, Leucovorin) Or CapeOx (Capecitabine, Oxaliplatin)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of locally advanced or metastatic colorectal cancer. No prior chemotherapy for metastatic disease. Presence of radiologically and/or clinically documented disease. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of 0 or 1. Adequate bone marrow, hepatic, renal function, Urine Creatinine Ratio (UPC) of &lt; A female subject must not be pregnant or breast feeding. Able to swallow and retain oral medications. Has had any major surgery, chemotherapy, hormone therapy, investigational agent, or radiotherapy within the last 28 days Prior treatment with pazopanib, or oxaliplatin. Known contraindications to the use of oxaliplatin, capecitabine, 5fluorouracil, or folinic acid. Participation in any investigational study within 28 days prior to study treatment. Women who are pregnant or lactating. Poorly controlled hypertension. A history of cardiovascular disease, arrhythmias, or significant ECG abnormalities. Any history of stroke. Current use of therapeutic warfarin. Known brain metastases. History of disease significantly affecting gastrointestinal function or major resection of the stomach or small bowel. Active infections or other serious illness. History of allergy to platinum compounds or heparin. Poor venous access.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>colorectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>pazopanib</keyword>
	<keyword>capecitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>CapeOx</keyword>
	<keyword>5-fluorouracil</keyword>
	<keyword>oxaliplatin</keyword>
	<keyword>combination therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>FOLFOX 6</keyword>
</DOC>