<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02771028</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this trial the investigators aim to establish whether Emotional Freedom Techniques (EFT) can reduce cognitive complaints in cancer survivors. All consenting patients aged 18 years or above, who have been diagnosed with a solid tumour of hematologic malignancy and who have completed or are in the late phase of a chemotherapy, radiotherapy, anti-hormonal or targeted therapy treatment, can participate in this trial. Patients should suffer from subjective cognitive complaints based on a score of 43 or more on the Cognitive Failure Questionnaire (CFQ). These patients will be randomly assigned to either the control or intervention group. Patients in the intervention group will be scheduled to receive an 8-week EFT intervention program. Other patients will be placed on an 8-week wait list after which patients will also start the EFT program.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Emotional Freedom Techniques as an Intervention Strategy to Reduce Patient Reported Cognitive Complaints in Cancer Survivors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Patients should have reached a minimum age of 18 years at the time of enrolment Histologically confirmed diagnosis of a solid cancer or hematologic malignancy Patients should have received chemo or radiotherapy, targeted therapy of hormonal treatment before enrollment (active treatment with antihormonal therapy or brachytherapy is allowed) Patients can be included in the latest phase of their chemotherapy, radiotherapy, antihormonal or targeted therapy treatment Patients should have been treated with curative intent or have an expected life expectancy of at least 5 years Patients must suffer from subjective cognitive complaints based on the Cognitive Failure Questionnaire (cutoff ≥ 43) Patients should be able to adequately communicate in Dutch or French Patients should present with a sufficient mental and physical functional status (according to investigator's judgment) Patients who received a treatment with palliative intent Patients showing signs of mental deterioration Patients suffering from an organic brain syndrome Patients who are alcohol or drug dependent Patients with a major psychiatric or neurologic disorder that could potentially invalidate assessment; a prior or current diagnosis of a depressive, anxiety or adjustment disorder is allowed</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>