<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01380223</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess the safety, tolerability, and pharmacodynamics of omecamtiv mecarbil infusion in healthy male volunteers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pharmacokinetic and Pharmacodynamic Study of Omecamtiv Mecarbil in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subject is male 2. Subject is aged between 18 and 50 years inclusive. 3. Subject has given signed informed consent. 4. Subject's Body Mass Index (BMI) is between 18 and 30 kg/m2 inclusive. 5. Subject weighs less than 100 kg. 6. Subject is considered to be in good health in the opinion of the investigator, as determined by: 1. A prestudy physical examination with no clinically significant abnormalities. 2. Vital signs within normal ranges (supine after 3 minutes rest heart rate: 40 to 80 bpm; systolic BP: 100 to 140 mmHg; diastolic BP: 5090 mmHg; respiration rate: 8 to 18 breaths per minute; oxygen saturation: 96100%) 3. An ECG with no clinically significant abnormalities. 7. Subject's prestudy clinical laboratory findings are within normal range or if outside of the normal range not deemed clinically significant in the opinion of the investigator. 8. Cardiac troponin I is less than the upper limit of the laboratory reference range. 9. A screening echocardiogram demonstrates normal cardiac function, an ejection fraction of between 40% and 70% with no significant valvular regurgitation (grade 1) and/or stenosis and images are deemed to be of good quality by the sonographer. 1. Subject has had a clinically significant illness in the four weeks before screening. 2. Use of prescribed mediations in the 3 weeks prior to dosing or overthecounter preparations (including vitamin supplements and herbal remedies) for 7 days prior to dosing, except paracetamol which will be allowed up to 48 hours prior to dosing. 3. Subject has a significant history of drug/solvent abuse or a positive drugs of abuse test at screening. 4. Subject with a history of alcohol abuse or currently drinks in excess of 28 units per week. 5. Subject smokes more than 5 cigarettes (or equivalent) per day. 6. Subject is not willing to refrain from caffeine/xanthine containing products from 48 hours prior to the screening medical and admission on Day 1 until the post study medical. 7. Subject is in the opinion of the investigator not suitable to participate in the study. 8. Subject who has participated in any clinical study with an investigational drug/device within three months prior to the first day of dosing. 9. Subject who has a positive result of HIV screen, Hepatitis B screen or Hepatitis C screen. 10. Subject has had a serious adverse reaction or significant hypersensitivity to any drug. 11. Subject has donated 500 ml or more of blood within the month prior to screening. 12. Subject has a history of cardiovascular disease or family history of premature cardiovascular disease or death.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>