<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01478477</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized pilot trial studies omega-3 fatty acid in preventing joint symptoms in patients with stage I-III breast cancer receiving anastrozole, exemestane, or letrozole. Omega-3 fatty acid supplement may lessen or prevent joint stiffness or pain in patients receiving hormone therapy for breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Omega-3 Fatty Acids in Preventing Joint Symptoms in Patients With Stage I-III Breast Cancer Receiving Anastrozole, Exemestane, or Letrozole</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the feasibility of evaluating joint symptoms in postmenopausal women with breast cancer randomized to n-3 PUFA (omega-3 fatty acid) vs. placebo supplementation using the Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Breast (FACT-B) and endocrine subscale (FACT-ES), Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) and Stanford's Health Assessment -Disability Index (HAS) during the first 6 months of adjuvant aromatase inhibitor (AI) therapy. II. To preliminarily evaluate the efficacy of n-3 PUFA vs. placebo supplementation on AI induced joint symptoms. III. To explore blood and imaging based biomarkers (plasma and red blood cell [RBC] levels of n-3 PUFAs, inflammatory cytokines and receptors, and intra-articular tenosynovial inflammation by musculoskeletal magnetic resonance imaging [MRI] imaging) of AI-induced joint symptoms in women on AI therapy randomized to n-3 PUFAs vs. placebo supplementation. OUTLINE: Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. ARM I: Patients receive omega-3 fatty acid orally (PO) once daily (QD) for 6 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. ARM II: Patients receive placebo PO QD for 6 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women diagnosed with breast cancer stages IIII initiating first adjuvant AI therapy with any of the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved AIs (anastrozole, exemestane, letrozole) Concurrent gonadotropinreleasing hormone (GnRH) agonist therapy is allowed Concurrent breast related radiation therapy is allowed Prior tamoxifen use is allowed Prior chemotherapy is allowed History of osteoarthritis and/or fibromyalgia is allowed Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document Metastatic malignancy of any kind Rheumatoid arthritis and other types of autoimmune and inflammatory joint disease, with the exception of osteoarthritis and fibromyalgia AI use &gt; 2 weeks prior to study enrollment Known bleeding disorders History of diabetes mellitus, heart disease or TIA/stroke Current use of warfarin or other anticoagulants Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia,or psychiatric illness/social situation that would limit compliance with study requirements Daily use of n3 PUFA concentrates or capsules or regular or any other supplements that might interact with n3 PUFA supplements within six months of study initiation; sporadic use of n3 PUFA supplement may be eligible if there has been a 3month washout period prior to randomization Pregnant or nursing women Known sensitivity or allergy to fish or fish oil Concurrent use of daily full dose aspirin (≥ 325 mg/day), nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) or NSAIDcontaining products or steroids; one month washout period is required prior to randomization Unable to give informed consent In patients consenting for optional MRIs, any contraindication to MRI examination including but not limited to ferromagnetic metal in the body, pacemaker, or severe claustrophobia</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>