<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01424813</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will measure the change in lung function in subjects with asthma after inhaling from either of two inhalers: Albuterol Spiromax® or placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A 12-week Study to Compare the Efficacy and Safety of Albuterol Spiromax® Versus a Placebo in People 12 Years and Older With Persistent Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albuterol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent/assent General good health Persistent asthma, with an FEV1 5080% predicted. Ability to perform spirometry in an acceptable manner as per protocol guidelines. Ability to perform PEFR with a handheld peak flow meter. Demonstration of reversible bronchoconstriction as verified by a 15% or greater increase from baseline FEV1. Taking inhaled corticosteroids at a stable dose for at least 4 weeks prior to the Screening Visit. Nonsmokers. Capable of understanding the requirements, risks, and benefits of study participation. Other inclusion criteria apply. Participation in any investigational drug trial within the 30 days preceding the Screening Visit (SV). A known hypersensitivity to albuterol or any of the excipients in the formulations. History of severe milk protein allergy. History of a respiratory infection or disorder that has not resolved within the 2 weeks preceding the Screening Visit (SV). Currently requires treatment with β2adrenergic receptor antagonists or nonselective βreceptor blocking agents. History of lifethreatening asthma that is defined for this protocol as an asthma episode that required intubation. Any asthma exacerbation requiring oral corticosteroids within 3 months of the Screening Visit (SV). A subject must not have had any hospitalization for asthma within 6 months prior to the Screening Visit (SV). Historical or current evidence of any clinically significant nonasthmatic acute or chronic condition including. Other exclusion criteria apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>dry powder inhaler</keyword>
	<keyword>short-acting beta2-agonist</keyword>
	<keyword>SABA</keyword>
	<keyword>bronchoconstriction</keyword>
	<keyword>bronchodilation</keyword>
	<keyword>bronchodilator</keyword>
	<keyword>metered dose inhaler</keyword>
</DOC>