<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01424228</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this trial is to evaluate the long-term (24 weeks) efficacy of prucalopride versus placebo in subjects aged 18 years and older with chronic constipation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Long-term Prucalopride Treatment With Chronic Constipation in Subjects Aged ≥ 18 Years</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this phase IV trial a total of 340 subjects (170 subjects per treatment group), with chronic constipation, are planned to be randomly assigned to double-blind treatment. The trial duration for a subject can be 26 to 28 weeks in total, including a 2- to 4-week run-in phase followed by a 24-week double-blind treatment phase. The patient will complete an e-diary. Adult subjects (≥18 to &lt;65 years of age) will take 2 mg prucalopride or matching placebo throughout the entire 24-week treatment period. Elderly subjects (≥65 years of age) will start at a dose of 1 mg prucalopride or matching placebo. In case of insufficient response the daily dose has to be increased to 2 mg (i.e. changed to 2 mg prucalopride or matching placebo).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Constipation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subject is a male or nonpregnant, nonbreastfeeding female outpatient ≥18 years of age (no upper age limit). 2. Subject has a history of constipation. The subject reports an average of ≤2 SBM/week that result in a feeling of complete evacuation (SCBM). 3. Subject agrees to stop his/her current laxative treatment and is willing to use rescue medication according to the rescue rule [bisacodyl/enemas]. 1. Subjects in whom constipation is thought to be druginduced 2. Subjects using any disallowed medication. 3. Subjects who previously used prucalopride. 4. Subjects suffering from secondary causes of chronic constipation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Long term</keyword>
	<keyword>Constipation</keyword>
	<keyword>Digestive signs and symptoms</keyword>
</DOC>