<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02139774</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is testing a walking program called Walk with Ease by the Arthritis Foundation with men undergoing treatment for prostate cancer. The researchers are interested in how easy or difficult it is for these men to participate in this program and whether or not is is helpful to them during their care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Using Walk With Ease Walking Program With Men 65 and Older Being Treated for Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Purpose: This pilot study evaluates the feasibility of implementing a moderate-intensity physical activity (PA) program in a sample of men age 65 or older with a prostate cancer diagnosis undergoing various forms of treatment or active surveillance. Participants: Men, 65 and older, with a prostate cancer diagnosis. Procedures (methods): This study will enroll subjects in a 6 week walking program called Walk with Ease (WWE) and see if walking can be sustained for up to three months. In addition, the study will perform a Geriatric Assessment and gather preliminary data on self-reported quality of life outcomes and self-reported physical activity as captured in a daily walking log.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>≥65 years of age Histologically confirmed Stage I, II or III prostate cancer (endocrine (± radiation) patients may be Stage IV) Undergoing prostate cancer treatment (postsurgery only, radiation only, endocrine therapy (± radiation), or active surveillance) English speaking IRB approved, signed written informed consent Approval from their treating physician to engage in moderateintensity physical activity Patientassessed ability to walk and engage in moderate physical activity Willing and able to meet all study requirements One or more significant medical conditions that in the physician's judgment preclude participation in the walking intervention Major surgery scheduled within the study period Unable to walk or engage in moderateintensity physical activity Already actively walking (150 minutes per week)</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prostate Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>Geriatric</keyword>
	<keyword>Radiation</keyword>
	<keyword>Arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Walking</keyword>
	<keyword>Endocrine Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Androgen Deprivation Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Active Surveillance</keyword>
	<keyword>Men</keyword>
</DOC>