<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02538029</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim of the proposed project is to characterize dual tasking (DT) deficits to improve motor, cognitive, and quality of life outcomes in individuals with Parkinson's disease (PD). Phase 1 of the intervention will involve an in-depth gait analysis on 15 individuals with PD. This gait analysis will utilize the Computer Assisted Rehabilitation Environment (CAREN) system, a virtual reality system with a fully integrated 3-D motion capture system. The purpose of Phase 1 is to generalize characteristics of gait and postural control during specific DT conditions. Phase 2 (N=20) involves the clinical translation of these findings. This phase will involve creating a clinical intervention based on the objective information gathered the CAREN system. The intervention will take place 3x/week for a total of 8 weeks. Interventional groups will include: 1) DT clinical group (N=10) and 2) Single task group (N=10). Outcome measures will be used at the beginning and end of the intervention to assess the feasibility and efficacy of the intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effects of Dual Task Training in Individuals With Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of idiopathic PD Able to provide informed consent Ability to ambulate ≥ 300ft with or without an assistive device Hoehn and Yahr stage 24 Undergone any surgical procedure for the treatment of PD, such as deep brain stimulation Those who are considered to be high risk exercisers per American College of Sports Medicine exercise screening questionnaire Musculoskeletal injury or neurological injury other than PD that would restrict physical activity Inability to follow 2 step commands Significant cognitive impairment as designated by ≥ 3 errors on the Short Portable Mental Status Questionnaire</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dual tasking</keyword>
</DOC>