<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00233818</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to assess the performance and safety of a formulation of the antiproliferative agent, sirolimus coated on modified Bx VELOCITY Balloon-Expandable Stent mounted on the Raptor Over The Wire (OTW) Stent Delivery System (SDS) in patients with de novo coronary artery lesions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>FIM-NL - First-in-Man Study (Netherlands Part) With Sirolimus Coated Modified BX Velocity Stent</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single center, non-randomized study. Patients who meet the eligibility criteria will be treated with the sirolimus coated modified Bx VELOCITY Balloon-Expandable Stent mounted on the Raptor OTW SDS. Patients will be followed for five years post-procedure, with all patients having a repeat angiography at 6 months, 18 months, and 48 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosis of angina pectoris as defined by Canadian Cardiovascular Society Classification (CCS) or a positive ischemia study; 2. Single de novo lesion requiring treatment in a major native coronary artery; 3. Target lesion is &lt;=18mm in length (visual estimate); 4. Target lesion is &gt;=3.0mm and &lt;=3.5mm in diameter (visual estimate); 5. Target lesion stenosis is &gt;50% and &lt;100% (visual estimate); 1. A Qwave or nonQwave myocardial infarction within the preceding 72 hours unless the CK and CKMB enzymes are back to normal; 2. Unprotected left main coronary disease with &gt;=50% stenosis; 3. Have an ostial target lesion; 4. Angiographic evidence of thrombus within target lesion; 5. Calcified lesions which cannot be successfully predilated; 6. Ejection fraction &lt;=30%; 7. Target lesion involves bifurcation (either stenosis of both main vessel and major branch or stenosis of just major branch); 8. Totally occluded vessel;</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2007</verification_date>
</DOC>