<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4345">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03050359</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TAK-438_304</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>U1111-1139-0293</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03050359</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of TAK-438 (Vonoprazan) to Lansoprazole in the Treatment of Duodenal Ulcer Participants With or Without Helicobacter Pylori Infection</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Double-Blind, Double-Dummy, Phase 3 Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Oral TAK-438 20 mg Compared to Lansoprazole 30 mg Once- or Twice-Daily in the Treatment of Endoscopically Confirmed Duodenal Ulcer Subjects With or Without Helicobacter Pylori Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Takeda</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Takeda</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to demonstrate the non-inferior efficacy of TAK-438 versus
      lansoprazole in the treatment of participants with duodenal ulcer.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The drug being tested in this study is called TAK-438. TAK-438 is being tested to treat
      people who have duodenal ulcers and also may or may not have Helicobacter pylori (HP)
      infection. This study will look at duodenal ulcer healing and also the elimination of HP in
      people who take TAK-438 versus lansoprazole. The study will enroll approximately 770
      patients.

      Participants will be randomly assigned (by chance, like flipping a coin) to one of the two
      treatment groups—which will remain undisclosed to the participant and study doctor during
      the study (unless there is an urgent medical need):

        -  TAK-438 20 mg

        -  Lansoprazole 30 mg

      HP+ participants will be asked to take a TAK- 438 tablet and a lansoprazole capsule twice
      daily in conjunction with bismuth-containing quadruple therapy for 2 weeks, followed up by a
      TAK-438 tablet and a lansoprazole capsule once daily for up to 6 weeks. HP negative (HP-)
      participants will be asked to take a TAK-438 tablet and a lansoprazole capsule once daily
      for up to 6 weeks.

      This multi-center trial will be conducted China, Korea, Taiwan and Philippines. The overall
      time to participate in this study is up to 10 weeks. Participants will make multiple visits
      plus final visit at 2 weeks or 4 weeks after last dose of study drug for a follow-up
      assessment.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Endoscopically Confirmed Healing of Duodenal Ulcer(s)</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4 or Week 6</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of endoscopic healing is defined as the percentage of participants in whom the disappearance of all white coats associated with duodenal ulcers has been endoscopically confirmed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Helicobacter Pylori Infected (HP+) Participants With Successful HP Eradication After 4 or 6 Weeks of Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>After 4 or 6 weeks of treatment (up to 10 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>HP infection status will be determined by ^13C Urea Breath Test (^13C-UBT). The urea breath test is used to detect infection with HP, a bacteria associated with stomach ulcers, by testing individual breath samples in a central laboratory.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Endoscopically Confirmed Healing of Duodenal Ulcer at Week 4</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of endoscopic healing is defined percentage of participants in whom the disappearance of all white coats associated with duodenal ulcers has been endoscopically confirmed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Posttreatment Resolution of Gastrointestinal Symptoms Associated With Duodenal Ulcer at Weeks 2 Through 6</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 2 up to Week 6</time_frame>
    <description>Gastrointestinal symptoms are defined as: epigastric pain (postprandial, fasting, nocturnal), abdominal bloating, nausea/vomiting, heartburn and lack of appetite.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">770</enrollment>
  <condition>Duodenal Ulcer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-438 20 mg (HP- Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAK-438 20 mg, tablets, orally, once daily and lansoprazole placebo-matching capsules, orally, once daily for up to 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-438 20 mg (HP+ Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAK-438 20 mg, tablets, orally, twice daily and lansoprazole placebo-matching capsules, orally, twice daily for first 2 weeks. Then TAK-438 20 mg, tablets, orally, once daily and lansoprazole placebo-matching capsules, orally, once daily from Week 3 to Week 6. Bismuth-Containing Quadruple Therapy (Amoxicillin 1g, clarithromycin 500 mg, and bismuth potassium citrate 220 mg, orally, twice daily) for first 2 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lansoprazole 30 mg (HP- Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Lansoprazole 30 mg, capsules, orally, once daily and TAK-438 placebo-matching tablets, orally, once daily for up to 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lansoprazole 30 mg (HP+ Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Lansoprazole 30 mg, capsules, orally, twice daily and TAK-438 placebo-matching tablets, orally, twice daily for first 2 weeks. Then lansoprazole 30 mg, capsules, orally, once daily and TAK-438 placebo-matching tablets, orally, once daily from Week 3 to Week 6. Bismuth-Containing Quadruple Therapy (Amoxicillin 1g, clarithromycin 500 mg, and bismuth potassium citrate 220 mg, orally, twice daily) for first 2 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TAK-438</intervention_name>
    <description>TAK-438 tablets</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-438 20 mg (HP- Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-438 20 mg (HP+ Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Vonoprazan</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lansoprazole</intervention_name>
    <description>Lansoprazole capsules</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lansoprazole 30 mg (HP- Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Lansoprazole 30 mg (HP+ Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Prevacid</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TAK-438 Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>TAK-438 placebo-matching tablets.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lansoprazole 30 mg (HP- Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Lansoprazole 30 mg (HP+ Participants)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lansoprazole Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Lansoprazole placebo-matching capsules</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-438 20 mg (HP- Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-438 20 mg (HP+ Participants)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bismuth-Containing Quadruple Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Amoxicillin, clarithromycin and bismuth potassium citrate.</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAK-438 20 mg (HP+ Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Lansoprazole 30 mg (HP+ Participants)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Biaxin</other_name>
    <other_name>pylera capsules</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        1. Has endoscopic evidence of active duodenal ulcer(s) (i.e., mucosal defects with white
        coating [including cases associated with blood coagulation as long as there is no active
        bleeding]) measuring 5 mm or larger in longest diameter within 14 days prior to
        randomization.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Has received TAK-438 in a previous clinical study or as a therapeutic agent.

          2. Has a history or clinical manifestations of significant central nervous system (CNS),
             cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic, renal, metabolic, gastrointestinal, urological,
             endocrine or hematological disease that, in the opinion of the investigator, would
             confound the study results or compromise participant safety.

          3. Has been treated with Helicobacter pylori eradication therapy within 30 days prior to
             study treatment.

          4. Has had any duodenal ulcer of &gt;2 cm in any diameter or with &gt;3 separate duodenal
             ulcers in total as evident by endoscopy within 14 days prior to randomization.

          5. Has a diagnosis of duodenal malignancy or a duodenal ulcer whose morphology suggested
             malignancy as evident by endoscopy within 14 days prior to randomization.

          6. Is suspected of having acute gastro-duodenal mucosal lesions (AGDML) as evident by
             endoscopy within 14 days prior to randomization.

          7. Has a linear ulcer (including a linear ulcer scar) that has been confirmed as evident
             by endoscopy within 14 days prior to randomization.

          8. Has active postoperative (eg, endoscopic mucosal resection / endoscopic submucosal
             dissection) ulcer(s) as confirmed by endoscopy within 14 days prior to randomization.

          9. Has gastric ulcer that has been confirmed by endoscopy within 14 days prior to
             randomization.

         10. Has ulcers for which medical therapy alone is not indicated (eg, perforation, pyloric
             stenosis, duodenal stenosis, major bleeding).

         11. Has undergone therapeutic upper gastrointestinal (GI) endoscopic therapy (eg,
             endoscopic hemostasis or excision including biopsy) within 30 days prior to visit 1.

         12. Has Zollinger-Ellison syndrome or gastric acid hypersecretion or those with a history
             of gastric acid hypersecretion.

         13. Has undergone major surgical procedures within 30 days prior to Visit 1 or are
             scheduled to undergo surgical procedures that may affect gastric acid secretion (eg,
             abdominal surgery, vagotomy or craniotomy).

         14. Has a history of malignancy or was treated for malignancy within 5 years before the
             start of the visit 1 (the participant may be included in the study if he/she has
             cured cutaneous basal cell carcinoma or cervical carcinoma in situ).

         15. Has a known acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) or hepatitis infection,
             including hepatitis virus carriers (hepatitis B surface-antigen [HBsAg] - or
             hepatitis C virus (HCV)-antibody-positive) (the participant may be included in the
             study if he/she is HCV-viral load-RNA-negative).

         16. Laboratory tests performed prior to randomization revealed any of the following
             abnormalities in the participant:

               1. Creatinine levels: &gt;2 mg/dL (&gt;177 μmol/L).

               2. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST), or total
                  bilirubin levels: &gt; upper limit of normal (ULN).

         17. Has hypersensitivity to TAK-438, proton pump inhibitors (PPIs), bismuth,
             clarithromycin, or amoxicillin. Skin testing may be performed according to local
             standard practice (for HP+ participants only).
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director Clinical Science</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Takeda</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Takeda Study Registration Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>+1-877-825-3327</phone>
    <email>medicalinformation@tpna.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 8, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 8, 2017</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Drug therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Gastrointestinal Diseases</keyword>
  <keyword>Digestive System Diseases</keyword>
  <keyword>Lansoprazole</keyword>
  <keyword>Anti-Ulcer Agents</keyword>
  <keyword>Gastrointestinal Agents</keyword>
  <keyword>Proton Pump Inhibitors</keyword>
  <keyword>Enzyme Inhibitors</keyword>
  <keyword>Molecular Mechanisms of Pharmacological Action</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Helicobacter Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Duodenal Ulcer</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Lansoprazole</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dexlansoprazole</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Clarithromycin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bismuth</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amoxicillin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Potassium Citrate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Molecular Mechanisms of Pharmacological Action</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
