<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02144519</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators long-term goal is to advance the adoption and successful implementation of policies that promote PA and nutrition in after school programs (ASP) nationwide. The investigators objective here is two fold. First, the investigators will test the effectiveness of two promising strategies designed to 1) increase the amount of PA children accumulate while attending an ASP and 2) promote changes in the nutritional quality of the snacks served. This represents a fundamental step in establishing practice-based guidelines (best practices) for the uptake and achievement of public health policy goals (CA and Harvard). Second, the investigators will examine the barriers and facilitators to implementing these strategies. The expected outcome of this study is evidence supporting best practices for ASPs to employ to meet policy goals.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physical Activity and Nutrition Intervention in Afterschool Programs</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators will use a 3-year delayed treatment, cluster randomized controlled trial design with 20 ASPs that serve mostly low-income and minority children (approximately 1300 children ages 6-12yrs) in Columbia, SC and address the following specific aims: Aim 1. Evaluate the impact of a staff-level intervention, a professional development training program focused on core competencies to promote physical activity, on children's physical activity levels; Aim 2. Evaluate the impact of a site-level intervention, a snack modification program that includes a discount buying program, on the quality of snacks served and consumed; and Aim 3. Evaluate the implementation of the staff-level and site-level interventions and identify organizational, staff, and setting characteristics that influence the process of implementing these strategies.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Programs that: Operate immediately after the school day Operate every day of the school year for a minimum of 2 hours Serve a minimum of 30 children of elementary age (612 years) Operate in a school, community or faith Setting Provide a snack Provide homework assistance/completion time Provide enrichment Provide opportunities for physical activity All children enrolled, staff, and afterschool program (ASP) leaders in the ASPs were eligible to participate in the study. Programs that: Were singularly focused Programs that were physical activity focused Children that: Have any physical and/or orthopedic impairment that would limit a child's ability to participate in regular physical activity.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>