<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02160782</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a long-term, open-label study with a double-blind, placebo-controlled, randomized drug withdrawal period in children with ALGS designed to evaluate the safety and efficacy of LUM001. The study is divided into 5 parts: a 6-week open-label, dose escalation period, a 12-week stable dosing period, a 4-week randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled drug withdrawal period, a 26-week long-term stable dosing period, and an optional 52 week follow-up treatment period for eligible subjects who choose to stay on treatment with LUM001. Subjects' participation in the optional follow-up treatment period will continue until the first of the following occur: (i) completion of 52 weeks of additional treatment (Week 100), or (ii) in the event that a new study of LUM001 opens to enrollment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Long-Term, Open-Label Study of LUM001 With a Double-Blind, Placebo Controlled, Randomized Drug Withdrawal Period to Evaluate Safety and Efficacy in Children With Alagille Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alagille Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Substance Withdrawal Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosis of Alagille Syndrome 2. Evidence of cholestasis 3. Moderate to severe pruritus 4. Females of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test during screening. 5. Sexually active females must be prepared to use an effetive method of contraception during the trial. 6. Subject is expected to have a consistent caregiver(s) for the duration of the study. 7. Caregivers (and age appropriate subjects) must complete at least 10 eDiary reports (morning or evening) during each of two consecutive weeks of the screening period . 1. Chronic diarrhea requiring ongoing intravenous fluid or nutritional intervention. 2. Surgical interruption of the enterohepatic circulation. 3. Previous liver transplant. 4. Decompensated cirrhosis, history or presence of clinically significant ascites, variceal hemorrhage, and/or encephalopathy. 5. History or presence of other concomitant liver disease, gallstones, or kidney stones. 6. Diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). 7. Cancers, except for in situ carcinoman, or cancers treated at least 5 years prior to screening with no evidence of recurrence. 8. Any female who is pregnant or lactating, or planning to become pregnant during the study period.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>