<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00444574</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study designed to evaluate the safety and efficacy of MTS compared to placebo with reference to CONCERTA® in pediatric subjects diagnosed with ADHD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of MTS Versus Concerta in Pediatric Patients (Aged 6-12 Years) With ADHD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase III, randomized, double-blind, multi-center, parallel-group, placebo-controlled, dose optimization study designed to evaluate the safety and efficacy of MTS (12.5, 18.75, 25, and 37.5 cm2) compared to placebo with reference to CONCERTA® in pediatric subjects diagnosed with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylphenidate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>male or female aged 612 years females of Childbearing Potential (FOCP) must have a negative serum beta Human Chorionic Gonadotropin (HCG) pregnancy test at Screening and a negative urine pregnancy test at Baseline. a primary diagnosis of ADHD based on a detailed psychiatric evaluation a total score of =&gt;26 on the ADHDRSIV at the Baseline Visit a minimum level of intellectual functioning, as determined by an IQ (based on KBIT) score of 80 or above no comorbid illness that could affect safety or tolerability or in any way interfere with the subject's participation in the study. EXCLUSION CRITERIA: a current, controlled (requiring a restricted medication) or uncontrolled, comorbid psychiatric diagnosis (except ODD) with significant symptoms such as Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD), psychosis, bipolar illness, pervasive developmental disorder, severe obsessive compulsive disorder, severe depressive or severe anxiety disorder a known nonresponder to psychostimulant treatment overweight (Body Mass Index (BMI)forage &gt;90th percentile) a history of seizures during the last 2 years (exclusive of infantile febrile seizures), a tic disorder, a current diagnosis and/or family history of Tourette's Disorder. Conduct Disorder. Subject has taken an investigational drug within 30 days prior to Screening.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD)</keyword>
</DOC>