<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00444639</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The active ingredient of Pamorelin® 11,25 mg is Triptorelin. Triptorelin is a substitute for a natural hormone produced in the body called Gonadotrophin-releasing hormone (GnRH). GnRH is a hormone secreted by hypothalamus (a gland located in brain) and controls the production of sex hormones (eg testosterone in men) in other organs in the body. The growth of prostate cancer cells, one of the most common cancers in men, is induced by the hormone testosterone. Hormonotherapy is one of treatments available to treat this type of disease by controlling the testosterone serum level. Pamorelin® 11,25 mg is normally injected in the muscle but this type of injection is not suitable for every patient. Therefore the primary purpose of this study is to assess the non-inferiority of the 12-week triptorelin formulation Pamorelin® 11,25 mg administered via subcutaneous (SC) injection as compared to Pamorelin® 11,25 mg administered via standard intramuscular (IM) injection based on the percentage of patients presenting a testosterone level ≤ 50 ng/dl at week 24.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Assess the Non-inferiority of Pamorelin® 11,25mg SC Injected Versus Pamorelin® 11,25mg IM Injected in Patients Suffering From Advanced Prostate Cancer (PAMOJECT)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triptorelin Pamoate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histological proven prostate cancer, locally advanced or metastatic and scheduled to receive hormonal deprivation therapy Life expectancy of more than 9 months Documented testosterone levels of ≥ 125 ng/dl measured by any laboratory or on site within the previous 6 months Has a history of hypersensitivity to the Investigational Medicinal Product or drugs with a similar chemical structure Has previously received a GnRH analogue, estrogens or a steroidal anti androgen within the last year preceding the study Concomitant anticoagulation treatment Patient who underwent an orchidectomy or who is scheduled to receive an orchidectomy during the course of this study Patient with known spinal medullar compression</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
</DOC>