<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00444080</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A prospective randomized trial to compare the safety and efficacy of the Ex-PRESS to trabeculectomy in patients with open angle glaucoma who failed medical or are allergic to medical treatment and for which filtering surgery is indicated</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Ex-PRESSTM Mini Glaucoma Shunt to Trabeculectomy in Subjects With Open Angle Glaucoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma, Open-Angle</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult subject over the age of 18 Subject diagnosed with open angle glaucoma (POAG, PXFG or PDSG) or ocular hypertension Subject is a candidate for filtering surgery with intraoperative antimetabolites IOP &gt; 18 mmHg on maximum tolerated medial therapy based on two measurements taken 1 hour apart at the same visit. Subject willing to attend all followup evaluations Subject willing to sign informed consent. Subject diagnosed with: PACG, NTG, secondary glaucoma, neovascular glaucoma Subject has history of glaucoma surgery (filtering, glaucoma drainage device, cyclo destructive procedures) Subject has history of penetrating keratoplasty (PKP) Subject underwent large incision extra capsular cataract extraction Subject had cataract phacoemulsification within the last month Subject has a visually significant cataract that is planned for extraction at the time of filtering surgery or within 12 months thereafter Any ocular disease or history in the operated eye other than glaucoma and cataract, such as uveitis, ocular infection, severe dry eye, severe blepharitis , active proliferative retinopathy, ICE syndrome, epithelial or fibrous down growth, aphakia, and ocular pathology that may interfere with accurate IOP measurements Subject has vitreous present in the anterior chamber for which vitrectomy is anticipated IOP of ≤18mmHg Subject participates in any other concurrent ocular investigation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ex-PRESS</keyword>
	<keyword>TRABECULECTOMY</keyword>
</DOC>