<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01671670</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Hypothesis: Acupuncture is efficacious and safe for patients with functional dyspepsia Design: - A single blind randomized controlled trial - 200 participants will be included - Two arms: acupuncture and sham acupuncture group</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acupuncture for Patients With Function Dyspepsia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Aim: to clarify the efficacy and safety of acupuncture for patients with functional dyspepsia Design: A single blind randomized controlled trial will be performed in Chengdu, Hunan and Chongqing province. Two hundred participants will be randomly assign to acupuncture and sham acupuncture group. Each participants will receive 20 sessions of acupuncture in 4 weeks, with a duration of 30 minutes in a session. The primary outcome is Patients' global assessments of efficacy in 16 weeks after inclusion. Secondary outcomes include validated Leeds Dyspepsia Questionnaire, Nepean dyspepsia index, etc.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dyspepsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastritis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Consistent with the diagnostic criteria of functional dyspepsia. Age of a subject is older than 18 and is younger than 65.（including 18 and 65） Include postprandial distress syndrome. Did not take any gastroenteric dynamic drugs in the last 15 days, and did not take part in any clinical trial. Informed consent is signed by a subject or his lineal relation. Patients with any contraindications of Itopride. Patients who are unconscious, psychotic. Patients with aggravating tumor and other serious consumptive disease, and who are subject to infection and bleeding. With serious protopathy or disease of cardiovascular, liver, renal, gastrointestinal, hematological systems and so on. Pregnant women or women in lactation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Functional dyspepsia</keyword>
	<keyword>postprandial distress syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>