<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01088191</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate safety and preliminary efficacy of MSB-CAR001 in subjects who have recently undergone an Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of MSB-CAR001 in Subjects 6 Weeks Post an Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, single center, randomized, double blind, controlled Phase 1b/2a study designed to evaluate the safety and tolerability of a single injection into the knee joint of two different doses of MPCs combined with Hyaluronan compared to Hyaluronan alone in patients who have recently undergone an Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction. All subjects in this study have undergone unilateral ACL reconstruction surgery within six months of injury. MSB-CAR001 plus Hyaluronan at one of two doses or Hyaluronan alone will be injected into the knee joint. After the screening and injection visits, each subject will be evaluated clinically within 3 days and 28 days after surgery, and at 2, 3, 6, 9, 12, 18, and 24 months after surgery. The radiographical exams will be performed at 6, 12, 18, and 24 months after surgery. Subjects will be evaluated at 24 months after surgery for safety.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyaluronic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Males or females at least 18 years of age, but not older than 40 2. ACL injury requiring reconstruction 3. Have undergone unilateral ACL reconstruction surgery within six months of injury; 4. Willing and able to undertake a standardized rehabilitation protocol 5. ACL graft used is autograft 6. Willingness to participate in followup for 24 months from the time of initial treatment 7. Ability to understand and willingness to sign consent form 1. Women who are pregnant or breast feeding or planning to become pregnant during the study 2. Previous allergic reaction to Hyaluronan 3. Systemic or local infection at the screen visit or at the time of the study injection 4. History of any autoimmune disease, such as, systemic lupus erythematosus, Addison's disease, Crohn's disease, or rheumatoid arthritis 5. Treatment with immunosuppression therapy within 6 months prior to screen (visit 1) 6. Acute or chronic infectious disease, including but not limited to human immunodeficiency virus (HIV); 7. Treatment and /or uncompleted followup treatment of any investigational therapy within 6 months before the procedure and /or intent to participate in any other investigational drug or cell therapy study during the 24 month followup period of this study; 8. Recipient of prior allogeneic stem cell/progenitor cell therapy 9. Undergoing a simultaneous procedure to the opposite knee 10. 20% or greater antihuman leukocyte antigen (HLA) antibody titer and/or has antibody specificities to donor HLA antigens; 11. Known sensitivities to bovine (cow), murine (mouse), chicken products and/or dimethylsulfoxide (DMSO). Previous allergic reaction to Hyaluronan; 12. History or current evidence of alcohol or drug abuse or is a recreational user of illicit drugs or prescription medications 13. History of prior surgery to the study knee joint 14. History of malignancy (excluding basal cell carcinoma that has been successfully excised) 15. Chondral lesions noted at time of surgical reconstruction greater than Grade 1a on any surfaces</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injury</keyword>
	<keyword>Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction</keyword>
	<keyword>Adult Stem Cells</keyword>
	<keyword>Mesenchymal precursor cells</keyword>
</DOC>