<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01088230</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see whether treating subjects for wrist rehabilitation following stroke with Botox® and robotic therapy is more effective than treatment with robotic therapy alone and no Botox®.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Impact of Botox® During Robotic Rehabilitation of the Wrist Following Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will explore new ways to facilitate rehabilitation of wrist function after stroke. One of the challenges of recovery is muscle stiffness or excessive muscle tone that often limits exercise or therapy progress. Taking this into account, the investigators propose treating the wrist and forearm with a combination of a one-time Botox® injection and a 6-week robotic therapy protocol to maximize recovery. Botox® is a drug that is injected directly into a muscle to temporarily relax the muscle. Botox® is commonly used to decrease muscle tone in tight muscles in the stroke population. Robotics therapy provides highly repetitive mass practice with visual and haptic feedback. Subjects will be randomized to two groups. Group A will receive the Botox® injection and group B will receive a placebo saline injection. Both groups will receive the same robotics therapy protocol. Subjects and investigators will be blinded to group assignment. The investigators would like to know if there are trends between groups in a variety of outcome measures depending on what intervention they received. The investigators predict that the treatment group will have better results than the control group on the Fugl Meyer, our primary outcome measure. The investigators hope the results of this pilot study will guide development of a larger clinical trial.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>onabotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins, Type A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>abobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>incobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<criteria>&gt; 6 months poststroke Single stroke Ashworth Scale of &gt; 2 but &lt; 4 for wrist flexors and pronators Able to follow multiple step directions Completed all active occupational therapy Motor strength &gt; 1/5 at the wrist extension and supination Passive ROM of 045 degrees at wrist flexion and extension, 020 degrees at radial deviation, 020 degrees at ulnar deviation, 045 degrees at pronation and supination No Botox® injection in the wrist/forearm muscles for at least 12 months Naïve to robotics study protocol Joint contracture and wrist or forearm</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>hemiparesis</keyword>
	<keyword>robotics</keyword>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Botox®</keyword>
	<keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>wrist spasticity</keyword>
</DOC>