<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01088178</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators study is a prospective randomized trial of women undergoing the levonorgestrel intrauterine system (LNG-IUS: Mirena©, Bayer) at three separate time periods: immediate post placental (IPP) defined as insertion within 10 min delivery of placenta, early post partum (EP) defined as insertion after 10 min but within 72hrs postpartum, or interval (INT) insertion defined as insertion after 6wks postpartum. This is a pilot study in preparation for a multicenter, prospective randomized study of long-acting reversible contraception in the postpartum period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Levonorgestrel-Intrauterine System (LNG-IUS) Insertion in the Postpartum Period</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Levonorgestrel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Contraceptive Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All reproductive age women who express a desire for the LNGIUS (Mirena©) at routine questioning at their 3638 week prenatal appointment or upon admission to labor and delivery are eligible for our study. Contraindications to the LNGIUS include: Pregnancy or suspicion of pregnancy, Congenital or acquired uterine anomaly including fibroids if they distort the uterine cavity, Postpartum endometritis within the past 3 months, Known or suspected uterine or cervical neoplasia or unresolved, abnormal pap smear, untreated acute cervicitis or vaginitis including bacterial vaginosis or other lower genital tract infections, acute liver disease or liver tumor, hypersensitivity to any component of the product, known or suspected carcinoma of the breast. Any of these conditions would exclude the patient from our study. Delivery &lt;36 weeks Intrapartum chorioamnionitis (defined as maternal fever &gt;100.4 and two of the following conditions: Maternal leukocytosis (greater than 15,000 cells/cubic millimeter), Maternal tachycardia (greater than 100 beats/minute), Fetal tachycardia (greater than 160 beats/minute), Uterine tenderness, Foul odor of the amniotic fluid Postpartum Hemorrhage (defined as &gt;500cc EBL for spontaneous vaginal delivery) Cesarean delivery if randomized to IPP or EP placement</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Long-Acting Reversible Contraception</keyword>
	<keyword>Contraceptive Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Therapeutic Uses</keyword>
	<keyword>Contraceptive Agents, Female</keyword>
	<keyword>Reproductive Control Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacologic Actions</keyword>
	<keyword>Levonorgestrel</keyword>
</DOC>