<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00856349</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical trial is to determine whether periodic therapy programming reports illustrating physician usage of shock reduction programming can increase utilization of recommended programming guidelines for defibrillators.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Medtronic Shock-Less Study on Physician Utilization of Shock Reduction Programming</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Shocks delivered to patients by defibrillators, while life-saving, can create anxiety, pain and decrease quality of life. Previous studies have shown that device programming and features can safely reduce the number of shocks patients receive. This study will explore the extent to which physicians use these programming and features. It will determine whether repeat and frequent awareness to how they program their own subjects and the programming trends of all enrolled subjects will change their programming patterns. This will be accomplished by understanding physicians' device programming behaviors and providing reports as a tool to help physicians manage their subjects and provide shock reduction programming recommended by previous publications.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject (or subject's legally authorized representative) is willing and able to sign and date the Patient Consent Form (PCF) and authorization for access to and use of health information, if applicable Subject has been implanted with a Medtronic market released ICD or CRTD device (US/Canada Concerto®/Virtuoso® or newer model; AsiaPacific, Israel, Latin America EnTrust™, InSync Sentry®, or Concerto®/Virtuoso® or newer model) within the past 30 days Subject has commercially released RA (if applicable), RV, and LV (if applicable) leads Subject is enrolled in a concurrent study that has not been approved for concurrent enrollment by the Medtronic Clinical Trial Leader</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Implantable Cardioverter Defibrillator (ICD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac Resynchronization Therapy-Defibrillator (CRT-D)</keyword>
	<keyword>Lead Integrity Alert (LIA)</keyword>
	<keyword>Therapy Programming Report (TPR)</keyword>
</DOC>