<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00856427</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial studies imaging markers in planning radiation therapy in patients with lung cancer. Implanting markers in the tumor that can be seen using imaging procedures during radiation therapy may allow x-rays to be sent directly to the tumor and cause less damage to normal tissue.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Implantation of Markers for the Radiotherapy of Lung Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - To acquire experience in the marker implantation process for mediastinal lymph nodes and primary lung tumors in patients with stage I-IIIB non-small cell lung cancer. - To characterize the potential side effects involved in the use of markers in these patients. - To analyze the positional stability of lung markers in these patients over a radiotherapy series. - To acquire experience in the use of markers for treatment planning and radiotherapy in these patients. OUTLINE: Patients undergo implantation of ≥ 1 small radio-opaque Visicoil™ marker into or close to the primary lesion and affected lymph nodes by bronchoscopy. Patients then undergo x-rays to document marker location, detect potentially dropped markers, and diagnose operation-related side effects (i.e., pneumothorax). After marker implantation, patients undergo stereotactic or conventionally fractionated radiotherapy for 30-33 daily fractions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of nonsmall cell lung cancer Stage IIIIB disease No prior surgical tumor resection Respirationinduced tumor motion &gt; 5 mm Recruited by attending physician or research nurse at the Medical College of Virginia Hospitals PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Not pregnant No insufficient lung function or other parameters prohibiting a bronchoscopy Not a prisoner or institutionalized PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics Concurrent chemotherapy allowed</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IA non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IB non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIA non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIB non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>