<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01754129</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In patients with advanced levodopa-responsive Parkinson's Disease and severe motor fluctuations despite optimized treatment with conventional oral Parkinson's Disease medications, treatment with Duodopa represents an alternative treatment option to improve motor, non-motor performance and overall quality of life. These benefits have been obtained in short and mid-term trials (mainly up to 2 years). Data on long-term effectiveness (5 years of treatment or more) and safety are not available. Also data concerning the benefit of Duodopa on cognitive function, axial symptoms and disability have to be confirmed. Recent data on deep brain stimulation (DBS), the alternative option treatment in advanced Parkinson's Disease patients, showed that after 5 years from the implant, a worsening of axial symptoms (gait and balance) and after 1 to 3 years of speech could occur. Moreover, it has never been assessed if the benefit on motor and non-motor symptoms in patients treated with DUODOPA could be influenced by age and duration of the disease, as already shown for DBS implanted patients. This study should clarify the missing information on long-term benefit of Duodopa (up to 7 years) especially focusing on motor fluctuations and disability.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Global REsponsE During iNFusIon of a gEl With LevoDopa/Carbidopa</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Post Marketing Observational Study to document the long-term clinical effectiveness of DUODOPA in Parkinson Disease patients under the conditions of a routine clinical setting.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carbidopa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levodopa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients already on treatment with DUODOPA ® (having already concluded the nasointestinal phase) according to the local DUODOPA® product label and to clinical routine care for advanced PD patients Patients with available data on Duodopa treatment, on previous PD conventional treatments and with at least one of the scales/questionnaires under study already collected on the patient clinical chart Patient or legal representative has given written informed consent Nonprofessional caregiver (relative or familiar who give daily assistance to the patient) has given his/her written consent • History or presence of any condition that might interfere with the longterm continuation of the duodenal infusion of DUODOPA</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Caregiver</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
	<keyword>Parkinson's Disease</keyword>
</DOC>