<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02840708</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objective: Evaluate Pharmacokinetics and determine the safety of GM-CSF single dose inhalation. Study Design: Pharmacokinetic open study</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SK-1401 (rhGM-CSF Agent for Inhalation) GM-CSF Inhalation Pharmacokinetic Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Aspiration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Alveolar Proteinosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autoimmune Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subjects judged to be appropriate for the study by the attending physician 2. can provide signed informed consent. aPAP patient must meet the following 3. aPAP patient aged over 20 and below 80 years old (as of the date of registration) 4. aPAP severity is mild or moderate. (not severe) Healthy volunteer must meet the following 5. Japanese healthy male subject aged over 20 and below 45 years old (as of the date of registration). 6. BMI (Body mass index) is between 18 and 25. 1. WBC of 12,000/mcl or more 2. Fever of 38 degree celsius or more 3. History of malignant disease within recent 5 years (not applied to the treated cases of local basal cell carcinoma) 4. Complication of severe cardiovascular diseases including congestive heart failure, angina pectoris, hemorrhagic tendency, etc. 5. Complication of respiratory diseases such as pulmonary infectious disease(incl. pulmonary tuberculosis), interstitial pneumonitis, lung fibrosis or bronchiectasis, in which the evaluations of safety of GMCSF therapy are considered to be difficult. 6. History or complication of infectious diseases which require systemic administration of antibiotics, antifungal or antiviral agents within recent 2 weeks. 7. liver dysfunction 8. renal dysfunction 9. Previous experience of severe and unexplained adverse events during aerosol delivery of any kind of medicinal product 10. Positive for HIVAb, HBsAg, HCVAb, STS or TPHA 11. allergic to GMCSF. 12. addicted to illegal drugs 13. Participation to other clinical trials within 12 weeks before registration. 14. smoking within 5 years 15. cannot follow the procedure defined in this protocol aPAP patient must exclude the following 16. Pregnant or possibly pregnant women, lactating women, and women who desire to become pregnant during the study period 17. Patients who have been treated with wholelung lavage, repeated segmentallung lavage, GMCSF or rituximab within 6 months before the start of the study. 18. taking other inhalation. Healthy volunteer must exclude the following 19. taking any medicines (incl. OTC).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>