<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00772447</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objectives of this study is to evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of Intravenous Daptomycin (Cubicin®)Compared with that of Comparator (Vancomycin or Vancomycin Followed by Semi-synthetic Penicillin-cloxacillin) in the Treatment of Chinese Subjects with Complicated Bacterial Skin and Skin Structure Infection due to Gram-Positive Pathogens.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>China Registration Study in Patients With Skin Infections</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Skin Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Daptomycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Penicillins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vancomycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cloxacillin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Provision of inform consent A diagnosis of of complicated skin and skin structure infection known or suspected to be due to Grampositive bacteria Diagnosis of bacterial skin and skin structure infection in the presence of some complicating factor, including infections involving deeper soft tissue or requiring surgical intervention, a preexisting lesion or underlying condition affect healing Subjects known to have any bloodstream infection (including bloodstream infection caused by S. aureus). Subjects whose baseline blood cultures are positive for any clinically pathogenic organism ( including S. aureus ) should be discontinued from study Minor or superficial skin infections, Infected "decubitus"ulcer, Perirectal abscess, Hidradenitis suppurativa, Myositis, Multiple infected ulcers at distant sites, Infected burn wounds of a large area, Conditions requiring surgery that in and of itself would cure the infection or remove the infected site (eg, amputation) Conditions requiring emergent surgical intervention at the site of infection (eg, progressive necrotizing infections)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Skin Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Complicated Bacterial Skin and Skin Structure Infection due to Gram-positive Pathogens</keyword>
</DOC>