<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00772668</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Monoclonal antibodies, such as rituximab, can block cancer growth in different ways. Some block the ability of cancer cells to grow and spread. Others find cancer cells and help kill them or carry cancer-killing substances to them. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as cyclophosphamide and prednisone, work in different ways to stop the growth of cancer cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Bortezomib may stop the growth of cancer cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth and by blocking blood flow to the tumor. Giving rituximab together with cyclophosphamide, bortezomib, and prednisone may kill more cancer cells. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is studying how well giving rituximab together with cyclophosphamide, bortezomib, and prednisone works as first-line therapy in treating patients with stage III or stage IV follicular lymphoma or marginal zone lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rituximab, Cyclophosphamide, Bortezomib, and Prednisone in Treating Patients With Stage III or Stage IV Follicular Lymphoma or Marginal Zone Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - To determine the overall response rate, in terms of complete response (CR), unconfirmed CR, and partial response, in patients with follicular lymphoma or marginal zone lymphoma treated with rituximab, cyclophosphamide, bortezomib, and prednisone (R-CVelP) as first line of treatment. Secondary - To determine progression-free survival of patients treated with this regimen. - To determine overall survival of patients treated with this regimen. - To determine the safety and tolerance to R-CVelP in these patients. OUTLINE: - Induction therapy: Patients receive rituximab IV and cyclophosphamide IV over 30 minutes on day 1, bortezomib IV on days 1 and 8, and oral prednisone once daily on days 1-5. Treatment repeats every 21 days for up to 8 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients then proceed to maintenance therapy. - Maintenance therapy: Patients receive rituximab IV on days 1, 8, 15, and 22. Treatment repeats every 6 months for up to 4 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study therapy, patients are followed every 4 months for 1 year, every 6 months for 2 years, and then annually thereafter.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Follicular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell, Marginal Zone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed grade 1 or 2 follicular lymphoma (FL) or marginal zone lymphoma (MZL) Stage III or IV disease Measurable or evaluable disease Previously untreated disease PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: ECOG performance status 13 ANC &gt; 1,000/mm³ Platelet count &gt; 100,000/mm³ (unless due to lymphoma) Bilirubin &lt; 2.0 mg/dL Creatinine &lt; 2 mg/dL (unless due to lymphoma) AST, ALT, and alkaline phosphatase &lt; 3 times upper limit of normal Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception No myocardial infarction within the past 6 months No NYHA class IIIIV heart failure No uncontrolled angina No severe uncontrolled ventricular arrhythmias No ECG evidence of acute ischemia or active conductive system abnormalities No hypersensitivity to boron or mannitol No serious medical or psychiatric illness likely to interfere with participation in this clinical study No history of HIV infection No concurrent or previous malignancy with poor prognosis (&lt; 90% probability of survival at 5 years) or actively treated for a second malignancy No peripheral neuropathy ≥ grade 2 within the past 14 days PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: No prior therapy for this disease including chemotherapy, singleagent rituximab, or radiotherapy No other concurrent anticancer therapy including chemotherapy, radiation, hormonal treatment, or immunotherapy At least 14 days since prior and no other concurrent investigational drugs No concurrent participation in another clinical study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage III grade 1 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV grade 1 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III grade 2 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV grade 2 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>