<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00772759</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the study is to investigate the safety and tolerability of single and multiple once daily ascending doses of AZD3199 delivered as dry powder via the Turbuhaler inhaler in healthy male Japanese subjects by assessment of incidence and nature of adverse events (AEs), clinically significant abnormalities in ECG parameters, blood pressure (BP), pulse rate, lung function parameters, body temperature and laboratory variables (clinical chemistry, haematology and urinalysis). The secondary objectives of the study are to investigate the pharmacokinetics (PK) of single and multiple ascending doses of AZD3199 by assessment of the degree of accumulation, dose proportionality and time linearity in healthy Japanese subjects, and to investigate systemic β 2- adrenoreceptor mediated effects of single and multiple ascending doses of AZD3199 by assessment of potassium and lactate concentrations, tremor and palpitations, heart rate, QTc, pulse rate, blood pressure and FEV1.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assess Safety, Tolerability and PK of AZD3199 in Japanese</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>AZD-3199</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Be healthy Japanese volunteers, both of the volunteer's parents, and all grandparents must be Japanese. The volunteer must have been born in Japan, have a valid Japanese passport and must not have lived outside Japan for for more than 5 years. BMI 18 27, Weight 50 85 kg Be nonsmoker or exsmoker who has stopped smoking (or using other nicotine products) for &gt;6 months prior to study start. Clinical normal physical findings Any clinically significant disease or disorder Any clinically relevant abnormal findings in physical examination, clinical chemistry, haematology, urinalysis, vital signs, ECG or lung function at baseline Any clinically important abnormalities in rhythm, conduction or morphology of resting ECG that may interfere with the interpretation of QTc interval changes. Use of any medication (including OTC), herbal preparations, vitamins or nutritional supplements within 2 weeks prior to Visit 2, except for occasional intake of paracetamol (maximum daily dose of 4 g)</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>AZD3199</keyword>
	<keyword>Japanese Healthy Volunteers</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase I study</keyword>
	<keyword>Single and Multiple Ascending Dose</keyword>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
	<keyword>tolerability</keyword>
	<keyword>PK</keyword>
</DOC>