<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01200602</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Megestrol acetate may help improve appetite and lessen weight loss caused by cancer. PURPOSE: This clinical trial studies megestrol acetate in treating weight loss or anorexia in young patients with malignancies who are undergoing radiation therapy and/or chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Megestrol Acetate in Treating Weight Loss or Anorexia in Young Patients With Malignancies Who Are Undergoing Radiation Therapy and/or Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:Proportion of Patients Who Maintain Weight or Experience Weight Gain. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:BMI Trends, Caloric Intake, Weight Maintenance Over Time, Toxicity Profile as Assessed by NCI Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Effects (CTCAE) v.4. OUTLINE: Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. ARM A: Patients receive oral megestrol acetate 1-2 times (10 mg/kg dose if once daily or 5 mg/kg dose if twice daily) daily for 4 weeks. ARM B (control): Patients are observed for weight loss and gain for 4 weeks. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 12 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anorexia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Body Weight Changes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Megestrol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Megestrol Acetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Any pediatric patient with an underlying diagnosis of a malignancy (excluding hematological malignancies like leukemias and lymphomas) ≥5% weight loss from diagnosis of primary malignancy (must be currently on chemotherapy and/or radiation therapy or scheduled to receive cancer therapy OR ≥5% weight loss following bone marrow transplant (autologous or allogeneic blood/bone marrow) and not actively receiving corticosteroid therapy Negative pregnancy test done =&lt; 7 days prior to registration for women of childbearing potential only Receiving tube feedings or parenteral nutrition Evidence of ascites Current (within the past 28 days) or planned treatment with adrenal steroids (shortterm use of dexamethasone around days of intravenous chemotherapy is allowed for protection against emesis), androgens, progestational agents, or appetite stimulants (e.g., dronabinol) Known mechanical obstruction of the alimentary tract, malabsorption, or intractable vomiting (&gt; 5 episodes/week) History of unresectable brain tumor or cancer metastatic to the brain History of thromboembolic disease Insulinrequiring diabetes Congestive heart failure and/or uncontrolled hypertension Anticoagulation Previous history of thrombosis (personal and immediate family) Concurrent corticosteroid therapy (except as an antiemetic)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>