<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00970372</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Norwegian Social and Welfare Act of 1992, opened for compulsory commitment of patients with serious alcohol and drug problems to inpatient care. Clinical research of compulsory committed dual diagnosed patients is to date unavailable and is demanded by the health authorities of Norway. Because there has been limited examination/screening and no post-treatment research efforts on this group of patients, the investigators have limited knowledge of the treatment as well as the patient group. Do compulsory treated patients differ from those voluntarily admitted? Does this type of treatment influence the patients' motivation to change their behaviour, and does the treatment effort lead to positive outcome effects in the long run? The primary aim is to acquire new and in depth descriptive knowledge about the compulsory treated group of patients according to: Drug dependence, psychiatric and somatic co-morbidity and socio-demographic characteristics, and investigate whether the treatment yields the intended outcomes in terms of improved substance abuse measures. A second aim is to compare the group with a corresponding group of voluntarily admitted patients within the same wards. A follow-up interview focusing on motivational issues within 6 months post treatment to evaluate the long-term results of the treatment is planned. A quasi-experimental, prospective case-control study will be conducted. Compulsory committed patients in five counties during a two year period, will be compared to a group of voluntarily admitted patients. The groups will be compared regarding 1) description and screening 2) motivation to change and 3) outcome results after 6 months. Both official authorities as well as clinical practitioners would benefit from valid Norwegian results and knowledge within this field to form further policies and evidence based best practice for this vulnerable group of patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dual-Diagnosis and Compulsory Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with alcohol and substance use disorders Estimated premorbid IQ of 70 or higher Active drug or alcohol abuse</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Coercion</keyword>
</DOC>