<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00399217</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose is to further evaluate the operation, safety, and feasibility of a subcutaneous implantable defibrillator (S-ICD) system in patients who require an implantable cardioverter defibrillator (ICD)for treating ventricular tachyarrhythmias. The S-ICD electrode and pulse generator emulator will be briefly implanted and tested during the standard implantation procedure of an ICD, but then the S-ICD system will be removed entirely.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Further Acute Research of a Subcutaneous Implantable Defibrillator (S-ICD) System</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objectives of this study are to further evaluate the S-ICD system's ability to identify and terminate induced ventricular tachyarrhythmias in patients acutely with an S-ICD emulator and parasternal electrode during the implant procedure of a standard transvenous ICD. The active emulator is not a powered medical device and all elements of the test system are removed following the testing. This acute intra-operative protocol will test the ability of the electrode and emulator to appropriately convert the arrhythmia and allos an assessment of post shock pacing.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tachycardia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tachycardia, Ventricular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ventricular Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients requiring ICD therapy according to National Centre for Clinical Excellence (NICE) criteria are eligible And patients who require replacement of an existing transvenous ICD system are eligible Patients unable or unwilling to provide informed consent Any conditions which precludes the subject's ability to comply with the study requirements, including completion of the study Females who are pregnant or lactating and premenopausal women who are unwilling to use adequate birth control for the duration of the study Participation in another investigational device trial at any time during the conduct of this study Patients with a serious medical condition and life expectancy of less than one year Patients with documented spontaneous and frequently recurring VT that is reliably terminated with antitachycardia pacing Patients with existing epicardial patches or subcutaneous electrodes in the left thoracic quadrant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>subcutaneous ICD</keyword>
	<keyword>ICD</keyword>
	<keyword>DFT</keyword>
	<keyword>Pacing threshold</keyword>
	<keyword>Polarity</keyword>
</DOC>