<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00993629</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will be an 8-week randomized, placebo-controlled clinical trial of pregnenolone administered adjunctively to treatment as usual in PTSD and depression in OEF/OIF Veterans.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adjunctive Pregnenolone in Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) and Depression in Operations Enduring Freedom and Iraqi Freedom (OEF/OIF) Veterans</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PTSD and depression are critical areas of immediate impact to Operation Enduring Freedom and Operation Iraqi Freedom (OEF/OIF) Veterans. Current treatments for PTSD (which frequently co-occurs with depression) remain limited, with many patients remaining symptomatic despite single or combination administration of SSRIs, mood stabilizers, antipsychotics and sedatives/hypnotics. In addition, many patients treated for depression remain symptomatic. New interventions are thus urgently needed in PTSD with co-occurring depression to ensure optimal functional outcomes for our Service members and their families.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of PTSD, diagnosis of MDD, age 1855, no change in psychotropic medication for &gt;=4 weeks, no anticipated need to to alter psychotropic medication for duration of study Unstable medical/neurological illness, diagnosis of bipolar disorder, schizophrenia or other psychotic disorder, cognitive disorder, substance dependence, positive urine drug screen at screening, use of hormonal supplementation, pregnancy/lactation, female patients who are sexually active and not using acceptable nonhormonal birth control, initiation/change of psychotherapy within 3 months of randomization, recent/current electroconvulsive therapy, regular use of opiates/barbiturates/benzodiazepines</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>PTSD</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurosteroids</keyword>
</DOC>