<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00993304</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted in Europe. The aim of this trial is to investigate whether a new compound, liraglutide, reduces the level of lipids (fat), including cholesterol, in the blood of type 2 diabetics, following a meal with high fat content.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Trial to Assess the Effect of Liraglutide on Blood Triglyceride (Fat) Levels After a Meal in Type 2 Diabetics</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects with type 2 diabetes mellitus (diet and exercise treated, or treated with specific oral antidiabetics (metformin, sulfonylureas and glinides) mono or combination therapy) diagnosed at least 3 months previously BMI between 18.5 and 40 kg/m2 HbA1c between 6.5 and 10.0% both inclusive Known or suspected allergy to trial products or related products Previous participation in this trial (randomised). Rescreening of screening failures is allowed only once Females of childbearing potential who are pregnant, breastfeeding or intend to become pregnant or are not using adequate contraceptive methods (adequate contraceptives are defined as combination oral contraceptives (OC), hormonal intra uterine devices (IUDs), implants and injectables; for Germany, a condom for the male partner must be used in combination with OC, IUD, implant or injectables for the duration of the trial and for 30 days following the last dose of trial medication) if not sterile or postmenopausal The receipt of any investigational drug within 3 months prior to this trial Previous insulin treatment (shortterm insulin treatment of up to 7 days are exempted if this has occurred no later than 3 months prior to screening). Cancer (except basal cell skin cancer or squamous cell skin cancer) or any clinically significant disorder (except type 2 diabetes) Clinically significant active cardiovascular disease including history of myocardial infarction (heart attack) within the past 6 months and/or heart failure at the discretion of the Investigator. History of alcoholism or drug abuse during the last 12 months Blood donation within the last 3 months. Plasma donation within the last month. Additional exclusion criteria for Germany: Male subjects who are sexually active and have partners who are or could be pregnant, not using a barrier method of contraception (e.g. condom) for the duration of the trial and for 30 days following the last dose of trial medication</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>