<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00308425</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim of this study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of EC-MPS plus valsartan as part of an intensified multifactorial intervention on the reduction of the 12-month rate of transplant nephropathy compared with EC-MPS plus standard practice of care in recipients of a first cadaver donor kidney transplant given CsA-ME, basiliximab, and short-term steroids.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Enteric-coated Mycophenolate Sodium (EC-MPS) Plus Valsartan in Patients With Kidney Transplants (MYTHOS</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Valsartan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria 1. Male and female patients aged 18 to 70 years 2. Patients receiving a first kidney transplant from a cadaver donor, who are scheduled to receive CsAME and antiCD25 antibody as primary immunosuppression; 3. Patients able to receive the first dose of ECMPS within 48 hours of graft reperfusion Exclusion criteria 1. Multiorgan recipients (e.g. kidney and pancreas, double kidney) or previous transplant with any other organ. 2. Recipient of a kidney from a nonheart beating, from a cadaver donor aged more than 70 years, or with cold ischemia time of more than 36 hours 3. Recipient who is HLAidentical to the donor 4. Patients with a PRA level (past or current level) higher than 50% 5. Patients with a known hypersensitivity to ECMPS or other components of the formulation (e.g. lactose). 6. Patients with thrombocytopenia (&lt; 75,000/mm3), with an absolute neutrophil count of &lt; 1,500/mm3, and/or leukocytopenia (&lt; 2,500/mm3), and/or hemoglobin &lt; 6 g/dL at Screening or Baseline. 7. HIVpositive 8. Positive HBsAg test for both donor and recipients. 9. Unstable angina, acute myocardial infarction or stroke during the last 6 month or heart failure NYHA class IIIIV or hemodinamically significant valvular heart disease 10. Liver injury as indicated by transaminase serum levels (ALT and/or AST) greater than 2 x ULN 11. Creatinine kinase (CK) levels greater than 5 x ULN. Additional protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Renal transplantation, EC-MPS</keyword>
</DOC>