<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02138513</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Mindfulness-based cognitive therapy has been demonstrated to be effective in reducing anxiety, depression and fatigue in cancer patients. As this intervention can be offered in groups, costs are relatively low. In addition, delivering MBCT online might make the intervention more accessible and cost-effectiveness. However, more information is needed about what treatment works best for which patient. Therefore, the aim of this study is to investigate clinical and cost-effectiveness of both individual MBCT online and MBCT offered as a group training compared to TAU . Study design: The design of the study will be a multi-centre, randomised, superiority trial, comparing MBCT online and MBCT offered as a group training with TAU. Participants in the TAU condition will be randomised to one of the treatment conditions after 3 months. Main assessments will take place at baseline (T0), post-treatment (T1), and 3 (T2) and 9 months after post-treatment (T3). We expect the MBCT conditions to be superior to TAU in terms of improving mindfulness skills, anxiety and depressive compants, psychological well-being, rumination and fear of cancer recurrence. We also expect the MBCT to result in patients returning to work earlier, have a higher work ability and have lower medical care costs, thereby being more cost-effective than TAU.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>(Cost-)Effectiveness of Mindfulness-Based Cognitive Therapy (MBCT) in Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>HADS ≥ 11 Cancer diagnosis (at present or past) Stable dose if using psychopharmacological medication for at least 3 months computer literacy and acces to internet capable of filling out questionnaires in Dutch severe psychiatric morbidity as psychoses, suicidal ideation previous mindfulnessbased treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mindfulness</keyword>
	<keyword>MBCT</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Oncology</keyword>
	<keyword>E-health</keyword>
	<keyword>Cost-effectiveness</keyword>
</DOC>