<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02138175</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine whether noninvasive hemoglobin monitoring is sensitive and accurate enough to detect a significant downward trend in hemoglobin in patients at risk for significant bleeding. If this can be shown, it has the potential to spare patients multiple invasive blood draws as well as allow for earlier detection of significant blood loss and therefore positively impact on patient morbidity and mortality. Additionally, it may represent significant financial cost savings in that it may allow for patients to be monitored in a non-intensive care unit setting. This will be an observational study. The continuous hemoglobin monitor will be connected to the patient and hemoglobin measurement data will be collected. Routine laboratory hemoglobin monitoring will occur concurrently at a pre-specified frequency as well as at the physician's discretion based on usual clinical information. The physician will be blinded to the continuous hemoglobin monitoring readings and therefore patient care will not be affected by the use of the monitor. Once the study has ended, the data will then be analyzed to assess for correlation between continuous hemoglobin monitoring readings and laboratory hemoglobin measurement.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Continuous Hemoglobin Monitoring: Detection of Acute Blood Loss - Accurate, Timely and Cost-effective</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>No recruitment initiated</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<criteria>&gt; 18 years of age admission to surgical intensive care unit suspected or high risk for ongoing blood loss</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>bleeding</keyword>
	<keyword>blood loss</keyword>
	<keyword>hemoglobin</keyword>
	<keyword>hemoglobin monitoring</keyword>
	<keyword>noninvasive monitoring</keyword>
</DOC>