<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02138149</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Spinal cord injury (SCI) almost always affects bladder function as well. As a result of this bladder dysfunction, individuals with SCI have to undergo regular invasive examination of their bladder function (urodynamic examination). The nerve growth factor (NGF) is released from smooth muscle cells of the bladder, and there are reports, that the concentration of NGF is elevated in the urine of patients with bladder dysfunction. The NGF concentration can also be measured in the blood. The concentration of NGF in the blood and urine of SCI individuals has not yet been investigated. These concentrations may correlate with the severity of bladder dysfunction, and may thus be used to replace or at least reduce the number of the more invasive urodynamic examinations. The hypothesis that urine and blood NGF concentrations in individuals with SCI are higher compared to individuals with healthy bladder function will be tested.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Is the Nerve Growth Factor (NGF) a Useful Biomarker in Neurogenic Bladder Dysfunction After Spinal Cord Injury?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitogens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Control Group physiologic bladder function no signed consent form age &lt;18 / &gt;80 years urinary tract infection bladder surgery radiation therapy of the pelvic area pregnancy bleeding disorder Study Group neurogenic detrusor overactivity presentation for urodynamic examination no signed consent form age &lt;18 / &gt;80 years urinary tract infection bladder augmentation bladder evacuation by permanent catheterization radiation therapy of the pelvic area pregnancy bleeding disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>spinal cord injury</keyword>
	<keyword>neurogenic lower urinary tract dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>nerve growth factor</keyword>
	<keyword>neurogenic detrusor overactivity</keyword>
	<keyword>urodynamics</keyword>
</DOC>