<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01091116</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether intra-articular (knee joint) administration of MEN16132 is effective reducing the pain from knee osteoarthritis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Locally Injected Bradykinin Antagonist for TReatment of OSteoarthritiS</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>MEN16132 is a non-peptide bradykinin B2-receptor antagonist showing analgesic and anti-inflammatory activity in nonclinical osteoarthritis models. This study is being conducted as a dose finding study to determine the safety and efficacy of MEN16132, given as three doses/four treatment regimens in comparison to placebo, as well the time to onset and duration of effect.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>(4-amino-5-(4-(4-(2,4-dichloro-3-(2,4-dimethyl-8-quinolyloxymethyl)phenylsulfonamido)tetrahydro-2H-4-pyranoylcarbonyl)piperazino)-5-oxopentyl)(trimethyl)ammonium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Main Male or female patients ≥40 years old. Symptomatic primary knee osteoarthritis (ACR criteria) since ≥6 months prior to screening, Kellgren Lawrence Grade 2 or 3, and representing an indication for intraarticular drug injection. &gt;50 mm VAS pain score assigned to the index knee at WOMAC VA 3.1A1 (pain while walking on a flat surface). &gt;125 mm VAS pain score assigned to the index knee at WOMAC VA 3.1 A subscore (total pain). Pain in the index knee on at least 50% of the days in the month preceding the screening. Main Patients with Kellgren &amp; Lawrence Grade I or IV (doubtful or severe) osteoarthritis of the knee. Knee condition representing an indication for surgery Patients with Inflammatory or crystal arthropathies, acute fractures, severe loss of bone density, bone necrosis. Patients with isolated patellafemoral syndrome or chondromalacia. Patients with OA predominant in the lateral compartment or any significant valgus deformity. Patients with any other disease or condition interfering with the free use and evaluation of the index knee for the 3 month duration of the trial (e.g. cancer, congenital defects, spine osteoarthritis). Major injury or surgery to the index knee within the previous 12 months prior to screening. Severe hip osteoarthritis ipsilateral to index knee. Any pain &gt;30 mm VAS that could interfere with the assessment of index knee pain (e.g. pain in any other part of the lower extremities, pain radiating to the knee). Any pharmacological or nonpharmacological treatment started or changed during 4 weeks prior to randomisation or likely to be changed during the duration of the study Use of systemic or topical corticosteroids &gt;10 mg prednisolone equivalent per day during 30 days prior to randomisation. Use of any pain or OA medication (e.g. NSAIDs, COX2 inhibitors, analgesics) during 1 or 2 weeks prior to randomisation. Any intraarticular or local periarticular punction, injection or surgery to the index knee during the 6 months prior to screening.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Injections, Intra-Articular</keyword>
</DOC>