<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01718301</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of a Response Guided Therapy of boceprevir 800 mg dosed three times a day (TID) orally (PO) in combination with Peginterferon (either alpha 2b or alpha 2a) and Ribavirin in HIV/HCV genotype 1 infected patients that failed to previous HCV therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>HIV Patients With Chronic Hepatitis C Genotype 1 Infection Who Failed Previously to Peginterferon /Ribavirin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coinfection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2a</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For inclusion in the study, subjects must have a qualifying regimen defined as peginterferon alfa2a plus ribavirin or peginterferon alfa2b plus ribavirin for a minimum of 12 weeks. If a subject has received more than one such regimen, the most recent regimen is considered the qualifying regimen. Subject must have previously documented chronic hepatitis C (CHC) genotype 1 infection. Subjects with other or mixed genotypes are not eligible. The HCVRNA result at the screening visit must confirm genotype 1 infection and be ≥10,000 IU/mL. Subject must have a liver biopsy with histology consistent with CHC and no other etiology and/or Fibroscan assessment. In case of: 1. No cirrhosis. Biopsies and/or Fibroscan must be within 18 months of screening visit. 2. Cirrhosis. No specific length of time would be requested. All patients with cirrhosis must have an ultrasound 6 month within of screening visit. Patients must be on stable antiretroviral therapy including a CD4 cell count of more than 100 per mm3 and a HIV plasmatic viral load undetectable (it is &lt; 50 copies/mL) for more than 6 months. Antiretroviral therapy must be Raltegravirbased (al least during the last 3 months). Subject must be ≥18 years of age. HIV treatment should not contain efavirenz (EFV), nevirapine (NVP), etravirine (ETV), didanosine (ddI), stavudine (d4T), zidovudine (AZT), or HIV protease inhibitors. Subject must weight between 40 kg and 125 kg. Subject and subject's partner(s) must each agree to use acceptable methods of contraception for at least 2 weeks prior to Day 1 and continue until at least 6 months after last dose of study drug. Subjects must be willing to give written informed consent and by investigator opinion be able to follow the protocol visit design. Subjects known to be coinfected with hepatitis B virus (HBsAg positive). Patients chronically infected with HCV genotype other than 1 CD4 cell count &lt; 100 cel/mm3. Plasma HIV RNA more than 50 copies/mL Platelet count less than 80.000 /mm3 Subjects who required discontinuation of previous interferon or ribavirin regimen for a severe adverse event considered by the investigator to be possibly or probably related to ribavirin and/or interferon. Treatment with ribavirin within 90 days and any interferonalpha within 1 month of Screening. Treatment for hepatitis C with any investigational medication. Prior treatments with herbal remedies with known hepatotoxicity are exclusionary. Participation in any other clinical trial within 30 days of randomization or intention to participate in another clinical trial during participation in this study. History of hemoglobinopathy (e.g., thalassemia) or any other cause of or tendency to hemolysis. Evidence of decompensate liver disease including, but not limited to, a history or presence of clinical ascites, bleeding varices, or hepatic encephalopathy. Diabetic and/or hypertensive subjects with clinically significant ocular examination findings. Unstable or untreated preexisting psychiatric condition. Any known preexisting medical condition that could interfere with the subject's participation in and completion of the study. Any current evidence of substance abuse of alcohol or other drugs. Subjects receiving opioid agonist substitution therapy but not enrolled in an opiate substitution maintenance program.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>HCV</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>Coinfection</keyword>
</DOC>