<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00168103</DOC>
	<brief_summary>HAE is a rare disorder characterized by functional C1 esterase inhibitor deficiency. If not treated adequately, the acute attacks of HAE can be life-threatening and may even result in fatalities, especially in case of swelling of the larynx. This clinical Phase 2/Phase 3 study was designed to provide clinically relevant data on dosing, efficacy and safety in subjects with HAE.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Human C1 Esterase Inhibitor (C1-INH) in Subjects With Acute Abdominal or Facial Hereditary Angioedema (HAE) Attacks</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>For each subject, only a single abdominal or facial attack was treated and evaluated. After receiving treatment, subjects were observed for a minimum of 4 hours, after which they could be discharged from the study center if they reported onset of symptom relief. Starting from 4 hours after treatment, subjects who reported insufficient or no symptom relief could receive a second dose of double-blind treatment (called "rescue medication") as follows: C1-INH 20 U/kg bw for subjects initially receiving placebo, C1-INH 10 U/kg bw for subjects initially receiving C1-INH 10 U/kg bw, and placebo for subjects initially receiving C1-INH 20 U/kg bw. The study was defined to be successful if the primary outcome measure and at least one of the secondary outcome measures were met in the comparison between the C1-INH 20 U/kg bw group and the Placebo group.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Angioedema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angioedemas, Hereditary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Complement C1s</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Complement C1 Inhibitor Protein</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Complement C1 Inactivator Proteins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Documented congenital C1INH deficiency Acute facial or abdominal HAE attack Key Acquired angioedema Treatment with any other investigational drug within the last 30 days before study entry Treatment with any C1INH concentrate within the previous 7 days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>C1 Inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Hereditary angioedema</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute HAE attack</keyword>
</DOC>