<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02639507</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research is to evaluate the effectiveness of vitrectomy for the treatment of diabetic macular edema. Diabetes is known to cause retinal blood vessels to leak, leading to swelling of the central retina (macula), and decreased vision. Removing the vitreous gel with vitrectomy surgery is known to decrease the swelling caused by diabetes. Diabetic retinopathy is often treated with laser or injections of medicine in to the eye.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>International Consortium Investigating Early Vitrectomy in Diabetic Macular Edema Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Macular Edema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Edema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Retinopathy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and women, &gt; 18 years of age with type 1 or 2 diabetes mellitus diagnosed and treated by an endocrinologist, internist or family medicine physician Background diabetic retinopathy DME with central subfield thickness (CST) &gt; 325 µm by Spectral Domain Optical Coherence Tomography (SDOCT) HbA1c level of &lt; 10.0 mg/dl Previous cataract surgery with implantation of a stable posterior chamber intraocular lens or a phakic eye with 1+ (out of 4+ scale) or less lens opacification Predominantly intact (80%) external limiting membrane (ELM) and photoreceptor inner/outer segment (IS/OS) lines within 500 µm of the fovea on horizontal and vertical SDOCT scans Best corrected Snellen visual acuity from 20/40 to 20/280 inclusive. Intraocular antivascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) injection within the previous 3 months Systemic antiVEGF or receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitor therapy within the previous 3 months Intraocular corticosteroid injection within the previous 6 months Periocular corticosteroid injection within the previous 3 months Vitreomacular traction on SDOCT scan (epiretinal membrane is allowed) Previous anterior or pars plana vitrectomy Glaucoma (IOP of &gt; 21 mmHg or regular use of more than 2 IOP lowering drugs) Previous trabeculectomy Likelihood of needing intraocular surgery within 6 months Hard exudates involving the fovea Proliferative diabetic retinopathy with any evidence of retinal traction Cataract of grade 2+ or greater.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>