<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00032084</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: A program that includes bupropion may be more effective in helping early-stage lung cancer patients to quit smoking. It is not yet known if a program to quit smoking is more effective with or without bupropion. PURPOSE: Randomized phase III trial to determine the effectiveness of a program to quit smoking with or without bupropion in treating patients who have undergone surgery for stage I or stage II non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>S0002 - A Program to Quit Smoking With or Without Bupropion in Treating Patients With Stage I or II Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Who Have Undergone Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Compare the effect of a smoking cessation intervention comprising behavior intervention and nicotine replacement with or without bupropion on 12-month quit rates in patients with completely resected stage I or II non-small cell lung cancer who are current smokers. - Compare the predictors of smoking cessation success in patients treated with these regimens. - Determine the relationship between smoking cessation and standard outcome measures (e.g., second malignancies, survival, and symptom status) in patients treated with these regimens. - Compare the effect of these treatment regimens on emotional functioning in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, double-blind, multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to gender, prior neoadjuvant or concurrent adjuvant chemotherapy and/or radiotherapy (yes vs no), and time since prior surgery (less than 6 months vs 6 to 12 months vs more than 12 months). Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 arms. All patients receive behavioral intervention comprising smoking cessation advice and education on day 1. Patients quit smoking on day 8. Patients then receive a nicotine transdermal patch once daily on days 8-77. - Arm I: Patients receive oral bupropion once daily on days 1-3 and twice daily on days 4-77. - Arm II: Patients receive oral placebo as in arm I. Patients are followed at 3, 6, and 12 months and then annually for 10 years. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 468 patients (234 [117 men and 117 women] per arm) will be accrued for this study within 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nicotine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupropion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of stage I or II nonsmall cell lung cancer with complete resection of all disease Must be free of recurrent or progressive disease Current smoker defined as: Smoked at least 100 cigarettes in entire life AND Currently smoking some days or every day Must establish a quit date that falls within 30 days after registration, but 7 days after physician advice and start of bupropion or placebo therapy PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: Zubrod 02 Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Cardiovascular: Not within an immediate postinfarction period No uncontrolled arrhythmias No unstable angina No uncontrolled hypertension (unstable blood pressure, diastolic pressure 90 mm Hg or greater) Other: Must be able to read, speak, and understand English Must be willing to allow testing of saliva for cotinine levels No history of seizures No history of eating disorders No known drugdrug interactions between nicotine patch and/or bupropion and patient's current or planned medications including chemotherapy and antiemetics No concurrent psychiatric diagnosis that would preclude study compliance PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: Concurrent adjuvant chemotherapy allowed Endocrine therapy: No concurrent systemic steroids Radiotherapy: Concurrent adjuvant radiotherapy allowed Surgery: See Disease Characteristics Recovered from prior surgery Other: Prior neoadjuvant therapy allowed At least 14 days since prior medications containing bupropion (e.g., Wellbutrin or Wellbutrin SR) No other concurrent medications that contain bupropion (e.g., Wellbutrin or Wellbutrin SR) No concurrent monoamine oxidase inhibitors No concurrent medications that lower seizure threshold (e.g., antipsychotics, antidepressants, or theophylline) No other concurrent nicotine replacement therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>