<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02944708</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to examine the efficacy of maintenance chemotherapy for the treatment of metastatic nasopharyngeal carcinoma. Participants will be randomized to 3 arms. Arm 1, control group, participants will receive only 4-8 cycles of conventional chemotherapy; arm 2, participants will receive 6 cycles of maintenance chemotherapy after conventional chemotherapy; arm 3, experiment arm, after conventional chemotherapy, participants will receive maintenance chemotherapy until disease progression or intolerable toxicities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial Evaluating Maintenance Chemotherapy for Metastatic Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase 3 randomized clinical trial to determine the efficacy of maintenance chemotherapy for the treatment of metastatic chemotherapy and how it should be delivered. Participants will be randomized to 3 arms. Arm 1 (control group), participants will receive only conventional chemotherapy; arm 2 (experimental group), participants will receive up to 6 cycles of maintenance chemotherapy after conventional chemotherapy; arm 3 (experimental group), after conventional chemotherapy, participants will receive maintenance chemotherapy until disease progression or intolerable toxicities. Participants in all 3 arms will receive similar conventional chemotherapy. Four to eight cycles of conventional chemotherapy with platinum-based regimen is preferred. Maintenance chemotherapy should use one of the regimens: S1 (40mg, twice a day for 14 days, every 3 weeks), capecitabine (1000mg/m^2, twice a day for 14 days, every 3 weeks) or Tegafur-uracil (100mg/m^2, q8h, for 14 days, every 3 weeks). The response of treatment will be evaluated according to RECIST criteria. Adverse events will be documented according to CTCAE v4.03.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nasopharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 and ≤ 70 years Histologically confirmed nasopharyngeal carcinoma, WHO (World Health Organization) classification II/III With distant metastasis With measurable lesions that can be detected by imaging studies Achieving PR (partial response) after 4 cycles of conventional chemotherapy Life expectancy ≥ 6 months ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group): 01, no significant active concurrent medical illnesses Adequate laboratory values within 30 dyas of enrollment to study defined as follows: N &gt; 2000/mm^3; PLT (platelet count) &gt; 100,000/mm^3; total bilirubin &lt; 1.5mg/dl; AST (aspartate aminotransferase)/ALT (alanine aminotransferase) &lt; 1.5 ULN (upper limit of normal); SCr (serum creatinine) &lt; 1.5mg/dl; CCR (creatinine clearance rate) &gt; 60ml/min Willing to accept adequate contraception for women with childbearing potential Ability to understand character and individual consequences of the clinical trial Willing to sign the written informed consent; Informed consent must be signed before the enrollment in the trial Received previous treatment for metastatic disease Pregnant or lactating women A diagnosis of malignancy other than CIS (carcinoma in situ) of the cervix, BCC (basal cell carcinoma) and SCC (squamous cell carcinoma) of the skin within the past 5 years Refusal of the patient to participate into the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>maintenance chemotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>