<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02944721</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to establish the genetic, neurophysiological and psychological phenotype of the patients presenting a persistent neuropathic pain after surgery of the breast cancer, by comparing the neuropathic painful patients with the not painful and with the not neuropathic painful . This will be realized on a transverse cohort ("Seintinelle"cohort) and confirmed on a forward-looking longitudinal cohort.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Genetic, Neurophysiological and Psychological Predictive Factors of Chronic Neuropathic Pain After Surgery for Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For both arms: Women over 18 years Having given a written consent form Affiliated to the social security scheme French language (read, written and spoken) Accepting the principle of the study and able to respect the conditions of the study. Other cancer or AIDS in evolution Bilateral Mastectomy Presence of chronic pain before the intervention for breast cancer, occupational accident, dispute or search for compensation Previous surgery on the same territory Peripheral neurological pathology or central (brain damage, multiple sclerosis) susceptible to interfere with the evaluation of the postoperative pain Heavy psychiatric histories: psychosis, severe depression having motivated a hospitalization, a suicide attempt Current major depressive episode at the time of the evaluation (cf. criterion diagnosis of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM5)) Abuse of drug or psychoactive substance (cf. definition of the DSM5) during the last six months; cognitive disorders (MMSE 24/30) or psychological incompatible with the respect and/or the understanding of the protocol Patients participating in another protocol of biomedical research. For longitudinal study: Patients who can be followed during the total duration of the study ( 12 months) for the longitudinal arm of the forwardlooking study Patients that must be operated for one of the two types of surgery: preservative surgery or mastectomy for breast cancer with ganglionic cleaning out Chemotherapy or radiotherapy before the surgery Previous surgery for a breast cancer Patients that must be operated for a surgery of the breast without ganglionic cleaning out For transversal study: Inclusion criteria: patients operated for a conservative surgery or a mastectomy for breast cancer with ganglionic cleaning out during 2 years before the inclusion Exclusion criteria patients operated for a surgery of the breast without ganglionic cleaning out Patients operated for more than 2 years</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neuropathic Pain</keyword>
</DOC>