<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02241499</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this trial, patients with histologically proven adenocarcinoma of the esophagus or esophagogastric junction noneligible for surgery or chemoradiation with curative intent will be included. Primary objective is to determine the rate of improvement in dysphagia after palliative short course hypofractionated radiotherapy (5 x 4 Gy) followed by chemotherapy consisting of oxaliplatin and fluorouracil. The rate of improvement of dysphagia is evaluated by a 5 graded dysphagia score, and a positive change of at least 1 score is considered to be an improvement.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Palliative Short-course Hypofractionated Radiotherapy Followed by Chemotherapy in Adenocarcinoma of the Esophagus or Esophagogastric Junction Trial - a Phase II Clinical Trial Protocol.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with histologically proven adenocarcinoma of the esophagus or esophagogastric junction noneligible for surgery or chemoradiation with curative intent Any T, N and M Age: 18 years or older WHO performance status ≤ 2 Life expectancy &gt; 3 months Dysphagia score &gt; 0 Adequate laboratory findings: hemoglobin &gt; 90 g/L, absolute neutrophil count 1.0 10 9/L, platelets ≥ 75 x 10 9/L, bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN), alanine aminotransferase (ALAT) ≤ 5 x ULN, creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN Fertile men and women must use effective means of contraception Signed written informed concent The patient must be able to comply with the protocol Prior treatment with selfexpanding metal stent (SEMS), radiotherapy or chemotherapy for the present disease Clinically significant (i.e. active) cardiovascular disease e.g. myocardial infarction (≤ 6 months) unstable angina, New York Heart Association (NYHA) grade IIIIV congestive heart failure Severe pulmonary disease e.g. pulmonary fibrosis Symptomatic peripheral neuropathy greater than grade 1 (CTCAE v. 4.0) Known hypersensitivity to any contents of the study drugs Pregnancy ( positive pregnancy test) and/or breast feeding Any other serious or uncontrolled illness which in the opinion of the investigator makes it undesirable for the patient to enter the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Digestive System Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Esophageal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Intestinal Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Gastrointestinal Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Digestive System Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Endoscopic response</keyword>
	<keyword>Fluorouracil</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic response</keyword>
	<keyword>Oxaliplatin</keyword>
	<keyword>Radiotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>