<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02241447</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to narrow the gap between patients being diagnosed with severe aortic stenosis and those being appropriately monitored and treated. For this purpose a prospective survey of current practice (3 months) will be conducted followed by a six month period of intervention during which a variety of quality improvements measures will be implemented. There will then be a 3 month follow-up period during which the legacy of this initiative will be monitored during which no intervention will be carried out.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Quality of Care in AS IMPULSE Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All patients meeting pre-specified criteria (severe aortic stenosis whether with or without symptoms) will be collected. There will be three phases at each site observation A, intervention, observation B. Observation A: In this phase, the nurse identifies cases with severe AS at the hub AND the satellite and collects their data. Baseline data for each patient will be collected and a follow-up will be done after three months for each patient to determine his/her outcome and the treatment that was decided on. There will also be an optional telephone follow-up to find out the patient's outcome. Intervention: In this phase, the physician referring a patient for echocardiography will be notified of a finding of severe aortic stenosis: the nurse brings cases with severe AS to the attention of the referring physician within a week (via phone, e-mail or letter) to make them aware of the diagnosis. Baseline and follow-up data will be collected for each patient as before. Moreover, more detailed data with regard to the patient's health status will be documented. Observation B: Same as Observation Phase A</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Constriction, Pathologic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aortic Valve Stenosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aortic valve area &lt; 1cm2 Indexed aortic valve area &lt;0.6 cm/m2 Maximum Jet velocity &gt; 4.0 m/sec Mean transvalvular gradient &gt; 40 mmHg Nonsevere aortic Stenosis (AS) Previous aortic valve replacement (AVR)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>aortic valve Stenosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Echo</keyword>
	<keyword>TAVI</keyword>
	<keyword>SAVR</keyword>
	<keyword>referral</keyword>
</DOC>