<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02241590</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Liver Cirrhosis is a common pathological consequence of chronic liver disease. Hepatitis B Virus (HBV) is one of most etiologies of liver cirrhosis in China. The effective inhibition of HBV can partially stop or reverse liver fibrosis in patients with chronic Hepatitis and liver cirrhosis due to HBV, and the anti-fibrotic strategy focusing on the regulation of hepatic extracellular matrix is still required and hopefully improve the efficacy of anti-virals for liver fibrotic patients with HBV, especially is necessary for in the patients with advance fibrosis stage ie. liver cirrhosis. Fuzheng Huayu has been found to enhance the degradation of collagens in fibrotic liver and have a good action against liver fibrosis in patients with chronic hepatitis B. However, there are no high quality clinical evidences which can demonstrate if the combination of anti-viral and anti-fibrotic therapy can improve the reversion of liver cirrhosis due to HBV. The primary objective of this study is to establish the safety and efficacy of the combination of Entecavir and Fuzheng Huayu for the reversion of liver fibrosis in patients with liver cirrhosis due to HBV.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Liver Cirrhosis Due to Hepatitis B Virus With Fuzheng Huayu and Entecavir</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Entecavir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>More than 6 months history of serum positive HBsAg Positive HBVDNA Age 1860 Ishak fibrosis score of the biopsy within 6 months ≥5, no antivirus or antifibrosis drug was taken within 6 months. ChildPugh&lt;7 (Stage A) The patient or the patient's guardian agrees to participate the random controlled trial and sign the Informed Consent Form. Primary Lamivudine, Adefovir dipivoxil and Entecavir resistance Decompensated liver cirrhosis Liver cancer Liver histology conform to other chronic liver disease cause (exclude fatty liver) NonHBV avihepadnavirus infected acute and chronic hepatitis, autoimmune hepatitis, primary biliary cirrhosis, primary sclerosing cholangitis, inherited metabolic liver disease, drug or toxic hepatitis, Alcoholic liver disease. Have psychiatric history or uncontrollable epilepsy patient. Uncontrollable diabetic patient History of Hemoglobin disease (such as Alpha globin generation barrier anemia, Sickle cell deficiency, Spherocytosis) or Hemolytic anemia patients caused by other reasons like autoimmunity. Severe background disease like chronic respiratory failure, circulatory failure, kidney failure etc. In situ organ transplantation (such as liver, kidney, lung and heart) or bone marrow transplantation and stem cell transplantation. Immunocompromised patients: such as HIV infection or take immunosuppressor or glucocorticoid (such as cyclosporin, azathioprine, adrenocortical hormone) within 3 months or chemotherapy drugs (such as cyclophosphamide, ammonia and cancer chemotherapy) and radioactive therapy. Gestation or lactation period women and women who plan to get pregnant during the study period. Patient who are allergy to the experimental drug. Using history of antiviral or antifibrosis drug within 6 months. Patients who are participating other trials. Other situation where PI thinks the patient should be excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>