<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02241460</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of treatment with Promescent Lidocaine Spray compared with placebo in patients with premature ejaculation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Promescent Lidocaine Spray in Men With Premature Ejaculation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Promescent Lidocaine Spray is a non-prescription drug that is marketed under an over-the-counter drug monograph (21 CFR Section 348.10 Subpart B (a)(2)) for male genital desensitizing drug products. In addition the evaluating the efficacy of treatment with Promescent, this study will evaluate patients' subjective distress, perception of improvement and optimal dose, and safety and tolerability of Promescent for patients with premature ejaculation and their respective partners.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Premature Ejaculation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject has provided written informed consent before screening. Subject is a male, 18 years of age or older. Subject meets the diagnostic criteria for premature ejaculation as defined by the DSMIVTR (Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 4th Edition, Text Revision; 2000). Subject has a stable, monogamous, heterosexual relationship and sexually active for at least the last 6 months. Subject and partner are willing and able to engage in sexual intercourse. Subject has never achieved an intravaginal ejaculation during the past 6 months (i.e., always ejaculates prior to penetration). Subject has other forms of ejaculatory dysfunction (e.g., retrograde ejaculation, anejaculation, painful ejaculation). In the opinion of the investigator, the subject has a condition or is in a situation that may put the subject at significant risk, may confound the study results, or may interfere significantly with the subject's ability to participate in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Premature Ejaculation</keyword>
	<keyword>Lidocaine</keyword>
</DOC>