<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02624661</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Trigeminal neuralgia is one of the strongest pains known to humans. Some patients do not have enough effect with the available pharmaceutical treatments and are offered a type of surgery, which involves the injection of glycerol in a nerve structure called trigeminal ganglion. The researchers will do a pilot study on 10 patients with a new surgical technique using neuronavigation. The researchers believe that this new neuronavigation-based system can improve the precision of the technique and reduce the risk for complications.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Glycerol Block of the Trigeminal Ganglion in Trigeminal Neuralgia Using a New Neuronavigation-based Surgical Technique</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Headache</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ganglion Cysts</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Synovial Cyst</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trigeminal Neuralgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Headache Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glycerol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed and written consent Trigeminal neuralgia defined in International Classification of Headache Disorders (ICHD)3 criteria Unsatisfactory effect of pharmacological treatment Microvascular decompression is seen as a better alternative Heart or lung disease Any kind of systematic or local disease or illness that may significantly increase the risk of complications for the procedure related to injection Psychiatric illness that hinders participation in the study Known pregnancy or breast feeding Inadequate use of contraceptives Overuse or abuse of opioids Abuse of medications, narcotics or alcohol Anomalies which hinder or impede the used method of injection Allergy or any other hypersensitivity reactions against marcain, lidocaine, xylocain or adrenalin</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Trigeminal ganglion</keyword>
	<keyword>Glycerol</keyword>
	<keyword>Nerve block</keyword>
</DOC>