<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="5866">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03030586</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ST0056</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03030586</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ADDIA Proof-of-Performance Clinical Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>ADDIA</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multi-centre Proof-of-performance Clinical Study to Validate Blood-based Biomarker Candidates for the Diagnosis of Alzheimer's Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Amoneta Diagnostics SAS</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>European Commission</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Firalis SA</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital, Strasbourg</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>IRCCS Centro San Giovanni di Dio Fatebenefratelli</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hôpitaux Civils de Colmar</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Istanbul University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital, Lille</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital, Geneva</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cliniques universitaires Saint-Luc- Université Catholique de Louvain</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Amoneta Diagnostics SAS</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of the ADDIA clinical Proof-of-Performance study is to validate the
      performance of ADDIA' blood biomarkers for diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease.

      ADDIA clinical study is a multi-centre, non-interventional, prospective,
      proof-of-performance study with only one visit.

      About 800 well-characterized subjects will be recruited into 3 groups in 2:1:1 ratio, namely
      patients with Alzheimer's disease (AD), patients with non-AD neurodegenerative disease (NAD)
      and 200 control subjects (healthy as compared to their age).

        -  400 patients with Alzheimer's disease (AD),

        -  200 patients with non-Alzheimer's neurodegenerative diseases (NAD),

        -  200 controls (healthy as compared to their age).
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood biomarkers for diagnosis of Alzheimer and/or other dementia type</measure>
    <time_frame>18 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Proof of Performance of ADDIA' blood biomarker-based test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biomarkers circulating in other body fluids for diagnosis of Alzheimer and/or other dementia type</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Validation of biomarkers circulating in other peripheral body fluids</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">800</enrollment>
  <condition>Alzheimer Disease</condition>
  <condition>Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration</condition>
  <condition>Lewy Body Disease</condition>
  <condition>Parkinson Disease Dementia</condition>
  <condition>Progressive Supranuclear Palsy</condition>
  <condition>Corticobasal Degeneration</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Alzheimer</arm_group_label>
    <description>400 patients in total, with approximately 200 patients with mild Alzheimer's disease and 200 patients with moderate to severe Alzheimer's disease will be recruited for sampling blood, urine (and other peripheral body fluids: tears and saliva as optional) for validation of biomarkers</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non-Alzheimer neurodegenerative disease</arm_group_label>
    <description>200 patients comprising:
75 patients with behavioural variant of Fronto-Temporal Lobe Degeneration (FTD),
50 patients with Parkinson's disease dementia (PDD),
50 patients with Lewy Body dementia (DLB) and
25 patients with Progressive Supranuclear Palsy (PSP) or cortico-basal degeneration (CBD) will be recruited for sampling blood, urine (and other peripheral body fluids: tears and saliva as optional) for validation of biomarkers</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Controls</arm_group_label>
    <description>200 healthy subjects</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        About 800 well characterized subjects will be enrolled into 3 groups in 2:1:1 ratio,
        namely Alzheimer's disease (AD), non-AD neurodegenerative diseases (NAD) and controls
        (healthy as compared to their age). The number of subjects is divided into 3 groups as
        following:

          -  400 patients with AD (50% with mild AD and 50% of with moderate to severe AD),

          -  200 patients with non-Alzheimer's neurodegenerative diseases (NAD): this group will
             comprise 75 patients with behavioural variant of Fronto-Temporal Lobe Degeneration
             (FTD) recruited according to Rascovsky et al., 2011; 50 patients with Parkinson's
             disease dementia (PDD), 50 patients with Lewy Body dementia (DLB) recruited according
             to McKeith et al., 2005 criteria; 25 patients with Progressive Supranuclear Palsy
             (PSP) or cortico-basal degeneration (CBD).

          -  200 controls (healthy as compared to their age).
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        For all groups:

          -  Male and female subjects, aged between 50 and 85 years.

          -  Signed and dated written informed consent obtained from the subject or the subject's
             legally acceptable representative (if applicable) in accordance with local
             regulations.

          -  AD, NAD patients and control subjects will be age-matched and mean age similar in the
             three groups.

          -  Able to comply with all study procedures.

        For AD group:

          -  Diagnosis of AD

               -  Specific clinical phenotype of AD: Presence of an early and significant episodic
                  memory impairment.

               -  Gradual and progressive change in memory function reported by patient or
                  informant over more than 6 months.

               -  Objective evidence of an amnesic syndrome of hippocampal type, based on
                  significantly impaired performance on an episodic memory test (Dubois et al,
                  2014).

          -  MMSE score of 25 - 21 in subjects with mild AD and &lt; 21 for patients with moderate to
             severe AD.

          -  FCSRT and MoCA tests compatible with AD diagnosis.

          -  Neuroimaging compatible with a diagnosis of AD: structural 3D MRI (volumes of
             hippocampus and cortical areas), other neuroimaging data (e.g. PET Amyloid scan and
             FDG PET) if practiced by clinical centres shall be compatible with AD diagnosis.

          -  Cerebrospinal fluid biomarker data showing positive levels of at least 2 out of 3
             biomarkers, Aβ1-42, phosphorylated-Tau and total-Tau.

        For NAD group:

        Frontotemporal dementia:

        Diagnosis with behavioral variant FTD (bvFTD) according to Rascovsky et al., 2011.

        The following findings must be present:

          -  Criteria for possible bvFTD.

          -  Functional decline (Clinical Dementia Rating Scale or Functional Activities
             Questionnaire scores).

          -  Imaging results consistent with bvFTD [one of the following must be present]:

               -  Frontal and/or anterior temporal atrophy on MRI.

               -  Frontal and/or anterior temporal hypoperfusion or hypometabolism on PET or SPECT
                  (if retrospective data available).

        Note: in case of familial form of bvFTD, the subject must be a member of family with a
        known mutation in one of the FRD related genes, MAPT, PGRN.

        Note: If taking acetylcholinesterase inhibitor and/or memantine treatments, the subject
        must have been taking such medication(s) for ≥3 months.

          -  MMSE &gt;21.MoCA and FCSRT tests performed.

          -  Neuroimaging: volumetric structural MRI finding compatible with bvFTD as above

          -  CSF biomarker data must show negative levels for all three or at least two out of
             three CSF biomarkers Aβ1-42, phosphorylated-Tau and total-Tau.

          -  Neuroimaging: volumetric structural MRI finding compatible with bvFTD as above.

        Parkinson's disease dementia (PDD):

          -  Subjects with Parkinson's Disease Dementia (PDD) with dementia after and not before
             developing Parkinson's disease (PD).

          -  PD is diagnosed by the 3 typical PD symptomatic findings: tremor, rigidity and slowed
             movement (bradykinesia).

        Note: Subjects with dementia and with LRRK2 gene mutation or with mutation in one of the
        following genes: PARK2 or SNCA, VPS35, PINK1, DJ1, ATP13A2, FBX07, SLC6A3, TAF1 are also
        included.

          -  L-DOPA responsive.

          -  Cognitive scores: MMSE score 21-25 for mild PDD; MMSE score &lt;21 for moderate to
             severe PDD. MoCA and FCSRT tests performed.

          -  Structural MRI: Evidence of relevant structural abnormality (i.e. basal ganglia for
             Parkinsonism and potentially medio-temporal or cortical findings that may be related
             to dementia). Retrospective Fluoro-dopa PET or SPECT data if available shall document
             the presence of dopaminergic dysfunction.

          -  CSF biomarkers showing negative levels of all three or at least two out of three CSF
             biomarkers: β-amyloid 1-42, Phosphorylated-Tau and Total-Tau.

        Lewy body Dementia (DLB):

          -  DLB should be diagnosed when dementia occurs before or concurrently with
             Parkinsonism.

          -  Patients diagnosed with probable DLB according to two out of the following criteria:

             o Fluctuating cognition with pronounced variations in attention and alertness,

             o Recurrent visual hallucinations that are typically well formed and detailed,

               -  Spontaneous features of Parkinsonism, OR

          -  Patients diagnosed with probable DLB according to one out of the above criteria and
             one of the following criteria:

               -  REM sleep behaviour disorder,

               -  Severe neuroleptic sensitivity,

               -  Low dopamine transporter uptake in basal ganglia (SPECT or PET imaging).

        Note: familial forms caused by mutation in genes SNCA, SNCB of DLB can be included.

          -  MMSE score: 10-25, MoCA and FCSRT tests performed.

          -  MRI: Relative preservation of medial temporal lobe structures.

          -  CSF biomarkers: negative levels of all three or at least two out of three CSF
             biomarkers: β-amyloid 1-42, Phosphorylated-Tau, Total-Tau.

        Progressive Supranuclear Palsy (PSP):

          -  Diagnosis of probable or possible PSP as defined by the National Institute of
             Neurological Disorders and Stroke and Society for Progressive Supranuclear Palsy
             (NINDS-SPSP) diagnostic criteria o Gradually progressive disorder,

               -  Onset at age 40 or later,

               -  Vertical (upward or downward gaze) supranuclear palsy and prominent postural
                  instability with tendency to fall in the first year of disease onset,

               -  No evidence of other diseases that could explain the foregoing features, as
                  indicated by mandatory exclusion criteria.

                  - Be able to ambulate and stand unassisted for 5 minutes.

                  - Be able to cooperate with gait and balance testing.

                  - MMSE score &gt;=21, FCSRT and MoCA tests performed.

                  - Brain MRI consistent with PSP: neuroradiologic evidence of relevant structural
                  abnormality in the midbrain and frontal lobes (i.e. basal ganglia, lobar
                  atrophy).

                  - CSF biomarkers: negative levels of all three or at least two out of three
                  biomarkers: β-amyloid 1-42, Phosphorylated-Tau, Total-Tau

        Corticobasal degeneration (CBD):

        - Diagnosis of possible CBD as described in the study protocol (Armstrong et al. 2013).

        Inclusion clinical criteria for possible CBD, with features of Cortico-Basal Syndrome
        (CBS). Progressive Supranuclear Palsy Syndrome (PSPS) included. Familial forms related to
        MAPT are included.

          -  Features of CBS: a) limb rigidity or akinesia, b) limb dystonia, c) limb myoclonus
             plus 1 of: d) orobuccal or limb apraxia, e) cortical sensory deficit, f) alien limb
             phenomena (more than simple levitation).

          -  Features of PSPS: Three of: a) axial or symmetric limb rigidity or akinesia, b)
             postural instability or falls, c) urinary incontinence, d) behavioural changes, e)
             supranuclear vertical gaze palsy or decreased velocity of vertical saccades.

        Note: subjects with probable sporadic CBD (no familial form) are excluded.

          -  Cognitive tests: MMSE &gt;=21, MoCA and FCSRT tests performed.

          -  Structural MRI findings: parietal cortical atrophy (asymmetric), basal ganglia
             atrophy and corpus callosum.

        CSF biomarkers: negative levels of all three or at least two out of three CSF biomarkers:
        β-amyloid 1-42, Phosphorylated-Tau, Total-Tau.

        Control group:

          -  Normal cognitive performance.

               -  MMSE score ≥26.

               -  Normal FCSRT score.

               -  Normal MoCA score.

          -  Normal findings Neuroimaging:

               -  Structural MRI: Normal 3D volumetric scores.

               -  Normal finding in β-amyloid PET scan if performed.

               -  Normal finding in other neuroimaging methods if performed.

          -  Retrospective CSF biomarkers not available or negative level for all three CSF
             biomarkers: β-amyloid 1-42, Phosphorylated-Tau, Total Tau.

        Exclusion Criteria for all groups:

        The following exclusion criteria apply to all three groups:

          -  Psychiatric history: schizophrenia, psychosis.

          -  Infection diseases, chronic inflammatory diseases (that affect the structure and/or
             function of blood cells (as these cells where ADDIA biomarkers are measured)/patients
             with an active infection/ immunosuppressive disorders/ treatment with
             immunosuppressive or immunomodulatory medication

          -  Vascular dementia.

          -  Subject taking medication interfering with cognitive functions and ADDIA biomarkers
             (listed in the study protocol and e-CRF).

          -  Major sensory deficits that could interfere with cognitive assessment (visual and
             auditory).

          -  Epilepsy.

          -  Neutropenia (Neutrophils &lt; 1,500/mm3 according to ethnic group)

          -  Thrombocytopenia (platelets: &lt; 100,000/mm3, rule out EDTA-induced
             pseudo-thrombocytopenia).

          -  Subjects with less than an elementary education are excluded

          -  If medication insurance is mandatory in the country, subject with no medication
             insurance are excluded.

          -  Current or past diagnosis of malignancy affecting blood cells (currently treated or
             stopped since less than 3 months).

          -  Patients with known contraindication for MRI imaging such as MRI-incompatible stent
             or MRI-incompatible endoprosthesis.

          -  Subject who did not sign the informed consent.

          -  Alcoholism.

        Exclusion criteria for AD group:

          -  Mixed dementia.

          -  Other dementia type besides AD.

          -  Other neurodegenerative disease besides AD.

          -  Absence of CSF biomarker data (and/or β-amyloid PET scan data) is an exclusive
             criteria for all subjects with sporadic forms of AD.

        Exclusion criteria for NAD group:

          -  AD diagnosis.

          -  Mixed dementia.

          -  Vascular dementia.

          -  Absence of CSF biomarker data in sporadic DLB and PDD and absence of CSF biomarker
             data and/or β-amyloid PET scan data in sporadic CBD, PSP is an exclusive criteria.
             Note: this is not an exclusive criteria for subjects with a familial form of NAD that
             is due to a mutation of a gene among MAPT, PGRN, SNCA, SNCB, PARK2 or SNCA, VPS35,
             PINK1, DJ1, ATP13A2, FBX07, SLC6A3 or TAF1, TREM2.

        Exclusion criteria for Control Group:

          -  Alzheimer.

          -  Dementia.

          -  Cognitive impairments.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Frédéric Blanc, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hôpitaux Universitaires Strasbourg</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jean-François Démonet, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hakan Gurvit, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Istanbul University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Moira Marizzoni, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>IRCCS Centro San Giovanni di Dio Fatenenefratelli</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>François Sellal, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hôpitaux Civils de Colmar</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Frisoni Giovanni, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hôpitaux Universitaires de Genève</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Florence Pasquier, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre Hospitalier Régional Universitaire de Lille</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adrian Ivanoiu, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cliniques universitaires Saint-Luc</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bruno Dubois, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hüseyin Firat, MD</last_name>
    <phone>33389911321</phone>
    <email>hueseyin.firat@firalis.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopitaux Universitaires de Strasbourg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Strasbourg</city>
        <state>Alsace</state>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Frédéric Blanc, MD</last_name>
      <phone>33388115858</phone>
      <email>frederic.blanc@chru-strasbourg.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IRCCS Centro San Giovanni di Dio Fatenenefratelli</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brescia</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Moira Marizzoni, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Vaudois</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lausanne</city>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jean-François Démonet, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istanbul University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hakan Gurvit, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 2, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 23, 2017</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Blood cell biomarkers, peripheral circulating biomarkers</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Supranuclear Palsy, Progressive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lewy Body Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
