<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02233712</DOC>
	<brief_summary>An open label, dose-finding, schedule-changing, sequential, multiple dose, multi-center study in patients with Stage I-III gastric cancer. The first group of patients received a starting dose of 250 µg at weeks 0, 1, and 3. Thereafter, allocation to treatment with 100 µg or 500 µg was based on antibody response and dose tolerability.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-label, Dose-finding Study to Determine Antibody Response to G17DT Treatment in Patients With Gastric Cancer.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastrins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed UICC Stage I, II or III gastric adenocarcinoma. Must have had a macroscopically curative resection for gastric cancer with absence of metastatic disease at the time of entry to the trial Male or female and over 18 years of age Must have a life expectancy of at least three months World Health Organization Performance Status of 0 to 1 Given written conformed consent Gastric surgery within four weeks of baseline (week 0) or gastric surgery anticipated in the period of the study History of other malignant disease within the previous five years, except nonmelanomatous skin cancer or in situ carcinoma of the uterine cervix Previous use within the last four weeks, concomitant use or anticipated use in the period of the study, of any anticancer therapies Concomitant use of immunosuppressants, including systemic (i.e. oral or injected) corticosteroids Females who pregnant, planning to become pregnant or lactating Taking part in another study involving an investigational or licensed drug or device in the three months preceding enrollment or during this study Previously received G17DT treatment Haemoglobin (Hb) &lt; 10.0 g/dL White blood cell count (WBC) &lt; 4.0 x 10^9/L Platelets &lt; 100 x 10^9/L</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>gastric cancer, stomach neoplasms,</keyword>
</DOC>