<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02233088</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Approximately 24% of the US adult population meet criteria for metabolic syndrome (MetS), diagnosed by a combination of abdominal obesity, elevated blood pressure, high triglyceride and low HDL-cholesterol level, and pre-diabetes. MetS quintuples the risk of diabetes, and doubles the risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD), particularly heart failure. Lifestyle modification is the initial step of treatment, but few studies have demonstrated early and sustained efficacy in remission of MetS. Our preliminary studies of a lifestyle change program for patients with MetS included a 1-year of development of an intervention by an interdisciplinary team of experts in medicine and the behavioral sciences. The investigators then tested the efficacy of the intervention in a treatment-only, proof-of-concept study. The investigators achieved our goal of 50% MetS remission after 2 years, in a sample of 26 patients. This study is the second step of a research program testing an innovative bio-behavioral intervention aimed at remitting MetS through lifestyle intervention, by focusing on eating patterns, daily activity, and stress management. The overarching objective of this research program is to determine the efficacy of the ELM lifestyle intervention to achieve remission of MetS. This purpose of the current study is to prepare for a large, randomized, clinical trial by conducting a smaller clinical trial that examines the acceptability of the ELM intervention (ELM Group) as compared to two other intervention arms (ELM Classes, ELM Individual).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pilot Study of a Lifestyle Intervention on the Metabolic Syndrome (3ELM Study)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The 3ELM ("Eat, Love, Move") study recruits 48 patients with MetS, and provides a 6-month intervention that aims to remit MetS by promoting the long-term adoption of healthier behaviors (diet, physical activity, stress reduction). Participants in 3ELM are randomly assigned to one of the study arms ("ELM Groups", "ELM Classes", "ELM Individual"); all of which receive some type of intervention in either group, class, or individual formats. The primary aim of this project is to pilot test the acceptability of each of the study arms and the outcome measures. The study also includes outcome assessments at 3 time points: at the start of the study, and at 3, and 6 months post baseline. All study participants will receive medical care (including metabolic syndrome care) from their regular medical doctors. Study staff will track participants' use of health care and wellness services during the study after obtaining participant permission to collect this data.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and women age 1872 years (children and the elderly need agespecific lifestyle tailoring). Able to walk 2 blocks (the patients should be able to engage in moderate intensity exercise). Have preference for making lifestyle changes to treat MetS. Able to participate in a lifestyle intervention for 6 months. Meet at least 3 Metabolic syndrome diagnostic criteria: abdominal obesity (waist girth &gt;102♂/88♀ cm), high blood pressure (≥130/85 mm Hg or treatment), triglyceridemia (≥150 mg/dL or fibrate therapy), low HDLcholesterol (&lt;40♂/50♀ mg/dL or niacin therapy) or fasting glucose ≥100 mg/dL (or prediabetes). Substance abuse within the past 12 months: alcohol use, current daily smokers (selfreport); and illicit drug use. Weight loss, exceeding 10% of initial weight, in the past 6 months or current use of medications for weight loss, bowel resection surgery, bariatric surgery, eating disorder. Other medical or behavioral limitations judged to interfere with study participation or the ability to follow study procedures (eg, scheduled surgery, travel plans or scheduling difficulties that do not permit full participation), limited English language, cognitive impairment, pregnancy, or psychiatric comorbidities (such as severe major depression, or psychotic disorders).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>72 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prediabetic State</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Enlarged Waist Elevated Triglycerides</keyword>
	<keyword>HDL Cholesterol, Low Serum</keyword>
</DOC>