<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00301080</DOC>
	<brief_summary>D-cycloserine may help lessen pain and other symptoms of peripheral neuropathy caused by chemotherapy. It is not yet known whether D-cycloserine is more effective than a placebo in treating peripheral neuropathy caused by chemotherapy. This randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial was designed to study D-cycloserine at 2 different doses to see how well each works compared to the other and to a placebo in treating cancer patients with peripheral neuropathy caused by chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>D-cycloserine in the Management of Chemotherapy-Induced Peripheral Neuropathic Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Initially, patients were randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms (D-cycloserine 250 mg twice daily or placebo twice daily), and treated for up to 4 weeks in the absence of unacceptable toxicity. Later, the design was changed to randomize patients to 1 of 3 arms as follows: - D-cycloserine 50 mg twice daily for up to 12 weeks - D-cycloserine 200 mg twice daily for up to 12 weeks - Placebo twice daily for up to 12 weeks</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neurotoxicity Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cycloserine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients will be at least 18 years of age. Patients will be experiencing moderate to severe peripheral neuropathic pain Patients may be on chronic adjuvant pain medications such as antidepressants but must be on stable doses for at least one week prior to admission. Patients may be taking concurrent opioids but they must be willing to allow us to monitor their opioid use while on the trial. Patients must have chronic peripheral neuropathic pain will be defined as pain of 3 or more months duration which began in association with chemotherapy. Patient's will have bilateral peripheral neuropathic pain symptoms primarily involving the feet Patients must have breast cancer (any stage) Patients must be able to read and speak English and provide informed consent. Patients may be receiving chemotherapy as long as the agents are not known to cause a peripheral neuropathy. Patients must have an ECOG Performance Status &lt; 3 and be able to attend the physician study visits Patients must not concurrently use gabapentin or pregabalin or must be willing to wean off their anticonvulsant medications prior to starting the trial. Patients may have diabetes mellitus (type 1 or 2) as long as there is no preexisting neuropathy. Exclusion criteria: Patients will not have secondary cause of neuropathic pain including: HIV/AIDS,traumatic injury, or a personal history of non chemotherapyinduced neuropathy. Patients will not have a history of major depression or severe anxiety. Women of childbearing age will agree to take measures to prevent pregnancy and will not breastfeed while on the study medication. Women who are currently pregnant will not be invited to participate in this study. Patients will not have a history of seizures. Patients cannot be currently receiving antibiotic therapy for tuberculosis (e.g. isoniazid).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>neurotoxicity</keyword>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>