<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01493934</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Insulin resistance, characterised by a depressed cellular sensitivity to insulin in insulin-sensitive organs, is a central feature of the metabolic syndrome. In people with no diabetes mellitus, the presence of metabolic syndrome leads to an increase of mortality, whatever the cause, but, as a majority, cardiovascular diseases. In patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus, the presence of a metabolic syndrome leads to an increase in major adverse cardiovascular events. The prevalence of metabolic syndrome is led to grow in a near future, because of the increase of diabetes mellitus and obesity prevalence. Actually, there is no simple tool to measure insulin resistance. The gold standard technique remains the hyperinsulinemic euglycemic clamp. However, the complexity and length of this technique render it unsuitable for routine clinical use. Many methods or index have been proposed to assess insulin resistance in human, but none have shown enough relevance to be used in clinical use. Within the investigators U877 INSERM team, the investigators previously performed in vivo biodistribution studies with 6-DIG (6-deoxy-6-iodo-D-glucose), a new tracer of glucose transport, radiolabelled with123 iodine, with and without insulin, on the one hand in genetically diabetic mice (db/db), consequently having a severe insulin resistance and in the other hand in rats with acquired insulin resistance after a "fructose diet". The investigators have demonstrated that 6-DIG is able to identify in vivo slight glucose transport variations in insulin sensible organs. Then, the investigators developed a fast and simple imaging protocol with a small animal gamma camera, which allows the obtaining of an insulin resistance index for each organ, directly transferable to human. The investigators project is to transfer to human this measurement technique, perfectly validated in animal. The main goal of this monocentric phase I-II study is to evaluate the tolerance to the insulin resistance measurement technique with 6DIG scintigraphy, in healthy volunteers and in diabetic patients. The investigators plan to enrol 6 healthy volunteers and 6 type 2 diabetic patients. The investigators secondary goals will be to evaluate feasibility and reproducibility of the measurement technique, to follow pharmacokinetic and to assess efficacy of 6-DIG to measure insulin resistance.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Development of a Fast Measurement Technique of Insulin Resistance in Human</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy volunteers Aged between 35 et 60 years old Body mass index between 20 and 25 Waist measurement &lt; 94 cm for men and &lt; 80 cm for women Normal basal glycemia, between 3,8 and 5,8 mmol/l Normal basal insulinemia, between 3 and 13 μUI/ml HbA1c &lt; 6% Total cholesterol &lt; 2 g/l LDL cholesterol &lt; 1,6 g/l HDL cholesterol 0,4 g/l for men and 0,5 g/l for women Triglyceride level &lt; 1,5 g/l For women not menopausal since at last one year or not surgically sterilised: Ongoing contraception, physical or hormonal, excepted local methods (spermicidal, diaphragm, condom, cape) Type 2 diabetic patients Aged between 35 et 60 years old Stable type 2 diabetes mellitus: no ketoacidosis sign during last month HbA1c between 6 and 8% during the 3 months before study inclusion Monotherapy by metformin or diet only For women not menopausal since at last one year or not surgically sterilised: Ongoing contraception, physical or hormonal, excepted local methods (spermicidal, diaphragm, condom, cape) Diabetes mellitus previously known Other ongoing progressive illness Psychiatric illness, needing a chronic treatment Previous history of myocardial infarction, coronary artery disease, cardiac rhythm troubles, stroke, epilepsy, cranial trauma, pituitary surgery, disease likely to reduce the ability of absorption, diffusion or excretion of the radiotracer. Severe hypertension defined by par SAP &gt; 180 mmHg and/or DAP &gt; 110 mmHg Allergy to one of the components of the products used during the study Nuclear medicine examination during the 30 days prior to study inclusion Treatment likely to interfere with glucose metabolism Alcohol or drug intoxication Vegetarian or restrictive lowcalory diet, Pregnant, parturient or breastfeeding women, Inappropriate way of life Type 2 diabetic patients. Previous history of myocardial infarction Severe hypertension defined by par SAP &gt; 180 mmHg and/or DAP &gt; 110 mmHg Previous history of coronary artery disease, cardiac rhythm troubles, stroke, epilepsy, cranial trauma, pituitary surgery, disease likely to reduce the ability of absorption, diffusion or excretion of the radiotracer. Psychiatric illness, needing a chronic treatment Ongoing insulin treatment Ongoing treatment other than metformin, likely to interfere with glucose metabolism Previous history of disease likely to reduce the ability of absorption, diffusion or excretion of the radiotracer Allergy to one of the components of the products used during the study Nuclear medicine examination during the 30 days prior to study inclusion Alcohol or drug intoxication Vegetarian or restrictive lowcalory diet, Pregnant, parturient or breastfeeding women, Inappropriate way of life</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>metabolic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>type 2 diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>insulin resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>Scintigraphy</keyword>
</DOC>