<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01493960</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if Kappaproct is effective in the treatment of chronic active ulcerative colitis patients not responding to available therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Efficacy and Safety of Kappaproct in Chronic Active Treatment Refractory Ulcerative Colitis Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is a placebo-controlled, double-blind, randomised study to assess the efficacy and safety of Kappaproct as an add-on to current practice in treatment refractory ulcerative colitis patients. The study population will be chronic active ulcerative colitis patients who are no longer responding adequately to standard therapies and who are potential candidates for colectomy. Kappaproct/placebo will be add-on treatment allowing all included patients to be on concomitant medication, as well as mandatory steroids at inclusion, throughout the study. Kappaproct (DIMS0150) is a modified single strand DNA-based synthetic oligodeoxyribonucleotide of 19 bases in length. The drug functions as an immunomodulatory agent by targeting the Toll-like receptor 9 (TLR9) present in immune cells (i.e., B-cells and pDCs) residing in high abundance on mucosal surfaces, such as colonic and nasal mucosa. The mucosa of the colon and rectum of patients with ulcerative colitis contains active immune cells, which produce damage to the tissue. The activation of these cells by Kappaproct results in the systemic release of specific cytokines (e.g., IL-10 and type I interferons) and chemokines which are believed to be important factors for the clinical effect of Kappaproct. Ex vivo experiments with Kappaproct have demonstrated that the drug has the ability to enhance the steroid sensitivity of peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) obtained from steroid refractory UC patients. Thus, the desired effect is to restore steroid sensitivity in steroid refractory patients such that they may benefit from the anti-inflammatory actions of the steroid and ultimately become steroid free. 120 eligible patients will be randomly assigned in a 2:1 allocation to receive two single rectal doses of Kappaproct at 30 mg each, or placebo, at week 0 and 4. The primary endpoint is the induction of clinical remission at week 12 and patients will be continuously followed for efficacy and safety until 12 months after the first dose. Secondary endpoints include the induction of symptomatic remission (number of stools and blood in stools), induction of registration remission (clinical and endoscopic remission) and rate of colectomy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female ≥ 18 years of age. 2. Well established diagnosis of moderate to moderately severe chronic active UC with a CAI score ≥9, an endoscopic score ≥2, not responding adequately to currently available therapies and potential candidates for colectomy. Previously tried therapies should include: At least one treatment course with mesalazine; at least 2.4 g/day for at least 4 weeks, or at least one treatment course with similar drugs in this class. At least one full dose treatment course of corticosteroids (which can be the treatment of a recent relapse), with up to 0.75 mg/kg as a starting dose or highest dose according to local clinical practice. At least one treatment course of azathioprine or mercaptopurine of at least 3 months duration and/or at least one adequate treatment course of an antiTNF alpha. Any unsuccessful combination treatment of the above. May have tried treatment with cyclosporine and/or tacrolimus or any other immunosuppressant/immunomodulating agent. Intolerance to any of the above medications is judged as inadequate response. 3. Patients shall at study enrolment be on an accumulated stable tolerable GCS dose equivalent to at least 140 mg of prednisolone/prednisone (by any route of administration) for the last two weeks. Patients may also be on concomitant therapies such as, but not restricted to, 5ASA, azathioprine and sulphasalazine. 4. Ability to understand the treatment, willingness to comply with all study requirements, and ability to provide informed consent. 1. Patients with suspicion of Crohn's enterocolitis, ischaemic colitis, radiation colitis, diverticular disease associated colitis, as well as microscopic colitis should be excluded. Patients with disease limited to the rectum (ulcerative proctitis) should also be excluded. 2. History or presence of a clinically significant cardiovascular, hepatic, renal, haematological, endocrine, neurological, psychiatric disease, or immune compromised state as judged relevant by the investigator. 3. Patients with acute fulminant UC and/or signs of systemic toxicity to an extent that requires immediate surgical action. 4. History or presence of any colonic malignancy and/or dysplasia. 5. Concomitant treatment with cyclosporine, tacrolimus, antiTNFs or similar immunosuppressants/immunomodulators is not allowed and should have been discontinued 4 weeks before enrolment. Patients who fail the washout criteria can undergo washout and be rescreened at a later time point. 6. Treatment with antibiotics or NonSteroidal AntiInflammatory Drugs (NSAIDs) within two weeks before enrolment. 7. An active ongoing infection. 8. Positive Clostridium difficile stool assay. 9. Currently receiving parenteral nutrition or blood transfusions. 10. Pregnancy or breastfeeding. 11. Women of childbearing potential not using reliable contraceptive methods (reliable methods are barrier protection, hormonal contraception, intrauterine device or abstinence) throughout the duration of the study (52 weeks). 12. Concurrent participation in another clinical study with investigational therapy or previous use of investigational therapy within 30 days before enrolment. Patients who fail the washout criteria can undergo washout and be rescreened at a later time point.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Colitis, Ulcerative</keyword>
	<keyword>Gastrointestinal Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunomodulatory Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucocorticoids</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-Inflammatory Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Therapeutic uses</keyword>
</DOC>