<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01972763</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine the effectiveness of Ranibizumab 0.5 mg or 1.0 mg in subjects who were previously treated with Bevacizumab and subsequently switched to Aflibercept. These subjects have demonstrated a sub-optimal therapeutic response to the previous therapies; therefore, the study aims to see if Ranibizumab may have a greater treatment effect.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ranibizumab for Recalcitrant Wet Age-related Macular Degeneration in Eyes Previously Switched From Bevacizumab and/or Ranibizumab to Aflibercept.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ability to provide written informed consent and comply with study assessments for the full duration of the study Age greater than or equal to 50 years Bestcorrected ETDRS VA between 20/25 to 20/320 Total area of subretinal hemorrhage and/or fibrosis comprising less than 50% of lesion Any neovascular lesion type of ARMD having previously received at least 3 doses 1.25 mg of bevacizumab and/or ranibizumab (minimum 3 monthly injections) followed by 3 monthly doses of aflibercept 2.0 mg (with last injection being within 8 weeks) with evidence of recalcitrant ARMD, defined by at least one of the following: persistent subretinal fluid with or without intraretinal cystic edema on SDOCT and/or leakage on fluorescein angiography Pregnancy (positive pregnancy test) or lactation or premenopausal women not using adequate contraception. The following are considered effective means of contraception: surgical sterilization or use of oral contraceptives, barrier contraception with either a condom or diaphragm in conjunction with spermicidal gel, an IUD, or contraceptive hormone implant or patch Any other condition that the investigator believes would pose a significant hazard to the subject if the investigational therapy were initiated Participation in another simultaneous medical investigation or trial History of prior vitrectomy surgery Previous treatment with photodynamic therapy, radiation, or any other intravitreal drug delivery, such as dexamethasone or triamcinolone Subretinal hemorrhage involving the central fovea &gt; 1 disc area, subfoveal atrophy CNVM secondary to causes other than ARMD Previous retinal pigment epithelial tear</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>