<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02314923</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Ebola virus has infected and killed people, mostly in Africa. In 2014, the Ebola virus has affected several thousand people. There is no approved effective way to treat or prevent Ebola. Researchers are trying to develop a vaccine for it. This is a study of the anti-Ebola vaccine BPSC-1001 to see if it is safe and to see how it affects people's immune system.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Placebo Controlled, Dose Response, Safety and Immunogenicity Study of Vesicular Stomatitis Virus (VSV) Ebola Vaccine in Healthy Adults (V920-004)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Between 1994 and the present, there have been many Ebola viruses (EBOV) outbreaks affecting mostly central Africa. However, the 2014 West African outbreak significantly exceeds all previous outbreaks in geographic range, number of individuals affected and in disruption of typical activities of civil society. This is a Phase 1 safety and tolerability study to evaluate a novel vaccine to Ebola using a live replicating vesicular stomatitis virus (VSV) replacing the gene encoding the G envelope glycoprotein with the gene encoding the envelope glycoprotein from the Zaire strain of Ebola (VSVΔG-ZEBOV also known as BPSC-1001).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject 1. Healthy adult male or nonpregnant, nonlactating adult female, ages 18 to 60 (inclusive) at the time of screening 2. Have provided written informed consent prior to screening procedures 3. Free of clinically significant health problems, as determined by pertinent medical history, physical examination and clinical judgment of the investigator. 4. Available, able, and willing to participate for all study visits and procedures. 5. Males and females who are willing to practice abstinence from sexual intercourse with the opposite sex, or willing to use effective methods of contraception, from at least 30 days prior to vaccination until study end. 6. Be willing to minimize blood and body fluid exposure of others for 7 days after vaccination by: 1. Using effective barrier prophylaxis, such as latex condoms, during penetrative sexual intercourse 2. Avoiding the sharing of needles, razors, or toothbrushes 3. Avoiding openmouth kissing 7. Resides in the geographic area of a clinical study site for 1 year after vaccination without risk of deployment outside the U.S. Subject Subjects meeting any of the following criteria will be excluded from the study: 1. History of prior infection with a filovirus or prior participation in a filovirus vaccine trial 2. History of prior infection with VSV or receipt of a VSV vectored vaccine 3. Has been involved in the care in any capacity of a patient with Ebola virus infection within the previous 21 days 4. Is a healthcare worker who has direct contact with patients (nurse, physician, dentist, emergency medical technician, dental hygienist) 5. Has a household contact (HHC) who is immunodeficient, on immunosuppressive medications, human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)positive, pregnant, has an unstable medical condition 6. Has an HHC, or is a childcare worker who has direct contact with children, 5 years of age or younger 7. Direct handson job preparing food in the food industry 8. History of employment in an industry involved in contact with ruminant animals, veterinary sciences, or other potential exposure to VSV 9. History of employment or activity which involves potential contact with filoviruses 10. History of severe local or systemic reactions to any vaccination or a history of severe allergic reactions 11. Known allergy to the components of the BPSC1001 vaccine product 12. Receipt of investigational product up to 30 days prior to randomization or ongoing participation in another clinical trial 13. Receipt of licensed nonlive vaccines within 14 days of planned study immunization (30 days for live vaccines) 14. Ability to observe possible local reactions at the eligible injections sites (deltoid region) is, in the opinion of the investigator, unacceptably obscured due to a physical condition or permanent body art 15. Acute or chronic, clinically significant psychiatric, hematologic, pulmonary, cardiovascular, or hepatic or renal functional abnormality as determined by the investigator based on medical history, physical examination, and/or laboratory screening test. This would include a known hemoglobinopathy or coagulation abnormality. 16. Any baseline laboratory screening test which in the opinion of the investigator, is considered clinically significant 17. Any serologic evidence of hepatitis B or C infection 18. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, including HIV1, HIV2 infection, cytotoxic therapy in the previous 5 years, and/or diabetes 19. Any chronic or active neurologic disorder, including migraines, seizures, and epilepsy, excluding a single febrile seizure as a child 20. Have a known history of GuillainBarré Syndrome 21. Have an active malignancy or history of metastatic or hematologic malignancy 22. Suspected or known alcohol and/or illicit drug abuse within the past 5 years 23. Moderate or severe illness and/or fever &gt;100.4°F within 1 week prior to vaccination (subjects can be rescheduled) 24. Pregnant or lactating female, or female who intends to become pregnant during the study period 25. Administration of IgGs and/or any blood products within the 120 days preceding study entry or planned administration during the study period 26. History of blood donation within 60 days of enrollment or plans to donate within the study period 27. Administration of chronic (defined as more than 14 days) immunosuppressants or other immune modifying drugs within 6 months of study entry 1. For corticosteroids, this includes prednisone, or equivalent, greater than or equal to 0.5 mg/kg/day 2. Intranasal, topical, and intraarticular steroids are allowed 28. Unwilling to allow storage and use of blood for future vaccine research 28. Research staff or the immediate family of research staff directly involved with the clinical study. 29. Unwilling to undergo diagnostic evaluation of joint signs and symptoms, which may include arthrocentesis if clinically indicated based on presence of effusion and if the procedure is acceptable to the subject at the time (Cohort 2 only) 30. Unwilling to undergo diagnostic evaluation of skin rash, to include punch biopsy if clinically indicated and if the procedure is acceptable to the subject at the time (Cohort 2 only) 31. Research staff or the immediate family of research staff directly involved in the clinical study 32. Any other significant finding that in the opinion of the investigator would increase the risk of the individual having an adverse outcome from participating in this study 33. Elective surgery or hospitalization planned during the period of study participation 34. Subject has traveled to an area where the World Health Organization has declared as an Ebola outbreak zone 35. History of chronic inflammatory disease (e.g., rheumatoid arthritis, psoriatic arthritis, reactive arthritis, ankylosing spondylitis, systemic lupus erythematosus, psoriasis, Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis, and gout), symptomatic osteoarthritis, or any other autoimmune or autoinflammatory disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>