<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01963000</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Community acquired pneumonia (CAP) is associated with a high in-hospital mortality. Standardization of diagnostics and adherence to sepsis bundles in the emergency department (ED) are associated with reduced mortality in patients with sepsis. Investigators examined whether the introduction of standardized care bundles and check lists in the ED are associated with a reduced mortality rate in patients hospitalized for CAP. This is an observational trial. The investigators retrospectively analyzed performance indicators of 2819 consecutive patients with CAP admitted to the Nuremberg Hospital, Germany, from 2008 to 2009. At the turn of the year, implementation of CAP care bundles took place including interprofessional education, checklists and institutionalized feedback. Primary endpoint was in-hospital mortality of CAP patients. After the implementation of CAP care bundles in the ED, mortality of affected patients was significantly lower in 2009 compared to 2008. This study should demonstrate that the implementation of a standardized CAP care bundle in the ED is associated with a risk reduction in affected patients. Standardization of diagnostic and therapeutic processes in the ED therefore improves the outcome of patients hospitalized for CAP.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Standardized Emergency Care for Community Acquired Pneumonia (CAP)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>all patients with community acquired pneumonia exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease malignancy immunosuppression neutropenia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Community Acquired Pneumonia</keyword>
	<keyword>Emergency Department</keyword>
	<keyword>Standardized Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Reduced Mortality</keyword>
	<keyword>CRB-65 Risk Classes</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibiotic Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>