<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01963429</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase 3 study is to evaluate the effectiveness of the comparison between radiofrequency ablation and hypofractionated proton beam radiation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison Between Radiofrequency Ablation and Hypofractionated Proton Beam Radiation for Recurrent/Residual HCC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The sample size for this study was based on a non-inferiority design. Primary objective: estimate local progression-free survival (LPFS) rate in two treatments Primary endpoint: 2-year LPFS rate Expected 2-year LPFS rate in the RFA: 85% Accural time and follow up time: 24 months and 24 months, respectively. Precision for 2-year LPFS rate estimation: Allowing a difference of 15% as the non-inferiority margin, with a power of 80% and a type I error level of 5%, evaluable 68 patients are required. Considering 5% of follow-up loss, we need 72 patients in each arm, so a total of 144 patients will be enrolled.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HCC diagnosed as (i) the presence of risk factors including hepatitis B or C virus and liver cirrhosis, a serum afetoprotein (AFP) level greater than 200 IU/ml and a radiologically compatible feature with HCC in one or more CT/MRI/angiograms, or (ii) the presence of risk factors including hepatitis B or C virus and liver cirrhosis, a serum afetoprotein (AFP) level less than 200 IU/ml, and a radiologically compatible feature with HCC in two or more CT/MRI/angiograms or (iii) histological confirmation HCC patients who had recurrent or residual tumor after other treatments without evidence of extrahepatic metastasis the largest diameter of tumor should be less than 3cm, and the number of tumor ≤2 no previous treatment to target tumors by other forms of RT liver function of ChildPugh class A or B7 (ChildPugh score of ≤7) Age of ≥18 years performance status of 0 to 2 on the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) score WBC count ≥ 2,000/mm3; hemoglobin level ≥ 7.5 g/dL; platelet count ≥ 50,000/mm3; and adequate hepatic function (total bilirubin ≤ 3.0 mg/dL; AST and ALT &lt; 5.0× upper limit of normal; no ascites) no serious comorbidities other than liver cirrhosis written informed consent evidence of extrahepatic metastasis age &lt; 18 years liver function of ChildPugh class B89 and C (ChildPugh score of &gt;7) or uncontrolled cases of active chronic hepatitis B previous history of other forms of RT adjacent to target tumors poor performance status of 3 to 4 on the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) score pregnant or breast feeding status previous history uncontrolled other malignancies within 2 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>hepatocellular</keyword>
	<keyword>Proton</keyword>
	<keyword>RFA</keyword>
</DOC>