<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02793492</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multi-center, single arm, non-randomized, prospective clinical study using the Misago® RX Self-expanding Peripheral Stent for treatment of de novo, restenotic, and/or occlusive lesion(s) of the common and/or external iliac artery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Misago® RX Self-expanding Peripheral Stent for Common and/or External Iliac Artery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Baseline: 1. Is ≥ 18 years old and of legal consent. 2. Is willing to comply with all followup evaluations at the specified times. 3. Subject or subject's legal representative has been informed of and understands the nature of the study and provides signed informed consent to participate in the study. 4. Has a Rutherford Clinical Category Score of 2, 3 or 4 (index limb only). 5. Resting ABI of &lt; 0.9, or abnormal exercise ABI. Intraprocedure: 6. De novo, restenotic, and/or occlusive target lesion(s) located within the native common and/or external iliac artery: proximal point at or distal to the ostium of the common iliac artery and distal point at least 1 cm above the Inferior Epigastric Artery (IEA) as measured by straight anteroposterior (AP) view. 7. Radiographic evidence of ≥ 50% stenosis or restenosis (from PTA or adjunct therapy, not including stents or stent grafts), or occlusion of target lesion(s) in the common iliac artery and/or external iliac artery. 8. Total combined length of lesion(s) is ≤ 120 mm as determined by the investigator and is amenable to stenting. 9. Reference vessel diameter is ≥ 4.0 mm and ≤ 9.0 mm. 10. Radiographic evidence in the target limb of straight line femoropopliteal flow, either not requiring CFA/SFA/popliteal treatment for significant stenosis (≥ 50% stenosis or occlusion, as confirmed by angiography during the index procedure), OR has undergone successful treatment according to protocol specifications with &lt; 30% residual stenosis and no procedural complications prior to enrollment in the study. 11. At least one patent infrapopliteal artery to the ankle not requiring intervention (i.e., &lt; 50% stenosis). 1. Has had previous stent or stentgraft implantation in the target lesion(s). 2. Has a contraindication or known untreatable allergy to antiplatelet therapy, anticoagulants, thrombolytic drugs or any other drug used during the study according to the protocol. 3. Has known hypersensitivity to contrast material that cannot be adequately pretreated. 4. Has known hypersensitivity to nickeltitanium (nitinol). 5. In the opinion of investigator, has bleeding diathesis, coagulopathy, and/or known hypercoagulable condition making the patient unsuitable for study participation. 6. Refuses blood transfusion. 7. Is female currently breastfeeding, pregnant, or of childbearing potential not using adequate contraceptives measures or refuses to use contraception throughout the duration of the study. 8. Has life expectancy of less than 1 year. 9. Has planned use of thrombectomy, atherectomy, brachytherapy, cryotherapy or laser devices to treat the common and/or external iliac arteries during the index procedure. 10. Has any planned surgical intervention (requiring inpatient hospitalization) 14 days before or 30 days after the index procedure. 11. Is currently participating in an investigational drug or other device study that has not yet reached the primary endpoint analysis. 12. Has known aortic disease requiring intervention within 9 months post index procedure. 13. In the opinion of the investigator, has one or more of the following comorbid conditions that may impact the subjects safety and/or participation in the study: History of severe liver disease (i.e. ascites, esophageal varices, liver transplant) Known or suspected active systemic infection or infection within the target limb Undergoing immunosuppressant therapy following organ transplant Chronic Kidney Disease Stage IIIB or worse (i.e., GFR &lt; 45 mL/min) New York Heart Association Classification of III or IV with hospitalization for decompensated heart failure within 30 days of index procedure Recent (within 30 days of index procedure) myocardial infarction Recent (within 30 days of index procedure) hemorrhagic or ischemic stroke Acute thrombophlebitis or deep venous thrombosis in the index limb to be treated Any other comorbid condition that in the judgment of the investigator precludes safe percutaneous intervention 14. Guide wire cannot successfully cross the target lesion(s) and reenter true vessel lumen beyond the lesion(s), and study device cannot be deployed so that its proximal and distal ends will be within the true vessel lumen.* 15. Aneurysmal target vessel.* 16. Presence of an acute intraluminal thrombus of the proposed lesion site(s).* 17. If treatment is required of a nontarget lesion distal to the target vessel during the index procedure, the nontarget lesion must be successfully treated (residual stenosis &lt; 30% and no procedural complications) prior to treatment of the target lesion and: Be located within the native CFA/SFA/PPA The distal point must be at least 1 cm above the first branch of the tibial trifurcation 18. Lack of straightline blood flow to the foot/ankle of the target limb prior to index procedure or inability to achieve straightline blood flow to the foot/ankle of the target limb through treatment of a nontarget lesion in the CFA/SFA/proximal popliteal during index procedure prior to enrollment.* 19. Perforation, flowlimiting dissection, or other injury requiring additional stenting or surgical intervention prior to the start of target lesion treatment.*</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>