<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00176020</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will be a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, single-center, 2 treatment, 3-­way crossover. Subjects will be randomly allocated to a treatment sequence – AAB, ABA or BAA. The two treatments will be: - Treatment A: 500 mg nicotinic acid (Niacor(R)) - Treatment B: Niacor(R) Placebo Each trial period will last one day, there will be a wash-out period of at least 2 days between each trial period. Five to seven days after study day 1 of trial period 3 there will be a final safety examination.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nicotinic Acid - Pharmacokinetics, Pharmacodynamics, Receptor Expression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Nicotinic Acids</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Niacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Niacinamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Good state of health physically and mentally Treatment with any other investigational product in the last 60 days before the day of randomization into the study Regular use of medication in the last 60 days before the day of randomization into the study except of oral contraceptives in female participants Treatment in the 60 days before the day of randomization into the study with any drug known to have a welldefined potential for toxicity to a major organ, or any substance which is known to induce or inhibit hepatic drug metabolism (including general anesthetics) Any drug intake (including overthecounter remedies) in the 2 weeks before the day of randomization into the study, unless the investigator considers a drug intake to be clinically irrelevant for the purpose of this study Any acute or chronic illness or clinically relevant findings in the prestudy examination Presence, history or sequelae of gastrointestinal (e.g. peptic ulcer), liver or kidney disease, or any other condition known to interfere with the absorption, distribution, metabolism or excretion of drugs History of hypersensitivity to the investigational product History or presence of abnormalities of the vascular bed History or presence of a dermatologic disease or skin lesions, particular in the area chosen for flush measurement History of allergy or hypersensitivity to other drugs or to food constituents History of other allergic diseases or hypersensitivity, unless the investigator considers it to be clinically irrelevant for the purpose of this study Blood donation of &gt; 400 ml in the 60 days before the day of randomization into the study Smoking Positive result in urine screen for drugs of abuse or in alcohol breath test Known or suspected to be drugdependent, including consumption of &gt; 30 g alcohol per day Pregnancy or lactation Subject is the investigator or any subinvestigator, research assistant, pharmacist, study coordinator, other staff or relative thereof directly involved in the conduct of the protocol Mental condition rendering the subject unable to understand the nature, scope, and possible consequences of the study Subject unlikely to comply with protocol, e.g., uncooperative attitude, inability to return for followup visits, and unlikelihood of completing the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2005</verification_date>
	<keyword>nicotinic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>flush symptom</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacodynamic</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetic</keyword>
</DOC>