<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01452321</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Several factors characterize repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) as a strategic aid in the treatment of postpartum depression. However, up to current days there have been no studies evaluating the effects of rTMS on neurocognitive and social performance of women suffering from the disorder. The present study evaluates the impacts of rTMS in clinical, cognitive and social performance.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation in Postpartum Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Transcranial magnetic stimulation is a noninvasive technique that can influence specific areas of the brain and has very few side effects. The treatment with transcranial magnetic stimulation requires attendance to hospital daily sessions for 4 consecutive weeks. Each session lasts up to 30 minutes. Side effects include scalp discomfort and mild headache. No anesthesia is required. Stimulation aims the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex, a region previously studied to treat depression symptoms with positive results. The present technique has never been employed in previous studies, but risks are insignificant.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression, Postpartum</mesh_term>
	<criteria>major depression with a puerperal onset, according to the criteria of the DSMIVR (APA, 2000), as well as through a structured clinical interview (SCID1/P v 2.0) baseline score of at least 14 points on the Hamilton Depression rating Scale17 items baseline score of at least 13 points on the Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale. range = 1836 years women who had given birth 16 months any pharmacological treatment other than clonazepam (1 mg/day) comprised ferromagnetic metallic implants pacemakers previous neurosurgery history of seizures major head trauma alcoholism drug addiction any psychiatric or neurological disorder other than depression and anxiety psychotic depression suicidal propensities</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>36 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation;</keyword>
	<keyword>Postpartum Depression;</keyword>
	<keyword>Clinical Performance;</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive Performance;</keyword>
	<keyword>Social Performance</keyword>
</DOC>