<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00475839</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Urinary incontinence is a major health issue in women. It is estimated to affect 30 - 40% of older women. Stress urinary incontinence, the most common form of this disease, is treated primarily with surgery. A woman's lifetime risk of surgery for SUI is 4%, with nearly 1/3 of surgery being performed for recurrences. Many different surgical procedures have been described for the treatment of SUI and there is no general agreement as to the most effective. This study compares the safety and efficacy of the tension-free vaginal tape procedure to the Monarc subfascial hammock procedure in the treatment of stress urinary incontinence.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Comparing Tension-free Vaginal Tape With the Monarc Procedure for Stress Urinary Incontinence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Enuresis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence, Stress</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Urinary incontinence symptoms Urodynamic stress incontinence confirmed with multichannel urodynamic testing Age of at least 21 years Desires surgical correction of stress urinary incontinence Postvoid residual volume &gt;100cc Detrusor overactivity on preoperative multichannel urodynamic testing History of previous synthetic, biologic or fascial suburethral sling Desires future childbearing Chronic inguinal or vulvar abscess or history of Hidradenitis Suppurativa History of bleeding diathesis or current anticoagulation therapy Inguinal lymphadenopathy or inguinal/vulvar mass Current genitourinary fistula or urethral diverticulum Reversible cause of incontinence (i.e. drug effect) Contraindication to surgery</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>stress urinary incontinence</keyword>
	<keyword>sling procedures</keyword>
	<keyword>tension-free vaginal tape</keyword>
	<keyword>transobturator</keyword>
</DOC>