<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01629563</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase III, multicentre, randomized, double-blind, parallel group, long-term study investigating the efficacy and safety of the 5mg and 10mg doses of PGL4001 for the treatment of uterine myoma. The target population is composed of pre-menopausal women with symptomatic uterine myoma(s) characterised by heavy bleeding.The main objective of this study is to assess the sustained efficacy and safety of long term on-off treatment with PGL4001 5 or 10mg doses on uterine bleeding, myoma size, pain and quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PGL4001 Efficacy Assessment in Reduction of Symptoms Due to Uterine Leiomyomata</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leiomyoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myofibroma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Be a premenopausal woman between 18 and 50 years inclusive. Have a Body Mass Index (BMI) ≥ 18 and ≤ 40. Have FSH levels ≤ 20 mIU/mL Have excessive uterine bleeding due to myoma. Have regular menstrual cycles Have a myomatous uterus &lt; 16 weeks with at least one myoma ≥ 3 cm in diameter. If of childbearing potential the subject must be practicing a nonhormonal method of contraception. Has a history of or current uterine, cervical, ovarian or breast cancer. Has a history of or current endometrium atypical hyperplasia or adenocarcinoma. Has a known severe coagulation disorder. Has a history of or current treatment for myoma with a Selective Progesterone Receptor Modulator (SPRM). Has abnormal hepatic function at study entry. Has a positive pregnancy test, is nursing or planning a pregnancy during the course of the study. Has a current (within twelve months) problem with alcohol or drug abuse. Is currently enrolled in an investigational drug or device study or has participated in such a study within the last 30 days.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>