<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01629771</DOC>
	<brief_summary>According to the World Health Organization, lymphatic filariasis, a mosquito-borne parasitic disease, is the second leading cause of disability worldwide. Across 81 countries, approximately 120 million people are infected with the disease, and of those infected, an estimated 40% reside in India alone. The most disfiguring symptoms of lymphatic filariasis, elephantiasis and lymphedema, cause long-term suffering in patients who are then often embarrassed or even rejected from their communities. Because of the disease's debilitating physical and social effects on patients, this study will explore the intersection of disability and health-related quality of life (HRQoL) in lymphatic filariasis patients in India. Specifically, HRQoL and disability in lymphatic filariasis subjects and age- and gender- matched control subjects will be compared. Two HRQoL tools , the general Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI) and a disease-specific instrument developed by a dermatology group in India will be used to gauge HRQol. In addition, the demographic and disease-specific factors associated with HRQoL and disability in filarial lymphedema subjects will be identified.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Disability and Quality of Life in Patients With Lymphatic Filariasis in Rural Southern India</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Filariasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Elephantiasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Elephantiasis, Filarial</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Case Inclusion Criteria Subjects with a clinical diagnosis of lymphatic filariasis Subjects over the age of 18 and able to give consent Case Exclusion Criteria Subjects on active treatment for lymphatic filariasis Subjects who are under the age of 18 or unable to give informed consent Control Inclusion Criteria Subjects without a clinical diagnosis of lymphatic filariasis Subjects over the age of 18 and able to give consent Control Exclusion Criteria Subjects without a clinical diagnosis of lymphatic filariasis Subjects who are under the age of 18 or unable to give informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>