<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01662336</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will assess the effectiveness of KASA (Kaletra Patient Support Program) on improving or maintaining treatment adherence in HIV positive patients that have been initiated on treatment with Kaletra®. This will be a purely observational study conducted on patients that will be on treatment with Kaletra®. All treatments will be as per routine care including the use of KASA which will be determined exclusively by the physician and the patient without consideration of the study. The efficacy of disease management programs as assessed in randomized clinical trials is not representative of real - life effectiveness observed under routine clinical practice. In real - life settings the utilization of and compliance with disease management programs by physicians and patients is not uniform. Therefore assessment of their true effectiveness is ideally conducted under a pure observational setting without any interference from the investigators with respect to making the programs available to patients and enforcing their adherence to them.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Real-life Effectiveness of the Kaletra Adherence Support Assistance (KASA) Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a 12-month, multi-center, Canadian Post Marketing Observational Study utilizing a prospective single cohort design. Patients that are treated with Kaletra® including those that are initiated on treatment with Kaletra® will be eligible to participate. All treatments including participation in the KASA (Kaletra Adherence Support Assistance) program will be according to the decision of the treating physician and the patients and will not be affected in any way by their decision to participate in the study. Follow-up will be for 12 months with visits conducted according to the physician judgment. However, assessments every six months will be recommended.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is HIV+ (positive for Human Immunodeficiency Virus) On treatment with Kaletra® or currently initiated on treatment with Kaletra®. Has provided written informed consent allowing the use of their data for the study and providing permission for contact by the study personnel. Willing to be enrolled in the Kaletra Adherence Support Assistance (KASA) program. Not willing to sign an informed consent. In the opinion of the treating physician is unlikely to be available for the 12month followup duration of the study. Is currently participating in a clinical trial of an investigational product. Not willing to participate in the KASA program.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Human Immunodeficiency Virus infection</keyword>
</DOC>