<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01662440</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Establish non-inferiority of the immune response and evaluate the safety and tolerability of Rabies and Japanese Encephalitis (JE) vaccines given concomitantly or alone and according to either of 2 schedules for preexposure prophylaxis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Immunogenicity of 2 Different Vaccination Schedules of Rabies and Japanese Encephalitis Vaccines in Healthy Adult Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Encephalitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Encephalitis, Japanese</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rabies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Males and females between 18 and 65 years of age (inclusive). 2. Subjects who have given written consent. 3. Individuals in good health as per investigator judgement. 1. If female, pregnancy or unwillingness to practice acceptable contraception. 2. If female, pregnant or breastfeeding or any positive/indeterminate pregnancy test. 3. Contraindication or precaution against Rabies and Japanese Encephalitis vaccination. 4. Unable to comprehend and to follow all required study procedures for the whole period of the study. 5. Participating in any other clinical trial 30 days prior to first study visit. 6. History of previous rabies/rabies immunoglobulin and/or Japanese Encephalitis immunization. 7. Receiving or planning to receive antimalarial medications (e.g. Mefloquine) 14 days prior to Day 1 vaccination through Day 43. 8. Received any other vaccines within 2 weeks prior to enrollment in this study or plan to receive any vaccine within 4 weeks from the study vaccines. 9. Ever received blood, blood products and/or plasma derivatives or any parenteral immunoglobulin preparation in the past 12 weeks. 10. Individuals who are part of study personnel or close family members conducting this study. 11. Body temperature ≥38 degrees Celsius (≥ 100.4° F) within 3 days of intended study vaccination. 12. Plans to travel within the next year to areas where Rabies and/or Japanese Encephalitis vaccine may be considered or offered. This includes but is not limited to India, Asia, PacificRim, African countries.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Rabies</keyword>
	<keyword>JE</keyword>
	<keyword>accelerated schedule</keyword>
</DOC>