<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02029924</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The addition of Biochaperone to insulin lispro may accelerate the onset and shorten the duration of action of insulin lispro due to a facilitation of the absorption of the insulin after subcutaneous injection. The aim of the trial is to assess the efficacy and safety of BioChaperone insulin lispro in subjects with Type 1 diabetes under a dose of 0.2 U/Kg. This trial is a single-center, randomised, double-blinded, two-treatment, two-period cross-over, 6-hour euglycaemic glucose clamp trial in subjects with Type 1 diabetes mellitus. Each subject will be randomly allocated to a single dose of BioChaperone insulin lispro 0.2 U/Kg and a single dose of Humalog® 0.2 U/Kg on 2 separate dosing visits.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Double-blinded, Randomised, Two -Period Crossover Euglycemic Clamp Trial Investigating the Pharmacokinetics, Glucodynamics and Safety of BioChaperone Insulin Lispro and Insulin Lispro (Humalog®) in Subjects With Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Lispro</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 1 diabetes mellitus for at least 12 months. Treated with multiple daily insulin injections or insulin pump for at least 12 months. Body Mass Index (BMI): 18.028.0 Kg/m². Type 2 diabetes mellitus. Receipt of any investigational product within 3 months prior to first dosing. Clinically significant abnormalities as judged by the investigator. Any systemic treatment with drugs known to interfere with glucose metabolism. History of alcoholism, or drug/chemical abuse as per Investigator's judgement. Use of tobacco or nicotinecontained product within 5 years prior to screening. Blood or plasma donation in the past month or more than 500 mL within 3 months prior to screening.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>