<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02201381</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the effectiveness of a regimen of selected metabolic treatments for patients with cancer in a real world setting and to conduct exploratory analysis on the relationship between the degree of response and changes in biochemical markers (such as glucose and lipid levels).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Safety, Tolerability and Efficacy of Metabolic Combination Treatments on Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a real world study since this gives the best opportunity to properly examine the effect of multi-drug regimens in representative populations. Including a standard of care arm is inappropriate, in a population in which that standard of care has already been shown to be ineffective or intolerable. Patients will be sent to the study clinic directly by their Health Care Professionals ("HCP's") . The study will consist of a pre-screening visit to determine eligibility for inclusion into the study, an initiation visit and then a follow up visit every three months thereafter. If required, unscheduled visits may take place. Day 0 (baseline) for each patient will be the initiation visit when study treatment is started. Prior to conducting any study-related procedures, subjects will provide written informed consent, eligibility will be assessed, a medical history and past medical records will be taken and vital signs will be measured. These records will include the stage of their disease, response to previous cancer therapy, their prior and current medications and any specific regimen they are currently on for their cancer. If prior medical records do not contain sufficient information to determine a baseline for the patient, additional blood tests and scans will be undertaken as appropriate. Patients will be monitored quarterly thereafter when blood tests (e.g. safety parameters, glucose, cholesterol, immune response and cancer markers where applicable) and scans (where applicable) will be taken. Patients will complete a quality of life questionnaire at baseline and then every 3 months. This will comprise the generic EQ-5D instrument and a disease- specific questionnaire (FACT or European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Quality of Life Questionnaire [EORTC-QLQ]). All patients will be on the same drug regimen (see below) at the same doses throughout the study. All patients will be followed up until they choose to leave the study, or death. Data from all patients recruited to the study will be analysed using an Intention-to-treat (ITT) philosophy, so data will be included in the primary analysis irrespective of whether the dose regimen was followed throughout the study. If appropriate, and numbers allow, analysis will also be conducted on the Per Protocol population, comprising those patients who adhere to the regimen as prescribed. Survival analysis methods will be used to estimate the PFS associated with the study regimen for each type of cancer. Estimates of PFS will be presented for various time points (to be specified) with associated confidence intervals. These estimates will be interpreted in the light of data obtained from the literature, and from eliciting expert opinion. Bayesian methods may be used where appropriate. Overall survival will be investigated in a similar way. The pattern of response to the regimen on quality of life will be investigated using repeated measures, mixed models analysis of variance to derive estimates of the change in EQ-VAS and utility scores derived from the EQ-5D at key time points. The data may also be used to calculate Quality-adjusted Life Years (QALYs) for use in health economic evaluation. Similar methods will be used for the disease-specific instrument. The estimated changes will be interpreted in the light of published data on meaningful changes in these variables. Separate estimates will be produced for each type of cancer if appropriate. Data will be shown in graphs. Tumour response, where applicable, will be summarised in tables and graphs. Estimates of response rates will be presented for each cancer type with confidence intervals. The relationship between changes in biochemistry values (glucose, lipids) and efficacy outcomes (Progression Free Survival (PFS), Overall Survival (OS) and HRQoL) will be investigated graphically, or using other methods as appropriate. Further exploratory analysis to investigate the effects of other factors such as age , ethnic backgrounds , cancer stage, and response to prior therapy, will also be conducted in order to try and characterise the profile of patients most likely to benefit from the study regimen. The characteristics of patients on the regimen and those who do not stay on the regimen, for whatever reason, will be summarised to see whether there is any observed bias. If appropriate, methods will be used to adjust for any observed bias, for example using propensity scores. OS can then be assessed adjusted for this to try and mitigate for any possible risk of bias which can occur in uncontrolled studies. Furthermore, by enrolling all eligible patients over a specified time frame, it is hoped that the risk of bias should be further reduced. In addition, a large number of patients are expected to participate in the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Doxycycline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mebendazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female 1885 years old meeting one or more of the following criteria: Metastatic disease Unable to tolerate standard of care Standard of care ineffective Standard of care side effects unacceptable Standard of care declined by patient Patient fail inclusion criteria for other cancer clinical trials Able to understand study requirements, agree to its provisions and to give written informed consent Major organ failure, renal, lung and liver failure Ilium, colon or stomach part or full removal Mentally incapacitated Has known or suspected problem with alcohol or drug abuse Is direct employee of the study site</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer Treatments</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer Palliative Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolism</keyword>
	<keyword>Existing Medicines</keyword>
	<keyword>Licensed Medicines</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
	<keyword>Real World</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Triple Negative Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Colon Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostrate Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Brain Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Ovarian Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>AML</keyword>
	<keyword>CML</keyword>
	<keyword>Leukemea</keyword>
	<keyword>Metformin</keyword>
	<keyword>Statins</keyword>
	<keyword>Mebendazole</keyword>
	<keyword>Doxycycline</keyword>
	<keyword>Ibuprofen</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic</keyword>
</DOC>