<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02201108</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: To assess the effect of teriflunomide in comparison to placebo on disease activity measured by time to first clinical relapse after randomization in children and adolescents 10 to 17 years of age with relapsing forms of multiple sclerosis. Secondary Objectives: - To assess the effect of teriflunomide in comparison to placebo on disease activity/progression measured by brain MRI and on cognitive function. - To evaluate the safety and tolerability of teriflunomide in comparison to placebo. - To evaluate the pharmacokinetics (PK) of teriflunomide.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy, Safety and Pharmacokinetics of Teriflunomide in Pediatric Patients With Relapsing Forms of Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>- A screening period up to 4 weeks - A double-blind treatment period of up to 96 weeks for each patient - An open-label period including the remainder of the initial 96 weeks, where applicable, and a 96-week extension, ie, up to a maximum of 192 weeks after randomization - A follow-up period of 4 weeks for patients discontinuing treatment Within the 96 weeks double-blind treatment period, the first 4 weeks are pharmacokinetic (PK) run-in phase in which PK samples (blood samples) will be collected from patients and then 4 weeks of analysis (no samples drawn). The PK run-in phase (total 8 weeks) is intended to provide individual PK parameters to allow the dose adjustment to the 14mg adult-equivalent dose for the rest of the study. Patients experiencing a relapse after the PK run-in phase (8 weeks) and if confirmed by the Relapse Adjudication Panel (RAP) and patients fulfilling MRI criteria (high number of new lesions at week 36, 48 or 72 compared to previous images) will have the option to continue in an open label teriflunomide treatment arm up to 192 weeks from randomisation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Patients with relapsing multiple sclerosis are eligible. Patients should meet the criteria of MS based on McDonald criteria 2010 and International Pediatric Multiple Sclerosis Study Group (IPMSSG) criteria for pediatric MS, version of 2012 (5) and have: at least one relapse (or attack) in the 12 months preceding randomization or at least two relapses (or attack) in the 24 months preceding randomization. ≤17 years of age and ≥10 years of age at randomization. Signed informed consent/assent obtained from patient and patient's legal representative (parents or guardians) according to local regulations. Exclusion criteria: EDSS score &gt; 5.5 at screening or randomization visits. Relapse within 30 days prior to randomization. Treated with: glatiramer acetate, interferons, or dimethyl fumarate within 1 month prior to randomization fingolimod, or intravenous immunoglobulins within 3 months prior to randomization natalizumab, other immunosuppressant or immunomodulatory agents such as cyclophosphamide, azathioprine, cyclosporine, methotrexate, mycophenolate, within 6 months prior to randomization, cladribine or mitoxantrone within 2 years prior to randomization. Treated with alemtuzumab at any time. History of HIV infection. Contraindication for MRI. Pregnant or breastfeeding females or those who plan to become pregnant during the study. Female patients of childbearing potential not using highly effective contraceptive method (contraception in both female and male is required). The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>