<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01974596</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study was evaluate the effects of the oral probiotic Lactobacillus reuteri Prodentis upon the peri-implant health of edentulous patients with dental implants and peri-implant mucositis, establishing comparisons versus implants without peri-implant disease. The hypothesis of the study is that using these probiotics are going to improve the periimplant health.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of Probiotics in Oral Health of Patients With Dental Implants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A double-blind, placebo-controlled, prospective cross-over study was made. All the patients were edentulous and were divided into two groups: A) with no peri-implant disease; B) with peri-implant mucositis affecting one or more implants. Patients with peri-implantitis were excluded. All patients in both groups initially received the oral probiotic Lactobacillus reuteri Prodentis, followed by placebo. Only the supervisor of the study knew this information; clinical examiner and patients were blind. Were studied: crevicular fluid volume, modified plaque index, probing depth, modified gingival index, and concentrations of interleukin 1β, interleukin 6 and interleukin 8, and Bacterial load.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Mucositis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Totally edentulous patients subjected to dental implant rehabilitation in one or both arches Prosthetic restoration in function for at least 24 months Healthy individuals without known disease Patients receiving any kind of local or systemic decontamination treatment of the oral cavity (e.g., antibiotics or rinses) in the last 3 months, or periodontal treatment in the last 6 months Uncontrolled periodontal disease Patients with immune deficiencies, diabetes, rheumatoid disease, head and neck radiotherapy, bisphosphonate treatment, chemotherapy or anticoagulation Patients with dental implants presenting intraoral exposure of the rough portion of any implant Smokers Incomplete protocols due to a lack of patient cooperation: a) failure to follow the treatment instructions; b) failure to report to the visit after one month of followup Failure to provide informed consent to participation the study Patients presenting at least one implant with periimplantitis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dental implants</keyword>
	<keyword>Probiotics</keyword>
	<keyword>Lactobacillus reuteri</keyword>
	<keyword>Periimplant mucositis</keyword>
	<keyword>Cytokines</keyword>
	<keyword>Bacterial load</keyword>
</DOC>