<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00866112</DOC>
	<brief_summary>People with mobility disabilities are at greater risk than the general population for incurring health problems. Many of these conditions are preventable through behavior and lifestyle changes such as exercise and physical activity. Recent evidence suggests that people with disabilities experience the same physiologic response to exercise as the general population. Nonetheless, nearly three-fourths of those with disabilities report being entirely sedentary or not active enough to achieve health benefits. Despite some knowledge of issues that limit physical activity among this population, few studies have investigated methods for promoting physical activity adoption among people with disabilities, including wheelchair users. The purpose of this study is to test the effectiveness of a behavioral intervention to promote physical activity adoption over 6 months and maintenance of physical activity over another 6 months by community-dwelling manual wheelchair users.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomized Exercise Trial for Wheelchair Users</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Palsy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Muscular Dystrophies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Dysraphism</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Be experiencing a permanent disability of at least 6 months that limits mobility sufficiently to require use of a wheelchair as the primary method of mobility outside the home Have not been moderately to vigorously physically active for the past 6 months Be willing to attend the educational workshop Receive physician approval for participation Exclusion criteria include: Presence of medical conditions such as uncontrolled cardiovascular problems that the patient's physician identifies as being contraindicated for exercise Pregnancy or planning to become pregnant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Wheelchair use</keyword>
	<keyword>Spinal cord injury</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiple sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Muscular dystrophy</keyword>
	<keyword>Cerebral palsy</keyword>
	<keyword>Spina bifida</keyword>
	<keyword>Amputation</keyword>
	<keyword>Arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
</DOC>