<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00866151</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to determine the association between genotypes and diet. The weight and weight loss data are already available from the previously completed study called: A to Z Study - Benefits and Risks of Alternative Weight Loss Strategies - A Clinical Trial, which was performed from 2003-2005 at Stanford University. In the present study, Interleukin Genetics will obtain DNA samples from the previously enrolled study subjects to investigate genetic influence of the response to macronutrient compositions of low caloric diets to weight loss.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A to Z Study Follow-up: Collection of DNA Data From Buccal Swabs</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Interleukin Genetics has derived, through an extensive search of the scientific literature, a genetic test panel in the area of Weight Management (WM), which includes the genes that have been shown to affect body weight. These genes have been associated with elevated risk for obesity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>BMI (body mass index): 2740 kg/m2 Gender: Women only Age: 2550 Menopausal status: premenopausal Weight stable for last 2months Not on a weight loss plan No ethnic restrictions No plans to move from the area over the next 6months Willing to accept random assignment Possess English speaking and reading skills to understand and complete forms such as informed consent and study evaluation Hypertension Diabetes (type 1 or 2) or history of gestational diabetes Heart disease diagnosis Renal or lever disease Active neoplasms Pregnant, lactating, within 6months of birth, or planning to become pregnant in the next 6months Hyperthyroidism, unless treated and under control Medications known to affect weight / energy expenditure Excessive alcohol intake (selfreported, &gt; 3 drinks/day) Postmenopausal, including surgical menopause Currently under psychiatric care, or severely clinically depressed (&gt;17 on Beck Inventory)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>genetic biomarker</keyword>
	<keyword>biomarker</keyword>
	<keyword>molecular diagnostics</keyword>
	<keyword>genes</keyword>
	<keyword>genetics</keyword>
	<keyword>overweight management</keyword>
	<keyword>weight management</keyword>
	<keyword>weight reduction</keyword>
	<keyword>SNPs</keyword>
	<keyword>single nucleotide polymorphisms</keyword>
</DOC>