<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00517842</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigational product is a specially formulated TCM and administered in the form of a capsule. Basic pre-clinical studies have suggested that it may have good immunomodulating functions, increases the activities of T-cells, B-cells and NK cells, enhances mitochondrial antioxidant status on various tissues including brain tissues. Therefore, this formulation may have special values in improving symptoms in Parkinson's disease patients. The purpose of the study is to determine the efficacy and safety of ViNeuro in patients with Parkinson's disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Triple-blinded, Randomised, Placebo-controlled Trial to Examine the Efficacy and Safety of ViNeuro in Patients With Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A subject will be eligible for study participation if he/she meets all the following criteria: 1. Age of at least 30 years 2. Diagnosis of symptomatic, idiopathic Parkinson' disease using The United Kingdom Parkinson's Disease Society Brain Bank Diagnostic Criteria (Appendix 3 in the protocol) 3. Stage 14 on the modified Hoehn and Yahr scale (Appendix 4 in the protocol) 4. Possesses three of the four cardinal signs of Parkinson's disease, i.e. rigidity, bradykinesia, resting tremor and postural instability, without any other known or suspected cause for their parkinsonism 5. If receiving levodopa or other symptomatic treatments, the subject should have shown a good response to it and have been on a stable dosage for at least 1 month prior to study entry 6. Voluntarily signs and dates an Informed Consent Form, approved by an Institutional Review Board (IRB)/Independent Ethics Committee (IEC), prior to any studyspecific procedures. A subject will be excluded from the study if he/she meets any of the following criteria: 1. Presence of atypical parkinsonian syndromes 2. Dementia as defined by the MiniMental State Examination score (Appendix 5 in the protocol) of 22 or less 3. Serious concurrent illness, such as active cardiac, renal, liver, or neoplastic disease 4. Used centrally active therapies, e.g. hypnotics, antidepressants, anxiolytics, within 60 days before study entry 5. Used methylphenidate, cinnarizine, reserpine, amphetamine, or monoamine oxidaseA inhibitors, e.g. pargyline, phenelzine, or tranylcpromine, within 3 months of study entry 6. Has history of receiving any neuroleptics 7. Used alphamethyldopa or flunarizine within 6 months of study entry 8. Females who are pregnant or breastfeeding. 9. Subjects who are currently participating in another investigational study or has been taking any investigational drug within the last 4 weeks prior to screening of this study (Visit 1). 10. Subjects who are taking any traditional Chinese medication, or has been taking any traditional Chinese medication within the last 2 weeks prior to screening of this study (Visit 1). 11. Any criteria, which, in the opinion of the investigator, suggests that the subject would not be compliant with the study protocol.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Parkinson's disease</keyword>
</DOC>