<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00517634</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the present study is to investigate whether the effects of salmeterol in combination with fluticasone propionate on blood markers of airway inflammation are maintained after chronic dosing and whether the effect is influenced by the time of allergen challenge relative to the time of dosing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Of Fluticasone Propionate/Salmeterol In Asthmatic Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A 12-week, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, three-period, cross-over pilot study comparing the effect of salmeterol/fluticasone propionate, fluticasone propionate and placebo on perpheral blood eosinophils and serum IL-5 in response to allergen challenge in asthma subjects when allergen challenge is administered at 1 hour or 11-12 hours post-dose of the dosing interval</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone Propionate, Salmeterol Xinafoate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Salmeterol Xinafoate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent. Outpatient. Male or nonpregnant/nonlactating female. Aged 1855. Diagnosis of asthma. Prebronchodilatory FEV1 &gt; 75% predicted. Using inhaled shortacting beta2agonists (SABA) with no inhaled corticosteroids. Judged capable of withholding SABA for at least 6 hours prior to visits. Reversibility of &gt;12% and 200mL or PC20 of &lt;8mg/mL. Demonstration of atopy History of lifethreatening asthma. Use of proscribed asthma medications. Use of antihistamines or potent inhibitors of CYP3A4. Respiratory tract infection. Asthma exacerbation with 4 weeks of Visit 1. Subjects with exercise induced asthma only. Concurrent respiratory disease. Other clinically significant, uncontrolled condition or disease. Use of any investigational drug within 30 days. Allergic to beta2agonists, inhaled corticosteroids or excipients. Positive pregnancy test. Using immunosuppressive medications. Milk protein allergy. Factors likely to interfere with attendance. Current smokers or exsmokers with a history of &gt;10 pack years. Affiliation wih Investigator site. Medications that may affect the course of asthma or interact with sympathomimetic amines.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>allergen challenge</keyword>
	<keyword>IL-5</keyword>
	<keyword>eosinophils</keyword>
</DOC>