<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03001804</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this non-interventional study is to collect primarily the percentage of patients who receive the full dose of dexamethasone (40 mg orally once daily on days 1, 8, 15 and 22 of the repetitive 28-day cycles, 20 mg in&gt; 75 year old patients) and in the registered indication under practice conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use Lenalidomide (Revlimid®) in Combination With Dexamethasone in Clinical Practice for the Treatment of Newly Diagnosed Multiple Myeloma (MM) Transplant Ineligible Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Multiple myeloma is still a persistent and life-threatening blood cancer that is characterised by tumour proliferation and suppression of the immune system. It is a rare but incurable disease. On average, multiple myeloma is diagnosed in people 65-74 years of age, and the majority of newly diagnosed patients may not be eligible for more aggressive treatment options such as high-dose chemotherapy with stem cell transplant. In February 2015 REVLIMID® (lenalidomide) was approved in combination with dexamethasone for the treatment of adult patients with previously untreated multiple myeloma who are not eligible for transplant. Looking in more detail at the combination of lenalidomide and dexamethasone, the role and especially the most adequate and effective dosage of dexamethasone in long term use with lenalidomide is not clearly defined or well characterised It is therefore of great relevance to gain insights into the clinical practice and the routine of dexamethasone management and dosing in long term use with Revlimid.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenalidomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thalidomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed Informed Consent Age ≥ 18 years Newly diagnosed Multiple Myeloma Not suitable for stem cell transplantation Appropriate methods of contraception according to the Risk Minimization Program (RMP) Adequate thrombosis prophylaxis Pregnant and lactating females No other formal exclusion criteria according to most recent European Summary of Product Characteristics (SmPC)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Revlimid</keyword>
	<keyword>Lenalidomide</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-transplantable</keyword>
</DOC>