<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03001336</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the potential association between thyroid function and diabetes complications in the elderly subjects with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Thyroid Function and Diabetes Complications</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Aims: We investigated the potential association between thyroid parameters and microalbuminuria in the euthyroid elderly subjects with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). Subjects: Elderly inhospital patients with T2DM who visited in the Department of Endocrinology at the Nanjing First Hospital from January 2011 to December 2012. Methods: Clinical factors, serum levels of glucose, lipids, free triiodothyronine (FT3), free thyroxine (FT4), thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH), thyroid autoantibodies,24h urine albuminuria and fluorescence fundus angiography are conducted. The relationships levels of thyroid function and diabetic complications are analysed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thyroid Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Complications</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients are ≥ 60 years old, with T2DM and the diagnostic criteria of T2DM is according to the World Health Organization in 1999. 2. Patients have normal thyroid function and negative for thyroid autoantibodies, such as thyroid peroxidase antibody (TPOAb) or thyroglobulin antibody (TGAb). 1. Patients with a history of thyroid disease or chronic liver disease or nondiabetic renal problems or cancer. 2. Patients use systemic drug therapy such as thyroxine, antithyroid drugs, glucocorticoids and oral contraceptives. 3. Patients are pregnant or lactating women. 4. Patients with acute intercurrent illness of diabetes. 5. Patients with an acute infection. 6. Patients with a history of drug abuse alcohol dependence in the past 5 years.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Thyroid</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
</DOC>