<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00498927</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as temozolomide, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well temozolomide works in treating patients with recurrent glioblastoma multiforme or other malignant glioma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Temozolomide in Treating Patients With Recurrent Glioblastoma Multiforme or Other Malignant Glioma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the progression-free survival rate at 6 months in patients with recurrent glioblastoma multiforme or other malignant glioma treated with temozolomide. Secondary - Determine the overall survival of patients treated with this drug. OUTLINE: Patients receive oral temozolomide once daily in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Blood samples are collected at baseline and every 2 months for 2 years for evaluation of markers of neo-angiogenesis. Samples are analyzed by protein expression, reverse-transcriptase PCR, ELISA, and western blot. (Samples are no longer being collected and tested as of 1/12/09)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Pathologically diagnosed glioblastoma multiforme or other malignant glioma Recurrent disease Must have received prior temozolomide PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Karnofsky performance status 60100% Granulocyte count ≥ 1,500/mm³ Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm³ SGOT ≤ 2.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) Creatinine ≤ 2 times ULN Bilirubin ≤ 2 times ULN No other active malignancy except for cervical carcinoma in situ or basal cell carcinoma of the skin No serious medical or psychiatric illness that, in the opinion of the investigator, would preclude study treatment No medical condition that precludes swallowing pills Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics Recovered from all prior therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent adult brain tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>adult giant cell glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult gliosarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult diffuse astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult pilocytic astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult subependymal giant cell astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic ependymoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult ependymoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult myxopapillary ependymoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult subependymoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic oligodendroglioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult oligodendroglioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult brain stem glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult mixed glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult pineal gland astrocytoma</keyword>
</DOC>