<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00498121</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Our aim in this study is to investigate the potential role of serum ProCT as an early diagnostic marker and later prognostic indicator for VAP.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Diagnostic and Prognostic Utility of Procalcitonin (ProCT) for Ventilator-associated Pneumonia (VAP)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Ventilator-associated pneumonia (VAP), a bacterial infection that develops after 48 hours or more of intubation, is associated with high morbidity and mortality. Rapid identification of VAP is required to improve survival and to reduce avoidable treatment-associated side effects. Procalcitonin (ProCT), a blood test, is a reasonably specific marker of bacterial infection and its level increases early in sepsis. In this study, a ProCT serum level will be measured in 50 patients with clinically suspected VAP. We aim to show that the ProCT level will be high early in VAP and will stay high in patients with poor prognosis. This will help to address the potential role of ProCT as part of early diagnosis and management of VAP.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia, Ventilator-Associated</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcitonin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>In the preceding 24 h, the appearance of a new opacity or opacities on chest Xray when compared to previous, and two of the following: 1. white blood cell count &gt; 12 or &lt; 5 x 10^9 cells/L, 2. temperature &gt; 38°C or &lt; 35°C, or 3. purulent secretions.endotracheal samples must be collected by bronchoscope/bronchoalveolar lavage with quantitative culture or endotracheal aspiration with quantitative culture (when available) or qualitative culture from each patient to be enrolled in the study. This is a routine procedure done in every case of suspected VAP and is considered to be the standard of care. 1. Known underlying chronic inflammatory condition of the lung (e.g., sarcoidosis, vasculitis) 2. Thyroid cancer patients 3. neutropenia (neutrophils &lt; 0.5 x 10^9 cells/L 4. Concomitant AIDS 5. Solid organ transplantation with severe immunosuppression 6. New Antibiotic use for more than 18 hrs before blood sample collection 7. Severe pancreatitis 8. Attending physician does not agree with enrollment into the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ventilator associated pneumonia.</keyword>
	<keyword>Procalcitonin.</keyword>
</DOC>