<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01413516</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This Investigator Initiated Research Award (IIR Award #WS981308) is a two-part pilot study that aims to examine acceptability and feasibility of varenicline use during an acute (72-hr) smoke-free hospitalization (Part 1) and 4-weeks post-hospitalization (Part 2).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Varenicline In-Patient Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The sample will be hospitalized patients smoking at least 10 cigarettes/day prior to hospitalization. Intention to quit smoking will not be required for study participation. Using a double-blinded, placebo-controlled, randomized design, participants will receive varenicline (0.5 mg BID as tolerated) or placebo during their hospitalization (Part 1) and will continue their study medication (placebo or active drug) for 4 weeks post-hospitalization (Part 2). Abstinence status will be examined at 4 weeks post-hospitalization.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Varenicline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The sample, 40 women and 40 men, will be hospitalized patients recruited from Stanford Hospital and Clinics who report smoking at least 10 cigarettes per day prior to hospitalization, have confirmed tobacco use by cotinine testing, and an expected hospitalization of at least 3 days duration from the date of study enrollment. Intention to quit smoking will not be required for study participation. Study exclusion criteria are: dementia or other brain injury precluding ability to participate; Alzheimer's Disease; Parkinson's Disease; Huntington's Disease; meningitis; seizure disorder of a sustained nature; delirium; brain surgery; drug and/or alcohol dependence; suicidal ideation; endstage renal disease (i.e., on dialysis); hypertensive crisis; stroke; myocardial infarction (MI) with severe cardiac damage; pregnancy or breastfeeding; nonEnglish speaking; complete homelessness; or currently engaged in tobacco treatment. Study staff will consult with clinical staff prior to approach for study enrollment. In cases of severe renal impairment (estimated creatinine clearance &lt;30 mL/min), medical staff will consult with participants' physician to assess the appropriateness for study enrollment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Varenicline</keyword>
	<keyword>Placebo</keyword>
	<keyword>Inpatient</keyword>
</DOC>