<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00388024</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Imaging procedures, such as PET scan and CT scan, may help doctors predict a patient's response to treatment and plan the best treatment. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is studying how well PET scans and CT scans show response to treatment in patients with locally advanced head and neck cancer undergoing chemotherapy and radiation therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PET Scans and CT Scans in Patients With Locally Advanced Head and Neck Cancer Undergoing Chemotherapy and Radiation Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the feasibility of performing positron emission tomography-computed tomography (PET-CT) imaging for early discrimination of treatment response and post-therapy neck management in patients with locally advanced cancer of the head and neck treated with definitive chemoradiotherapy. Secondary - Perform semiquantitative analysis of tracer uptake in these patients using standard uptake values and qualitative analysis of tracer uptake using pure visual analysis. - Determine the feasibility of distinguishing benign from malignant processes during initial tumor staging of these patients by whole-body PET-CT imaging. - Correlate staging by whole-body PET-CT imaging with staging by standard CT/MRI, clinical exam, and pathologic specimen. - Determine the feasibility of PET-CT imaging in these patients in treatment position for radiotherapy treatment planning, correlate the results with standard CT/MRI images, and record the differences. - Perform PET-CT imaging in these patients during weeks 2 and 4 of chemoradiotherapy to evaluate the predictive value of response to treatment at these time points. - Determine if the time interval for treatment monitoring at 6 and 12 weeks post chemoradiotherapy is important for the predictive value of PET-CT imaging. - Evaluate patients with clinical or radiographic abnormalities worrisome for residual or recurrent disease with PET-CT imaging at 6 and 12 weeks post chemoradiotherapy to assess the need for additional therapies (i.e., neck dissection). OUTLINE: This is a pilot study. Patients receive fludeoxyglucose F 18 (FDG) IV over 90 seconds prior to the initial scan. Patients undergo whole-body computed tomography (CT) imaging with contrast followed by positron emission tomography (PET) imaging (approximately 1 hour after FDG injection) for initial staging and simulation for radiotherapy treatment planning. After PET-CT evaluation, patients with locoregional disease are recommended for standard-care chemoradiotherapy. Patients with evidence of M1 disease that is confirmed by CT/MRI and/or biopsy are treated at the discretion of the attending clinician. During chemoradiotherapy, patients undergo PET-CT imaging, as described above, at the beginning of week 2 and during week 4 for treatment monitoring and early detection of recurrent or residual disease. Follow-up PET-CT scans are performed, as described previously, at 6 weeks and then at 3 months after completion of chemoradiotherapy. After completion of study procedures, patients are followed periodically for up to 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Unknown Primary</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed squamous cell carcinoma or lymphoepithelioma of the head and neck, including any of the following sites: Oral cavity Oropharynx Hypopharynx Larynx Nasopharynx Unknown primary of the head and neck region Stage III or IV disease Definitive chemoradiotherapy with curative intent must be planned PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Able to tolerate positron emission tomography (PET) imaging Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception No poorly controlled diabetes mellitus (e.g., fasting glucose &gt; 200 mg/dL) despite medication PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics No prior radiotherapy to head and neck</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III lymphoepithelioma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III lymphoepithelioma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell carcinoma of unknown primary</keyword>
	<keyword>newly diagnosed carcinoma of unknown primary</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic squamous neck cancer with occult primary squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>untreated metastatic squamous neck cancer with occult primary</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV lymphoepithelioma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV lymphoepithelioma of the oropharynx</keyword>
</DOC>