<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00388999</DOC>
	<brief_summary>MBL deficient patients enrolled in this protocol are scheduled to be treated with melphalan-based high-dose chemotherapy followed by autologous hematopoietic stem cell transplant (HSCT) for their multiple myeloma. Patients are randomized to 0.5 mg/kg, 1.0 mg/kg, or no rhMBL.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intravenous rhMBL in Patients With Multiple Myeloma Receiving Chemotherapy Followed by Stem Cell Transplant</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>MBL deficient patients will be randomized in a ratio of 2:2:1 to receive up to 4 weekly i.v. infusions of rhMBL at a dose of 0.5 mg/kg or 1.0 mg/kg, or standard anti-infectious prophylactic therapy alone. A total of 20 patients will be treated in each of the rhMBL arms, and 10 patients will receive best standard supportive prophylactic therapy but not rhMBL. All patients are to receive anti-infectious prophylactic supportive therapy as per institutional standards.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Major Patients must meet all of the following criteria to be eligible for enrollment into the study: Capable of understanding the protocol requirements and risks and providing written informed consent. Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of multiple myeloma. Mannosebinding lectin level &lt;300 ng/mL. Age ≥18 years old. Score of 0 to 2 on the Zubrod performance status scale. Patient is scheduled to receive melphalanbased highdose chemotherapy and autologous HSCT for the treatment of multiple myeloma. Concurrent serious medical illness that could potentially interfere with protocol compliance. Concurrent or previous malignancy associated with a poor prognosis. Known chronic infectious disease, such as acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) or hepatitis (for hepatitis and human immunodeficiency virus [HIV] will not be performed). Positive screening pregnancy test or is breastfeeding. Female or male patient of reproductive capacity unwilling to use methods appropriate to prevent pregnancy during the course of this protocol. Known or clinically suspected active brain metastases. Current participation in another clinical study with an investigational agent and/or use of an investigational drug.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Stem Cell Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>rhMBL</keyword>
</DOC>