<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00388362</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To study the effectiveness of an immunosuppressive drug, sirolimus in the treatment of chronic graft versus host disease in combination with prednisone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sirolimus as Treatment of Steroid-Refractory or Steroid-Dependent Chronic Graft-Versus-Host Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this trial is to study the effectiveness of an immunosuppressive drug, sirolimus, in the treatment of chronic graft versus host disease in combination with prednisone. Graft versus host disease (GVHD) is a common complication in patients who have received blood or marrow transplantation from a related or unrelated donor. Chronic GVHD occurs approximately 100 days after transplantation and is the result of the donor immune system recognizing the patient's tissues as foreign and creating harmful effects on the patient';s organs. We hope the use of sirolimus will decrease the significant disabling effects and deaths caused by chronic GVHD.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Graft vs Host Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologicallyconfirmed active chronic GVHD &gt;100 days following allogeneic bone marrow/peripheral blood/umbilical cord blood transplantation that has failed prior therapy. In the event that histological confirmation poses undue risk, clinical evaluation is sufficient. Women must have a negative pregnancy test before sirolimus administration and women of childbearing potential agree to use a medically acceptable contraceptive throughout the treatment period and for 3 months after discontinuation of sirolimus. Any woman becoming pregnant during the treatment period must discontinue the use of sirolimus. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;1000/mm^3, unless receiving GCSF to maintain neutrophil count &gt;500/mm^3 Discontinuation of cyclosporine or FK506 at the time of initiating sirolimus with cyclosporine trough level &lt;100 mg/dl and FK506 level &lt; 5 mg/dl Karnofsky performance score &gt; or = 50 during prestudy screening Written, signed, and dated informed consent Uncontrolled systemic infection Unstable disease states (i.e., hepatic failure, ventilatorydependent respiratory failure, etc.) Serum creatinine &gt; or = 3.0 mg/dL, platelet count &lt; or = 50,000/mm^3 History of Posttransplant microangiopathic hemolytic anemia Uncontrolled hyperlipidemia Use of any investigational drug within 4 weeks of entry into the study Use of methotrexate or antibody therapies within 24 hours of sirolimus administration Inability to tolerate oral therapy for any reason Evidence of infiltrate, cavitation, or consolidation on chest xray during prestudy screening Known hypersensitivity to macrolide antibiotics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>GVHD</keyword>
</DOC>