<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00832091</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability and effectiveness of Thymosin Beta 4 administered topically in patients with Venous Stasis ulcers</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Thymosin Beta 4 in Patients With Venous Stasis Ulcers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-response study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability and effectiveness of Thymosin Beta 4 (Tβ4), administered topically, in patients with Venous Stasis (VS) ulcers. VS ulcers develop on the ankle or lower leg in patients with chronic vascular disease. In these patients, blood flow in the lower extremities is impaired, leading to edema (swelling) and mild redness and scaling of the skin that gradually progress to ulceration. Tβ4 is a synthetically-produced copy of a naturally occurring 43 amino acid peptide that has wound healing and anti-inflammatory properties and can up-regulate the expression of laminin-5.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Postphlebitic Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Postthrombotic Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Varicose Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed Consent Form signed by the patient Male or female, between 18 and 79 years of age At least one venous leg ulceration stable for at least 6 weeks before enrollment Surface area between 3 and 30 cm2 Have clinical evidence of active infection on the index ulcer Use of any experimental drug, or participation in any clinical study, within the 60 days before enrollment Use of systemic or topical steroidal therapy, immunotherapy, or cytotoxic chemotherapy within the 60 days before enrollment History of adverse reaction to any ingredients of the study medication Clinically significant neurological, cardiovascular, respiratory, hepatic, renal, metabolic and dermatologic disease other than venous ulcers Current or former malignancy Arterial disorder resulting in ulcerated ulcers Diabetes mellitus Pregnant or lactating (breastfeeding) women. A serum pregnancy test will be performed at screening for female patients of childbearing potential</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Venous Stasis Ulcers</keyword>
	<keyword>venous insufficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>leg ulcers</keyword>
	<keyword>Thymosin Beta 4</keyword>
	<keyword>Laminin-5</keyword>
</DOC>