<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00832143</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Neonatal mortality rate in Uttar Pradesh, Northern India is 53.6 per thousand, and accounts for 8% of global neonatal deaths.It has been argued that prompt and appropriate care-seeking for sick neonates can substantially reduce neonatal mortality. This pre and post intervention trial was done to assess the impact of a pictorial "Neonatal referral Card" and one-to-one counseling of mothers on the qualified medical care-seeking behavior for sick neonates in urban Lucknow. The study hypothesis was that the counseling on danger signs along with neonatal referral card has no impact on availing services of a qualified medical practitioner by caregivers of sick neonates.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Referral Card on Neonatal Medical Care Seeking for Institutional Births in Urban Lucknow</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study was conducted in two government maternity hospitals in Lucknow. Neonates enrolled in the pre intervention phase were followed up for 6 weeks+15 days but did not recieve the study intervention. While, the mothers of the neonates enrolled in the post intervention phase recieved the study intervention within 48 hours of institutional delivery.Enrollment and follow-up procedures were same in both the phases.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Neonates born in the participating hospital within last 48 hours and the parents on which gave written informed consent to participate in the study. Neonates presenting with any clinically detectable congenital malformation at birth or who required any resuscitation at birth or who were admitted for any morbidity immediately after birth or those who were not the residents of Lucknow or were likely to leave the city limits within next one month.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>4 Weeks</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>neonatal illness</keyword>
	<keyword>qualified care seeking</keyword>
	<keyword>Behaviour change</keyword>
	<keyword>Urban slums</keyword>
	<keyword>India</keyword>
	<keyword>Neonatal morbidity</keyword>
	<keyword>Care seeking for neonatal illnesses</keyword>
	<keyword>Qualified medical care seeking</keyword>
	<keyword>Integrated management of neonatal and childhood illnesses (IMNCI)</keyword>
</DOC>