<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00832182</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted in Europe and Asia. The aim of this clinical trial is to investigate the long-term safety of insulin aspart in the management of type 1 diabetes. An extension to the ANA/DCD/065 trial</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Examining the Long-term Safety of Insulin Aspart When Used as a Part of the Treatment for Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin degludec, insulin aspart drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isophane insulin, beef</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Aspart</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Long-Acting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isophane Insulin, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Isophane</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Protamines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed informed consent obtained before any trialrelated activities. (Trialrelated activities are any procedure that would not have been performed during normal management of the subject) The subject must have completed the ANA/DCD/065 trial Impaired hepatic function Impaired renal function Total daily insulin requirements of more than 1.4 U/kg Cardiac problems Uncontrolled hypertension Known or suspected allergy to trial product or related products Current hypoglycaemic unawareness as judged by the investigator Known or suspect abuse of alcohol or narcotics Women breastfeeding or having the intention of becoming pregnant, or if judged not to be using adequate contraceptive measures (adequate measures are intrauterine device (IUD), oral contraception and barrier methods) Any condition that the Investigator and/or Sponsor feels would interfere with trial participation or evaluation of results</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>