<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00708552</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is designed to investigate the efficacy, safety and tolerability of SB-742457 versus placebo in subjects with mild-to-moderate Alzheimer's disease. SB-742457 is an experimental treatment which increases the levels of certain chemicals in the brain that are often decreased in patients with Alzheimer's disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of SB-742457 or Donepezil Versus Placebo in Subjects With Mild-to-moderate Alzheimer's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Donepezil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Subjects and their caregivers must provide informed consent prior to study entry. Subjects must have a clinical diagnosis of probable mildtomoderate Alzheimer's disease with a documented 6month history of AD symptoms Subjects must have a regular caregiver who is willing to attend visits, oversee the subject's compliance with the study and report on the subject's status. Female subjects of childbearing potential must agree to pregnancy testing and approved form of birth control. Exclusion criteria: Diagnosis of possible, probable or definite vascular dementia. History/evidence of any other CNS disorder that could be interpreted as a cause of dementia History of known or suspected seizures, loss of consciousness or significant head trauma Subjects with ECG, blood pressure and laboratory values outside of protocol criteria are excluded. Subjects with known photosensitivity Subjects with a history of previous exposure to SB742457, taking agents for which there is a theoretical risk of interaction with SB742457, or taking medication for Alzheimer's disease or centrally acting agents which might impact study outcomes may not participate.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognition</keyword>
	<keyword>SB-742457</keyword>
</DOC>