<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01245608</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of this study is to determine the effects of a fixed dose combination of valsartan, hydrochlorothiazide, atorvastatin and aspirin (PolyPill) on prevention of cardiovascular events in adults older than 50. Various liver-related variables will also be recorded which will allow studying the effects of PolyPill on the liver and the effect of liver diseases such as nonalcoholic steatohepatitis on cardiovascular events and the protective effect of PolyPill.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prevention of Cardiovascular Disease Using a Single PolyPill in an Urban Population - Focus on Liver-Related Variables.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>2400 subjects will be randomly selected from participants of the Golestan Cohort Study (GCS) who are living in Gonbad and are over 50 years old. These subjects will be randomized to either receive PolyPill or no treatment. Those agreeing to the study will undergo additional measurements (in addition to the baseline measurements performed in the GCS) including liver-related tests such as liver enzyme levels, abdominal ultrasonography and liver stiffness measurement. Some additional tests such as color doppler ultrasonography of carotid vessels will also be performed. Subjects in the PolyPill arm who have no contraindication for the components of the pill will receive a single daily dose of PolyPill for 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Being enrolled in Golestan Cohort Study Debilitating disease causing inability to comply Contraindications to any of the components of PolyPill Not consenting to the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Atorvastatin</keyword>
	<keyword>Aspirin</keyword>
	<keyword>nonalcoholic steatohepatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>nonalcoholic fatty liver disease</keyword>
	<keyword>antihypertensive agents</keyword>
</DOC>