<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01998880</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This open-label, randomized, 3-arm study will evaluate the efficacy and safety of obinutuzumab (RO5072759) in combination with chlorambucil as compared to rituximab plus chlorambucil or chlorambucil alone in patients with previously untreated chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL). Patients will be randomized 2:2:1 to receive a maximum of six 28-day cycles of either RO5072759 (1000mg iv infusion, on days 1, 8 and 15 of cycle 1 and day 1 of cycles 2-6) plus chlorambucil (0.5 mg/kg orally, days 1 and 15 of cycles 1-6), or rituximab (iv infusion day 1, 375 mg/m^2 cycle 1, 500 mg/m^2 cycles 2-6) plus chlorambucil, or chlorambucil alone. Anticipated time on study treatment is &gt;6 months and follow-up for disease-progression and safety will be at least 5 years. In the US, this trial is sponsored/managed by Genentech.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CLL11: A Study of Rituximab With Chlorambucil or Chlorambucil Alone in Patients With Previously Untreated Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (Stage 1b)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Protocol BO21004 is divided into 3 separate Unique Protocol IDs for reporting results on clinicaltrials.gov because there are 3 separate primary analyses conducted at different time-points. - BO21004 (Stage 1a) [NCT01010061] includes the analysis of 2 of the 3 arms obinutuzumab plus chlorambucil (Glb) compared to chlorambucil (Clb) reported separately. - BO21004 (Stage 1b) [NCT01998880] includes the analysis of 2 of the 3 arms rituximab plus chlorambucil (RClb) compared to chlorambucil (Clb) reported here. - BO21004 (Stage 2) [NCT02053610] includes the analysis of 2 of the 3 arms obinutuzumab plus chlorambucil (Glb) compared to rituximab plus chlorambucil (RClb) reported separately.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obinutuzumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorambucil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults &gt;/=18 years Documented Cluster of Differentiation Antigen 20 (CD20) + BCell Chronic Lymphocytic Lymphoma (BCLL) Previously untreated Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL) requiring treatment according to the National Cancer Institute (NCI) criteria Total Cumulative Illness Rating Scale (CIRS) &gt; 6 and/or creatinine clearance &lt; 70 ml/min Prior CLL therapy Transformation of CLL to aggressive NonHodgkin's Lymphoma (NHL) (Richter's transformation) History of other malignancy unless the malignancy has been in remission without treatment for &gt;/=2 years prior to enrolment, and except for carcinoma in situ of the cervix, basal or squamous cell skin cancer, surgically treated lowgrade prostate cancer, or ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) of the breast treated with lymphectomy alone Positive hepatitis serology (HBV, HCV) or positive HIV or Human T Cell Leukemia Virus (HTLV) testing Patients with active infection requiring systemic treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>