<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01998243</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Introduction: bariatric surgery shows an important morbidity and there are some reports that have used preoperative intragastric-balloons (IGB-BIB®) to decrease surgical morbidity. Patients Methods: Since 2009 we are performing a randomized and prospective study to assess the usefulness of (IGB-BIB®) before bariatric surgery [sleeve resection (SR) or gastric bypass (GB)] "group A" vs a control group "B" with the same type of surgical procedures but without preoperative IGB-BIB. All patients coming for both groups were followed at 4-week intervals by a nurse practitioner and dietitian for 6 months, Nurse practitioner made the dietetics adjustments (750-1500 Kcal) , provide advice and assess the evolution of weight loss The hypothesis was that preoperative IGB-BIB helps the patients to lose weight ( more than 10%) ,and the weight loss will contribute to decrease surgical morbidity by at least 30%, and also will decrease hospital stay Objective: to check if morbidity, mortality and hospital stay decreased in the IGB-BIB ® group, and secondly if the weight before surgery was associated with surgical morbidity. secondary objective : Assess the rate of IGB-BIB failure.Intragastric balloon failure was considered when the weight loss is less than 10% from the initial weight. We defined severe complication whenever the patient had to be admitted in the hospital after discharge, new surgeries or transfusions were required or the hospital stay was longer than 7-10 days.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Usefulness and Safeness Of Intra-Gastric Balloon Before Bariatric Surgery In Morbid Obesity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obesity, Morbid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients older than 18 and younger than 80 yo 2. Morbid obesity (BMI ≥ 40 kg/m2 ) with indication for laparoscopic bariatric surgery or Morbid obesity (BMI ≥ 35 kg/m2) with important comorbidity 3. Conventional Medical treatment (diet and drugs) should have failed before 4. Patients included should be operated by a laparoscopic gastric sleeve or by laparoscopic gastric bypass 5. Obesity should no be secondary to any other systemic disease 6. Firmed informed consent 1. slight adherence to previous medical treatments . 2. Hiatal hernia more than 3 cms 3. Patients with gastric or duodenal ulcer disease not treated and cured 4. Severe esophagitis 5. Psychiatric diseases (depression, bulimia etc) 6. Associated Severe Systemic Disease not amenable to improve with weight loss, and with implication ON decreasing life expectancy (cancer, symptomatic ischemic cardiopathy or terminal renal failure ) 7. Patients with previous antireflux surgery 8. Patients with Inflammatory bowel diseases 9. Patients with indication or already been on anticoagulant treatment . 10. Addiction to Drugs or alcohol 11. Past history of gastric surgery,or any other type of bariatric surgery or gastric complication related to gastric lapband 12. Patient refusing to be followed 6 months before and after surgery 13. Pregnancy or foreseeable pregnancy during the study 14. Patients taking anticoagulant agents or steroids 15. Patients with gastric or esophageal varices 16. PPI allergy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>morbid obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>bioenterics intragastric balloon</keyword>
	<keyword>bariatric surgery</keyword>
</DOC>