<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01166750</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a randomized wait-list controlled trial with repeated measures. There will be two groups: (1) standard medical care (wait-list control), and (2) standard medical care plus the adjunctive Jointstrong pain coping skills CD-ROM program (treatment). The study will have four phases: Pre-intervention Baseline (2 weeks); Intervention (4 weeks); immediate post-intervention follow up (2 weeks); and 12-week post-intervention follow up (2 weeks). The purpose of this study is to determine if using a CD-ROM program for juvenile arthritis can help children learn how to improve their symptoms on their own and reduce the frequency of symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Jointstrong Intervention for Juvenile Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>If your child is eligible and decides to participate in this study, this participation will last approximately eight weeks. Please refer to the table at the end of this consent form. Your child's participation in this study will involve the completion of daily questionnaires during a one-week baseline period and a one-week follow-up period. These questionnaires will contain various questions about your child's arthritis and his/her ability to do various activities. The questionnaires will take approximately 15-30 minutes each week to complete. Your child will be randomly assigned to complete one of two CD-ROM programs. One of the CD-ROM programs is a "control" program that contains educational information about arthritis and medical treatments and the other is the "treatment" program and contains the same educational information as the control program plus information on behavioral strategies for controlling symptoms of arthritis. Your child's participation in this study will involve working through one of these CD-ROM programs over a one-month period. Your child will also continue to receive medical treatment from the rheumatologist treating your child for arthritis. The CD-ROM programs involve working through developmentally appropriate lessons on the nature of arthritis and how to treat it. The CD-ROM programs are divided into weekly "modules" and are designed to be completed within four weeks. Lessons take an average of 15 minutes to complete (plus "homework"), and there is an average of 4 lessons to complete each week. Your participation in this study will involve the completion of questionnaires and helping your child understand any parts of the study that he or she does not understand.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria. Patients recruited for this study will meet the following inclusion criteria: (a) are 812 years of age; (b) have a diagnosis of JA by a pediatric rheumatologist using established criteria, and (c) have JArelated (joint) pain occurring on an average of at least once per week by patient report [9]. Participants in the age range 812 years will be recruited because the intervention will be tailored to children (future studies will involve creating and testing a version of Jointstrong for adolescents). Although access to a home computer with a CDROM drive is required for the study, this will not be an inclusion criterion, and we expect the lack of access will be rare, as our pilot data on 37 children with headaches found that only 2% (1 child) did not have adequate home computer access [15]. So as not to exclude the few children without access who otherwise qualify for the study, we will lend laptop computers to these children. All children meeting symptom inclusion criteria will therefore be able to use the adjunctive CDROM programs in a home setting. Exclusion Criteria. Patients will be excluded from the study if (a) their parents or rheumatologist report they have been diagnosed with a mental health condition or they are receiving concurrent psychotherapy; or (b) their 14day baseline pain diaries indicate they have pain, on average, less than one day per week; or (c) they do not speak English.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>