<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01166334</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Would you like to quit smoking? Seattle's Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center is launching a new study that may be able to help. Participants who enroll in this study will be randomly assigned by computer (like flipping a coin) to one of two online programs. The goal of this study is to learn which of these programs is the most effective at helping people stop smoking. Findings from this study will be used to help build more effective online smoking cessation programs in the future. Participants in both of the smoking cessation programs used in this study will receive: - Interactive tools for dealing more effectively with urges to smoke - Step-by-step guides for quitting smoking - Personalized plans for quitting and remaining smoke-free - Electronic links for reaching one-on-one expert help for quitting Participants will be asked to complete online questionnaires, including a brief three-month follow-up survey. There is no cost for participating in this study. To enroll in this study or for more information, please visit www.webquit.com. This study is being conducted by Seattle's Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center (www.fhcrc.org), a world leader in advancing the prevention, diagnosis and treatment of cancer. The principal investigator for the WebQuit smoking cessation study is Dr. Jonathan Bricker, a faculty member at both the Hutchinson Center and at the University of Washington in Seattle.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>WebQuit Online Smoking Cessation Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>18 or older a current resident of the US someone who has smoked daily for at least the past 12 months someone who wants to quit smoking in the next 30 days willing and able to read in English able to connect to the Internet for at least one hour per week for three consecutive months able to use a website not participating in other smoking cessation interventions willing and able to complete a Baseline Survey willing to be randomized to either online program inability to meet inclusion criteria</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Smoking</keyword>
	<keyword>Smoke</keyword>
	<keyword>Cigarette</keyword>
	<keyword>Cessation</keyword>
	<keyword>Quit</keyword>
	<keyword>Online</keyword>
	<keyword>Web</keyword>
	<keyword>Stop</keyword>
</DOC>