<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01166945</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators objective is to compare short course (5 days) to long course (14 days)antibiotics for the treatment of acute bacterial sinusitis in children. The investigators hypothesize that short course therapy will lead to more frequent relapses of sinusitis and will not reduce resistant organisms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Short (5 Days) Versus Long (14 Days) Duration of Antimicrobial Therapy for Acute Bacterial Sinusitis in Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sinusitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clavulanic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amoxicillin-Potassium Clavulanate Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clavulanic Acids</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amoxicillin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Infective Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. children with nasal discharge (of any quality) or daytime cough (which may be worse at night) or both persisting for 10 days or more without evidence of improvement. 2. families need to be English speaking 1. used antibiotics within the last 15 days; 2. had symptoms for &gt; 30 days; 3. have concurrent streptococcal pharyngitis or acute otitis media (as the standard doses for both of these conditions is 10 days); 4. are allergic to penicillin; 5. have symptoms that suggest a complication due to acute bacterial sinusitis that necessitates hospitalization, intravenous antibiotics or subspecialty evaluation 6. been diagnosed with either immunodeficiency or anatomic abnormality of the upper respiratory tract 7. history of recurrent acute sinusitis (more than 3 episodes in 6 months or 4 episodes in a year) 8. history of chronic sinusitis (more than 90 days of respiratory symptoms in this or the previous respiratory season) 9. girls who have begun menstruating</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Child</keyword>
	<keyword>Child, preschool</keyword>
	<keyword>Sinusitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Antimicrobial agents</keyword>
</DOC>