<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01166438</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Urinary incontinence is a prevalent condition that markedly impacts quality of life and disproportionately affects women. Overactive Bladder syndrome (OAB) is defined as symptoms of urgency and frequency with urge urinary incontinence (OAB-wet) and without urge incontinence (OAB-dry). Conservative first line treatments for urge incontinence combined with other OAB symptoms (OAB-wet) include behavioral therapy, pelvic floor training +/- biofeedback, or the use of anticholinergic medications. These treatment modalities may not result in total continence and often drug therapy is discontinued because of lack of efficacy, side effects and cost or because of not wanting to take a pill. Behavioral therapy and pelvic muscle exercises require consistent, active intervention by the patient which is often not sustained. Thus, the objective of the Anticholinergic vs Botox Comparison Study (ABC) is to determine whether a single intra-detrusor injection of botulinum toxin A (Botox A®) is more effective than a standardized regimen of oral anticholinergics in reducing urge urinary incontinence. The null hypothesis is that there is no difference in the change from baseline in average number of urge urinary incontinence episodes over 6 months between groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Anticholinergic vs. Botox Comparison Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a 6-month double-blind randomized trial comparing intra-detrusor botulinum toxin A (Botox A®) and anticholinergic therapy in women without neurologic disease with urge incontinence. Subjects will be followed up to an additional six months off study drug to determine duration of treatment effect. The primary aim is to compare the change in urge incontinence episodes over 6 months between women receiving a single intra-detrusor injection of 100 unit of botulinum toxin A (Botox A®) plus daily oral placebo tablets versus women receiving a single intra-detrusor injection of saline plus daily anticholinergic therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Enuresis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Overactive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence, Urge</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trospium chloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Solifenacin Succinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins, Type A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>abobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>onabotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>incobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholinergic Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject has signed informed consent. Females at least 21 years of age Five or more urge urinary incontinence episodes on a threeday voiding diary. Urge incontinence episodes will be determined based on voiding diary and subject indication of coincident urge symptoms, allowing selfcharacterization of incontinence type. Urge predominant (urge &gt;50% of total incontinent episodes) urinary incontinence based on selfreported characterization of incontinent episodes on diary. Demonstrated ability (or have caregiver demonstrate ability) to perform clean intermittent selfcatheterization in the event that this would be required. Request for treatment for urge urinary incontinence. The patient may have tried other nonpharmacologic treatments for urge incontinence, such as supervised behavioral therapy, supervised physical therapy, unsupervised physical therapy, supervised biofeedback, and transvaginal electrical stimulation. Subject has undergone 3week washout period if subject were on anticholinergic therapy prior to enrollment. Subject is able to complete all study related items and interviews. Any previous therapy with trospium chloride, solifenacin, or darifenacin Failed three or more anticholinergic drugs. Contraindication to anticholinergic therapy, specifically with solifenacin or trospium. Current symptomatic urinary tract infection that has not resolved prior to randomization. Uncontrolled narrowangle glaucoma Gastric retention Baseline need for intermittent self catheterization PVR &gt;150ml on 2 occasions with void(s) of greater than 150ml Surgical treatment for stress incontinence (sling, Burch or urethral injection) or pelvic organ prolapse recommended or planned at enrollment by study investigator(s). Any prior intradetrusor botulinum toxin A injections Previous or currently implanted neuromodulation (sacral or tibial). Surgically altered detrusor muscle, such as augmentation cystoplasty. Known allergy to botulinum toxin A. Women with known neurologic disease believed to potentially affect urinary function (Multiple sclerosis, spinal cord injuries, myasthenia gravis, CharcotMarieTooth disease). Known allergy to lidocaine. Currently pregnant or lactating patients or patients planning pregnancy within the next year. Sexually active premenopausal women with a uterus who have either not had a tubal ligation or are not on a medically approved form of contraception for at least 3 months prior to and throughout the duration of the study. Cystoscopic findings that preclude injection, in the opinion of the investigator. Current or prior bladder malignancy. In the opinion of the investigator, inability to understand diary instructions and complete 3day voiding diary. Subjects who are on anticoagulant therapy,excluding aspirin Subject has been previously diagnosed with interstitial cystitis or chronic pelvic pain syndrome. Subjects with hematuria who have not undergone a clinically appropriate evaluation. Subjects taking aminoglycosides at the time of injection. Serum creatinine level greater than twice the upper limit of normal within the previous year. Two or more hospitalizations for medical conditions in the previous year. Plans to move out of area in the next 6 months.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>incontinence</keyword>
	<keyword>overactive bladder</keyword>
	<keyword>botox</keyword>
	<keyword>anticholinergic</keyword>
</DOC>