<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00882245</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Atopic Dermatitis is a chronic inflammatory skin disease that affect 10 to 15% of children and 2 to 10% of adults. AD is characterised by an itchy skin eruption and may cover large parts of the body. The exact cause is unknown but is thought to be an interplay between genetic and and environmental factors. The objective of this study is to determine whether SRD441 ointment is a safe and effective therapy for mild to moderate Atopic Dermatitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of SRD441 Ointment in Patients With Atopic Dermatitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis, Atopic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eczema</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female subjects aged 18 or over Subjects with a history of AD Written and dated informed consent Satisfactory medical assessment with no clinical relevant abnormalities. Subjects with current or recurrent disease (except AD) that could affect the site of application, the action, absorption or disposition of the investigational product, or clinical or laboratory assessments. Subjects who have medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory abnormality that may increase the risk associated with trial participation or investigational product administration or may interfere with the interpretation of trial results and, in the judgement of the investigator, would make the subject inappropriate for entry into this trial. Subjects with any skin tattoo, scar, cuts, bruises, or other skin damage, including excessive UV exposure, at the possible drug application sites which could impact the application of the test agent or confound the local assessments during this study. Subjects with clinically significant renal and liver parameters, as defined as greater than 1.5 x creatinine and 3 x AST ULN (upper limit of normal) respectively.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2009</verification_date>
</DOC>