<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="147333">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01182415</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>09-444</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01182415</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>High Dose Chemotherapy and Stem Cell Transplant for Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma or Central Nervous System (CNS) Lymphoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Trial of Hihg-Dose Thiotepa, Busulfan, Cyclophosphamide, and Rituximab With Autologous Stem Cell Transplantation for Patients With CNS Involvement by Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma or Primary CNS Lymphoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Genentech, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Otsuka America Pharmaceutical</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Current standard treatments for lymphoma involving the central nervous system include
      chemotherapy or whole brain radiation therapy (WBRT). However, many patients do not respond
      to this treatment, and some of the patients who do respond relapse after treatment.

      Previous research has shown that a stem cell transplant of a patient's own cells (autologous
      stem cell transplant) may be more effective for some patients with lymphoma involving the
      CNS. In previous research using autologous stem cell transplants for lymphoma involving the
      CNS, a conditioning regimen consisting of the drugs thiotepa, busulfan and cyclophosphamide
      (TCE) was used. These drugs have been shown to enter the nervous system.

      In this research study, the investigators are adding the drug rituximab (Rituxan) to the
      drug cytarabine for the stem cell mobilization process. Cytarabine is a standard drug for
      mobilization. In addition, rituximab will be added to the conditioning regimen of thiotepa,
      busulfan and cyclophosphamide. Rituximab is approved by the FDA for the treatment of some
      types of lymphomas, but is not approved for use in lymphomas that involve the CNS. Rituximab
      is known to be able to enter the CNS. Previous research has suggested that it may help treat
      lymphoma that involves the CNS.

      The goal of this research study is to see if adding rituximab to the stem cell mobilization
      and conditioning regimens helps treat lymphoma that involves the central nervous system.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      If the screening procedures confirm that you are eligible to participate in the research
      study you will have the following procedures.

      Stem cell mobilization - this will take place over at least 9 days to prepare you to donate
      your stem cells for your autologous transplant. The drugs cytarabine, rituximab and Neupogen
      (G-CSF) will be given. You will be in the hospital for 2 days to receive the cytarabine
      infusions (and the 1st rituximab infusion of day 1 of stem cell mobilization). Then you will
      be discharged. You will receive the Neupogen injections as an outpatient.

      Stem cell collection (leukapheresis) - When your doctor determines that your stem cell count
      is high enough you will have your stem cells collected by a procedure called leukapheresis.
      Leukapheresis is performed by collecting blood from a vein and processing it through a
      machine that removes the stem cells that are needed to produce bone marrow. The rest of the
      blood is returned to you through another vein. The harvested stem cells will be frozen and
      stored. These cells will be returned to you after you complete the conditioning regimen with
      high dose chemotherapy.

      Conditioning regimen (high dose chemotherapy) - You will enter the hospital for the
      conditioning regimen and stay for about 30 days after you receive your stem cell transplant.
      The conditioning regimen to help kill cancer cells before your stem cell transplant will
      take place over 9 days. All drugs will be given intravenous (through an IV).

      Infusion of stem cells (stem cell transplant) - Your cells will be given to you through your
      vein, similar to an IV infusion. The infusion usually takes several hours.

      After you are discharged, you will be asked to return at about 4 weeks, 8 weeks, 12 weeks
      and 14 weeks after the stem cell transplant. At each visit you will have a physical exam,
      questions to measure your mental functioning, blood tests. About 14 weeks after the stem
      cell transplant you will have an eye exam, echocardiogram, lung function tests, whole body
      PET-CT scan, brain MRI or CT scan, MRI or CT of spinal cord (for patients who may have
      lymphoma in the spinal cord), collection of cerebral spinal fluid, and bone marrow
      aspiration.

      You will have follow-up visits for 6 month to up to 4 years after the stem cell transplant.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>No masking</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients with CNS involvement by B-cell NHL, relapsed PCNSL, or relapsed PIOL who are alive and progression-free at one year</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1-year progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1-year Event free Survival (EFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1-year overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>CNS Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>High-dose chemotherapy with autologous stem cell transplant</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>High-dose chemotherapy with autologous stem cell transplant</intervention_name>
    <description>High-dose chemotherapy with rituximab, thiotepa, busulfan, and cyclosphosphamide followed by autologous stem cell transplant</description>
    <arm_group_label>High-dose chemotherapy with autologous stem cell transplant</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  One of the following clinical criteria:secondary CNS NHL; synchronous CNS NHL;
             relapsed PCNSL; relapsed IOL; PCNSL or IOL which has only achieved a PR after
             adequate initial therapy

          -  Must have CNS or intraocular involvement by NHL

          -  Subjects with secondary CNS NHL, relapsed PCNSL, or relapsed IOL will have received
             Salvage therapy for their CNS disease

          -  Subjects with synchronous CNS NHL will have received primary therapy including
             CNS-directed therapy

          -  Must demonstrate a partial or complete response of the CNS and systemic disease to
             pre-enrollment therapy, and must be in PR or CR at the time of enrollment

          -  Age &gt;/= 18 and &lt;/= 75 years

          -  Life expectancy &gt;/= 3 months

          -  ECOG performance status &lt;/= 2

          -  Must have adequate organ function as defined by the protocol

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Stable or progressive CNS or systemic disease (SD orPD) at the time of enrollment

          -  Systemic or intrathecal chemotherapy or radiotherapy within 2 weeks prior to starting
             therapy on study

          -  Actively receiving any other study agents aimed to treat their disease

          -  A prior HDT-ASCT or allogeneic stem cell transplant (myeloablative or
             nonmyeloablative)

          -  Burkitt's lymphoma or acute lymphoblastic lymphoma

          -  A history of severe allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or
             biologic composition to cytarabine, thiotepa, busulfan, cyclophosphamide, or
             rituximab

          -  Serious uncontrolled concurrent illness

          -  Any evidence of prior exposure to Hepatitis B virus

          -  HIV-positive

          -  Pregnant or lactating

          -  A history of malignancy other than NHL or PCNSL unless disease-free for at least 5
             years and are deemed by the investigator to be at low risk for recurrence of that
             malignancy. Individuals with the following cancers are eligible if diagnosed and
             treated within the past 5 years: cervical cancer in situ, and basal cell or squamous
             cell carcinoma of the skin
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yi-Bin A Chen, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chen YB, Batchelor T, Li S, Hochberg E, Brezina M, Jones S, Del Rio C, Curtis M, Ballen KK, Barnes J, Chi AS, Dietrich J, Driscoll J, Gertsner ER, Hochberg F, LaCasce AS, McAfee SL, Spitzer TR, Nayak L, Armand P. Phase 2 trial of high-dose rituximab with high-dose cytarabine mobilization therapy and high-dose thiotepa, busulfan, and cyclophosphamide autologous stem cell transplantation in patients with central nervous system involvement by non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Cancer. 2015 Jan 15;121(2):226-33. doi: 10.1002/cncr.29023. Epub 2014 Sep 9.</citation>
    <PMID>25204639</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 21, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 30, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yi-Bin A. Chen, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CNS involvement</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Thiotepa</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
