<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="139194">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01288976</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EU-0901</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01288976</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ACCESS-Europe A Two-Phase Observational Study of the MitraClip® System in Europe</brief_title>
  <acronym>ACCESS-EU</acronym>
  <official_title>ACCESS-Europe A Two-Phase Observational Study of the MitraClip® System in Europe</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Evalve</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Evalve</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The MitraClip System enables the European physicians an alternative therapeutic option for
      patients with mitral regurgitation (MR). Therapeutic alternatives are open-heart cardiac
      surgery, and palliative medical therapy with or without device therapy. The study will
      observe the outcomes of patients treated with the MitraClip System throughout 12-months as
      compared to the outcomes of patients treated by alternative therapies.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PHASE I:

      The primary objective of ACCESS-EU Phase I is to gain information in the European Union
      Countries regarding the use of the MitraClip System with respect to health economics and
      clinical care.

      PHASE II: (HAS BEEN CLOSED BY SPONSOR) The primary objective of ACCESS-EU Phase II is to
      gather additional clinical data, specifically Echocardiography Core Laboratory measurements
      of MR severity and left ventricular volumes and diameters, and other echocardiographic
      measures, on patients undergoing the MitraClip procedure in the European Union Countries,

      Clinical data collected from both study phases, is expected to contribute to decision making
      with regards to MitraClip therapy selection in patients with MR: (a) by establishing the
      value of the MitraClip therapy in the continuum of care; and (b) by providing practical
      information that will allow physicians to make therapeutic decisions, assist hospitals to
      make purchasing decisions, and assist insurers in making coverage decisions.

      Study Design:

      ACCESS-Europe is a two-phase prospective, observational, multicenter post-approval study of
      the MitraClip System for the treatment of mitral regurgitation (MR) in the European Union
      Countries. Patients will be evaluated per standard practice at baseline, discharge, 6-Months
      and 12-Months.

      Phase I of the study consists of patients who receive the MitraClip system for the treatment
      of MR and two concurrent comparator groups of (a) medically managed heart failure patients
      with MR and (b) patients who have undergone mitral valve surgery for MR. The two comparator
      groups will be followed and evaluated primarily from a health economic perspective.

      ACCESS EU Study Phase II will consist of only patients who receive the MitraClip System,
      with the objective to collect additional clinical data, specifically Echocardiography Core
      Laboratory evaluation of MR severity and other echocardiographic measures.

      Enrollment of patients in each study phase is as follows:

      ACCESS-EU PHASE I:

        -  A minimum of 300 MitraClip Therapy group patients,

        -  A minimum of 100 patients in the Mitral Valve Surgery comparator group

        -  As many patients as possible in the Medical Therapy comparator group

      First Patient Enrollment Projection: Q1, 2009 Last Patient Enrollment Projection: Enrollment
      in the Mitral Valve Surgery and Medically Therapy groups ceased on December 31, 2010.
      Enrollment in the MitraClip group will cease when Phase II of the study is initiated at each
      site.

      ACCESS-EU PHASE II:

      A minimum of 300 MitraClip therapy subjects will be enrolled in Phase II.

      First Patient Enrollment Projection: Q2, 2011 Last Patient Enrollment Projection: Enrollment
      will cease when the Sponsor has determined that an adequate number of patients have been
      enrolled.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Quality of Life at 12-month follow-up.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Minnesota Living with Heart Failure Questionnaire will be used as a measure of the patients' perceptions of the effects of congestive heart failure on their lives.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in 6-minute walk distance test at 12 months.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The 6-minute walk distance test will be used to measure the patient's exercise capacity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">567</enrollment>
  <condition>Mitral Valve (MV) Regurgitation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MitraClip Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients treated with the MitraClip System.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Medical Management</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with MR managed non-surgically based on standard hospital clinical practice.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mitral Valve Surgery</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with MR managed surgically (repair or replacement) based on standard hospital clinical practice.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MitraClip</intervention_name>
    <description>The MitraClip System includes a MitraClip device, a Steerable Guide Catheter, and a MitraClip Delivery System that enables placement of the MitraClip device on the mitral valve leaflets</description>
    <arm_group_label>MitraClip Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Medical Management</intervention_name>
    <description>The Non-Surgical Medically Managed Heart Failure (HF) Group consists of patients with mitral regurgitation (MR) in whom the MR is managed non-surgically based on standard hospital clinical practice. Patients with MR who receive a pacemaker, Implantable Cardiac Defibrillator (ICD) and/or Cardiac Resynchronization Therapy (CRT) treatments may be included</description>
    <arm_group_label>Medical Management</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mitral Valve Surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>The Mitral Valve Surgery Group consists of patients with MR in whom the MR is managed surgically (repair or replacement) based on standard hospital clinical practice. Patients with concurrent coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) or aortic/tricuspid valve or and other cardiac procedure except atrial fibrillation surgery are excluded.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mitral Valve Surgery</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with Mitral Regurgitation
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Per the current approved labeling for the Conformity European (CE) Marked MitraClip
             System.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Per the current approved labeling for the CE Marked MitraClip System.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Barathi Sethuraman, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Abbott Vascular Structural Heart (Evalve Inc)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wolfgang Schillinger, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universitatsmedizin Gottingen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Francesco Maisano, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fondazion Ctr San Raffaele Del Monte Tabor Istituto</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitatsmedizin Gottingen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gottingen</city>
        <zip>37075</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.abbottvascular.com/us/index.html</url>
    <description>Sponsor information</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rogers JH, Yeo KK, Carroll JD, Cleveland J, Reece TB, Gillinov AM, Rodriguez L, Whitlow P, Woo YJ, Herrmann HC, Young JN. Late surgical mitral valve repair after percutaneous repair with the MitraClip system. J Card Surg. 2009 Nov-Dec;24(6):677-81. doi: 10.1111/j.1540-8191.2009.00901.x. Epub 2009 Jul 24.</citation>
    <PMID>19682161</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Feldman T, Kar S, Rinaldi M, Fail P, Hermiller J, Smalling R, Whitlow PL, Gray W, Low R, Herrmann HC, Lim S, Foster E, Glower D; EVEREST Investigators.. Percutaneous mitral repair with the MitraClip system: safety and midterm durability in the initial EVEREST (Endovascular Valve Edge-to-Edge REpair Study) cohort. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009 Aug 18;54(8):686-94. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2009.03.077.</citation>
    <PMID>19679246</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Herrmann HC, Kar S, Siegel R, Fail P, Loghin C, Lim S, Hahn R, Rogers JH, Bommer WJ, Wang A, Berke A, Lerakis S, Kramer P, Wong SC, Foster E, Glower D, Feldman T; EVEREST Investigators.. Effect of percutaneous mitral repair with the MitraClip device on mitral valve area and gradient. EuroIntervention. 2009 Jan;4(4):437-42.</citation>
    <PMID>19284064</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Luk A, Butany J, Ahn E, Fann JI, St Goar F, Thornton T, McDermott L, Madayag C, Komtebedde J. Mitral repair with the Evalve MitraClip device: histopathologic findings in the porcine model. Cardiovasc Pathol. 2009 Sep-Oct;18(5):279-85. doi: 10.1016/j.carpath.2008.07.001. Epub 2008 Aug 13.</citation>
    <PMID>18703359</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Silvestry FE, Rodriguez LL, Herrmann HC, Rohatgi S, Weiss SJ, Stewart WJ, Homma S, Goyal N, Pulerwitz T, Zunamon A, Hamilton A, Merlino J, Martin R, Krabill K, Block PC, Whitlow P, Tuzcu EM, Kapadia S, Gray WA, Reisman M, Wasserman H, Schwartz A, Foster E, Feldman T, Wiegers SE. Echocardiographic guidance and assessment of percutaneous repair for mitral regurgitation with the Evalve MitraClip: lessons learned from EVEREST I. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2007 Oct;20(10):1131-40. Epub 2007 Jun 13.</citation>
    <PMID>17570634</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Borgia F, Di Mario C, Franzen O. Adenosine-induced asystole to facilitate MitraClip placement in a patient with adverse mitral valve morphology. Heart. 2011 May;97(10):864. doi: 10.1136/hrt.2010.208132. Epub 2010 Oct 29.</citation>
    <PMID>21036802</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tamburino C, Immè S, Barbanti M, Mulè M, Pistritto AM, Aruta P, Cammalleri V, Scarabelli M, Mangiafico S, Scandura S, Ussia GP. Reduction of mitral valve regurgitation with Mitraclip® percutaneous system. Minerva Cardioangiol. 2010 Oct;58(5):589-98.</citation>
    <PMID>20948505</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ciobanu A, Bennett S, Azam M, Clark A, Vinereanu D. Incremental value of three-dimensional transoesophageal echocardiography for guiding double percutaneous MitraClip ® implantation in a 'no option' patient. Eur J Echocardiogr. 2011 Feb;12(2):E11. doi: 10.1093/ejechocard/jeq118. Epub 2010 Sep 27.</citation>
    <PMID>20876188</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lim DS, Kunjummen BJ, Smalling R. Mitral valve repair with the MitraClip device after prior surgical mitral annuloplasty. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2010 Sep 1;76(3):455-9. doi: 10.1002/ccd.22547.</citation>
    <PMID>20839359</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kalarus Z, Kukulski T, Lekston A, Streb W, Sikora J, Nadziakiewicz P, Gasior M, Poloński L, Zembala M. [Methodology and safety of transvascular reduction of severe ischaemic mitral insufficiency with MitraClip in high-surgical-risk patients - first three cases in Poland]. Kardiol Pol. 2010 Jun;68(6):729-35. Polish.</citation>
    <PMID>20806217</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Geidel S, Ostermeyer J, Lass M, Schmoeckel M. Complex surgical valve repair after failed percutaneous mitral intervention using the MitraClip device. Ann Thorac Surg. 2010 Jul;90(1):277-9. doi: 10.1016/j.athoracsur.2009.12.048.</citation>
    <PMID>20609795</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mauri L, Garg P, Massaro JM, Foster E, Glower D, Mehoudar P, Powell F, Komtebedde J, McDermott E, Feldman T. The EVEREST II Trial: design and rationale for a randomized study of the evalve mitraclip system compared with mitral valve surgery for mitral regurgitation. Am Heart J. 2010 Jul;160(1):23-9. doi: 10.1016/j.ahj.2010.04.009.</citation>
    <PMID>20598968</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jönsson A, Settergren M. MitraClip catheter-based mitral valve repair system. Expert Rev Med Devices. 2010 Jul;7(4):439-47. doi: 10.1586/erd.10.23.</citation>
    <PMID>20583881</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ussia GP, Barbanti M, Tamburino C. Feasibility of percutaneous transcatheter mitral valve repair with the MitraClip system using conscious sedation. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2010 Jun 1;75(7):1137-40. doi: 10.1002/ccd.22415.</citation>
    <PMID>20336809</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tamburino C, Ussia GP, Maisano F, Capodanno D, La Canna G, Scandura S, Colombo A, Giacomini A, Michev I, Mangiafico S, Cammalleri V, Barbanti M, Alfieri O. Percutaneous mitral valve repair with the MitraClip system: acute results from a real world setting. Eur Heart J. 2010 Jun;31(11):1382-9. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehq051. Epub 2010 Mar 18.</citation>
    <PMID>20299349</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Franzen O, Baldus S, Rudolph V, Meyer S, Knap M, Koschyk D, Treede H, Barmeyer A, Schofer J, Costard-Jäckle A, Schlüter M, Reichenspurner H, Meinertz T. Acute outcomes of MitraClip therapy for mitral regurgitation in high-surgical-risk patients: emphasis on adverse valve morphology and severe left ventricular dysfunction. Eur Heart J. 2010 Jun;31(11):1373-81. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehq050. Epub 2010 Mar 10.</citation>
    <PMID>20219746</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Argenziano M, Skipper E, Heimansohn D, Letsou GV, Woo YJ, Kron I, Alexander J, Cleveland J, Kong B, Davidson M, Vassiliades T, Krieger K, Sako E, Tibi P, Galloway A, Foster E, Feldman T, Glower D; EVEREST Investigators.. Surgical revision after percutaneous mitral repair with the MitraClip device. Ann Thorac Surg. 2010 Jan;89(1):72-80; discussion p 80. doi: 10.1016/j.athoracsur.2009.08.063.</citation>
    <PMID>20103209</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Maisano F, Franzen O, Baldus S, Schäfer U, Hausleiter J, Butter C, Ussia GP, Sievert H, Richardt G, Widder JD, Moccetti T, Schillinger W. Percutaneous mitral valve interventions in the real world: early and 1-year results from the ACCESS-EU, a prospective, multicenter, nonrandomized post-approval study of the MitraClip therapy in Europe. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2013 Sep 17;62(12):1052-61. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2013.02.094. Epub 2013 Jun 7.</citation>
    <PMID>23747789</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ussia GP, Cammalleri V, Scandura S, Immè S, Pistritto AM, Ministeri M, Chiarandà M, Caggegi A, Barbanti M, Aruta P, Tamburino C. Update on percutaneous mitral valve therapy: clinical results and real life experience. Minerva Cardioangiol. 2012 Feb;60(1):57-70.</citation>
    <PMID>22322574</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Maisano F, Godino C, Giacomini A, Denti P, Buzzatti N, Arendar I, Colombo A, Alfieri O, La Canna G. Patient selection for MitraClip therapy impaired left ventricular systolic function. Minerva Cardioangiol. 2011 Oct;59(5):455-71. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21983306</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 6, 2014</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 25, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Mitral Valve</keyword>
  <keyword>Mitral Regurgitation</keyword>
  <keyword>MitraClip</keyword>
  <keyword>Mitral Valve Surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Mitral Valve Insufficiency or Mitral Regurgitation</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
