<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00231205</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to test accuracy of positive preejection velocity to predict left ventricular remodeling and long-term prognosis after revascularization in 200 patients with chronically dysfunctional myocardium. Patients will be followed for 3 years. Our hypothesis is that tissue-Doppler-derived analysis of positive preejection velocity allows to select optimal responders to revascularization; it means individuals with the greatest benefit in terms of LV remodeling and long-term prognosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TDI Preejection Velocities and Myocardial Viability</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of the project is to study clinical and prognostic value of new echocardiographic technique, so called positive preejection velocity (+VIC), in patients with chronic ischemic left ventricular (LV) dysfunction indicated for revascularization. Pilot studies has shown high accuracy of pulsed Tissue Doppler imaging (TDI)-derived resting pattern of +VIC to detect viable myocardium in patients with both acute myocardial infarction and chronically dysfunctional myocardium. The aim of the project is to test accuracy of +VIC to predict LV remodeling and long-term prognosis after revascularization in patients with chronically dysfunctional myocardium. Study population will consist of two groups of patients with stable ischemic LV dysfunction: group A- patients indicated for revascularization (n=200), group B- matched control group treated conservatively (case-control design) (n=100). All patients will be followed for 3 years. Endpoints include: 1) LV remodeling at 6 and 24 months and 2) MACE at 6, 12 and 36 months follow-up. Our hypothesis is that TDI-derived analysis of +VIC allows to select optimal responders to revascularization; it means individuals with the greatest benefit in terms of LV remodeling and long-term prognosis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. occluded or suboccluded left anterior descending coronary artery (LAD) at recent coronary angiography (&lt; 3 months); 2. LV ejection fraction &lt; 40%; 3. 3 and more akinetic or severely hypokinetic segments in the LAD perfusion territory at resting echocardiography. Patients with recent acute coronary syndrome, atrial fibrillation, bundle branch block, LV hypertrophy or aneurysm, significant valvular disease, pacemakers or internal defibrillators, poor echocardiographic image quality and contraindications for MRI are excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2005</verification_date>
	<keyword>viability</keyword>
	<keyword>myocardium</keyword>
	<keyword>preejection velocity</keyword>
	<keyword>CAD</keyword>
	<keyword>echocardiography</keyword>
	<keyword>tissue Doppler</keyword>
</DOC>