<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00081094</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Imaging procedures, such as carbon-11 acetate positron emission tomography (PET) and fludeoxyglucose F 18 PET, may improve the ability to detect hepatocellular carcinoma (liver cancer) and allow doctors to plan the most effective treatment. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is studying how well carbon-11 acetate PET and fludeoxyglucose F 18 PET work in detecting cancer in patients with liver cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Positron Emission Tomography Using Carbon-11 Acetate and Fludeoxyglucose F 18 in Detecting Hepatocellular Carcinoma (Liver Cancer) in Patients With Known or Suspected Liver Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deoxyglucose</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorodeoxyglucose F18</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION: Biopsyproved HCC (stage I and II by conventional staging) or one or more of the following in a patient with clinically documented cirrhosis: AFP &gt; 200 mg/dL; A contrastenhancing tumor mass (&gt;1 cm) by CT or MRI; or A tumor mass confirmed by arteriography. Patient must provide written informed consent and have completed conventional imaging and staging before initiation of PET imaging. EXCLUSION: Pediatric patients under the age of 18 will be excluded from consideration from this study. Patients with a known prior malignancy (with the exception of basal cell carcinoma of the skin and carcinoma in situ of the cervix) within 5 years will be excluded from entry into the study. However, patients with a prior HCC thought to have a new primary or recurrent HCC are eligible. Pregnant and breastfeeding patients. Patients with poorly controlled diabetes mellitus (fasting blood glucose level &gt; 200 mg/dL)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult primary hepatocellular carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult primary liver cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>localized resectable adult primary liver cancer</keyword>
</DOC>