<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03080792</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The PRESENT-P study is a one-arm exercise intervention study for hematological cancer patients prior allogeneic stem cell transplantation (allo-HCT). This pilot study will investigate in a prehabilitation approach the safety and feasibility of high-intensity exercise program directly prior transplantation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pre-Exercise for Allogeneic Stem Cell Transplant Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The major objective of PRESENT-P is to investigate the feasibility and safety of a high intensity endurance exercise training (HIIT) and progressive resistance exercise prior allo-HCT. This multicenter pilot study will include n=30 patients. Patients perform two supervised exercise sessions per week. Recruitment take place 6-12 weeks prior allogeneic stem cell transplantation. Further aims of this pilot study are: to estimate the number of eligible patients, evaluate the recruitment procedure, and to explore the effect of HIIT prior allo-HCT on maximal oxygen uptake (VO2peak),submaximal endurance capacity, muscle strength, patient-reported-outcomes including QoL and physical functioning.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Hematological cancer, e.g. AML, CLL, MM Scheduled for alloHCT at the University Clinic Heidelberg or other cooperation sites within the next 412 weeks Patients ≥ 18 years of age Sufficient German language skills Willing/ able to train at the provided exercise facilities twice per week and to take part in the scheduled testing Signed informed consent Heart insufficiency &gt; NYHA III or uncertain arrhythmia Uncontrolled hypertension Severe renal dysfunction (GFR &lt; 30%, Creatinine&gt; 3mg/dl) Reduced standing or walking ability Insufficient hematological capacity (either hemoglobin value below 8 g/dl or thrombocytes below 30.000/µL) Any other comorbidities that preclude participation in the exercise programs Engaging in systematic intense exercise training (at least 1h twice per week)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>stem cell transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>high intensity interval training</keyword>
	<keyword>resistance training</keyword>
	<keyword>physical fitness</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
</DOC>