<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02199795</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a small pilot randomized controlled trial which will enroll both subacute (&lt;6 mos) and chronic (&gt;6 mos) stroke survivors (n=18 total) with dorsiflexion weakness. The subjects will be stratified based on interval post-stroke and baseline level of motor impairment and then randomized to Contralaterally Controlled Neuromuscular Electrical Stimulation (CCNMES) versus control. The primary objective of this study is to compare the effect of 6-weeks of lower extremity CCNMES, applied in an anti-phase application, on motor impairment and functional mobility to a control group; the effect of interval post-stroke, subacute (early) versus chronic (late) post-stroke, will be assessed. The secondary objective is to determine the effect of 6-weeks of lower extremity anti-phase CCNMES on functional magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) cortical activation patterns using an ankle dorsiflexion paradigm. The specific use of functional MRI as an outcome measure is to explore a central mechanism for between-group differences. AIM 1: Determine the effect of lower extremity CCNMES, applied in an anti-phase application, on motor impairment and functional mobility in hemiparesis compared to a control group; assess the effect of application in the subacute (&lt; 6 mos, early) versus chronic (&gt; 6 mos, late) post-stroke period. Hypothesis: Subjects randomized to the lower extremity CCNMES group will achieve greater improvement in motor impairment and functional mobility as compared to the control group; subjects in the subacute post-stroke period will achieve greater improvement than subjects in the chronic post-stroke period. AIM 2: Demonstrate change in functional MRI activation patterns using an ankle dorsiflexion paradigm following the lower extremity anti-phase CCNMES intervention. Hypothesis: Subjects randomized to the anti-phase CCNMES group will demonstrate change in functional MRI cortical activation patterns which differs from the control group; subjects in subacute post-stroke period will demonstrate change in functional MRI activation patterns that are distinct from change noted in chronic subjects. AIM 3: Define a central mechanism for post-stroke motor and functional recovery associated with lower extremity anti-phase CCNMES. Hypothesis: Change in functional MRI cortical activation patterns following anti-phase CCNMES intervention will correlate with change in motor impairment and functional mobility.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Functional Electrical Stimulation Mediated Neuroplasticity: Lower Extremity CCNMES in Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paresis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 21 to 75 years Minimum of 2 wks from a first clinical nonhemorrhagic or hemorrhagic stroke Medically stable Unilateral lower extremity hemiparesis Ankle dorsiflexor strength of ≤4/5 on the Medical Research Council scale, while seated NMES of the paretic ankle dorsiflexors produces ankle dorsiflexion to neutral without pain. Full voluntary ROM of the contralateral ankle Skin intact on bilateral lower extremities Able to don the NMES system or caregiver available to assist with device if needed. Able to hear and respond to stimulator auditory cues Able to follow 3stage commands Able to recall 2 of 3 items after 30 minutes Cognition and communication adequate for safe use of the device based on neurological assessment by physician principal investigator Severely impaired cognition and communication History of peroneal nerve injury History of Parkinson's, spinal cord injury, traumatic brain injury, or multiple sclerosis Uncontrolled seizure disorder Uncompensated hemineglect (extinguishing to double simultaneous stimulation) Edema of the paretic lower extremity Absent sensation of paretic lower extremity Evidence of deep venous thrombosis or thromboembolism History of cardiac arrhythmias with hemodynamic instability Cardiac pacemaker or other implanted electronic system Botulinum toxin injections to any lower extremity muscle in the last 3 months Pregnancy Symptomatic peripheral neuropathy Current use of psychoactive medications (except selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor and serotoninnorepinephrine reuptake inhibitor antidepressants) Acetylcholinesterase inhibitor usage Unstable asthmatic condition Metallic implants (including clips and/or wires) Prosthetic heart valves Cardiac, renal or other stent History of claustrophobia Low visual acuity Body weight or body habitus not compatible to MRI machine Medical, psychological, or social concern identified by the principal investigator or coinvestigator which suggests inappropriateness of subject participation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>hemiplegia</keyword>
	<keyword>footdrop</keyword>
	<keyword>electrical stimulation</keyword>
</DOC>