<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02199236</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see what amount of radiation is safe to give to rectal or anal cancer patients who are being treated with a procedure called brachytherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose Escalation Trial of Endoluminal High-Dose-Rate Brachytherapy With Concurrent Chemotherapy for Rectal or Anal Cancer in Patients With Recurrent Disease or Undergoing Non-Operative Management</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anus Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed locally residual or recurrent cancer of the rectum or anus Prior pelvic EBRT Age &gt; or = to 18 years ECOG performance status 0, 1, or 2 At least 4 weeks from prior major surgery or radiotherapy Have undergone Surgical, Medical and Radiation Oncology evaluations to confirm : Eligible for infusional 5FU or capecitabine Will not undergo surgery for the study disease Able to receive HDR brachytherapy ANC ≥ 1.5 cells/mm3 and PLT ≥100,000/mm3 Adequate Renal function: Creatinine &lt;1.5 x the upper limit of normal (ULN) or calculated creatinine clearance of ≥ 50cc/min Adequate Hepatic functions: Bilirubin less than 1.5 mg/dL; (except in patients with Gilbert's Syndrome, who must have a total bilirubin less than 3.0 mg/dL) AST or ALT &lt;3xULN, or &lt;5x ULN if known liver metastases Normal Cardiac function: No active coronary artery disease; No New York Heart Association class II, III or IV disease; No arrhythmia requiring treatment Maximum tumor length of 7 cm at time of brachytherapy treatment start Women who are pregnant. Women of childbearing potential who are unwilling or unable to use an acceptable method to avoid pregnancy for the entire treatment period and after receipt of brachytherapy. Male subjects must also agree to use effective contraception during the treatment period and until 1 year after the completion of brachytherapy. Patients with any other concurrent medical or psychiatric condition or disease which, in the investigator's judgment, would make them inappropriate candidates for entry into this study. Patients on concurrent anticancer therapy other than that allowed in the study. Contraindications to general anesthesia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>High-Dose-Rate Brachytherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>oral capecitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>infusional 5-FU</keyword>
	<keyword>Questionnaires</keyword>
	<keyword>14-104</keyword>
</DOC>