<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01363297</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Phase 1 portion of this study will assess the safety, tolerability and efficacy at increasing dose levels of inotuzumab ozogamicin in subjects with CD22-positive relapsed or refractory adult acute lymphocytic leukemia (ALL) in order to select the recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) and schedule. The Phase 2 portion of the study will evaluate the efficacy of inotuzumab ozogamicin as measured by hematologic remission rate (CR + CRi) in patients in second or later salvage status.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Evaluating Inotuzumab Ozogamicin In Acute Lymphocytic Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects with CD22positive ALL with either refractory disease (i.e. disease progression or no response while receiving their most recent prior anticancer therapy), or relapsed disease (i.e. response to their most recent prior anticancer therapy with subsequent relapse). Subjects enrolled in the Phase 2 portion of the study must be due to receive salvage 2 or later therapy. Subjects with Philadelphia chromosomepositive (Ph+) ALL must have failed standard treatment with at least one tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Adequate renal and hepatic function, and negative pregnancy test for women of childbearing potential. Subjects with isolated extramedullary relapse or active central nervous system (CNS) leukemia. Prior allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplant (HSCT) or other antiCD22 immunotherapy within 4 months, or active graft versus host disease (GvHD) at study entry. Evidence or history of venoocclusive disease (VOD) or sinusoidal obstruction syndrome (SOS).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Relapsed/Refractory Acute Lymphocytic Leukemia (ALL)</keyword>
</DOC>