<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01363908</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label study to assess the pharmacokinetics, safety, efficacy and tolerability of SSP-004184AQ. The study consists of two phases: the pharmacokinetic phase, using a single 16 mg/kg dose of SSP-004184AQ; and the chronic dosing phase, during which patients will receive an additional 48 weeks of SSP-004184AQ dosing. Two age groups will be studied: 6-&lt;12, and 12-&lt;18 years old. The study is designed to initially assess the pharmacokinetics and safety of SSP-004184AQ in older children (adolescents, 12-&lt;18 years old) and then if deemed safe, in younger children (6-&lt;12 years old).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Efficacy and Pharmacokinetics of an Oral Iron Chelator Given for a Year to Pediatric Patients With Iron Overload</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Pharmacokinetic Phase: Patients will receive a single 16 mg/kg dose of SSP-004184AQ in capsule form. Chronic Dosing Phase: Patients will receive SSP-004184AQ capsules daily for 48 weeks. Doses may range from 8-60 mg/kg/d.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thalassemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron Overload</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>beta-Thalassemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Parents willing and able to sign the approved informed consent for their children and subjects between the ages of 6 and &lt;18 years willing and able to provide their assent (based on institutional guidelines). Able to swallow whole capsules. Age &gt;6 and &lt;18 years. Transfusiondependent subjects who have transfusional iron overload requiring chronic treatment with deferoxamine, deferasirox, or deferiprone. A transfusion dependent subject is defined in this study as one with a minimum transfusion history totaling more than 20 units of packed red blood cells OR a calculated iron load based on transfusion history of 200mg/kg AND a transfusion requirement of 7 or more transfusions per year; or, in subjects with sickle cell anemia, be iron overloaded but can be receiving transfusion exchange therapy in lieu of transfusions. In the opinion of the Investigator (and in consultation with the subject's parents), the subject is able to discontinue all existing iron chelation therapies for a minimum period of 15 days prior first dose of SSP004184AQ, for the initial pharmacokinetic period of 8 days (if applicable), and for up to 49 weeks if continuing into the chronic dosing phase. Subjects able to have an MRI must have: 1. liver iron concentration &gt;2 and &lt;30mg/g (dry weight, liver) by FerriScan® R2 2. cardiac MRI T2* &gt;10ms (Note: Subjects not able to have an MRI will be considered iron overloaded on the basis of serum ferritin only.) Serum ferritin &gt;500ng/mL at Screening. Mean of the previous 3 pretransfusion hemoglobin concentrations greater than or equal to 7.5g/dL. If appropriate, depending on age, female subjects of childbearing potential need to use a medically acceptable method for birth control from screening until 30 days after the last dose of the study drug. Females of childbearing potential must have a negative serum betaHCG pregnancy test at the Screening Visit and a negative urine pregnancy test at the Baseline Visit. Females of childbearing potential must agree to abstain from sexual activity that could result in pregnancy or agree to use acceptable methods of contraception. Exclusion Criteria As a result of medical review, physical examination (including height and weight) or Screening investigations, the Principal Investigator considers the subject unfit for the study. Iron overload from causes other than transfusional hemosiderosis. Severe cardiac dysfunction. Nonelective hospitalization within the 30 days prior to Baseline testing. Evidence of clinically significant oral, cardiovascular, gastrointestinal, hepatic, biliary, renal, endocrine, pulmonary, neurologic, psychiatric, or skin disorder that contraindicates dosing with SSP004184AQ. Evidence of significant renal insufficiency, eg, serum creatinine above the upper limit of normal or proteinuria greater than 1 gm per day. Known sensitivity to any ingredient in the SSP004184AQ formulation. Platelet count below 100,000/µL or absolute neutrophil count less than 1500/mm3 at Screening. ALT &gt;180 IU/L at Screening. Use of any investigational agent within the 30 days prior to Baseline testing. Pregnant or lactating females. Cardiac left ventricular ejection fraction a) Below the locally determined normal range in the 12 months prior to screening by echocardiography or MRI or &lt;50% at Baseline testing by MRI (echocardiograph is acceptable for LVEF if MRI information is not available).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Beta-Thalassemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Sickle Cell Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Transfusional iron overload</keyword>
	<keyword>Iron Overload</keyword>
	<keyword>Iron Chelation</keyword>
</DOC>