<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02941679</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A phase 3 study to evaluate efficacy and safety of HCP1202</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Efficacy and Safety Evaluation of HCP1202 in COPD Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is designed as a multi-center, double-blinded, randomized, phase 3 clinical trial to evaluate the efficacy and safety of HCP1202 compared to either treatment with HGP1011 or HCP0910 in COPD patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or Female adults aged ≥ 40 years. Patients diagnosed with COPD. Patients with FEV1/FVC &lt; 0.7 at screening. Patients with a postbronchodilator FEV1 &lt; 60% of the predicted normal OR Patients with a postbronchodilator FEV1 &lt; 80% of the predicted normal if COPD exacerbation is moderate or worse developed at least twice within the past year or hospitalization occurred at least once within the past year due to COPD exacerbation. Patients with COPD Assessment Test ≥ 10. Patients with a history (current or exsmokers) of smoking 10 packyears or more (e.g. 10 pack years = 1 pack/day x 10 years, or ½ pack/day x 20 years). Patients who understand the process of clinical trial and signed written informed consent. Patients with a current diagnosis of asthma. Patients with the following lung disorders that can affect the clinical trial, except for COPD: lung cancer, interstitial lung disease, thromboembolic pulmonary disease, moderate to severe bronchiectasis, sarcoidosis, pulmonary fibrosis, pulmonary hypertension, active tuberculosis, clinically significant tuberculous destroyed lung, alpha1antitrypsin deficiency, etc. Patients underwent pulmonary lobectomy or lung volume reduction surgery within the past year. Patients who developed COPD exacerbation where antibiotics and/or systemic corticosteroids and/or hospitalization is advisable within 4 weeks prior to Visit 1 or during Runin period (but, rescreening is possible 4 weeks after resolution of the COPD exacerbation occurred within 4 weeks prior to Visit 1). Patients who administered antibiotics for lower respiratory infection within 4 weeks prior to Visit 1 or during Runin period (but, rescreening is possible 4 weeks after resolution of COPD exacerbation occurred within 4 weeks prior to Visit 1). Patients who have changed the COPD treatment method within 12 weeks prior to Visit 1 (but, PDE4 inhibitor can be used until 4 weeks prior to Visit 1). Patients administered systemic corticosteroids within 4 weeks prior to Visit 1. Patients with the following clinically significant cardiovascular diseases: a history of myocardial infarction or unstable angina within 6 months prior to Visit 1, a history of unstable arrhythmia where its therapy method has been changed within 1 year prior to Visit 1, a history of hospitalization from NYHA Class IIIIV heart failure, a history of atrial fibrillation, negative cardiac tachycardia, and/or hypertrophic cardiomyopathy. Patients with a history of long QTc syndrome. Patients with the clinical significance of ECG abnormality at screening (QTc(F) ≥ 470 ms). Patients who require longterm oxygen therapy for more than 12 hours a day. Patients participated in acute respiratory rehabilitation within 6 months prior to Visit 1 (except for the patients under stabilized respiratory rehabilitation therapy of at least 6 weeks).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>