<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00603083</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether the investigator standardized pain treatment plus local pain treatment is more effective than the investigator standardized pain treatment plus placebo in total hip arthroplasty.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Postoperative Pain Treatment in Total Hip Arthroplasty: A Study to Assess the Effect of Local Analgesia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketorolac</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketorolac Tromethamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Scheduled for an uncemented unilateral Total Hip Replacement because of osteoarthritis Willingness and possibility to follow the instructions of the study 18 years or older written informed consent and authority after it has been read and understood. Operation with anterior approach or using navigation Do not understand or speech danish Can not use the painscore Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) Special indications for Total Hip Replacement Anaesthetized in general anaesthesia where a tube is demanded Daily use of strong opioids, based on the investigators assessment Fertile women ASAscore: 3 and 4 Known allergy against the standardized pain treatment, the study drugs and placebo, Ropivacaine, Ketorolac, Adrenalin. Treatment with Lithium, Dihydroergotamin, full anticoagulant treatment or MAOinhibitor Following illness: Active gastric ulcer or earlier gastrointestinal bleeding, ulceration or perforation of any kind. Suspicions of manifest gastrointestinal bleeding and/or cerebrovascular bleeding Haemorrhagic diathesis Coagulation disorder Severe thrombocytopenia Severe heart insufficiency Severe risk of postoperative bleeding or delayed haemostatic Myocardium hypertrophy or ischaemic heart disease Hypertension Hypovolemics Anhydration angiooedema Asthma Bronchospasm Severe liver insufficiency Rhinostenosis because of polyostotic Narrowangled glaucoma Phaeochromocytoma Low plasmpotassium Thyreotoxicosis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hip Arthroplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment Outcome</keyword>
	<keyword>Local Anesthesia</keyword>
</DOC>