<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02893657</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the present study is the evaluation of the occurrence and effect of hepatic dysfunction on outcome following cardiac surgery, as well as the monitoring of changes in liver haemodynamics in the early postoperative period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Role and Dynamics of Liver Dysfunction in Patients Undergoing Cardiac Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Prospective, consecutive study of patients undergoing cardiac surgery in Heart and Vascular Center, Semmelweis University, Budapest. Registered data: - Anamnestic and demographic data - Liver dysfunction prior surgery, etiology of liver dysfunction - Perioperative clinical data: laboratory tests, imaging, haemodynamic measures - risk prediction score of the American Society of Anesthesiologists(ASA), EUROpean System for Cardiac Operative Risk Evaluation (EuroScore), Acute Physiology and Chronic Health Evaluation II (APACHE II), Simplified Acute Physiology Score (SAPS II), Canadian Cardiovascular Society grading of angina pectoris (CCS) - Model for End-Stage Liver Disease (MELD), MELD excluding International Normalised Ratio (INR) (MELD-XI), modified MELD score (modMELD), Child-Pugh The occurrence and etiology pattern of hepatic impairment are going to be evaluated according to age and type of cardiac illness. Correlations between perioperative haemodynamical alterations and structural, functional changes in hepatic status will be investigated. The impact of hepatic impairment on surgical outcome is going to be examined by multivariate regression models.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients over 18 years of age admitted for elective cardiac surgical procedures Not willing to participate. Pregnant women. During active psychiatric hospital care. Patients with defined legal incapability or limited capability. Nonevaluable patient due to insufficient clinical information Patients with a transplanted heart.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>MELD score</keyword>
	<keyword>hemodynamics</keyword>
	<keyword>liver abnormalities</keyword>
</DOC>