<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02893514</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will develop a clinical decision support tool that assists primary care providers in carrying out substance use interventions, and then compare (in Phase 2) two clinical scenarios, screening only (SO) vs. SUSIT, (on dose of substance use brief intervention received) and changes in drug use at 3 and 6 months, among primary care patients. Investigators will develop the Clinical Decision Support (CDS) component and then test the full SUSIT approach, using mixed methods to assess its acceptability and adoption, and gathering preliminary data on its efficacy for reducing unhealthy drug use. CDS development is concurrent with the SO phase to avoid losing valuable time, but will be conducted at a secondary study site to avoid contaminating the SO condition.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Leveraging Technology to Address Unhealthy Drug Use in Primary Care Settings</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study has 3 specific aims: Aim 1 is to develop clinical decision support that assists primary care providers in carrying out a brief intervention. Aim 2 is to assess the impact of the SUSIT on dose of substance use brief intervention received by patients. Aim 3 is to gather preliminary evidence on the efficacy of the SUSIT approach for reducing moderate-risk drug use.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Substance use screening results (collected using the tabletbased screening tool) indicating current moderate risk drug use, based on a substance specific involvement score (SSIS) indicating current (past 3 months) use of at least one drug with a moderate risk level (SSIS 426), in the absence of any highrisk drug or alcohol use (SSIS 27+); Presenting for visit with a participating PCP Prior participation in the study (i.e. participation in the SO study phase would preclude participation in the SUSIT phase); Attending a formal addiction treatment program (not including informal treatment such as Alcoholics Anonymous, Narcotics Anonymous), in the past 3 months; Pregnant (based on selfreport).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug Use</keyword>
</DOC>