<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02893930</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II trial studies how well sapanisertib works in treating patients with pancreatic neuroendocrine tumor that has spread to other places in the body, does not respond to treatment, or cannot be surgically removed. Drugs such as sapanisertib may stop the growth or shrink tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sapanisertib in Treating Patients With Metastatic or Refractory Pancreatic Neuroendocrine Tumor That Cannot Be Removed by Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To evaluate overall response rate associated with sapanisertib (TAK-228) in patients with advanced pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors (PNETs). SECONDARY ENDPOINTS: I. To evaluate progression-free survival (PFS) associated with TAK-228 in patients with advanced pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors (PNETs). II. To measure the safety and tolerability of TAK-228 in patients with advanced PNETs. III. To evaluate disease control rate associated with TAK-228 in patients with advanced PNETs. IV. To measure duration of response rate associated with TAK-228 in patients with advanced PNETs. OUTLINE: Patients receive sapanisertib orally (PO) once daily (QD) on days 1-28. Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 3 months for 2 years and then every 6 months for 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuroendocrine Tumors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoid Tumor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Neuroendocrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenoma, Islet Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Islet Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have unresectable or metastatic, histologically confirmed low or intermediate grade (Klimstra Criteria) pancreatic neuroendocrine tumor Refractory disease to treatment with mTOR inhibitor Patients must have measurable disease Documented radiological evidence for disease progression (measureable or nonmeasurable) =&lt; 12 months prior to enrollment NOTE: If patient has had previous radiation to the marker lesion(s), there must be evidence of progression since the radiation; at least one measureable lesion as per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) Prior sunitinib permitted Prior or concurrent therapy with SSA is permitted; a stable dose at least 2 months prior to study start and must continue on the stable dose while receiving study treatment; SSA is not considered as systemic treatment Disease that is currently not amenable to surgery, radiation, or combined modality therapy with curative intent Recovered from adverse events to grade 1 or less toxicity according to Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events version 4.0 (CTCAE 4.0) due to agents administered previously NOTE: Chemotherapyinduced alopecia and grade 2 neuropathy are acceptable Patients must have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1 Leukocytes &gt;= 3,000/mm^3 Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1.5 x 10^9/L Hemoglobin &gt;= 9 g/dL Platelets &gt;= 100 x 10^9/L Total serum bilirubin =&lt; institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; 3.0 x ULN Serum creatinine =&lt; 1.5 X institutional ULN and creatinine clearance &gt;= 60 ml/min NOTE: Creatinine clearance must be calculated using the CockcroftGault equation Women must not be pregnant or breastfeeding; all females of childbearing potential must have a blood test or urine study within 7 days of registration to rule out pregnancy; a female of childbearing potential is any woman, regardless of sexual orientation or whether they have undergone tubal ligation, who meets the following criteria: 1) has not undergone a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy; or 2) has not been naturally postmenopausal for at least 24 consecutive months (i.e., has had menses at any time in the preceding 24 consecutive months) Women of childbearing potential and sexually active males must be strongly advised to use an accepted and effective method of contraception or to abstain from sexual intercourse for the duration of their participation in the study Patients must not have poorly differentiated neuroendocrine carcinoma, highgrade neuroendocrine carcinoma, adenocarcinoid, goblet cell carcinoid and small cell carcinoma Patients must not have radiotherapy, or major surgery within 4 weeks prior to study treatment start No hepatic artery embolization or cryoablation/ radiofrequency ablation of hepatic metastasis within 2 months of study treatment start Patients must NOT have previous or concurrent malignancy within 2 years; exceptions are made for patients who meet any of the following conditions: Adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, superficial bladder cancer OR Adequately treated stage I or II cancer currently in complete remission, or any other cancer that has been in complete remission for at least 2 years More than 2 prior systemic treatment regimens (including cytotoxic chemotherapy, targeted therapy, immunotherapy) Diabetes mellitus on active treatment, or subjects with either of the following: Fasting blood glucose (FBG) &gt;= 130mg/dL (mmol/L) OR Glycosylated hemoglobin measurement (HbA1c) &gt;= 7% Patients with a history of the following within =&lt; 6 months of study entry are not eligible: Ischemic myocardial event, including angina requiring therapy and artery revascularization procedures Ischemic cerebrovascular event, including transient ischemic attack (TIA) and artery revascularization procedures Requirement for inotropic support (excluding digoxin) or serious (uncontrolled) cardiac arrhythmia (including atrial flutter/fibrillation, ventricular fibrillation or ventricular tachycardia) New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III or IV heart failure Pulmonary embolism Patients with known significant active cardiovascular or pulmonary disease at the time of study entry are ineligible Patients with known manifestations of malabsorption due to prior gastrointestinal (GI) surgery, GI disease, or for an unknown reason that may alter the absorption of TAK228 are ineligible Patients with uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements, are ineligible Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)positive patients on combination antiretroviral therapy are ineligible Subjects taking strong cytochrome P450, family 3, subfamily A, polypeptide 4 (CYP3A4) and cytochrome P450, family 2, subfamily C, polypeptide 19 (CYP2C19) inhibitors and/or inducers should be considered with caution; alternative treatments that are less likely to affect TAK228 metabolism, if available, should be considered; if a subject requires treatment with 1 or more of the strong CYP3A4 and CYP2C19 inhibitors and/or inducers, the study doctor should be consulted</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>