<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02647801</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this trial is to test a novel network approach (Bringmann et al., 2013), which enables to investigate the complex, interdependent network of self-control and its influences in everyday life. By adding an intervention to the network, such as mindfulness training, it is also possible to explore the way mindfulness changes connection strengths between network variables. For six weeks, an ambulatory assessment and additional seven weekly laboratory sessions are conducted with 120 students from the Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz who are randomized to a control (n=60) or intervention condition (n=60). Pre and post measurement sessions take place to assess self-reported trait self-control and mindfulness and a behavioral measure of mindfulness (Levinson, Stoll, Kindy, Merry &amp; Davidson 2014). Participants of both the experimental and control condition come to five weekly lab meetings in which they fill out questionnaires to assess changes in self-reported self-control and mindfulness. But only participants of the experimental condition take part in weekly computer based mindfulness trainings. During the ambulatory assessment, participants complete questionnaires six times a day via mobile phones that are randomly prompted and answer questions about state self-control, motivation, affect, and current situation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Self-control and Mindfulness Within Ambulatorily Assessed Network Systems Across Health Related Domains</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>understanding and speaking German aged between 18 and 65 years knowledge about how to use a mobile phone psychological disease mental or somatic disability that could impair the usage of a mobile phone</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Network approach</keyword>
	<keyword>mindfulness</keyword>
	<keyword>self-control</keyword>
	<keyword>ambulatory assessment</keyword>
</DOC>