<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02088346</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose is to evaluate the effectiveness and safety profile of telemedicine consultation system in making decision on IV thrombolysis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acute Stroke Advancing Program Using Telemedicine</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The rate of intravenous thrombolysis with tissue-type plasminogen activator or urokinase for stroke patients was extremely low in China. It has been demonstrated that telestroke may help to increase the rate of intravenous thrombolysis and improve the stroke care quality in the local hospitals. The aim of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of decision making of intravenous thrombolysis via telemedicine consultation system for acute ischemic stroke patients in China This trial network consists of one hub hospital (Xijing Hospital) and 14 spoke hospitals in the remote area of Shanxi Province. The telemedicine consultation system is an interactive, 2-way, wireless, audiovisual system based on portable hardwares--tablet computer or smartphone. Before this study, we have been investigating the usual stroke care quality in the spoke hospitals without the guidance from the hub hospital, which will be used as the historical control of this study. After that, the teleconsultation system will be introduced.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients older than 18 years and less than 80 years Acute ischemic stroke Presenting to Emergency Department of spoke hospitals within 4.5 hours of stroke symptom onset National Institutes of Health Stroke Scale (NIHSS) between 4 and 25 Signed consent form by the patient or his relatives Time of symptom onset unclear Unlikely to complete study through 3month followup</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Thrombolysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Tissue plasminogen activator</keyword>
	<keyword>Urokinase</keyword>
	<keyword>Telemedicine</keyword>
</DOC>