<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02088827</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The rates of sedentary activity are increasing. Studies have shown that time spent on doing sedentary activities is an independent risk factor for cardiovascular disease. Prior studies have shown that interrupting inactivity improved the body's handling of blood glucose and gene expression. The investigators plan to explore this further by examining the effects of interrupting 4 hours of inactivity with 2 minutes of moderate intensity exercise every 20 minutes on the following metabolic parameters: blood pressure, cortisol, C-Reactive Protein, glucose and insulin levels.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Sedentary Behaviour on Metabolic Parameters</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There is a current trend towards increasing time spent in sedentary behaviour. More jobs are being automated, and more time is spent in front of a computer, playing video games and watching television.Current studies suggest that sedentary behaviour is an independent risk factor for cardiovascular disease. Increasing time spent in sedentary behaviour has been linked to all-cause mortality, markers of cardiovascular disease and metabolic syndrome. However, the data is mainly from cross-sectional studies and based on self-recall, limiting the ability to draw definitive conclusions. Current exercise guidelines recommend at least 150 minutes of moderate to vigorous intensity exercise per week. It may be difficult for some elderly people to meet these guidelines. Older adults with diabetes are already at a higher risk fo conditions that are affected by sedentary behaviour and may stand to benefit the most from intervention. This study proposes to study the effects of breaking up sedentary activity with moderate intensity exercise on multiple metabolic parameters in older adults with diabetes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>65 years of age or older type 2 diabetes managed with diet or oral hypoglycemic agents using insulin to manage diabetes baseline of presession blood glucose reading equal to or greater than 10 mmol/L any medical condition that would limit the ability to perform activity portion of the study people not comfortable exercising on a stationary bicycle subject answers yes to one of more of the questions in the Physical Activity Readiness Questionnaire</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Sedentary Behaviour</keyword>
	<keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Older Adults</keyword>
</DOC>