<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02304003</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary aim of this study is to investigate wether an evidence-based physiotherapy regimen is more effective than standard care in patients referred for arthroscopic surgery of the shoulder. It is hypothesized that a multimodal physiotherapy regimen will relieve pain, improve shoulder function and reduce the need for subacromial decompression surgery of the shoulder compared to standard care/wait and see controls.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of an Evidence-based Physiotherapy Regimen for Patients With Rotator Cuff Tendinopathy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There has been a fourfold increase in surgery rates for non-traumatic shoulder disorders , despite increasing evidence demonstrating that there is no difference in effect between physiotherapy based- and surgical interventions. The target population for this study is patients suffering from rotator cuff tendinopathy waiting for subacromial decompression surgery at a university hospital in Norway. During this waiting period , study participants will be randomly assigned to standard follow up or a physiotherapy regimen in primary care. We want to compare the effect of a structured physiotherapy regimen consisting of heavy slow resistance exercises, stretching, manual mobilization and low level laser therapy to standard follow up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Shoulder Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tendinopathy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Shoulder Impingement Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients on need for surgery ( placed at surgical waiting list at hospital or referred to surgery by their GP ) 1. Typical history with difficulties working with arms elevated over the head, and pain located in the upper segment of C5 dermatome. 2. Symptom duration of minimum 3 months. 3. Three or more reproducible signs of rotator cuff tendinopathy / subacromial impingement: Positive isometric abduction and/or lateral rotation (Ombregt, Bisschop &amp; Veer, 2003) Painful arc during active abduction (Ombregt, Bisschop &amp; Veer, 2003) Positive Neers sign (Neer, 1972 ; Tennent, Beach &amp; Meyers, 2003) Positive Jobes test (Jobe &amp; Moynes, 1982 ; Tennent, Beach &amp; Meyers, 2003) Positive HawkinsKennedy impingement test (Hawkins &amp; Kennedy, 1980) 1. Shoulder pain due to trauma, e.g. fall. 2. Reduced ROM consistent with adhesive capsulitis/frozen shoulder 3. History in combination with examination and tests (apprehension/relocation), giving reason to suspect pathological instability 4. Full thickness rupture of rotator cuff tendon 5. OA of the glenohumeral joint, Os acromiale with decreased space of the subacromial space, previous fractures in the shoulder complex or shoulder surgery on the symptomatic side. 6. Subjects with other comorbidity: Rheumatological or neurological disease, fibromyalgia or symptoms from the cervical spine 7. Subjects suffering from serious psychiatric illness. 8. Subjects unable to understand English or Norwegian. 9. Less than 3 positive reproducible sings of rotator cuff pathology / subacromial disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Shoulder tendinopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>Subacromial impingement syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Rotator cuff tendinopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>Supraspinatus tendinopathy</keyword>
</DOC>