<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01191190</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients who have relapsed/refractory CLL and require therapy as per iwCLL guidelines will be eligible. Subjects will receive a treatment with ofatumumab and HDMP for three consecutive 4 week cycles. The primary endpoint is to determine the complete response (CR) to therapy and the secondary endpoints will assess the safety and tolerability of the regimen, the impact of the treatment on progression free, treatment free, overall survival, and pharmacokinetics of ofatumumab. Patients will receive allopurinol for tumor-lysis prophylaxis and antimicrobial prophylaxis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ofatumumab and High-dose Methylprednisolone in Patients With Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients who have relapsed/refractory CLL and require therapy as per iwCLL guidelines will be eligible. Subjects will receive a treatment with ofatumumab and HDMP for three consecutive 4 week cycles. The primary endpoint is to determine the complete response (CR) to therapy and the secondary endpoints will assess the safety and tolerability of the regimen, the impact of the treatment on progression free, treatment free, overall survival, and pharmacokinetics of ofatumumab. Cycles 1-3 will be administered without scheduled interruption every 28 days for a total of 12 weeks of therapy. Patients will receive allopurinol for tumor-lysis prophylaxis and antimicrobial prophylaxis. Blood glucose levels will be monitored immediately after HDMP infusion by finger stick glucometry. Two months following completion of treatment a response assessment will occur per iwCLL guidelines. The treatment will be administered as outpatient, and each cycle will be four weeks in duration.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Previously treated patients with a diagnosis of CLL 2. Previous treatment with any monoclonal antibody or chemotherapy regardless of response as defined by the iwCLL Working Group Guidelines as evidenced by: progressive marrow failure as manifested by the development of, or worsening of, anemia and/or thrombocytopenia massive (i.e. at least 6cm below the left costal margin) or progressive or symptomatic splenomegaly massive nodes (i.e. at least 10cm in longest diameter) or progressive or symptomatic lymphadenopathy. progressive lymphocytosis with an increase of more than 50% over a 2month period or lymphocyte doubling time (LDT) of less than 6 months. autoimmune anemia and/or thrombocytopenia that is poorly responsive to corticosteroids or other standard therapy (See Section 10.2) 3. Constitutional symptoms, defined as any one or more of the following diseaserelated symptoms or signs: unintentional weight loss of 10% or more within the previous 6 months significant fatigue (i.e. ECOG PS 2 or worse, inability to work or perform usual activities), fevers higher than 100.5ºF or 38.0ºC for 2 or more weeks without other evidence of infection, night sweats for more than 1 month without evidence of infection 4. Subjects must be 18 years of age or older, male or female. 5. ECOG performance status of 02. 6. Subjects must be able to give informed consent. 7. Females of child bearing potential(FCBP)† must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 10 14 days prior to and again within 24 hours of starting treatment and agree to use a medically accepted contraceptive method for the duration of this study. 1. Hepatitis BsAg positive, Hepatitis BcAb positive, and Hepatitis C positive patients. 2. Known HIV positive patients. 3. Diabetics. 4. Patients with uncontrolled Autoimmune Hemolytic Anemia (AIHA) or autoimmune thrombocytopenia (ITP). 5. Screening laboratory values within these ranges: platelets &lt;50 x 109/L, neutrophils &lt;1.0 x 109/L, creatinine &gt;2.0 times upper normal limit,total bilirubin &gt;1.5 times upper normal limit (unless a known history of Gilbert's disease), ALT &gt;2.5 times upper normal limit (unless due to disease involvement of liver), alkaline phosphatase &gt;2.5 times upper normal limit (unless due to disease involvement of the liver or bone marrow) 6. Inability to provide informed consent. 7. Concurrent malignancy (excluding basal and squamous cell skin cancers). 8. Active fungal, bacterial, and/or viral infection. 9. History of peptic ulcer disease resulting in GI bleeding within the last 6 months. 10. Untreated metabolic disorders such as hypothyroidism and Cushing's disease. 11. History of steroidinduced psychosis. 12. Estimated life expectancy of less than 3 months by the investigator's best clinical judgment. 13. Serious medical condition that would render the subject medically unstable. 14. Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding. 15. History of Pancreatitis. 16. History of Diverticulitis. 17. Patients with known hypersensitivity to ofatumumab or known history of anaphylaxis to Rituximab or alemtuzumab. 18. Concurrent use of other anticancer agents or treatments. 19. Subjects who have current active hepatic or biliary disease (with exception of patients with Gilbert's syndrome, asymptomatic gallstones, liver metastases or stable chronic liver disease per investigator assessment).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Relapsed</keyword>
	<keyword>Refractory</keyword>
</DOC>