<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02910466</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic hypoparathyroidism is a life-long disease for which the chronic administration of rhPTH(1-84) is a potential treatment option. The group of subjects in the AAAE0544 core study has been taking rhPTH(1-84) for the treatment of hypoparathyroidism for up to 11 years. This study is designed to extend this experience and gain knowledge about how safe and effective rhPTH(1-84) is in patients with hypoparathyroidism over a long-term duration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Extended Use of Recombinant Human Parathyroid Hormone (rhPTH(1-84)) in Hypoparathyroidism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypoparathyroidism</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subjects that are currently or previously enrolled in the core study (AAAE0544) and have maintained uninterrupted therapy with rhPTH(184) (transient interruptions of up to 1 month continuously off treatment may be allowed). 2. Signed and dated informed consent form (ICF). 3. Adult men and women 18 to 85 years of age. 4. History of hypoparathyroidism for at least 12 months prior to rhPTH(184) treatment, defined by the requirement for supplemental calcium and/or active vitamin D to maintain serum calcium along with an undetectable or insufficient Parathyroid hormone (PTH) concentration. 5. Able to perform daily subcutaneous selfinjections of study medication (or have designee perform injection). 6. Willingness and ability to understand and comply with the protocol. Women must agree to pregnancy testing and acceptable methods of contraception, as detailed in the protocol. 1. The subject is treated or has been treated with any investigational drug, aside from rhPTH(184), within 30 days of consent. 2. As assessed by the investigator, the subject has a safety or medical issue that contraindicates participation in the study. 3. The subject and/or the subject's parent(s) or legallyauthorized representative(s) is unable to understand the nature, scope, and possible consequences of the study. 4. The subject is unable to comply with the protocol, eg, uncooperative with protocol schedule, refusal to agree to all of the study procedures, inability to return for evaluations, or is otherwise unlikely to complete the study, as determined by the investigator or the medical monitor. 5. The subject is pregnant or lactating. 6. Subjects who are at increased baseline risk for osteosarcoma such as subjects with Paget's disease of bone or unexplained elevations of alkaline phosphatase, subjects with hereditary disorders predisposing to osteosarcoma or subjects with a prior history of external beam or implant radiation therapy involving the skeleton.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>