<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02910206</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Elderly patients have high mortality and postoperative complications rate after surgery, especially postoperative cardiac complications. A meta-analysis revealed haemodynamic intraoperative events significantly increased the risk of postoperative cardiac complications.To limit the risk, optimize the intraoperative management of circulation is essential. Anesthetic drug may effect on the haemodynamic intraoperative, reduction of postoperative complications should aimed at choosing the optimal anesthetic drug with minimal effect on haemodynamic.So this study is to explore the comparative efficacy and safety of anesthetic drug (etomidate or propofol) in elderly patients</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Etomidate to Improve Outcome in Elderly Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Postoperative Complications</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Propofol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etomidate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sufentanil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisatracurium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atracurium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged between 65 and 80 years old. Patients who received laparoscopic gastrointestinal surgery under general anesthesia,expected duration of surgery between 1 and 4 hour. American Society of Anesthesiologists class I to III. Body Mass Index between 18 and 25 kg/m2. Patients who signed written informed consent Cerebrovascular accident occurred within the previous 3 months,such as stroke or transient ischemic attack Patients with serious hepatic dysfunction ( the serum level of alanine transaminase, conjugated bilirubin, aspartate transaminase, alkaline phosphatase or total bilirubin is 2 folds more than upper normal limit) or renal dysfunction(creatinine clearance rate less than 30 milliliter per minute). Diabetic patients with complication (diabetic ketoacidosis, hyperosmotic coma,all kinds of infection, macroangiopathy, diabetic nephropathy, retinopathy, diabetic cardiomyopathy, diabetic neuropathy, diabetic foot). Unstable angina and myocardial infarction occurred within the previous 3 months Preoperative blood pressure more than or equal to 180/110 mmHg Confirmed or suspected of narcotic analgesics abusing or long term using Taken corticosteroids or immunosuppressive agents for more than 10 days with the previous 6 months or had history of adrenal suppression or immune system disease. Patients with thyroid hypofunction. Patients with history of asthma. Patients with history of surgery within previous 3 months. Patients allergic or contraindicated to propofol or etomidate Patients participated in other study within the last 30 days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>etomidate</keyword>
	<keyword>propofol</keyword>
</DOC>