<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02388256</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: Patients who undergo laparoscopic surgical resection of colorectal cancer may experience various post-operative symptoms (e.g., pain, nausea and vomiting, and anxiety) and limitation of daily activities (e.g., walking capacity). There is also a risk of post-operative complications and a prolonged hospital stay due to complications. Patients who underwent surgical resection may have experienced chronic pain, anxiety/depression, or diminished quality of life. The physical, psychological, and functional aspects of patients' disorders imply the necessity of multidisciplinary care, including complementary or traditional medicines such as acupuncture. This study aims to assess whether acupuncture treatment, combined with an enhanced recovery program after surgery in an inpatient care setting is effective than only an enhanced recovery program after surgery. Objective: To assess the effectiveness and safety of acupuncture combined with an enhanced recovery program after surgery to reduce postoperative symptoms and improve functional recovery and the patients' quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acupuncture for Enhanced Recovery After Surgery in Patients Undergoing Laparoscopic Colorectal Cancer Resection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients undergoing elective laparoscopic surgery of colorectal cancer resection (right hemicolectomy, left hemicolectomy, anterior resection with primary anastomosis, and low anterior resection with loop ileostomy for fecal diversion) Patients aged 18 to 75 American Society of Anesthesiologists Grade 1 to 2 Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Grade 0 to 2 Written informed consents Pregnancy Inflammatory bowel disease Comorbidities that may affect outcomes of surgery (e.g., chronic kidney disease, chronic liver disease, cardiopulmonary failure, and diabetes with complications) Resection of other organs for radical removal of colorectal cancer Patients requiring enterolysis due to previous history of abdominal surgery Obstructive colorectal cancer Metastatic colorectal cancer Cognitive impairment that may affect the patient's ability to complete the outcome assessments Previous history of stroke Previous history of sensitive reaction to acupuncture Patients unable to cooperate with acupuncture treatments Pacemaker implantation Previous history of epilepsy Patients who have received Korean medicine treatments (acupuncture, moxibustion, cupping, or herbal medicine) within 2 weeks Patients who have participated in other trials within 3 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>colon</keyword>
	<keyword>colorectal</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>neoplasm</keyword>
</DOC>