<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00761007</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate the benefit of treatment with oral dose of Ibodutant (code: MEN 15596) on IBS symptoms and the safety and tolerability of this therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ibodutant for Relief of Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IRIS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) is a functional disorder characterised by chronic or recurrent abdominal pain or discomfort associated with altered bowel habits. This trial aims to evaluate the efficacy of Ibodutant in improvement of IBS symptoms through a daily oral administration, testing three dosages or placebo in IBS patients for 4-weeks. In each patient, the experimental clinical phase encompasses a screening/ 2-week run-in period (no study medication), followed by a 4-weeks treatment period and a 2-weeks treatment withdrawal period, for total study duration of 8 weeks in each patient.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female patients aged 18 70 years. 2. Clinical diagnosis of IBS . 3. For patients older than 50 years or patients with positive family history of colorectal cancer: normal results from colonoscopy or flexible sigmoidoscopy. 4. Use of appropriate contraceptive methods. 5. Normal physical examination or without clinically relevant abnormalities. 1. Patients with organic abnormalities of the gastrointestinal tract including history of colonic or major abdominal surgery, current or previous diagnosis of neoplasia, inflammatory bowel diseases, symptomatic gallbladder stone disease, diverticulosis/diverticulitis, ectopic endometriosis. 2. History of gluten enteropathy. 3. Lactose intolerance as assessed by response to diet 4. Diagnosis of ova or parasites, or occult blood in the stool in the previous 6 months. 5. Previous diagnosis of Diabetes Mellitus (either type 1 or 2) 6. Unstable medical condition. 7. Concomitant medication within 7 days prior to screening with drugs known to interfere with gastrointestinal motility and sensitivity. 8. Pregnancy or breastfeeding. 9. Patient not able to understand or collaborate throughout the study. 10. Participation in other clinical trials in the previous 4 weeks.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Bowel disease</keyword>
</DOC>