<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00761189</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of paliperidone extended-release (ER) in participants with schizophrenia (psychiatric disorder with symptoms of emotional instability, detachment from reality, often with delusions and hallucinations, and withdrawal into the self).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PaliperidoNe Extended-Release [ER] Dosing and Clinical Response in Acute Schizophrenia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label (all people know the identity of the intervention), multi-centric (conducted in more than one center), prospective (study following participants forward in time), single arm, and non-comparative study of paliperidone Extended Release(ER) in participants with schizophrenia. The total study duration will be approximately of 104 weeks per participant. The study consists of following parts: Screening (that is, 14 days before study commences on Day 1); acute Treatment phase (single-oral dose of paliperidone for 12 weeks, dose ranging from 3 to 12 milligram); Extension phase 1 (12 weeks) and Maintenance treatment which will be followed by additional Extension phase 2 and long-term maintenance treatment. Efficacy of the participants will primarily be evaluated by Clinical Global Impression-Improvement (CGI-I) scale score. Participants' safety will be monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paliperidone Palmitate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants with Clinical Global ImpressionSeverity (CGIS) score greater than or equal to 4 points (moderately ill) at Screening Childbearing potential women who consent to the consistent use of the acceptable contraception (oral contraceptive, contraceptive injection, intrauterine device, double barrier method and contraceptive patch) Participants who are capable of and willing to fill out the questionnaire for themselves Participants who are compliant with selfmedication or can receive consistent help or support Have schizophrenia diagnosis by Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, fourth edition (DSMIV) Participants with the past history of neuroleptic malignant syndrome (NMS) Participants with Treatment Resistance history who have failed to be properly treated with more than two other kinds of antipsychotic agents (at least 4 weeks of the therapeutic dose administration) Participants with severe (pathologic or iatrogenic) gastrointestinal stenosis or participants who can not swallow the drug whole (The study drug must not be chewed, divided, melted or grinded because it can impact the study drug release profile.) Participants who have been exposed to the study drug within one month before screening Participants with significant risk including suicide or aggressive behavior</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Paliperidone</keyword>
	<keyword>R076477</keyword>
	<keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
</DOC>