<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT00683488</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>This exploratory study adapt test combine cognitive behavioral treatment contingency management intervention alcohol and/or marijuana abuse use HIV-infected adolescent .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Integrated Treatment Marijuana Abuse HIV+ Youth</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Marijuana Abuse</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adolescents age 1624 year ( inclusive ) time inform consent/assent determine medical record review verbal verification refer professional HIVinfected aware status document medical record review verbal verification refer professional Receives service one three participate ATN clinic site community partner A score 2 great CRAFFT indicate possible alcohol marijuana use problem abuse Alcohol and/or Marijuana Use Abuse Disorder indicate SSPQX Appropriate outpatient intensive outpatient level care accordance American Academy Child Adolescent Psychiatry practice parameter decide site mental health provider consultation Drs . Brown EspositoSmythers Englishspeaking Ability willingness provide inform consent/assent study participation Satisfactorily understand nature study inform consent process document Consent Form Comprehension Assessment Questionnaire Presence serious psychiatric symptom ( e.g. , active hallucination , think disorder ) Visibly distraught ( e.g. , suicidal , homicidal , exhibit violent behavior ) Intoxicated influence alcohol substance time study entry</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Substance Abuse</keyword>
	<keyword>Adolescent community reinforcement approach</keyword>
	<keyword>Adolescent Risk Behavior Assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>Child Adolescent Services Assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive behavioral therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive Therapy Rating Scale</keyword>
	<keyword>Individual behavior therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Individual cognitive problem solve</keyword>
	<keyword>Motivational enhancement therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV-Positive Youth With Substance Abuse</keyword>
	<keyword>Complementary Therapies</keyword>
</DOC>