<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02649582</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this phase I/II trial, the primary objective is to determine overall and progression-free survival of patients with newly diagnosed glioblastoma when autologous Wilms' tumor 1 (WT1) messenger (m)RNA-loaded dendritic cell (DC) vaccination is added to adjuvant temozolomide maintenance treatment following (sub)total resection and temozolomide-based chemoradiation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adjuvant Dendritic Cell-immunotherapy Plus Temozolomide in Glioblastoma Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Glioblastoma multiforme (GBM), a microscopically infiltrative disease, is the most common malignant brain tumor worldwide. Despite optimized standard of care treatment median survival and prognosis remain poor with a median survival of only 15% and five year survival after diagnosis of 5%. In this single arm single centre phase I/II trial the investigators will determine the overall and progression free survival of patients with newly diagnosed GBM when autologous WT1 mRNA loaded dendritic cell vaccination is added to standard of care treatment. During two years of recruitment the investigators will include 20 patients with newly diagnosed, histologically verified glioblastoma (WHO grade IV) who have received a total or subtotal resection of the tumor. Patients who underwent prior radiation or chemotherapy or with a history of other malignancy will be excluded. In addition to standard of care consisting of adjuvant chemoradiation with temozolomide and temozolomide maintenance patients will receive an intradermal vaccination with autologous WT1 mRNA-loaded dendritic cells commencing 1 week after radiotherapy. The dendritic cell therapy product will be generated and administered in the Antwerp University Hospital, more specifically the Center for Cell Therapy and Regenerative Medicine (CCRG) and the Division of Hematology, both headed by Prof. Zwi Berneman. Recruitment will begin in December 2015. After 2 years of follow up overall and progression free survival analysis will be performed and this will be compared with the published data of standard of care treatment without vaccination. In addition the investigators will look for feasibility, incidence of adverse events and immunogenicity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Newly diagnosed, histologically verified glioblastoma (WHO grade IV) Aged ≥ 18 years Total or subtotal resection: Total resection: macroscopic complete resection as assessed by the neurosurgeon and absence of any residual contrastenhancing mass on postoperative (≤ 72h) brain MRI Subtotal resection: macroscopic complete resection as assessed by the neurosurgeon, but with residual contrastenhancement ≤ 2 cm³ on postoperative (≤ 72h) brain MRI Signed informed consent Willing and able to comply with the protocol as judged by the Investigator Estimated to start with chemoradiation ≥ 28 days and ≤ 49 days following surgical resection Adequate hematologic, renal, and hepatic function at time of screening: Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dL (transfusion is allowed to maintain or exceed this level) Monocyte count (Mo) ≥ 0.2 x 10^9/L Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.0 x 10^9/L Platelet count (PLT) ≥ 100 x 10^9/L Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x the upper limit of normal (ULN) Liverfunction values &lt; 3 x ULN No corticosteroid treatment ≤ 1 week before apheresis WHO performance status ≤ 2 Life expectancy ≥ 3 months as estimated by the Investigator History of another malignancy, except for adequately controlled basal cell skin carcinoma, squamous skin carcinoma, or carcinoma in situ of the uterine cervix Prior radiation or chemotherapy Any preexisting contraindication for temozolomide treatment Any preexisting contraindication for contrastenhanced brain MRI Pregnant or breastfeeding Documented immune deficiency or systemic immunesuppressive treatment Positive viral serology for HIV, HBV, HCV, or syphilis at time of screening Any other condition, either physical or psychological, or reasonable suspicion thereof on clinical or special investigation, which contraindicates the use of the vaccine, or may negatively affect patient compliance, or may place the patient at higher risk of potential treatment complications</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dendritic cells</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemoimmunotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Adjuvant therapy</keyword>
</DOC>