<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01113411</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The fracture of the proximal humerus represents 4% of the fractures encountered in clinics and it must be treated surgically. Thus, the aim of the surgical treatment is to maintain bone alignment, articular congruity, vascularization of the humeral head and provide a painless shoulder with satisfactory function. The objective of this study is to demonstrate the potential benefits of an early rehabilitation program on shoulder function.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Intensive Rehabilitation on Shoulder Function After Proximal Humerus Fracture</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female over 18 years Unstable fracture of the proximal humerus Twopart and threepart fractures according to the Neer classification Closed fracture Time between trauma and surgery less than or equal to 7 days Signing of consent form Stable fracture of the proximal humerus (not requiring surgery) Fourpart fracture on the Neer classification Fracturedislocation or fracture involving the articular surface Isolated fracture of the large or small tuberosity Pathological fracture Fracture associated with neurovascular lesions Bilateral fractures Fracture associated with long bones fracture Polytrauma Previous history of fracture or surgery to the ipsilateral proximal humerus Severe COPD Severe neuromuscular disorders (Parkinson, hemiparesis, myasthenia gravis, muscular dystrophy, etc. ...) Remote location of patient's home which makes it difficult to come to facility for followup visits Any medical condition making it impossible for the patient to perform the exercise program (Alzheimer, dementia, etc. ...) Man or woman incapacitated sign consent form Any other condition which prevents the assessor from fully monitoring the patient during study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>humerus fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>locked plate</keyword>
</DOC>