<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02012179</DOC>
	<brief_summary>SODIUM-HF is a multicenter clinical trial in ambulatory patients with chronic HF to evaluate the efficacy of a low sodium containing diet on a composite clinical outcome composed of of all-cause mortality, cardiovascular hospitalizations and cardiovascular emergency department visits. The hypothesis of this study is that patients following a low-sodium containing diet will have fewer clinical events (fewer hospital readmissions or emergency department visits, longer survival) than those randomized to Usual Care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SODIUM-HF: Study of Dietary Intervention Under 100 MMOL in Heart Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients recruited if they are 18+ years or older, with confirmed diagnosis of HF (both reduced and preserved systolic function are eligible), NYHA class IIIII, and willing to sign informed consent. Subjects will be excluded if: Average dietary intake of &lt;1500 mg/ day by a quantitative or semiquantitative method Serum sodium &lt;130mmol/L Renal failure (glomerular filtration rate &lt;30 mL/min) Hepatic failure Uncontrolled thyroid disorder Cardiac device (ICD or CRT) or revascularization procedure (PCI or CABG) in previous month or planned in next 3 months Hospitalization due to cardiovascular causes in previous 1 month Uncontrolled atrial fibrillation (resting heart rate &gt;90 bpm) Active malignancy Moderatesevere dementia Enrolled in another interventional research study Patients will be excluded, if in the opinion of the investigator, another condition exists that would preclude dietary compliance or compliance with the protocol.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diet</keyword>
	<keyword>Dietary sodium reduction</keyword>
	<keyword>Salt restriction</keyword>
	<keyword>Nutrition</keyword>
</DOC>