<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02012426</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the current study is to demonstrate that a commercial weight management diet (i.e. low energy density) influences satiation, hunger and satiety and leads to lower energy intake during ad-libitum meals and over a full day. We further seek to demonstrate the sustainability of this effect following 12- week weight loss on the weight management program. - We hypothesise that formulated (low energy) meals will lead to decreased hunger, greater fullness and reduced desire to eat compared to standard meals. - We hypothesise that the commercial weight management program will lead to greater weight loss compared to control program. - We hypothesise that formulated meals (high consumer acceptance) will improve hedonic control over eating (lower wanting for high fat food) - We hypothesise that the commercial weight management program will improve hedonic control over eating (reduced experience food cravings)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of a Multi-component Weight Management Program on Appetite, Food Preference and Body Weight</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>BMI of 28 45 kg/m2 Reporting an interest in weight loss, not actively participating in a commercial weight loss program, Not increased physical activity levels in the past 24 weeks Able to eat most everyday foods and fruits and vegetables Written informed consent to be given Significant health problems that could cause confounding effects between intervention and control. Taking any medication or supplements known to affect appetite or weight within the past month and/or during the study Pregnant, planning to become pregnant or breastfeeding History of anaphylaxis to food Known food allergies or food intolerance Smokers and those who have recently ceased smoking Participants receiving systemic or local treatment likely to interfere with evaluation of the study parameters Those who have previously taken part in a commercial weight loss program in the last 6 months? . Participants who work in appetite or feeding related areas Participants unable to consume foods used in the study Participants who have had bariatric surgery Participants with a history of eating disorder Presence of untreated hypothyroidism Inability to fully comply with intervention or study procedures Insufficient English language skills to complete study questionnaires</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>