<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01682629</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigative team's purpose for conducting this research is to improve effective and efficient translation and implementation of evidence based advanced life support practice to providers of care for children. This specific project aims to accomplish 2 major goals. The investigators aim to evaluate the utility of a debriefing script specifically designed to facilitate debriefing when used by novice Pediatric Advanced Life Support instructors during low and high realism simulation-based learning. Secondly, the investigators hope to evaluate the effectiveness of high realism simulation vs. low realism simulation in achieving PALS-based educational outcomes, such as knowledge and skill acquisition. The investigators hypothesize that SCRIPTED debriefing by novice instructors following low and high fidelity simulation-based learning will : 1. Improve the cognitive performance and knowledge of multidisciplinary team members as assessed by a cognitive performance tool and multiple choice testing compared with more traditional, NON-SCRIPTED debriefing; 2. Improve the behavioural, teamwork and communication skills of multidisciplinary team members as assessed by a validated assessment tool compared with more traditional, NON-SCRIPTED debriefing; The investigators hypothesize that HIGH REALISM simulation-based learning will: 1. Improve the cognitive performance and knowledge of multidisciplinary team members as assessed by a cognitive performance tool and multiple choice testing compared with more traditional, LOW REALISM simulation; 2. Improve the behavioural, teamwork and communication skills of multidisciplinary team members as assessed by a validated assessment tool compared with more traditional, LOW REALISM simulation;</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Examining the Effect of a Scripted Debriefing on Resuscitation Performance in Pediatrics</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria (Novice Instructors): senior residents (general pediatric, emergency medicine, pediatric subspecialty) in year three of training or above nursing staff, respiratory therapists or paramedics with greater than 5 years of clinical experience recent PALS certification within the past 2 years Inclusion Criteria (Team composition) 1 or 2 pediatric nurses, 2 physicians (residents/fellows in pediatrics, anesthesia, family medicine, emergency medicine, pediatric emergency medicine, pediatric critical care or pediatric anesthesia) and/or 1 pediatric respiratory therapist or 1 pediatric transport paramedic Exclusion Criteria (Novice Instructors): experienced instructors, defined as having taught three or more courses for healthcare professionals where simulation was followed by debriefing Exclusion Criteria (Team composition)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pediatric</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac</keyword>
	<keyword>Arrest</keyword>
	<keyword>Simulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Debriefing</keyword>
	<keyword>Realism</keyword>
</DOC>