<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02805374</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to evaluate the effect of food on the pharmacokinetics of a single oral dose of ASP1517 in non-elderly healthy adult male subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Food Effect Study to Evaluate the Pharmacokinetics of ASP1517</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Body weight: ≥50.0 kg and &lt;80.0 kg Bodymass index : ≥17.6 and &lt;26.4 kg/m2 Subject must agree to use two of the established contraceptive methods after informed consent acquisition through 84 days after the last administration of the study drug. Subject must agree not to donate sperm after informed consent acquisition through 84 days after the last administration of the study drug. Received or is scheduled to receive any investigational drugs in other clinical trials or postmarketing studies within 120 days before screening or during the period from screening to the hospital admission day of Period 1 Received or is scheduled to receive medications (including overthecounter [OTC] drugs) within 7 days before the hospital admission day of Period 1 Received or is scheduled to receive supplements within 7 days before the hospital admission day of the Period 1 Deviates from any of the normal range of blood pressure, pulse rate, body temperature and standard 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG) at screening or the hospital admission day of Period 1 Meets any of the criteria for laboratory tests at screening or the hospital admission day of Period 1. Normal ranges of each test specified at the test/assay organization will be used as the normal ranges in this study. Concurrent or previous drug allergies. Development of (an) upper gastrointestinal symptom(s) within seven days before the hospital admission day of Period 1. Concurrent or previous hepatic disease, heart disease, respiratory disease, gastrointestinal disease, renal disease, endocrine disease, cerebrovascular disorder, malignant tumor, retinal neovascular lesions and macular edema. A history of digestive tract excision. Previous use of hypoxia inducible factorprolyl hydroxylase inhibitors (HIFPHI) such as ASP1517 (FG4592), YM311(FG2216) or erythropoietin products. Excessive alcohol or smoking habit.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>44 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>ASP1517</keyword>
	<keyword>Food effect</keyword>
</DOC>