<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02805465</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a multicenter, prospective, randomized cross-over study to compare His Bundle Pacing (HBP) with Bi-Ventricular Pacing (BiVP) in HF Patients with AF who need atrial-ventricular node ablation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of His Bundle Pacing and Bi-Ventricular Pacing in Heart Failure With Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients who meet the inclusion and exclusion criteria will be enrolled into the study. In the study, both atrial-ventricular node(AVN) ablation and Cardiac Resynchronization Therapy (CRT) implantation are performed with HBP lead implanted and connected with the A port of CRT device. Followed with successful AVN ablation, HBP lead and CRT implantation, patients are 1:1 randomized into BiVP and HBP group for 9 months and then crossover for another 9 months. The primary end points of the study is the change of left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) in both HBP and BiV pacing group.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is at least 18 years old Subject or authorized legal guardian or representative has signed and dated the Informed Subject is expected to remain available for followup visits at the study center Subjects with heart failure NYHA Class IIIV Subjects with LVEF no greater than 40% Subjects with persistent atrial fibrillation or atrial flutter with uncontrolled ventricular rate Subjects with the width of ECG Q, R, S wave (QRS) complex &gt;120ms Subjects with life expectancy less than 3 years Subjects with mechanical right heart valve Subjects with primary valvular disease Subjects with heart transplant, or is currently on a heart transplant list Subjects who are pregnant, or of childbearing potential and not on a reliable form of birth control Subjects with significant renal dysfunction, as manifested by serum creatinine level &gt;2.5 mg/dl or ≥275 μmol/L or estimated glomerular filtration rate (GFR) ≤30 mL/min/1.72 m2, which is documented within the 30 days prior to enrollment or at baseline. Subjects with significant hepatic dysfunction, as evidenced by a hepatic function panel (serum) &gt; 3 times upper limit of normal, which is documented within the 30 days prior to enrollment or at baseline. Subjects with chronic or treatmentresistant severe anemia (hemoglobin &lt;10.0 g/dL), which is documented within the 30 days prior to enrollment or at baseline</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Heart Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Atrial Fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>CRT</keyword>
	<keyword>BiVP</keyword>
	<keyword>HBP</keyword>
</DOC>