<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01608568</DOC>
	<brief_summary>1.0 STUDY OBJECTIVE 1.1 PRIMARY OBJECTIVE - To compare two methods of polypropylene mesh attachment during robotic assisted laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy (RALSC): running technique using self-anchoring 1 barbed delayed absorbable suture (Quill™ SRS, Angiotech Pharmaceuticals, Inc. Vancouver, Canada) versus interrupted technique using 0 non-barbed delayed absorbable suture (PDS II™, Ethicon, Somerville, NJ, USA). 1.2 SECONDARY OBJECTIVE - To compare robotic assisted laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy anatomic failure rates at 6 months post-operative follow-up using self-anchoring 1 barbed delayed absorbable suture (Quill™ SRS, Angiotech Pharmaceuticals, Inc. Vancouver, Canada) versus 0 non-barbed delayed absorbable suture (PDS II™, Ethicon, Somerville, NJ, USA). The investigators will also assess mesh erosion rates, costs, and surgeon satisfaction rates. 2.0 HYPOTHESIS 2.1 Primary: 2.1.a. Attachment of mesh using the running technique with self-anchoring 1 barbed delayed absorbable suture (Quill™ SRS, Angiotech Pharmaceuticals, Inc. Vancouver, Canada) will be faster than the standard fixation interrupted technique using 0 non-barbed delayed absorbable suture (PDS II™, Ethicon, Somerville, NJ, USA). 2.2 Secondary: 2.2.a. Attachment of mesh using the running technique with self-anchoring 1 barbed delayed absorbable suture (Quill™ SRS, Angiotech Pharmaceuticals, Inc. Vancouver, Canada) will be less costly than the standard fixation interrupted technique using 0 non-barbed delayed absorbable suture (PDS II™, Ethicon, Somerville, NJ, USA). 2.2.b. Failure rates and mesh erosion rates for each technique will be equally low. 2.2.c. Surgeons will prefer the barbed running technique over the interrupted technique based on subjective surgeon satisfaction questionnaires.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Affixing Polypropylene Mesh Using Barbed Suture (Quill™ SRS) During Robotic Assisted Laparoscopic Sacrocolpopexy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Prolapse</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA &gt;18 years old Undergoing RALSC with or without other procedures for pelvic organ prolapse or incontinence Willing to return for followup visits Written informed consent obtained from each subject Must be having a robotic assisted laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy Decline to participate Pregnant or contemplating future pregnancy Unable to participate in the informed consent process</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sutures</keyword>
	<keyword>Pelvic Organ Prolapse</keyword>
	<keyword>Sacrocolpopexy</keyword>
	<keyword>Robotic Assisted Laparoscopy</keyword>
</DOC>