<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01608412</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study hypotheses to be tested in this study are: - Conversion to everolimus at 3 months post-transplantation is safe and effective; - Accurate noninvasive molecular diagnostic tests can replace biopsy at 3 months pre-conversion (for the diagnosis of subclinical cellular and/or humoral rejection, tissue fibrosis and calcineurin inhibitor-induced nephrotoxicity) in kidney transplant recipients; - Follow-up biopsy at 12 months post-conversion (for the diagnosis of tissue fibrosis) can be replaced with accurate noninvasive molecular diagnostic tests in kidney transplant recipients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Trial to Assess the Efficacy and Safety of the Conversion to Everolimus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients undergoing their first living or deceaseddonor kidney transplant who maintain a functioning graft 3 months posttransplant; Older than 18 years; Panelreactive antibodies lower than 20%; Baseline immunosuppression with tacrolimus, mycophenolate sodium (MPS) and prednisone at randomization at 3 months. eGFR &lt; 35 mL/min at randomization; Urine proteintocreatinine ratio &gt; 0.8 at randomization; Episode of acute rejection with Banff histological classification &gt; 1A in the first 3 months posttransplant; Cholesterol &gt; 350 mg/dL or triglycerides &gt; 400 mg/dL with therapy at randomization; Active infection at randomization; Chronic liver disease; Refusal to participate in the study; Contraindications to kidney biopsy; Biopsy findings at 3 months posttransplant including borderline rejection, cellular rejection or antibodymediated rejection.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>renal transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>everolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>tacrolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>molecular evaluation</keyword>
</DOC>