<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01835002</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the long term effects of transcorneal electrostimulation (TES) in patients with retinitis pigmentosa (RP). In a prior study (NCT00804102) the results of short term stimulation pointed to a positive effect on the visual field and other parameters. In this study, the patients will be stimulated with the OkuStim device for half a year and safety parameters will be measured.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Transcorneal Electrical Stimulation - Multicenter Safety Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Retinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinitis Pigmentosa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients with retinitis pigmentosa (rodcone dystrophy) after prescription of electrical stimulation by an ophthalmologist adult patients who are capable of giving consent, Visual acuity ≥ 0.02 because the electrode is to be positioned on the eye at home, the patient or his family members should have sufficient fine motor skills (assessment by the study physician) the patient must be capable of giving consent and a medical assessment that he/she is able to participate in the whole study according to the protocol diabetic retinopathy neovascularisation of any origin after arterial or venous occlusion after retinal detachment silicone oil tamponade dry or exudative agerelated macular degeneration macular edema all forms of glaucoma any form of corneal degeneration that reduces visual acuity systemic diseases that are difficult to control or manage, that could endanger the normal study schedule patients in a permanently poor general condition, which could hinder the regular attendance at control examinations in the clinic forms of mental illness related to the bipolar affective and schizoidaffective disorders, and all forms of dementia simultaneous participation in another interventional study or history of interventions whose effect may still persist</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>transcorneal electrostimulation</keyword>
</DOC>