<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01835951</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Simulation-based training is essential in learning or maintaining skills in high risk industry such as aviation and railway and in the medical field like anaesthesia. Debriefing following simulation is fundamental in order to reduce the emotional impact of the session and to asses the technical and non-technical skills (behavior). Even if the ideal debriefing method is still to be found, individual debriefing is considered as the gold standard but time consuming. The DEBRIEF-SIM study is a prospective, single blinded, multicentric and randomized study that will compare the individual (defined by learning couple resident and nurse) approach to a grouped (several couples) debriefing. The primary end point is to define the noninferiority of this approach compared to the individual one on the educational impact. The learners will be debriefed according to their randomization after the first session, but will all undergo individual debriefing following the second session.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Individual Versus Grouped Debriefing Approaches in Anaesthesia Crisis Simulation-Based Training. What Impact On The Technical Score ?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Individual debriefing consists in a individual meeting between each subject of the study and the investigator to analyze the management of the anaesthesia crisis simulated. Grouped debriefing consists in the analysis by the investigator of the management of the anaesthesia crisis simulated in the presence of all the subjects included in the Grouped Debriefing group.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Doctor: resident in anesthesia and intensive care CHU Besançon and Dijon Student nurse anesthetist: Student nurse anesthesist 1st or 2nd year of school Besançon and Dijon Subjects incapable of giving consent: incapacitated (subjects under guardianship), minors (&lt; 18 years) Refusal to participate in the study Refusal to sign the confidentiality clause</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Simulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Debriefing</keyword>
	<keyword>Anaesthesia Crisis Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac Arrest</keyword>
	<keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
</DOC>