<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01835015</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and serum pharmacokinetics of CLG561 in subjects with advanced age-related macular degeneration (AMD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetics of CLG561 in Patients With Advanced Age-Related Macular Degeneration</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Subjects were divided into 5 cohorts, with the subjects in each cohort being administered a single IVT dose of CLG561 in 1 of 5 concentration levels A-E, where A=lowest and E=highest. All subjects received active CLG561. Progress from one cohort to the next was time-lagged to allow for safety review. Dosing was also time-lagged within each cohort. Only one eye (designated as the study eye) was dosed per subject. Post-dose safety assessments and ocular examination occurred immediately after the IVT injection and continued throughout the outpatient visits at pre-determined timepoints. Collection of post-injection blood samples began after the IVT injection at pre-determined timepoints. Subjects were followed for up to 84 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of agerelated macular degeneration in study eye, as specified in protocol. Poor visual acuity in study eye, as specified in protocol. Willing to receive meningitis and pneumonia vaccinations at least 2 weeks prior to study treatment. Females must be postmenopausal and/or surgically sterile. Other protocoldefined inclusion criteria may apply. Treatments to the study eye within 28 days prior to study treatment, as specified in protocol. Any disease or medication expected to cause systemic or ocular immunosuppression. Participation in another interventional clinical study or use of any experimental treatment for AMD within 12 weeks prior to study treatment. Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>First in human</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Tolerability</keyword>
	<keyword>Serum PK</keyword>
	<keyword>Intravitreal (IVT)</keyword>
	<keyword>Age-related macular degeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>AMD</keyword>
	<keyword>Geographic Atrophy</keyword>
	<keyword>Choroidal neovascularization</keyword>
</DOC>