<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02396784</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Early STOPP project promotes good health in children from early age by supporting good habits for the whole family. Our aim is to see if we can prevent overweight and obesity in children in families where parents are overweight or obese. Normal weight parents will also be needed in this study. Background: Several daily habits lead to less favorable health factors. For example, using the car instead of cycling or walking - leads to less activity in everyday life. Individuals also eat more unhealthy foods in larger portions. In combination with genetics, social in heritage and surrounding factors this contributes to increase overweight and obesity among children not only in adults but also in children. Good treatment for childhood obesity are lacking, making prevention very important. The earlier good habits are introduced to a child the better it is. In Early STOPP project we study food, physical activity and sleep habits in the families with a child of one year of age. The height, weight, waist circumference and blood pressure will be recorded in both child and parents. The parents will answer questionnaires about food, physical activity and sleeping habits for both the child and themselves. During the study, the child's physical activity will be measured. Based on our observations we aim to develop the preventive strategies for the families with very young children.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Early Stockholm Obesity Prevention Program (EarlySTOPP-China)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>one obese or two overweight parents, 1 year old child weight effecting diseases</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>child overweight</keyword>
	<keyword>child obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>targeted intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>development of overweight</keyword>
</DOC>