<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="29396">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02724020</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>C31005</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2015-002133-22</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>U1111-1172-1808</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02724020</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>MLN0128 and MLN0128 + MLN1117 Compared With Everolimus in the Treatment of Adults With Advanced or Metastatic Clear-Cell Renal Cell Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Open-label Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Single-Agent MLN0128 and the Combination of MLN0128+MLN1117 Compared With Everolimus in the Treatment of Adult Patients With Advanced or Metastatic Clear-Cell Renal Cell Carcinoma That Has Progressed on Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor-Targeted Therapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Millennium Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Takeda</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will evaluate the efficacy and safety of single-agent MLN0128 and the combination
      of MLN0128 + MLN1117 compared with everolimus in the treatment of participants with
      metastatic clear-cell renal cell carcinoma (mccRCC) that have progressed on vascular
      endothelial growth factor (VEGF)-targeted therapy.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The drugs being tested in this study are called MLN0128 and MLN1117. MLN0128 and MLN1117 are
      being tested to treat people who have mccRCC. This study will assess the efficacy and safety
      of MLN0128 and MLN1117 as well as how it is processed by the body in participants with
      advanced or mccRCC.

      The study will enroll approximately 189 participants. Participants will be randomly assigned
      (by chance, like flipping a coin) to one of the three treatment groups:

        -  Everolimus 10 mg once daily (QD)

        -  MLN0128 30 mg once weekly (QW)

        -  MLN0128 4 mg + MLN1117 200 mg QD x 3 days per week

      All participants will be asked to take the study drug at the same time on each scheduled
      day.

      This multi-center trial will be conducted worldwide. The overall time to participate in this
      study is 2 years after last participant is randomized, or when the last participant
      discontinues study treatment (approximately 3 years). Participants will make multiple visits
      to the clinic including a follow-up visit 30 to 40 days after receiving their last dose of
      study drug or prior to start of subsequent anticancer therapy for safety assessment.
      Participants will then be followed for Progression Free and Overall Survival.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-Free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose of study drug to disease progression or death (approximately 3 years)</time_frame>
    <description>PFS is defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of first documentation of Progressive Disease (PD) according to Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) Version 1.1 or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first. For a participant whose disease has not progressed and is last known to be alive, PFS will be censored at the last response assessment that is Stable Disease (SD) or better. PD is defined as at least a 20% increase in the sum of the longest diameter (LD) of target lesions, taking as reference the smallest sum LD recorded since the treatment started or the appearance of one or more new lesions.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose of study drug through 30 days after the last dose of study drug (up to 27 months)</time_frame>
    <description>An Adverse Event (AE) is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical investigation participant administered a drug; it does not necessarily have to have a causal relationship with this treatment. An AE can therefore be any unfavorable and unintended sign (eg, a clinically significant abnormal laboratory finding), symptom, or disease temporally associated with the use of a drug, whether or not it is considered related to the drug. A treatment-emergent adverse event (TEAE) is defined as an adverse event with an onset that occurs after receiving study drug.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose of study drug to death (approximately 3 Years)</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival is defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of death. Participants without documentation of death at the time of analysis will be censored at the date last known to be alive.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time-to-progression (TTP)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose of study drug until disease progression, or death which occurs first (approximately 3 Years)</time_frame>
    <description>Time-to-progression is defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of first documentation of PD. For a participant whose disease has not progressed, TTP will be censored at the last response assessment that is Stable Disease or better. PD is defined as at least a 20% increase in the sum of the LD of target lesions, taking as reference the smallest sum LD recorded since the treatment started or the appearance of one or more new lesions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose of study drug until discontinuation of study drug due to disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, or death which occurs first (approximately 24 months)</time_frame>
    <description>ORR is defined as the percentage of participants who achieve a best response of complete response (CR) or partial response (PR) according to RECIST Version 1.1. CR is defined as the disappearance of all target lesions, non-target lesions, and normalization of tumor marker level. PR is defined as at least a 30% decrease in the sum of longest diameter (LD) of target lesions taking as reference the Baseline sum LD.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Benefit Rate (CBR)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose study drug until discontinuation of study drug due to disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, or death which occurs first (approximately 24 months)</time_frame>
    <description>CBR is defined as the percentage of participants who achieve a best response of complete response (CR), partial response (PR) or stable disease (SD) according to RECIST Version 1.1 and will be reported for both CBR with any duration SD and CBR with SD duration of at least 4 months. CR is defined as the disappearance of all target lesions, non-target lesions, and normalization of tumor marker level. PR is defined as at least a 30% decrease in the sum of longest diameter (LD) of target lesions taking as reference the Baseline sum LD. SD is defined as neither sufficient shrinkage to qualify for PR nor sufficient increase to qualify for PD, taking as reference the smallest sum LD since the treatment started.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">189</enrollment>
  <condition>Clear-cell Metastatic Renal Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Everolimus 10 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Everolimus 10 mg, capsules, orally, once daily (QD) in a 28-day cycle until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, consent withdrawal, or death up to 24 months, or longer upon discussion with the investigator and the sponsor if the patient is believed that the patient would derive benefit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MLN0128 30 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>MLN0128 30 mg, capsules, orally, once weekly (QW) on Days 1, 8, 15, and 22 of a 28-day cycle until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, consent withdrawal, or death up to 24 month or longer upon discussion with the investigator and the sponsor if the patient is believed that the patient would derive benefits.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MLN0128 4 mg + MLN1117 200 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>MLN0128 4 mg, capsules, orally, QD 3 days per week and MLN1117 200 mg, capsules, orally, QD 3 days per week on Days 1-3, 8-10, 15-17 and 22-24 of a 28-day cycle until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, consent withdrawal, or death up to 24 months or longer upon discussion with the investigator and the sponsor if the patient is believed that the patient would derive benefit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Everolimus</intervention_name>
    <description>Everolimus capsules</description>
    <arm_group_label>Everolimus 10 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MLN0128</intervention_name>
    <description>MLN0128 capsules</description>
    <arm_group_label>MLN0128 30 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MLN0128 4 mg + MLN1117 200 mg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TAK-228</other_name>
    <other_name>INK0128</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MLN1117</intervention_name>
    <description>MLN1117 capsules</description>
    <arm_group_label>MLN0128 4 mg + MLN1117 200 mg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TAK-117</other_name>
    <other_name>INK1117</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Male or female participants aged 18 years or older.

          2. Histologically confirmed renal cell carcinoma with a clear-cell component.

          3. Evidence that the renal cell carcinoma is advanced or metastatic.

          4. Radiologic evidence of progressive disease (according to [RECIST Version 1.1) either
             during or within 6 months after stopping their most recent systemic therapy for RCC
             before enrollment into this study.

          5. At least 1, prior line of VEGF-targeted therapy, but not more than 4 total prior
             lines of systemic therapy. Exposure to more than 1 line of VEGF-targeted therapy is
             acceptable. Participants may also have received prior therapies with interferon,
             interleukin 2 (IL-2), anti-PD1 antibodies, cabozantinib or other experimental agents,
             but not prior therapy with any agent that targets phosphoinositide 3-kinase (PI3K) ,
             serine/threonine-specific protein kinase (AKT), or mechanistic (or mammalian) target
             of rapamycin (mTOR).

          6. Karnofsky Performance Status (KPS) ≥70%.

          7. Life expectancy of ≥3 months.

          8. Female participants who:

               -  Are postmenopausal for at least 1 year before the screening visit, OR

               -  Are surgically sterile, OR

               -  If they are of childbearing potential, agree to practice 1 highly effective
                  method of contraception, and 1 additional effective (barrier) method, at the
                  same time, from the time of signing the informed consent through 90 days (or
                  longer, as mandated by local labeling [eg, United States Prescribing Information
                  (USPI), Summary of Product Characteristics (SmPC), etc;]) after the last dose of
                  study drug, OR

               -  Agree to practice true abstinence, when this is in line with the preferred and
                  usual lifestyle of the participant. (Periodic abstinence [eg, calendar,
                  ovulation, symptothermal, postovulation methods],withdrawal, spermicides only,
                  and lactational amenorrhea are not acceptable methods of contraception. Female
                  and male condoms should not be used together.)

             Male participants, even if surgically sterilized (ie, status postvasectomy), who:

               -  Agree to practice highly effective barrier contraception during the entire study
                  treatment period and through 120 days after the last dose of study drug (or
                  longer, as mandated by local labeling [eg, USPI, SmPC, etc]), OR

               -  Agree to practice true abstinence, when this is in line with the preferred and
                  usual lifestyle of the participant (Periodic abstinence [eg, calendar,
                  ovulation, symptothermal, postovulation methods for the female partner],
                  withdrawal, spermicides only, and lactational amenorrhea are not acceptable
                  methods of contraception. Female and male condoms should not be used together.)

               -  Agree not to donate sperm during the course of this study or within 120 days
                  after receiving their last dose of study drug.

          9. Suitable venous access for the study-required blood sampling.

         10. Screening clinical laboratory values:

               -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 2000/μL and platelet count ≥100,000/μL;

               -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 2.5 X the
                  upper limit of normal (ULN);

               -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 X ULN;

               -  Estimated creatinine clearance by Cockcroft-Gault ≥40 mL/min/1.73m^2;

               -  Glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1c) &lt;7.0%, fasting serum glucose ≤ 130 mg/dL, and
                  fasting triglycerides ≤ 300 mg/dL.

         11. At least 14 days since the end of prior systemic VEGF-targeted treatment (ie,
             sunitinib, pazopanib, axitinib, or sorafenib), radiotherapy, or surgical procedure
             with resolution of all treatment-related toxicity (except alopecia and
             hypothyroidism) either to Grade 0 or 1 (National Cancer Institute Common Terminology
             Criteria for Adverse Events [NCI CTCAE] Version 4.03) or to baseline.

         12. At least 21 days since the last dose of bevacizumab, other antibody, or interferon.

         13. Voluntary written consent given before performance of any study-related procedure not
             part of standard medical care, with the understanding that consent may be withdrawn
             by the participant at any time without prejudice to future medical care.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Central nervous system (CNS) metastasis.

          2. Other clinically significant co-morbidities, such as uncontrolled pulmonary disease,
             active CNS disease, active infection, or any other condition that might compromise
             the participant's participation in the study.

          3. Known human immunodeficiency virus infection.

          4. Known hepatitis B surface antigen-positive, or known or suspected active hepatitis C
             infection.

          5. Treatment with strong inhibitors and/or inducers of cytochrome P450 (CYP) 3A4,
             CYP2C9, or CYP2C19 within 1 week preceding the first dose of study drug.

          6. Manifestations of malabsorption due to prior gastrointestinal (GI) surgery, GI
             disease, or for an unknown reason that may alter the absorption of everolimus,
             MLN0128, or MLN1117. In addition, participants with enteric stomata are excluded.

          7. Women who are either breast feeding or pregnant.

          8. History of any of the following within the last 6 months before administration of the
             first dose of study drug

               -  Ischemic myocardial event, including angina requiring therapy and artery
                  revascularization procedures;

               -  Ischemic cerebrovascular event, including transient ischemic attack and artery
                  revascularization procedures;

               -  Requirement for inotropic support (excluding digoxin), or serious (uncontrolled)
                  cardiac arrhythmia (including atrial flutter/fibrillation, ventricular
                  fibrillation, or ventricular tachycardia);

               -  Placement of a pacemaker for control of rhythm;

               -  New York Heart Association Class III or IV heart failure;

               -  Pulmonary embolism.

          9. Significant active cardiovascular or pulmonary disease including:

               -  Uncontrolled hypertension (ie, either systolic blood pressure &gt;160 mm Hg;
                  diastolic blood pressure &gt;95 mm Hg). Use of anti-hypertensive agents to control
                  hypertension before Cycle 1 Day 1 is allowed;

               -  Pulmonary hypertension.

               -  Uncontrolled asthma or oxygen saturation &lt;90% by arterial blood gas analysis or
                  pulse oximetry on room air;

               -  Significant valvular disease; severe regurgitation or stenosis by imaging
                  independent of symptom control with medical intervention; or history of valve
                  replacement;

               -  Medically significant (symptomatic) bradycardia;

               -  History of arrhythmia requiring an implantable cardiac defibrillator;

               -  Baseline prolongation of the rate-corrected QT interval (QTc; eg, repeated
                  demonstration of QTc interval &gt;480 ms, or history of congenital, long-QT
                  syndrome, or torsades de pointes).

         10. Diagnosed or treated for another malignancy within 2 years before administration of
             the first dose of study drug, or previously diagnosed with another malignancy and
             have any evidence of residual disease. Participants with nonmelanoma skin cancer,
             superficial bladder cancer, very low risk prostate on observation, or carcinoma in
             situ of any type are not excluded if they have undergone complete resection.

         11. Prior therapy with agents that target PI3K, AKT, or mTOR. Participants with known
             hypersensitivity to everolimus or rapamycin derivatives are also excluded.

         12. Any serious medical or psychiatric illness that could, in the investigator's opinion,
             potentially interfere with the completion of treatment according to this protocol.

         13. Participants requiring daily or chronic use of a proton pump inhibitor (PPI) and/or
             having taken a PPI within 7 days before receiving the first dose of study drug.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director Clinical Science</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Takeda</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Medical Information Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>+1-844-662-8532</phone>
    <email>GlobalOncologyMedinfo@takeda.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Myers</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>West Palm Beach</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Goshen</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Hackensack</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Chattanooga</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Worth</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Edmonton</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Winnipeg</city>
        <state>Manitoba</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Greenfield Park</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Brno</city>
        <country>Czech Republic</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Olomouc</city>
        <country>Czech Republic</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Prague 5</city>
        <country>Czech Republic</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Praha</city>
        <country>Czech Republic</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Bordeaux cedex</city>
        <state>Gironde</state>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Suresnes Cedex</city>
        <state>Hauts de Seine</state>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Rennes cedex</city>
        <state>Ille et Vilaine</state>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Herblain</city>
        <state>Loire Atlantique</state>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Vandoeuvre les Nancy Cedex</city>
        <state>Meurthe et Moselle</state>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Paris Cedex 10</city>
        <state>Paris</state>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Paris cedex 13</city>
        <state>Paris</state>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Paris Cedex 15</city>
        <state>Paris</state>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Le Mans Cedex 02</city>
        <state>Sarthe</state>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>La Roche sur Yon</city>
        <state>Vendee</state>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Meldola</city>
        <state>Forli - Cesena</state>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Bologna</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Napoli</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Padova</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Pavia</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Roma</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Bielsko-Biala</city>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Lodz</city>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Poznan</city>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Warszawa</city>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Wroclaw</city>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Oviedo</city>
        <state>Asturias</state>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>L'Hospitalet de Llobregat</city>
        <state>Barcelona</state>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Lugo</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Exeter</city>
        <state>Devon</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Greater London</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Manchester</city>
        <state>Greater Manchester</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Liverpool</city>
        <state>Norfolk</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Cardiff</city>
        <state>South Glamorgan</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Swansea</city>
        <state>South Glamorgan</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Guildford</city>
        <state>Surrey</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Czech Republic</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Poland</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 2, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 25, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Drug Therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endothelial Growth Factors</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
