<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="29324">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02724956</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HSC-MS-14-0970</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02724956</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ambu Auragain Vs Teleflex LMA Supreme Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>AURAGAIN</acronym>
  <official_title>Randomized Comparison of Ambu Auragain and Teleflex LMA Supreme Using Clinical and Fibreoptic Assessments in Elective Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>No</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_ppsd>No</is_ppsd>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      SIGNIFICANCE

      Since the introduction of the first Laryngeal Mask Airway, the Classic LMA, the use of
      Supraglottic airway (SGA) devices has experienced a remarkable evolution, and SGAs are now
      routinely used in clinical anesthesia. Some of the newer SGAs have a built-in gastric
      drainage channel to facilitate efflux of gastric fluid and gas, and to allow the insertion
      of a gastric tube. These devices are referred to as &quot;Second Generation SGAs&quot;. One of the
      SGAs on the market is the LMA Supreme which is a single-use modification of the older,
      reusable LMA Proseal (Teleflex). The Supreme has a pre-curved rigid airway tube similar to
      the Ambu Aura SGAs. The concept of a curved airway tube is to imitate the airway anatomy
      during device placement, thus making insertion relatively easy and smooth. Due to the
      similarities between the AuraGain and the Supreme, a randomized, prospective clinical study
      with a detailed evaluation of the performance of these two devices will be conducted. A
      clinical evaluation of device insertion and function, both as a ventilatory device and an
      intubation conduit, oropharyngeal Leak Pressure (OLP), and functionality of the gastric
      drainage channel will be performed in elective patients with normal airway anatomy.
      Moreover, a fiberoptic assessment of the glottic view via the SGA device and signs of airway
      morbidity will be investigated.

      SPECIFIC AIMS

      The purpose of this study is to compare, the use of the Ambu AuraGain and Teleflex LMA
      Supreme regarding OLP, rate of successful intubation and ventilation, ease of SGA insertion,
      anatomical fit of the SGA, functionality of gastric drainage channel, and post-operative
      complications.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aims of Evaluation:

        -  Glottic view via SGA by fiberoptic assessment.

        -  SGA ease of insertion, Rate of successful intubation, functionality as a ventilation
           device.

        -  Functionality of gastric drainage channel &amp; intubation conduit.

        -  OLP - Oropharyngeal Leak Pressure.

        -  Post-operative complications &amp; airway morbidity

      CRF: Age, Gender, Height, Weight, BMI, Fasting time, ASA, Mallampati, TM, SM and
      Interincisor distance, lower jaw protrusion.

      aScope Preparation Procedures:

        -  Inspect scope for: damage, mechanical performance (110 ͦ flexion), monitor connection.

        -  Evaluate picture quality: (contrast, light), place 1 cm from black letters on white
           background.

        -  Lubricate insertion cord.

        -  Place lubricated ETT tube without ISO connector on proximal portion of insertion cord.

        -  When aScope fulfills functional criteria, place on prep. Table and turn off. Clean with
           alcohol wipe.

        -  Pre-lubricate the SGA

      Patient:

        -  Monitoring: 3 lead ECG / Pulse Oximetry / BP/ End-expiratory gas analysis

        -  Record @ Pre-induction, Pre-Oxygenation, Post-induction, post-SGA insertion, 10 min
           after, q15min, PACU

        -  Supine position

        -  Circuit filled w/ 100% O2, 10 L/m (EtO2)

        -  Preoxygenation by facemask (3min)

        -  Induction: Fentanyl 1 µ/kg IV &amp; Propofol 1.5-2.0 mg/kg IV

        -  Vital signs

        -  No evidence of eyelash reflex and assurance of mask ventilation

        -  Paralysis: Rocuronium 0.6 mg/kg IV

        -  Attach &quot;ToF&quot; Train of Four twitch monitor

      I. Adequacy of Device Placement and Ventilation

      Insertion of SGA:

        -  Sniffing Position.

        -  Lubricate posterior surface of SGA.

        -  T1 Start: tip of cuff touching patient's lips. T1 Stop: appearance of the first square
           end tidal carbon dioxide (ETCO2) trace.

        -  Place cuff at anterior hard palate, using index finger of dominant hand to push device
           into hypo-pharynx.

        -  During insertion- tip of cuff pressed upwards against hard palate and cuff flattened
           against it.

        -  Use Jaw lift technique if necessary.

        -  Confirm placement of SGA: teeth between bite absorption marks indicated on proximal end
           of SGA &amp; Quantitative waveform capnography.

        -  No appearance of CO2 curve suggests incomplete placement of SGA. Remove SGA and
           Re-attempt.

        -  An insertion ATTEMPT is when the SGA touches the patient's lips to the first complete
           CO2 trace.

        -  A FAILED insertion is the need for &gt; 3 attempts or if the entire process exceeds 180
           seconds.

        -  Inflate SGA cuff to 60 cm H2O (aneroid manometer). *Note* volume of air.

        -  Secure SGA to patient's cheek w/ tape.

        -  Record position optimizing maneuvers: adjustments to head/neck, additional jaw lift,
           depth of insertion, lateral insertion technique, changing size of SGA.

      Fiber-optic evaluation of the SGAs anatomical position:

        -  Determine laryngeal view after ventilation achieved.

        -  Record Maximal optical view; POGO score and presence of blood.

        -  If epiglottis is down-folded, perform jaw lift, and reassess POGO.

        -  Use channel of aScope to remove secretions, blood or debris.

        -  Remove aScope and use the suction catheter if this fails.

        -  Clean lens of aScope w/ alcohol wipe before new attempt.

      Investigation of the Functionality of the gastric drainage channel of the SGAs:

        -  W/ a pre-lubricated gastric tube; (16 Fr./ Ambu Auragain) &amp; (14 Fr./ Teleflex LMA
           Supreme).

        -  Pass tube through gastric drainage channel to depth of 40-50 cm.

        -  Confirm placement w/ (1) stethoscope &amp; (2) aspiration of gastric contents.

        -  Minimum of 2 ml. of gastric content is needed to confirm placement w/o audible leak.

        -  An insertion ATTEMPT is when the tip of the G-tube touches the proximal channel.

        -  An insertion FAILURE is the inability to: (1) pass G-tube to appropriate depth, (2)
           auscultate inflated air, (3) aspirate gastric contents.

        -  Record volume of air evacuated, volume of gastric contents, number of insertion
           attempts, ease of insertion of gastric tube and fluid observed in gastric channel.

      Measurement of the oropharyngeal leak pressure (OLP):

        -  Record prior to surgical incision and at the end of surgery.

        -  Close adjustable pressure-limiting valve w/ a fresh gas flow of 3 L/min. *Note*
           pressure at equilibrium.

        -  Maximum pressure allowed is 40 cm H2O.

        -  Auscultate epigastrium during measurement to detect air entrainment into stomach.

        -  Record OLP and audible leaks (stomach, mouth).

      II. Use of SGA as an Intubation Conduit

      AuraGain Procedure:

        -  Lubricate airway tube of SGA &amp; pass the aScope through until visualization of the
           carina.

        -  Mallinckrodt size 7.0 mm ETT for females and a 8.0 mm ETT for males.

        -  Pass ETT tube down the insertion cord of the aScope &amp; verify placement.

        -  Inflate cuff and remove aScope.

      LMA Supreme Procedure:

        -  Mount the (AIC) Aintree Catheter over the aScope &amp; insert assembly through SGA into
           trachea.

        -  Withdraw aScope/ SGA &amp; pass a maximum recommended ETT over the AIC into trachea.

        -  An ATTEMPT is when the tip of the ETT touches the SGA connector and advanced inside the
           SGA.

        -  If an UNSUCCESSFUL attempt occurs, withdraw the ETT from SGA. Re-attempt.

        -  Only 3 attempts w/ 2 differently sized SGAs permitted to place device.

        -  Perform standard endotracheal intubation if unsuccessful after 3 attempts.

        -  Record intubation time (tip of aScope touching SGA connector until endoscopic
           confirmation of placement).

        -  Record: Size of SGA, Size of ETT, number of intubation attempts.

        -  Qualitative Assessment of: Ease of intubation 1-5 (1: Very Easy, 2: Easy, 3: Slight
           Resistance, 4: Difficult, 5: Not Possible.)

      Removal of the ETT where the AuraGain has been used as an intubation conduit: Extubation
      procedure:

        -  Inflate cuff of SGA to pressure of 60 cm H20. (measure w/ aneroid manometer).

        -  Deflate completely cuff of ETT and remove. Continue ventilation w/ SGA.

        -  Record Time of SGA cuff re-inflation &amp; ETT removal.

        -  Record OLP.

      Removal of the SGA:

        -  Remove &quot;partially deflated&quot; AuraGain at end of surgery w/ patient awake and upon Return
           of Spontaneous Respiration.

        -  Remove &quot;partially deflated&quot; LMA Supreme during intubation procedure, while leaving the
           AIC in place.

        -  Inspect SGAs for blood.

      Postoperative Complications:

        -  Transport patient to PACU on 100% O2.

        -  Obtain VS &amp; assess sore throat w/ VAS score 1-5 (1: No pain, 5: Severe)

        -  Assess post-op sore throat, dysphonia, dysphagia, mucosal, lip, lingual, dental injury
           or bronchospasm 45 minutes after recovery.

        -  Rescue analgesia chosen by investigator. If patient is asleep, analgesic will be given
           at discretion of attending.

        -  Record VS and pain q30min. until discharge from PACU.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Participant, Outcomes Assessor</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oropharyngeal Leak Pressure (OLP)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>o Qualitative Assessment of: (1: Very Easy, 2: Easy, 3: Slight Resistance, 4: Difficult, 5: Not Possible.)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of successful intubation and ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative Assessment of: (1: Very Easy, 2: Easy, 3: Slight Resistance, 4: Difficult, 5: Not Possible.)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ease of SGA insertion</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative Assessment of: (1: Very Easy, 2: Easy, 3: Slight Resistance, 4: Difficult, 5: Not Possible.)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anatomical fit of the SGA</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative Assessment of: (1: Very Easy, 2: Easy, 3: Slight Resistance, 4: Difficult, 5: Not Possible.)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Functionality of gastric drainage channel</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative Assessment of: (1: Very Easy, 2: Easy, 3: Slight Resistance, 4: Difficult, 5: Not Possible.)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-operative complications</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Hoarseness Sore Mouth Sore Neck Sore Jaw Dysphonia Dysphagia Alteration in Tongue PAIN (VAS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Anesthesia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ambu Auragain</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Supraglottic airway (SGA) device placement using the Ambu Auragain
AuraGain Procedure:
Lubricate airway tube of SGA &amp; pass the aScope through until visualization of the carina.
Mallinckrodt size 7.0 mm ETT for females and a 8.0 mm ETT for males.
Pass ETT tube down the insertion cord of the aScope &amp; verify placement.
Inflate cuff and remove aScope.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Teleflex LMA Supreme</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Supraglottic airway (SGA) device placement using the Teleflex LMA Supreme
Mount the (AIC) Aintree Catheter over the aScope &amp; insert assembly through SGA into trachea.
Withdraw aScope/ SGA &amp; pass a maximum recommended ETT over the AIC into trachea.
An ATTEMPT is when the tip of the ETT touches the SGA connector and advanced inside the SGA.
If an UNSUCCESSFUL attempt occurs, withdraw the ETT from SGA.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Supraglottic airway (SGA) device</intervention_name>
    <description>Fiber-optic evaluation of the SGAs anatomical position Investigation of the Functionality of the gastric drainage channel of the SGAs Measurement of the oropharyngeal leak pressure (OLP)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ambu Auragain</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Teleflex LMA Supreme</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ambu aScope</intervention_name>
    <description>The investigation will be performed with the aid of the flexible scope, the Ambu aScope, which will be introduced into the airway tube and guided through the SGA until it will be possible to view the vocal cords. Description of the maximal optical view will be measured by the Percentage Of Glottic Opening (POGO)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ambu Auragain</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Teleflex LMA Supreme</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        Adult elective surgical patients ASA I-III Mallampati I-II BMI &lt; 30 kg/m2

        Exclusion Criteria:

        ASA IV-V Mallampati III - IV prone surgery Surgery Duration &gt; 4 hrs. fasting &lt; 8 hrs. Risk
        for regurgitation Respiratory tract pathology Odynophagia Known difficult airway Upper lip
        bite / inter-incisor &lt; 2.5 cm TM &lt; 5 cm limited neck movement airway-face pathology
        dementia

        Study Population - 50 patients undergoing elective surgical procedure

        Sampling method - The treatment will be named 1 for Ambu, 2 for Supreme for both parts of
        the study in the list. Block randomization in X blocks of X patients will be used.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carin A Hagberg, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Carin A Hagberg, MD</last_name>
    <phone>713-500-6200</phone>
    <email>Carin.A.Hagberg@uth.tmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Tariq A Syed, MS</last_name>
    <phone>713-500-6304</phone>
    <email>Tariq.A.Syed@uth.tmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Hermann Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 24, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 22, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Carin A. Hagberg</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
