<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01935219</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to assess the effectiveness of an intervention to address both executive function and processing speed changes that contribute to poor driving performance in adults with Mild Cognitive Impairment (MCI). Our hypotheses are that the study intervention will improve performance on a driving simulator and will improve (i) executive function, specifically attention and planning, (ii) useful field of view, (iii) mood, (iv) quality of life, and (v) reported motor vehicle crashes and driving infractions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Performance in Drivers With Mild Cognitive Impairment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Executive function and processing speed are recognized critical correlates of driving performance and have been shown to decline in older adults and in persons with mild cognitive impairment. Members of our research team have shown that group executive function training such as Goal Management Training results in benefits for healthy older adults, including improved simulated daily activities. The ultimate purpose of our research is to develop interventions to help maintain older adults' mobility in order to assist their 'aging at home'. The planned study will assess the effectiveness of an intervention that includes Goal Management Training + processing speed training (using DriveSharp software), which is designed to address both executive function and processing speed changes that contribute to poor driving performance in people with diagnosed mild cognitive impairment. The investigators will measure the effectiveness of the intervention on driving performance, sustained attention, divided attention, executive function, depressive symptoms and quality of life.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methamphetamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>mild cognitive impairment currently driving or voluntarily stopped driving within the past year fluent in English visual problems that cannot be corrected with standard lenses alcohol/substance abuse stroke with residual motor /sensory deficit traumatic brain injury seizure in the past two years Parkinson's disease Multiple sclerosis untreated sleep apnea history of motion sickness history of dizziness, vertigo active primary psychiatric disorder requiring treatment on a dose of cognitive enhancing medication for less than 3 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>mild cognitive impairment</keyword>
	<keyword>seniors</keyword>
	<keyword>cognitive training</keyword>
	<keyword>driving</keyword>
	<keyword>driving simulation</keyword>
	<keyword>intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>goal management training</keyword>
	<keyword>process speed training</keyword>
</DOC>