<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02253355</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluate the effects and safety of Deep Brain Stimulation (DBS) to treat on patients with Treatment-Resistant Depression (TRD) and using functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI)to evaluate the influence of acupuncture on patients, which will be afford objective evidence for the mechanism of Acupuncture on depression.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PINS Stimulator System for Patients With Treatment Resistant Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Treatment-Resistant</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subject is aged ages 2070 years 2. Diagnosed with nonpsychotic major depressive disorder, single or recurrent episode by DSMIVTR criteria 3. First episode onset before age 45 4. Current episode &gt; 12 months duration 5. In the current episode: Documented resistance (i.e. persistence of the major depressive episode) to a minimum of 4 adequate depression treatments from at least 3 different treatment categories (e.g. SSRI's) 6. SNRI's, TCA's, MAOinhibitors, Mirtazipine, Nefazodone, Trazodone, Bupropion, lithium augmentation, thyroid augmentation, ECT); Adequacy of treatments as defined by a score of at least 3 according to the amended Antidepressant Treatment History Form (ATHF) criteria 7. Hamilton Depression Rating Scale (HDRS) of &gt; 20 at 3 separate baseline visits, rated by 2 separate psychiatrists, Baseline 2 and Baseline 3 HDRS scores cannot improve ≥ 25% 1. Patients with hearing impairment 2. Failures of important organs and in severe conditions 3. Be reluctant or disabled to receive neuropsychological assessments; 4. Participate in other clinical trial 5. Has a life expectancy of &lt; 1 year 6. The investigator and/or enrollment review committee, would preclude participation in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>