<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02253225</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators propose to examine both resting state activity and functional activity during rumination and during self-processing to study the relationship between neural correlates of rumination/self-focus and self-processing in major depression and bipolar disorder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Self Focus in Bipolar Disorder: A Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI) Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Negative rumination, a specific form of self-focus, characterized by repetitively focusing on one's symptoms of distress, and the possible causes and consequences of these symptoms, is a hallmark of depression. Nearly a decade of research has culminated in evidence that the tendency to engage in negative rumination is highly correlated with depressive symptoms. Rumination also plays a critical role in the etiology and maintenance of depressed states and predicts risk for mania in bipolar disorder. Despite the central role of rumination in major depression and bipolar disorder, there have been few studies to date investigating the functional neuroanatomy of negative rumination, and no studies of positive rumination. The few neuroimaging studies that have utilized measures of the tendency to engage in negative rumination have focused on brain functioning when performing tasks that involve processing emotional or self-referential stimuli, but they have not studied resting state activity or functional activity during negative and positive rumination. We are examining both resting state activity and functional activity during negative and positive rumination and during self-processing to study the relationship between the neural correlates of rumination/self-focus and self-processing in major depression and bipolar disorder.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Healthy Controls: Righthanded (as determined by the Handedness Inventory; Oldfield, 1971) Normal or correctedto normal vision and hearing Exclusion Criteria for Healthy Controls: Any current or past psychiatric history Significant medical, psychiatric or neurological illness Currently taking antidepressants, mood stabilizers, or benzodiazepines Positive MR screen (e.g., metal implant, claustrophobia, etc) Inclusion Criteria for Patients with Major Depression: Current diagnosis of MDD Righthanded (as determined by the Handedness Inventory; Oldfield, 1971) Normal or correctedto normal vision and hearing Exclusion Criteria for MDD Patients: If a history of substance abuse, at least 6 months in remission Current suicidal ideation or history of suicide attempts Positive MR screen (e.g., metal implant, claustrophobia, etc) Inclusion Criteria for patients with BPAD: Current diagnosis of BPAD Righthanded (as determined by the Handedness Inventory; Oldfield, 1971) Normal or correctedto normal vision and hearing Exclusion Criteria for BPAD Patients: If a history of substance abuse, at least 6 months in remission Current suicidal ideation or history of suicide attempts Positive MR screen (e.g., metal implant, claustrophobia, etc)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bipolar Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Major Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Rumination</keyword>
	<keyword>Self Processing</keyword>
</DOC>