<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02590601</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Peripartum cardiomyopathy (PPCM) is a rare, but significant heart disease affecting young women in the puerperal period. Thus far, no specific treatment has been approved to treat this disease. PPCM has a wide spectrum of clinical manifestations ranging from mild heart failure to severe cardiomyopathy, cardiogenic shock and death. A significant proportion of survivors have persistent chronic heart failure leading to disabling symptoms and decreased quality of life. Animal studies have suggested that prolactin is central to the development of PPCM. Prolactin has pro-inflammatory and anti-angiogenic effects that may promote PPCM. Bromocriptine, a central dopamine agonist known to decrease prolactin levels, might thwart its deleterious effects in women suffering from PPCM. Following this rationale, bromocriptine should improve myocardial function in women suffering from PPCM and thus, improve cardiovascular outcomes and healthcare outcomes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bromocriptine in the Treatment of Peripartum Cardiomyopathy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bromocriptine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age ≥ 18 years; 2. Peripartum cardiomyopathy defined by the following criteria: Development of heart failure in the last month of pregnancy or within 5 months of delivery; Absence of an identifiable alternative cause of heart failure; Absence of recognizable heart disease prior to the last month of pregnancy; Left ventricular systolic dysfunction demonstrated by classic echocardiographic criteria, such as depressed ejection fraction; 3. Recent onset of PPCM ( 1 month); 4. Written informed consent. 1. Hypersensitivity or contraindication to bromocriptine; 2. Patients already taking bromocriptine for PPCM or for another indication; 3. Cardiogenic shock before enrolment; 4. Survival expected to be less than 1 year due to noncardiovascular causes (eg. cancer); 5. Participation to another investigational drug or investigational device study within 30 days prior to randomization (participation to registries is allowed); 6. Patients who in the opinion of the investigator will not comply with specified drugs, or followup evaluation.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>PPCM</keyword>
	<keyword>Bromocriptine</keyword>
	<keyword>Peripartum cardiomyopathy</keyword>
</DOC>