<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00705588</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Pulmonary arterial hypertension is a chronic disease of the lung blood vessels resulting in constriction and high pressures. Treatment is given with a variety of drugs including the prostanoid class (e.g. epoprostenol, iloprost and the phosphodiesterase 5 (PDE-5) inhibitors (e.g. sildenafil). Although these drugs are known to be effective alone, little is known about combining them together in various combinations. In this trial we will add a long-acting PDE-5 inhibitor to the treatment of patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension who currently are receiving only a prostanoid drug.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long Acting Phosphodiesterase 5 Inhibitors as Add-on Therapy for Patients With Pulmonary Hypertension Treated With Prostanoids.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Familial Primary Pulmonary Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phosphodiesterase 5 Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vardenafil Dihydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tadalafil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All patients must satisfy current diagnostic criteria for pulmonary artery hypertension based on their historical right heart catheter data (within 3 years of study enrollment): Mean PAP &gt;25mmHg at rest or &gt;30mmHg with exercise, by a PCWP&lt; 15mmHg and by PVR &gt;3 Wood Units. Currently stable for at least 3 months on prostanoid monotherapy (epoprostenol iv or iloprost inhaled). Willing and able to participate in all study followup procedures. New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class IIIV. Six minute walking distance between 100450 meters at the baseline assessment. Women of childbearing age must demonstrate adequate contraception or undergo a pregnancy test. Patients with congenital heart disease are eligible for inclusion. Functional Class NYHA Class I. PAH due to chronic pulmonary thromboembolic disease, left heart disease, chronic lung diseases (VC or FEV1 &lt; 60% of predicted) or chronic hypoxia. Acute intercurrent illness requiring hospital admission in the month proceeding screening. Any nonPAH medical condition likely to interfere with participation in evaluation of study endpoints, e.g. musculoskeletal disorders. Any uncontrolled or terminal nonPAH medical condition likely to interfere with completion of the study, according to the judgment of the study physician. Concomitant therapy with drugs known to interact adversely with the study drug. Chronic renal failure creatinine clearance &lt;50ml/min as calculated with the Cockcroft equation. Current participation in another clinical trial. Pregnancy or planned pregnancy during the study period.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2008</verification_date>
</DOC>