<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01270100</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to develop and pilot-test a Recovery Management Intervention (RMI) program for heroin addicts released from compulsory rehabilitation in China. The project has the following specific aims: Primary aims: Aim 1. To engage key stakeholders in the local communities involved in supporting the transition of heroin addicts released from compulsory rehabilitation to the community; Aim 2. To identify potential barriers for participating in MMT in China; Aim 3. To develop and deliver educational/training materials on HIV risks, relapse prevention, and MMT; Aim 4. To adapt and develop the Recovery Management Intervention (RMI) program for heroin addicts released from compulsory rehabilitation in China; Aim 5. To conduct a pilot trial and obtain preliminary outcome data associated with RMI, relative to enhanced standard care. Secondary aim: Aim 6. To explore predictors of relapse and HIV/AIDS risk behaviors. It is hypothesized that the intervention will reduce drug use relapse and the negative consequences associated with relapse, including HIV risk behaviors</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Recovery Management Intervention in China</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The study population will be drawn from all adult patients at participating compulsory rehabilitation facilities who: 1. have been incarcerated for at least one year and would have been eligible for MMT at the time of incarceration, 2. have at least 1 month remaining before release, 3. met the DSMIV criteria for heroin dependence at the time of incarceration, 4. are willing to enroll in methadone maintenance treatment, and 5. are Shanghai residents who reside in the areas of Shanghai targeted by the study. Individuals diagnosed with severe mental illness will not be eligible to participate.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>