<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00973973</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate NBI-56418 compared to placebo (also known as a sugar pill) for its effects on endometriosis related pelvic pain and its safety.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Study of NBI-56418 Sodium in Subjects With Endometriosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 2, multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo controlled parallel group study to assess the efficacy and safety of 150 mg NBI-56418 administered once daily (q.d.) for up to 24 weeks. Approximately 120 subjects will be randomized (1:1) to 150 mg NBI-56418 q.d. or placebo q.d. for the first 8 weeks of dosing. Following 8 weeks of dosing, subjects will continue in the study for an additional 16 weeks in an open-label phase where all subjects still enrolled in the study will receive 150 mg q.d.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Endometriosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Be female, aged 18 to 49 years, inclusive. Have moderate to severe pelvic pain due to endometriosis. Have a history of regular menstrual cycles. Have been surgically (laparoscopy or laparotomy) diagnosed with endometriosis within 8 years of the start of screening. Have a Body Mass Index (BMI) of 18 to 36 kg/m2, inclusive. Agree to use two forms of nonhormonal contraception during the study. Exclusion Criteria Are currently receiving GnRH agonist, a GnRH antagonist other than NBI56418, or danazol or have received any of these agents within 6 months of the start of screening. Are currently receiving DMPASC or DMPAIM or have received any of these agents within 3 months of the start of screening. Are currently using hormonal contraception or other forms of hormonal therapy or received such treatment within the last month. Have had surgery for endometriosis within the last month. Have had a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy. Are using systemic steroids on a chronic or regular basis within 3 months. Have uterine fibroids ≥3 cm in diameter. Have pelvic pain that is not caused by endometriosis. Have unstable medical condition or chronic disease. Have been pregnant within the last six months. Currently breast feeding.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pelvic Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>NBI-56418</keyword>
	<keyword>Endometriosis</keyword>
</DOC>