<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00296855</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The particular aim of this study is the comparison of the diagnostic results of MRA images upon application of Vasovist (gadofosveset), a contrast agent not yet available on the market, with the MRA images upon application of a conventional extracellular contrast agent. A catheter angiography, which will be performed as a routine diagnostic procedure for vascular diseases, will serve as an evaluation standard.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison Study of Vasovist® Magnetic Resonance Angiography (MRA) and an MRA With a Conventional Extracellular Contrast Agent With X-ray Angiography in Patients With Peripheral Artery Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study has previously been posted by Schering AG, Germany. Schering AG, Germany has been renamed to Bayer Schering Pharma AG, Germany. Bayer Schering Pharma AG, Germany is the sponsor of the trial.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with a certain circulation disorder (aortoiliac disease Fontainestage IIb / IV) and an indication for the evaluation of the peripheral runoff arteries from the infrarenal aorta to the calves Patients who are scheduled for Xray angiography and magnetic resonance angiography (MRA) of the arteries mentioned above Patients who have had a contrastenhanced MRA examination of the arteries mentioned above using a standard extracellular contrast agent performed within 1 7 days prior to the study MRA examination Less than 18 years of age Women who are pregnant, breast feeding or who are of childbearing potential and have not had a negative urine pregnancy test the same day as the study MRA examination Requiring immediate therapy for their vascular disease or in whom conduct of all three angiographic procedures is not possible Not being able to remain lying down for at least 45 60 min Patients with a history of serious allergic reactions to any allergen including drugs and contrast agents or with a history of sickle cell disease or other hemolytic anemia Having any contraindication to magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) examination or specifically for MRA (e.g. pacemaker, recent wound clips, and severe claustrophobia)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Peripheral artery disease</keyword>
</DOC>