<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00296192</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this trial is to evaluate safety and efficacy of rotigotine nasal spray (SPM 952) in a single dose application scheme. Subjects will undergo a 2 - 28 days screening period in which eligibility criteria will be checked. Subjects will then be hospitalized for one night. In the morning of the next day, subjects will be randomly assigned either to rotigotine or placebo nasal spray and will then receive a single dose of trial medication. Safety assessments after application include adverse events, 12-lead electrocardiograms, blood pressure and heart rate assessments, and laboratory checks. Efficacy will be assessed by application of motor examination scores. The first subject is planned to be enrolled in February 2006. The last subject is planned to be enrolled in May 2006. Last subject out is expected for August 2006.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy, Safety and Tolerability of Rotigotine Nasal Spray for the Acute Treatment of Parkinson Symptoms</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of this trial is to evaluate safety and efficacy of rotigotine nasal spray (SPM 952)in a single dose application scheme. Subjects will undergo a 2-28 days screening period in which eligibility criteria will be checked. Subjects will then be hospitalized for one night. In the morning of the next day, subjects will be randomly assigned either to rotigotine or placebo nasal spray and will then receive a single dose of trial medication. Safety assessments after application include adverse events, 12-lead electrocardiograms, blood pressure and heart rate assessments, and laboratory checks. Efficacy will be assessed by application of motor examination scores.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>N 0437</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female subjects with idiopathic Parkinson's disease for at least 3 years in duration At least 30 years of age Patients with atypical Parkinson's or clinically relevant concomitant diseases or medical conditions</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Rotigotine</keyword>
	<keyword>Rotigotine nasal spray</keyword>
	<keyword>Efficacy, safety and tolerability</keyword>
	<keyword>Parkinson's disease</keyword>
</DOC>