<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00296816</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Feasibility study to assess a novel combination of cytotoxic agents, docetaxel and oxaliplatin, as first-line therapy in the treatment of ovarian cancer and the impact of angiogenesis inhibition for the progression and prognosis of ovarian cancer by concurrent addition of bevacizumab (Avastin®).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TEACO: Taxotere, Eloxatin, Avastin in Cancer of the Ovary</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants were - administered study medication approximately 28 days after initial surgery for ovarian cancer - received the study treatment regimen of up to one year unless there was disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, death, participant refusal, or treatment delay beyond the time frame permitted for each treatment Participants were followed for survival for a minimum 3 years from the date of enrollment</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: 1. Females 18 years of age or older 2. Participants with a histologic diagnosis of ovarian, primary peritoneal, or fallopian tube carcinoma, Stage Ib IV, with either optimal (≤ 1 cm residual disease) or suboptimal residual disease ( &gt; 1 cm maximal diameter any remaining lesion) following initial surgery. 3. Participants with the following histologic epithelial cell types are eligible: Serious adenocarcinoma, endometrioid adenocarcinoma, mucinous adenocarcinoma,undifferentiated carcinoma, clear cell adenocarcinoma, mixed epithelial carcinoma, transitional cell carcinoma, malignant Brenner's Tumor, or adenocarcinoma N.O.S. 4. Participant must have adequate bone marrow function 5. Participant must have adequate renal function 6. Participant must have adequate urine protein/creatinine reaction (UPC) of &lt;1.0; 7. Participant must have adequate neurologic function 8. Hepatic function: Total Bilirubin ≤ ULN; AST and ALT and Alkaline Phosphatase must be within the range allowing for eligibility. In determining eligibility the more abnormal of the two values (AST or ALT) should be used. 9. Blood Coagulation parameters: PT such that international normalized ratio (INR) is &lt; 1.5 (or an inrange INR, usually between 2 and 3, if a participant is on stable dose of therapeutic Warfarin or low molecular weight heparin) and a PTT &lt; 1.2 times the upper limit normal. 10. Participants must be enrolled in the study prior to 50 days (every effort will be made for prior to 28 days) after initial surgery performed for the combined purpose of diagnosis, staging and cytoreduction. 11. Participants with measurable and nonmeasurable disease are eligible. Participants with suboptimal disease are eligible. Participants may or may not have cancerrelated symptoms. 12. Participants who have met the preentry requirements specified including serologic measurement of CA125 as a baseline for subsequent determination of response using Rustin criteria. 13. Participants with a GOG Performance Status of 0, 1, or 2. EXCLUSION CRITERIA: 1. Participants with a current diagnosis of epithelial ovarian tumor of low malignant potential (Borderline carcinomas) are not eligible. Participants with a prior diagnosis of a low malignant potential tumor that was surgically resected and who subsequently develop invasive adenocarcinoma are eligible, provided that they have not received prior chemotherapy for any ovarian tumor. 2. Germ cell tumors, sex cordstromal tumors, carcinosarcomas, mixed mullerian tumors or carcinosarcomas, metastatic carcinomas from other sites to the ovary and low malignant potential tumors including so called micropapillary serous carcinomas are not eligible. 3. Participants who have received prior radiotherapy to any portion of the abdominal cavity or pelvis are excluded. Prior radiation for localized cancer of the skin is permitted, provided that it was completed more than 5 years prior to enrollment, and the participant remains free of recurrent or metastatic disease. 4. Participants who have received any prior anticancer chemotherapy or biologic therapy for any malignancy are excluded. 5. Participants with synchronous primary endometrial cancer, or a past history of primary endometrial cancer, are excluded, unless all of the following conditions are met: Stage not greater than IB; Less than 3 mm invasion without vascular or lymphatic invasion; No poorly differentiated subtypes, including papillary serous, clear cell, or other FIGO Grade 3 lesions. 6. Participants with any history of cancer, with the exception of inclusion criteria #2 and #3, and nonmelanoma skin cancer, who are cancer free for the last 5 years, are excluded. 7. Participant with acute hepatitis or active infection that requires parenteral antibiotics. 8. Participants with serious, nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture. This includes history of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation or intraabdominal abscess within 28 days. Participants with granulating incisions healing by secondary intention with no evidence of fascial dehiscence or infection are eligible but require weekly wound examinations. 9. Participants with active bleeding or pathologic conditions that carry high risk of bleeding,such as known bleeding disorder, coagulopathy, or tumor involving major vessels. 10. Participants with history or evidence upon physical examination of CNS disease, including primary brain tumor, seizures not controlled with standard medical therapy, any brain metastases, or history of cerebrovascular accident (CVA, stroke), transient ischemic attack (TIA) or subarachnoid hemorrhage within six months of the first date of treatment on this study. 11. Participants with clinically significant cardiovascular disease. 12. Participants with clinically significant proteinuria. Urine protein should be screened by urinalysis. Participants discovered to have a urine protein: serum creatinine ratio greater than or equal to 1 should undergo a 24hour urine collection, which must be an adequate collection and must demonstrate &lt; 1000 mg protein/24 hr to allow participation in the study. 13. Participants with or with anticipation of invasive procedures. 14. Participants with GOG Performance Grade of 3 or 4. 15. Participants who are pregnant or nursing. 16. Participants with known hypersensitivity to Chinese hamster ovary cell products or other recombinant human or humanized antibodies and hypersensitivity to polysorbate 80 or hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs and its ingredients. 17. Participants who participated in a study with any investigational product/device within the last 30 days. 18. Any medical condition that in the judgment of the investigator would jeopardize any participant safety or the study drug evaluation for efficacy and safety.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>