<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01517659</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluate the safety and efficacy of non-invasive fat reduction in the inner thighs with the ZELTIQ CoolSculpting System.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Non-Invasive Reduction of Fat in the Inner Thighs</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lipid Metabolism Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 1. Male or female subjects &gt; 18 years of age and &lt; 65 years of age. 2. Subject has clearly visible fat on the inner thighs and in the investigator's opinion, may benefit from the treatment. 3. Subject has not had weight change exceeding 10 pounds in the preceding month. 4. Subject with body mass index (BMI) up to 30. [BMI is defined as weight in pounds multiplied by 703 divided by the square of the height in inches.] 5. Subject agrees to maintain his/her weight (i.e., within 5 pounds) by not making any major changes in his/her diet or lifestyle during the course of the study. 6. Subject has read and signed a written informed consent form. Exclusion Criteria 1. Subject has had a surgical procedure(s) in the area of intended treatment. 2. Subject has had an invasive fat reduction procedure (e.g., liposuction, abdominoplasty, mesotherapy) in the area of intended treatment. 3. Subject has had a noninvasive fat reduction and/or body contouring procedure in the area of intended treatment within the past 6 months. 4. Subject needs to administer, or has a known history of, subcutaneous injections (e.g., heparin, insulin) into the area of intended treatment within the past month. 5. Subject has a known history of cryoglobulinemia, cold urticaria, or paroxysmal cold hemoglobinuria. 6. Subject has a known history of Raynaud's disease, or any known condition with a response to cold exposure that limits blood flow to the skin. 7. Subject has a history of a bleeding disorder or is taking any medication that in the investigator's opinion may increase the subject's risk of bruising. 8. Subject is taking or has taken diet pills or supplements within the past month. 9. Subject has any dermatological conditions, such as moderate to excessive skin laxity, or scars in the location of the treatment sites that may interfere with the treatment or evaluation (stretch marks is not an exclusion). 10. Subject has an active implanted device such as a pacemaker, defibrillator, or drug delivery system 11. Subject is pregnant or intends to become pregnant in the next 8 months. 12. Subject is lactating or has been lactating in the past 6 months. 13. Subject is unable or unwilling to comply with the study requirements. 14. Subject is currently enrolled in a clinical study of any other unapproved investigational drug or device. 15. Any other condition or laboratory value that would, in the professional opinion of the investigator, potentially affect the subject's response or the integrity of the data, or would pose an unacceptable risk to the subject.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lipolysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Cryolipolysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Fat Reduction</keyword>
</DOC>