<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01517503</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will investigate the effectiveness of Cognitive Therapy and Acceptance and Commitment Therapy in a randomized controlled trial among patients with Major Depressive Disorder in routine clinical practice. Furthermore, the study will investigate whether each specific treatment approach is mediated by its proposed theoretical mechanism.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acceptance and Commitment Therapy Versus Cognitive Therapy for the Treatment of Major Depressive Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The current study aims at investigating the effectiveness of Cognitive Therapy and Acceptance and Commitment Therapy in a randomized controlled trial among patients with MDD in routine clinical practice. Further, the study will investigate whether each specific treatment approach is mediated by its proposed theoretical mechanism. Patients have to meet diagnostic criteria for nonpsychotic MDD as determined by the Structured Interview for DSM-IV. Each client will receive either Cognitive Therapy or Acceptance and Commitment Therapy that will last between 16 to 20 sessions. Based on previous results, it is expected that both treatment forms will prove beneficial for the patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Meeting DSMIV criteria for MDD 2. Between the ages of 18 and 65yearsold 3. Having sufficient fluency in Dutch to complete treatment and research protocol 1. DSMIV criteria for bipolar disorder (past or present) 2. Psychotic disorders 3. Substance dependence disorders (current or within the past 6 months), or 4. Organic brain syndrome. 5. Borderline or antisocial personality disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>