<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02970721</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of the proposed project is to evaluate adverse maternal and fetal outcomes in women who are treated and women who are untreated with mood stabilizing medication for bipolar disorder during pregnancy, compared to women without bipolar disorder during pregnancy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Risk of Adverse Birth Outcomes in Women Treated for Bipolar Disorder During Pregnancy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Bipolar disorder is a chronic and episodic mental illnesses characterized by recurrent episodes of mania, hypomania, and depression separated by periods of normal mood. Unlike normal mood fluctuations, bipolar disorder results in extreme shifts of a person's mood and behaviour. In Canada, the estimated lifetime prevalence of bipolar disorder is 2.2% and it is one of the leading causes of disability worldwide. While there no cure for bipolar disorder, treatment is available to manage frequent relapses and alleviate mood symptoms. The pharmacotherapy regimen consists of mood stabilizers alone or in combination with antipsychotic agents and antidepressants. The overarching goal of treatment is to achieve a euthymic state and to restore psychosocial functioning and reduce associated mortality and morbidity. The onset of BD typically occurs during adolescence and early adulthood and disproportionately affects women, placing them at risk of experiencing recurrence episodes throughout their childbearing years. Women with bipolar disorder are faced with a dilemma when making the decision to maintain treatment during pregnancy. Some choose to stop treatment to minimize the risk of exposing the fetus to the medications out of concern of harm. Alternatively, discontinuing treatment increases the risk of illness recurrences such that it may compromise the mother's ability to care for herself and the baby. Prior evidence suggests that there is a 70% risk of relapse during pregnancy among women who choose to discontinue medication, particularly when stopped abruptly. There remains much uncertainty about the effects of using mood-stabilizing treatment for bipolar disorder during pregnancy. Studies that have investigated the safety of mood stabilizer use during pregnancy have presented inconclusive results.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pregnancy Complications</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women of ages of 15 and 40 Previously hospitalized for a singleton delivery between 20002014. Eligible for the provincial drug benefit plan during index pregnancy, Age &lt;15 or &gt;40 No prescription in ODB in 6 months prior to pregnancy to 6 months after delivery</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>