<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02902692</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The current study will examine the effects of a brief mindfulness based intervention (BMBI) on mood, memory and attention in comparison to a wait-list control (WLC) group. Participants for the study will be 90 adults aged 50 years and above who have presented at a memory clinic within SLaM NHS Trust with subjective cognitive concerns and/or those who have received a diagnosis of mild cognitive impairment (MCI) from their memory clinic.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mindfulness for Older Adults With Cognitive Concerns</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants will be randomly assigned to either the BMBI group or the WLC group. Those assigned to the BMBI group will complete a number of cognitive assessments and questionnaires at Time 1. They will then receive a 45 minute mindfulness intervention. Following this, they will be asked to practice mindfulness for 30 minutes per day for 7 days a week in their own homes. After 7 days, participants in the BMBI group will be invited to complete a paired set of cognitive assessments and questionnaires (Time 2). Participants in the WLC group will complete the same number of cognitive assessments and questionnaires as the BMBI group at Time 1. However, they will not receive the 45 minute mindfulness intervention nor will they be asked to practice it at home for 7 days. After 7 days, participants in the WLC group will be invited to complete a paired set of cognitive assessments and questionnaires (Time 2). After completion of the measures at Time 2, the WLC participants will then receive the 45 minute mindfulness intervention. All assessments, questionnaires and the intervention will be carried out either in a SLaM memory clinic or at participants own homes depending on level of mobility.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<criteria>People aged 50 years and older with subjective memory concerns (SMC) and/or those who meet criteria for amnestic mild cognitive impairment (MCI) who have been seen by one of the three SLAM memory services (i.e. Croydon Memory Service; Southwark and Lambeth Memory Service; and Lewisham Memory Service) in the past three months. Participants must be able to give informed consent to participate. Diagnosis of dementia or multidomain mild cognitive impairment, intellectual disability, current substance misuse, a current diagnosis of epilepsy or another neurodegenerative disorder (such as Parkinson's), a history of brain injury or stroke, a severe and enduring mental health disorder (e.g. severe depression or anxiety, personality disorder, schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder, bipolar affective disorder), active suicidal ideation, severe sensory impairment that would significantly impair a person's ability to engage in the intervention.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>brief</keyword>
	<keyword>mindfulness</keyword>
</DOC>