<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02165774</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Prospective, randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind multicenter trial including 4 tertiary sacral neuromodulation referral centers in Switzerland (Zürich, Bern, Nottwil, St.Gallen). Patients with refractory neurogenic LUTD are included and randomized after neuromodulator implantation into sacral neuromodulation ON or sacral neuromodulation OFF (n=30) for a 2 months double-blind phase. In addition to standard neuro-urological assessments, patients who agree will also undergo neurophysiological investigation of the lower urinary tract, i.e. recording of current perception thresholds, sensory evoked potentials, and electroencephalography after stimulation of the urethra and bladder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sacral Neuromodulation for Neurogenic LUT Dysfunction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neurotransmitter Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Refractory neurogenic LUTD Urgency frequency syndrome and/or urgency incontinence refractory to antimuscarinics (pharmacotherapy for at least 4 weeks with at least 2 antimuscarinics) Chronic urinary retention refractory to alphablocker (pharmacotherapy with an alphablocker for at least 4 weeks) Combination of urgency frequency syndrome and/or urgency incontinence and chronic urinary retention refractory to antimuscarinics (pharmacotherapy for at least 4 weeks with at least 2 antimuscarinics) and alphablocker (pharmacotherapy with an alphablocker for at least 4 weeks) Stable neurological disease/injury for at least 12 months Age minimum 18 years Informed consent Botulinum A toxin injections into the detrusor and/or urethral sphincter in the last 6 months Age under 18 years Pregnancy Individuals especially in need of protection (according to Research with Human Subjects published by the Swiss Academy of Medical Sciences) No informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>sacral neuromodulation, neurogenic lower urinary tract dysfunction</keyword>
</DOC>