<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01842360</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of a biological vaccine (MV130 in subjects with Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) compared with a placebo group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Efficacy and Safety of MV130 in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Double blind parallel placebo controlled study. The subjects will receive medication during 12 months and will be followed up during another six months</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent. Both gender Age between 35 and 85. Must be able to follow the treatment regimen Diagnosis of moderate COPD according to GOLD criteria Consumption of 10 or more packs of cigarettes/year Fertile women of must use an approved contraceptive method Pregnant women, breastfeeding Subject who has participated in a study or clinical trial with an investigational product in the last 3 months before inclusion Subject with severe COPD Subject with a history of hypersensitivity to any component of the vaccine Subject outside of age range Subject diagnosed with asthma Subject who has had an exacerbation 4 weeks before starting the trial. Subject that have needed corticosteroids in the last 4 weeks before starting the trial Subject diagnosed with Primary or Secondary Immunodeficiency Subjects with chronic lymphoproliferative disease Subjects with chronic infectious disease Subject with chronic heart disease, arrhythmias, or episodes of arrhythmia secondary to the administration of bronchodilators. Subject diagnosed with COPD and chronic colonization by Pseudomonas aeruginosa</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)</keyword>
</DOC>