<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01842139</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized phase I trial studies the side effects and best way to give vaccine therapy together with basiliximab in treating patients with acute myeloid leukemia (AML) in complete remission. Vaccines made from the WT1 peptide may help the body build an effective immune response to kill cancer cells. Montanide ISA 51 VG and poly-ICLC may enhance this response. Monoclonal antibodies, such as basiliximab, can block cancer growth in different ways. Some block the ability of cancer to grow and spread. Others find cancer cells and help kill them or carry cancer-killing substances to them. It is not yet known whether WT1 126-134 peptide vaccine with Montanide ISA 51 VG is more effective than with poly-ICLC when given together with basiliximab in treating AML</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vaccine Therapy and Basiliximab in Treating Patients With Acute Myeloid Leukemia in Complete Remission</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To examine the immunogenicity of WT1 peptide (WT1 126-134 peptide vaccine) emulsified in Montanide (Montanide ISA 51 VG) in elderly patients with AML. II. To determine whether toll-like receptor 3 (TLR3) agonist (poly-L-lysine and carboxymethyl cellulose [poly ICLC]) could be a potent immunologic adjuvant, and increases the frequencies of WT1-specific T cells following vaccination. III. To determine whether depletion of regulatory T cells occurs upon administration of the anti-cluster of differentiation (CD)25 monoclonal antibody Basiliximab, and whether this is associated with increased frequencies of WT1-specific T cells following vaccination. IV. To assess whether WT1 vaccination +/- TLR3 agonist (poly ICLC) combined with Basiliximab results in decreased levels of WT1 transcripts in peripheral blood cells compared to WT1 vaccination +/- TLR3 as measured by quantitative reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR). SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To examine the safety and gain preliminary information on efficacy of WT1 peptide vaccination +/- TLR3 agonist (poly ICLC) combined with Basiliximab. OUTLINE: Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. ARM A: Patients receive WT1 126-134 peptide vaccine emulsified in Montanide ISA 51 VG subcutaneously (SC) on day 0 and then once every 2 weeks. ARM B: Patients receive WT1 126-134 peptide vaccine emulsified in poly-ICLC SC on day 0 and then once every 2 weeks. ARM C: Patients assigned to Arm C receive basiliximab intravenously (IV) over 30 minutes on day -7 and WT1 126-134 peptide vaccine as in Arm A or Arm B, whichever had a superior cellular immune response. In all arms, treatment continues for 12 weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients may then receive 6 additional monthly vaccinations. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for up to 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Basiliximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Poly ICLC</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Freund's Adjuvant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Poly I-C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboxymethylcellulose Sodium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with Hematological malignancies, including AML, MDS, CML in blast phase and other conditions at the investigator's discretion. Bone marrow biopsyconfirmed CR or CRi, more than CR1 is allowed, such as CR2 or CR3. The enrollee is deemed not a candidate for stem cell transplant due to advanced age or comorbidities; or the enrollee does not have donor available; or enrollee refuses stem cell transplant due to personal belief; or stem cell transplant is not current standard of care. Patients who are post stem cell transplant in CR or CRi are allowed if they are off immunosuppression,and not treated with systematic steroid for GVHD Karnofsky performance status index &gt; or = 80% Written informed consent Absolute neutrophil count &gt; or = 500/μl Platelet count &gt;= 20,000/μl with transfusion Creatinine = or &lt; 2 x upper limit of normal (ULN) Serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) and serum glutamic pyruvate transaminase (SGPT) = or &lt; 5 x ULN Bilirubin = or &lt; 3 x ULN Human leukocyte antigens (HLA) typing: patient must express HLAA2 Age &gt; 18 years and &lt; 85 years Electrocardiogram (EKG) without evidence of arrhythmia or changes that indicate acute ischemia Pulse oximetry showing oxygen saturation of at least 90% on room air No irreversible coagulopathy, international normalized ratio (INR) =&lt; 2 No sign of tumor lysis syndrome, uric acid needs to be in normal range prior to treatment Not in diabetic ketoacidosis (DKA), sickle cell crisis, and not having severe peripheral vascular disease on active anticoagulation treatment Pregnant or nursing women; women who still have childbearing potential must be tested for urinary or serum beta human chorionic gonadotropin (βHCG) Biological or chemotherapy in the 4 weeks prior to the start of dosing Patients with intrinsic immunosuppression, including seropositivity for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antibody; patients should be tested for HIV Serious concurrent infection, including active tuberculosis, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C; patients should be tested for hepatitis B surface antigen and hepatitis C antibody; patients who are hepatitis C antibody (Ab) positive can be eligible if they are PCR negative Active or history of confirmed autoimmune disease Concurrent systemic corticosteroids (except physiologic replacement doses) or other immunosuppressive drugs (eg. cyclosporin A) Active or history of autoimmune disease including but not limited to rheumatoid arthritis (rheumatoid factor [RF]positive with current or recent flare), inflammatory bowel disease, systemic lupus erythematosus (clinical evidence with antinuclear antibody [ANA] 1:80 or greater), ankylosing spondylitis, scleroderma, multiple sclerosis, autoimmune hemolytic anemia, and immune thrombocytopenic purpura; seropositivity alone will not be considered positive Psychiatric illness that may make compliance to the clinical protocol unmanageable or may compromise the ability of the patient to give informed consent; patients with clinical evidence of dementia should have a competent designee participate in decision</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>