<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00530010</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Internal radiation therapy uses radioactive material placed directly into or near a tumor to kill tumor cells. Using radiolabeled glass beads to kill tumor cells may be effective treatment for liver cancer that cannot be removed by surgery. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well radiolabeled glass beads work in treating patients with liver cancer that cannot be removed by surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Radiolabeled Glass Beads in Treating Patients With Liver Cancer That Cannot Be Removed by Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Provide supervised access to treatment with yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres (TheraSphere®) to eligible patients with cancer of the liver who are not candidates for surgical resection. - Evaluate patient experience and toxicities associated with yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres (TheraSphere®) treatment. OUTLINE: This is a humanitarian device exemption use study. Patients receive yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres (TheraSphere®) into the liver tumor through a percutaneously placed catheter into the hepatic artery. Patients may receive additional treatment 4-12 weeks after initial treatment at the discretion of the study physician. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed at 2 weeks, 30 days, and then once a year for approximately 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Confirmed diagnosis of intrahepatic carcinoma Histopathology confirmation may be waived in patients with a radiographically identifiable liver mass AND known laboratory or clinical risk factors for cancer or elevated tumor markers such as AFP Unresectable disease No portal hypertension with portal venous shunt away from the liver No significant extrahepatic disease representing an imminent lifethreatening outcome No evidence of potential delivery of &gt; 16.5 mCi (30 Gy absorbed dose) radiation to the lungs on either of the following: First yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres (TheraSphere®) administration Cumulative delivery of radiation to the lungs over multiple treatments PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Inclusion criteria: ECOG performance status 02 Absolute granulocyte count ≥ 1,500/μL Platelet count &gt; 25,000/μL Serum creatinine &lt; 2.0 mg/dL (unless using noniodinated contrast or on dialysis) Serum bilirubin ≤ 3.0 mg/dL (in some cases where there is an elevated bilirubin and the tumor may be isolated from a vascular standpoint, treatment may proceed) Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception Exclusion criteria: Any of the following contraindications to angiography and selective visceral catheterization: History of severe allergy or intolerance to any contrast media, narcotics, sedatives, or atropine, that cannot be controlled using basic angiographic techniques Bleeding diathesis, not correctable by usual forms of therapy Severe peripheral vascular disease that would preclude catheterization Evidence of any detectable Tc99 macroaggregated albumin flow to the stomach or duodenum, after application of established angiographic techniques to stop such flow Severe liver dysfunction or pulmonary insufficiency Active uncontrolled infection Significant underlying medical or psychiatric illness PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: At least 4 weeks since prior and no other concurrent anticancer therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult primary hepatocellular carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>localized unresectable adult primary liver cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>advanced adult primary liver cancer</keyword>
</DOC>