<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00530088</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Photodynamic therapy uses a drug that becomes active when it is exposed to a certain kind of light. When the drug is active, tumor cells are killed. Photodynamic therapy using porfimer sodium may be effective against mouth or throat dysplasia and cancer of the mouth and throat. PURPOSE: This phase I trial is studying how well photodynamic therapy using porfimer sodium works in treating patients with recurrent mouth or throat dysplasia, recurrent in situ cancer of the mouth or throat, or stage I cancer of the mouth or throat.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Photodynamic Therapy Using Porfimer Sodium in Treating Patients With Recurrent Mouth or Throat Dysplasia or Recurrent In Situ Cancer or Stage I Cancer of the Mouth or Throat</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - To determine the response of patients with recurrent dysplasia, squamous cell carcinoma in situ, or stage I squamous cell carcinoma of the oral cavity or the larynx treated with photodynamic therapy using porfimer sodium. - To identify the local toxicity of this treatment in these patients. OUTLINE: Patients receive porfimer sodium subcutaneously followed by photodynamic therapy (PDT) comprising laser light delivered by a single or a diffuser (i.e., for broad areas of dysplasia) fiberoptic lens fiber. Patients with incompletely treated or missed sites of disease may receive another dose of laser light on day 5 without additional porfimer sodium. Patients with multicentric disease may undergo additional PDT at least 4-6 weeks after the initial treatment. After completion of study therapy, patients are followed for 1-2 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dihematoporphyrin Ether</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trioxsalen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Biopsy confirmed oral cavity or larynx lesion with mildtosevere dysplasia OR in situ or stage I (T1, N0) squamous cell carcinoma of the oral cavity or larynx Recurrent disease PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: ECOG performance status 02 WBC ≥ 4,000/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Total bilirubin ≤ 2.0 mg/dL Creatinine ≤ 2.0 mg/dL Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 3 times upper limit of normal (ULN) SGOT ≤ 3 times ULN Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must practice effective contraception No porphyria or hypersensitivity to porphyrin or porphyrinlike compounds PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Any type of prior therapy allowed More than 4 weeks since prior and no concurrent chemotherapy or radiotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage 0 laryngeal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage 0 lip and oral cavity cancer</keyword>
</DOC>