<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00690222</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose is to determine if an intracameral solution of 0.2% tropicamide and 2% phenylephrine can dilate the pupil for cataract surgery as well as pre-operative topical 1% tropicamide and 5% phenylephrine. We will be looking at two separate groups of patients, those with and those without pseudoexfoliation syndrome. We will be looking at how each method affects the size of the pupil at the beginning and at the end of cataract surgery. In addittion, we will look at what effect the two different methods have on blood pressure and heart rate in the pre-operative, peri-operative and post-operative periods.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intracameral Mydriasis Versus Topical Mydriasis in Cataract Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cataract</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Exfoliation Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mydriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mydriatics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phenylephrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tropicamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxymetazoline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ability to give consent Greater than 18 years of age Planned clear cornea cataract extraction and placement of foldable posterior chamber intraocular lens No secondary procedure planned (i.e. trabeculectomy, keratectomy, corneal transplant, vitreoretinal procedure etc.) Systemic condition capable of undergoing topical anesthesia No previous intraocular surgery Pseudoexfoliation syndrome (PXF) for group 1 No Pseudoexfoliation syndrome for group 2 Not fulfilling inclusion criteria Any iris pathology including but not limited to posterior synechia, iridocorneal endothelial syndrome, corectopia, traumatic mydriasis, Horner's syndrome, Adie's pupil, cyclodialysis, iridodialysis Previous or concurrent use of Flomax® or similar alphaantagonist medication Corneal pathology affecting pupil magnification or measurement (keratoconus, peripheral thinning, sclerocornea, scarring) Uncontrolled Hypertension (greater than 170/90 on preoperative assessment on day of surgery as measured by automated DATEX monitor)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>cataract surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>phacoemulsification</keyword>
	<keyword>pupil</keyword>
	<keyword>dilation</keyword>
	<keyword>mydriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>intracameral</keyword>
	<keyword>topical</keyword>
	<keyword>pseudoexfoliation syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>