<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00690248</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Observational, non-interventional, transversal, multicenter, open label (No treatment is involved). The primary objective is to detect the prevalence of depressive symptoms in bipolar patients admitted to a psychiatric Unit due to an acute mania episode. Secondary objectives include 1) to evaluate, the relationship between depressive symptoms and severity of mania; 2) to evaluate, the relationship between depressive symptoms and anxiety; 3) to evaluate, the relationship between depressive symptoms and psychotic symptoms; 4) to evaluate, the relationship between depressive symptoms and insight; 5) to evaluate, the relationship between depressive symptoms and clinical global impression; 6) to evaluate, the relationship between depressive symptoms and previous treatment with antipsychotics (whatever the antipsychotic was); 7) to evaluate, the relationship between depressive symptoms and length of admission; 8) to evaluate factors (demographic, evolution…) which could be involved in the presence of depressive symptoms within an acute manic episode; 9) to evaluate, the difference on the initial prescription due to the detection of depressive symptoms; 10) to evaluate, if exists, differences on the previous psychiatric diagnosis in patients with and without depressive symptoms. The primary endpoint is score of the MADRS (Montgomery-Asberg Depression Rating Scale) in bipolar patients with acute mania</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Depressive Symptoms in Acute Manic Episode</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosed of Bipolar Disorder based on DSMIVTR Patients admitted to an acute inpatient psychiatric Unit due to an acute manic episode (as defined in DSMIV_TR) Provision of written informed consent. Total score in Young Mania Rating Scale &gt;=20 Able to understand and comply with the requirements of the study Mental retardation Patients with manic symptoms are due to substance use, based in the investigator opinion Patients with unstable organic diseases, who are not receiving adequate treatment, according the investigator opinion. Participation in a trial with drugs within 4 weeks of enrolment into this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute mania</keyword>
	<keyword>Bipolar disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>depressive symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>mixed mania</keyword>
</DOC>