<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00056264</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of infliximab (Remicade) in patients with Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD). Infliximab (Remicade) targets specific proteins in the body's immune system to help control the development of inflammation to help reduce painful disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Safety and Efficacy of Infliximab (Remicade) in Patients With COPD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) is a smoking-related inflammatory lung disease that results in reduced lung function, causing the symptoms or problems that you have when breathing. COPD includes both chronic bronchitis and emphysema. The symptoms of COPD are cough, sputum (phlegm) production, breathlessness, and wheezing. Advanced disease may also involve changes in appetite and weight loss. The drug used in this study is called Remicadeâ, and the active component is called infliximab. Infliximab binds to and blocks the activity of a naturally occurring substance in the body called tumor necrosis factor alpha or TNFa, which may be associated with inflammation and a decrease in lung function.The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of infliximab in the treatment of patients with symptoms of moderate to severe COPD.Patients will be receive infusions of either placebo, 3 mg/kg infliximab or 5mg/kg infliximab at weeks 0, 2, 6, 12, 18, and 24.Safety evaluations will be performed at specified intervals throughout the study and will consist of laboratory tests, vital signs (such as blood pressure), physical examinations and the occurrence and severity of adverse events as well as other study specific procedures. Patients will receive infusions of either placebo, 3 mg/kg infliximab or 5mg/kg infliximab at weeks 0, 2, 6, 12, 18, and 24.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infliximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have moderate or severe COPD Patients must have at least one episode of COPDrelated symptoms (eg, cough, sputum production, shortness of breath) within 2 months prior to screening Exclusion Criteria: Patients must not have asthma as main component of obstructive airway disease Patients must not have had a moderate or severe exacerbation of COPD within previous 1 month</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</keyword>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
	<keyword>Infliximab</keyword>
	<keyword>Remicade</keyword>
</DOC>