<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01700816</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out if using bright light sessions during bone marrow transplant can prevent people from developing confusion also known as delirium.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prevention of Delirium After Bone Marrow Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a pilot, double blind randomized study conducted in patients scheduled to undergo bone marrow transplant at the Massachusetts General Hospital. The goal of this study is to look at the usefulness of bright light therapy in the prevention of delirium in a population at high risk for developing this condition. Delirium can develop in up to half of the people that undergo bone marrow transplant. Symptoms include changes in level of alertness, confusion, and temporary problems with memory and attention. In severe cases, it can be accompanied by agitation, paranoia(overly suspicious), and hallucinations(seeing or hearing things that are not really there). Bright light uses no medication and is often used to treat seasonal affective depression and multiple sleep disorders. The light boxes are portable and are placed in front of individuals for about 30 minutes every day.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Delirium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 or older Male or female Patients scheduled to undergo HSCT English speaking Previous history of bipolar affective disorder Ongoing delirium History of substance abuse/dependence within 6 months prior to HSCT History of invasive melanoma. Patients with a history of basal cell carcinoma, melanoma in situ, or squamous cell carcinoma are permitted to enroll if the lesion(s) have been excised with negative margins History of medical/dermatological conditions that make skin especially sensitive to light,such as systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) and/or porphyria Eye condition that makes eyes vulnerable to light damage Concomitant use of medications that increase sensitivity to sunlight, such as the herbal supplement St. John's Wort Established primary insomnia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Delirium</keyword>
	<keyword>Hematopoietic stem cell transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone marrow transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Bright Light Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>