<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01700114</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to collect data to describe the real-world use and safety and effectiveness of MelaFind® in a post-approval clinical setting.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Post-Approval Study of MelaFind</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective of this study to test the hypothesis that, among eligible and evaluable lesions with central histological reference standard status melanoma or high-grade lesion, the relative sensitivity ρ comparing enrolling dermatologists after MelaFind use with enrolling dermatologists if MelaFind were not available is greater than 110%. This represents a clinically meaningful increase in sensitivity. The secondary objectives of this study are to evaluate real-world use and safety and effectiveness of MelaFind in a clinical setting.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The lesion is pigmented (i.e., melanin, keratin, blood) Clinical management of the lesion by the examining dermatologist is either biopsy of the lesion in toto, or 3month followup of the lesion The diameter of the pigmented area is between 2 and 22 millimeters The lesion is accessible to the MelaFind handheld imaging device The patient, or a legally authorized representative, has consented to participate in the study and has signed the Informed Consent Form The patient has a known allergy to isopropyl alcohol The lesion has been previously biopsied, excised, or traumatized The skin is not intact (e.g., open sores, ulcers, bleeding) The lesion is within 1 cm of the eye The lesion is on mucosal surfaces (e.g., lips, genitals) The lesion is on palmar hands The lesion is on plantar feet The lesion is on or under nails The lesion is located on or in an area of visible scarring The lesion contains foreign matter (e.g., tattoo, splinter, marker)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pigmented Skin Lesions</keyword>
	<keyword>Dermatology</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>MelaFind</keyword>
</DOC>