<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02992795</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective, non-blinded, matched control study of young athletes (ages 10-28 years old) in collegiate sports. The cohorts are defined in accordance to the athlete's exposure of injury. All subjects will complete a minimum of one recording based on their assigned cohort. Concussed athletes will complete an additional 3 weeks of follow-up recordings post injury. The symptomatic evaluation, physical examination, neurological baseline testing, and BrainPulse recordings will be entered in a database to determine clinical outcome and assess device utilization.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Unblinded Data Collection Study of Concussion Using BrainPulse</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cohort I is defined as all enrolled athletes at the University of Wyoming and is divided into two sub-cohorts: Cohort Ia include all athletes participating in Division 1 Athletics; Cohort Ib are athletes subscribed to the Head Health Network. Cohort II is defined as all injured athletes participating in the teams and includes two sub-cohorts: Cohort IIa is defined as non- concussed injured athletes; Cohort IIb concussed athletes per reference standard.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Brain Concussion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female young athletes between ages 1828 yrs 2. Enrolled at the University of Wyoming and currently participating in Division 1 Athletics 3. Completed the following baseline testing: SWAY balance, KingDevick, C3Logix 4. Willing and able to participate in all study evaluations and allow access to medical testing and records 5. Signed informed consent, or have a legally authorized representative willing to provide informed consent on behalf of the subject if the subject is a minor 1. Prior concussion diagnosed by a physician in the last 2 weeks assessed via interview with athlete (not including a recent concussion within the last 3 days) 2. Any serious medical, social or psychological condition that in the opinion of the investigator would impair ability to provide informed consent or otherwise disqualify a patient from participation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>28 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>