<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02992925</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to: - (cohort 1) evaluate safety and immunogenicity (Haemophilus influenzae type b, Hib) of BK1310. - (cohort 2) evaluate efficacy of BK1310 for all antigens (anti-PRP, diphtheria toxin, pertussis, tetanus toxin, and polio virus), after 3 times of injection, when compared noninferiority with co-administration of ActHIB® and Tetrabik, as well as safety, in healthy infants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 3 Study of BK1310 in Healthy Infants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy infants aged ≥2 and &lt;43 months at the first vaccination of the study drug (recommended: ≥2 and &lt;7 months). Those who are applicable of the following conditions must be carefully observed before the enrollment: infants with known underlying disease such as cardiovascular disease, renal disease, hepatic disease, blood dyscrasia, respiratory disease or developmental disorder. Infants who developed fever within 2 days after any previous vaccination. Infants with history of convulsions. Written informed consent is obtained from a legal guardian (parent) With past diagnosis of immunodeficiency or currently under immunosuppressive treatment Have close relatives (the third degree of kinship) diagnosed with congenital immunodeficiency Possibility of anaphylaxis due to food or pharmaceuticals With experience of Hib infection, diphtheria, pertussis, tetanus or acute poliomyelitis With experience of Hib, diphteria, pertussis, tetanus or polio vaccination. Administered a live vaccine within 27 days before the first vaccination of the study drug, or inactivated vaccine or toxoid within 6 days before vaccination Administered transfusion, immunosuppressant (excluding drugs for external use), or immunoglobulin formulation Administered corticosteroid 2 mg/kg per day or more as prednisolone (excluding drugs for external use) Participated in other studies within 12 weeks before obtaining consent With the gestational age &lt;37 weeks or weighed less than 2500 grams at birth. Considered to be not eligible by the principal investigators (subinvestigators) of the enrollment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>43 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Haemophilus influenza type b</keyword>
	<keyword>Adsorbed Diphteria-purified Pertussis-Tetanus-Inactivate poliovirus combined vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Hib</keyword>
	<keyword>DPT-IPV</keyword>
</DOC>