<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01211483</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1b/2 study. In Phase 1b, subjects will know the treatment they are receiving. Subjects will receive Erlotinib + U3-1287. The Phase 1b portion will determine if adding U3-1287 to Erlotinib will be safe in subjects with advanced non-small cell lung cancer who fail prior treatment. In the Phase 2 portion, subjects will be blinded to the treatments they are receiving. Subjects will receive either Erlotinib alone or Erlotinib + U3-1287. The Phase 2 portion will determine if adding U3-1287 to Erlotinib will be safe and improve survival in subjects with advanced non-small cell lung cancer who failed the first treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Erlotinib With or Without Investigational Drug (U3-1287) in Subjects With Advanced Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed stage IIIB or IV NSCLC. Recurrent disease (either no response to treatment or subsequent relapse after an objective response) that has progressed after first line therapy. Measurable disease. ≥ 18 years of age. ECOG performance status of 0 or 1. Adequate organ and bone marrow function. Agreement to use effective contraception while on treatment and for at least 6 months after end of treatment. Treatment with anticancer therapy, antibody based therapy, retinoid therapy, or hormonal therapy within 4 weeks before study treatment. Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt; 45%. Therapeutic radiation or major surgery within 4 weeks before study treatment or palliative radiation therapy within 2 weeks before study drug treatment. Previous use of EGFRtargeted regimen, antiHER2, antiHER3, or antiHER4 therapy. More than 2 prior chemotherapy regimens for NSCLC (Phase 2 subjects only). Uncontrolled infection requiring IV antibiotics, antivirals, or antifungals, known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, or active hepatitis B or C infection at time of screening. Clinically active brain metastases.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>