<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01211626</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall study design includes two parts, Part A and Part B. Part A evaluated ANA773 following oral administration to healthy volunteers. A total of 40 evaluable healthy volunteers were enrolled in Part A of the study. Part B evaluated ANA773 following oral administration to patients with chronic HCV infection. A total of 34 evaluable patients were enrolled in Part B of this study in 2 study centers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of ANA773 in Healthy Volunteers and Patients With Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) to Assess Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics (PK) and Pharmacodynamics (PD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Design: Part A evaluated ANA773 following oral administration to healthy volunteers. A total of 40 evaluable healthy volunteers were enrolled in Part A of the study. Part B evaluated ANA773 following oral administration to patients with chronic HCV infection. A total of 34 evaluable patients were enrolled in Part B of this study in 2 study centers.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Part A Inclusion: Male or female, ages 18 to 65 years No clinically significant abnormalities No serious or severe chronic conditions Nonsmokers Part A Exclusion: Female subjects who are pregnant or breastfeeding History of significant medical condition that could interfere with study medication or associated study assessments History of or current drug or alcohol abuse Part B Male or female, ages 18 to 65 years Diagnosed with chronic liver disease consistent with chronic hepatitis C infection for at least 6 months Screening HCV RNA ≥ 375,000 copies/mL or ≥ 75,000 IU/mL Naïve to or have relapsed from prior IFNalpha based therapy Part B Female subjects who are pregnant or breastfeeding Received antiviral therapy or immunomodulatory therapy within 90 days prior to administration of the first dose of study medication Use of an investigational drug or participation in an investigational study with a licensed drug within 30 days History of significant medical condition that could interfere with study medication or associated study assessments History of or current drug or alcohol abuse</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>