<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00497575</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Long term follow-up of the patients with delayed TSH elevation or subclinical hypothyroidism has been seldom reported. The purpose of this study was to explore the diagnostic criteria for subclinical hypothyroidism and the initial dosage of L-thyroxine through long-term follow up for infants with subclinical hypothyroidism ，and evaluate the curative effect.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Diagnosis and Follow-up of Patients With Subclinical Hypothyroidism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Long term follow-up of the patients with delayed TSH elevation or subclinical hypothyroidism has been seldom reported. The purpose of this study was to explore the diagnostic criteria for subclinical hypothyroidism and the initial dosage of L-thyroxine through long-term follow up for infants with hyperthyrotropinemia，and evaluate the curative effect.All live-born neonates in province took part in the screening program from October, 1999 to September ,2006. Laboratory tests are performed as a time resolved fluoro-immunoassay (TRFIA). TSH is measured with a cut-off &gt; 9 mU/L. The diagnostic standard for subclinical hypothyroidism was: TSH ≥ 20 mU/L, T3 and T4 normal or low-normal ,or TSH &gt; 5.6 mU/L and &lt; 20 mU/L on initial determination and on follow-up or TSH levels increase on follow-up and/or gradually declining T4 levels.L-Thyroxine was administered for substitution therapy. After 2 years therapy，allround evaluation was performed. Compare the correlation to effects with different level of TSH、starting time of therapy and environment. Compare the effects between subclinical、temporary and permanent hypothyroidism.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypothyroidism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Congenital Hypothyroidism</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The diagnostic standard for manifest hypothyroidism and subclinical hypothyroidism was defined as follows: Hypothyroidism TSH &gt; 40 mU/L and T3 and T4 below the reference range or TSH &gt; 40 mU/L, T3 normal and T4 below the reference range [2] Subclinical hypothyroidism TSH ≥ 20 mU/L, T3 and T4 normal or lownormal or TSH &gt; 5.6 mU/L and &lt; 20 mU/L on initial determination and on followup or TSH levels increase on followup and/or gradually declining T4 levels.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Congenital Hypothyroidism</keyword>
	<keyword>diagnosis</keyword>
	<keyword>L-thyroxine</keyword>
	<keyword>newborn screening</keyword>
</DOC>