<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00103389</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as docetaxel, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. PI-88 may stop the growth of non-small cell lung cancer by blocking blood flow to the tumor. It may also help docetaxel work better by making tumor cells more sensitive to the drug. Giving docetaxel together with PI-88 may kill more tumor cells. It is not yet known whether giving docetaxel together with PI-88 is more effective than docetaxel alone in treating non-small cell lung cancer. PURPOSE: This randomized phase II trial is studying docetaxel and PI-88 to see how well they work when given together compared to docetaxel alone in treating patients with stage IIIB or stage IV non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Docetaxel With or Without PI-88 in Treating Patients With Stage IIIB or Stage IV Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Compare the safety and efficacy of docetaxel with vs without PI-88 in patients with stage IIIB or IV non-small cell lung cancer. Secondary - Determine the efficacy markers of docetaxel and PI-88 in these patients. - Determine the safety and potential efficacy of PI-88 alone as maintenance therapy in patients whose disease has been controlled with docetaxel and PI-88 combination therapy. - Determine the safety and potential efficacy of PI-88 alone as third-line therapy in these patients. OUTLINE: This is an open-label, randomized, multicenter study. Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. - Arm I: Patients receive docetaxel IV over 1 hour on days 1, 8, and 15. - Arm II: Patients receive docetaxel as in arm I. Patients also receive PI-88 subcutaneously once daily on days 1-4, 8-11, and 15-18. In both arms, treatment repeats every 28 days for up to 6 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients in arm II with stable or responding disease after 6 courses may continue to receive PI-88 alone as maintenance therapy. Patients in arm I with progressive disease or unacceptable toxicity before the completion of 6 courses may receive PI-88 alone as third-line therapy. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: Approximately 100 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of nonsmall cell lung cancer Stage IIIB or IV disease Eligible for secondline docetaxel Disease progression during or after completion of prior firstline therapy comprising radiotherapy and/or platinumbased chemotherapy PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 18 and over Performance status ECOG 01 Life expectancy At least 2 months Hematopoietic Neutrophil count &gt; 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count &gt; 100,000/mm^3 WBC &gt; 3,000/mm^3 No history of thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura or other platelet disease Hepatic Bilirubin normal ALT and AST ≤ 2.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) (1.5 times ULN if alkaline phosphatase &gt; 2.5 times ULN) Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 5 times ULN (unless bone metastases are present) PT &lt; 1.5 times ULN Activated PTT normal Renal Creatinine clearance or glomerular filtration rate &gt; 50mL/min Cardiovascular None of the following within the past 3 months: Myocardial infarction Stroke Congestive heart failure Immunologic No history of immunemediated thrombocytopenia No evidence of antiheparin antibodies No history of allergy and/or hypersensitivity to anticoagulants or thrombolytic agents, especially heparin No history of allergy to polysorbate 80 No uncontrolled or serious infection within the past 4 weeks Other Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy Not specified Chemotherapy See Disease Characteristics No prior docetaxel Endocrine therapy Not specified Radiotherapy See Disease Characteristics More than 3 months since prior radiotherapy to &gt; 30% of marrowbearing bone Concurrent local palliative radiotherapy allowed Surgery More than 4 weeks since prior major surgery Other More than 4 weeks since prior antineoplastic therapy More than 2 weeks since prior and no concurrent heparin or lowmolecular weight heparin More than 4 weeks since prior investigational therapy No concurrent aspirin or aspirincontaining medications except lowdose aspirin (≤ 100 mg/day) No concurrent nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs except cyclooxygenase2 inhibitors No concurrent warfarin or warfarincontaining medications except lowdose warfarin (≤ 1 mg/day) No concurrent antiplatelet drugs, including any of the following: Abciximab Clopidogrel Dipyridamole Ticlopidine Tirofiban No concurrent drugs that may inhibit docetaxel metabolism, including any of the following: Cyclosporine Terfenadine Ketoconazole Erythromycin Troleandomycin No other concurrent investigational drugs No other concurrent antineoplastic therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>