<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="33404">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02671760</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SM-A-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02671760</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pilot Study of a Combination Drug Product for Treatment of Short-term Insomnia</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Double-Blind, Single-Dose Study to Assess the Pharmacodynamic Effects of SM-1 Versus Comparator and Placebo in a 5 Hour Phase Advance Model of Insomnia in Adults Who Suffer From Short-Term Insomnia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sequential Medicine Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Clinilabs</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sequential Medicine Ltd</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effect of a combination drug product containing
      diphenhydramine, zolpidem and lorazepam on total sleep time. Participants will be adults who
      sometimes have difficulty falling asleep or staying asleep, but who do not have chronic
      insomnia. The study involves 3 one-night stays in a sleep center in New York City.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effect of a combination drug product containing
      50 mg diphenhydramine, 5 mg zolpidem and 0.5 mg lorazepam on total sleep time, and to
      determine the contribution of diphenhydramine to the combination, using a 5-hour Phase
      Advance model of sleep challenge. This is a 3-arm cross-over study; each participant will
      receive 3 single-dose treatments on consecutive visits. The 3 arms are: investigational
      combination product, placebo, and a 2-drug comparator containing the zolpidem and lorazepam
      components but not diphenhydramine. Participants will be adults who sometimes have
      difficulty falling asleep or staying asleep, but who are generally healthy and do not have
      chronic insomnia or sleep apnea.

      A total of 39 subjects are being recruited. Subjects who qualify for participation will be
      asked to keep a sleep diary to document their sleep times leading up to and during the
      study, and will be asked to spend 7-8 hours in bed at a regular bedtime during the study.
      Qualifying participants also will not anticipate significant disruptions in their sleep
      schedules, for example by traveling across timezones or changing shifts at work, during the
      study. The study requires 3 one-night stays in a sleep center in New York City, for
      administration of the study treatments and EEG measurements. Qualifying subjects will
      anticipate being able to return to the sleep center, located in Manhattan, for a total of 4
      visits, including initial screening and 3 treatment times.

      During each sleep center visit, subjects will be given their study treatment and be put to
      bed 5 hours before their usual bedtime, and sleep time will be monitored for 8 hours. Each
      subject will receive all 3 treatments, although the sequence of the 3 treatments will be
      randomized. Both subjects and study personnel monitoring the subjects will be blinded to the
      identity of the treatment administered at each visit.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Total Sleep Time</measure>
    <time_frame>8 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Latency to persistent sleep</measure>
    <time_frame>8 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Time it takes to fall asleep</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of awakenings</measure>
    <time_frame>8 hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Latency to REM sleep onset</measure>
    <time_frame>8 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Time required to achieve REM sleep</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability will be assessed in terms of the incidence, severity and relationship to treatment of AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>8 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence, severity and relationship of AEs to treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability in terms of residual sleepiness</measure>
    <time_frame>8 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Changes from baseline by treatment in the Karolinska Sleepiness Scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability in terms of residual sleepiness</measure>
    <time_frame>8 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Changes from baseline by treatment in the Digit Symbol Substitution Test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">39</enrollment>
  <condition>Short-term Insomnia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>SM-1</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Comparator</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>2-drug combination</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SM-1</intervention_name>
    <description>3-drug combination product containing 50 mg diphenhydramine, 5 mg zolpidem and 0.5 mg lorazepam</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Comparator</intervention_name>
    <description>2-drug combination comprised of 5 mg zolpidem and 0.5 mg lorazepam</description>
    <arm_group_label>Comparator</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Body mass index (BMI) between 19 and 32 kg/m2, inclusive;

          -  Report occasional difficulty falling asleep or staying asleep;

          -  Report a regular, habitual bedtime between 21:00 and 24:00, routinely spend at least
             7.5 and no more than 9.0 hours in bed each night and observe a bedtime that does not
             vary by more than 2 hours over the course of the week. Subjects will be required to
             complete at least 5 days of sleep information in a diary provided at the screening
             visit and returned to study personnel no later than 24 hours prior to check-in for
             the first overnight visit.

          -  Be in good general health as determined by a thorough medical history and physical
             examination including vital signs and clinical laboratory tests;

          -  Females of childbearing potential must be using an acceptable method of
             contraception, have a negative serum pregnancy test at screening and have a negative
             urine pregnancy test before randomization and prior to each Treatment Period.
             Acceptable methods of contraception include oral, intrauterine and injectable
             contraceptives or double barrier methods. After screening, subjects using oral
             contraceptives must agree to add a double barrier method until 30 days following the
             last dose of study medication. Female subjects relying on oral contraceptives must
             have been using them for at least one month prior to screening;

          -  Female subjects who have been surgically sterilized are eligible if they have a
             negative serum pregnancy test at screening and negative urine pregnancy test at
             check-in for Visits 2 and 3, or are post-menopausal as defined by the cessation of
             menses for a period of at least 2 years prior to screening or have had a complete
             hysterectomy;

          -  Male subjects must use an acceptable method of contraception during the course of the
             study and for the 30 days following the last dose of study medication. Acceptable
             methods of contraception include:

               1. Abstinence

               2. A condom and one of the following:

             i. Vasectomy for more than 6 months. ii. Female partner who meets one of the
             following conditions:

               1. Uses a spermicidal gel or foam; or

               2. Has had a tubal ligation, hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy; or

               3. Is post-menopausal (menopause is defined as over the age of 60 years, or between
                  45 and 60 years being amenorrheic for at least 2 years with plasma follicle
                  stimulating hormone (FSH) level &gt; 30 UI/L); or

          -  Be able to read, understand, and provide written/dated informed consent before
             enrolling in the study and must be willing to comply with all study procedures;

          -  Be willing and able to be confined to the clinical research site for one night in
             each of 3 treatment periods as required by the protocol.

          -  Refrain from alcohol on PSG days;

          -  On the days of check-in for each of the study's two treatment periods, refrain from
             the use of alcohol and from napping, defined as any sleep episode occurring outside
             of the subject's main sleep episode of the day;

          -  Report a recent history of napping of no more than once per week.

          -  An Epworth Sleepiness Scale score ≤8 at screening.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Clinically significant, acute illness within 14 days prior to screening (Visit 1).

          -  Clinically significant, unstable medical illness;

          -  Evidence or history of clinically significant allergic (except for untreated,
             asymptomatic, seasonal allergies at time of dosing), hematological, renal, endocrine,
             pulmonary, gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, hepatic or neurological disease;

          -  History of cancer or diabetes;

          -  A supine blood pressure &gt; 140/90 millimeters mercury (mm/Hg) at screening;

          -  Heart rate &gt; 100 beats per minute (BPM) at screening;

          -  Clinically significant psychiatric illness, including chronic psychiatric illness or
             the history or presence of any Axis I condition;

          -  History or presence of chronic pain;

          -  Lifetime history of seizure disorder or serious head injury;

          -  Clinically significant sleep disorder, including insomnia, sleep apnea, narcolepsy,
             parasomnia, restless leg syndrome or circadian rhythm disorder;

          -  Any condition that may affect drug absorption;

          -  Travel across more than three time zones, an expected change in sleep schedule or
             involvement in night shift work within one month prior to screening or during the
             study period;

          -  Any clinically significant abnormal finding on physical examination, vital signs or
             clinical laboratory tests, as determined by the Investigator;

          -  History of allergies, or known sensitivity, hypersensitivity, or adverse reaction to
             any drug similar to diphenhydramine, zolpidem or lorazepam;

          -  Pregnant or lactating females;

          -  Positive serum pregnancy test at Visit 1 or positive urine pregnancy test at check-in
             for Visit 2 or 3;

          -  Positive urine drug screen at the Visit 1;

          -  Recent history (≤ one year) of alcohol or drug abuse, or current evidence of
             substance dependence or abuse as defined by DSM-V criteria;

          -  Regular consumption of &quot;large amounts&quot; of xanthine-containing substances (i.e., more
             than 500 mg of caffeine per day or equivalent amounts of xanthine-containing
             substances);

          -  Self-report of a usual consumption of more than 14 units of alcohol per week. One
             unit of alcohol is equivalent to 12 ounces of beer, 4 ounces of wine or 1 ounce of
             liquor;

          -  Use of more than 10 products containing nicotine per day or routinely smokes during
             sleep period

          -  Discontinuation of smoking or participation in a smoking cessation program within 90
             days of screening;

          -  Any use with the six months prior to screening of restricted concomitant medications
             including prescription hypnotics, antidepressants, anxiolytics, anticonvulsants or
             narcotics;

          -  Use of any prescription drug, OTC medication, grapefruit juice, herbal preparation or
             food supplement, excluding vitamins, acetaminophen or hormonal contraceptives within
             two weeks of randomization;

          -  Use of any investigational drug within 30 days prior to screening or any prior
             exposure to the study drugs diphenhydramine, zolpidem or lorazepam or other drugs of
             the same pharmaceutical classes;

          -  Positive alcohol breathalyzer test at the time of screening or prior to dosing at
             Visit 2, 3 or 4.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas Dahl, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Sequential Medicine Ltd</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Maha Ahamad, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Clinilabs</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>September 12, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 20, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Short-term insomnia</keyword>
  <keyword>difficulty sleeping</keyword>
  <keyword>sedative</keyword>
  <keyword>hypnotic</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
