<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01955694</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will be conducted in subjects with clinical diagnosis of worsening chronic heart failure and either type 2 diabetes mellitus (DM) with or without chronic kidney disease (CKD) or moderate CKD alone treated with evidence-based therapy for heart failure (HF) for at least 3 months prior to emergency presentation to hospital using a multi-center, randomized, adaptive, double-blind, double-dummy, comparator-controlled, parallel-group design. Primary objective of the study is to investigate efficacy [percentage of subjects with a relative decrease in N-terminal prohormone B-type natriuretic peptide (NT-proBNP) of more than 30% from baseline to Visit 10 (Day 90)] and safety of different oral doses of BAY94-8862 given once daily.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase IIb Safety and Efficacy Study of BAY94-8862 in Subjects With Worsening Chronic Heart Failure and Left Ventricular Systolic Dysfunction and Either Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus With or Without Chronic Kidney Disease or Moderate Chronic Kidney Disease Alone</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ventricular Dysfunction, Left</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eplerenone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spironolactone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects with worsening chronic heart failure requiring emergency presentation to hospital and treatment with intravenous (IV) diuretics at hospital Subjects with either type 2 DM or moderate CKD Acute denovo heart failure or acute inflammatory heart disease, e.g. acute myocarditis Acute coronary syndrome (ACS) (elevated cardiac troponins which are not caused by an ACS are not an exclusion criterion) in the last 30 days prior to the screening visit Cardiogenic shock Valvular heart disease requiring surgical intervention during the course of the study Subjects with left ventricular assistance device or waiting for heart transplantation Stroke or transient ischemic cerebral attack in the last 3 months prior to the screening visit Addison's disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>BAY94-8862</keyword>
	<keyword>MR antagonist</keyword>
	<keyword>Heart failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Japanese patients</keyword>
</DOC>