<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01516541</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group study will evaluate the potential of dalcetrapib to reduce cardiovascular morbidity and mortality in patients with stable coronary heart disease (CHD), with CHD risk equivalents or at elevated risk for cardiovascular disease. Eligible patients will be randomized to receive either dalcetrapib 600 mg orally daily or placebo orally daily, on a background of contemporary, guidelines-based medical care. Anticipated time on study treatment is 4 years.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Dalcetrapib in Patients With Stable Coronary Heart Disease, With Coronary Heart Disease Risk Equivalents or at Elevated Risk for Cardiovascular Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyslipidemias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dalcetrapib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients, &gt;/= 45 years of age Established cardiovascular disease A stable coronary disease B cerebrovascular disease C peripheral artery disease Without established coronary disease D pharmacologically treated type 2 diabetes mellitus and one or more risk factor(s) for cardiovascular disease E 3 or more risk factors for cardiovascular disease Receiving evidencebased medical and dietary management of dyslipidemia Occurrence of myocardial infarction, hospitalization for unstable angina, stroke or revascularization (coronary, carotid or peripheral) within three months prior to randomization Uncontrolled hypertension Uncontrolled diabetes Concomitant treatment with any other drug raising HDLC Previous treatment with compounds targeting cholesteryl ester transfer protein (CETP)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>