<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT00442403</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>This study aim evaluate safety efficacy standard chloroquine drug regimen administration supplement dehydroepiandrosterone sulfate drug-resistant malaria .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Efficacy Chloroquine Associated With Dehydroepiandrosterone Sulphate Treat Uncomplicated Falciparum Malaria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Worldwide progression Plasmodium falciparum chloroquine ( CQ ) , amodiaquine sulfadoxine-pyrimethamine resistance leave alternative control malaria , particularly Africa . For strain P. falciparum P. berghei , resistance CQ AQ link increase reduce glutathione ( GSH ) level GSH-related enzyme activity , glucose 6-phosphate deshydrogenase ( G6PD ) . The pro-hormone dehydroepiandrosterone sulphate use potentiate antimalarial action CQ drug resistant P. falciparum strain , inhibit parasite G6PD activity . This hormone second advantage : metabolise human series potent immunomodulatory steroid may causal pathway allow induction protective immune response several infection , include malaria . This first study evaluate tolerance efficacy standard CQ regimen supplement dehydroepiandrosterone sulphate treatment drug resistant uncomplicated falciparum malaria .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chloroquine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chloroquine diphosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dehydroepiandrosterone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>sign inform consent ( informed consent give legal guardian child ) ; age egal 15 year ; fever ( axillary temperature egal 37.5 °C less 40°C ) history fever within last 24 hour ; sign suggestive febrile illness ; absence sign complicate malaria ( WHO criteria ) ; willingness participate followup 14 day positive thick blood film P. falciparum without detectable infectious microorganism patient take glucocorticoid immunosuppressive drug , indicate recent antimalarial drug history ( verbal questionnaire ) ; severe malaria ; mixed infection ; woman use contraceptive ; pregnant woman ; breastfeed woman .</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Malaria</keyword>
	<keyword>Plasmodium falciparum</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Chloroquine</keyword>
	<keyword>Dehydroepiandrosterone sulphate</keyword>
</DOC>