<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02937636</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This single-centre, examiner-blind, randomized, stratified, two-treatment, parallel group clinical study will evaluate the efficacy of a 0.454% w/w stannous fluoride dentifrice compared to a reference dentifrice to control gingivitis (gingival bleeding and visual signs of gingival inflammation) in dentally and periodontally healthy adult volunteers over 12 weeks use in a Chinese population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>To Investigate the Gingivitis Efficacy of a Stannous Fluoride Dentifrice in a Chinese Population</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This clinical study will be carried out in healthy adult volunteers with moderate gingivitis. Treatment effect will be determined by evaluating the efficacy, in a Chinese population, of a dentifrice containing 0.454% w/w stannous fluoride to control gingivitis and supra-gingival plaque following 6 and 12 weeks twice daily brushing, compared to a fluoride control dentifrice. During the 12 week treatment period, participant will brush with their allocated study product twice daily.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Gingivitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorophosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorides</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tin Fluorides</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Demonstrates understanding of the study procedures, restrictions and willingness to participate as evidenced by voluntary written informed consent and has received a signed and dated copy of the informed consent form. Aged 18 to 65 years. Understands and is willing, able and likely to comply with all study procedures and restrictions. Good general and mental health with, in the opinion of the investigator or medically qualified designee: No clinically significant and relevant abnormalities in medical history or upon oral examination, absence of any condition that would impact on the participant's safety or wellbeing or affect the individual's ability to understand and follow study procedures and requirements. A minimum of 20 natural teeth (all teeth; incisors, canines, premolars &amp; molars), and a minimum of 40 gradable surfaces for MGI, BI and PI. A scorable surface is defined as a surface that has 50% of the surface gradable for each clinical index. Third molars, orthodontically banded/bonded, fully crowned or extensively restored or grossly carious teeth are not included in the tooth count, moderate gingivitis present at the screening visit (in the opinion of the clinical examiner from a gross visual examination) and mean whole mouth MGI between 1.75 and 2.30 and a mean overall PI score &gt;1.5 at Baseline visit. Women who are known to be pregnant or who are intending to become pregnant over the duration of the study. Women who are breastfeeding Known or suspected intolerance or hypersensitivity to the study materials (or closely related compounds) or any of their stated ingredients. Screening: Currently taking antibiotics or requiring antibiotic use prior to dental prophylaxis or other dental procedures, currently taking an antiinflammatory medication or traditional Chinese medicines (TCM) which, in the opinion of the Investigator, could affect gingival condition, currently taking a systemic medication which, in the opinion of the Investigator, could affect gingival condition (e.g. calcium channel blockers, or aspirin therapy). Baseline (Visit 2): Has taken, or currently taking, antibiotics in the previous 14 days, or an antiinflammatory medication or a systemic medication days (e.g. calcium channel blockers, or aspirin therapy) which, in the opinion of the Investigator, could affect gingival condition in the previous 14 days. Have current active caries or periodontitis that may, in the opinion of the investigator, compromise the study or the oral health of the participants if they participate in the study, restorations in a poor state of repair, partial dentures or orthodontic appliances, teeth bleaching within 12 weeks of screening and use of a chlorhexidine mouthwash currently, or within 14 days of baseline. Participation in another clinical study or receipt of an investigational drug or investigational oral care product within 30 days of Baseline (Visit 2) and previous participation in this study. Recent history (within the last year) of alcohol or other substance abuse. An employee of the sponsor or the study site or members of their immediate family and employed by any dentifrice manufacturer or their immediate family.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>