<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02937818</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study design This is a Phase II, open-label, multi-drug, multi-center, multi-arm, signal-searching study in patients with extensive-stage small-cell lung cancer (SCLC) who have refractory or resistant disease from prior platinum-based chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase II, Study to Determine the Preliminary Efficacy of Novel Combinations of Treatment in Patients With Platinum Refractory Extensive-Stage Small-Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is modular in design, allowing evaluation of the preliminary efficacy, safety, tolerability, and immunogenicity of novel combinations of immunotherapies and/or deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) damage repair inhibitors in patients with platinum refractory or resistant extensive-stage-disease SCLC. Patient who has progressive disease (PD) during first-line platinum-based chemotherapy (platinum refractory) or PD within 90 days after completing first-line platinum-based chemotherapy (platinum resistant) will be enrolled to the study. The primary objective of the study is to assess the preliminary efficacy of each treatment arm based on objective response rate (ORR). This study will consist of a number of arms (sub-studies), each evaluating the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of a specific agent or combination. This study will open with 2 arms (Arms A and B), and additional arms may open, provided there is compelling rationale for the combination and safe and tolerable doses and schedules have been determined from ongoing Phase I studies. There are 2 pre-defined arms: A. Durvalumab + tremelimumab followed by durvalumab monotherapy B. AZD1775 + carboplatin (CBDP)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tremelimumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>GENERAL (APPLICABLE TO BOTH ARMS): INCLUSION: 1. Male or female ≥18 years at the time of screening. 2. Written informed consent and any locally required authorization (eg, Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act in the US, EU Data Privacy Directive in the EU) obtained from the patient/legal representative prior to performing any protocolrelated procedures, including screening evaluations. 3. Histologically or cytologically documented extensive disease American Joint Committee on Cancer Stage IV SCLC (T any, N any, M1 a/b), including patients with: T34 due to multiple lung nodules that are too extensive or have tumor/nodal volume that is too large to be encompassed in a tolerable radiation plan. Biopsyproven mixed SCLC and NSCLC histology Brain metastases; must be asymptomatic or treated and stable off steroids and anticonvulsants for at least 1 month prior to study treatment. Patients with suspected brain metastases at screening should have a computed tomography (CT)/magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the brain prior to study entry. 4. Patients must have demonstrated progressive disease (PD) either during firstline platinumbased chemotherapy (platinum refractory) or within 90 days of completing platinumbased chemotherapy (platinum resistant), and have not received further treatment apart from firstline platinumbased chemotherapy. 5. World Health Organization (WHO)/Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 01, 02 depending on the arm (please refer to the specific modular appendix for details). 6. At least 1 lesion, not previously irradiated, that can be accurately measured at baseline as ≥10 mm in the longest diameter (except lymph nodes, which must have a short axis ≥15 mm) with CT or MRI and that is suitable for accurate repeated measurements as per RECIST 1.1 guidelines. 7. Willingness and ability to comply with study and followup procedures. 8. Life expectancy of at least 8 weeks. 9. Adequate organ and marrow function as defined in each specific arm. 10. Evidence of postmenopausal status or negative urinary or serum pregnancy test for female premenopausal patients. Women will be considered postmenopausal if they have been amenorrheic for 12 months without an alternative medical cause. The following agespecific requirements apply: Women &lt;50 years of age would be considered postmenopausal if they have been amenorrheic for 12 months or more following cessation of exogenous hormonal treatments and if they have luteinizing hormone and folliculostimulating hormone levels in the postmenopausal range for the institution or underwent surgical sterilization (bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy). Women ≥50 years of age would be considered postmenopausal if they have been amenorrheic for 12 months or more following cessation of all exogenous hormonal treatments, had radiationinduced oophorectomy with last menses &gt;1 year ago, had chemotherapyinduced menopause with &gt;1 year interval since last menses, or underwent surgical sterilization (bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy). EXCLUSION: 11. Involvement in the planning and/or conduct of the study (applies to both AstraZeneca staff and/or staff at the study site). 12. Previous enrollment in the present study. 13. Participation in another clinical study with an investigational product (IP) during the last 4 weeks. 14. Concurrent enrollment in another clinical study unless it is an observational (noninterventional) clinical study or the followup period of an interventional study. 15. Major surgical procedure (as defined by the Investigator) within 28 days prior to the first dose of IP. Note: Local surgery of isolated lesions for palliative intent is acceptable. 16. Any condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would interfere with the evaluation of the IP or interpretation of patient safety or study results, including but not limited to ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirement, substantially increase risk of incurring AEs from the study medications, or compromise the ability of the patient to give written informed consent. 17. Radiation therapy to the chest and wholebrain irradiation must be completed at least 4 weeks prior to start of study treatment, and patients must have recovered from any acute adverse effects prior to start of study treatment. An exception to this is palliative radiotherapy for bone lesions and must be completed before the first dose of study treatment. 18. Past medical history of interstitial lung disease, druginduced pneumonitis, radiation pneumonitis that required steroid treatment, or any evidence of clinically active interstitial lung disease. 19. History of hypersensitivity to active or inactive excipients of any investigational drug in the study or drugs with a similar chemical structure or class to those investigated in the study. 20. Patients with Grade ≥2 neuropathy will be evaluated on a casebycase basis after consultation with AstraZeneca Study Physician. 21. History of another primary malignancy except for: Malignancy treated with curative intent and with no known active disease ≥5 years before the first dose of study drug and of low potential risk for recurrence Adequately treated nonmelanoma skin cancer or lentigo maligna without evidence of disease Adequately treated carcinoma in situ without evidence of disease (eg, cervical cancer in situ) 22. History of leptomeningeal carcinomatosis. 23. Spinal cord compression unless asymptomatic or treated and stable off steroids and anticonvulsants for at least 1 month prior to study treatment. 24. Female patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding. Additional arm specific inclusion/exclusion criteria can be found in protocol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>130 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Platinum Refractory Extensive-Stage Carcinoma, Small Cell Lung</keyword>
	<keyword>Platinum Refractory Extensive-Stage Oat Cell Carcinoma of Lung</keyword>
	<keyword>Platinum Refractory Extensive-Stage Oat Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Platinum Refractory Extensive-Stage Small Cell Cancer Of The Lung</keyword>
	<keyword>Platinum Refractory Extensive-Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>