<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02937922</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Introduction: Endothelial dysfunction precedes atherosclerosis being evidenced in patients with hypertension. Increasing physical activity levels and/or physical exercise are part of the recommendations of antihypertensive therapy. However, the effects of oscillations and/or increase the systemic blood pressure induced by exercise session on endothelial function has not been studied. Objective: To evaluate the effect of aerobic exercise, resistance exercise and combined exercise on endothelial injury levels in patients with hypertension. Methodology: Hypertensive (n = 51) and healthy subjects (n = 30) (30-59 years old) will perform at random 40 minutes of aerobic exercise (50-60% of heart rate reserve) or 40 minutes of resistance exercise (4 x 12 repetitions of exercises for lower limbs, 60-70% of one repetition maximum and 60-90 second interval) or 40 minutes of combined exercise (20 minutes of resistance exercise and 20 minutes of aerobic exercise, in that order). Blood will be collected 10 minutes before, 10 and 60 minutes after intervention for the quantification of endothelial microparticles (MPE) circulating (induced endothelial lesion) and endothelial progenitor cells (EPC) circulating (endothelial recovery capacity) by flow cytometry. Ambulatory blood pressure monitoring (ABPM) will be held before and after the intervention. Ultrasonography is used to measure the flow-mediated dilation of the brachial artery 10 minutes before, 10, 30 and 60 minutes after the intervention. Statistics: generalized estimating equation (GEE) for repeated measurements and Person correlation, being significant p &lt; 0.05. It is expected to show results to ensure cardiovascular protection in patients with hypertension caused by different types of exercise and consequent endothelial injury and release induced regenerative factors. Knowledge of the magnitude of injury and endothelial recovery provided by different types of exercise can contribute scientifically to health professionals aimed at prescribing exercise with a vascular protective vision in patients with hypertension.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Exercise on Endothelial Injury in Hypertensive Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults with hypertension; 30 to 59 years old. Diabetes; Heart disease; Participating in any regular exercise program over the last six months; Orthopedic impairments or any physical or mental limitation that prevents achievement of physical exercise; Body Mass Index in class II obesity or more (BMI ≥ 35 kg / m2); Smoking.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>59 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Endothelium</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Endothelial progenitor cell</keyword>
	<keyword>Endothelial microparticle</keyword>
</DOC>