<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01648205</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether late sodium channel blockade might be effective in shortening the QTc interval in various LQT3 mutations and be considered as a safe therapeutic option for LQT3 patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Study of Sodium Channel Blocker in LQT3 Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>LQT3 mutations in the LQTS Registry will be studied using in vitro expression studies to determine whether ranolazine causes a decrease in late sodium current, slower recovery from inactivation and/or changes in time course of inactivation, ameliorating the causative functional effect of each individual mutation. Individuals with select LQT3 mutations already studied in vitro will be invited to participate in a short term (2 day) study in the Clinical Research Center studying the effects of an oral dose of ranolazine on QTc duration and other ECG, echocardiogram and Holter-derived parameters. The same individuals, as well as other individuals with the same mutation, will be invited to participate in a 6-month study involving ranolazine and matched placebo, to help evaluate the long-term effectiveness of ranolazine in the population. Periodic ECGs and 24-hour Holter recordings will be obtained for evaluation of QTc duration and other ECG and Holter-derived parameters.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Long QT Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ranolazine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sodium Channel Blockers</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Genotyped positive for LQT3 (SCN5A) mutation Age 21 years or older Not currently taking an antiarrhythmic drug (beta blockers are allowed) Enrolled in LQTS Registry Age less than 21 years Not confirmed to have an LQT3 mutation Significant comorbidity that would preclude subject's safe participation in this study Females who are pregnant or nursing Females of childbearing age who are not using acceptable method of birth control Evidence of prior sensitivity to ranolazine Hepatic or renal disease that might adversely affect ranolazine excretion Currently taking strong CYP3A inhibitors Currently taking Pgp inhibitors Currently taking CYP3A inducers In vitro studies of specific mutation show no effect of ranolazine on late sodium current kinetics or show repolarization prolongation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ranolazine</keyword>
	<keyword>clinical trial</keyword>
</DOC>