<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01967511</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to establish the functional, molecular and genetic profile of fibroblasts from Fibromuscular Dysplasia (FMD) patients. This cellular profile will be compared against the profile of fibroblasts obtained from age- and gender-matched healthy control subjects. This cellular data will be supplemented by a detailed clinical history and evaluation, assessment of circulating protein and cytokine levels in FMD versus healthy control subjects, and DNA sequencing aiming to define the causative genetic mutation(s).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Defining the Basis of Fibromuscular Dysplasia (FMD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Specific aims - Specific aim 1: To establish a library of fibroblasts, DNA, plasma and serum from patients with FMD and unaffected healthy control subjects. - Specific aim 2: To compare the in vitro characteristics of fibroblasts from FMD patients and healthy control subjects. - Specific aim 3: To define and compare the genetic (DNA sequencing) and circulating cytokine profile of FMD versus healthy control subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibromuscular Dysplasia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients of any age and freely willing to participate. For patients &lt; 18 years of age consent will be via parents. Fluency in either English or Spanish. Signed, informed consent For FMD subjects a clinical diagnosis of FMD, with fulfillment of standard diagnostic criteria. For healthy controls no clinical features of FMD, and absence of any major ongoing systemic disease including any condition requiring hospitalization, immune suppression, intravenous or injected medications or that result in functional impairment in the performance of activities of daily living. Where possible, healthy controls will be unaffected family members. Healthy controls will be matched to enrolled FMD patients on the basis of gender and approximate age (within a 5 year window of another FMD subject). Patients who have comorbidities which reduces life expectancy to one year. Patients with any solid organ or hematological transplantation, or those in whom transplantation is considered. Active autoimmune disease. Illicit drug use. HIV positive. Prior malignancy. Any other form of vascular disease, including coronary artery disease or peripheral vascular disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cross-sectional study</keyword>
	<keyword>Fibromuscular dysplasia</keyword>
	<keyword>Fibroblast</keyword>
	<keyword>FMD</keyword>
</DOC>