<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02164864</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to compare a Dual Antithrombotic Therapy (DAT) regimen of 110mg dabigatran etexilate b.i.d. plus clopidogrel or ticagrelor (110mg DE DAT) and 150mg dabigatran etexilate b.i.d. plus clopidogrel or ticagrelor (150mg DE-DAT) with a Triple Antithrombotic Therapy (TAT) combination of warfarin plus clopidogrel or ticagrelor plus ASA &lt;= 100mg once daily (warfarin-TAT) in patients with Atrial Fibrillation that undergo a PCI with stenting (elective or due to an Acute Coronary Syndrome). The study aims to show non-inferiority of each dose of DE-DAT when compared to Warfarin-TAT in terms of safety. Safety will be determined by comparing the rates of bleeding events, assessed using the modified International Society of Thrombosis and Haemostasis classification of Major Bleeding and Clinically Relevant Non Major Bleeding Events.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Dual Therapy With Dabigatran vs. Triple Therapy With Warfarin in Patients With AF That Undergo a PCI With Stenting (REDUAL-PCI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ticlopidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clopidogrel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dabigatran</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ticagrelor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Warfarin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Male or female patients aged &gt;=18 years Patients with Non Valvular Atrial Fibrillation Patient presenting with: An ACS (STEMI, NonSTEMI [NSTEMI] or unstable angina [UA]) that was successfully treated by PCI and stenting (either Bare Metal Stent or Drug Eluting Stent) Or Stable Coronary Artery Disease with at least one lesion eligible for PCI that was successfully treated by elective PCI and stenting (either BMS or DES) The patient must be able to give informed consent in accordance with International Conference on Harmonisation Good Clinical Practice guidelines and local legislation and/or regulations. Exclusion criteria: Patients with a mechanical or biological heart valve prosthesis Cardiogenic shock during current hospitalisation Stroke within 1 month prior to screening visit Patients who have had major surgery within the month prior to screening Gastrointestinal haemorrhage within one month prior to screening, unless, in the opinion of the Investigator, the cause has been permanently eliminated Major bleeding episode including lifethreatening bleeding episode in one month prior to screening visit Anaemia (haemoglobin &lt;10g/dL) or thrombocytopenia including heparininduced thrombocytopenia (platelet count &lt;100 x 109/L) at screening Severe renal impairment (estimated CrCl calculated by CockcroftGault equation) &lt;30mL/min at screening Active liver disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>