<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01140516</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study focuses on the relationship between prophylaxis antibiotics and frequency of urinary tract infection in children diagnosed with antenatal hydronephrosis. Hydronephrosis is the most common fetal abnormality occurring in 1-5% of all pregnancies. Currently, with the widespread accessibility of antenatal ultrasound across cities in Ontario, the detection of hydronephrosis has become even more common. As a result, thousands of infants with hydronephrosis have been seen and managed by pediatricians, pediatric nephrologists, pediatric urologists, and family physicians. The investigators need to determine if antibiotic prophylaxis is effective in reducing the number of urinary tract infections in this population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Antibiotics Versus Placebo to Treat Antenatal Hydronephrosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Urinary Tract Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydronephrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibiotics, Antitubercular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trimethoprim</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Infants with AHN (one to seven months of age) confirmed postnatally with renalbladder ultrasound and/or a dilated ureter ≥ 7mm 2. SFU grade III and IV AHN (high grade hydronephrosis) 3. Patients without grades II to V VUR determined by voiding cystogram (includes UPJOlike and primary megaureter (hydroureteronephrosis) only); 4. Parent or legal guardian able to give free and informed consent 1. Infants with grades II to V VUR 2. Infants with posterior urethral valves or PruneBelly syndrome 3. Duplication anomalies (ureteroceles, ectopic ureters) 4. Other conditions that may require chronic use of antibiotics 5. Previous renal failure 6. Allergy to trimethoprim 7. Coenrollment in another intervention trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>7 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Antenatal</keyword>
</DOC>