<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01140971</DOC>
	<brief_summary>PURPOSE: The purpose of this study is to determine the effectiveness of balloon dilatation (Foley) with vaginal misoprostol for cervical ripening and induction of labor. METHOD: a randomized clinical assay has been performed with 160 women with indication of induction of labor, randomly divided in two groups, 80 for Foley catheter and 80 for misoprostol.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Foley Catheter Versus Vaginal Misoprostol for Cervical Ripening and Induction of Labor</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The cesarean delivery rate has risen dramatically in almost all world. Brazil shows the highest rate in the world so we need urgently efforts to reduce this fact. Several studies have shown that maternal morbidity and mortality rates are higher in cesarean deliveries. On the other hand an abdominal delivery cost much more than a vaginal delivery. A clinical trial to assess the performance of two simple and sheep methods can provide evidence based on local experience. Our results alow us to recommend both methods for clinical practice with a good possibility to reduce cesarean rates and without adverse events.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oligohydramnios</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pregnancy, Prolonged</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Misoprostol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Gestational age from 37 weeks, feto unic, alive and cephalic, Bishop index equal or lesser than four. uterine scar, premature rupture of the membranes, fetal weight bigger than 4000 g, previous placenta, conditions that imposed the immediate ending of the gestation.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Balloon dilatation,</keyword>
	<keyword>misoprostol,</keyword>
	<keyword>cervical ripening,</keyword>
	<keyword>obstetric labor,</keyword>
	<keyword>labor induced.</keyword>
</DOC>