<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01140334</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate methods to help people in substance abuse treatment receive better psychiatric care. Patients enrolled in the study will be offered three months of standard psychiatric treatment, which consists of weekly individual counseling and group counseling, as well as regular appointments with a psychiatrist. Patients will be randomly assigned to standard psychiatric care or standard psychiatric care plus voucher incentives. These incentives can be earned by successfully attending all scheduled psychiatric appointments each week. The investigators expect that patients in the voucher condition will attend more psychiatric sessions, which will lead to greater reductions in psychiatric distress.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment for Psychological and Drug Abuse Problems</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Male and female opioid-dependent patients at Addiction Treatment Services with any current psychiatric disorder (N = 100) will be randomly assigned to one of two psychiatric service conditions: 1) reinforced on-site integrated care (ROIC), with voucher incentives contingent on attending weekly psychiatric sessions; or 2) standard on-site integrated care (SOIC). Participants in both conditions will receive access to the same schedule and range of psychiatric and substance abuse treatment services. Participants will be assessed for 3-months post-randomization to determine rates of service utilization and adherence to psychiatric care, changes in scope and severity of psychiatric and psychosocial problems, and rates of drug use and treatment retention. Positive findings would have considerable heuristic and health care policy and practice implications. The entire study, including dissemination of the major findings at a national meeting and submission of the first manuscript, is designed to be completed within 2-years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 18 years of age Voluntarily seeking psychiatric treatment Meets DSMIV criteria for opiate dependence Meets FDA/CSAT guidelines for methadone maintenance Meets DSMIV criteria for at least one current psychiatric disorder Pregnancy Onset or acute exacerbation of a medical illness requiring immediate and intense care An organic mental disorder (e.g., delirium, dementia) Current participation in psychiatric care Mandatory psychiatric treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Psychiatric adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>Voucher incentives</keyword>
	<keyword>Methadone treatment</keyword>
</DOC>