<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01767610</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To develop combination product of micronized fenofibrate plus pitavastatin, we would like to evaluate pharmacokinetic drug interaction by comparing the steady-state pharmacokinetic characteristics of each arms after repeated administrating Lipilfen cap. 160mg(micronized fenofibrate 160mg)by Dae Woong Pharma. and Livaro tab. 2mg (pitavastatin Ca 2mg) by Joong Wae Pharm. through 3 period by separately or combinedly.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Pharmacokinetic Interaction Between Micronized Fenofibrate and Pitavastatin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fenofibrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pitavastatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Years 2055 2. Body weight≥50kg and 18≤BMI≤29kg/m2 3. Volunteer 1. Subject with serious active cardiovascular, respiratory, hepatology, renal, hematologic, gastrointestinal, immunologic, dermal, neurologic, or psychological disease or history of such disease 2. Subject with symptoms of acute disease within 28days prior to study medication dosing 3. Subject with known for history which affect on the absorption, distribution, metabolism or excretion of drug 4. Subject with clinically significant active chronic disease 5. Subject with any of the following conditions in laboratory test i. AST(aspartate aminotransferase) or ALT(alanine transferase) &gt; upper normal limit × 1.5 ii. Total bilirubin &gt; upper normal limit × 1.5 iii. renal failure with Creatinine clearance &lt; 50mL/min iv. creatine phosphokinase &gt; upper normal limit × 2 6. Positive test results for hepatitis B virus surface antigen, antihepatitis C virus antibody, venereal disease research laboratory test 7. Use of any prescription medication within 14 days prior to study medication dosing 8. Use of any medication such as overthecounter medication including oriental medication within 7 days prior to study medication dosing 9. Subject with clinically significant allergic disease (except for mild allergic rhinitis and mild allergic dermatitis that are not needed to administer drug) 10. Subject with known for hypersensitivity reaction to fenofibrate, fenofibric acid or statin 11. gallbladder disease 12. Subject who experiences photoallergy or phototoxicity during administrating fibrates or ketoprofen 13. Subject with genetic deficiency such as galactose intolerance, Lapp lactose deficiency or glucosegalactose malabsorption 14. Subject who is not albe to taking the institutional standard meal 15. Subject with whole blood donation within 60days, component blood donation within 20days 16. Subjects receiving blood transfusion within 30days prior to study medication dosing 17. Participation in any clinical investigation within 60days prior to study medication dosing 18. Continued excessive use of caffeine (caffeine &gt; five cups/day), alcohol(alcohol&gt;30g/day) and severe heavy smoker(cigarette &gt; 10 cigarettes per day) 19. Subjects with decision of nonparticipation through investigator's review due to laboratory test results or other excuse such as nonresponding to request or instruction by investigator</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>