<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01767714</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is to determine if NHL patients mobilized with G-CSF (10 µg/kg/day [GRAN® only]) plus 0.24 mg/kg/day of plerixafor are more likely to achieve a target number of ≥5 × 10^6 CD34+ cells/kg in 4 or fewer days of apheresis than NHL patients mobilized with G-CSF plus placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Plerixafor Plus G-CSF to Mobilize and Collect 5×10^6CD34+ Cells/kg in Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma (NHL) Patients for Autologous Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Eligible patients who are unable to achieve adequate apheresis cell counts may enter an Open-Label Rescue Period where they will receive plerixafor, following the same study schedule as during the Double-Blind Treatment Period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>JM 3100</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenograstim</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Has a biopsyconfirmed diagnosis of NHL Is in first or second complete remission or partial remission, defined for the purpose of this study as complete or partial response following first or secondline therapy Treatment with an autologous peripheral HSC transplant is planned and the patient is eligible for autologous transplantation Has an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 or 1 Has recovered from all acute toxic effects of prior chemotherapy or other cancer treatment. Has an actual body weight &lt;175% of their ideal body weight (IBW) The patient agrees to use a highly effective method of contraception from Day 1 through ≥3 months following plerixafor treatment. Concurrent serious illness and pathological conditions Has undergone previous HSC collections or collection attempt Has had any autologous or allogeneic HSC transplant Has active central nervous system (CNS) involvement Bone marrow lymphoma cells involvement &gt;20%, as assessed by bone marrow biopsy within 4 months before signing the ICF Has received radiation therapy to the pelvis Has a diagnosis of all leukemias including any type of CLL Active infection Pregnant or nursing Anticipated posttransplant chemotherapy and/or radiation therapy below the diaphragm Received any prior radioimmunotherapy Prior 1,3bis(2chloroethyl)1nitrosourea (BCNU) within 6 weeks prior to first dose of GCSF Prior cancer therapy, other investigational therapy within 4 weeks prior to first dose of GCSF Prior granulocyte/macrophagecolony stimulating factor (GMCSF) or pegfilgrastim within 3 weeks prior to the first dose of GCSF Prior GCSF within 2 weeks prior to the first dose of GCSF Inadequate organ funtion evidenced by unacceptable laboratory result</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>hematopoietic stem cell transplantation</keyword>
</DOC>