<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01207622</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the study is to investigate the efficacy of Atomoxetine (ATMX) in the treatments of adolescent and young adult Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) with comorbid Substance Use Disorder (SUD). The secondary objective of the study is to determine the efficacy of ATMX in preventing SUD relapse. As previous pre-clinical work has demonstrated that ATMX has led to significant improvement in ADHD in children and lacks abuse liability, the investigators hypothesize that ATMX will be efficacious in treating ADHD in adolescents and young adults with SUD, and that ATMX will also be efficacious in preventing SUD relapse.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Atomoxetine for ADHD in Adolescents and Young Adults With SUD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atomoxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female outpatients 1530 years. Subjects with a DSMIV diagnosis of ADHD (combined or inattentive subtype) as determined by clinical evaluation and/or ADHD module of structured diagnostic interview, completed by the study clinician. Subjects with a current or recent (within three months) substance use disorder (drugs or alcohol) as determined through clinical evaluation and/or ascertained through structured diagnostic interview. Subjects with an ADHD CGIS of &gt;= 4 (moderate impairment). Pregnant or nursing females. Subjects with a clinically unstable medical condition that will either jeopardize patient safety or affect the scientific merit of the study, or who undergo a change in treatment during the study. Recent history of intravenous drug use, or subjects who have current DSMIV criteria for abuse or dependence of cocaine, MDA, MDMA, gammahydroxybutyrate, methamphetamines, amphetamines, opioids, PCP, or benzodiazepines that in the opinion of the investigator will interfere in their ability to participate safely in the study. Subjects with Mental Retardation or Organic Brain Syndromes. Subjects who are psychotic or have a history of bipolar disorder. Participants who are taking any psychotropic or antiSUD medications will be excluded from the study. Current DSMIV diagnosis of major depression, depressive disorders, or anorexia as manifested by clinical interviews.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>