<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02469545</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to determine the influence of supplementation of probiotic Lactobacillus Plantarum 299V vs. placebo of probiotic during antidepressant monotherapy with SSRI (Selective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitor) in patients with major depression.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Lactobacillus Plantarum 299v Supplementation on Major Depression Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>For period of 8 weeks patient will receive probiotic Lactobacillus Plantarum 299V or its placebo as a supplementation of regular depression treatment with SSRI (Escitalopram or Sertraline). Psychometric and biochemical parameters will be monitored and evaluated. At day one, after 3 weeks (day 21) and after 8 weeks (day 56) of the study psychometric parameters will be measured such as Hamilton Depression Rating Scale, PSS-10 Scale, SCL-90 scale. At day one and after 8 weeks (day 56) of the study cognitive functions will be measured using: CVLT- California Verbal Learning Test, RFFT Ruff Figural Fluency Test, Stroop Test, Connecting Points Test (A and B), Attention and Perceptivity Test. At day one and after 8 weeks (day 56) of the study biochemical parameters will be measured such as: morning cortisol, pro and anti-inflammatory cytokines, tryptophan and its kynurenic pathway metabolites concentrations.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antidepressive Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sertraline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citalopram</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Serotonin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexetimide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Serotonin Uptake Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Unipolar depression, with at least one depressive episode, present episode since at least 2 weeks, with Hamilton Depression Scale scoring 18 and higher with BMI =18,9 29,9 kg/m2 Inflammatory diseases eg. rheumatoid diseases, inflammatory bowel diseases, autoimmunological diseases Metabolic diseases e.g. diabetes type I,II, obesity (Body Mass Index)&gt;30 kg/m2 Previously diagnosed other psychiatric diseases other than depression, psychoactive substances abuse, organic brain dysfunctions Smokers Patients after surgeries in last 3 months Oncological patients Patients during pregnancy or lactation Drugs which might influence measured parameters (e.g. lithium, antibiotics, glucocorticosteroids, antipsychotic drugs) Changes in routine blood biochemical parameters: morphology, electrolytes, Aspartate Aminotransferase (AST), Alanine Aminotransferase (ALT), creatinine, urea, Creactive protein (CRP), thyroidstimulating hormone (TSH).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>depression</keyword>
	<keyword>microbiota-gut-brain axis</keyword>
	<keyword>Lactobacillus Plantarum 299v</keyword>
	<keyword>probiotic</keyword>
</DOC>