<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02015468</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A prospective, randomized study investigating the possible benefits of immediate mobilization and frequent physiotherapy following a wrist fracture treated by volar plating. The current study will test the following null hypothesis: There is no significant difference between patients who receive a cast for the first 2 weeks postoperatively and then instructions in home exercises and patients who receive a cast for 2-3 days postoperatively and then have frequent sessions with a physiotherapist following volar locked plating for a extraarticular distal radius fracture, as evaluated by self-reported satisfaction after 3 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Value of Early Mobilization and Physiotherapy Following Wrist Fractures Treated by Volar Plating</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will focus on patients treated with volar locked plating following an extraarticular distal radius fracture. In a prospective manner the investigators intend to analyze hand function, x-ray and other parameters in order to investigate whether early mobilization and a targeted program of physiotherapy postoperatively leads to a better functional result and earlier return to a normal activity level. The investigators analysis will also focus on the safety of early mobilization with regards to possible detrimental effects on the osteosynthesis, bony union, associated soft-tissue injuries and functional outcome. The investigators also intend to assess the cost of more intensive follow-up and physiotherapy and do a cost-benefit evaluation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Radius Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Position prior to primary reduction: Dorsal tilt &gt; 25째 Radial shortening&gt; 6 mm Radial inclination reduced by more than 15째 Radiocarpal malalignment &gt; 7 mm Dorsal /volar metaphyseal comminution Volar displacement of the distal fragment(= Smith's fracture) Position after initial reduction: Dorsal tilt &gt; 5째 Radial shortening &gt; 4 mm Radial inclination reduced by more than 10째 Radiocarpal malalignment &gt; 4 mm 1. GustiloAnderson type III open fractures 2. Previous distal radius/ulnafracture and/or disabling hand injury of the same extremity 3. Previous distal radius fracture or other disabling injury to the contralateral side 4. Dementia or other psychiatric illness which affect compliance 5. Congenital anomaly 6. Bilateral radius fracture 7. Concurrent fractures to the upper or lower extremities or other illness which affect movement of the extremities 8. Systemic joint disease such as rheumatoid arthritis 9. Patients who do not speak Norwegian 10. Pathological fracture other than osteoporotic fracture 11. Congenital bone disease (for example osteogenesis imperfecta) 12. Age below 18 and above 70 13. Patients not belonging to Akershus University Hospital</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Distal radius fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>Wrist fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>Physiotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Immobilization</keyword>
	<keyword>Volar locking plates</keyword>
	<keyword>Mobilization</keyword>
</DOC>