<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01934127</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and immunogenicity of different formulations of GSK Biologicals H7N1 influenza vaccine in subjects 21 to 64 years of age. The study will evaluate safety related events and antibody immune responses to different formulations of study vaccine and placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunogenicity and Safety Study of Different Formulations of GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) Biologicals H7N1 Influenza Vaccine Administered to Adults 21 to 64 Years of Age</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female adults who are 21 to 64 years of age (inclusive) at the time of first study vaccination. Written informed consent obtained from the subject. Subjects who the investigator believes can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol. Healthy subjects as established by medical history and physical examination. Access to a consistent means of telephone contact, which may be either in the home or at the workplace, land line or mobile, but NOT a pay phone or other multipleuser device. For subjects who undergo a screening visit, results of all safety laboratory tests obtained at the screening visit must be within reference ranges. Results of any repeat testing cannot be used to qualify a subject for enrollment. Female subjects of nonchildbearing potential may be enrolled in the study. Nonchildbearing potential is defined as current tubal ligation, hysterectomy, ovariectomy or postmenopause. Female subjects of childbearing potential may be enrolled in the study, if they have practiced adequate contraception for 30 days prior to vaccination, and have a negative pregnancy test on the day of vaccination, and agree to continue to practice adequate contraception until 2 months after the last dose administered. Presence or evidence of neurological or psychiatric diagnoses which, although stable, are deemed by the investigator to render the potential subject unable/unlikely to provide accurate safety reports. Presence or evidence of substance abuse. Diagnosed with cancer, or treatment for cancer within three years. 1. Persons with a history of cancer who are diseasefree without treatment for three years or more are eligible. 2. Persons with a history of histologicallyconfirmed basal cell carcinoma of the skin successfully treated with local excision only are excepted and are eligible, but other histologic types of skin cancer are exclusionary. 3. Women who are diseasefree three years or more after treatment for breast cancer and receiving longterm prophylaxis are eligible. Diagnosed with excessive daytime sleepiness (unintended sleep episodes during the day present almost daily for at least one month), or narcolepsy. History of narcolepsy in subject's parent, sibling or child Presence of a temperature ≥ 38.0ºC (≥100.4ºF), or acute symptoms greater than "mild" severity on the scheduled date of first vaccination. NOTE: The subject may be vaccinated at a later date, provided symptoms have resolved, and all other eligibility criteria continue to be satisfied. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition including history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. Receipt of systemic glucocorticoids within 30 days prior to the first dose of study vaccine/placebo, or any other cytotoxic, immunosuppressive or immunemodifying drugs within 6 months of first study vaccine/ placebo dose. Topical, intraarticularly injected, or inhaled glucocorticoids, topical calcineurin inhibitors or imiquimod are allowed. Any significant disorder of coagulation or treatment with warfarin derivatives or heparin. Persons receiving individual doses of low molecular weight heparin outside of 24 hours prior to vaccination are eligible. Persons receiving prophylactic antiplatelet medications, e.g., lowdose aspirin, and without a clinicallyapparent bleeding tendency, are eligible. An acute evolving neurological disorder or Guillain Barré Syndrome within 42 days of receipt of prior seasonal or pandemic influenza vaccine. Administration of an inactive vaccine within 14 days or of a live attenuated vaccine within 30 days before the first dose of study vaccine/placebo. Planned administration of any vaccine other than the study vaccine/placebo before blood sampling at the Day 42 visit. Previous administration of any H7 vaccine or physicianconfirmed H7 disease. Use of any investigational or nonregistered product other than the study vaccine within 30 days preceding the first dose of study vaccine/placebo, or planned use during the study period. Receipt of any immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within 90 days before the first dose of study vaccine/placebo, or planned administration of any of these products during the study period. Any known or suspected allergy to any constituent of influenza vaccines or component used in the manufacturing process of the study vaccine including a history of anaphylactictype reaction to consumption of eggs; or a history of severe adverse reaction to a previous influenza vaccine. Known pregnancy or a positive urine betahuman chorionic gonadotropin (βhCG) test result before the first dose of study vaccine/placebo. Lactating or nursing women. Any condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, prevents the subject from participating in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Immunogenicity</keyword>
	<keyword>H7N1</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>AS03 adjuvant</keyword>
	<keyword>Adults</keyword>
</DOC>