<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00786331</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to compare time to progression between the combination pemetrexed-carboplatin and pemetrexed alone in previously treated patients with locally advanced or metastatic NSCLC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pemetrexed +/- Carboplatin as Second Line Treatment in NSCLC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In spite of the superiority of single agent over best supportive care in second-line NSCLC, the prognosis of these patients remains poor with a median survival of 6-7 months, justifying the evaluation of new regimens in this setting. An open question in the second-line treatment of NSCLC remains the possible superiority of combination chemotherapy over single agent, as it has been clearly demonstrated in first-line. Particularly, the addition of platinum to either docetaxel or pemetrexed should be further investigated especially in patients with prior response/stable disease to platinum-based first-line chemotherapy. Pemetrexed has shown anti-tumor activity in combination with other chemotherapy agents, including gemcitabine, vinorelbine, taxanes, cisplatin and carboplatin. In this multicenter, open label, randomized phase II trial, pemetrexed 500 mg/m2 and carboplatin AUC 5 will be administered on day 1 every 3 weeks until progression of disease or for a maximum of 4 courses in the experimental arm. The control arm will be pemetrexed as single agent at 500 mg/m2 on day 1 every 3 weeks until progression of disease or for a maximum of 4 courses.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>written informed consent Histologically or cytologically confirmed nonsmallcell lung cancer Unresectable stage IIIB, stage IV and unresectable local relapse or metastatic disease, with evidence of disease progression after first line chemotherapy which should have included a platinum agent. ECOG performance status lower than or equal to 2 Adequate hematological, hepatic and renal functions Life expectancy greater than or equal to 12 weeks Prior treatment with only 1 chemotherapy regimen for the treatment of advanced disease which should have included a platinum agent At baseline, presence of at least one measurable target lesion as per RECIST criteria Prior treatment with pemetrexed. Patients who are pregnant or lactating Patients with any underlying medical condition that might be aggravated by treatment or which cannot be controlled. Symptomatic brain metastases History of another malignancy within the past five years except basal cell carcinoma of the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix. Concomitant treatment with any other anticancer drug.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>second line treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>pemetrexed</keyword>
	<keyword>carboplatin</keyword>
</DOC>