<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00375440</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if tranexamic acid significantly reduces blood loss and blood transfusion in revision total hip replacement. Tranexamic acid is a drug that helps to reduce blood loss during surgery. Revision total hip replacement surgery is treatment for patients who have previously had hipe replacement surgery which failed and must be repaired/replaced.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tranexamic Acid Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Tranexamic acid is an anti-fibrinolytic agent that inhibits fibrinolysis leading to a reduction of blood loss without concurrently increasing the risk of thromboembolic complications. Several studies have shown that tranexamic acid reduces blood loss and blood transfusions in primary total hip and knee arthroplasty. However, there have not been any studies that evaluate its efficacy in revision total hip arthroplasty. The significance of this study is that the need for blood transfusions and their complications may be minimized in revision hip arthroplasty if tranexamic acid is found to significantly decrease the amount of blood transfusions. After the patient has been consented, he or she will be randomized into one of two groups (tranexamic acid and placebo) by the School of Pharmacy. The placebo will be crystalloid fluid of equal volume as tranexamic acid. The patient will then undergo revision total hip arthroplasty by Dr. Rosenstein and be administered tranexamic acid or placebo. Blood loss will be recorded intraoperatively and postoperatively through drains. Criteria for blood transfusion include hemoglobin less than 10g/dl or hematocrit less than 30%. Once the operation ends, the drug or placebo will be discontinued and the postoperative care is unchanged from current standards/protocols. Intraoperative blood loss, total blood loss, and number of blood transfusions will be recorded and analyzed. Length of acute hospital stay will also be recorded. A cost analysis will be performed comparing tranexamic acid to blood transfusions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tranexamic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Failed primary total hip arthroplasty (femoral stem, acetabular component, or both) 18100 years of age Prosthetic infection Primary total hip arthroplasty Prisoners Pregnancy Previous adverse reaction to tranexamic acid Bleeding/coagulation disorders Renal insufficiency (serum creatinine&gt;two standard deviations for age) History of deep venous thrombosis or pulmonary embolism Religious beliefs/practices prohibiting blood transfusions Wards of the state Cognitively impaired patients Terminally ill patients Students and/or employees Color blindness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tranexamic Acid</keyword>
	<keyword>Revision Total Hip Replacement</keyword>
	<keyword>Reduction in Blood Loss</keyword>
</DOC>