<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00368303</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is to investigate the non-inferior efficacy of Paroxetine Controlled Release to Paroxetine Immediate Release, as well as the drug tolerability profile when treated on patients with Major Depression.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Local Register Study For Major Depression Of Paroxetine Controlled Release</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paroxetine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with Major Depressive Disorder,score on depression rating scale reach a specific point(17 item Hamilton Depression Scale&gt;18). Exclusion criteria: patients use monoamine oxidase inhibitors (MAOIs), benzodiazepines, Chinese herbal medicines, acupuncture, moxibustion or other psychoactive medications other than zolpidem, zopiclone;diagnosed with other Axis I disorder other; not responsive to paroxetine therapy before; pregnant or lactating, have serious medical disorder or condition that would preclude the administration of paroxetine; have a history of seizure disorders (except for febrile seizures in childhood); require treatment with warfarin anticoagulants, phenytoin, cimetidine, sumatriptan, type 1C antiarrhythmics, quinidine or sulfonylurea derivatives; are substance abuse or dependence (alcohol or drugs) within 6 months prior to this trial; have had electroconvulsive therapy within 2 months of entry into the study; pose a current, serious suicidal or homicidal risk; have taken other psychotropic drugs or antidepressants other than MAO inhibitors within 7 days of baseline and MAO inhibitors within 14 days of baseline; have taken any investigational drug, or participated in a clinical trial within the past 3 months; are hypersensitivity to paroxetine; have undergoing formal psychotherapy/psychoanalysis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Major Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>paroxetine controlled release (CR)</keyword>
	<keyword>paroxetine immediate release (IR)</keyword>
</DOC>