<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02056496</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Pomegranate phenolics (such as the ellagitannin punicalagin and ellagic acid) are metabolized by the human gut microbiota to yield a number of metabolites called urolithins (mainly Uro-A). Both ellagic acid (EA) and urolithins can exert a number of biological activities. However, the bioavailability of ellagic acid has been reported to be very low and the existing studies are controversial so far. The investigators want to carry out a robust (cross-over, double-blind) pharmacokinetic assay in 20 healthy volunteers, using two types of pomegranate extracts (PEs). PEs with low (PE-1) and high (PE-2) punicalagin:EA ratio will be administered. The investigators will analyze blood and urine samples using UPLC-ESI-QTOF-MS/MS. The investigators will evaluate: - The pharmacokinetics of EA. - The effect of punicalagin:free EA ratio on the pharmacokinetics of EA and urolithins production.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetics and Bioavailability of Pomegranate Phenolics and Urolithins in Healthy Subjects.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Aged 1835 years. Healthy status (no illness in the previous 3months). Smoking. Pregnancy/lactation. Severe medical illness/chronic disease/ or gastrointestinal pathology (ulcers, irritable bowel syndrome, ulcerative colitis, Crohn disease etc.). Previous gastrointestinal surgery Recent use of antibiotics (within 1month prior to the study) Suspected hypersensitivity to pomegranate or any of its components Consumption of nutraceuticals, botanical extracts or other vitamin supplements or taking medication. Regular consumption of ellagitannincontaining foodstuffs (walnuts, pomegranate, strawberries, raspberries, oakaged red wine) (after filling a foodfrequency questionnaire). Intake of ellagitanninscontaining foodstuffs the week before the pharmacokinetic intervention.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pomegranate</keyword>
	<keyword>Ellagic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Urolithins</keyword>
	<keyword>Bioavailability</keyword>
</DOC>