<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01488123</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether a four-month manualized Ayurvedic intervention will improve quality of life in recent breast cancer survivors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Integrative Approaches for Cancer Survivorship</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cancer associated symptoms and impaired quality of life remain significant problems for patients despite advances in cancer treatment. Few effective treatment options exist for these symptoms. Integrative medicine is rising in popularity in the United States; however, few integrative medicine modalities have been rigorously studied. Ayurveda, a whole system of medicine that originated in the Indian subcontinent, has its own system of diagnostics and therapeutics, and among its strengths are wellness and prevention. We aim to perform a prospective single arm clinical study of a manualized Ayurvedic approach in breast cancer survivors with impaired quality of life. Specifically, we aim to develop the manualized Ayurvedic intervention; to assess feasibility; and to determine whether clinically meaningful effects can be achieved with the intervention.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Female breast cancer survivor who is over 1 month and less than 12 months beyond the completion of primary therapy (surgery, radiation, and chemotherapy) Having received chemotherapy as part of their primary therapy for breast cancer Be in a complete remission Aged 18 years or older Able to read, write, and understand English Karnofsky Performance Status (KPS) 67 greater than 60. Ability to give informed consent Having received Ayurvedic treatment within 2 months of study enrollment Receiving chemotherapy or radiotherapy at the time of study enrollment. Trastuzumab therapy is not exclusionary. Being within 1 month (before or after) of surgery for breast cancer (including breast reconstructive surgery). Smaller surgical procedures such as implant exchange are not exclusionary. Patients on adjuvant hormone therapy for less than 1 month</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast, Cancer, Survivorship, Integrative, Complementary</keyword>
</DOC>