<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01916798</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Intralipid can suppress natural killer cells that are known to be involve in repeated implantation failure and recurrent miscarriages.Intralipid is made of purified soybean oil, egg phospholipids, glycerol and water. It provides essential fatty acids, linoleic acid, omega- 3 and 6 fatty acids and alpha-linolenic acid. The effects of Intralipid in suppressing natural killer cell activity (NKa) were found to be comparable to intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) by laboratory experiments.We will study the effect of intralipid infusion on the pregnancy outcome of women aged 35-40 years with history of repeated implantation failure of miscarriage and who have positive peripheral blood natural killer cells</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intralipid Therapy for Women 35-40 Years With Positive Natural Killer Cells Undergoing Intracytoplasmic Sperm Injection (ICSI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Soybean oil, phospholipid emulsion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subfertile women aged 3540 years with repeated implantation failure or recurrent miscarriage with positive natural killer cells undergoing Intracytoplasmic sperm injection (ICSI ) cycle. women above 40years or less than 35 years Disturbances of normal fat metabolism such as pathologic hyperlipidemia,Lipoid nephrosis or acute pancreatitis with hyperlipidemia. Allergic to eggs, soybean oil, or safflower oil. Severe liver disease, kidney disease, lung disease, anemia, blood coagulation disorder. Uterine fibroid, endometrial polyp, endometriosis and hydrosalpinx. Antiphospholipid syndrome (lupus anticoagulant and/or anticardiolipin antibodies (Immunoglobulin G or M)[IgG or IgM]); other recognised thrombophilic conditions (testing according to usual clinic practice). Intrauterine abnormalities (as assessed by ultrasound, hysterosonography, hysterosalpingogram, or hysteroscopy). Fibroids distorting uterine cavity. Abnormal parental karyotype.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Infertility</keyword>
	<keyword>intralipid</keyword>
	<keyword>invitro fertilization</keyword>
	<keyword>repeated implantation failure</keyword>
	<keyword>repeated miscarriage</keyword>
</DOC>