<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01916694</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Diabetes in pregnancy (gestational diabetes) is becoming more common. It can lead to problems for both mothers-to-be and their babies such as causing a large baby and difficult birth. Gestational diabetes in the mother may also lead to effects on the long term health of the baby. Most people today use mobile phones. Our research is looking at using a mobile phone app to help with diabetes care in pregnancy. In particular, the investigators are using phones which connect to the standard blood glucose monitoring machines given to all women with gestational diabetes to see if sending the hospital team blood test results between clinic appointments can result in the need for fewer clinic visits. The investigators are also testing to see how acceptable using mobile phones in this way, is to our patients and that the control of the blood glucose and outcomes for the mother and baby are at least as good as standard care. The investigators are planning to recruit 200 women who receive care for their gestational diabetes at the Oxford University Hospitals NHS (National Health Service) Trust. They will be randomised so that 100 will receive standard care, and 100 will have a mobile phone "app" linked to the blood glucose machines to send blood glucose readings directly to the diabetes care team to review. Both groups will be asked to test their blood glucose levels at home regularly with a glucometer. All participants will also be given lifestyle advice to reduce the chance they will need medication. Blood glucose control will be measured also by the percentage of glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) at the time of diagnosis of gestational diabetes and before delivery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial of Remote Evaluation and Treatment of Gestational Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes, Gestational</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pregnant women with an abnormal 75 gram 2 hour glucose tolerance test as defined by the IADPSG (International Association of Diabetes in Pregnancy Study Group) Willingness and able to give informed consent Female aged between 1840 years Singleton pregnancy Able to travel to hospital independently Impaired cognitive function such that she is unable to operate mhealth equipment Any evidence of fetal compromise Known risk factors for obstetric complications, other than obesity and diabetes Gestational diabetes requiring immediate pharmacologic treatment Twins or higher order pregnancy OGTT (Oral Glucose Tolerance Test) suggesting preexisting diabetes (fasting blood glucose &gt;= 7.0 or 2 hour &gt;= 11.1 mmol/L Gestation greater than 34+6 at the time of potential recruitment Unable to speak English well enough to explain or use equipment</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gestational diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>m Health</keyword>
	<keyword>Smartphone</keyword>
	<keyword>Blood glucose monitoring</keyword>
</DOC>