<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02361086</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this clinical study is to determine the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics and activity of once-daily (QD) oral dosing of VT-464, a lyase-selective inhibitor of CYP17, in patients with castration-resistant prostate cancer (CRPC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate Once-Daily Oral VT-464 in Patients With Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 1/2 study of VT-464 in chemotherapy-naïve CRPC patients who are treatment-naive or who have failed prior therapy with abiraterone and/or enzalutamide. The study will examine several parallel QD dosing regimens of VT-464 using a traditional modified "3+3" Fibonacci study design. Approximately 3 dose-levels of VT-464 will be examined in each dosing regimen that is fully enrolled.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Patients must have documented histological or cytological evidence of adenocarcinoma of the prostate. Patients must have a minimum serum PSA level of &gt;2 ng/ml that is rising based on the Prostate Cancer Working Group 2 criteria. Patients must have castrate levels of testosterone (&lt;50 ng/dl [1.74 nmol/l]). Patients must have undergone orchiectomy, or have been on LHRH agonists or antagonists, for at least 3 months prior to study entry. Patients on LHRH agonists/antagonists must remain on these agents for the duration of the study. Patients must have an ECOG Performance Score of 0 or 1. Key Patients who have received prior cytotoxic chemotherapy for castrationresistant prostate cancer unless enrolled in a previous chemotherapy cohort. Patients who have received secondline antihormonal therapy, including ketoconazole, aminoglutethimide, or highdose estrogen within 30 days of study entry. Patients who have completed sipuleucelT (Provenge ®) treatment within 30 days of study entry. Patients who have received TOK001 (Galeterone®) or any other investigational product directed towards the androgen receptor or androgen biosynthesis. Patients who have received antiandrogens such as flutamide (EULEXIN®), bicalutamide (CASODEX®), or nilutamide (NILANDRON®) for &gt; 3 months must be off treatment for 6 weeks and demonstrate a continued rise in PSA after withdrawal. Patients on antiandrogens for &lt; 3 months must be off medication for 2 weeks. Patients on 5 alpha reductase inhibitors such as finasteride (PROSCAR®, PROPECIA®), or dutasteride (AVODART®) must stop medication at least 3 months from study entry. Patients who require pharmacological or replacement doses of systemic corticosteroids or who have received systemic corticosteroids within 30 days of study entry; use of topical, inhaled or ophthalmic steroids is permitted. Patients who have received palliative radiotherapy within 4 weeks of study entry. Patients with a history within the last 3 years of another invasive malignancy.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>castration-resistant prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>CYP17</keyword>
	<keyword>P450c17a</keyword>
	<keyword>lyase</keyword>
</DOC>