<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02361593</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to evaluate efficacy and safety of transparent cap-assisted endoscopic sclerotherapyI(lauromacrogol injection) in management of esophageal varices.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Transparent Cap-assisted Endoscopic Sclerotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Endoscopic procedures now play a great role in management of esophagogastric varices. Endoscopic variceal ligation(EVL) was recommended as first line therapy for primary and secondary prophylaxis in patients with esophageal varices. Previous studies have showed a superiority of EVL over endoscopic injection of sclerotherapy(EIS), mainly because of lower occurrence rate of complications. Procedure related complications were related to total amount of lauromacrogol, number of treatment and expertise of the endoscopists. Transparent cap has already been reported to assist in other endoscopic procedures, such as biopsy of Barret esophagus or endoscopic submucosal dissection. Accuracy and vision were improved with the help of transparent cap in the front of endoscopy. We have tried transparent cap-assisted sclerotherapy in some patients with in our hospital. Now a randomized controlled trial was conducted to evaluate efficacy and safety of transparent cap-assisted endoscopic sclerotherapy in management of esophageal varices.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal and Gastric Varices</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients presented to our hospital with esophageal varices diagnosed by gastroscopy, with or without gastric varices. The age of the patients range from 18 to 80 years old. Patients who have contraindications for lauromacrogol therapy or transparent cap. Patients who have no previous upper gastrointestinal bleeding history. Patients who have fecal disease that could greatly impact survival, such as uremia, advanced cancer or respiratory failure, et al.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>76 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>endoscopic sclerotherapy, esophageal varices, transparent cap</keyword>
</DOC>