<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02561676</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic pain (pain that is that is present for a long period of time) is very common among people with spinal cord injury (SCI). The purpose of this study is to compare how well two different web-based education programs reduce the level to which chronic pain interferes with daily activities and well-being.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Functioning in Persons With Chronic Pain Post-SCI Through Virtual Classroom Education</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Chronic pain (pain that is present for a long period of time) is common among people with spinal cord injury (SCI). The pain is often severe and can affect daily activities. Unfortunately, common treatments such as medications provide incomplete relief from chronic pain. Thus, persons with SCI have to find alternate ways to live a happy, healthy, and productive life, even with some pain. The purpose of this study is to compare how well two different web-based education programs reduce the level to which chronic pain interferes with daily activities and well-being.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>SCI for at least one year Chronic pain for at least three months that is moderate to severe Fluent in English Not currently starting a new pain treatment or changing a previous pain treatment Lack of access to a computer with highspeed internet access, at home or another location Cancer or conditions that may worsen over time (such as multiple sclerosis, Parkinson Disease, Alzheimer's disease) and may affect physical or mental functioning Significant difficulties with learning or memory Previous participation in a health and function education program specifically designed for people with chronic pain and SCI Inability to understand English well Other conditions not related to SCI that cause pain (such as fibromyalgia)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mindfulness</keyword>
	<keyword>Spinal Cord Injury</keyword>
</DOC>