<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02561767</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to determine the efficacy and safety of allogeneic bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells in kidney transplantation from Chinese donation after citizen's death (DCD). A pair uremia patients receiving kidney grafts from a same donor are randomized into two groups: MSCs group and control group. Besides routine induction therapy (ATG or Basiliximab) and maintenance immunosuppressive drugs (low-dose Tacrolimus + MPA + prednisone), patients in MSCs group are administered MSCs treatment (1*10^6/kg). Allogeneic bone marrow-derived MSCs (1*10^6/kg) are given intravenously at day 0 (post renal reperfusion during surgery), day 7, day 14 and day 21. The renal allograft function, rejection, patient/graft survival and severe adverse events within 12 months post-transplant are monitored.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of BM-MSCs in DCD Kidney Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Necrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Tubular Necrosis, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Basiliximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Primary kidney transplantation 2. Receiving induction therapy and combined immunosuppressive regimens (CNIs + MPA + steroids) 3. Patient is willing and capable of giving written informed consent for study participation and able to participate in the study for 12 months 1. Secondary kidney transplantation 2. Combined or multiorgan transplantation 3. Women who are pregnant, intend to become pregnant in the next 1 years, breastfeeding, or have a positive pregnancy test on enrollment or prior to study medication administration 4. Panel reactive antibody (PRA)&gt;20% 5. CDC crossmatch is positive 6. Donors or recipients are known hepatitis C antibodypositive or polymerase chain reaction (PCR) positive for hepatitis C 7. Donors or recipients are known hepatitis B surface antigenpositive or PCR positive for hepatitis B 8. Donors or recipients are known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection 9. Patients with active infection 10. Recipients with a history of substance abuse (drugs or alcohol) within the past 6 months, or psychotic disorders that are not capable with adequate study followup. 11. Patients with severe cardiovascular dysfunction 12. WBC&lt;3*10^9/L or RBC &lt;5g/dL 13. Highly allergic constitution or having severe history of allergies. 14. Patients with active peptic ulcer disease, chronic diarrhea, or gastrointestinal problem affect absorption 15. Patients with a history of cancer within the last 5 years 16. Prisoner or patients compulsorily detained (involuntarily incarcerated) for treatment or either a psychiatric or physical (e.g. infectious disease) illness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>kidney transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>mesenchymal stem cell</keyword>
	<keyword>donation after citizen's death</keyword>
	<keyword>ischemia reperfusion injury</keyword>
	<keyword>renal function recovery</keyword>
</DOC>