<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01929460</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Our hypothesis is that a single dose of antibiotics at time of EUS-guided pancreatic cyst aspiration is equally effective to the usual regimen of 3 days of post-procedural antibiotics.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pilot Study on the Use of Prophylactic Antibiotics for EUS-guided Pancreatic Cyst Aspiration</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>With the increased use of cross sectional imaging, there appears to be an increasing prevalence of pancreatic cysts being incidentally discovered. A critical step in the workup of pancreas cysts is to determine whether the cyst is mucinous or non-mucinous, through a procedure called endoscopic ultrasound - fine needle aspiration (EUS-FNA). Current guidelines suggest the use of antibiotics in cyst aspiration, usually 3 days after the procedure. However, these recommendations are based on limited data from over 15 years ago. More recent retrospective observations suggest equivalent safety when little, or even no antibiotics are given.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cysts</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Cyst</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ciprofloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibiotics, Antitubercular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients between the age of 1890 who present for an EUS / pancreas cyst evaluation Patients outside the age range Patientrelated factors (unable to provide consent, unable to understand English, allergic to cipro) Highrisk patients for infective endocarditis Bacterial infection or use of antibiotics within 6 weeks of EUS Pancreatitis within the past 6 months Underlying immunosuppression (for example, uncontrolled diabetes such as hemoglobin A1c above 7 or glucose &gt; 180; renal failure; cirrhosis; preexisting malignancy especially hematologic malignancy such as leukemia / lymphoma / multiple myeloma; HIV/AIDS) Currently taking immunosuppressive medications (for conditions such as rheumatoid arthritis, inflammatory bowel disease, organ transplant) Radiographic or endosonographic evidence of cyst cavity debris / necrotic debris Severe systemic disease (for example, NYHA class III or IV heart failure, oxygendependent COPD)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>