<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00988390</DOC>
	<brief_summary>- Context: Mothers living with HIV (MLH) and their children face predictable challenges: maintaining physical and mental health, parenting while ill, and addressing HIV-related stressors. - Objective: To evaluate the efficacy of a family-based intervention over time; to contrast the life adjustments of HIV-affected families and their non-HIV-affected neighbors in the current treatment era. - Design: Randomized controlled trial of MLH and a longitudinal comparison of MLH to a neighborhood cohort using random effect regression. - Participants and Intervention: MLH (n = 339) and their school-age children (n = 259) were randomly assigned to receive 1) an intervention of 16 sessions in a cognitive-behavioral, small-group format; or 2) control. MLH and their children were compared to non-HIV-affected families recruited at shopping markets. Participant retention was high: 84% at 6 months, 83% at 12 months, and 78% at 18 months. - Main Outcome Measures: Family functioning and conflict, mental and physical health, sexual behavior, and substance use.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mothers Living With HIV and Their Adolescent Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria for Intervention/Control, mother living with HIV: Mother or primary female caregiver Enrolled in HIVrelated clinical cares At least one child between the age of 6 and 20 years Inclusion Criteria for neighborhood control, nonHIVaffected mother: Mother or primary female caregiver not HIVpositive At least one child between the age of 6 and 20 years Exclusion Criteria (Intervention/Control/Neighborhood): Mother less than 18 years old Unable or willing to give informed consent Psychosis or neurological damage as judged by the investigator in consultation with clinical supervisor</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>mothers living with HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>family intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>family functioning</keyword>
	<keyword>conflict</keyword>
	<keyword>Mental health</keyword>
	<keyword>and physical health</keyword>
	<keyword>Family relationships (functioning and conflict)</keyword>
</DOC>