<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00988897</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: - To demonstrate that re-challenge with an oxaliplatin based regimen (modified FOLFOX-6) will provide a clinical disease control rate (DCR) of at least 20% at the end of the chemotherapy. Secondary Objective: - To evaluate other measures of tumour's responses and safety.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Colorectal Cancer RECHALLENGE</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Histologically proven adenocarcinoma of colon or rectum Measurable metastatic disease, either inoperable, or residual after surgical procedure No prior chemotherapy for metastatic disease For colon cancer: prior adjuvant chemotherapy with oxaliplatin that ended at least 12 months prior to enrollment. For rectal cancer: at least 12 months since prior use of oxaliplatin in neoadjuvant or adjuvant chemotherapy Adequate liver and kidney function: Total bilirubin inferior to 1.5 ULN Serum Creatinine inferior to 150 umol/L Creatinine clearance (ClCr) &gt; 30 mL/min ALT / AST inferior to 3 ULN Adequate hematological function Neutrophils &gt; or equal 1.5 x 109/L Platelets &gt; or equal 100 x 109/L Exclusion criteria: Metastatic disease presenting without prior adjuvant chemotherapy Metastatic disease presenting after nonoxaliplatincontaining adjuvant chemotherapy Peripheral sensory or motor neuropathy &gt; grade 1 Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance status &gt; 2 Other active malignancy History of known allergy to oxaliplatin or other platinum compounds, to 5FU, to Leucovorin or to any ingredients in the formulations or the containers Patients who are pregnant, or breastfeeding Patients with severe renal impairment (ClCr &lt; 30 mL/min) Pernicious anemia or other megaloblastic anemia with Vitamin B12 deficiency Patients with reproductive potential not implementing accepted and effective method of contraception (the definition of effective method of contraception will be based on the investigators' judgment) Participation in another clinical trial with any investigational drug within 30 days prior to study screening For patient who will receive Bevacizumab: Bevacizumab is contraindicated in patients with know hypersensitivity to any components of the product and to Chinese hamster ovary cell product or other recombinant human or humanized antibodies Presence of any symptoms suggesting brain metastasis The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
</DOC>