<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02363569</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective study, where the investigators will monitor pregnant women at 4-23 weeks of pregnancy coming to the "Women- E.R." at "Meir" Hospital due to spontaneous -or after intercourse- bleeding or bleeding secretions. The women will fill out questionnaires regarding past illness, vaginal bleeding, and gynecologic history. Then they will undergo full examination including ultrasound. After discharge, the investigators will recommend to all the women who came due to bleeding or bleeding secretions to avoid intercourse for two weeks after the bleeding stops. Afterwards they will be monitored until their delivery date (filling questionnaires a month after coming to the E.R. and at the end of the pregnancy). After they give birth the investigators will assess the rate of pregnancy, obstetric and embryonic complications in each of the study groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Prognosis of Early Pregnancy With Post Coital Bleeding</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective study, where the investigators will monitor pregnant women at 4-23 weeks of pregnancy coming to the "Women E.R" at "Meir" Hospital due to spontaneous -or after intercourse bleeding - bleeding secretions. The women will be divided in to two groups 1. Pregnant women (age 18-40) at 4-23 weeks of pregnancy with spontaneous bleeding or bleeding secretions 2. Pregnant women (age 18-40) at 4-23 weeks of pregnancy that have appealed to the "Women ER" 24 hours after bleeding or bleeding secretions due to intercourse. The women will fill out questionnaires regarding past illness, vaginal bleeding, and gynecologic history. Then they will undergo full examination including ultrasound. After discharge, the investigators will recommend to all the women who came due to bleeding or bleeding secretions to avoid intercourse for two weeks after the bleeding stops. Afterwards they will be monitored until their delivery date (filling questionnaires a month after coming to the E.R. and at the end of the pregnancy) The doctor that had examined the women, will have to fill out questionnaires regarding the bleeding source, the time after intercourse, how long after the intercourse the bleeding had appeared and which kind of examination he had carried out. A month after their appeal to the E.R. and after they give birth ,the investigators will assess the rate of pregnancy, obstetric and embryonic complications in each of the study groups, by phone.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<criteria>women (age 1840) with early pregnancy (423 weeks) with singleton or twins pregnancy that address to the "Women E.R." due to vaginal bleeding. age &gt;40 or &lt;18 women with history of more then 3 abortions. women with history of more then 2 pre term labor ectopic pregnancy placental previa women who takes anticoagulation therapy women with known pathology at cervix. women with known uterus defect. pregnancies with chromosomal defects or birth defects that was discovered at the screening tests.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>post coital bleeding</keyword>
	<keyword>vaginal bleeding</keyword>
</DOC>