<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01724359</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate efficacy, safety and tolerability of flexible, once-daily doses of paliperidone extended-release (ER) in patients with schizophrenia from Argentina and Colombia that previously failed treatment with other antipsychotic agents.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tolerability, Safety and Efficacy of Flexibly Dosed Paliperidone ER in Patients With Schizophrenia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single arm (one group of patients), open-label (all people know the identity of the intervention) multicenter 6-month study. Throughout the study flexible dosing of paliperidone ER in a range of 3 to 12 mg/day may be used. Flexible dosing will allow investigators to adjust the dosage of each patient based on the individual needs. Patients will receive 3, 6, 9 or 12 mg of paliperidone ER once daily for 6 months. The tablets will be taken orally. Adjustment of the dosage will be done at the investigator's discretion, based on the individual patient's clinical response and tolerability to the study drug.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paliperidone Palmitate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient meets the criteria for schizophrenia Patient is previously nonacute and has been given an adequate dose of an appropriate oral antipsychotic for an adequate period of time prior to enrollment, but previous treatment is considered unsuccessful due to one or more of the following reasons: lack of efficacy, lack of tolerability or safety, lack of compliance and/or other reasons to switch to another antipsychotic medication Patient is healthy on the basis of a physical examination and vital signs at screening Women must be postmenopausal for at least 1 year, surgically sterile, abstinent, or, if sexually active, agree to practice an effective method of birth control before entry and throughout the study Patients on clozapine, any conventional depot neuroleptic or risperidone longacting injections during the last 3 months Patients with serious unstable medical condition, including known clinically relevant laboratory abnormalities Patients with history or current symptoms of tardive dyskinesia and neuroleptic malignant syndrome Patients judged to be at high risk for adverse events, violence, or selfharm Patients with known hypersensitivity to paliperidone ER or to risperidone Patients with a current use or known history (over the past 6 months) of substance dependence</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Paliperidone extended-release (ER)</keyword>
	<keyword>Antipsychotic agents</keyword>
</DOC>