<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01724554</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to look at how effective, safe, and well tolerated Intravitreal Aflibercept Injection is in subjects with Central Retinal Vein Occlusion (CRVO) or Proliferative Diabetic Retinopathy (PDR).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Intravitreal Aflibercept Injections on Capillary Non-Perfusion</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Protocol available upon request.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Retinopathy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Vein Occlusion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosis of one or more of the following: Proliferative retinopathy (PDR) Macular edema secondary to CRVO Proliferative disease secondary to CRVO (anterior segment or posterior segment neovascularization). 2. Be in need of IAI treatment, whether previously treated or treatmentnaïve. 3. Age &gt; 18 years. 1. Subjects with macular edema secondary to diabetic retinopathy without concomitant proliferative diabetic retinopathy. 2. Subjects with cataract or other media opacities impairing adequate visualization of the retina to the extent that good quality images are impossible. 3. Presence of any substantial ocular disease (other than diabetic retinopathy or central retinal vein occlusion) that may compromise vision in the study eye and /or confound interpretation of the data; e.g. substantial cataracts, advanced glaucoma, optic neuritis, optic neuropathy or atrophy, marked macular atrophy, history of retinal detachment, uveitis, viral or other forms of chorioretinitis, etc. 4. Active intraocular inflammation (grade trace or above) in the study eye, or history of idiopathic or autoimmuneassociated uveitis in either eye. 5. Uncontrolled glaucoma in the study eye (defined as intraocular pressure ≥ 25 mmHg despite treatment with antiglaucoma medication). 6. History of rhegmatogenous retinal detachment or macular hole (Stage 3 or 4) in the study eye. 7. Participation in a study of an investigational drug or device within 30 days prior to potential enrollment into the study. 8. Intraocular surgery (including cataract surgery) in the study eye within 60 days preceding baseline. 9. History of vitrectomy surgery in the study eye. 10. Subjects with 12 or more antiVEGF injections within 24 months prior to Screening. 11. Subjects who received antiVEGF therapy within 30 days of Screening or received steroid or laser therapy within 90 days of Screening. 12. Subjects allergic to fluorescein, povidone iodine (Betadyne) or aflibercept 13. Pregnant or breastfeeding women.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>