<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01724346</DOC>
	<brief_summary>An Open-label Extension Study in Patients 65 Years or Older with Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL) or Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma (SLL) Who Participated in Study PCYC-1115-CA (PCI-32765 versus Chlorambucil)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-label Extension Study in Patients 65 Years or Older With Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia or Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study PCYC-1116-CA is an open-label, multicenter extension of Study PCYC 1115-CA (RESONATE™-2, the parent study), and it will run concurrently with the parent study. A patient will be transferred to PCYC-1116-CA after Independent Review Committee (IRC) confirmation of disease progression (PD) in the parent study or at closure of the parent study by the sponsor, whichever comes first. After PD, selection of second-line therapy, when clinically indicated, is at the discretion of the investigator and can include second-line PCI-32765 (for patients randomized to chlorambucil in the parent study who also meet the criteria for second-line PCI-32765 therapy), second-line chlorambucil (for patients randomized to PCI-32765 in the parent study), or other therapies. Assessments in the extension study vary depending on the treatment to which the patient was randomized in the parent study, the disease-progression status at transfer to the extension study, and the planned treatment in the extension study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorambucil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Randomized in the parent study, PCYC1115CA 2. Informed consent for Study PCYC1116CA 3. IRCconfirmed PD in the parent study PCYC1115CA or closure of the parent study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>CLL, SLL</keyword>
</DOC>