<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02257957</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Dry eye is a chronic condition that decreases function and affect visual function with severe discapacity until now treatments are based in artificial eye drops. Platelet rich plasma has emerged as a strategy for cellular restoration, the purpose of this study is to evaluate their effects in lacrimal production and safety of this intervention in patients with severe dry eye.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Platelet -Rich Plasma (PRP) Injection for the Treatment of Severe Dry Eye</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Dry eye is a chronic condition that decreases function and affect visual function with severe discapacity until now treatments are based in artificial eye drops. Platelet rich plasma has emerged as a strategy for cellular restoration, the purpose of this study is to evaluate their effects in lacrimal production and safety of this intervention in patients with severe dry eye.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Keratoconjunctivitis Sicca</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dry Eye Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sjogren's Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyaluronic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tetrahydrozoline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>• Patients with symptomatic Dry eye Shirmer ≤10 mm in 5 min BUT ≤10 seconds Corneal staining ≥3 Age range: 18 years and older. Both genders and all ethnic groups comparable with the local community. Able to understand and willing to sign a written informed consent Able and willing to cooperate with the investigational plan. Able and willing to complete all mandatory followup visits. • Patients who are currently engaged in another clinical trial, unwilling or unable to give consent, to accept randomization, or to return for scheduled visits. Children under 18. Pregnant women or expecting to be pregnant during the study. Systemic immune deficient conditions such as AIDS or under systemic immunosuppressant. Concomitant use of systemic antibiotics or steroids. Contact lens wear Active ocular infection or allergy Unable to close eyes or uncontrolled blinking</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>