<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02257723</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study investigates the effect of hospital-based intensive non-surgical treatment in musculoskeletal patients admitted to an integrated hospital that offers both complementary and alternative medicine (CAM) and conventional medicine treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Integrated CAM Treatment in Hospitalized Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study investigates the effect of hospital-based intensive non-surgical treatment in musculoskeletal patients admitted to an integrated hospital that offers both complementary and alternative medicine (CAM) and conventional medicine treatment. Inpatients received treatment according to a CAM treatment protocol (herbal medicine, acupuncture, bee venom pharmacopuncture, and Chuna manipulation) and conventional medicine treatment as needed. The main outcome measures were the duration of pain, NRS of back pain, radiating leg pain, neck pain, radiating arm pain, knee pain, shoulder pain, previous surgery, previous interventions (injections), Oswestry Disability Index (ODI), Vernon-Mior Neck Disability Index, the Korean Western Ontario McMaster Index, Shoulder Pain and Disability Index, range of motion (ROM), Straight leg raise test (SLR), alcohol use, smoking, exercise at admission, 2 weeks, and discharge.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neck Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Shoulder Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Stenosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intervertebral Disc Displacement</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients hospitalized due to spine or joint diseases Main complaint other than back pain, radiating leg pain, neck pain, radiating arm pain, knee pain or shoulder pain Cause of pain nonrelated to spine, joint or soft tissue; for example, spinal tumors, pregnancy, urolithiasis, etc. Refusal to provide the information needed for clinical research</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Inpatient care</keyword>
	<keyword>Complementary and alternative medicine</keyword>
	<keyword>Integrated medicine</keyword>
</DOC>