<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02257502</DOC>
	<brief_summary>After myopia, the second etiology of choroidal neovascularization (CNV) in young adults (&lt;50 years old) is idiopathic choroidal neovascularization (ICNV) whose etiology remains unknown. This is a rare and severe disease, which can lead to blindness. ICNV is treated at the moment with off-label anti-VEGF (Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor) therapy and could also benefit from aflibercept (EYLEA), a new anti-VEGF currently indicated in Age-related Macular Degeneration (AMD). Case reports suggest that such patients would not need as many injections as in AMD. INTUITION is an open-label, single arm, prospective, multicenter, phase II study. The main objective is to demonstrate the effectiveness in clinical terms after 52 weeks of treatment with aflibercept on the visual acuity of patients affected by ICNV. A specific dosage regimen is designed to achieve maximum efficiency. The patients are followed on a monthly basis until 52 weeks. Intravitreal injections of aflibercept are initiated with a Treat &amp; Extend (TAE) regimen until 20 weeks (3 mandatory injections with reinjection only in case of CNV activity). Then, a pro re nata (PRN) regimen is considered until 52 weeks (reinjection in case of CNV activity).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Evaluating the Efficacy of Aflibercept for the Treatment of NVCI in Young Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Choroidal Neovascularization</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neovascularization, Pathologic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 &lt; Age &lt; 50 years old Patient who give voluntary signed informed consent Patient affiliated with the French universal health care system or similar Patient with ICNV with active primary subfoveal, retrofoveal or juxtafoveal lesions that affect the fovea as evidenced by angiography (fluorescein and/or indocyanin green) and/or SDOCT in the studied eye Patient willing, committed and able to return for all clinic visits and complete all studyrelated procedures Pregnant women Sexually active men or women of childbearing potential who are unwilling to practice adequate contraception during the study Patient who is protected adults according to the terms of the law (French public health laws) Involvement in another clinical trial (studied eye and/or the other eye) Patient with nonICNV, especially: AMD High myopia defined as refraction ≥ 6 diopters Other curative treatment of ICNV in the studied eye during the last 3 months before the first intravitreal injection: antiVEGF therapy, juxta or extrafoveal macular laser, photodynamic therapy, surgery, external radiotherapy, transpupillary thermotherapy ... Medical history of retrofoveal focal macular laser photocoagulation in the studied eye Subretinal haemorrhage reaching the fovea centre, with a size &gt; 50% of the lesion area Fibrosis or retrofoveal retinal atrophy in the studied eye Retinal pigment epithelial tear reaching the macula in the studied eye Medical history of intravitreal medical device in the studied eye Medical history of autoimmune or idiopathic uveitis Proved diabetic retinopathy Intraocular pressure ≥ 25 mmHg despite two topical hypotonic treatments Aphakia or lack of lens capsule (not removed by YAG laser) in the studied eye Arterial hypertension that is not controlled by an appropriate treatment Previous or actual treatment with systemic administration of antiVEGF therapy Known hypersensitivity to aflibercept, or another drug composite of the medicinal product used; allergy to fluorescein, indocyanin green, anaesthetic eye drops Active or suspected ocular or periocular infection Serious active intraocular inflammation in the studied eye Medical history of intraocular surgery within 28 days before the first injection in the studied eye Any illness or ocular condition that would require an intraocular surgery in the studied eye within 12 months after the inclusion Follow up not possible during 12 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>aflibercept</keyword>
	<keyword>iodiopathic choroidal neovascularization</keyword>
	<keyword>young patient</keyword>
</DOC>