<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00843128</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objective: To evaluate the efficacy of robot-assisted gait training (RAGT) in MS patients with severe walking disabilities (Expanded Disability Status Scale [EDSS] 5.5-7) as compared to regular physiotherapy. Methods: Prospective, randomized, controlled clinical trial comparing RAGT with conventional walking training (CWT) in a group of stable MS patients (n=40) during an outpatient rehabilitation program. Inclusion criteria are chronic or secondary progressive MS patients with EDSS between 5.5-7, stable treatment 3 months before study entry, without generalized diseases. All patients will sign an informed consent. Following randomization, 20 patients will be treated with RAGT, 12 sessions over three weeks. The control group will be treated by CWT, 12 sessions in three weeks. The primary outcome measures will be the Functional Ambulatory Capacity (FAC) scale and the 6-minutes walking distance. The secondary outcome measures will be the Time up &amp; Go (TUG) test, 10 Meter Walking test, Berg balance test, EDSS score, FIM score and RAND questioner for quality of life. All tests will be performed by an external blinded assessor at baseline, after three weeks, and at follow-up after 3 months and six months. Importance: We anticipated that Robot-assisted gait training will be found as feasible and may be an effective therapeutic option in MS patients with severe walking disabilities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effectiveness of Locomotor Therapy Using Robot-Driven Gait Orthosis System in Multiple Sclerosis Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. chronic or secondary progressive MS patients with EDSS between 5.57, 2. stable treatment 3 months before study entry. 1. Other generalized diseases. 2. Pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2009</verification_date>
</DOC>