<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00476645</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if treatment with fulvestrant leads to a slowing of tumor progression in patients who have developed androgen-independent (AIPC) or hormone-refractory prostate cancer (HRPC) and who have a rising serum prostate specific antigen (PSA).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fulvestrant in Hormone Refractory Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to determine if treatment with fulvestrant leads to a slowing of tumor progression in patients who have developed androgen-independent (AIPC) or hormone-refractory prostate cancer (HRPC) and who have a rising serum prostate specific antigen (PSA). In vitro studies have shown that fulvestrant downregulates androgen receptor (AR) in LNCaP cancer cell lines to a significant extent, thereby inhibiting growth of tumor cells. In addition, it is important to emphasize that fulvestrant has also been found to decrease growth of AR-negative prostate cancer cells. These observations provide the rational for using fulvestrant for the treatment of AIPC and HRPC.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fulvestrant</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must give signed written informed consent Must be of age 18 years or older Histologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the prostate Must be currently receiving LHRH agonists and have castrate levels of testosterone or have had an orchiectomy Must have had rise in PSA despite antiandrogen withdrawal Must exhibit two consecutive rises in PSA after the last hormonal manipulation Minimum PSA &gt; 5mg/dL KPS &gt; 80% Up to one prior chemotherapy treatments allowed Life expectancy of greater than 6 months Concomitant hormonal therapy other than an LHRH Noncompliance Platelets less than 100 x 10e9 /L International normalization ratio (INR) greater than 1.6 Total bilirubin greater than 1.5 x ULRR ALT or AST greater than 2.5 x ULRR if no demonstrable liver metastases or greater than 5.0 x ULRR in presence of liver metastases History of bleeding diathesis (ie, disseminated intravascular coagulation [DIC], clotting factor deficiency) History of longterm anticoagulant therapy (other than antiplatelet therapy) History of hypersensitivity to active or inactive excipients of fulvestrant (ie, castor oil or Mannitol)</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>