<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00476463</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Combination therapy with anti-HBV activity may both increase HBV suppression rates and reduce emergence of resistant strains. Several new therapeutic agents are currently in development, however combination therapy trials in the HBV-infected population have only recently commenced. No such trials have been undertaken in the HIV/HBV co-infected population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Tenofovir and Emtricitabine in ARV-naive Patients With HIV/HBV Co-infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary study objective is to compare HBV DNA suppression to levels below the limit of detection (&lt;400 copies/ml) by week 48 in each treatment group. Virological and clinical anti-HBV efficacy of tenofovir and emtricitabine in antiretroviral naive patients with HIV/HBV co-infection.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coinfection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent Documented HIV infection (positive serology for HIV1 and detectable HIV1 RNA) Age 18 70 years HBV DNA &gt; 106 copies/ml HBsAg positive for &gt; 6 months In case documented duration of HBsAg seropositive is less than 6 months (this situation is most likely to occur in patients newly presenting to the HIVoutpatient clinic) the patient is eligible if the patient is: 1. HBsAg positive and 2. HBc core IgM antibody negative and 3. the liver biopsy gives evidence for a chronic active hepatitis. Thus making it likely that this patient has acquired the HBV infection more than 6 months ago. ALT &lt; 10 x ULN Creatinine &lt;= 2.0mg/dl Platelet count &gt;= 50,000/mm3 HIV1 therapy naive No prior exposure to antiHBV agents (LAM, adefovir, TDF) although prior IFN treatment allowed HCVRNA positive or AntiHAV IgM positive Acute hepatitis (serum ALT &gt; 1000 U/L) Prior LAM, TDF, or ADV therapy Active opportunistic infection Other causes of chronic liver disease identified ( autoimmune hepatitis, haemochromatosis, Wilsons disease, alfa1antitrypsin deficiency) Concurrent malignancy requiring cytotoxic chemotherapy Decompensated or Child's C cirrhosis Alfafetoprotein (AFP) &gt; 3X ULN (unless negative CT scan or MRI within 3 months of entry date) Pregnancy or lactation Any other condition which in the opinion of the investigator might interfere with compliance or outcome of the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>TDF+FTC</keyword>
	<keyword>FTC</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV/HBV</keyword>
	<keyword>TDF compared to TDF+FTC in HIV/HBV</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment Naive</keyword>
</DOC>