<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02146365</DOC>
	<brief_summary>One possible mechanism of protection from pneumococcal disease with a killed whole cell vaccine is by altering the carriage of pneumococcus germs in the nose and throat of those who get the vaccine. This study will look at nasal swabs from toddlers who received a killed whole cell pneumococcal vaccine (PATH-wSP) in VAC-010 and compare them to nasal swabs from toddlers of the same age who did not receive the PATH-wSP vaccine. This information will be used to help further develop the PATH-wSP vaccine. The research will be done in Kenya at one site in Kisumu (KEMRI). The study will enroll healthy Kenyan toddlers (12-15 months of age) who are participating in the VAC-010 study (N=250) and whose parents provide consent for this study. In addition 50 healthy Kenyan toddlers of similar age who did not participate in the VAC-010 study will also be enrolled. The toddlers will be followed for 6 months and will have 5 study visits. During those study visits each toddler will have their nose and back of their throat swabbed. The material from the swab will be analyzed for the presence and type of pneumococcal and other germs. At the last visit, one blood sample (5 ml or approximately 1 tsp) will be obtained. There will be no direct benefit to the participants other than direct and immediate medical care as needed. Parents of all participants will provide written informed consent.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nasopharyngeal Carriage Study in Healthy Kenyan Toddlers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pneumococcal Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For Toddlers Enrolled in VAC010: Randomization in VAC010. Subject's parent must provide voluntary written informed consent for subject to participate in the study, is fully capable of comprehending and complying with study requirements and procedures, able and willing to return for all scheduled followup visits, and has expressed availability for the required study period, with access to a consistent means of telephone contact. An illiterate parent will require an impartial witness to be present during consenting process to include discussing the consent form, verbal consent and thumbprinting. Subject has not completed his or her final vaccination in VAC010. For Toddlers NOT Enrolled in VAC010 (PCVprimedonly cohort): Healthy Kenyan toddlers between 12 to 15 (inclusive) months of age who have completed their primary EPI vaccines, with the exception that the birth dose of oral polio vaccine is not required. See Appendix A for a summary of the Kenyan EPI schedule. Subjects who have not received a PCV booster following primary PCV series. Subject's parent must provide voluntary written informed consent for subject to participate in the study, is fully capable of comprehending and complying with study requirements and procedures, able and willing to return for all scheduled followup visits, and has expressed availability for the required study period, with access to a consistent means of telephone contact. An illiterate parent will require an impartial witness to be present during consenting process to include discussing the consent form, verbal consent and thumbprinting. Subjects who were not born premature, had a birth weight of &gt; 2.5 kg, and who have a weighttoheight Z score of ≥ 2 at the time of enrollment. For Toddlers NOT enrolled in VAC010 (PCVprimed only): Use of any investigational or nonregistered drug within 90 days prior to screening, or planned during the course of study participation. Immunosuppression or immunodeficiency (inclusive of human immunodeficiency virus [HIV]) by medical history (inclusive of possible HIV through maternal fetal transfer at time of birth or through breast milk). Chronic, clinically significant pulmonary, cardiovascular, hepatobiliary, gastrointestinal, renal, neurological, or hematological functional abnormality or major congenital defects or illness that requires medical therapy, by medical history or clinical assessment. This includes abnormal vital signs as assessed by toxicity scoring (Appendix B). Any medical or social condition that in the opinion of the investigator may interfere with the study objectives, pose a risk to the study subject, or prevent the subject from completing the study. An employee (or first degree relative of employee) of the Sponsor, the Clinical Research Organization (CRO), the investigator or any site personnel. Disorders that require (d) chronic administration (defined as more than 14 consecutive days) of immunosuppressants or other immunemodifying drugs within the 6 months prior to enrollment. An immunosuppressant dose of glucocorticoid will be defined as a systemic dose &gt;10 mg of prednisone (adult dosage) adjusted for equivalent dosing in toddlers by weight. The use of topical glucocorticoids will be permitted. Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within the 6 months preceding enrollment in the study; or anticipation of such administration during the study period. History of meningitis, seizures or any neurological disorder. Subject who has evidence of congenital abnormality or developmental delay. Any evidence of fetal alcohol syndrome or history of alcohol abuse in mother during pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>