<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02146833</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label, Phase 2 clinical study of the oral Selective Inhibitor of Nuclear Export (SINE) Selinexor (KPT-330) in patients with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SHIP (Selinexor in Hormone Insensitive Prostate Cancer)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 2, open-label study to explore the effect of selinexor (KPT-330) therapy in patients with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC). Approximately 50 patients are planned for enrollment. Patients will receive an oral dose of Selixenor on one of three dosing schedules.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically proven adenocarcinoma of the prostate with evidence for skeletal metastases on bone scan and/or CT scan. Must have received at lease one agent known to impact survival (abiraterone, enzalutamide, ect.) Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) ≤ 2 or a Karnofsky Performance Status (KPS) ≥ 60%. Serum testosterone levels &lt; 50ng/ml Ongoing gonadal androgen deprivation therapy with LHRH analogues or orchiectomy. Patients, who have not had an orchiectomy, must be maintained on standard dosing of LHRH analogue therapy at appropriate frequency for the duration of the study Progression of disease despite androgen ablation shown by objective, documented evidence of disease progression (excluding PSA). Discontinuation of any glucocorticoids prescribed to specifically treat prostate cancer (e.g., as a secondary hormonal manipulation) &gt; 4 weeks prior to receiving first dose of study drug. Glucocorticoids prescribed for a chronic noncancerrelated illness (e.g., asthma or COPD) that is well controlled with medical management are permissible to an equivalent of ≤ 10 mg prednisone daily. Histologic variants other than adenocarcinoma in the primary tumor Patients who require or may be expected to require urgent treatment with docetaxel during the study (e.g., patients with visceral metastases). Therapy with other hormonal therapy, including any herbal product known to decrease PSA levels (e.g., Saw Palmetto and PCSPES) within 4 weeks prior to receiving first dose of study drug. Therapy with samarium153, strontium89, or radium223 within 8 weeks prior to first dose of study drug. Prior external beam radiation therapy completed &lt; 3 weeks or single fraction of palliative radiotherapy within 14 days prior to first dose of study drug. Any "currently active" second malignancy, other than nonmelanoma skin cancer. Patients are not considered to have a "currently active" malignancy, if they have completed therapy and are considered by their physician to be at least less than 30% risk of relapse over next 3 months. Active or uncontrolled autoimmune disease that may require corticosteroid therapy during study Severely compromised immunological state, including known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) Known acute or chronic hepatitis B or C Chemotherapy and other investigational therapies (targeted or immunotherapy) will require a 3week washout period before treatment initiation</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>castrate-resistant prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Karyopharm</keyword>
	<keyword>KPT-330</keyword>
	<keyword>selinexor</keyword>
</DOC>