<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02918513</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to explore the efficacy and feasibility of an integrated, prescriptive, and trackable wellness intervention combining five wellness elements including exercise, mindfulness, sleep, social connectedness, and nutrition.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>WILD 5 Wellness: A 90-Day Intervention (WILD = Wellness Interventions for Life's Demands)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study involves participating in a 90-day integrated, prescriptive, trackable wellness intervention, which includes five wellness elements: exercise, mindfulness, sleep, social connectedness, and nutrition. The intervention is divided into three phases (each spanning 30-days): Phase 1 - 'Boot Camp', Phase 2 - Solidify, and Phase 3 - Sustain. Program requirements include: Implementing 5 wellness interventions daily for the first 30-days, at least 5 days for the next 30-days, and at least 3 days for the final 30-days, documenting daily online adherence, completing daily wellness exercises to improve mental wellness, and completing online program forms prior to beginning the program, at 30-days, and again at 90-days. Once eligibility is confirmed via the initial orientation/screening call, study personnel will mail each participant a WILD 5 Wellness Workbook within one day of emailing participants their unique identification codes plus their start dates. Participants will be instructed to document adherence regarding their daily wellness practices and their daily wellness exercises online via Qualtrics, an online survey software. Participants can document their daily adherence using their computer and/or their smartphone as Qualtrics offers a mobile version of the Participant Tracking Form. A copy of the Participant Tracking Form will also be available in the WILD 5 Workbook so participants that prefer keeping a daily paper log can do so, and they can then transfer their program adherence information to the online Participant Tracking Form throughout the program. The workbook will contain the participant's personal identification code; no personal identification will appear in the workbook in order to protect participant confidentiality. One day prior to a participant's start date, which will be set during the orientation/screening call, participants will receive an automated email from an online automated email service (MailChimp), with a reminder about their start date, and encouragement to contact study personnel with any questions or concerns. Participants will also receive daily motivational emails from an online automated email service (MailChimp), which will provide general information about one of the five wellness elements and/or one of the wellness exercises, as well as encouragement to track their participation on a daily basis, and encouragement to contact study personnel via email with any questions and/or concerns.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress, Psychological</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults (18 years of age or older) English speaking Access to a reliable Internetenabled computer Possess basic computer skills Selfidentify as having at least one of the health conditions listed on the online registration form or Selfidentify as a community participant without a health condition. Acutely suicidal and/or actively psychotic NonEnglish speaking Do not have access to an Internetenabled computer Report a lack of basic computer skills Pregnant or plan to get pregnant during the next 90days.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Wellness</keyword>
	<keyword>Mental Wellness</keyword>
	<keyword>Well-Being</keyword>
</DOC>