<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01404806</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to describe drug concentrations of an investigational HIV medication, GSK1349572, in blood plasma, cervicovaginal fluid, vaginal and cervical tissue in HIV negative women.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>GSK1349572 Exposure in Blood, Cervicovaginal Fluid, and Cervical and Vaginal Tissue in Healthy Female Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Purpose: The purpose of this study is to describe first dose and steady state pharmacokinetics of GSK1349572 in cervicovaginal fluid (CVF) and vaginal (VT) and cervical (CT) tissue compared to blood plasma (BP) in HIV-1 negative women. Based on current literature, GSK1349572 has demonstrated a desirable pharmacokinetic profile in BP, including low to moderate pharmacokinetic variability (CV% 9-41), extended t1/2 (13-15h) and trough concentrations which remain 25-fold higher than the protein-adjusted IC90 ~0.064µg/mL for wild type virus. Understanding pharmacokinetic behavior of GSK1349572 in multiple female biological compartments will inform its role in sterilizing the genital tract in HIV-infected women, as well as protect mucosal tissue against HIV infection (pre/post-exposure prophylaxis).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dolutegravir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy premenopausal female subjects between the ages of 18 and 35 years, inclusive, with an intact uterus and cervix. Body Mass Index (BMI) of approximately 1830 kg/m2 and a total body weight of &gt;50kg (110 lbs) Negative serum pregnancy test at screening and should be using at least one of the following methods of contraception: 1. Abstinence 2. Bilateral tubal ligation 3. Condom with spermicidal gel or foam 4. Stable male partner who has had a vasectomy, or stable female only partners 5. Hormonal contraceptives (oral) provided the subject remains on the treatment until the followup visit and has been using oral contraceptives for at least 3 months prior to the first dose of trial medication Must agree to abstain from use of intravaginal products for 72 hours prior to the screening visit Must agree to abstain from any sexual activity for 72 hours prior to the Day 1 study visit and through study completion Previous gynecological examination with documentation of a normal Pap smear within the last year as part of clinical care Regular menstrual cycles with at least 21 days between menses (unless on contraception that causes amenorrhea or irregular menses) Evidence or history of clinically significant hematological, renal, endocrine, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, hepatic, psychiatric, neurologic, or allergic disease (including drug allergies, but excluding untreated, asymptomatic, seasonal allergies at time of dosing) History of hysterectomy, loop electrosurgical excision procedure (LEEP), conization or cryosurgery Pregnant or lactating Unwilling to refrain from sexual intercourse or from using intravaginal medications/products from 72 hours prior to Day 1 until discharge from the study Any condition possibly affecting drug absorption (eg, gastrectomy) Positive urine drug screen Active hepatitis B infection Active hepatitis C infection A positive test for bacterial vaginosis, syphilis, gonorrhea, chlamydia, HIV, HSV2 (active lesions) or trichomonas at screening History of regular use of tobacco or nicotinecontaining products exceeding 5 cigarettes per day within 3 months prior to screening History of regular alcohol consumption exceeding 14 drinks [1 drink = 5 ounces (150mL)] of wine or 12 ounces (360mL) of beer or 1.5 ounces (45mL) of spirits per week History of bleeding or clotting disorders Documented allergic reaction to lidocaine, silver nitrate, ferric subsulfate solution (Monsel's solution) or any iron containing products. Treatment with an investigational drug within 4 months preceding the first dose of trial medication. Use of clinically significant prescription or nonprescription drugs within 7 days prior to the first dose of study medication, unless in the opinion of the Investigator and GSK Medical Monitor the medication will not interfere with the study procedures or compromise subject safety. Blood donation of approximately 1 pint (500mL) within 56 days prior to dosing. History of sensitivity to heparin or heparininduced thrombocytopenia. Unwilling to abstain from alcohol use from 48 hours prior to the first dose of study medication until after the followup visit. Using an intrauterine device for contraception. Using depomedroxyprogesterone (DepoProvera®) for contraception. Systolic blood pressure is outside the range of 90140mmHg, diastolic blood pressure is outside the range of 4590mmHg or heart rate is outside the range of 50100 bpm for female subjects even after a single repeat reading. Any clinically significant abnormalities to pulse or conduction observed on screening ECG</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>