<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00345007</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Assess recovery of macula function after successful scleral buckling surgery for rhegmatogenous retinal detachment by using the multifocal ERG in the postoperative period i.e. recovery of functional integrity 2. Assess the relationship between the neurosensory retina and the retinal pigment epithelium/choriocapillaris after scleral buckling i.e. recovery of structural integrity 3. Assess if there is a difference between macula function postoperatively, in eyes with retinal detachments involving the macula and those that do not.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Macular Function After Scleral Buckle</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with acute rhegmatogenous retinal detachments managed by scleral buckling surgery will be recruited into 3 groups. (Please see attached appendix A) We define the area of the macula as the area within the temporal vascular arcades with the horizontal radius defined between the optic disc and the foveal centre. Group A: Macula not detached Group B: Macula partially detached i.e. detachment stops within the macula Group C: Macula is totally detached After scleral buckling surgery for the retinal detachment, the patients will be examined at Day 1, week 1, month1, 3 and 6. During these visits, they will be examined clinically, as well as undergo tests - refraction, colour vision (D-15) &amp; contrast sensitivity testing, OCT and multifocal ERG. (Please see attaced visit schedule).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Detachment</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Acute rhegmatogenous retinal detachment undergoing scleral buckling surgery Only eye patients Patients who undergo surgery which require use of intravitreal gases Patients who will not be able to cooperate for the mfERG and OCT testing Patients with macula hole detachments Fellow eye with poor vision resulting in inability to fixate for the mfERG</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2005</verification_date>
	<keyword>Retinal detachment</keyword>
	<keyword>Macular function</keyword>
	<keyword>Multifocal electrophysiology</keyword>
</DOC>