<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02347839</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to studying neoadjuvant gefitinib followed by surgery, followed by adjuvant gefitinib to see how well it works in treating patients with unresectable stage III NSCLC harboring EGFR mutations.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>NEoadjuvant Gefitinib fOllowed by Surgery and gefiTinib In unresectAble sTage III NSCLC With EGFR Mutations.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Concurrent chemoradiotherapy is the recommended therapeutic approach for patients with unresectable stage III non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), although surgery offers the chance of cure. With combined-modality therapy with radiation therapy and chemotherapy, the prognosis of stage III NSCLC remains poor. Gefitinib has shown great efficacy in NSCLC patients with EGFR mutations. This study is to studying neoadjuvant gefitinib followed by surgery, followed by adjuvant gefitinib to see how well it works in treating patients with unresectable EGFR mutant stage III NSCLC.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gefitinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Target population is unresectable stage III (III Abulky N2, III B) NSCLC with EGFR activating mutation in exon 19 or 21 Written informed consent provided Aged 1875 years Able to comply with the required protocol and followup procedures Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 01 Had a life expectancy of 12 weeks or more Adequate hematological function, liver function and renal function Female participants should not be pregnant or breastfeeding Known severe hypersensitivity to gefitinib or any of the excipients of this product Inability to comply with protocol or study procedures Had had previous chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or agents directed at the HER axis (e.g. erlotinib, gefitinib, cetuximab, trastuzumab) Had a history another malignancy in the last 5 years with the exception of cured basal cell carcinoma of the skin, cured in situ carcinoma of the uterine cervix and cured epithelial carcinoma of the bladder Interstitial pneumonia Eye inflammation not fully controlled or conditions predisposing the subject to this Any unstable systemic disease (including active infection, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable angina, congestive heart failure, myocardial infarction within the previous year, serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication, hepatic, renal, or metabolic disease) Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection Pregnancy or breastfeeding women History of neurologic or psychiatric disorders Ingredients mixed with small cell lung cancer patients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>