<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02347930</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Establish an integrated evaluation system of ultrasound technology for the prognosis of acute kidney injury, and in order to achieve non-invasive, reliable early diagnosis "gold standard". Set up collabration with the expert in National Cheng Kung University Medical Center of Taiwan who did a lot of excellent work in basic research of prevention the progression of acut kidney injury. Study the experience about prevention progression of kidney disease in clinical and basic field. Establish cooperation with the professional in Hong Kong University of Science and Technology. To set up the system of natural products research and assess the Astragalus medicinal value.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Establish and Apply the Evaluation System of Ultrasonic Integrated Technology for Prevention and Treatment of Acute Kidney Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must satisfy the following criteria to be enrolled in the study: 1. Clinical diagnosis of acute or chronic kidney injury 2. Male or female, aged 1880 years old 3. signed informed consent 4. Patients can breathe in, breathe out and hold their breathe with ease, communication without difficulty. Potential subjects who meet any of the following criteria will be excluded from participating in the study: 1. Refuse to sign informed consent 2. allergy to micro bubble hexafluoride drug 3. Patients with cardiopulmonary insufficiency, pleural effusion, pulmonary infections 4. Patients with asthma, chronic bronchitis 5. Patients with pregnancy 6. Patients can't cooperate or have a difficulty in breathing in, breathing out or holding their breathe 7. Patients beening diagnosed with Endstage kidney disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>acute kidney injury</keyword>
	<keyword>ultrasound technology</keyword>
</DOC>