<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00903188</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study intends to determine whether steroid withdrawal or calcineurin inhibitor withdrawal is superior for graft function and graft survival. Secondary endpoints for this study are: incidence of tumors and cardiovascular events. The primary objective: To assess if superior graft function (glomerular filtration rate (GFR) difference of 10 ml/min) will be achieved at 1 year after transplantation in cohorts of de novo kidney transplant patients treated with Myfortic-everolimus plus steroids compared to Myfortic-cyclosporine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Calcineurin Inhibitor (CNI) Versus Steroid Cessation in Renal Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Methodology: - A 5-year, multicentre, prospective, randomized, open-label, controlled study - Group 1: Simulect + cyclosporine + Myfortic + steroid stop at 3 months - Group 2: Simulect + cyclosporine (decrease dose in one week at month 3 and replace by everolimus) + Myfortic + steroid maintenance. - In both groups MPA AUC monitoring will be done at 5-7 days and at 3 months, to ensure sufficient MPA protection. Sample size calculations: A total of 152 patients will be randomized (76 patients per group) Population: De novo kidney transplant recipients. Study duration: 1.5 years inclusion+ follow-up during the first 5 years</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Basiliximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcineurin Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female recipients of a de novo kidney transplant, aged above 18 years Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test with sensitivity equal to at least 50 mIU/ml Patients must be capable of understanding the purpose and risks of the study, and must sign an informed consent form Multiple organ transplantation (e.g., Kidneypancreas, kidneyheart, kidney liver,...) Transplantation of a patient who got another organ transplant previously Recipients of a HLAidentical livingrelated renal transplant Patients with PRA &gt; 30%, patients who have lost a first graft from rejection within two years after transplantation, and African European patients. Patients with primary renal disease at risk for recurrence: FSGS, MPGN, HUS Pregnant or lactating women WBC &lt; 2.5 x 109/l (IU), platelet count &lt; 100 x 109/l (IU), or Hb &lt; 6 g/dl at the time of entry into the study Active peptic ulcer Severe diarrhea or other gastrointestinal disorder, which might interfere with their ability to absorb oral medication, including diabetic patients with previously diagnosed diabetic gastroenteropathy Known HIV1 or HTLV1 positive tests The use of investigational drugs or other immunosuppressive drugs, as those specified in this protocol Patients receiving bile acid sequestrants Psychological illness or condition, interfering with the patient's compliance or ability to understand the requirements of the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Renal Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>graft function</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiovascular events</keyword>
	<keyword>malignancy</keyword>
	<keyword>cyclosporin</keyword>
	<keyword>steroids</keyword>
	<keyword>mycophenolate</keyword>
	<keyword>everolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>renal biopsies</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
</DOC>