<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00403000</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Dutasteride may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well dutasteride works in treating patients with recurrent prostate cancer that did not respond to androgen-deprivation therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dutasteride in Treating Patients With Recurrent Prostate Cancer That Did Not Respond to Androgen-Deprivation Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Evaluate the time to disease progression in patients with recurrent prostate cancer that progressed during androgen-deprivation therapy who are treated with dutasteride. - Evaluate the toxicity of dutasteride in these patients. Secondary - Evaluate the serum prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level and objective radiographic response rate in patients treated with dutasteride. - Determine the survival of patients treated with dutasteride. - Determine the quality of life of patients treated with dutasteride. OUTLINE: Patients receive oral dutasteride once daily until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Quality of life is assessed at baseline and then every 3 months thereafter. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed periodically. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 27 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dutasteride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of prostate cancer Asymptomatic progressive disease despite androgendeprivation therapy Progression must occur during androgendeprivation therapy comprising orchiectomy or luteinizing hormonereleasing hormone (LHRH) analogue with or without antiandrogen AND after antiandrogen withdrawal Concurrent LHRH monotherapy (i.e., LHRH analogs, such as leuprolide acetate or goserelin) required in patients who did not undergo prior bilateral orchiectomy to assure testicular androgen suppression Recurrent disease, as indicated by at least 1 of the following: Prostatespecific antigen (PSA) at baseline ≥ 2.0 ng/mL Biopsyconfirmed local recurrence Increase in size of measurable lesions on radiographic study New lesion on a nuclear bone scan Two successive increases in serum PSA measured at least 1 week apart PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: ECOG performance status 02 Life expectancy ≥ 12 weeks Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL Bilirubin ≤ 2.0 mg/dL SGOT ≤ 4 times upper limit of normal Creatinine ≤ 2.0 mg/dL Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 3 months after completion of study therapy PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics At least 28 days since prior radiotherapy and recovered At least 28 days since prior flutamide OR at least 42 days since prior bicalutamide or nilutamide Patients who have previously progressed despite antiandrogen withdrawal and who have started antiandrogens without reduction of serum PSA are eligible without requiring a 28 or 42day washout interval after antiandrogen withdrawal No other prior systemic therapies, except androgendeprivation therapy (i.e., orchiectomy or LHRH analogues only) or antiandrogens Surgery, brachytherapy, externalbeam radiotherapy, and cryotherapy are not considered systemic therapies No other concurrent anticancer therapy No concurrent use of any of the following: Finasteride Other investigational 5αreductase inhibitors Anabolic steroids Alphareceptor blockers (e.g., indoramin, tamsulosin hydrochloride, prazosin, terazosin, alfuzosin hydrochloride, and doxazosin) Drugs with antiandrogenic properties (e.g., spironolactone, flutamide, bicalutamide, cimetidine, ketoconazole, metronidazole, and progestational agents) Products containing selenium ≥ 75 mcg or vitamin E ≥ 100 IU Saw palmetto EG6761 No concurrent radiotherapy, including palliative radiotherapy for pain control</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent prostate cancer</keyword>
</DOC>