<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01707888</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Surgery may be the best treatment choice for early stage non-small cell lung cancer. And VATS major lung resection have been preferred as a standard radical procedure for early stage non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC).This study aim to investigate the outcome of VATS major lung resection for lung cancer as a real-world study in china.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>VATS Major Lung Resection for Chinese Early-stage Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Surgery may be the best treatment choice for early stage non-small cell lung cancer. And VATS major lung resection have been preferred as a standard radical procedure for early stage non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC).This study aim to investigate the outcome of VATS major lung resection for lung cancer as a real-world study in china.This is a multicenter, prospective study, aimed To evaluate the short-term and long- term outcome of VATS major lung resection for early stage lung cancer. Patients will be followed up every 3 months for 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Preoperative criteria: i) nonsmall cell lung cancer is suspected, ii) clinical stage I/II (3) Intraoperative criteria: i) Histologically confirmed NSCLC, ii) resected by VATS or converted open lobectomy,sleeve lobectomy or pneumonectomy and nodal dissection/sampling. (4) No prior ipsilateral thoracotomy (prior diagnostic thoracoscopy is allowed). (5) No prior chemotherapy or radiation therapy for any malignant diseases. (6) Expected postoperative FEV1.0&gt;=800 mL and PaO2&gt;=65 torr. (7) Performance status of 0 or 1. (8) Sufficient organ functions. (9) Written informed consent. 1. Active bacterial or fungous infection. 2. Simultaneous or metachronous (within the past 5 years) double cancers. 3. Women during pregnancy or breastfeeding. 4. Interstitial pneumonitis, pulmonary fibrosis, or severe pulmonary emphysema. 5. Psychosis. 6. Systemic steroids medication. 7. Uncontrollable diabetes mellitus. 8. Uncontrollable hypertension. 9. History of severe heart disease, heart failure, myocardial infarction within the past 6 months or attack of angina pectoris within the past 6 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>