<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00580411</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is an epidemiological and descriptive study of the lifetime relationship of insomnia to alcohol problems.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Timeline Study of Alcohol Use and Its Relationship to Insomnia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must be between the ages of 1870, may be male or female, and from any ethnic background. Individuals must have the capacity to give IRBapproved study consent. Subjects must at least have a lifetime history of being heavy alcohol drinkers (i.e., drinks approximately 21 alcoholic drinks or more per week). Alternatively, subjects are eligible if they meet criteria for a lifetime history of either alcohol dependence or alcohol abuse. Overall, a subject must meet at least one of these alcohol criteria: a lifetime history of heavy drinking, alcohol abuse or alcohol dependence. Subjects must have a complaint of chronic insomnia, reporting either six or less hours TST, on average at least three times per week. Exclusion Criteria Potential subjects with a lifetime diagnosis of Bipolar Affective Disorder, Schizophrenia, Borderline Personality Disorder, dementia of any type, or epilepsy will not be admitted to the study. Subjects will be excluded with a diagnosis of any other substance dependence syndrome other than alcohol dependence, nicotine dependence, and/or caffeine dependence. However, individuals may have a history of episodic abuse of cannabis, cocaine, sedatives/hypnotics and opiates, amphetamines, and hallucinogens. Also, subjects may be on prescription benzodiazepine or related sedative/hypnotic therapy. Any condition or treatment of a condition that is likely to confound the experimental design or the results will be prohibited by the PI.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>