<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01737047</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to identify medical conditions that may cause particular problems to individuals receiving care for HIV infection over the age of 50. In addition, as the effects and potentially the side effects, of HIV medication may change with age, this study will also investigate the association between age and differing effects of antiretroviral therapies such as treatment outcomes, side effects and the levels of drugs in blood. Results from this study may inform future HIV treatment guidelines on how we monitor individuals with HIV infection. The results may also assist in the design of future studies for the treatment of diseases associated with ageing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Prospective, Observational Study to Examine the Effects of Ageing on the 'Pharmacokinetic and Clinical Observations in People Over Fifty'</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Multicentre, prospective, observational study over 3 years. Our study will describe the impact of advancing age on the experience of living with HIV in England and Ireland. To address this we will establish cohorts of HIV-positive people aged &gt;50 and &lt;50 years as well as demographically matched HIV-negative people aged &gt;50 years. 1. To analyse the incidence and outcomes of co-morbidities in older-HIV-positive people and their relationship with demographic/clinical factors. 2. To evaluate associations between antiretroviral drug concentrations and age, and to assess the potential impact of age on drug efficacy, drug-drug interactions and co-morbidities. 3. To contribute to the development and implementation of evidence-based recommendations for the clinical monitoring of older HIV-positive patients. 2000 will be recruited in all either white or black african individuals (self reported) 1000 will be Over 50 years of age and HIV positive, 500 will be under the age of 50 and will be HIV positive and 500 will be over the age of 50 and be HIV negative.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Seropositivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Integrase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Older HIVpositive cohort (n=1000): documented HIV infection age &gt;50 years at study entry self defined white or black African ethnicity likely route of HIV acquisition via sexual exposure Either by male to male exposure if white or by heterosexual exposure if white or black African able to comprehend study patient information leaflet Younger HIVpositive cohort (n=500): documented HIV infection age &lt;50 at study entry* self defined white or black African ethnicity likely route of HIV acquisition via sexual exposure Either by male to male exposure if white or by heterosexual exposure if white or black African. able to comprehend study patient information leaflet this group will comprise of at least 150 subjects in each of the following age groups: 2029, 3039, 4049 years. Recruitment will be monitored by the Study Monitoring Team. HIVnegative cohort (n=500): documented negative HIV test at screening age &gt;50 years at study entry self defined white or black African ethnicity registered with a General Practitioner and gives permission for contact with that General Practitioner. in the opinion of the investigator, those unable or unwilling to comply with the requirements of the study life expectancy less than 6 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>Ageing</keyword>
</DOC>