<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01737710</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Atopic dermatitis, also called eczema, is a disease in which the skin is dry and scaly with severe itching. People who have atopic dermatitis often have complications from skin infections; these can include eczema herpeticum after herpes simplex virus infection or eczema vaccinatum after smallpox vaccination. People with atopic dermatitis may suffer from skin infections and may therefore respond differently to vaccinations. A new flu vaccine which is injected into the skin instead of into muscle has recently been approved by the Food and Drug Administration for vaccination of the general population including patients with atopic dermatitis. This new vaccine has been shown to work as well as the vaccine which is injected into muscle when tested in people without atopic dermatitis. The main purpose of this study is to compare how people with atopic dermatitis respond to this new flu vaccine compared to non-atopic volunteers without atopic dermatitis. The second purpose is to look at how people with atopic dermatitis respond to the new vaccine which is injected into the skin compared to the vaccine which is injected into muscle.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Atopic Dermatitis Research Network (ADRN) Influenza Vaccine Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis, Atopic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eczema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Enrolled in the ADRN Registry study; Active, mild to severe AD (lesions present) with or without a history of eczema herpeticum or who are nonatopic as diagnosed using the ADRN Standard Diagnostic Criteria; and Willing to sign the informed consent form prior to initiation of any study procedure. Pregnant or lactating. Women of child bearing potential must avoid becoming pregnant (use of an effective method of contraception or abstinence) for the duration of their participation in the study; Have a known allergy to any component of the Fluzone® Intradermal or Fluzone® (Intramuscular) vaccines, including egg protein, or have had a severe allergic reaction to a previous dose of any influenza vaccine; known or suspected congenital or acquired immunodeficiency or who have had immunosuppressive therapy (excluding steroids) such as anticancer chemotherapy or radiation therapy within the preceding 6 months; Received systemic steroid therapy for 2 or more weeks at a dose ≥ 20 mg/day prednisone equivalent within 1 month prior to the day of vaccination or expect to receive within 3 weeks postvaccination; Received a cumulative dose of inhaled and/or intranasally administered corticosteroids ≥ 880 mcg/day fluticasone equivalent for 2 or more weeks within 1 month prior to the day of vaccination or expect to receive within 3 weeks postvaccination; A chronic illness, including but not limited to, cardiac, renal, or autoimmune disorders, or diabetes, at a stage that could interfere with study conduct or completion, based on the opinion of the Investigator. Asthma and underlying allergic conditions such as allergic rhinitis are not exclusionary; A neoplastic disease or any hematologic malignancy. Participants who have been disease free for at least six months will not be excluded; Participated in another clinical trial investigating a vaccine, drug, medical device, or a medical procedure in the four weeks preceding the study vaccination or who plan to participate in another clinical trial during the present study period; Any skin disease other than AD that might compromise the stratum corneum barrier (e.g., bullous disease, psoriasis, cutaneous T cell lymphoma [also called Mycosis Fungoides or Sezary syndrome], dermatitis herpetiformis, HaileyHailey, or Darier's disease); Received blood or bloodderived products that might interfere with the assessment of immune response in the past 3 months prior to vaccination or who plan to receive such products during the study period; Received previous vaccination (Fluzone® or another vaccine) against influenza in the past 6 months prior to vaccination; Received any other live vaccines within 4 weeks or inactivated vaccines within 2 weeks prior to study vaccination or who plan to receive any vaccination during the study period; Thrombocytopenia or bleeding disorder in the 3 weeks preceding vaccination; Personal or family history of GuillainBarré Syndrome; A first degree relative already enrolled in the study; Determined to be ineligible based on the opinion of the Investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Influenza Vaccines</keyword>
	<keyword>Dermatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Injections, Intradermal</keyword>
	<keyword>Injections, Intramuscular</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Diseases, Eczematous</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypersensitivity, Immediate</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypersensitivity</keyword>
	<keyword>Immune System Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Genetic Diseases, Inborn</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Diseases, Genetic</keyword>
</DOC>