<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01737294</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This non-interventional study will evaluate the efficacy, tolerability, health related quality of life and use of health resources associated with QUTENZA treatment when QUTENZA is used in standard clinical practice. The patient's primary diagnosis of peripheral neuropathic pain (PNP) will be classified into subtypes: post-herpetic neuralgia (PHN); HIV-associated neuropathy (HIV-AN); neuropathic back pain; cancer-related neuropathic pain; post-operative &amp; post-traumatic neuropathic pain; and 'other' neuropathies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Observation of the Use of QUTENZA™ in Standard Clinical Practice</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A detailed medical history will be taken, with particular emphasis on the primary PNP diagnosis. In addition to all current neuropathic pain medications, all previous therapies (pharmacological and surgical) for PNP from the point of primary diagnosis will be documented. QUTENZA treatments may be repeated up to every 90 days, in line with the Summary of Product Characteristics document (SPC) as determined by the persistence or return of pain. Patients who have not required treatment for 365 days or longer may re-enter a treatment cycle if their treating physician decides to retreat them with QUTENZA in the course of standard clinical management. The duration of participation for each patient will be at least 12 months following first QUTENZA treatment. Short questionnaires will be completed by the investigator whilst in contact with the patient (either in person or by telephone) at the following time points: 1) Screening prior to the first QUTENZA treatment; 2) at each QUTENZA treatment visit; 3) 2 weeks, 8 weeks following the first QUTENZA treatment 4) 12 weeks following each QUTENZA treatment; 5) any additional contact with the patient outside the protocol schedule. For patients not returning for retreatment with QUTENZA within any of 6 months, 9 months, and 1 year of their previous QUTENZA treatment further follow-up questionnaires will be completed. End of study (EoS) is defined as one year after the last patient enrolled receives their first QUTENZA treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capsaicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. The investigator has decided to treat the patient with QUTENZA as part of provision of standard care for the treatment of peripheral neuropathic pain in nondiabetic adults either alone or in combination with other medicinal products for pain 2. The patient is willing and able to comply with protocol requirements for the duration of study participation 1. The neuropathic painful areas are located only on the face, above the hairline of the scalp, and/or in proximity to mucous membranes 2. The patient has a history of Type I or Type II diabetes mellitus 3. The patient has a diagnosis of any major psychiatric disorder or evidence of cognitive impairment including dementia that, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with patient's ability to complete study evaluations 4. The patient has received any prior treatment with QUTENZA patches, including blinded patches administered as part of a clinical trial 5. The patient has hypersensitivity to capsaicin (i.e. chilli peppers or overthecounter [OTC] capsaicin products), any QUTENZA excipients or adhesives, or local anesthetics 6. The patient has participated in any other clinical study or received an investigational drug within 30 days prior to Screening Visit 7. The patient currently engages in any active substance abuse or has a history of chronic substance abuse within 1 year prior to the Screening Visit; or any prior chronic substance abuse (including alcoholism) likely to reoccur during the study period as judged by the investigator 8. The patient, in the opinion of the investigator, is not suitable to participate in this NIS for any reason</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Phase IV</keyword>
	<keyword>Peripheral Neuropathic Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>QUTENZA</keyword>
</DOC>