<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01704664</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Perioperative immunonutrition in gastric cancer patients can reduce perioperative morbidity and may improve quality of their life. Patients with gastric cancer will be divided into four groups depending on the type of artificial nutrition. Group I (enteral feeding) and II (enteral feeding and parenteral nutrition with glutamine) will be administered nutritional therapy during the postoperative period, group III (oral arginine) and IV (parenteral immunonurition) patients will be treated nutritionally both prior to and after the surgery. The lymphocytes and their subpopulations, interleukin IL-1B,-6,-23, and the phagocytic, and bactericidal activity of blood platelets will be determined before and after nutritional therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Perioperative Immunonutrition, Phagocytic and Bactericidal Activity of Blood Platelets in Gastric Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Surgical treatment of gastric cancer is associated with a high risk of perioperative complications. Morbidity of cancer patients increases in concert with the clinical stage of the malignancy. It is postulated that a reduction in perioperative morbidity and improved quality of life of patients with advanced gastric cancer can be achieved by proper preparation to surgery, among others. One of such methods is the implementation of immunostimulating nutritional therapy during the perioperative period.The stage of cancer will be graded according to TNM classification. The patients will be randomly assigned to four clinical groups based on the type of nutritional therapy implemented.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>gastric cancer for group III constituted gastric cancer associated with severe gastrointestinal obstruction</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>malnutrition,</keyword>
	<keyword>perioperative artificial nutrition,</keyword>
	<keyword>immunonutrition,</keyword>
	<keyword>gastrectomy,</keyword>
	<keyword>lymphocytes,</keyword>
	<keyword>interleukin,</keyword>
	<keyword>blood platelets,</keyword>
	<keyword>phagocytic and bactericidal activity of blood platelets</keyword>
</DOC>