<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01704040</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purposes of this study are to evaluate the safety (Parts 1 and 2) and efficacy (Part 2) of pretreatment with CNTO 3157 in healthy adult and asthmatic adult participants before and after intranasal (into the nose) inoculation with human rhinovirus type 16 (HRV-16).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of CNTO 3157 in Healthy Normal and Asthmatic Participants Inoculated With Human Rhinovirus Type 16</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a two-part, randomized (participants are assigned to treatment by chance), double-blind (participants and investigators do not know what study agent is being administered), placebo-controlled study. A placebo appears identical to a study agent, has no active ingredients, and helps investigators evaluate the effect of a study agent. In Part 1, following administration of CNTO 3157 or placebo, the severity of an upper respiratory tract infection, due to inoculation with HRV 16, will be assessed in healthy participants for safety reasons. In Part 2, following administration of CNTO 3157 or placebo and inoculation with HRV-16, efficacy and safety will be assessed in asthmatic participants using standard assessments to evaluate asthma treatments. The study (Parts 1 and 2) will be completed when the last participant completes the last visit (Week 11) in Part 2.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Understanding of the study and a signed informed consent form before any studyrelated procedures Willing and able to adhere to the restrictions specified in the protocol Results of the following laboratory tests within the following limits: serum alanine aminotransferase (ALT) levels ≤2 x ULN; serum aspartate aminotransferase (AST) levels ≤2 x ULN Part 1 (healthy participants): a). Body weight in the range of 40 to 125 kg, inclusive. Have a body mass index (BMI) of 19 to 32 kg/m2, inclusive b). Healthy with no clinically significant abnormalities as determined by medical history, physical examination, blood chemistry assessments, hematologic assessments, coagulation and urinalysis, measurement of vital signs, and 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG) performed at Screening Visit 2 Part 2: a). (BMI) of 19 to 40 kg/m2, inclusive; have a physiciandocumented diagnosis of asthma for at least 6 months prior to Screening Visit 2; have stable asthma based on physician assessment at Screening Visit 2 b). Have an Asthma Control Questionnaire (ACQ) symptom score less than (&lt;)2.5 at Screening Visit 2 c). Have a prebronchodilator forced expiratory volume in the first second (FEV1) greater than or equal to (&gt;=) 65 percent of predicted normal value at Screening Visit 2 Part 1 (healthy participants): Has any condition that in the opinion of the investigators, would constitute a risk or a contraindication for participating in the study, prevent the participant from meeting or performing study requirements, or could interfere with the study objectives, conduct, or evaluation At Screening Visit 1 and throughout the study, works with (or lives with a family member who cares for) the elderly, (eg, nursing home), or lives with someone who may be at risk from transmission of the human rhinovirus type 16 (HRV16) challenge agent, including, but not limited to, individuals with chronic lung disease (including asthma), a premature infant, or an immunocompromised individual Has had any acute illness, including a common cold, within 4 weeks prior to Screening Visit 1, or has had a major illness or hospitalization within 6 months prior to Screening Visit 1 Has active allergic rhinitis or perennial allergy symptoms (eg, due to ragweed) at Screening Visit 2 or expects to have active allergic rhinitis or perennial allergy symptoms during the study Has a current infection (eg, sepsis, pneumonia or pyelonephritis), or has been hospitalized and/or received antimicrobials for a serious infection during the 6 months prior to Screening Visit 1 Part 2 (asthmatic patients): Has a history of any other chronic lung disease, including chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), bronchiolitis, bronchiectasis, allergic bronchopulmonary aspergillosis (mycosis), occupational asthma, sleep apnea, pulmonary hypertension, or any other obstructive pulmonary disease, liver or renal insufficiency; significant unstable cardiac, vascular, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, endocrine, neurologic, hematologic, rheumatologic, psychiatric, or metabolic disturbances, or other body system disorders that are clinically significant in the opinion of the investigator Has ever had an episode of lifethreatening asthma defined as respiratory arrest or requiring intubation for asthma Has been hospitalized (for greater than 24 hours) due to asthma in the 5 years prior to Screening Visit 1 Has experienced an asthma exacerbation in the 12 weeks prior to Screening Visit 1 requiring management with systemic steroids Is receiving a highdose inhaled corticosteroid (ICS) (&gt;500 µg/day to fluticasone or equivalent). Use of low or medium dose ICS (≤500 µg/day fluticasone or equivalent) with or without permitted controller medications, eg, longacting Beta2 agonists (LABA), leukotriene receptor antagonists (LTRA), is allowed</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Healthy volunteers and asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>CNTO 3157</keyword>
	<keyword>Rhinovirus</keyword>
</DOC>