<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01402297</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to investigate the effect of inhaled apocynin on ROS (reactive oxygen species) and NOS (reactive nitrogen species) synthesis in 13 COPD patients. Effects of nebulized apocynin (0.5 mg/ml, 6 ml) were assessed in exhaled breath condensate (EBC) after 30, 60 and 120 minutes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hydrogen Peroxide and Nitrite Reduction in Exhaled Breath Condensate of COPD Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Apocynin reduced hydrogen peroxide concentration in exhaled breath condensate 60 and 120 minutes after apocynin nebulization comparing to placebo (0.43 μM vs. 0.59 μM and 0.41 μM vs. 0.58 μM respectively, p&lt;0.05). Interestingly, apocynin caused decrease of NO2- concentration 30, 60 and 120 minutes after apocynin inhalation (3.9 μM vs. 4.5 μM, 3.8 μM vs. 4.5 μM and 3.7 μM vs. 4,4 μM respectively, p&lt;0.05) comparing to placebo, but did not cause any significant changes in concentration of NO3- in any timepoint (p&gt;0.05). No influence of apocynin on safety parameters, and no adverse effects has been observed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acetovanillone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrogen Peroxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients suffering from bronchial COPD (II and III stage) patients free of any medication few days before research patients had not suffered from any infectious diseases including upper respiratory tract infections for at least 3 months prior to the study Patients suffering from GOLD I stage patients taking medications few days before the study infectious diseases that had occurred 3 months or less before the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>apocynin</keyword>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
</DOC>