<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00520351</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate and compare, on a daily wear basis, the performance of two contact lens care solutions when used with silicone hydrogel soft contact lenses with regards to comfort and dryness symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Lens Care Regimens With a Silicone Hydrogel Lens (Emerald)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of the study is to evaluate and compare, on a daily wear basis, the performance of two contact lens care solutions when used with silicone hydrogel soft contact lenses with regards to comfort and dryness symptoms by observing changes within the cornea and collecting subjective ratings</detailed_description>
	<criteria>A person is eligible for inclusion in the study if he/she: 1. Is at least 17 years of age and has full legal capacity to volunteer. 2. Has read, understood and signed an information consent letter. 3. Is willing and able to follow instructions and maintain the appointment schedule. 4. Is presently using either biweekly or monthly replacement lenses. 5. Has symptoms of ocular dryness as determined by specific prescreening criteria. 6. Is correctable to a visual acuity of 6/9 or better (in each eye) with their habitual vision correction. 7. Has clear corneas and no active ocular disease. 8. Has had an ocular examination in the last two years. A person will be excluded from the study if he/she: 1. Is an asymptomatic lens wearer. 2. Is a daily disposable contact lens wearer. 3. Is a current extended wear contact lens wearer. 4. Currently uses one of the study lens care regimens. 5. Has any clinically significant blepharitis. 6. Has undergone corneal refractive surgery. 7. Is aphakic. 8. Has any active ocular disease. 9. Has any systemic disease affecting ocular health. 10. Is using any systemic or topical medications that may affect ocular health. 11. Has known sensitivity to the diagnostic pharmaceuticals to be used in the study. 12. Is participating in any other type of clinical or research study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>