<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03072121</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether Shexiang Baoxin Pill is effective in the treatment of coronary artery disease not amenable to revascularization on the basis of western medicine therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Curative Effect Evaluation of Shexiang Baoxin Pill on Coronary Artery Disease Not Amenable to Revascularization</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The western medicine treatment for CAD not amenable to revascularization is limited. Shexiang Baoxin Pill, a kind of Chinese patent medicine has been used for treating coronary artery disease in clinical practice in China for many years. Shexiang baoxin pill(SBP) is applicable to "Qi deficiency and blood stasis syndrome" in traditional Chinese medicine. Recent experimental research has indicated that SBP can improve myocardial ischemia and promote therapeutic angiogenesis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ticlopidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clopidogrel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atorvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metoprolol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isosorbide-5-mononitrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trimetazidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isosorbide Dinitrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isosorbide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants are aged between 45 and 75 years, diagnosed with sever CAD through coronary arteriography which shows that the left main coronary artery and threevessel have sever diffuse stenosis, calcification or vascular ectasia, be in accordance with Traditional Chinese Medicine syndrome of "Qi deficiency and blood stasis syndrome" or "phlegm and stasis mutual obstruction syndrome". Patients with severe valvular disease, congenital cardiomyopathy decompensation Patients with CAD complicated with severe multiple organ disease such as severe heart failure, severe lung, liver or renal dysfunction, peptic ulcer in active stage, or intracranial hemorrhage Patients that use highdose steroids due to connective tissue disease Patients with serious infections Patients with malignant tumor Patients with hematopoietic diseases Pregnant or lactating women.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>coronary artery disease</keyword>
	<keyword>revascularization</keyword>
	<keyword>Shexiang Baoxin Pill</keyword>
</DOC>