<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01790594</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out if the drug NULOJIX速 (belatacept) will minimize the amount of other anti-rejection medications necessary and thereby reduce the long-term side effects caused by the other medications. The researchers also want to learn more about the safety of this treatment and long term health of transplanted pancreases and kidneys.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Optimization of NULOJIX速 Usage Towards Minimizing CNI Exposure in Simultaneous Pancreas and Kidney Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Transplant recipients have to take anti-rejection medications to prevent their immune systems (the body's natural defense system against illness) from rejecting their new organs. Most patients who receive a transplanted organ must take these anti-rejection medications for the rest of their lives, or for as long as the transplanted organ continues to work. Taking standard anti-rejection medications for a long time can cause serious side effects, including pancreas and kidney damage. There would be a benefit to finding new anti-rejection medications that work just as well, but could lessen the amount of anti-rejection medications that are taken long term.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antilymphocyte Serum</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abatacept</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancrelipase</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ability to understand and provide written informed consent; Candidate for a primary simultaneous kidney and pancreas allograft with random cpeptide &lt;0.3 ng/mL; No known contraindications to study therapy using NULOJIX速 (belatacept); Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test upon study entry; Female and male participants with reproductive potential must agree to use FDA approved methods of birth control during participation in the study and for 4 months following study completion; No donor specific antibodies prior to transplant that are considered to be of clinical significance by the site investigator; Negative crossmatch, actual or virtual, or a Panel Reactive Antibodies (PRA) of 0% on historic and admission sera, as determined by each participating study center; A documented negative Tuberculosis (TB) test within the 12 months prior to transplant. If documentation is not present at the time of transplantation, and the subject does not have any risk factors for TB, a TBspecific interferon gamma release assay (IGRA) may be performed. Need for multiorgan transplantation other than a kidney and pancreas; Recipient of previous organ transplant; EpsteinBarr Virus (EBV) seronegative recipients or recipients whose EBV serostatus is unknown prior to the time of transplantation; Individuals infected by the hepatitis B or C viruses or HIV; Individuals who have required treatment with systemic prednisone or other immunosuppressive drugs within 1 year prior to transplant; Individuals previously treated with NULOJIX速 (belatacept); Any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with the participant's ability to comply with study requirements; Use of investigational drugs within 4 weeks of enrollment; Known hypersensitivity to mycophenolate mofetil (MMF)or any of the drug's components; Administration of live attenuated vaccine(s) within 8 weeks of enrollment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>kidney</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreas</keyword>
	<keyword>immunosuppression</keyword>
	<keyword>calcineurin inhibitor (CNI)</keyword>
</DOC>