<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02582749</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Newly diagnosed metastatic prostate cancer subjects with bone metastases will be accrued to this stratified randomized 2-arm Phase II trial. Subjects will be randomized 1:2 to ADT or ADT with Radium-223 dichloride respectively.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Androgen Deprivation Therapy +/- Radium-223 Dichloride in Metastatic Prostate Cancer With Bone Metastases</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OUTLINE: This is a multi-center, randomized trial. STRATIFICATION FACTORS: Subjects will be stratified based on serum total alkaline phosphatase at baseline and extent of disease (described below). Randomization will occur within stratification group. - Extent of Disease: &lt;6 skeletal metastases with no visceral metastases versus ≥6 skeletal metastases or visceral metastases. - Serum total alkaline phosphatase at baseline: normal vs abnormal. Abnormal alkaline phosphatase is defined as &gt; 130 IU/L. Early Induction or Late Induction status will not be a stratification criterion. TREATMENT SCHEDULE: CONTROL ARM A All subjects will receive androgen deprivation therapy with a LHRH agonist (any LHRH agonist such as leuprolide acetate or goserelin acetate is acceptable) or a LHRH antagonist (degarelix) or bilateral orchiectomy, with dosage determined by the treating physician. Route of administration and cycle days will be administered as per package insert. Androgen deprivation therapy with LHRH agonist or LHRH antagonist will be given continuously. All subjects will receive bicalutamide, 50 mg Oral (PO) Daily TREATMENT SCHEDULE: EXPERIMENTAL ARM B All subjects will receive androgen deprivation therapy with a LHRH agonist (any LHRH agonist such as leuprolide acetate or goserelin acetate is acceptable) or a LHRH antagonist (degarelix) or bilateral orchiectomy, with dosage determined by the treating physician. Route of administration and cycle days will be administered as per package insert. Androgen deprivation therapy with LHRH agonist or LHRH antagonist will be given continuously. All subjects will receive bicalutamide, 50 mg oral (PO) daily All subjects will receive Radium-223 dichloride, 50 kBq (1.35 microcurie) per kg body weight, intravenous (IV bolus) every 28 days for 6 injections The following laboratory values must be obtained within 28 days prior to registration for protocol therapy: Hematopoietic: - Hemoglobin (Hgb) ≥ 8.0 g/dL (80 g/L) without packed RBC transfusion - Platelets ≥ 100 K/mm3 - Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 K/mm3 Hepatic: - Total Bilirubin ≤ 2 x institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) except subjects with Gilbert's Syndrome, who must have a total bilirubin less than 3.0 mg/dL - Aspartate aminotransferase (AST, SGOT) ≤ 2.5 x institutional ULN (≤ 5 x institutional ULN in the presence of liver metastases). - Alanine aminotransferase (ALT, SGPT) ≤ 2.5 x institutional ULN (≤ 5 × institutional ULN in the presence of liver metastases). Renal: - Estimated Creatinine Clearance by Cockcroft-Gault formula ≥ 30 mL/min</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bone Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bone Marrow Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Succinylcholine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bicalutamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Radium Ra 223 dichloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All subjects or their legally authorized representative must be informed of the investigational nature of the study and provide written informed consent and HIPAA authorization for release of personal health information before performance of any study related procedure not part of routine medical care. NOTE: HIPAA authorization may be included in the informed consent or obtained separately. Men ≥ 18 years of age at the time of informed consent. Histological or cytological evidence of prostate adenocarcinoma. All subjects must have radiologic or pathologic evidence of skeletal metastases with ≥ 2 skeletal lesions at baseline on bone scan or axial imaging or with bone pain within 28 days prior to the initiation of androgen deprivation therapy. All subjects must also have a radiographic assessment (chest or abdominal/pelvic CT or MRI) within 28 days before or after the initiation of androgen deprivation therapy but do not need to have measurable disease. ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) Performance Status of 02 within 28 days prior to registration. ECOG Performance Status of 3 will only be allowed if judged by the treating investigator as attributable exclusively to bone pain. Subjects must fall into one of the two populations below: EARLY INDUCTION GROUP: Subjects who have started androgen deprivation therapy (luteinizing hormonereleasing hormone (LHRH) agonist or antagonist therapy with or without an antiandrogen agent) a maximum of 28 days before registration and who otherwise meet all the eligibility criteria. LATE INDUCTION GROUP: Subjects who have NOT started any androgen deprivation therapy (luteinizing hormonereleasing hormone (LHRH) agonist or antagonist therapy with or without an antiandrogen agent). Antiandrogen receptor antagonist therapy must be bicalutamide. Subjects already started on other antiandrogens must be willing to switch over to bicalutamide. Any prior androgendeprivation therapy or finasteride as neoadjuvant or adjuvant therapy or for biochemical recurrence must have been discontinued at least 6 months prior to registration. Prior surgical treatment for prostate cancer is allowed but must have been completed at least 14 days prior to registration and any toxicity from such therapy must have recovered to ≤ grade 1 per CTCAE version 4 criteria by the time of registration. All subjects, including those who are surgically sterilized, must be willing to use an effective method of contraception (barrier method of birth control or abstinence) from the time informed consent is signed until 6 months after completion of protocol therapy. Subjects must consent to bank whole blood, serum, plasma for future unspecified studies. Prior cytotoxic chemotherapy for metastatic prostate cancer. Prior cytotoxic chemotherapy with curative intent in the neoadjuvant or adjuvant setting is allowed but must have been completed at least 6 months prior to registration. No cytotoxic chemotherapy is allowed during protocol specified therapy. Prior concomitant therapy with ketoconazole, aminoglutethimide or abiraterone acetate or enzalutamide (MDV3100) or intent to treat with the above. Concurrent megestrol for hot flashes is allowed. Prior or ongoing bisphosphonate (e.g,. zoledronic acid) or RANKL inhibitor (e.g. denosumab) use is NOT allowed except when used solely for osteoporosis and strictly per guidelines for that indication. Bisphosphonate or RANKL inhibitor cannot be initiated for any indication during protocol specified therapy without consent of the sponsorinvestigator of the study. Prior systemic radiotherapy with strontium89, samarium153, rhenium186 or rhenium188. Diagnosis of aplastic anemia, pure red cell aplasia, myelodysplasia or any of the other bone marrow failure states. Any neuroendocrine differentiation including small cell carcinoma on histology or cytology. No prior malignancy except for nonmelanomatous skin cancer or nonmuscle invasive bladder cancer or adequately treated Stage I or II cancer (adequacy at discretion of treating investigator) from which the subject is currently in complete remission, or any other cancer from which the subject has been diseasefree for at least 3 years. History of or active CNS metastasis (brain, leptomeningeal or cord compression). Brain imaging studies are not required for eligibility if the subject has no neurologic signs or symptoms suggestive of brain metastasis. Subjects with neurological symptoms are recommended to undergo a head CT scan (with or without intravenous contrast) or brain MRI (with or without intravenous contrast) to exclude brain metastasis. If brain imaging studies are performed, they must be negative for CNS disease. Skull bone involvement without neurological impact by prostate cancer is allowed. Treatment with any other investigational agent within 28 days prior to registration. Subjects must not be treated with any other investigational agent while on protocol specified therapy. Prior hemibody external radiation. Any external radiation therapy must have been completed at least 14 days prior to registration. Any toxicity from such therapy must have recovered to ≤ grade 1 per CTCAE version 4 criteria by the time of registration. Clinically significant infections as judged by the treating investigator. Subjects must not have been diagnosed with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, active chronic hepatitis B or C, lifethreatening illness unrelated to cancer, or any serious medical or psychiatric illness that could, in the investigator's opinion, potentially interfere with participation in this study. Subjects should be tested for hepatitis B or C or HIV infection during screening only if they are considered by the investigator to be at high risk for these infections. Known hypersensitivity to bicalutamide. Known gastrointestinal (GI) disease or procedure that could interfere with the GI absorption or tolerance of bicalutamide, including difficulty swallowing oral medications. Grade III/IV cardiac disease as defined by the New York Heart Association Criteria (i.e., subjects with cardiac disease resulting in marked limitation of physical activity or resulting in inability to carry on any physical activity without discomfort), symptomatic pulmonary embolism within 3 months, unstable angina pectoris, myocardial infarction within 6 months, or serious uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmia as determined by the treating physician.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Androgen Deprivation Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Androgen Receptor Antagonist</keyword>
	<keyword>Radium-223 Dichloride</keyword>
	<keyword>Placebo</keyword>
</DOC>