<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02582866</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study is conducted to evaluate the long-term safety and tolerability of lacosamide (LCM) in patients receiving LCM in SP0994 [NCT01465997]. The study will enable collection of additional monotherapy safety data, and will facilitate access to treatment until commercial availability for monotherapy use.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Study to Investigate the Long-term Use of Lacosamide as Monotherapy in Subjects Who Completed Study SP0994</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lacosamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>An Institutional Review Board /Institutional Ethics Committee approved written Informed Consent Form (ICF) is signed and dated by the subject or by the parent(s) or legal representative. The ICF or a specific Assent form, where required, will be signed and dated by minors Subject/legal representative is considered reliable and capable of adhering to the protocol, visit schedule, and medication intake according to the judgment of the investigator Subject has completed the Termination Visit of SP0994 [NCT01465997] and has been treated with lacosamide monotherapy Subject is receiving any investigational drugs or using any experimental devices in addition to lacosamide (LCM) Subject experienced a seizure at the 3rd target dose (i.e. LCM 600 mg/day) during SP0994 Subject required another Anti Epileptic Drug (AED) for the treatment of seizures Subject meets a "must" withdrawal criteria for SP0994 Subject is experiencing an ongoing Serious Adverse Event from SP0994 Female subject who is pregnant or nursing, and/or a woman of childbearing potential who is not surgically sterile, 2 year postmenopausal or does not practice one highly effective method of contraception, unless sexually abstinent, for the duration of the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lacosamide</keyword>
	<keyword>Vimpat</keyword>
	<keyword>Epilepsy</keyword>
	<keyword>Partial onset seizures</keyword>
	<keyword>Tonic-clonic seizures</keyword>
	<keyword>Monotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>AED</keyword>
</DOC>