<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00805675</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the safety, tolerability and effectiveness of 12 weeks of treatment with telbivudine 600 mg daily plus tenofovir DF 300 mg one daily (OD) taken together vs. tenofovir DF 300 mg once daily (QD) or vs telbivudine 600 mg monotherapy daily (QD). This is an open labeled, active controlled, viral kinetics study which means the subjects and study doctor will know what study drug subjects have been assigned. This study is open to male and female subjects, &lt;40 years of age, who have been infected with HBV for at least 6 months and have not received oral treatment for HBV.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Telbivudine and Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Treatment on the Hepatitis B Virus DNA Kinetics in CHB</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Telbivudine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronic HBV infection, defined as positive serum HBsAg for at least 6 months, or HBsAg positive &gt; 3 months and negative for IgM antiHBc and positive for IgG antiHBc Age &lt; 40 years old HBeAg positive HBV DNA &gt; or = to 10^7 copies/mL by Abbott realtime PCR ALT &lt; or = to 1 ULN Willing and able to provide written informed consent No prior oral HBV therapy (e.g., nucleotide and/or nucleoside therapy or other investigational agents for HBV infection) Is willing and able to comply with the study drug regimen and all other study procedures and requirements Is willing and able to provide written informed consent before any study assessment is perform Decompensated liver disease defined as direct (conjugated) bilirubin &gt; 1.2 × ULN, PT &gt; 1.2 × ULN, platelets &lt; 150,000/mm3, serum albumin &lt; 3.5 g/dL, or prior history of clinical hepatic decompensation (e.g. ascites, jaundice, encephalopathy, variceal hemorrhage). Received interferon (pegylated or not) therapy within 6 months of the screening visit αfetoprotein &gt; 50 ng/mL Evidence of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) Coinfection with HCV (by serology), or HIV, Significant renal, cardiovascular, pulmonary, or neurological disease. Received solid organ or bone marrow transplantation. Is currently receiving therapy with immunomodulators (e.g., corticosteroids, etc.), investigational agents, nephrotoxic agents, or agents susceptible of modifying renal excretion. Has proximal tubulopathy. Use of other investigational drugs at the time of enrollment, or within 30 days History of hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs or to drugs of similar chemical classes Is pregnant or breastfeeding. Is a women of childbearing potential (WOCBP)unless postmenopausal or using one or more acceptable method of contraception. Patient has any other concurrent medical or social condition likely to preclude compliance with the schedule of evaluations in the protocol, or likely to confound the efficacy or safety observations of the study. Patient is currently abusing alcohol or illicit drugs, or has a history of alcohol abuse or illicit substance abuse within the preceding two years. Patient has a medical condition that requires prolonged or frequent use of systemic acyclovir or famciclovir. Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic HBV</keyword>
	<keyword>Asian adult subjects with chronic HBV, in immune tolerant phase, and positive for hepatitis B e antigen (HBeAg)</keyword>
</DOC>