<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02756494</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Stroke is the fifth leading cause of death in the United States and the leading cause of disability. However, in China, stroke is one of the most frequent causes of death and chronic disability. Ischemic strokes in adults younger than 45 years of age were regarded as a relatively uncommon event in the proportion of &lt;5% of all ischemic strokes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ischemic Stroke in Chinese Young Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Currently, stroke is the fifth leading cause of death in the United States and the leading cause of disability. However, in China, stroke is one of the most frequent causes of death and chronic disability. Ischemic strokes in adults younger than 45 years of age were regarded as a relatively uncommon event in the proportion of &lt;5% of all ischemic strokes. Our study aimed to evaluate some Biomarkers Underlying in Ischemic Stroke in Chinese Young Adults.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Infarction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients between 18 and 45 years of age with a first ever ischaemic stroke are eligible for this study from the Department of Beijing Chaoyang Hospital between January 1, 2016 and December 31, 2016. All patients were defined as a sudden loss of global or focal cerebral function that persisted with a probable vascular cause for 24h and confirmed by brain CT or MRI. The exclusion criteria will include patients with intracranial lesions or cerebrovascular disease (including cerebral venous sinus thrombosis) History that have caused sequelae, such as movement disorders, mood disorders, cognitive dysfunction or speech problems; or individuals who are pregnant or breast feeding. Patients with serious diseases that are related to the heart, liver, kidney or haematopoietic system will not be allowed to participate.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>