<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02785809</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to investigate whether there is a correlation between anti-Müllerian hormone during long-term use of combined oral contraceptives and the recovery time before recovered menstrual cycle after discontinuation of oral contraceptives.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ovarian Function and Reserve Parameters After Discontinuation of Long-term Use of Oral Contraception</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: Hormonal contraception is widely used among women worldwide; 50-89% of all women in the Western countries use oral contraception at some point in their lives. Oral contraceptives (OC) suppress the hypothalamic-pituitary-ovarian axis through a negative feedback of ethinyl estradiol and progestins and thereby potentially influence the markers of ovarian reserve due to a suppressed release of gonadotropins, which will impair the growth of antral follicles. Methods and Materials: Participants for this studies will be included through the Fertility Assessment and Counseling Clinic, Rigshospitalet, Herlev- and Hvidovre Hospital. Inclusion criteria: Use of oral contraception (for study 3 at least during the last three years). Exclusion criteria: Known infertility, known thyroid disease. Aims: Study 3: Investigate the ovarian reserve markers after discontinuation of OC over a period of three months in women with a history of long-term OC use. The women will be followed with serial ultrasounds and blood samples and will complete a menstrual calendar.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Contraceptives, Oral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Contraceptive Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Minimum three years of oral contraceptives. Known infertility, known thyroid disease.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>26 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Oral contraceptives</keyword>
	<keyword>long-term use</keyword>
	<keyword>AMH</keyword>
	<keyword>Ovarian reserve parameters</keyword>
</DOC>