<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00922350</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to verify that nebulization with bronchodilators associated with heliox gas (helium + oxygen) and the posture of a leaning forward truck is effective in patients with an asthma attack.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Heliox and Posture in Patients With Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>When associated with inhaled bronchodilators, the heliox, a mixture of helium and oxygen in obstructive lung diseases with asthma, reduces the turbulence of airflow despite high rates, due to its low density. Although the first report of the use of heliox in the treatment of asthma dating to 1935, few controlled studies are available clarify the impact of the use of heliox in hospital admission of patients with acute asthma attacks refractory to standard treatment. The severe airflow obstruction, observed in cases of acute asthma, also leads to lung hyperinflation that favors the increase of respiratory work by increasing the load for the inspiratory muscles by placing them at a mechanical disadvantage. Various body positions were studied relating them to muscle activity with mechanical disadvantage. These studies suggest that the influence posture acts mainly in the position of the diaphragm, thus, increasing the stress related to other muscles such as the abdominals and the effect of gravity on these. This study aims to: assess the efficiency of the positioning body associated with nebulization with bronchodilators carried by heliox during acute severe asthma in adults, using as the primary outcomes FEV1, FVC and PEF and secondary outcomes as the Borg scale, inspiratory capacity, RR, HR and SpO2.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bronchodilator Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>reversibility of bronchial obstruction after administration of bronchodilator drugs for at least 10% in FEV1 a clinical diagnosis of acute severe asthma a history of asthma over 1 year duration of the crisis of current asthma lasting less than seven days were unable to understand or perform the spirometric maneuver smoking (within the last 3 years associated with a higher consumption of 100 cigarettes/year) other pulmonary comorbidities lower to upper airways heart failure heart rate greater than 150 bpm systolic pressure below 90 mmHg or greater than 150 MHG pregnancy inability to stay inline with the trunk forward</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>heliox</keyword>
	<keyword>bronchodilators</keyword>
	<keyword>posture</keyword>
</DOC>