<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00922376</DOC>
	<brief_summary>New telemedicine systems have been designed to assist people suffering from diabetes in the management of their chronic disease. More recently the focus has been moving to portable systems equipped with Bluetooth. This study consists of evaluating an application called the Think Positive (T+) diabetes management software. It is a randomized controlled trial designed to compare, over a nine month period, a group of patients receiving usual care with a group of patients using the T+ system. The objectives of the study are to investigate the extent to which this telemedicine application helps patients control their blood sugar levels (HbA1c), as well as the extent to which its users consider it to be acceptable. The impact of its use on factors such as diabetes self-care, health status, quality of life, self-confidence in diabetes management, fear of hypoglycemia and illness representations will also be examined. Because of the supplementary real-time support and feedback that T+ offers, its use should lead to better outcomes in diabetes management than usual care does.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of the Clinical Efficacy and Acceptability of Think Positive (T+) in Diabetes Management</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 1 and type 2 diabetes patients Insulin requiring patients Sufficiently fluent in english HbA1c &gt; 7.5 Last visit with Diabetes Specialist Nurse (DSN) &lt; 12 months Psychiatric disorders Poor vision or/and lack of manual dexterity Prior use of T+ Participation in another ongoing trial Patients with antenatal/gestational Patients who are in transition between the children services and adult services Insulin pump users</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>self- management</keyword>
	<keyword>glycemic control</keyword>
	<keyword>telehealth</keyword>
	<keyword>mhealth</keyword>
</DOC>