<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00922103</DOC>
	<brief_summary>For patients with ulcerative colitis, eligible for surgical treatment, which restorative surgical procedure: the standard ileo pouch anal anastomosis or the alternative ileo neo rectal anastomosis is the best in terms of complications, functional outcome and health status and quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Investigate the Ileo Neo Rectal Anastomosis Compared to the Ileo Pouch Anal Anastomosis for Patients With Ulcerative Colitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This research is designed to answer questions from the medical profession and patients´ community (Crohn en Colitis Ulcerosa Society, the Netherlands) whether the new INRA technique needs further development on a broader scale or not. The research project will be conducted in the two institutes where INRA procedures have been carried out and in the UMCN to recruit matched control IPAA patients. There is a large experience with the IPAA procedure in this latter institute. The University of Tilburg will participate to work on health status and quality of life aspects. They have a large experience with quality of life research in general and have participated in QOL research in this topic before. The aim of this historical cohort study is to establish the value of INRA, compared to IPAA, for patients with ulcerative colitis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>UC patients with INRA procedure Age, sex and disease specific matched group of UCIPAA patients with temporary diverting ileostomy from the same period Written informed consent Exclusion criteria Pregnancy Malignancy (apart from basalioma or carcinomainsitu of cervix) Psychiatric disease or inability to assess follow up</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Colitis, Ulcerative</keyword>
	<keyword>Ileo Neo Rectal Anastomosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Ileal Pouch Anal Anastomosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
	<keyword>functional results</keyword>
	<keyword>reconstructive surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>surgery</keyword>
</DOC>