<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02572882</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Microbiome trial is a non-randomized, open-label, crossover, multi-center study of p-inulin for patients with hemodialysis-dependent end-stage renal disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gut Microbiome and p-Inulin in Hemodialysis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This primary objective of this exploratory study is to characterize the safety and tolerability of p-inulin in altering the composition and function of the human gut microbiome, thereby reducing the generation of gut-derived uremic toxins, improving gut barrier function and attenuating systemic inflammation in patients treated with maintenance hemodialysis. The study also aims to assess the feasibility of conducting a full-scale trial of p-inulin. The primary efficacy parameters of the trial will be intra- and inter-participant variability in gut metabolites and bacterial composition. Secondary parameters of interest include tolerability and safety of p-inulin, willingness of hemodialysis patients to enroll in a study requiring repeated collection of stool samples, and participant adherence to agent treatment and specimen collection schedules.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dysbiosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Maintenance hemodialysis therapy for endstage renal disease At least 18 years of age At least 90 days since hemodialysis initiation Selfreported average stool frequency of at least 1 every other day For women of childbearing potential, willingness to use a highly effective method of birth control for up to 4 weeks after the last dose of pinulin. Ability to provide consent Use of prebiotics or probiotics during the past 8 weeks Consumption of probiotic yogurt during the past 2 weeks Use of antibiotics within the past 8 weeks Presence of HIV infection, chronic wound infection, osteomyelitis, or current hemodialysis Inflammatory bowel disease, chronic diarrhea, current C. difficile infection Cirrhosis or chronic active hepatitis Anticipated kidney transplantation, change to peritoneal dialysis, or transfer to another dialysis unit within 9 months Expected survival less than 9 months Pregnancy, anticipated pregnancy, or breastfeeding Incarceration Participation in another intervention study Severe anemia defined as hemoglobin &lt;9.0 g/dl within the past 4 weeks as documented in the dialysis unit patient record</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>hemodialysis</keyword>
	<keyword>p-inulin</keyword>
	<keyword>gut microbiome</keyword>
</DOC>