<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02572804</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective randomised controlled trial that will compare the outcomes of rectus sheath catheters to epidurals in patients who have undergone a cystectomy, via a lower midline abdominal incision for bladder cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparing Rectus Sheath Catheter to Epidural Post Cystectomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will compare the outcomes of two different pain control techniques, used as standard of care, following major abdominal surgery for bladder removal. Rectus sheath catheters are small tubes that are positioned into a specific area of the cut abdominal wall at the end of surgery; whereas an epidural is a tube that is positioned into the back. Both allow administration of local anaesthetic for pain control. The current gold standard is an epidural. This study will aim to evaluate this and show the comparative efficacy of the rectus sheath catheter, which anecdotally the investigators have found superior in practice.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients over or equal to the age of 19 years old who can understand the study protocol and are able to give consent Patients with an American Society of Anaesthesiology (ASA) classification 1 to 3 Patients must have a preoperative oral 24 hour opioid consumption of less than or equal to 30mg morphine equivalents Patients must be able to understand and be able to use patient controlled analgesia Patients must be undergoing a cystectomy with an infraumbilical midline incision Patients with BMI greater than 40 Patients with an allergy to local anaesthetics Patients who are contraindicated to having an epidural (e.g. coagulopathic, distorted anatomy, patient refusal, infection at the site of proposed insertion) Patients with previous spinal surgery at the proposed site of epidural Patients with neurodegenerative disorders or spinal cord injury Patients with known anatomy that would not permit placement of the rectus sheath catheters e.g. Prune Belly Syndrome Patients undergoing another complex abdominal procedure in addition to cystectomy and reconstruction requiring extension of the abdominal incision above the umbilicus.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>bladder cancer-cystectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>rectus sheath catheter</keyword>
	<keyword>epidural</keyword>
</DOC>