<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02372916</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Given the aging population who will be affected by wet AMD and lack of effective GA treatment, it is crucial to assess the safety profile of repeated ranibizumab injections in AMD patients with GA, particularly the possible risk of GA development and enlargement. This potential adverse effect has significant implication in the discussions with patients regarding the risks and benefits of AMD treatment and injection frequency. While monthly injections provide slight improvement of visual acuity at 2 years (Martin et al., 2012), the risk of GA enlargement may offset this benefit in visual acuity. Previous studies assessed the association between intravitreal ranibizumab injections and de novo GA development in injection-naïve eyes (Martin et al, 2012, Querques et al., 2012., Grunwald et al., 2014), rather than GA enlargement in patients with preexisting GA. To the best of the investigators knowledge, there has been no prospective study assessing the association between intravitreal ranibizumab injections and rate of GA progression in patients with pre-existing GA. There is also no prospective study comparing the morphological features of GA between patients who are receiving intravitreal injections and those who are not, nor the concordance of GA enlargement rate between the 2 eyes among patients receiving and not receiving treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Geographic Atrophy and Intravitreal Ranibizumab Injections</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Geographic Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt; 50 years old Patients with preexisting GA secondary to AMD NOT requiring intravitreal injections (i.e. Dry AMD) Patients with preexisting GA and CNV secondary to AMD requiring intravitreal injections (i.e. Exudative AMD) and are treatmentnaïve patients Patients with preexisting GA and CNV secondary to AMD requiring intravitreal injections (i.e. Exudative AMD) and have received previous intravitreal injections. Able to maintain steady fixation in foveal and parafoveal area for fundus imaging Geographic atrophy (GA), both fovealsparing and foveal GA. Fovealsparing GA is defined as no GA within 250μm of the centre (Sunness et al. 1999) Area of GA can be imaged in its entirety and is not contiguous with areas of peripapillary atrophy Adequate media clarity for quality fundus images Inability to undergo study procedures (e.g. contraindications to intravitreal injections) or attend followup visits CNV attributable to other causes than AMD Active intraocular inflammation Any other retinopathy, including diabetic retinopathy, retinal venous occlusion, epiretinal membrane</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>