<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00210119</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Imatinib mesylate is standard treatment of Chronic myeloid leukaemia, complete cytogenetic response is obtained in most of cases but molecular response concerned only a small part of the patients. To increase molecular response ratio we decided to increase imatinib dose to limited resistance to this drug and to add zoledronate for it anti tumoral activity to increase anti leukemic effect. We plan to accrue 37 patients in 5 centers. We will analyse molecular expression of BCR-ABL transcript after 6 months of treatment, safety, duration of response, VEGF expression and LTgd production.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Imatinib Mesylate and Zoledronic Acid in Patients With Chronic Myeloid Leukaemia in Cytogenetic Response Without Molecular Response</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelogenous, Chronic, BCR-ABL Positive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Imatinib Mesylate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zoledronic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diphosphonates</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: at registration· Chronic myeloid leukaemia Ph+ confirmed by cytogenetic analysis or BCRABL translocation by molecular biology· Chronic phase:&lt;15% blast cells in blood and 5% in bone marrow&lt;30% blast cells+promyelocyte cells in blood and bone marrow&lt;20% basophils in blood&gt;100.000 platelets· Without extra medullar attempt excepted hepatosplenomagalia· First line of treatment· Biology and biochemistry with normal levels· Male or female&gt;18 years old· Signed written consent· ECOG&lt;3At inclusion· Chronic myeloid leukaemia with cytogenetic response without molecular response after one year of treatment by imatinib and BCRABL transcript detected by RTPCR · Other cancer excepted basocellular or cervix carcinoma · Major surgery in last 2 weeks previous inclusion· Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding (are unable to use an acceptable method to avoid pregnancy of his partner for the entire study period)· Dementia or altered mental status that would prohibit the understanding or rendering of informed consent · Abnormal renal function with creatinine clearance &lt; 30 ml/ minuteAccording to CockcroftGault : CrCl= [[140age (years)] x weight (kg)]/ [72 x serum creatinine (mg/dL)] {x 0.85 for women}· Chronic myeloid leukaemia in acute phase or in pass to be in acute phase · Treatment with bisphosphonates in last 6 months previous inclusion · Intolerance to bisphosphonates: hypersensitivity, on course dental problem, including tooth or mandibular infection; dental traumatism or recent diagnosis or previous mandibular osteonecrosis, or dental extraction with cicatrisation delay or necessity to set bone evidence · Mandibular surgery in last 6 weeks or planned in the future during treatment (tooth extraction)· Serious uncontrolled medical disorder or active infection that would impair the ability of the subject to receive protocol therapy: diabetes, thyroid pathology, neuropsychiatric illness, myocardial infarction or congestive heart failure grade 34 according to " New York Heart association"· History of psychiatric or depressive pathology · HIV positivity known · Inclusion in other study investigating antineoplastic molecule in last 30 days previous inclusion</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic myeloid leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>imatinib mesylate</keyword>
	<keyword>zoledronate</keyword>
	<keyword>molecular response</keyword>
</DOC>