<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00210587</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of epoetin alfa (PROCRITÂ®) administered 80,000 Units every three weeks in cancer patients that are not receiving chemotherapy or radiation therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Efficacy and Safety Study for Epoetin Alfa (PROCRIT) in Cancer Patients Not Receiving Chemotherapy or Radiation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The current approved dosage for epoetin alfa is 40,000 Units once per week with an escalation to 60,000 Units once per week if the response is inadequate after four weeks of treatment at 40,000 Units. This dosing scheme, while proven to be efficacious, is often inconvenient for both patients and medical personnel. This is an open-label, non-randomized, multi-center pilot study with the objective to investigate the efficacy of epoetin alfa (PROCRIT®) with regard to hematopoietic response when administered at 80,000 Units subcutaneously every three weeks in anemic patients with cancer not receiving chemotherapy or radiation therapy. Patients will receive two epoetin alfa injections (40,000 Units per injection) under the skin once every three weeks for a maximum of 13 weeks, totalling a maximum of four treatments. Doses may be reduced depending on the patients' hemoglobin level.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed diagnosis of nonmyeloid malignancy Baseline hemoglobin value of &lt;= 11 g/dL unrelated to transfusion Patients must not be receiving or planning to receive chemotherapy or radiotherapy within the 13week study period. However, patients receiving hormonal therapy or nonmyelosuppressive therapies are allowable Female patients with reproductive potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test at screening Patients must have signed an informed consent Uncontrolled hypertension History (within 6 months) of uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmias, or history of pulmonary emboli, deep vein thrombosis, ischemic stroke, other arterial or venous thrombotic events (excluding superficial thromboses), or known history of chronic coagulation disorder Transfusion within 28 days prior to first dose Planned chemotherapy or radiation during study and no prior chemotherapy within 8 weeks or radiation within 4 weeks of study entry No prior treatment with Epoetin alfa or any other erythropoietic agent within the previous two months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>hemoglobin level</keyword>
</DOC>