<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00872326</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to assess the efficacy and safety of autologous transplantation of bone-marrow cells for therapeutic angiogenesis and vasculogenesis in diabetic patients with non-revascularizable critical limb ischemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Autologous Bone Marrow Derived Mononuclear Cells in Treating Diabetic Patients With Critical Limb Ischemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Phase I/II, prospective, single-center study, with consecutive inclusion of 20 diabetic patients with critical limb ischemia due to bellow-the-knee extensive arterial disease. After the inclusion, patients are submitted to a bone-marrow aspiration (30 ml) under sedation. Autologous bone-marrow mononuclear cells (minimum 80 millions mononuclear cells) are infused intraarterially at popliteal artery by blocking antegrade perfusion during 3 minutes. Clinical and angiographic follow-up will be performed at 3 months after the infusion to assess the efficacy of autologous mononuclear cells transplantation in terms of: - Changes in below-the-knee angiography from baseline to 3 months follow-up. - Changes in Ankle-Brachial pressure Index, transcutaneous oxygen pressure, and size of main ischemic ulcer will be also assessed at target limb.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Foot</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diabetic patients under treatment (type I or II) Critical limb ischemia (rest pain and/or nonhealing ischemic ulcers lasting more than 4 weeks, and/or AnkleBrachial Index &lt; 0,8) Not suitable to be revascularized (surgical and interventional consensus) Neoplastic disease and/or hematologic disease during the last 2 years Diabetic retinopathy Ischemic ulcer greater than 10 cm2 Major amputation at target limb Life expectancy &gt; 2 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes Complications</keyword>
	<keyword>Lower limb ischemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Adult stem cells</keyword>
</DOC>