<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00872898</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the safety and efficacy of memantine extended release, as well as its extent of absorption in pediatric patients with autism.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Pharmacokinetics, Safety, Efficacy, and Tolerability of Memantine in Children With Autism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multicenter, two-part study in pediatric (ages 6 to 18 years) patients diagnosed with autism. Patients participating in Part One will receive a single open-label dose of memantine. Blood samples for pharmacokinetic analysis will be collected. Part Two is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled 12-week efficacy and safety study evaluating change in all core domains (social interactions, communication, and restricted interests and repetitive behaviors) of autism. In the Forest autism trials conducted in children ages 6-12, dosing with an extended release formulation of memantine was weight-based. These weight based dose limits were selected to ensure exposure in terms of area under the curve (AUC) was less than the predefined limit of 2100 ng∙h/mL that represented a 10-fold lower exposure than observed at the NOAEL (No observed adverse effect level) of 15 mg/kg/day in juvenile rats. The weight-based dose limits in these studies were as follows: - Group A: ≥ 60 kg; max 15 mg/day - Group B: 40-59 kg; max 9 mg/day - Group C: 20-39 kg; max 6 mg/day - Group D: &lt; 20 kg; max 3 mg/day</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Memantine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males or females ages 6 to 12 years Diagnosis of autistic disorder, according to DSMIVTR using Autism Diagnostic InterviewRevised and Autism Diagnostic Observation Schedule (modules 2 &amp; 3). A knowledgeable caregiver capable of providing reliable information about the patient's condition, able to attend all clinic visits with the patient Patients over age 12, only if they completed Study MEMPK21 Medical history of active epilepsy/seizure disorder except simple febrile seizures Participation in any other clinical investigation using an experimental drug within 30 days of the start of this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>autism</keyword>
	<keyword>memantine</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatric</keyword>
	<keyword>Forest Laboratories</keyword>
	<keyword>Autism in pediatric patients</keyword>
</DOC>