<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00872066</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to monitor the performance of artificial hip joints implanted with two different bone cements, SmartSet® HV and SmartSet® GHV, in the treatment of patients with hip joint disease requiring a total hip replacement. Patients who enter the study will be randomly allocated to SmartSet® HV or SmartSet® GHV and will be evaluated at regular intervals following hip surgery using patient, clinical and x-ray assessments</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess the Long-term Performance of SmartSet® HV and SmartSet® GHV Bone Cements in Primary Total Hip Replacement</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Necrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Femoral Fractures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Dislocation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Dislocation, Congenital</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Slipped Capital Femoral Epiphyses</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Collagen Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rheumatic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gentamicins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>i) Male or female subjects, aged between 18 and 75 years (inclusive). ii) Subjects who are able to give voluntary, written informed consent to participate in this investigation and from whom consent has been obtained. iii) Subjects who, in the opinion of the Investigator, are able to understand this investigation, cooperate with the investigational procedures and are willing to return to the hospital for all the required postoperative followups. iv) Subjects requiring primary total hip arthroplasty and are considered suitable for a cemented femoral component. i) Subjects who, in the opinion of the Investigator, have an existing condition that would compromise their participation and followup in this study. ii) Women who are pregnant. iii) Subjects who are known drug or alcohol abusers or with psychological disorders that could effect followup care or treatment outcomes. iv) Subjects who have participated in a clinical study with an investigational product in the last 6 month(s). v) Subjects who are currently involved in any injury litigation claims. vi) Subjects with contraindications normally applicable to the use of conventional bone cement, in accordance with the manufacturer's Instructions For Use.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hip</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Cement</keyword>
</DOC>