<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02508558</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Previous studies have neglected two important aspects for the China National Space Administration. First, while biomechanical models are very sensitive to the characteristics of the subjects, data have been collected on subjects with biomechanical characteristics very different from those of "typical" Chinese astronauts. Second, pure video analysis techniques and kinematic data lack the necessary acceleration information important to understanding the forces exerted during movement and control of human motion. While some studies used force and moment sensors to aid in robot torque control and human joint work estimation, investigators are unaware of any studies performed in a microgravity environment that have combined the kinetic force and moment information with acceleration measurements to enable more reliable motion tracking without the need for acceleration estimation. This is why MICR0-G sensors and accompanying kinematic video system have been developed in order to provide for detailed analyses of the astronaut movement control strategy (joint forces and torques, kinetic and acceleration measurements). Knowledge of the joint torques permits us to calculate the joint and musculoskeletal dynamics required to execute the microgravity motions, as well to provide insight into the altered movement strategies in reduced gravity as compared to 1-G locomotion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Validation of Methods for Evaluating Operation Force, Motion and Visual Perception in Weightlessness</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Healthy Chinese volunteers (men or women) Living in France and affiliated to a French Social Security system Aged from 22 to 45 Body Mass Index from 19 to 25 Who accepted to take part in the study Who has given their written stated consent Who has passed a medical examination similar to a standard aviation medical examination for private pilot aptitude (JAR FCL3 Class 2 medical examination). There will be no additional test performed for subject selection Person who took part in a previous biomedical research protocol, of which exclusion period is not terminated Pregnant women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>22 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>