<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00628160</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Septic shock is a frequent and severe complication in cirrhosis. Current mortality rate ranges between 50 and 80% of cases. Refractory shock, hepatorenal failure and variceal bleeding are the main causes of death of these patients. Terlipressin administration could prevent these complications and improve survival in this setting. Aim: To evaluate the effects of terlipressin administration on hospital survival in cirrhotic patients with severe sepsis or septic shock. Methods: Prospective, open labelled, controlled trial evaluating 72 cirrhotic patients with severe sepsis or septic shock who will be randomized to receive terlipressin plus alpha-adrenergic drugs or only alpha-adrenergic drugs at shock diagnosis. Patients will be submitted to continuous systemic hemodynamic monitoring (S. Ganz catheter or Vigileo). Changes in vasoactive systems and cytokines levels will be also evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Terlipressin in Septic Shock in Cirrhosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Prospective, open labelled, RCT evaluating 72 cirrhotic patients with severe sepsis or septic shock (36 per arm) who were randomized to receive terlipressin plus alpha-adrenergic drugs or alpha-adrenergic drugs in the first 24h after septic shock diagnosis. Impact of terlipressin administration on shock reversal, changes in vasoactive systems, inflammatory response, incidence of variceal bleeding and type-1 HRS and ICU and hospital mortality was investigated</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Shock</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Shock, Septic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adrenergic Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Norepinephrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dopamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Terlipressin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lypressin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dopamine Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age between 18 and 80 years; 2. Diagnosis of cirrhosis based on histology or on clinical, laboratory and ultrasonographical data; 3. Diagnosis of septic shock based on the presence of data compatible with systemic inflammatory response syndrome, a mean arterial pressure below 60 mmHg during more than 1 hour despite adequate fluid resuscitation, and need for circulatory support with vasopressor drugs. 1. More than 24 hours of evolution of the shock; 2. Cardiac index &lt; 2,5 l/min; 3. History of HIV infection or clinically relevant pulmonary, renal or cardiac disease except for atrial fibrillation; 4. Pregnancy; 5. Advanced hepatocellular carcinoma (Milan criteria); 6. Previous history of transplantation; 7. Uncontrolled gastrointestinal bleeding.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Septic shock</keyword>
	<keyword>Cirrhosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Survival</keyword>
</DOC>