<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01459159</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicenter, single arm open label Phase 2b Study of oral ezatiostat (Telintra®) in Patients who are RBC tranfusion dependent, Low to INT-1 IPSS risk, non-del (5q) Myelodysplastic Syndrome (MDS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of (Telintra®) in Non-Del(5q) Myelodysplastic Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Primary or de Novo MDS Low to Intermediate1 IPSS risk of MDS ECOG performance score of 0 or 1 Documentation of significant anemia with or without additional cytopenia Adequate kidney and liver function Patients must have discontinued hematopoietic growth factors at least 3 weeks prior to study entry Deletion of the 5q chromosome [del(5q) MDS] Prior allogenic bone marrow transplant for MDS Known sensitivity to ezatiostat (injection or oral tablets) Prior treatment with hypomethylating agent (HMA) (e.g., azacitadine, decitabine) History of MDS IPSS risk score of greater than 1.0 Pregnant or lactating women Any severe concurrent disease, infection or comorbidity that, in the judgement of the investigator, would make the patient inappropriate for study entry Oral steroids greater than 10 mg per day. Exceptions: those prescribed for other conditions (such as new adrenal failure, asthma, arthritis) or brief sterioid use (such as tapered dosing for an acute nonMDS condition) History of hepatitis B or C, or HIV</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hematology</keyword>
	<keyword>MDS</keyword>
	<keyword>Myelodysplastic Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Low risk MDS</keyword>
	<keyword>Int-1 risk MDS</keyword>
	<keyword>Transfusion dependence</keyword>
	<keyword>Telintra</keyword>
	<keyword>ezatiostat</keyword>
	<keyword>ezatiostat hydrochloride</keyword>
	<keyword>TLK199</keyword>
	<keyword>Glutathione</keyword>
	<keyword>Glutathione analog</keyword>
	<keyword>Glutathione Transferase</keyword>
	<keyword>Glutathione Transferase P1-1 inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>GST P1-1 inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Apoptosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Differentiation</keyword>
	<keyword>Enzyme inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>non-del (5q)</keyword>
	<keyword>non-deletion 5q</keyword>
</DOC>