<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01097005</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the efficacy and safety of long-term treatment with clarithromycin in patients with Non-tuberculous Mycobacterial Pulmonary Infections.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Special Investigation of Clarith/Klaricid in Patients With Non-tuberculous Mycobacterial Pulmonary Infections</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: The revised 2007 American Thoracic Society/Infectious Diseases Society of America guidelines recommend a clarithromycin-based combination therapy for treatment of Mycobacterium avium complex (MAC) lung disease and stipulate approximately 1 year of continuous treatment after bacilli negative conversion. However, supporting data are insufficient. Objectives: To obtain data on the clinical outcome of clarithromycin-based regimens by conducting a nationwide prospective study mainly of MAC lung disease. Methods: In accordance with the guidelines, patients were enrolled in this survey according to their chest radiographic findings and microbiologic test results. They were treated with a multi-drug regimen including clarithromycin, rifampicin, and ethambutol (clarithromycin -based regimen) until bacilli negative conversion on continual treatment for 1 year. Data were collected "pre-administration," "on the bacilli negative conversion," and "at 6 months after the end of treatment."</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycobacterium Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycobacterium Infections, Nontuberculous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clarithromycin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients with Pulmonary nontuberculous mycoplasma infection and who are indicated for treatment with Klaricid Exclusion Criteria Contraindications according to the package insert Patients with a history of hypersensitivity to any ingredient of Klaricid Patients who are receiving pimozide, ergotcontaining products, or cisapride Patients who have AIDS (Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mycobacterium Infections, Atypical</keyword>
</DOC>