<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01097070</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics (behavior in the body) of bevirimat administered for 15 days to HIV-positive individuals.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 2 Study to Assess the Pharmacokinetics of Bevirimat 100 mg Tablets Given to HIV-1 Positive Patient for 15 Days</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Have documentation of HIV1 infection in their medical records (documentation of any prior plasma viremia is acceptable). Have a CD4+ lymphocyte count &gt;/= 100 cells/mm3. Have a screening plasma HIV1 RNA value, measured by the Roche Amplicor assay, of &lt;400 copies/mL. Be receiving an ARV therapy regimen containing at least 3 drugs which has been unchanged for at least 8 weeks prior to screening, and which is to be continued through Day 15 of the study. Be informed of the nature of the study and provide written informed consent. Be legally competent and able to communicate effectively with study personnel. Be able and willing to comply with outpatient visits. Presence of any acute illness within 14 days prior to study entry. Presence of any AIDSrelated opportunistic infection (Category C according to the CDC Classification System for HIV1 Infection, 1993 Revised Version) that is unstable in the Investigator's opinion or diagnosed in the 30 days prior to study entry. Patients who are, in the opinion of the Investigator, unable to comply with the dosing schedule and protocol evaluations. Patients with malabsorption syndromes affecting drug absorptions (e.g. Crohn's disease, chronic pancreatitis). Patients with systolic blood pressure &lt; 90 mmHg or &gt; 160 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &lt; 50 mmHg or &gt; 110 mmHg. A history of seizures (excluding pediatric febrile seizures) or current administration of prophylactic antiseizure medication for the indication of seizures or seizurerelated conditions. A history of cerebrovascular accident (CVA) or transient ischemic attacks (TIA). Patients who have received radiation therapy or cytotoxic chemotherapeutic agents within 4 weeks prior to first dose of study drug. Patients who have received treatment with immunomodulating agents such as IL2, alphainterferon, betainterferon, or gammainterferon within 4 weeks prior to first dose of study drug. Receipt of an investigational drug or product, or participation in a drug study within a period of 30 days prior to receiving study medication. Bupropioncontaining products require at least a 14day washout period and will not be approved for coadministration. Rifampin or other rifamycin products require at least a 28day washout period and will not be approved for coadministration.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>