<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01097369</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: To determine the incidence, titer and type of anti-rasburicase antibodies in the context of hypersensitivity reaction(s) or the loss of uricolytic activity occurring in patients with relapsed leukemia/lymphoma who have been re-treated with rasburicase and have experienced a hypersensitivity reaction or loss of uricolytic activity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Elitek (Rasburicase) Immuno-Monitoring Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Tumor Lysis Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rasburicase</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 1. Previous history of rasburicase exposure and history of administration of a repeat (2nd) series of rasburicase injections (in the context of supportive care for relapsing leukemia/lymphoma) and subsequent development of either a hypersensitivity reaction (HSR) or loss of uricolytic activity (defined as failure to achieve uric acid level of &lt; or = 7.5 mg/dl measured 48 hours after the first rasburicase injection). 1. A severe hypersensitivity reaction (NCI Grade 3, 4 or 5) is defined as: Allergic reaction; allergy; anaphylactic shock; bronchospasm; bullous skin eruption; dermatitis exfoliative; drug hypersensitivity; dyspnea; hypotension; hypoxia; rash; rash erythematous; rash maculopapular, urticaria; pyrexia/fever; edema; chest discomfort; hypersensitivity (NOS); pharynx discomfort; hoarseness; pharyngeal erythema; pruritus; erythema; localized exfoliation; rash papular; swelling ¿ face/facial; toxic skin eruption; hot flush; flushing; rash macular; rash pruritic; pruritus allergic. 2. Loss of uricolytic activity can be defined as: uric acid levels &gt; 7.5 mg/dl measured 48 hours after the first rasburicase injection¿, which is a time point coincident with administration of the third dose of rasburicase (within that second course of treatment with this agent). 2. Patients should have received at least 2 doses of rasburicase during the repeat (2nd) administration in the event of loss or uricolytic activity. At least 1 dose of rasburicase should be administered during the repeat (2nd) administration for diagnosis of HSR. Exclusion criteria: 1. Concomitant treatment with human IV immunoglobulin (IVIG) 2. Concomitant treatment with TNFalpha antagonists/inhibitors, i.e. adalimumab, infliximab, and etanercept 3. Concomitant treatment with Interferonalpha (IFNalpha) 4. Unwillingness or inability to comply with the requirements of the protocol. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>