<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01512108</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial was conducted in Japan. The aim of this trial was to evaluate the safety and efficacy of once daily administration of liraglutide in combination with an oral anti-diabetic drug (OAD) in Japanese subjects with type 2 diabetes who are insufficiently controlled on OAD monotherapy. All subjects will continue their pre-trial OAD (either glinide, metformin, alpha-glucosidase inhibitor or thiazolidinedione) during the trial at unchanged type and dose.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Liraglutide in Combination With an OAD in Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes Insufficiently Controlled on OAD Alone</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypoglycemic Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent obtained before any trialrelated activities (trialrelated activities are any procedures that would not have been performed during normal management of the subject.) Japanese subjects with type 2 diabetes on monotherapy with an OAD (either glinide, metformin, aglucosidase inhibitor or thiazolidinedione) within approved Japanese labelling in addition to diet and exercise therapy. Total daily dose and type of drug should have remained unchanged for at least 8 weeks prior to Visit 1 Type 2 diabetes mellitus (clinically diagnosed) for at least 6 months HbA1c between 7.010.0% (both inclusive) Body Mass Index (BMI) below 40.0 kg/m^2 Outpatients who have no plans for an educational hospitalisation for the purpose of glycaemic control. However, hospitalisation for training of selfinjection from Visit 2 that is for no longer than one week is allowed Subjects able and willing to perform selfmonitoring of plasma glucose (SMPG) Subjects with known or previous malignant tumor and are strongly suspected of recurrence (except basal cell skin cancer or squamous cell skin cancer) Calcitonin above or equal to 160 pg/mL Personal history of nonfamilial medullary thyroid carcinoma Family or personal history of multiple endocrine neoplasia type 2 (MEN2) or familial medullary thyroid carcinoma (FMTC) History of chronic pancreatitis or idiopathic acute pancreatitis Recurrent severe hypoglycaemia (more than 1 severe hypoglycaemic event during the last 12 months) or hypoglycaemic unawareness as judged by the investigator or hospitalisation for diabetic ketoacidosis during the previous 6 months Treatment with GLP1 receptor agonist or dipeptidyl peptidase 4 (DPP4) inhibitor within 12 weeks prior to Visit 1 Having contraindications to liraglutide and any of the OADs (according to Japanese labelling)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>