<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01328951</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This double-blind, placebo-controlled study will evaluate the benefit of first-line maintenance erlotinib (Tarceva) versus erlotinib at the time of disease progression in participants with advanced NSCLC who have not progressed following 4 cycles of platinum based-chemotherapy and whose tumor does not harbor an epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)-activating mutation. Participants will be randomized to receive either erlotinib 150 milligrams (mg) orally (PO) once daily or placebo. Participants who progress on placebo will receive erlotinib 150 mg PO once daily as second-line therapy, and those who progress on erlotinib may switch to a non-investigational, second-line chemotherapy. Treatments will continue until disease progression, death, or unacceptable toxicity. Participants may also be entered into a final Survival Follow-Up (SFU) period upon treatment discontinuation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of First-line Maintenance Erlotinib Versus Erlotinib at Disease Progression in Participants With Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC) Who Have Not Progressed Following Platinum-Based Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Disease Progression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults greater than or equal to (≥) 18 years of age, or legal age of consent if greater than 18 Advanced or recurrent (Stage IIIB) or metastatic (Stage IV) NSCLC Completion of 4 cycles of platinumbased chemotherapy without progression (end of last chemotherapy cycle less than or equal to [≤] 28 days prior to randomization) Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 or 1 Prior exposure to agents directed at human epidermal growth factor receptor (HER) axis (e.g. erlotinib, gefitinib, cetuximab) Participants whose tumors harbor an EGFRactivating mutation Prior chemotherapy or therapy with systemic antineoplastic therapy for advanced disease before Screening Use of pemetrexed in maintenance setting (pemetrexed allowed during the chemotherapy runin) Participants who have undergone complete tumor resection after responding to the platinumbased chemotherapy during the Screening phase Any other malignancies within 5 years, except for curatively resected carcinoma in situ of the cervix, basal or squamous cell skin cancer, ductal carcinoma in situ, or organconfined prostate cancer Central nervous system (CNS) metastases or spinal cord compression that has not been definitely treated with surgery and/or radiation, or treated CNS metastases or spinal cord compression without stable disease for ≥2 months Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B, or hepatitis C infection Any inflammatory changes of the surface of the eye</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>