<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01530243</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the investigators study is to evaluate whether alpha-blockers such as terazosin and anti-cholinergics such as tolterodine can be relieve the DJ-stent related symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Terazosin and Tolterodine on Ureteral Stent Related Symptoms</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Ureteral stent (US) has been as essential tool in the urologist's surgeries and is useful instruments that its indications increase due to new stent technologies and improvement of patient's comfort. US associated with discomfort complications that include lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS) as frequency, urgency, dysuria, incomplete emptying, flanks and suprapubic's pain, incontinence, hematuria, movement of stent, infection and encrustation of stent. US related symptoms are as same as LUTS due to benign prostate hyperplasia and overactive bladder which relieve with alpha-blockers and anticholinergic. The purpose of our study is to investigate the effect of terazosin and tolterodine lonely and together in comparison of placebo on US related symptoms. The investigators study will be done prospectively. The patients who underwent indwelling Double-j stent distributed into four groups: 1)receive placebo 2)receive terazosin 2mg twice 3)receive tolterodine 2mg daily 4) receive terazosin 2mg twice and tolterodine 2mg daily. All of the patients receive prophylactic antibiotic and on demand analgesic. After entrance to study, they fulfill the International Prostatic Symptoms Score (IPSS) and Visual Analog Scale (VAS) on the before indwelling US, two weeks after indwelling US and US removal time, then the investigators will evaluate the drug's effect on US related symptoms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tolterodine Tartrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Terazosin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prazosin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>If a patient does not meet any exclusion criteria and to be undergone doubleJ stent indwelling. 1. Prior history of pelvic surgery 2. Prior history of Transurethral Resection of the either Prostate or Bladder Tumor 3. Benign prostate hyperplasia 4. Recent or recurrent urinary tract infection 5. Chronic medication with betablockers or Anticholinergic 6. Pregnancy 7. Prostatitis 8. Prostate cancer 9. Bilateral ureteroscopy or ureteral stenting 10. Age &lt; 18 and &gt; 55 11. Stone size &gt; 20 mm 12. Diabetes 13. Bladder Outlet Obstruction</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>