<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01530620</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical study is to compare efficacy and safety of propiverine hydrochloride extended and immediate release formulations in patients suffering from neurogenic detrusor overactivity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Tolerability of Propiverine Hydrochloride in Patients With Neurogenic Detrusor Overactivity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Enuresis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Neurogenic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urologic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Overactive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Propiverine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female Caucasian patients aged ≥18 and ≤70 years Voluntarily signed informed consent Neurogenic detrusor overactivity with occurrence of reflex detrusor contractions Reflex volume of ≤250 mL Intact reflex arcs in the area of segments S2S4 Patients suffering from multiple sclerosis under unstable conditions Augmented reflex bladder Patients with increased residual urine (≥20 % of the maximum bladder capacity), in whom catheterization is not possible Acute urinary tract infection Electrostimulation therapy (within 4 weeks propir to Visit 1) Anomalies of the lower genitourinary tract (e.g. ectopic ureters, fistulas, urethral stenosis) Radiation bladder, interstitial cystitis, bladder calculi, bladder carcinoma Surgery of the lower genitourinary tract within the last 6 months (e.g. prostatectomy, hysterectomy, tumor surgery) Preexisting medical contraindications for anticholinergics Cardiac insufficiency (NYHA stage III/ IV) Therapy with botulinum toxin within the last 12 months Evidence of severe renal, hepatic or metabolic disorders History of drug or alcohol abuse Concomitant medication known to have a potential to interfere with the trial medication Known hypersensitivity to Propiverine hydrochloride or excipients contained in the trial medication, respectively Pregnant or breastfeeding women, or women of childbearing potential without using any reliable contraceptive method Patients with impaired cooperation or who are unable to understand the nature, scope and possible consequences of the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Antimuscarinics</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurogenic bladder</keyword>
	<keyword>Propiverine</keyword>
	<keyword>Urodynamics</keyword>
</DOC>