<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01530269</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Positron emission tomography using carbon-11 acetate (AC-PET) may help find local or distant metastases from prostate cancer. This clinical trial is studying how this imaging test may help influence the choice and extent of initial treatments, and subsequent treatments.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>C11-Sodium Acetate PET/CT Imaging for Metastatic Disease in Intermediate-to-high Risk Prostate Adenocarcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the role of positron emission tomography using carbon-11 acetate (AC-PET) in the initial and subsequent management of patients with prostate cancer at intermediate or high risk for recurrence after initial curative therapy. - Compare the value of AC-PET in predicting recurrence of prostate cancer with that of conventional approaches (e.g., pre-operative clinical staging, prostate-specific antigen, Gleason score, prostate and lymph node histology) in these patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male patients will be studied who have prostate cancer: Diagnosed with prostate adenocarcinoma Has completed conventional staging examinations, including histologic evaluation with Gleason score, CT scan of the abdomen and pelvis, and wholebody bone scintigraphy Candidate for curative prostatectomy OR curative radiotherapy OR staging lymphadenectomy prior to surgery Deemed to be at intermediate or high risk for recurrence or metastatic disease after initial curative treatment, as defined by of one of the following: Gleason score &gt;= 7 or PSA &gt;= 10 Gleason score &lt; 7 or PSA &lt;10 ng/mL with positive surgical margins, biopsy proven or suspected regional nodal involvement or conventional imaging showing limited metastatic disease that may be amenable to directed radiotherapy Rising or nonresponding PSA &lt; 18 years old claustrophobic patients</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>intermediate</keyword>
	<keyword>high</keyword>
	<keyword>risk</keyword>
	<keyword>radiation</keyword>
	<keyword>therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>planning</keyword>
	<keyword>surgical</keyword>
	<keyword>immunotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>hormone</keyword>
</DOC>