<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01101815</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will obtain pilot data on the impact oral naltrexone 50 mg/day vs. a sustained-release naltrexone implant on response to antiretroviral therapy (ART) in opioid addicted patients beginning ART in St. Petersburg, Russia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adherence to HIV Therapy in Heroin Addicts</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will randomize, in a 1:1 ratio, 260 recently detoxified opioid addicts beginning ART to a 48-week course of biweekly drug counseling with either oral naltrexone 50 mg/day + placebo naltrexone implant, or placebo tablet + naltrexone implant. Approximate balanced randomization will be achieved by using an urn randomization design within each set of sites based in two baseline characteristics: (1) viral load &gt;100,000 copies/&lt;100,000 copies, and (2) CDF count &gt;50/&gt;50 copies. The primary outcome will be the response to ART as measured by reduction in viral load at 24 and 48 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Naltrexone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heroin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HIV+ men or women with no prior ART Age 18 and above CD4+ lymphocyte counts &lt;350 cells/mm3 Viral load of 1,000 copies or more Meet DSMIV criteria for Opioid Dependence in Early Remission Negative opiate urine toxicology and alcohol breath test No evidence of physiologic dependence on physical examination and After naloxone challenge Stable address in St. Petersburg or the Leningrad Region Telephone number where subjects can be reached (most patients in prior Studies have mobile phones and all live with friends or relatives) Negative pregnancy test &amp; use adequate contraception if childbearing age Ability to give informed consent as judged by ability to read the consent and correctly answer 9 of 10 questions about the study on a quiz that will be administered after discussing the study and reading the consent (patients will be given three opportunities to retake and pass the quiz if they fail the first time) Currently psychotic as determined by psychiatric examination (schizophrenia, Paranoid disorder, mania) Suicidal or homicidal ideation requiring immediate attention as determined at Baseline assessment Uncontrolled seizure disorder; Cognitive impairment with inability to read and understand the consent Significant laboratory abnormality such as &gt;2 grade anemia, hepatic transaminase Levels &gt;3 times upper limit of normal, serum creatinine &gt;1.5 times UNL Legal charges with impending incarceration Concurrent participation in another treatment study Currently taking naltrexone.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Viral Loads</keyword>
	<keyword>Naltrexone</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Risk</keyword>
	<keyword>Substance Abuse</keyword>
</DOC>