<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01887639</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A non interventional, descriptive, longitudinal cohort study is designed, trying to obtain local data about the prevalence of non remitted depressed patients after an antidepressant treatment, and to get information about sociodemographic and clinical characteristics of these patients as well as features of their treatments and compare them with those of the patients that achieve remission. Also the effect of patient´s expectation in the treatment outcome will be examined.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prevalence and Risk Factors in Unipolar Depression Patients Without Remission After One Antidepressant Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A non interventional, descriptive, longitudinal cohort study is designed, trying to obtain local data about the prevalence of non remitted depressed patients after an antidepressant treatment, and to get information about sociodemographic and clinical characteristics of these patients as well as features of their treatments and compare them with those of the patients that achieve remission. Also the effect of patient´s expectation in the treatment outcome will be examined. Non psychotic depressed patients that are initiating an antidepressant treatment will be recruited. Socio demographic and clinical features will be recorded as well as their expectations before the treatment. Severity of depression and treatment characteristics will be recorded after 4 to 8 weeks of drug treatment at an adequate dose. Variables will be compared between the patients that will achieve remission and those that do not.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antidepressive Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female and male aged 18 to 75 years old. Outpatients with a current episode of nonpsychotic unipolar major depression according to the DSM IVTR. Severity of illness assessed by means of a score ≥ 14 in the HAM D17 Have not been medicated for the current depression episode with an antidepressant Provision of subject informed consent Patients participating in any clinical trial, the subject cannot take part in this study. The individual has participated in the last 3 months (including this study) or is participating in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-psychotic unipolar major depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Resistant depression</keyword>
</DOC>