<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01497080</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Problem Distal radius fractures (DRF) are common and result in a variable amount of disability. The investigators have completed considerable work in developing tools that measure impairment and disability after DRF . The investigators initial studies indicate that the associated disablement process is multifactorial and variable with only 25% of the resultant disability predicted by baseline patient and injury characteristics. The investigators see DRF as a signal event where some people are at-risk of transitioning from an active lifestyle to inactivity and subsequent health risks. The investigators recent data confirms variable participation following a DRF. The traditional focus in orthopedic/rehabilitative approaches to DRF fracture management has been localized to the wrist, largely ignoring this potential transition and its health impacts. The investigators will initiate a line of investigation that will profile the at-risk older adult who presents with a DRF with the ultimate goal of accurate identification and prevention of adverse activity transitions (active to inactive). In this study the investigators will identify the extent of the problem by quantifying changes in activity/participation and its short-term health impacts. The investigators will also identify the risk factors present at time of injury that predict a loss of mobility/activity/participation. This work has the potential to identify tools and/or clinical prediction rules that identify at-risk individuals at a critical time where early intervention might most easily prevent adverse outcomes associated with inactivity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Distal Radius Fracture Prospective Database 50-80 Years Old</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Radius Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>individuals 5080 years old one month of fracture resulting from a fall from standing height or less will be recruited through our orthopedic surgeon wrist fracture previous history of humeral, hip or vertebral fracture • Testing will not be performed on patients with evident postural instability, severe chronic conditions (Parkinson's disease) or other vestibuloocular abnormalities.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>distal radius fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>Condition</keyword>
	<keyword>risk factors</keyword>
	<keyword>adverse activity transitions following DRF</keyword>
	<keyword>optimal assessment approach</keyword>
</DOC>