<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02476630</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Oxygen concentration for patients undergoing cardiac catheterization and during admission to an intensive care unit is important outcome measure for clinical care. Currently, the tool used to monitor the oxygen concentration is a central venous access positioned in the superior vena cava or in the pulmonary artery to monitor the central venous oxygen saturation (ScvO2). However, it is invasive and not always possible due to a lack of a central line access. In this research study, the investigator would like use a noninvasive means for the ScvO2 by using the thenar tissue oxygen concentration (StO2). The primary aim for the study is to determine if the thenar StO2 correlates with ScvO2 and can serve as a noninvasive surrogate for ScvO2.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Thenar Tissue Oxygen Concentration (StO2): A Non-invasive Surrogate for Central Venous Oxygen Saturation (ScvO2)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants will be undergoing a cardiac catheterization at Shands Children's Hospital or will be admitted to the intensive care unit, and as part of the clinical care either a central venous access positioned in the superior vena cava or in the pulmonary artery. As a part of the routine clinical care blood gases are frequently taken for continuous evaluation of therapy to monitor the central venous oxygen saturation (ScvO2). A measurement of thenar tissue oxygen concentration will be timed with a central venous blood gas draw to monitor the tissue oxygen concentration (StO2). The StO2 measurement will be taken by using the InSpectraTM StO2 monitor manufactured by Hutchinson Technology INC. after applying the noninvasive clip on probe to the thenar eminence of the right hand to measure the StO2 level. After a stable reading is obtained for 60 seconds it will be recorded. The two different measurements of oxygen concentration will be compared to determine if a correlation exists.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Age 1 month to 21 years of age admitted to the intensive care unit or undergo cardiac catheterization at Shands Children's Hospital and have a central venous access positioned in the superior vena cava or pulmonary artery. 1. Age less than 1 month or more than 21 years 2. Burns of the hand 3. Infection of hand 4. Fracture of upper extremity 5. Hematoma of hand over thenar eminence</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>