<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02476006</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: To provide patients with severe hypercholesterolemia at risk for subsequent cardiovascular (CV) events and not adequately controlled with currently available lipid-modifying therapy (LMT) access to alirocumab ahead of commercial availability and to document the overall safety and tolerability of alirocumab in this patient population. Secondary Objectives: To document the effect of alirocumab on low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) levels as well as non-high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (non-HDL-C), total cholesterol (total-C), high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C), and triglyceride (TG) levels after 12 weeks of treatment. To document patient's acceptability of self-injection (Self Injection Assessment Questionnaire, SIAQ).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Tolerability, and Effect of Alirocumab in High Cardiovascular Risk Patients With Severe Hypercholesterolemia Not Adequately Controlled With Conventional Lipid-modifying Therapies (ODYSSEY APPRISE)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study duration includes a screening period of up to 3 weeks, a treatment period of a minimum of 12 weeks and up to a maximum 30 months, and at least 2 weeks after the last study treatment injection.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypercholesterolemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Either A, B, C, D, or E below and not adequately controlled with a maximally tolerated dose of statin with or without other LMTs, all at stable doses for at least 4 weeks prior to the screening visit (Week 3): A. Patients suffering from heterozygous familial hypercholesterolemia (heFH) with LDLC concentrations ≥160 mg/dL (4.14 mmol/L) despite treatment. B. Patients suffering from heFH with LDLC concentrations ≥130 mg/dL (3.36 mmol/L) despite treatment and two or more CV risk factors among this list: LDLC &gt;250 mg/dL (6.46 mmol/L) at the time of the FH diagnosis (before treatment). Family history of prematureonset coronary heart disease (CHD; firstdegree male relative with onset before age 55 years; firstdegree female relative with onset before age 65 years). Metabolic syndrome. HDLC &lt;40 mg/dL (1.03 mmol/L). Hypertension (blood pressure &gt;140/90 mmHg or drug treatment). Lipoprotein a (Lp[a]) ≥50 mg/dL (1.78 µmol/L). Tendon xanthoma. C. Patients suffering from heFH with LDLC concentrations ≥130 mg/dL (3.36 mmol/L) despite treatment and one of the following characteristics: Established CHD or other cardiovascular disease (CVD; history of acute myocardial infarction, ischemic stroke, peripheral arterial disease, coronary or peripheral arterial revascularization, stable or unstable angina, transient ischemic attack, carotid artery stenosis ≥50%, or aortic abdominal aneurysm). Drugtreated type 2 diabetes mellitus or type 1 with target organ damage. Family history of first or seconddegree relative with very premature onset CHD (first or seconddegree male relative with onset before age 45; first or seconddegree female relative with onset before age 55). D. NonFH patients suffering from established CHD or other CVD (history of acute myocardial infarction, ischemic stroke, peripheral arterial disease, coronary or peripheral arterial revascularization, stable or unstable angina, transient ischemic attack, carotid artery stenosis ≥50%, or aortic abdominal aneurysm) and with LDLC concentrations ≥130 mg/dL (3.36 mmol/L). E. Patients suffering from progressive CVD (coronary artery disease, or peripheral arterial occlusive disease or cerebrovascular disease as documented clinically or by imaging techniques, with a subsequent CV event [acute MI, ischemic stroke, ischemiadriven revascularization, unstable angina, transient ischemic attack] occurring despite stable doses of maximally tolerated LLT) with LDLC concentrations ≥100 mg/dL (2.59 mmol/L). Exclusion criteria: Not on a stable dose of LMT (including statin) for at least 4 weeks prior to the screening visit (Week 3) and from screening to enrollment. Use of a fibrate other than fenofibrate within 4 weeks of the screening visit (Week 3) or between screening and enrollment. Daily doses above atorvastatin 80 mg, rosuvastatin 40 mg, or simvastatin 40 mg (except for patients on simvastatin 80 mg for more than one year, who are eligible). Use of statin other than simvastatin, atorvastatin, or rosuvastatin prior to the screening visit (Week 3) or between screening and enrollment, except when there is a documented reason for intolerance to the abovementioned potent statins (in which case the use of a different statin is allowed). Fasting serum TG &gt;400 mg/dL (&gt;4.52 mmol/L) at the screening visit (Week 3). Uncontrolled hypertension (&gt;180 mmHg systolic and/or &gt;110 mmHg diastolic at randomization visit). New York Heart Association Class III or IV congestive heart failure persisting despite treatment. History of hemorrhagic stroke. Liver transaminases &gt;3 times the upper limit of normal. Laboratory evidence of current hepatitis B or C infection. Creatine kinase &gt;3 times the upper limit of normal. Estimated glomerular filtration rate &lt;30 mL/min/1.73 m^2. Pregnant or breastfeeding woman or with childbearing potential without appropriate contraception. Male participant with a female partner of childbearing potential not protected by a highlyeffective method(s) of birth control. Patients eligible for enrollment into an ongoing clinical study of alirocumab conducted at the same investigational site. Hypersensitivity to alirocumab or any of the excipients. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>