<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02996214</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the efficacy and the safety of paclitaxel liposome injection and carboplatin compared with gemcitabine and carboplatin as first-line therapy in advanced squamous cell carcinoma of lung.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lipusu Advanced Squamous Cell Carcinoma of Lung Study Carboplatin in Advanced Squamous Cell Carcinoma of Lung</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to investigate the efficacy and the safety of paclitaxel liposome injection and carboplatin compared with gemcitabine and carboplatin as first-line therapy in advanced squamous cell carcinoma of lung. This study is the Superiority Trial.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Aged 1875 years old, both gender; 2. ECOG: 01; 3. Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of squamous nonsmallcell lung cancer (stage IIIB or IV); 4. No prior chemotherapy, biological therapy or immunotherapy; or subjects have recurrence and metastasis more than 6 months after the end of chemotherapy, but not gemcitabine or paclitaxel; 5. At least one radiographically measurable or assessable lesion on chest CG according to RECIST1.1 (response evaluation criteria of solid tumors); regional lymph node metastases may also be measured or assessed by imaging (mediastinal lymph nodes); 6. Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks; 7. Before treatment, blood tests or biochemical measurements must meet the following criteria: White blood cell count (WBC)≥ 4.0*109/L; Neutrophil count (ANC)≥ 2.0*109/L; Platelet count (PLT)≥ 100*109/L; Hemoglobin (Hb)≥ 100g/L; Hepatic function: serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times the upper normal limit, aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤ 2.5 times the upper normal limit; Renal function: creatinine ≤ 1.5 times the upper normal limit; 8. Signed informed consent. 1. Hypersensitivity reaction to the interventional drugs; 2. Pregnant or breastfeeding; 2.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>