<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02996617</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Neutropenia is one of the most frequent adverse effects of chemotherapy, and the main factor to limit the dosage and the continuation of chemotherapy. The PEG-rhG-CSF has increased plasma half-life, and prolonged efficacy in compare with rhG-CSF. The purpose of this study is to determine the safety and effectiveness of PEG-rhG-CSF in preventing neutropenia following chemotherapy in patients with non-Hodgkin lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PEG-rhG-CSF in Patients With Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma Receiving Chemotherapy to Prevent Neutropenia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Neutropenia is a common clinical complication of chemotherapy in cancer patients. It is an important factor that delays the course of standard treatments in patients. Recombinant human granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (rhG-CSF) is an effective drug for the treatment of chemotherapy-induced neutropenia. However, for patients with neutropenia, multiple rhG-CSF treatments are usually required. This is likely to extend the antitumor treatment period and increase physical and mental stress in patients. Pegylated recombinant human granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (PEG-rhG-CSF) is rhG-CSF chemically modified by a single methoxy polyethylene glycol group; it is able to alleviate neutropenia with a single dose. The aim of the present study was to determine the safety and effectiveness of preventive treatment with pegylated recombinant human granulocyte colony stimulating factor (PEG-rhG-CSF) on concurrent chemotherapy-induced neutropenia and to provide a rational basis for its clinical application. Therefore, the investigators designed the multi-center, open-label,randomized controlled clinical study and aimed to compare the efficacy and safety between PEG-rhG-CSF and rhG-CSF in non-Hodgkin lymphoma receiving chemotherapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neutropenia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Investigator diagnosis of nonHodgkin lymphoma(Highly invasive lymphoma/Burkitt lymphoma were excluded) Age 18 to 80 years ECOG performance status ≤ 2 receive multicycle Chemotherapy naive grade 3/4 neutropenia occurred in the patient's first cycle chemotherapy or the risk of neutropenia ＞20% without rhGCSF support Expected survival time≥3 months; cNormal bone marrow function(absolute neutrophil count ≥1.5 × 109/L; platelet count ≥ 80 × 109/L) Liver function: transaminase≤2.5× upper limit of normal value，bilirubin≤2.5×upper limit of normal value; serum creatinine≤2×upper limit of normal value; Patients with severe complications or severe infection; Invasion of central nervous system; Patients with severe visceral organ dysfunction, heart block, myocardial infarction within 6 months; Prior bone marrow stem cell or organ transplantation patients with severe allergic constitution, or those who are allergic to Escherichia coli products; 5. Patients participate in other clinical studies within 4 weeks; Pregnancy, lactation Other patients who are not suitable for the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lymphomas Non-Hodgkin's B-Cell</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphomas Non-Hodgkin's T-Cell</keyword>
	<keyword>PEG-rhG-CSF</keyword>
	<keyword>Neutropenia</keyword>
</DOC>