<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01471925</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A phase III, randomized, open-label, superiority study comparing the incremental product esomeprazole associated with sodium bicarbonate made by Eurofarma and Nexium® in the treatment of gastroesophageal reflux disease. The study will enroll 94 patients in each arm (total of 188 patients).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Comparing Esomeprazole Associated With Sodium Bicarbonate From Eurofarma and Esomeprazole in Treatment of Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease ESOBIC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Gastroesophageal Reflux</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esomeprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ICF signing; Age ≥ 18 years; Gastroesophageal reflux disease diagnosis; Grade 0 to grade III reflux esophagitis, assessed by means of upper gastrointestinal endoscopy; Ability to have the endoscopy, pHmetry and esophageal manometry examinations performed; Washout period of 1 week without using PPI, H2 antagonists and prokinetic agents and of at least 1 day without using antacids. Presence of esophagitis requiring intervention (grade IV), esophageal varices, Barrett's esophagus, systemic sclerosis or ulcers (gastric or duodenal ulcers); Previous gastric or esophageal surgery; Dietary sodium restriction, metabolic alkalosis, hypokalemia, Barter syndrome; Pregnancy or breastfeeding; Concomitant diseases, such as kidney, liver and heart failure; Suspected or confirmed cancer of any type; Abusive drug or alcohol use; Abnormal values for white blood cells, platelets or hemoglobin; Significant changes in serum sodium, potassium, calcium or creatinine concentrations; Treatment with PPI, H2 antagonists or prokinetic agents that may not be withheld during the washout period of 1 week or during the study; Intolerance or allergy to any of the components in the drug products assessed in the study; Use of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), antiemetic agents, macrolide antibiotics and systemic corticoids for a period equal to or greater than 2 weeks before the study or that is expected to require prolonged use during study treatment; Concomitant use or requirement of a gastric pHdependent medication for optimal absorption; Scheduled use of other medications metabolized by cytochrome CYP during the study; History of active peptic ulcer; Rare hereditary problems of fructose intolerance, glucosegalactose malabsorption or sucroseisomaltase insufficiency; Recent participation (within the last 12 months) in another clinical study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>