<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00741065</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study purpose: To examine the safety of myocardial regeneration by direct epicardial shock wave therapy in combination with coronary artery bypass grafting.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>DESWT-Pilot Study on the Safety of Myocardial Regeneration by Direct Epicardial Shock Wave Therapy in Combination With Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Direct epicardial shock wave therapy: DESWT will be performed in adjunct to a standard CABG procedure. Prior to aortic cross clamping, DESWT will be performed using a CardioGold® CG050 (CRT Cardiac Regeneration Technologies, Woodstock, USA / manufactured by MTS-Europe GmbH, Konstanz, Germany) shock wave therapy device and a specially designed handheld applicator under sterile conditions. Depending on the localisation of the myocardial infarct scar, 290-310 impulses will be applied to the anterior, lateral, or posterior wall. Shock waves will be generated at 1 or 2 Hz in a non ECG triggered fashion, should DESWT result in significant ventricular arrhythmias, ECG gating will be initiated. After completion of DESWT, CABG will be continued in a regular fashion.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Male or female patients above 18 years of age undergoing primary coronary artery bypass grafting. Patients have to present with reduced left ventricular function defined as LVEF &lt; 50%. Patients have to present with regional left ventricular wall motion abnormalities. Patients have to give written informed consent to participate in the study. Significant concomitant valve disease(except significant valve disease not detected in preoperative cardiac ultrasound that is detected intraoperatively). HIV positive patients. Hepatitis C positive patients. Patients in cardiogenic shock. Patients with a contraindication for cardiac MRI. Present contraindication for transoesophageal echocardiography (TEE). History of significant ventricular arrhythmias, except arrhythmias associated with MI. Highly reduced left ventricular function defined as LVEF &lt;30%. Present comorbidity which reduces life expectancy to less than 6 months. Presence of ventricular thrombus. Presence of a cardiac tumor. Pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting</keyword>
	<keyword>Myocardial Regeneration</keyword>
</DOC>