<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00741650</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A randomized controlled trial comparing a new approach to musculoskeletal pain consisting of education and peer involvement to treatment as usual. All local government employees in 1-3 Norwegian municipalities will be invited to participate.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ibedrift- A Trial Comparing a New Approach to Musculoskeletal Pain Consisting of Education and Peer Involvement to Treatment as Usual</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of the study is to systematically test a new treatment method for musculoskeletal pain in Norway. The intervention focuses on attempting to treat musculoskeletal pain outside the traditional medical system as much as possible, to avoid the establishment of a patient identity and passive patient behavior. In addition, participants are given reasons to stay active, and not advice to stay active. Ibedrift is a randomized controlled trial with the aim of studying the effect of a new treatment regime for musculoskeletal pain, focusing on didactic information about low back pain with peer support. Those participants not in the control group will have the option of contacting a peer advisor, a non health professional trained by the iBedrift crew to give information about back pain and reasons to stay active. For those who have not recovered within a short period of time, and who are randomized to full treatment, the peer advisor can send them directly to health personnel for a brief intervention consisting of a medical examination with screening for conditions that need treatment, counseling and education. The intervention was done in 2 Norwegian municipalities for all local government employees. Randomization was done at the level of working units (schools, offices etc) which allows for more message containment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neck Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All employees above 18 years Cancer Known congenital musculoskeletal disease Cauda equina syndrome</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Musculoskeletal pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Brief cognitive intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive behavior therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Intervention Study</keyword>
	<keyword>Health prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>workplace intervention</keyword>
</DOC>