<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00635843</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical trial is to assess the safety and effectiveness of the MAVERICK™ Total Disc Replacement as a method of treating patients with lumbar degenerative disc disease at one level from L4-S1, with overall success being the primary endpoint of the clinical trial. The primary objective is to show non-inferiority of the investigational device to the control treatment. If non-inferiority is established, superiority will be examined.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>MAVERICK™ Total Disc Replacement- Pivotal Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>For this clinical trial, there are two treatment groups, i.e., investigational patients who receive the MAVERICK™ Total Disc Replacement and control patients who receive the anterior lumbar interbody fusion procedure with INFUSE® Bone Graft/LT-CAGE® Lumbar Tapered Fusion Device. Each investigational site will enroll patients in a 2:1 investigational:control treatment randomization scheme.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Intervertebral Disc Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Has DDD as noted by back pain of discogenic origin, with or without leg pain, with degeneration of the disc confirmed by patient history Has 1 or more of the following documented by CT, MRI, or plain xrays: modic changes, high intensity zones in the annulus, loss of disc height, decreased hydration of the disc Has documented annular pathology Has singlelevel symptomatic degenerative involvement from L4S1 requiring surgical treatment Has intact facet joints at the involved vertebral levels documented by CT and/or MRI Has preop Oswestry score≥30 Has preop back pain score ≥20 Age 18 to 70 yrs who are skeletally, mature, inclusive Has not responded to nonoperative treatment for 6 mos If childbearing potential, patient is nonpregnant, nonnursing, and agrees not to become pregnant for 1 yr after surgery Is willing and able to comply with the study plan and sign the Patient Informed Consent Form Has primary diagnosis of a spinal disorder other than DDD at involved level Had previous posterior lumbar spinal fusion surgical procedure at involved level Had prior posterior lumbar surgery resulting in significant muscle/ligament morbidity, not including facet saving techniques Had previous anterior lumbar spinal surgery at involved level Requires spinal fusion and/or arthroplasty at more than 1 lumbar level Has severe pathology of facet joints of involved vertebral bodies Has any posterior element insufficiency Has spondylolisthesis Has spinal canal stenosis Has rotatory scoliosis at involved level Level treated has fractures secondary to trauma Has any of the following that may be associated with a diagnosis of osteoporosis (if Yes, a DEXA Scan is required): Postmenopausal NonBlack female over 60 yrs of age and weighs less than 140 pounds; Postmenopausal female that has sustained a nontraumatic hip, spine or wrist fracture; Male over the age of 60 that has sustained a nontraumatic hip or spine fracture. If level of BMD is 3.5 or lower or 2.5 or lower with vertebral crush fracture, the patient is excluded Has fever (temp &gt; 101°F oral) at time of surgery Has a condition that requires postop medications that interfere with fusion, such as steroids or prolonged use of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs, excluding routine perioperative, nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs. Does not include low dose aspirin for prophylactic anticoagulation Has overt or active bacterial infection, either local or systemic and/or potential for bacteremia Has presence or prior history of malignancy (except for basal cell carcinoma of skin) Has documented metal allergy, titanium alloy intolerance or cobaltchromemolybdenum alloy Is mentally incompetent. If questionable, obtain psych consult Has a Waddell Signs of Inorganic Behavior score of 3 or greater Has chronic or acute renal and/or hepatic failure or prior history of renal and/or hepatic parenchymal disease Is prisoner Is pregnant Is an alcohol and/or drug abuser as defined by currently undergoing treatment for alcohol and/or drug abuse Has received drugs that may interfere with bone metabolism within 2 weeks prior to the surgery date, excluding routine perioperative, nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs Has history of autoimmune disease Has history of exposure to injectable collagen implants Has history of hypersensitivity to protein pharmaceuticals (monoclonal antibodies or gamma globulins) or collagen Has received treatment with an investigational therapy within 30 days prior to implantation surgery or treatment is planned during 24 months following the implantation surgery Has received any previous exposure to any/all BMP's of either human or animal extraction Has history of allergy to bovine products or a history of anaphylaxis Has history of any endocrine or metabolic disorder known to affect osteogenesis Has any disease that would preclude accurate clinical evaluation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lumbar degenerative disc disease at one level from L4-S1</keyword>
</DOC>