<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01326845</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of the study is to evaluate and compare the frequency and severity of GI adverse events in different dose administration regimens. The patient population consists of low or intermediate (int-1) risk myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS) patients with transfusional iron overload. The study patients are randomized to either a morning dose of 20 mg/kg/day deferasirox or an evening dose of the same. Patients are then followed up for 6 months for any GI events and are assessed using patient reported outcomes tools e.g. a patient diary.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Myelodysplastic Syndrome (MDS) Gastrointestinal (GI) Tolerability Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron Overload</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deferasirox</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent prior to any screening procedures Male or female patients ≥ 18 years of age Patient must weigh between 45135 kg Patients with low or intermediate (int1) risk MDS, as determined by IPSS score or RA, RARS by WHO criteria. IPSS must be confirmed by a bone marrow examination within 6 months prior to study entry and must be hematologically stable Deferasirox naïve: Sexually active premenopausal female patients must use doublebarrier contraception, oral contraceptive plus barrier contraceptive, or must have undergone clinically documented total hysterectomy and/or oophorectomy, tubal ligation History or current GI disease Systemic diseases which could prevent study treatments Left ventricular ejection fraction&lt; 50 % by echo cardiography Serum creatinine &gt; 1.2 x ULN at screening Platelet counts &lt; 25x 109/L except in cases where guidance is already given in the local deferasirox label AST or ALT &gt; 2.5 xULN at screening Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gastrointestinal adverse events,</keyword>
	<keyword>myelodysplastic syndrome,</keyword>
	<keyword>transfusional iron overload diarrhea,</keyword>
	<keyword>constipation abdominal pain,</keyword>
	<keyword>vomiting</keyword>
</DOC>