<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01326559</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study Objective: Primary 1. To evaluate the complete response (CR) rate with induction chemotherapy using Docetaxel, Cisplatin and Fluorouracil(TPF) followed by Docetaxel plus Cetuximab (TC) in concurrence with intensity-modulated radiotherapy (IMRT). Secondary 1. To determine the overall response rate. 2. To determine the locoregional and distant control rate 3. To determine the progression-free survival (PFS) 4. To determine the overall survival (OS) 5. To determine the safety of the induction chemotherapy and concurrent chemoradiation plus Cetuximab.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate Induction Chemotherapy Using Docetaxel, Cisplatin and Fluorouracil in Concurrence With Intensity-modulated Radiotherapy for Local Recurrent Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma (NPC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nasopharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Recurrent T3N0N1M0 NPC (by AJCC/UICC 6th edition) and at least 1 year from the end of last primary course of radiotherapy Age &gt; 18 to &lt; 70 years Performance status: &lt; 1 by ECOG System (Appendix I) Adequate bone marrow &amp; renal function Patients having Bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x ULN, ASAT &amp; ALST=&lt; 1.5 x ULN, Serum creatinine=&lt; 1.25 x ULN and / or Creatinine clearance &gt;= 60ml/min Patients having WBC &gt;= 3x10e9/L, Neutrophils 1.8x10e9/L, Platelets &gt;= 100 x10e9/L,Hemoglobin &gt;=10g/dL Signed written informed consent Patients must have at least one measurable lesion Use of investigational agent within the past 28 days Pretreatment with an antiEGFR drug Severe cardiac disease such as heart failure, coronary artery disease or myocardial infarction within the last 12 months History of severe pulmonary diseases Active infection or other systemic disease under poor control Uncontrolled chronic neuropathy Know grade 3 or 4 allergic reaction to any of the components of the treatment Estimated life expectancy is less than 3 months Pregnancy or breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>induction chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>docetaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>cisplatin</keyword>
	<keyword>fluorouracil</keyword>
	<keyword>cetuximab</keyword>
	<keyword>intensity-modulated radiotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>