<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="137374">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01312844</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2009P002288</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01312844</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of the Use of IV Scopolamine to Augment the Efficacy of Electroconvulsive Therapy (ECT)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pilot Study of the Use of IV Scopolamine to Augment the Efficacy of Electroconvulsive Therapy (ECT)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary purpose of this study is to assess the ability of scopolamine to improve the
      antidepressant effects of ECT and to determine whether scopolamine will shorten the time to
      response and remission for patients receiving ECT.

      The hypothesis are:

        1. Patients receiving ECT plus scopolamine will have greater improvement in depression
           symptoms than those receiving ECT plus placebo.

        2. Patients receiving scopolamine in addition to ECT will require fewer ECT treatments to
           obtain response/remission compared to the group receiving ECT plus placebo.

        3. Time to response and to remission in the scopolamine group will be significantly
           shorter compared to ECT alone.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) is a highly effective treatment for severe major depression.
      It has been estimated that approximately 10 percent of all patients admitted to the hospital
      for treatment of major depressive disorder receive ECT.

      However, not all patients who receive ECT respond, and of those who do, not all achieve
      remission. Furthermore, while there is a wide range in the number of ECT treatments done
      among all people with depression, the average is approximately eight treatments. Because
      treatments are usually done three times per week (Monday, Wednesday, and Friday), the
      minimal length of stay for the average person receiving inpatient ECT is typically greater
      than two weeks.

      Finally, ECT is not without risk, and every round of ECT incurs additional risk of not just
      the treatment itself, but also the risks of general anesthesia. Thus, although ECT is a
      robust mode of treatment for Major Depressive Disorder (MDD), there remains a need for
      improved treatment efficacy and speed of onset. Improving the efficacy of ECT would not only
      benefit individuals with MDD, but also have far-reaching effects for the health care system
      as it could impact the cost and resources utilized.

      Ideally, an agent could be added to augment the effect of ECT, both in terms of efficacy as
      well as speed of onset. In 2006, Furrey et al, reported the rapid antidepressant effect of
      the antimuscarinic drug, scopolamine, delivered parenterally. Significant antidepressant
      effect was found after the first scopolamine administration. The improvement was reported
      immediately following the first IV administration, increased across all treatments, and was
      sustained into the placebo crossover period.

      Scopolamine is an anticholinergic muscarinic agent, with activity in the CNS and pilot data
      to suggest a significant impact on rapidly improving depressive symptoms in patient with
      MDD, when administered IV. Thus, it serves as a reasonable choice to augment the effects of
      ECT in the treatment of patients with MDD.

      Primary Aim 1) Assess the ability of scopolamine to augment the antidepressant effects of
      ECT.

      Hypothesis 1a: Patients receiving ECT plus scopolamine will have significantly greater mean
      improvement on total HAM-D score between baseline and endpoint than those receiving ECT plus
      placebo.

      Hypothesis 1b: Patients receiving scopolamine in addition to ECT will require fewer mean ECT
      treatments to obtain response/remission compared to the group receiving ECT plus placebo.

      Primary Aim 2) Evaluate the hypothesis that scopolamine will shorten the time to response
      and remission for patients receiving ECT.

      Hypothesis 2: Time to response and to remission in the Scopolamine group will be
      significantly shorter compared to ECT alone.

      Secondary Aim: Provide evidence for the tolerability of intravenous scopolamine administered
      during ECT.

      Hypothesis 3a: There will be no between group difference (between ECT plus scopolamine vs
      ECT plus placebo) in mean number of ECT sessions withheld due to cognitive impairment (as
      determined by attending psychiatrist).

      Hypothesis 3b: There will be no between group differences (between ECT plus scopolamine vs
      ECT plus placebo) with regards to the mean number of moderate to severe side effects.

      Hypothesis 3c: There will be no significant difference between the scopolamine plus ECT
      group and the placebo plus ECT group on mean levels of physiological measures of ECT
      including: heart rate, blood pressure, seizure length, duration of muscle paralysis,
      duration of asystole, and energy need to induce seizure.

      Exploratory Analyses: we will assess whether the scopolamine plus ECT group will have a
      shorter average length of stay on the inpatient psychiatric unit compared to those receiving
      ECT plus placebo.

      We will also assess whether the scopolamine plus ECT group will have significant differences
      in the cognitive measures at endpoint compared to those receiving ECT plus placebo.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>April 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ham D 17 scores</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of ECT treatment (on average, 2 weeks)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to response/remission</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of ECT treatment (usually 2 weeks)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of ECT treatments to response/remission</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of ECT treatment (usually 2 weeks)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">16</enrollment>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Scopolamine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receiving IV scopolamine at ECT treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receiving IV placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Scopolamine</intervention_name>
    <description>Those receiving active drug will receive scopolamine 4mcg/kg IV with each treatment, until completion of ECT</description>
    <arm_group_label>Scopolamine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Males and females between the ages of 18-50 (inclusive)

          -  DSM-IV diagnosis of Major Depressive Disorder (MDD), without psychotic features, and
             a HAM-D-17 score of 18 or higher

          -  Female subjects must be postmenopausal, surgically sterile, or, if of child-bearing
             age, using double-barrier contraceptive method or prescription oral contraceptives
             (e.g. estrogen-progestin combinations), contraceptive implants (e.g. NorplantTM,
             DepoProveraTM, or transdermally delivered contraceptives (Ortho EvraTM) before entry
             and throughout the study; and have a negative urine b-HCG pregnancy test at
             screening.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Substance use disorder active use within the last 6 months (per assessment using
             SCID)

          2. Organic mental disorders

          3. Seizure disorders

          4. Unstable physical disorder or physical disorder judged to significantly affect the
             central nervous system function

          5. Heart block

          6. Pre-existing sick-sinus

          7. Chronic treatment with beta blockers

          8. Any cardiac arrhythmia

          9. Hypotension

         10. Coronary artery disease

         11. Liver and renal function impairment

         12. Urge incontinence or prostatic hypertrophy

         13. Colitis

         14. Crohn's disease

         15. GI motility disorders

         16. Asthma

         17. COPD

         18. Treatment with anti-cholinergic and cholinomimetic medications

         19. Contraindications to scopolamine including hypersensitivity to scopolamine, other
             belladonna alkaloids, and/or any component of the formulation

         20. Wide and narrow angle glaucoma

         21. Acute hemorrhage

         22. Paralytic ileus

         23. Myasthenia gravis

         24. Patients on belladonna, belladonna alkaloids, cisapride, or potassium chloride
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>John D Matthews, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David Abramson, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Maurizio Fava, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02144</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>John Matthews, M.D.</last_name>
      <email>jmatthews@partners.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>July 24, 2014</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 4, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>John D. Matthews</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator, Assistant Professor of Psychiatry, Harvard Medical School</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Scopolamine Hydrobromide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Butylscopolammonium Bromide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
