<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02646579</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if dry needling both low back and extremity areas is more effective for reducing pain and improving strength, balance and functional performance among patients with chronic musculoskeletal conditions compared to dry needling of extremity areas only.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Dry Needling Using Spinal and Peripheral Sites Versus Peripheral Sites Only</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will determine if spinal and peripheral dry needling sites results in decreased pain, increased muscle strength, increased proprioception and increased functional performance among individuals with chronic musculoskeletal conditions of the lower extremities, such as plantar fasciitis, Achilles tendinopathy, and patellofemoral pain syndrome. Specific aims are to determine if individuals with chronic musculoskeletal conditions of the lower extremities receiving dry needling to both spinal and peripheral sites exhibit differences in pain, muscle strength, proprioception, and unilateral hop test scores compared to individuals with chronic musculoskeletal conditions of the lower extremities receiving dry needling to peripheral sites only.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fasciitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Patellofemoral Pain Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fasciitis, Plantar</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tendinopathy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Unilateral chronic lower extremity musculoskeletal condition Ability to perform a unilateral onequarter squat on involved side without pain Asymptomatic during walking History of systemic neurological or arthritic condition History of bony or peripheral nerve trauma or surgery lower extremities No contraindications to dry needling Not currently receiving treatment for the chronic lower extremity musculoskeletal condition</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Orthopedics</keyword>
</DOC>