<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01801527</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: Cancer is increasingly viewed as a chronic disease and therefore there is a growing need for long-term treatments. Breast cancer survivors suffer physical impairment after oncology treatment. This impairment reduces quality of life (QoL) and increases the prevalence of conditions associated to unhealthy life-style. Objective: The overall objective of e-Cuidate telerehabilitation will be to evaluate short and long-term effects telehealth program. Methods: Seventy-two breast cancer survivors (age range: 18-65 years) will be recruited through oncology and breast units at the Virgen de las Nieves Hospital and San Cecilio Hospital and associations of breast cancer patients in Granada. Patients will be randomized to receive the online rehabilitation group (n=36) or usual care (control) group (n=36). Telerehabilitation group will receive an eight-week online intervention and control group receive recommendations about usual care. Discussion: The investigators study attempts to increase the level of fitness and reduce musculoskeletal disorders in breast cancer patients through a strategy for care based on telerehabilitation to promote therapeutic exercise.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Telehealth System to Improve Quality of Life in Breast Cancer Survivors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of stage I, II, or IIIA breast cancer Medical clearance of participation Without chronic disease or orthopaedic that would interfere with ability to participate in a physical activity program Access to Internet Basic ability to use the computer or living with a relative who has this ability Completion of adjuvant therapy except for hormone therapy No history of cancer recurrence Have interest in improving lifestyle: fitness/stress level Have signed informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Telehealth</keyword>
	<keyword>Fatigue</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
	<keyword>Telerehabilitation</keyword>
</DOC>