<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01801124</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Phase 4 study evaluating the effectiveness of EXPAREL when infiltrated into the the Transversus Abdominis Plane (TAP).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>EXPAREL Infiltrated Into the TAP for Postoperative Analgesia in Unilateral Abdominal Hernia Repair</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, open-label, non-randomized study evaluating the effectiveness of abdominal analgesia when using 266 mg EXPAREL to infiltrate into the TAP unilaterally.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hernia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hernia, Abdominal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and females, aged 1875 years inclusive, and ASA physical status 13. Undergoing open repair of a unilateral abdominal hernia below the level of the umbilicus. Abdominal incision length of 312 cm. Subjects must be physically and mentally able to participate in the study and complete all study assessments. Subjects must be able to give fully informed consent to participate in this study after demonstrating a good understanding of the risks and benefits of the proposed components of the TAP infiltration. History of hypersensitivity or idiosyncratic reactions to amidetype local anesthetics Any subject whose anatomy, or surgical procedure, in the opinion of the Investigator, might preclude the potential successful performance of a TAP infiltration. Any subject who in the opinion of the Investigator, might be harmed or be a poor candidate for participation in the study. Any subject, who in the opinion of the Investigator, is on chronic pain medicine. Any female subject who is currently pregnant. Subjects who have received any investigational drug within 30 days prior to study drug administration, or planned administration of another investigational product or procedure during their participation in this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>analgesia</keyword>
	<keyword>hernia repair</keyword>
</DOC>