<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01801631</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: In type 2 diabetes mellitus patients, an acute coronary event (ACE) may result in a decreased quality of life and increased distress. According to the American Diabetes Association, transition from the acute care setting is a high-risk time for all patients, but tailored support specific to diabetes is scarce in that period. The investigators developed an intervention by a diabetes nurse to help diabetic patients reduce distress after their first ACE. The intervention is based on Bandura's Social Cognitive Theory, Leventhal's Common Sense Model, and on results of focus groups which were conducted to define the needs and wishes of type 2 diabetes patients and their partners regarding professional support after an ACE. The aim of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of the intervention to reduce distress. The hypothesis is that patients who receive the intervention will have less diabetes related distress compared to the control group. Methods/Design: Randomized controlled trial. Patients will be recruited directly after discharge from hospital. A diabetes nurse will visit the patients in the intervention group (n = 100) within three weeks after discharge from hospital, two weeks later and two months later. The control group (n = 100) will receive a telephone consultation. The primary outcome is diabetes related distress, measured with the Problem Areas in Diabetes questionnaire (PAID). Secondary outcomes are quality of life, anxiety, depression, HbA1c, blood pressure and lipids. Mediating variables are self-management, self-efficacy and illness representations. Variables will be measured with questionnaires directly after discharge from hospital and five months later. Biomedical variables will be obtained from the records from the primary care physician and the hospital. Differences between groups in change over time will be analyzed according to the intention-to-treat principle. Discussion: Type 2 diabetes patients who experience a first ACE need tailored support after discharge from the hospital. This trial will provide evidence of the effectiveness of a supportive intervention to reduce distress in these patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tailored Support for Type 2 Diabetes Patients With an Acute Coronary Event After Discharge From Hospital</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>See citation design paper</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>History of type 2 diabetes (&gt;1 year) Discharged from the hospital after a first acute coronary event defined as a Myocardial Infarction (MI), Coronary Artery Bypass Graft (CABG) procedure or Percutaneous Transluminal Coronary Angioplasty (PTCA) Sufficient knowledge of the Dutch language A serious illness or condition which will prevent full participation Not able to fill in questionnaires</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 2 diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute Coronary Event (ACE)</keyword>
	<keyword>Distress</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary care</keyword>
	<keyword>Illness representations</keyword>
</DOC>