<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01801202</DOC>
	<brief_summary>- The study will re-confirm that the LightSheer Duet HS 805 nm handpiece is safe for removal of unwanted hair, and will result in hair removal and permanent hair count reduction. - Twenty (20)subjects, Fitzpatrick Skin Type I-IV will be included in a single site. - Each subject will receive five treatments at four to six week intervals and return for follow-up visits at three and six months after the last treatment for evaluation of the treated areas.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Evaluation of LightSheer Duet 805nm HS Handpiece</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>1. Able to read, understand and provide written Informed Consent; 2. Healthy adult, male or female, 18 years of age or older with skin type IIV; 3. Having a suitable treatment area for hair removal; 4. Able and willing to comply with the treatment/followup schedule and requirements; 5. Women of childbearing potential (women who have not had a hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy or are not postmenopausal) are required to be using a reliable method of birth control at least three months prior to enrollment and throughout the course of the study. 1. Pregnant, expectation of pregnancy, postpartum or nursing (&lt;6 months); 2. Hormonal disorders that may affect hair growth; 3. Immunosuppressive diseases, including AIDS and HIV infection, or use of immunosuppressive medications; 4. Livedo reticularis; 5. Uncontrolled systemic diseases such as diabetes; 6. Active infections in the treated area; 7. Dysplastic nevi; 8. Significant concurrent skin conditions or any inflammatory skin conditions; 9. Active cold sores, open lacerations or abrasions; 10. Chronic or cutaneous viral, fungal, or bacterial diseases; 11. Current cancer; 12. History of skin cancer or precancerous lesions at the treatment areas; 13. Use of Accutane™ (Isotretinoin) within the past six month; 14. Keloid formation in the treatment area; 15. Tattoos in the treatment area; 16. Bleeding coagulopathies or use of anticoagulants; 17. Autoimmune disorders; 18. Erythema ab igne, when identified treatments should be discontinued; 19. Photosensitivity disorder that can be exacerbated by laser or intense light; 20. Herpes simplex in the treatment area; 21. Use of medications, herbal supplements, perfumes or cosmetics that may affect sensitivity to light; 22. Poor wound healing; 23. Sunburns; 24. Unable or unlikely to refrain from artificial tanning, including the use of tanning booths, prior (at least a week) and during the course of the evaluation; 25. Prior skin treatment with laser or other devices on the same treated areas within the last six months prior to study enrollment or during the course of the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>