<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03039439</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a pilot biomarker study designed to compare frequencies of mutations between groups of malignant, benign and normal tissue or blood of patients with parathyroid disease and identify the potential genes showing molecular aberrations as other types of cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Molecular and IHC Profiling of PTH Tumors to Evaluate Targeted Agents</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is dual-fold: 1. To determine the differences in clinical behavior and immunohistochemical (IHC) biomarkers between parathyroid carcinoma (PC), atypical neoplasm (AN) and parathyroid adenoma (PA). This will allow to use these markers as a diagnostic and screening tool when evaluating parathyroid tumors. 2. To determine which potential genes can be used in patients with parathyroid tumors for diagnostic purposes. Genomic analysis of tumor samples will be performed to identify molecular aberrations for which novel targeted therapies have been recently developed.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. The patient cohort for this study consists of all patients within the prospectively maintained parathyroid database within the Department of Surgical Oncology at the University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center (MDACC) or from collaborating sites, with tissue or blood available from 19682015, previously consented for the use of the tissue for research purposes (via Protocols LAB 080034, PA110695 and LAB030320 or the appropriate external mechanism for collaborating sites). 2. All patients with a known diagnoses of PHPT operated/treated in the Department of Surgical Oncology of MDACC or at a collaborating site. Patients that have provided consent for the use of the tissue or blood for research purposes will then be considered for our study (via Protocol LAB030320 and LAB 080034 or the appropriate external mechanism for collaborating sites). 3. All consented patients with known diagnoses of PHPT with a histopathological diagnosis of: parathyroid carcinoma, atypical parathyroid neoplasm or parathyroid adenoma. There will be no restrictions on age, gender, or ethnicity 4. Selected patients obtained through outside collaboration who meet the selection criteria for tissue availability and diagnostic suitability for inclusion in the study (See Criteria 3 for diagnostic criteria). 1. Patients without tissue available for analysis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Immunohistochemical profiling of tumors</keyword>
	<keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
</DOC>