<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03039400</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Physical activity is a crucial component to wellness and is associated with multiple health benefits. Persons with MS may find it challenging to participate in regular physical activity or exercise, which is activity done to improve health and/or fitness. This research will test an innovative web-based intervention to help persons with moderate-to-severe disability manage their condition through a maintenance exercise program with specialized physiotherapist guidance and support. The researchers will examine adherence to the web-based physiotherapy program compared to standard physiotherapy care. Forty-five people with MS will be randomly assigned to the web group or standard care group at a rate of 2:1. Participants in the web group will receive supported and individualized web-based physiotherapy. Participants in the standard care group will receive a written exercise program. Regular participation (adherence) in the exercise programs will be evaluated in both groups over six months. The research will also examine participant satisfaction with the programs, safety, MS symptoms, and physical function. A web-based approach may be widely accessible to persons with MS in their own homes and could support long-term participation in physical activity important to wellness.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physiotherapist-guided Home Exercise in Moderate to Severe MS</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>diagnosed with MS moderate to severe disability (PDDS 27) able to access the internet in your current living environment already doing structured exercise more than once per week residing &gt;300km from Saskatoon (unless able to travel to Saskatoon for the appointments) unable to understand the intent and process of this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>