<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02371031</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a pilot study designed to evaluate the potential of using FDOPA-PET/MRI for improving surgical planning and providing non-invasive prognostic information in patients with gliomas that have substantial non-enhancing regions. The results will be used to develop larger adequately powered studies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>FDOPA-PET/MRI for the Pre-operative Evaluation of Gliomas</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dihydroxyphenylalanine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Known or suspected diagnosis of intracranial glioma with substantial nonenhancing regions as assessed by contrast enhanced MRI. For the purposes of this study, gliomas with substantial nonenhancing regions are defined as having contrastenhancing volumes of less than 50% of the total estimated tumor volume. Gliomas that do not have any contrastenhancing regions are eligible for this study. Standard of care surgical resection and/or stereotactic biopsy of the brain tumor planned within 2 weeks of the FDOPAPET/MRI study. At least 18 years of age. Measurable disease on MRI defined as tumor measuring at least 1 cm in two perpendicular dimensions. Karnofsky performance of &gt; 50 corresponding to ECOG categories 0, 1, or 2. Patients who are unable to walk because of paralysis, but who are up in a wheelchair, will be considered ambulatory for the purpose of assessing the performance score. Creatinine clearance or radioisotope glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &gt; 30 mL/min/1.73 m^2 Patient or legally authorized representative must be able to understand and willing to sign a written informed consent document. Patients undergoing PET/MRI: contraindication to gadolinium contrast enhanced brain MRI (i.e., allergy to gadolinium contrast, MRIincompatible implantable devices, GFR &lt; 30 mL/min/1.73, and severe claustrophobia). At the discretion of the responsible physician, FDOPAPET/CT may be performed if PET/MRI is contraindicated or unavailable. If FDOPAPET/CT is performed, the patient must have undergone a contrastenhanced MRI for fusion with FDOPAPET no more than 4 weeks before the FDOPAPET/CT. Prior chemotherapy or radiation therapy for the brain tumor. Prior biopsy or surgical resection of the glioma without additional therapy is not an exclusion criterion. Pregnant and/or breastfeeding. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative urine or serum pregnancy test no more than 3 days prior to FDOPA injection.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>