<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02371941</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of oral cromolyn sodium when made into a viscous preparation for the treatment of eosinophilic esophagitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Oral Cromolyn Sodium for the Treatment of Eosinophilic Esophagitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Eosinophilic esophagitis is an antigen-mediated allergic disease of the esophagus characterized by symptoms of gastrointestinal complaints and eosinophilic inflammation limited to the esophagus. Currently, first line therapeutic recommendations include swallowed, topical steroids or dietary therapy. While both work for the majority of patients, they both have limitations. The investigators are examining the use of oral cromolyn sodium as a treatment for this condition. This medication is a non-steroid that is already approved for other conditions. When taken orally, it is essentially not absorbed systemically, so side effects are minimal. There is only 1 brief, retrospective report of its use in this condition suggesting it does not work. However, from studying swallowed, topical steroids, it may require formulating the medication into a viscous preparation for it to work.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Esophagitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eosinophilic Esophagitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cromolyn Sodium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of eosinophilic esophagitis Concomitant treatment with swallowed corticosteroids. Any prior use of swallowed corticosteroids will require a 4 week washout period. Pregnancy (all females of child bearing potential will have urine pregnancy test done at baseline). Evidence of pathologic eosinophilia in other locations in the GI tract. Participation in another research protocol Reduced Renal or Hepatic Function (all subjects will have a baseline creatinine and liver function panel drawn)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>