<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01372007</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Total mesorectal excision (TME) is a precise dissection of the rectum and all para-rectal lymph nodes within the mesorectal envelope. It is becoming universally recognized and accepted as the standard technique for surgical excision of rectum carcinomas. TME results in lowest rates of local recurrence, especially when combined with pre-operative chemo-radiotherapy. Especially after pre-operative chemo-radiotherapy, the post-operative drainage may be important. The quick decrease of this drainage will enable the early mobilisation of the patient and may shorten the time of hospitalization. If this decrease in fluid production can be achieved, it will have a positive effect on the Quality of Life of the patient and will ensure health economic savings by reduction of hospitalization time and resources. Somatostatin analogues have shown to be able to decrease the secretion of numerous types of bodily fluids. The aim of this study is to investigate if lanreotide Autogel 120mg is capable to reduce the fluid discharge in patients that underwent a TME for rectumcarcinoma. Lanreotide Autogel 120mg compared to placebo, administered post-surgery on the fluid discharge in the drain of the patient that underwent a total mesorectum excision (TME) for rectal carcinoma. Patient planned to have a TME will be asked to participate in the study. When they have provided written informed consent, they will be randomized 1:1 to receive either placebo or lanreotide autogel 120mg. Drain fluid will be checked for hematocrit daily post-surgery. Once hematocrit levels of the drain fluid are &lt;10%, study medication or placebo will be administered. After administration the volume of the drain fluid will be measured every 12 hours for at least 5 days. A sample of the drain fluid will be collected every 24 hours for at least 5 days and frozen at -70°C for total protein content, sodium and chloride analysis afterwards. If the patient has a hematocrit &gt;10% in his drain fluid for a period of 5 days, this patient can not be randomized.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Influence of Somatuline Autogel 120mg on Post-operative Drainage After Total Mesorectum Excision for Rectumcarcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lanreotide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiopeptin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>male and female patients 1875 years written informed consent to participate the study scheduled to have a total mesorectal excision (TME) for rectumcarcinoma patients with a known intolerance for somatostatin analogues, lanreotide or any of it's excipients patients younger than 18 years patients unable to provide written informed consent patients who received somatostatin or any of it's analogues the last 30 days before the start of the study Pregnant and breastfeeding women Women not using contraception</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Rectal carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>