<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01870297</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this study is to assess the safety and tolerability of LY3025876 given alone (Part A) and in combination with liraglutide (Part B) in participants with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of LY3025876 in Participants With Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will also evaluate how much of the study drug enters the blood stream and how long it takes for the body to remove the study drug. Information about any side effects that may occur will also be collected. Participants will continue their usual diet and exercise program and may remain on their physician-prescribed dose of metformin. Each part of the study is expected to last 10 to 12 weeks on average, not including screening. Participants may only enroll in one part.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) as determined by the investigator, controlled with diet or exercise alone or on a stable dose of metformin for at least 30 days Have a body mass index (BMI) greater than or equal to 23 and less than or equal to 45 kilograms per square meter (kg/m^2) at screening Have a supine blood pressure reading at screening of between 90160 millimeter of mercury (mmHg) (systolic) and 4095 mmHg (diastolic) Women not of childbearing potential due to surgical sterilization (hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy or tubal ligation) or menopause Have taken LY3025876 or investigational drugs like it (for example, other fibroblast growth factor21 [FGF21]related drugs) or have known allergies to these drugs History or presence of bone disease (including osteoporosis or unhealed fractures) Current active treatment of periodontal disease Have had a significant change in weight, defined as a gain or loss of at least 4 kilogram (kg) (9 pounds) in the last 3 months Have had greater than 1 episode of severe hypoglycemia within 6 months of screening that required the assistance of another person to actively administer carbohydrate, glucagon, or other resuscitative actions or had a seizure or coma Have known allergies or a history of intolerance to liraglutide, glucagonlike peptide 1 (GLP1) analogues, or other related compounds Have a history of acute or chronic pancreatitis Have a personal or family history of medullary thyroid carcinoma or have multiple endocrine neoplasia syndrome type 2</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>