<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02719379</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Advisory Committee for Immunization Practices (ACIP) from the Centers for Disease Control (CDC) recommends that children (6-18 years) and adults (≥19 years old) with chronic lung condition such as asthma or cigarette smoking be vaccinated with Pneumococcal vaccine (PPSV23). The purpose of this study is to increase awareness of vaccination to late adolescents with asthma and smokers (social aspect of study), and to recommend vaccination (which is the clinical aspect). Individuals who agree to receiving vaccine will be enrolled in research to determine whether late adolescents with and without asthma (smokers) have distinctive pneumococcal vaccine response patterns and whether such patterns are associated with subsequent variance in asthma outcomes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immune Response to Pneumococcal Polysaccharide Vaccine (23-valent) Predicts Asthma Status and Outcomes in Late Adolescents With Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heptavalent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Reside in Olmsted County, Minnesota (defined by Olmsted County address in medical record within one year prior to last followup date as of data abstraction) Receive medical care from Mayo Clinic clinical practice Signed research authorization for using medical record for research Diagnosis of an immunodeficiency (primary and secondary) Previous or current diagnosis of a Rheumatological disorders (Rheumatoid arthritis, Lupus, Sjögren, and vasculitis), cancer (chronic lymphocytic leukemia, nonHodgkin lymphoma, and Bcell malignancy), diabetes, active infection (pneumonia, otitis media, HIV, and EBV), other chronic diseases (multiple sclerosis, etc), renal disease such nephritic syndrome, and protein losing enteropathy Current or previous use (within the last 6 months) of systemic corticosteroids, and other immunosuppressive agents (cyclosporin, methotrexate, and mycophenolic acid) Vaccination of PPSV23 (receiving childhood pneumococcal vaccination during infancy is eligible for this study) Pregnancy Enrollment will be delayed 2 weeks for those subjects that can be included but have upper respiratory infection or viral illness to allow for natural resolution.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>20 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>