<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01066429</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Poor prognosis dufuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL) represents 50% of all DLBCL with overall cure rates ranging from 50-60% with modern dose-dense immunochemotherapy regimens such as R-CHOP14. Using an alternative strategy, as infusional and dose-adjusted R-EPOCH, the investigators have shown an 83% of complete responses (CR), with an estimated 5-year overall survival (OS) rate of 75% (García-Suárez et al. British Journal of Haematology 2007, 136:276). Despite this improvement in outcome, the search for new treatment strategies should continue. Therefore, compared with prior R-EPOCH the investigators decided to investigate whether the introduction of dexamethasone (40 mg IV on days 1-5) in place of prednisone (based upon data which demonstrated that the former was associated with enhanced Central Nervious System penetration) and the reduction of treatment intervals from 3 to 2 weeks would be feasible and might improve the outcome in this group of patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>DA-EDOCH14-R in Poor-prognosis Diffuse Large B-cell Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Medication, Dose and Method for Administration: - Rituximab: 375 mg/m2, endovenous, according to the protocol of the service, day 1 (except in the first cycle, in which it will be on day 5). - Etoposide: 50 mg/m2/day, in continuous 24-hour infusion, days 1 to 4. - Adriamycin: 10 mg/m2/day, in continuous 24-hour infusion of, days 1 to 4. - Vincristine: 0.4 mg/m2/day, in continuous 24-hour infusion, days 1 to 4 - Dexamethasone: 40 mg, endovenous, days 1 to 5. Followed by prednisone 30 mg (day +6), 20 mg (day +7), and 10 mg (day +8). - Cyclophosphamide: 750 mg/m2, endovenous, in 30 minutes, day 5, after ending the continuous infusion of adriamycin, etoposide and vincristine. - MESNA (If the dose of Cyclophosphamide is &gt; 1 g/m2</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signing the Informed Consent. Histology: diffuse large Bcell lymphoma de novo (primary mediastinal Bcell lymphomas will be included provided that they have a mass greater than 7 cm in larger diameter) and follicular NHL grade 3b. aaIPI: 23. Age: Between 18 and 70 years. General Condition (ECOG/WHO): Proper organic function, defined by: FEVI ≥ 40%, serum creatinine &lt; 150 µmol/L, serum bilirubin &lt; 30 µmol/L, control of other medical conditions such as: infection, leukocytes ≥ 3.5 x 109/l and platelets ≥ 100 x 109/l (except if they are caused by lymphomatous infiltration of bone marrow or of the spleen). HIVpositive. Pregnancy or breastfeeding. Serious disease compromising the performance of the therapeutic regimen. Recent history of another malignant disease (except skin cancer different from melanoma or carcinoma insitu of the cervix), prior radiotherapy or chemotherapy, history of indolent lymphoma. CNS infiltration at diagnosis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>poor-prognosis diffuse large B-cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>dose-adjusted</keyword>
	<keyword>R-EDOCH-14</keyword>
	<keyword>rituximab</keyword>
	<keyword>age-adjusted IPI</keyword>
	<keyword>toxicity</keyword>
</DOC>