<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00010335</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the safety and long term complications of total body irradiation in combination with cyclophosphamide, anti-thymocyte globulin, and autologous CD34-selected peripheral blood stem cell (PBSC) transplantation in children with refractory autoimmune disorders. II. Determine the efficacy of this treatment regimen in these patients. III. Determine the reconstitution of immunity after autologous CD34-selected PBSC transplantation in these patients. IV. Determine engraftment of autologous CD34-selected PBSC in these patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Study of Total Body Irradiation in Combination With Cyclophosphamide, Anti-thymocyte Globulin, and Autologous CD34-Selected Peripheral Blood Stem Cell Transplantation in Children With Refractory Autoimmune Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients receive filgrastim (G-CSF) subcutaneously daily until peripheral blood stem cell (PBSC) collection is completed. CD34+ cells are separated from the rest of the PBSCs. Patients undergo total body irradiation twice daily on days -5 and -4. Patients receive anti-thymocyte globulin IV on days -5, -3, -1, 1, 3, and 5 and cyclophosphamide IV on days -3 and -2. CD34-selected PBSCs are reinfused on day 0. Patients receive G-CSF IV daily beginning on day 0 and continuing until blood counts recover. Patients are followed annually for 5 years and then every 5 years thereafter.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autoimmune Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Scleroderma, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Scleroderma, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatomyositis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antilymphocyte Serum</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Diagnosis of 1 of the following based on American College of Rheumatology (ACR) Criteria: Severe juvenile rheumatoid arthritis (systemic onset or polyarticular course) Juvenile systemic lupus erythematosus Systemic sclerosis Dermatomyositis Refractory to standard or aggressive therapy OR unacceptable toxicity from standard therapy Reasonable expectation of possible improvement as evidenced by a good potential for rehabilitation therapy and adequate social factors No serious CNS damage that would preclude significant functional recovery Prior/Concurrent Therapy Chemotherapy: At least 4 weeks since prior methotrexate or cyclophosphamide Endocrine therapy: At least 4 weeks since prior intraarterial steroids Juvenile rheumatoid arthritis patients should continue steroids without taper throughout mobilization and harvest of stem cells If receiving corticosteroids, must be continued without taper Other: At least 4 weeks since prior antiinflammatory agents such as nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) or sulfasalazine At least 4 weeks since prior cyclosporine, tacrolimus, mycophenolate mofetil, azathioprine, penicillamine, or etanercept Patient Characteristics Life expectancy: At least 30 days Hematopoietic: Absolute neutrophil count at least 1,000/mm3 OR Platelet count at least 100,000/mm3 No bone marrow aspirate or biopsy consistent with production defect (depletion of neutrophil precursors or megakaryocytes) No myelodysplasia Hepatic: Bilirubin no greater than 2.5 mg/dL AST no greater than 300 U/L on two sequential tests No severe liver dysfunction within past month No active hepatitis A, B, or C Renal: No endstage glomerulonephritis or renal disease Creatinine clearance at least 40 mL/min Cardiovascular: No uncontrolled malignant arrhythmia No New York Heart Association class III or IV congestive heart failure Ejection fraction at least 50% Pulmonary: DLCO at least 45% (DLCO at least 70% for patients with pulmonary disease caused by documented processes other than primary autoimmune disorder, such as infectious pneumonia or aspiration pneumonia) No severe pulmonary hypertension (PAP greater than 50) without potential for significant improvement Other: No medical or psychosocial reasons that would make hematopoietic stem cell collection intolerable No increased anesthetic risks No fever higher than 39 degrees C No positive serology for toxoplasmosis No active life threatening infection not responsive to therapy No other disease or organ dysfunction that would limit survival No known hypersensitivity to murine or equine proteins No known primary immunodeficiency disease HIV negative</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>arthritis &amp; connective tissue diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>dermatomyositis</keyword>
	<keyword>immunologic disorders and infectious disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>juvenile rheumatoid arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
	<keyword>systemic lupus erythematosus</keyword>
	<keyword>systemic sclerosis</keyword>
</DOC>