<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00010413</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the response rate and 1-year event-free survival of patients with refractory pemphigus treated with high-dose cyclophosphamide.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II Study of High-Dose Cyclophosphamide in Patients With Refractory Pemphigus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: Patients receive cyclophosphamide IV on days 1-4 and filgrastim (G-CSF) beginning on day 10 and continuing until blood counts recover. Patients are followed monthly for 6 months, every 2 months for 6 months, every 4 months for a year, and then annually thereafter.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pemphigus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Definitive diagnosis of pemphigus, including all of the following: Typical clinical lesions Histologically proven by skin or mucous membrane biopsy Pemphigus IgG autoantibodies in skin or mucous membrane by direct immunofluorescence (IF) Circulating pemphigus IgG autoantibodies in serum by indirect IF Dependence on highdose corticosteroids Persistent disease activity despite treatment with mycophenolate mofetil or azathioprine, or inability to tolerate these drugs (for paraneoplastic pemphigus, persistent disease activity despite treatment with cyclosporine) Prior/Concurrent Therapy No concurrent cytotoxic therapy Patient Characteristics Performance status: Karnofsky 20100% Renal: Creatinine no greater than 2.5 mg/dL Cardiovascular: LVEF at least 40% Pulmonary: FVC, FEV1, or DLCO at least 50% predicted Other: Not pregnant Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 9 months after study Not preterminal or moribund</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>immunologic disorders and infectious disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>pemphigus</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
</DOC>