<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01817335</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot clinical trial studies psycho-educational program in increasing knowledge and satisfaction and decreasing distress in younger patients with cancer receiving treatment. Psycho-educational program may increase knowledge and satisfaction and decrease distress in younger patients with cancer receiving treatment</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Psycho-Educational Program in Increasing Knowledge and Satisfaction and Decreasing Distress in Younger Patients With Cancer Receiving Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Providing a psycho-educational group to young adults while examining the feasibility of such a group with patients on treatment. II. Examining effectiveness of the program through evaluating pre-post changes in participant distress, evaluating increases in participant' knowledge regarding disease issues and coping, and evaluating participant satisfaction. OUTLINE: Patients undergo psycho-educational program comprising medical/symptom management and communication with a medical team, coping skills, self image, and relationships and communication for 1.5 hours once weekly for 6 weeks. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 30 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Currently in active treatment (diagnosed and receiving treatment within 2 weeks of initial study enrollment; active treatment includes currently receiving any of the following: chemotherapy, radiation therapy, maintenance drugs, surgery, clinical trial enrollment, or current relapse/secondary malignancy) Inpatient or outpatient Cancer diagnosis Physician approval Informed consent Significant psychiatric or developmental issues, as determined by screening interview conducted by psychologist or clinical social worker Currently off treatment (longer than 2 weeks at the time of enrollment) In isolation or with isolation precautions NonEnglish speaking</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>