<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01817218</DOC>
	<brief_summary>INTRODUCTION: Vascular ulcers are an important pathology in the daily medical practice in all the assistance levels, and they have big repercussion referring to individual, social and labour levels, supposing a big consumption of human and material resources.The cure with autologous platelet rich plasma (autologous PRP) has demonstrated in different studies a decrease in the cicatrization time comparing to conventional methods in hospital levels, which becomes interesting contrasting its efficacy in primary care. AIM:Evaluate the practicability, security and potential of the autologous PRP in the treatment of vascular ulcers, comparing to the conventional treatment ( cure with humid environment), in primary care patients with chronic venous insufficiency in C-6 degree (CEAP classification). DESIGN:A pilot study will be executed, which will consist in a randomized clinical test, multicentred, in parallel groups and opened. 40 patients suffering of venous vascular ulcers will be studied, who will be between the age of 40-80 years old, and who will be attached to five health centers. Variables for the identification, following, result and patient profile have been defined. Emphasize the variables of "ulcer area decreasing", "CIVIQ index", "% one cure per week" .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Feasibility and Safety and Evaluation of the Potential Efficacy of Autologous Platelet-rich Plasma in the Treatment of Vascular Venous Ulcers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Varicose Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients resident in Barakaldo, who are seen in treatment rooms at the Zaballa outpatient clinic or one of the following health centres: Zaballa, La Paz, Urban, or San Vicente, in the EzkerraldeaEnkarterri Health Region of the Basque Health Service Osakidetza. Men or women of 40 to100 years of age Patients with stage C6 chronic venous insufficiency according to the CEAP classification Patients with vascular ulcers which have not responded to conventional treatment in 2 to 6 months Patients who present an analytical before entering the study with a normal range of number of platelets, red blood cells and hematocrit An ulcer of 35 cm in diameter An ABI of greater than or equal to 0.8 or less than or equal to 1.5. Independent patients or with sufficient family support Patients have given written informed consent Patients with chronic treatment with immunosuppressive or retroviral drugs Coagulopathies Patients with chronic infectious diseases Patients under radiotherapy or chemotherapy Patients with a history of neoplasia Patients with more than two active ulcers Pregnant women Patients with active cellulitis or fever An ABI of less than 0.8 or more than 1.5.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>PRP</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic vascular ulcer</keyword>
	<keyword>primary care</keyword>
</DOC>