<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01817933</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The recovery of range of motion and muscle power after surgical intervention of the fracture will mostly affect patient's daily activities. So postoperative rehabilitation program will play the important role. Correct and effective physical therapy will reduce the functional impairment of limbs after long term casting or surgical fixation, and accelerate to recover the independent daily activities. There is no consensus between immediate or delay and the duration of continue physical therapy will improve the shoulder function、muscle power and degree of satisfaction( physiological function、social function、mental health、 pain、 general health status ) after surgical fixation of fractures. This study will evaluate the patients of the fracture that including of the humeral neck fracture, vertebral fracture, distal radial fracture and hip fractures after surgical fixation, to see the difference of fracture healing time, function recovery and pain sensation after intervention of physical therapy at different time point. From this study, we hope to discriminate the timing of intervention and duration of physical therapy which is the key factors for postoperative prognosis of fractures fixation, and to set up the perfect rehabilitation program in ChangHua Christian Hospital. The results of this study will improve the discomfort of fracture patient's recovery or reduce the complications rate, and set up the standard treatment policy of our hospital , also was the model of other hospitals.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Integrated Rehabilitation Program for Fractures</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Fractures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Radius Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients with humeral neck fracture, vertebral fracture, distal radial fracture or hip fractures after surgical fixation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>