<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="11356">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02959099</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1310014469</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02959099</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Incident COronary EveNts Identified by Computed Tomography</brief_title>
  <acronym>ICONIC</acronym>
  <official_title>Incident COronary EveNts Identified by Computed Tomography</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The ICONIC study is a retrospective, international, multicenter, nested case-control study
      based on propensity scoring methods to match patients with (Cases) and without (Controls) an
      acute coronary syndrome (ACS). Our objective is to identify atherosclerotic plaque
      characteristics (APCs) that may be implicated in future ACS and compare gender-specific
      disparities, if any, in coronary plaques among women and men who subsequently experience a
      future ACS. The primary outcome is an ACS comprised of ST elevation myocardial infarction
      (STEMI), non-ST elevation MI (NSTEMI), or unstable angina, and the secondary outcome of MI
      includes STEMI and NSTEMI only.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BACKGROUND:

      Coronary artery disease (CAD) is accountable for a substantial portion of cardiovascular
      morbidity and mortality worldwide. Although traditional risk prediction algorithms to
      determine individuals at risk of future ACS have been used, these approaches are still
      considered less precise for estimating individual risk, and can misclassify a large
      proportion of definite acute myocardial infarction (AMI) as low-risk individuals for future
      AMI. Moreover, current risk evaluation has focused primarily on identifying individuals with
      high-grade stenosis, yet, the majority of ACS tend to occur without prior high-grade
      coronary stenosis in the culprit event-causing plaques. Notably, in relation to gender
      disparity, these findings are more apparent, with prognosis appearing considerably worse for
      women, with greater morbidity and mortality in the post-AMI period. Although autopsy
      examinations and invasive modalities such as intravascular ultrasound (IVUS) have revealed
      characteristics of vulnerable plaque with high ACS risk, these modalities have assessed
      patients only after rather than before the occurrence of an ACS, which may impede on
      determining a cause-effect relationship.

      Coronary computed tomographic angiography (CCTA) of 64-detector rows or greater hold promise
      as a non-invasive modality, and has often displayed high diagnostic performance for the
      evaluation of CAD as compared with invasive coronary angiography. CCTA is capable of
      evaluating specific features of atherosclerotic plaque as well as coronary arterial wall in
      a similar fashion to IVUS. Consequently, APCs can be readily visualized by CCTA in culprit
      lesions post ACS and have demonstrated high agreement with invasive methods. Though to date,
      the utility of APCs by CCTA for prognostication of future risk of ACS remains unexplored
      either at a per-patient or per-lesion basis. Further still, no adequately sized study has
      examined the gender-specific disparity in APCs among individuals prior to the occurrence of
      an ACS.

      STUDY OVERVIEW:

      The ICONIC is a nested case-control study based similarly upon the dynamic COronary CT
      Angiography EvaluatioN For Clinical Outcomes: An InteRnational Multicenter (CONFIRM)
      registry, encompassing a well-characterized patient cohort that is capable of detecting a
      meaningful association between APCs and future ACS. ICONIC will employ CCTA to
      comprehensively determine whether coronary APCs beyond traditional angiographic measures of
      CAD will be implicated in future ACS, and further, to effectively prognosticate
      gender-specific risk for future ACS. To this end, ICONIC will essentially examine the
      primary hypothesis that APCs within coronary plaques implicated in future ACS differ from
      APCs not implicated in future ACS. Secondly, in order to compare the disparity in coronary
      plaques for women versus men who subsequently experience a future ACS, ICONIC will test
      gender-specific difference in plaque characteristics among men and women who will experience
      a future ACS.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ACS</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>ACS includes ST elevation MI, non-ST elevation MI, unclassified MI, or unstable angina</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>STEMI and NSTEMI</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>ST elevation MI and Non-ST elevation MI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1998</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Coronary Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cases</arm_group_label>
    <description>ACS Patients</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Controls</arm_group_label>
    <description>Non-ACS Patients</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Total 13 sites provided both CCTA images and granular clinical data for core laboratory
        adjudication. Several countries in Asia, Europe, and North America currently represent
        this multinational effort. The population for ICONIC comprises a representative sample of
        individuals with suspected CAD who have undergone CCTA by ≥64-detector rows. In this
        regard, ICONIC recruited adult individuals who were deemed suitable for study enrollment
        according to the inclusion and exclusion criteria set out. Patients with a prior history
        of CAD before CCTA scanning were excluded from enrollment. Death occurring on the same day
        as an ACS, or after an ACS, met the inclusion criteria. Likewise, interval
        revascularization between CCTA and ACS did not warrant exclusion from ICONIC.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Cases

        Inclusion criteria:

          -  Age ≥18 years

          -  Adjudicated STEMI / NSTEMI / Unclassified MI / UA

        Exclusion criteria:

          -  Not ACS, Possible MI, Possible UA, and Absence of cardiac enzymes

          -  Lack of CCTA

          -  Prior history of CAD (Revascularization or MI) in RedCAP/CONFIRM (Revascularization
             or MI date precedes CCTA)

          -  ACS in revascularized segment

          -  Prior revascularization found on CCTA during MEDIS evaluation

          -  Type 4a, 4b, or 5 MI (Interval revascularization is not an exclusion criteria)

        Controls

        Inclusion criteria:

          -  Age ≥18 years

          -  Propensity score matched within a caliper predetermined from original cohort to
             reduce 95% bias.

        Exclusion criteria:

          -  Prior history of CAD

          -  Death
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baptist Hospital of Miami</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33176</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Walter Reed Army Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20889</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>William Beaumont Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Royal Oak</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48073</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Innsbruck Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Innsbruck</city>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Ottawa Heart Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ottawa</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Providence Health Care St. Paul's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Munich</name>
      <address>
        <city>Munich</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Clinical Sciences and Community Health, University of Milan &amp; Centro Cardiologico Monzino, IRCCS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milan</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Parma</name>
      <address>
        <city>Parma</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seoul National University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Severance Cardiovascular Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Leiden University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leiden</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital da Luz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lisboa</city>
        <country>Portugal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>Portugal</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Min JK, Dunning A, Lin FY, Achenbach S, Al-Mallah MH, Berman DS, Budoff MJ, Cademartiri F, Callister TQ, Chang HJ, Cheng V, Chinnaiyan KM, Chow B, Delago A, Hadamitzky M, Hausleiter J, Karlsberg RP, Kaufmann P, Maffei E, Nasir K, Pencina MJ, Raff GL, Shaw LJ, Villines TC. Rationale and design of the CONFIRM (COronary CT Angiography EvaluatioN For Clinical Outcomes: An InteRnational Multicenter) Registry. J Cardiovasc Comput Tomogr. 2011 Mar-Apr;5(2):84-92. doi: 10.1016/j.jcct.2011.01.007. Epub 2011 Feb 1.</citation>
    <PMID>21477786</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 4, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>November 4, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Acute myocardial infarction</keyword>
  <keyword>ST elevation myocardial infarction</keyword>
  <keyword>Non ST elevation myocardial infarction</keyword>
  <keyword>Unstable angina</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronary computed tomography angiography</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
