<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02600572</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Determine the changes in attention level due to isometric exercises and level three progression eccentric movements. The attention level will be measured using a mental speed test (how quickly a subject can process information and make decisions based upon that information). Another outcome measure will be the ability of the subject to maintain balance</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Changes in Attention Level Due to Isometric Exercises and Level Three Progression Eccentric Movements</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>On Day 1, subjects will complete the mental speed test and will undergo CDP testing using the modified Clinical Testing of Sensory Integration in Balance (mCTSIB) protocol: the subjects will be required to stand on a hard or compliant surface (a 4" tall foam cushion of known mechanical properties) in a comfortable posture, feet shoulder width, with eyes open or closed, head straight and arms to the side and free to move, gazing forward, and breathing normally. These will constitute the baseline information. Subjects will be divided into two groups: a isometric group (performing the isometric exercises) and an eccentric group (performing the eccentric exercises). At the end of Day 1, the isometric group will perform the isometric exercises while the eccentric group will act as control (no exercise). On Day 2, subjects will complete the mental speed test and will undergo the CDP testing a second time. These will constitute the first follow-up information. At the end of Day 2, the eccentric group will perform the eccentric exercises while the isometric group will act as control (no exercise). Throughout Day 3, subjects will complete the mental speed test and undergo the CDP testing a third time. This will constitute the second and last follow-up information.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Healthy individuals Any pathology preventing the subject to safely perform the isometric exercises (the clinician enrolling the subjects will make the decision)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>balance, postural</keyword>
	<keyword>postural equilibrium</keyword>
	<keyword>mental speed</keyword>
	<keyword>isometric exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>eccentric exercise</keyword>
</DOC>