<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02600052</DOC>
	<brief_summary>INTRODUCTION: Parkinson's disease (PD) is a neurodegenerative disorder that causes motor disorders such as bradykinesia, rigidity and tremor. In addition to the motor symptoms occurring in the overall PD patients, mostly there is associated respiratory disorders. The respiratory impairment may be due by postural changes, limiting the flexibility and expandability of the chest wall causing decreased lung volumes and flows. So the exercise Proprioceptive Neuromuscular Facilitation (PNF) is a tool designed to reduce the changes in respiratory function, the commitment of the respiratory muscles, and allows greater flexibility of the chest wall, reducing the rigidity of the rib cage. To evaluate the effects of respiratory pattern of Proprioceptive Neuromuscular Facilitation on the distribution of pulmonary ventilation, compartmental volumes of diaphragmatic mobility and functional capacity in patients with Parkinson's disease. METHODS: The study is a clinical trial randomized, in which participants to be elected for the study should present diagnosis of PD, staging of disease between II and III according to Hoehn and Yahr. Initially, the participants will undergo the collection of data on medical history, assessment of pulmonary function by spirometry and respiratory muscle strength measured by the manometer. Then will undergo evaluation of the breathing pattern and tricompartmental distribution of the volume of the chest wall by hemithorax by Plethysmography Optoelectronic; Quantify the mobility of the right diaphragm in total lung capacity for maneuver and during the current volume by ultrasonography. After the evaluation, participants will undergo intervention which will consist of three stages: first occur first session of the PNF later aerobic training for 30 minutes, ending with one PNF session.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Pattern Respiratory PNF Associated Aerobic Training on Lung Volumes and 6MWT Test in Parkinson Individuals</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Individuals with stage II and III between the Hoehn and Yahr classification; minimum score of 28 on the Mini Mental Examination for Parkinson. individuals with rheumatologic or orthopedic diseases or deformities / abnormalities in the spine that compromise the respiratory mechanics; respiratory comorbidities; history of smoking; history of thoracic or abdominal surgery; clinical instability characterized by infections and / or hemodynamic defined as greater than 150 bpm heart rate or systolic blood pressure less than 90 mmHg; Not present exchange of the drug in the last 30 days.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>