<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02615184</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety and effectiveness of treatment with once daily (QD) oral administration of dexlansoprazole 30 or 60 mg for 8 to 12 weeks in pediatric subjects aged 1 to 11 years inclusive, with erosive esophagitis (EE) and to assess the safety and effectiveness of dexlansoprazole 15 or 30 mg compared to placebo in maintenance of healed EE for 16 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 2, Double Blind Study to Assess Dexlansoprazole Delayed-Release Capsules for Healing of Erosive Esophagitis (EE) and Maintenance of Healed EE in Pediatric Participants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The drug being tested in this study is called dexlansoprazole. Dexlansoprazole is being tested to heal erosive esophagitis (EE) and maintain healing of EE in pediatric participants aged 1 to 11 years. This study will look at the healing of EE followed by maintained healing of EE in children who take dexlansoprazole. The study will be conducted in two periods; a Healing of EE Period and a Maintenance of Healed EE Period. Approximately 80 patients will be enrolled in this study. Participants will be randomly assigned (by chance, like flipping a coin) to receive dexlansoprazole 60 mg or dexlansoprazole 30 mg for 8 to 12 weeks during the Healing of EE Period. Participants who have healed EE confirmed by endoscopy at week 8 or 12 will enter the Maintenance of Healed EE Period and will be randomly assigned to receive half their healing dose of dexlansoprazole,( i.e., either 30 mg, dexlansoprazole 15 mg), or placebo (this is a capsule that looks like the study drug but has no active ingredient). All participants will be asked to take one capsule at the same time each day throughout the study. All participants will be asked to record any time they have heartburn symptoms in a diary. Subjects who complete the 16 weeks of the Maintenance of Healed EE Period (Week 24 or Week 28 as applicable) and have maintained healing of EE as confirmed by endoscopy, will enter a Post-Treatment Follow up Period for up to 3 months after the last dose of study drug. During this period subjects will continue to complete the symptom questionnaires daily in the eDiaries and return for a clinic visit each month. Subjects who require an invasive procedure or treatment with a proton pump inhibitor (PPI) or histamine 2-receptor antagonist (H2RA) for gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD)/EE will be discontinued from the Post-Treatment Follow-up Period and a Final Study Visit will be performed. This multi-center trial will be conducted worldwide. The overall time to participate in this study is up to 40 weeks. Participants will make multiple visits to the clinic including a final visit 3 months after last dose of study drug for a follow-up assessment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Esophagitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexlansoprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lansoprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. In the opinion of the investigator, the participant (as age appropriate) and/or parent(s) or legal guardian are capable of understanding and complying with protocol requirements. 2. Prior to any studyspecific procedures being performed, the informed consent and the assent form must be signed and dated by parent(s) or legal guardian and by the participant respectively, if appropriate. 3. Has a medical history of symptoms of gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD) for at least 3 months prior to Screening. 4. Has medical history of at least 1 failed attempted withdrawal of prior proton pump inhibitor (PPI)/acid suppressive therapy with a return of symptoms upon withdrawal. 5. Has met the electronic diary (eDiary) qualification criteria as assessed by the Pediatric GERD Symptom Daily Diaries (PGSDD), defined as hurting or burning in the stomach, chest, or throat on at least 3 of any 7 consecutive days during the Screening Period. (Note: If an endoscopy performed within 1 week of signing informed consent and assent is used to confirm diagnosis of erosive esophagitis (EE), the participant does not need to meet this criterion). 6. Has endoscopic evidence of EE with HetzelDent (HD) Grade ≥2 based on the screening endoscopy performed either during the Screening Period or within 1 week prior to signing informed consent and assent (as applicable). An endoscopy that was performed within 1 week prior to signing informed consent and assent, as applicable, is an acceptable replacement for the Screening endoscopy if EE is documented by HD classification scale criterion previously described, protocolrequired biopsies were collected and endoscopic pictures were obtained. 7. Is male or female and age 1 to 11 years inclusive at Screening. 1. Has evidence of cardiovascular, pulmonary, central nervous system, hepatic, hematopoietic, renal, or metabolic disorder, severe allergy, asthma, or allergic skin rash that suggests any uncontrolled, clinically significant underlying disease or condition (other than the disease being studied), which may impact the ability of the participant to participate or potentially confound the study results. 2. Has a coexisting disease affecting the esophagus (eg, esophageal varices, scleroderma, viral or fungal infection, or esophageal stricture), history of radiation therapy or cryotherapy to the esophagus, caustic or physiochemical trauma such as sclerotherapy to the esophagus. 3. Has any findings in his/her medical history, physical examination, or safety clinical laboratory tests giving reasonable suspicion of underlying disease that might interfere with the conduct of the trial. 4. Has a history of hypersensitivity or allergies to dexlansoprazole or any component of dexlansoprazole or any PPI (including lansoprazole, omeprazole, rabeprazole, pantoprazole, or esomeprazole) or antacids. 5. Is required to take excluded medications or it is anticipated that the participant will require treatment with at least 1 of the disallowed concomitant medications during the study evaluation period. 6. Has a condition that may require inpatient surgery during the course of the study. 7. Has a known history of Barrett's with dysplastic changes in the esophagus. 8. Has a known history of eosinophilic esophagitis (EoE) or endoscopic findings suggestive of EoE (≥15 eosinophils per highpowered field [HPF]). 9. Has history of celiac disease, confirmed by histology or tests positive for tissue transglutaminase (tTG) antibody. 10. Has history of inflammatory bowel disease, or irritable bowel syndrome. 11. Has active gastric or duodenal ulcers within 4 weeks prior to Day 1. 12. Requires dilatation of esophageal strictures and/or strictures preventing passage of the endoscope during the Screening endoscopy. Schatzki's ring (a ring of mucosal tissue near the lower esophageal sphincter) is acceptable. 13. A female participant who has reached menarche. 14. Is known to be positive for the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). 15. Has current or clinical history of ZollingerEllison syndrome or other hypersecretory condition. 16. Has a history of gastric, duodenal, or esophageal surgery except simple oversew of an ulcer. A history of gastric tube and/or percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy (PEG) placement is allowed. 17. Had an acute upper gastrointestinal hemorrhage within 4 weeks prior to endoscopy. 18. Has donated or lost &gt;10% of the total blood volume, undergone plasmapheresis, or has had a transfusion of any blood product within 90 days prior to the first dose of study drug. 19. Has a known history of alcohol abuse or illegal drug use within the past 12 months prior to the first dose of study drug. 20. Has any screening abnormal laboratory value that suggests a clinically significant underlying disease or condition that may prevent the participant from entering the study; or the participant has: creatinine &gt;1.5 mg/dL, alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and/or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt;2 times the upper limit of normal (×ULN), or total bilirubin &gt;2.0 mg/dL with AST/ALT elevated above the limits of normal values. 21. Is an immediate family member, study site employee, or is in a dependent relationship with a study site employee who is involved in the conduct of this study or may consent and assent under duress. Students of the institution/research facility who are under the supervision of, or in a subordinate role to, the investigator are also ineligible. 22. The participant, in the opinion of the investigator, is unlikely to comply with the protocol or is unsuitable for any other reason. 23. Has participated in another clinical study and/or has received any investigational compound within 30 days prior to Screening. 24. Tests positive for H. pylori. However, participants who are positive and have received therapeutically approved eradication therapy within the past 6 months will be allowed to participate.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug therapy</keyword>
</DOC>