<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02615444</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether daily consumption of soluble fibre, oat beta glucan (4g), for six weeks will have any impact on overweight/obese individuals in terms of risk factors used to define metabolic disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effects of Beta-glucan Enriched Oatcake Consumption on Metabolic Disease Risk Factors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to determine whether daily consumption oat beta glucan (4g) for six weeks will have any impact on overweight/obese individuals in terms of risk factors used to define metabolic disease. Oat beta-glucan has been incorporated into a novel oatcake product manufactured by Nairn's Oatcakes Ltd. Consumption of the oatcake products will deliver enough oat-beta glucan to the diet to meet European Food Safety Authority health claims for lowering blood cholesterol and reducing post-prandial glycaemic responses.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and females 18 years and older Waist circumference measurements of ≥94cm for males and 80cm for females, or a body mass index of ≥30kg/m2 Individuals who are able to provide informed consent Postmenopausal females Smokers Individuals who suffer from, or taking medication for, cardiovascular or gastrointestinal disease Impaired glucose tolerance/Diabetes mellitus Pregnancy or breastfeeding Those who have high dietary fibre intakes (&gt;20g/day) Known food allergies to oats, wheat, lactose, or sesame seeds</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metabolic Syndrome X</keyword>
	<keyword>Overweight</keyword>
	<keyword>Waist Circumference</keyword>
	<keyword>Blood Pressure</keyword>
	<keyword>Cholesterol</keyword>
	<keyword>Oat beta glucan</keyword>
</DOC>