<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004402</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Compare the rate of treatment failure in osteopetrosis patients receiving interferon gamma in combination with calcitriol to the rate of treatment failure in patients receiving calcitriol alone. II. Compare the number of adverse events or clinical manifestations of disease progression occurring in these patients. III. Assess the effects of interferon gamma on hematopoiesis, cranial nerve function, and rate of infection in these patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase III Randomized Study of Interferon Gamma in Children With Severe, Congenital Osteopetrosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: This is a randomized, placebo controlled, open label study. Patients are randomized to one of two arms (interferon gamma in combination with calcitriol or calcitriol alone). Arm I: Patients receive calcitriol once daily. Interferon gamma is administered by subcutaneous injection three times a week. Arm II: Patients receive calcitriol once daily. Patients may continue treatment in the absence of toxicity and disease progression. If disease progression is diagnosed in the control group, patients will then receive interferon gamma in combination with calcitriol. Patients are followed every 4 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteopetrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-gamma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcitriol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Biopsy and xray confirmed primary osteopetrosis Presence of anemia and/or cranial nerve compression Prior/Concurrent Therapy Biologic therapy: No prior/concurrent bone marrow transplantation No prior interferon gamma No other investigational biologic agents Chemotherapy: No prior/concurrent chemotherapeutic agents for bone marrow transplantation Endocrine therapy: Prior/concurrent corticosteroid as supportive therapy allowed Radiotherapy: Not specified Surgery: At least 5 days since major surgery Other: Prior/concurrent calcitriol as supportive therapy allowed Prior/concurrent transfusion as supportive therapy allowed Prior/concurrent dietary therapy allowed Patient Characteristics Age: 2 months to 10 years Performance status: Not specified Life expectancy: At least 6 months Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Bilirubin less than 2 mg/dL Renal: Creatinine less than 1.5 mg/dL OR Creatinine clearance greater than 50 mL/min Pulmonary: No uncorrected airway obstruction Other: No active infection requiring intravenous antibiotics No known seizure disorder not related to hypocalcemia No uncorrected hydrocephalus No MRI evidence of cerebral atrophy Must maintain or gain body weight No sleep apnea No thrombocytopenia No massive splenomegaly</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2001</verification_date>
	<keyword>genetic diseases and dysmorphic syndromes</keyword>
	<keyword>osteopetrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
</DOC>