<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004781</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Evaluate the development of oral manifestations of human immunodeficiency virus infection in relationship to the onset of immunologic alterations and systemic symptoms in different risk groups: gay/bisexual men, male intravenous drug users, and female intravenous drug users. II. Evaluate the immune and inflammatory response to periodontal and other microbial pathogens. III. Evaluate the bacterial species infecting the oral cavity in patients in these risk groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Oral Manifestations of Human Immunodeficiency Virus Infection in High Risk Groups</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: Patients undergo a periodontal assessment every 6 months until medically unable to continue. The oral/dental exam includes saliva and gingival crevicular fluid analysis and, as indicated, oral photographs.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Candidiasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Candidiasis, Oral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Human immunodeficiency virus infection (HIV) seropositive or seronegative At risk for HIV, i.e.: Gay/bisexual men Male intravenous drug users Female intravenous drug users No acquired immunodeficiency syndrome Currently enrolled in Columbia Presbyterian Medical Center protocol "The Natural History and Progression of HIV Infection"</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 1997</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV-associated candidiasis</keyword>
	<keyword>candidiasis</keyword>
	<keyword>disease-related problem/condition</keyword>
	<keyword>fungal infection</keyword>
	<keyword>immunologic disorders and infectious disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>infection</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
</DOC>