<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004449</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the effectiveness of intensive one-on-one behavioral treatment in the home or neighborhood compared with at home, individualized, parent training in preschool aged children with autism. II. Identify intake measures that predict differences in outcome between subjects in the experimental group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized Study of Intensive One-on-one Behavioral Treatment for Preschool Aged Children With Autism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: This is a randomized study. Children are randomized to receive either 35 hours of intensive one-on-one behavioral treatment in the home and neighborhood for 2 years or individualized, in home parent training for 6 months. A common group of tests to evaluate autism are administered at intake, 12 and 24 months into treatment, and when patients reach age 6.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Diagnosis of autism based on the Autism Diagnostic Interview using the ICD10 research criteria Ratio IQ score greater than 35 determined from the Bayley Scales of Infant Development Patient Characteristics Other: Must reside within 60 km (37.5 miles) of a treatment site EXCLUSION CRITERIA: Severe medically induced limitations defined as: Any condition requiring prosthetic devices (e.g., blindness, deafness, or cerebral palsy) Any illness that has prevented or would prevent a subject from participating in 30 hours a week of treatment for six consecutive weeks or more (e.g., metastasized cancer or end stage renal disease) Any known genetic disorder (e.g., Fragile X, PKU, or Down Syndrome) Any other disorder that rules out autism according to ICD10 criteria (e.g., Rett's Syndrome)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>3 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>autism</keyword>
	<keyword>neurologic and psychiatric disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
</DOC>