<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004787</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Assess the efficacy of recombinant human granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF) in raising the absolute neutrophil count, platelet count, and hemoglobin level in patients with inherited bone marrow failure syndromes. II. Assess the efficacy of a reduced maintenance dose in patients who respond to daily G-CSF. III. Assess the toxic effects of G-CSF in these patients. IV. Measure bone marrow progenitor colonies before and after G-CSF. V. Measure CD34-positive cells in marrow and blood before and after G-CSF using flow cytometry and immunohistochemistry.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II Pilot Study of Granulocyte Colony-Stimulating Factor for Inherited Bone Marrow Failure Syndromes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: Patients receive granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF) subcutaneously every day for 8 weeks; nonresponders receive an increased dose for an additional 8 weeks. Patients who respond at week 8 or 16 are then tapered to a lower maintenance dose of G-CSF administered every other day through week 40. The dose is adjusted to maintain an absolute neutrophil count above 1500. Patients are removed from study for failure to achieve a complete response by week 16, unacceptable nonhematologic toxicity, the identification of a clonal karyotype in marrow, or the onset of leukemia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thrombocytopenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fanconi Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fanconi Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyskeratosis Congenita</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenograstim</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Inherited bone marrow failure syndrome, including: Fanconi's anemia Dyskeratosis congenita Shwachman syndrome Amegakaryocytic thrombocytopenia Decreased megakaryocytes in infancy No thrombocytopenia with absent radius syndrome (TAR) No trisomy 13 or 18 No clonal bone marrow karyotype Prior/Concurrent Therapy At least 4 weeks since growth factors Concurrent therapy allowed if not altered for 30 days prior to entry through week 8 No concurrent investigational drugs Patient Characteristics Hematopoietic: ANC &lt;1000 No leukemia Other: No medical or psychiatric contraindication to protocol participation No pregnant or nursing women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2001</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fanconi's anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Shwachman syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>aplastic anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>dermatologic disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>dyskeratosis congenita</keyword>
	<keyword>hematologic disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
	<keyword>thrombocytopenia</keyword>
</DOC>