<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004796</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Assess the effect of lactulose on the circadian rhythm of plasma melatonin in patients with subclinical hepatic encephalopathy. II. Assess the intrasubject variability of circadian melatonin levels and neuropsychological tests. III. Assess which elements of the neuropsychological test battery show the response to lactulose.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II Study of Lactulose and Circadian Rhythms in Patients With Cirrhosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: Patients are alternately assigned to 1 of 2 treatment groups: no therapy for 3 weeks followed by lactulose for 3 weeks versus lactulose for 3 weeks followed by no therapy for 3 weeks. A dietician advises patients on a 1 g/kg per day protein diet. The lactulose dose is adjusted to result in 2 or 3 loose bowel movements per day.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatic Encephalopathy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension, Portal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lactulose</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Clinical diagnosis of cirrhosis with portal hypertension or portalsystemic shunting Prior/Concurrent Therapy No concurrent therapy for hepatic encephalopathy Patient Characteristics Age: Under 65 Performance status: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: See Disease Characteristics Renal: Not specified Other: No alcohol intake within 1 month prior to entry No requirement for beta blockers No requirement for corticosteroids Not in intercontinental travel</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 1998</verification_date>
	<keyword>cardiovascular and respiratory diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>cirrhosis</keyword>
	<keyword>gastrointestinal disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>hypertensive disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>portal hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
</DOC>