<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004311</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Evaluate insulin resistance in thin and obese hyperandrogenic women with polycystic ovarian disease or hyperandrogenism insulin resistance acanthosis nigricans syndrome and in thin and obese controls, using an estimation of tissue sensitivity to insulin. II. Evaluate the effect of androgen suppression with leuprolide acetate and spironolactone on insulin secretion and resistance.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II Study of the Effect of Leuprolide Acetate and Spironolactone on Insulin Resistance in Hyperandrogenic Women With Polycystic Ovarian Disease or Hyperandrogenism Insulin Resistance Acanthosis Nigricans Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: Participants are treated with subcutaneous leuprolide acetate followed by oral spironolactone. Each treatment is administered daily for 6 weeks, with a 6-week washout between drugs. Patients and controls are alternately assigned to begin treatment with leuprolide acetate or spironolactone.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polycystic Ovary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acanthosis Nigricans</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leuprolide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spironolactone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Polycystic ovarian disease Oligomenorrhea or amenorrhea Hirsutism Hyperandrogenism Hyperandrogenism insulin resistance acanthosis nigricans syndrome Hyperandrogenism Oligomenorrhea or amenorrhea Insulin resistance Acanthosis nigricans Hematocrit at least 30% Women with normal menstrual cycles not using oral contraception entered as controls</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2000</verification_date>
	<keyword>acanthosis nigricans</keyword>
	<keyword>dermatologic disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>endocrine disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>polycystic ovarian syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
</DOC>