<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004398</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Evaluate the efficacy of tin mesoporphyrin in patients with acute porphyria attacks who are also treated with a standard course of heme arginate. II. Evaluate the safety and tolerability of tin mesoporphyrin when administered to these patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase I Study of Heme Arginate With or Without Tin Mesoporphyrin in Patients With Acute Attacks of Porphyria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: This is an randomized, unblinded, multicenter study. Patients are randomized to receive heme arginate alone or both heme arginate and tin mesoporphyrin. Patients receive a single intravenous dose of tin mesoporphyrin immediately before the first dose of heme arginate. Heme arginate is administered daily for 4 days. Patients are followed at 3 and 6 days after treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Porphyrias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Porphyria, Erythropoietic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tin mesoporphyrin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Documented acute intermittent porphyria, variegate porphyria, or hereditary coproporphyria No chronic or subacute symptoms (present for longer than 2 weeks) Prior/Concurrent Therapy At least 3 weeks since prior treatment with heme arginate or tin mesoporphyrin Patient Characteristics Renal: Urinary porphobilinogen at least 40 mg/24 hr Other: Not pregnant Fertile female patients must use effective contraception during and 6 months before study No evidence that symptoms are due to another acute illness No acute hemorrhagic disorder such as: Gastrointestinal bleeding Intracerebral hemorrhage No known sensitivity to heme preparation or tin mesoporphyrin No other medical condition that might increase risk to patient</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2000</verification_date>
	<keyword>inborn errors of metabolism</keyword>
	<keyword>porphyria</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
</DOC>