<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004582</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see if ABT-378/ritonavir plus efavirenz is safe and effective in lowering the amount of HIV in the blood of patients who have been treated with more than 1 protease inhibitor (PI).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ABT-378/Ritonavir and Efavirenz in HIV-Infected Patients Who Have Taken More Than One Protease Inhibitor in the Past</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All patients take ABT-378/ritonavir and efavirenz; there are no placebos in this study. Patients take study medications for 48 weeks, during which time there will be 15 study visits. There is a possibility of a study extension after 48 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lopinavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Protease Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Efavirenz</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Protease Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients may be eligible for this study if they: Are HIVpositive. Have a viral load (level of HIV in the blood) of at least 1,000 copies/ml. Have been receiving stable (no changes) antiHIV treatment that includes at least 1 PI for at least 8 weeks prior to study entry. Have received more than 1 PI for at least 12 weeks each at some time in the past. Exclusion Criteria Patients will not be eligible for this study if they: Have had any active opportunistic (AIDSrelated) infections within the past 30 days. Have ever received nonnucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitors (NNRTIs), such as delavirdine, nevirapine, or efavirenz. Have received certain medications. Are pregnant or breastfeeding. Abuse alcohol or drugs.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2000</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV Protease Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>Ritonavir</keyword>
	<keyword>Reverse Transcriptase Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-HIV Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Viral Load</keyword>
	<keyword>ABT 378</keyword>
	<keyword>efavirenz</keyword>
</DOC>