<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004816</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Evaluate the safety and immunogenicity of single and multiple doses of M-T412, a chimeric murine-human anti-CD4 monoclonal antibody, in patients with multiple sclerosis. II. Evaluate the pharmacokinetics of M-T412. III. Obtain preliminary data on the clinical response to M-T412.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Maintenance Extension of Phase I Pilot Study of Chimeric Anti-CD4 Antibody M-T412 in Patients With Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: This is an open label, dose escalating study. Escalating doses of M-T412 are administered to cohorts of 5 patients each receiving a single dose intravenously over 2 hours. Patients who complete the single dose assessment of M-T412 may receive up to 3 additional single doses of M-T412 IV over 2 hours, with each repeated dose given at least 1 month apart. Then, patients receive one dose level of M-T412 IV over 2 hours at 3 month intervals over a period of 12 months for a total of 5 doses. Once recovery of CD4 cells is obtained, the next scheduled infusion of M-T412 begins. Patients are omitted from study if CD4 cells remain attenuated following 2 scheduled infusion sessions. Patients are followed at 3, 6, 12, and 24 months after the first infusion.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Diagnosis of chronic, advanced, progressive multiple sclerosis (MS) Prior/Concurrent Therapy Biologic therapy: No sensitivity to murine proteins No prior treatment at any time with antiCD4 antibodies, other murine antibodies, or other antiT cell antibodies (e.g., xenologous or human) At least 4 weeks since use of other biological agents Chemotherapy: No concomitant chemotherapy At least 3 months since prior chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: No concomitant steroidal therapy At least 3 months since prior steroidal therapy Radiotherapy: No total lymphoid irradiation prior to study No concomitant radiotherapy At least 3 months since prior radiotherapy Other: No use of investigational drugs within 30 days prior to study Patient Characteristics Age: 21 to 75 Hematopoietic: Hemoglobin at least 10 g/dL WBC at least 4000/mm3 Granulocyte count at least 1500/mm3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm3 CD4+ lymphocyte count at least 300 cells/mm3 Other: Not pregnant or lactating Effective contraception required of fertile patients for 3 months prior to and during study No substance abuse (e.g., drug or alcohol) Not HIV positive No AIDSRelated Complex (ARC) No serum antibodies to HIV Negative serum antibody test for HIV within 1 month prior to study No underlying medical or psychiatric condition</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2001</verification_date>
	<keyword>multiple sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>neurologic and psychiatric disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
</DOC>