<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004256</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Radiation therapy uses high-energy x-rays to damage tumor cells. Drugs such as sargramostim may protect normal cells from the side effects of radiation therapy. PURPOSE: Randomized phase II trial to determine the effectiveness of sargramostim in preventing mucositis in patients who are receiving radiation therapy for laryngeal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sargramostim to Prevent Mucositis in Patients Receiving Radiation Therapy for Laryngeal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the efficacy of sargramostim (GM-CSF) in reducing the duration and severity of mucositis resulting from accelerated radiotherapy in patients with laryngeal carcinoma. - Determine the effect of GM-CSF on quality of life aspects of these patients as assessed by nutritional status, analgesic use, and days in the hospital. OUTLINE: This is a randomized study. Patients receive radiotherapy in 16 fractions over 21 days. Patients are randomly allocated to one of two treatment arms before scheduled radiotherapy begins. - Arm I: Patients receive sargramostim (GM-CSF) SC daily for 14 days beginning on day 14 of the course of radiotherapy. - Arm II: Patients do not receive GM-CSF. Patients are followed weekly until mucositis is healed, as well as at weeks 2 and 6 following the end of radiotherapy. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 34 patients (17 per arm) will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mucositis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Radiation Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Laryngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of laryngeal cancer with intention to treat by radiotherapy using a 16 fraction 3 week scheme Stage I or II No known CNS disease PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 20 to 80 Performance status: WHO 01 Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Hepatic function normal Renal: Renal function normal Other: Not pregnant or nursing No serious active infection requiring antibiotic therapy No autoimmune disease No known seizures No psychosocial factors that would preclude study compliance No allergies to sargramostim (GMCSF) Willingness to cooperate for regular mirror examination of the larynx PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: No concurrent immunotherapy Chemotherapy: No concurrent chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: No prior or concurrent corticosteroids No concurrent hormonal therapy Radiotherapy: See Disease Characteristics Surgery: No major organ allografts Other: No other concurrent investigational drugs</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage I laryngeal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II laryngeal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent laryngeal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>oral complications</keyword>
	<keyword>radiation toxicity</keyword>
</DOC>