<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004126</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Combining more than one drug may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of combining paclitaxel and oxaliplatin in treating patients who have recurrent or advanced non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Paclitaxel and Oxaliplatin in Treating Patients With Recurrent or Advanced Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the overall, partial, and complete response rates in patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer treated with oxaliplatin plus paclitaxel. II. Assess the overall survival, time to tumor progression, and toxicities associated with this combination regimen in this patient population. III. Assess the neurologic toxicity of this combination regimen and its correlation with creatinine clearance in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients receive paclitaxel IV over 1 hour followed by oxaliplatin IV over 2 hours on day 1. Treatment repeats every 3 weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients are followed for at least 2 years or until death. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: Approximately 17-37 patients will be accrued for this study within 24 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC) Stage IIIB with pleural effusion OR Stage IV OR Recurrent disease Bidimensionally measurable disease PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: ECOG 02 Karnofsky 50100% Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: WBC greater than 3,000/mm3 Absolute neutrophil count at least 1,500/mm3 Platelet count greater than 100,000/mm3 Hepatic: Bilirubin normal SGOT less than 2 times normal Renal: Creatinine no greater than 1.5 mg/dL OR Creatinine clearance at least 50 mL/min BUN less than 1.5 times normal Cardiovascular: No symptomatic congestive heart failure No unstable angina or myocardial infarction within the past 6 months No evidence of heart block greater than first degree, bundle branch block, or ventricular or supraventricular arrhythmia Other: No allergy to platinum compounds or antiemetics appropriate for study No other uncontrolled illness No active or ongoing infection No evidence of peripheral neuropathy by physical exam or history Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 6 months after study PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: No prior chemotherapy for advanced NSCLC At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: Not specified Radiotherapy: At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy Surgery: Not specified Other: No other concurrent investigational agents No concurrent antiretroviral therapy for HIV positive patients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>