<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00004695</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine whether polyethylene-glycol-conjugated interleukin 2 (PEG-IL-2) can reduce the number of infections in patients with common variable immunodeficiency. II. Determine whether this therapy can improve lung functions in these patients with pulmonary impairment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized Study of Polyethylene-Glycol-Conjugated Interleukin 2 in Patients With Common Variable Immunodeficiency</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: This is a randomized, open-label study. Patients are randomized to receive polyethylene-glycol-conjugated interleukin 2 (PEG-IL-2) or placebo. Patients receive PEG-IL-2 or placebo by subcutaneous injection weekly for 18 months. Patients maintain a daily diary for 24 months. Patients are followed every 4 months for 2 years. Completion date provided represents the completion date of the grant per OOPD records</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Common Variable Immunodeficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interleukin-2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Documented common variable immunodeficiency defined as a reduction of serum IgG by at least 2 standard deviations In vitro lymphocyte proliferative response to PEGIL2 of at least 10 times more than unstimulated cultures Prior/Concurrent Therapy No biologic response modifier therapy (i.e., interferon, cyclosporin A) except prednisone (maximum 10 mg/day) Concurrent treatment with same dosage intravenous gammaglobulin for at least 6 months is required Patient Characteristics Life expectancy: At least 24 months Other: Not pregnant or nursing HIV negative</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 1999</verification_date>
	<keyword>common variable immunodeficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>immunologic disorders and infectious disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>primary immunodeficiency disease</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
</DOC>