<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02940418</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Allogenic adipose derived mesenchymal stem cells will be injected into patients newly diagnosed with type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of Stem Cells in Diabetes Mellitus Type 1</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Adipose derived mesenchymal stem cells (ASCs) are to be collected from blood group O donor, cells will be passaged to passage 5. Before release the sample will be subject to our release criteria which include: testing for any bacterial or fungal growth as well as endotoxin and mycoplasma. All these tests must be negative. In addition the cell count and viability (must be more than 80%) are done before release. Surface markers documentation is done on the cells before release using flow cytometry. The cells should be infused within 2 hours of release. The dose to is to be repeated after 6 months of a total of two doses in patients. Tests and follow up are to be one at week 12, 24 and 36 when the study is stopped. These cells will be injected intravenously into patients newly diagnosed with type 1 Diabetes Mellitus.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adult Patients with Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus. 2. Age from 18 years to 35 years either gender. 3. Duration of disease: not exceeding 3 years unless Cpeptide is not less than 0.5 ng/ml 4. CPeptide at inclusion base line should not be less than 0.5 ng/ml 5. No clinical evidence of renal, retinal, vascular or skin complications 6. Body Mass Index not exceeding 30 7. Any HbA1c 8. At least one positive antibody either antiGlutamic Acid Decarboxylase65 or InsulinomaAssociated2 Autoantibodies (anti1A2) 9. Informed Consent by patient 1. Age less than 18 years and more than 35 years 2. Pregnancy 3. Married women or women expected to be married within the study period 4. History of allergy, Cancer, bronchial asthma, liver disease or hepatitis 5. Diabetic coma or precoma current or recent within the last 2 months 6. CPeptide less than 0.5 ng/ml 7. Disease duration more than 3 yrs. 8. Complication mentioned in 5 above in inclusion 9. Nonconsenting patient or withdrawal of consent. 10. Bleeding disorders</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Type 1</keyword>
	<keyword>Adipose derived mesenchymal stem cells</keyword>
</DOC>