<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01576991</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to describe the relationship between leukocyte, granulose cell and polar body telomere length, telomere injury foci (TIFs), polarized light microscopy of oocyte spindles and their frequency in the eggs from older women and associations with aneuploidy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Telomeres and Reproduction in Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The chances of conception decrease and miscarriage increase with a women's age, and the locus of reproductive aging is the egg (1). Egg dysfunction affects most women beginning by their late '30's and for many women age related egg dysfunction represents a major cause of infertility. The cause of age related egg dysfunction is poorly understood, but telomere dysfunction may play an important role. Our group has demonstrated that genetic or pharmacologic shortening of telomeres in the eggs of mice, which normally do not exhibit age related egg dysfunction, mimics reproductive aging in women, with cell cycle arrest, apoptosis, spindle dysmorphologies and chromosomal abnormalities (1,2). Moreover, a pilot study the investigators conducted five years ago suggested that telomere length of spare human eggs may predict the outcome of womens' InVitro Fertilization (IVF) cycles (3). Subsequently, other investigators have demonstrated that telomere length of circulating leukocytes predicts miscarriages (4).</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Ages 18 to 48 Undergoing InVitro Fertilization Willing to donate spare eggs, granulosa cells and blood Willing to give written informed consent Not undergoing InVitro Fertilization Not willing to donate spare eggs, granulosa cells or blood Not willing to give written informed consent Previously donated spare eggs, granulosa cells or blood for this research project</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>