<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02527096</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The principal objective is to evaluate the antiviral efficacy of 48 weeks treatment with the two-drugs combination dolutegravir(Tivicay®) and lamivudine(TEpivir®) in HIV-1 infected patients virologically suppressed with triple HAART.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Trial Evaluating Maintenance Therapy With Lamivudine (Epivir®) and Dolutegravir (Tivicay®) in Human Immunodeficiency Virus 1 (HIV-1) Infected Patients Virologically Suppressed With Triple Highly Active Antiretroviral Therapy (HAART) (ANRS 167 Lamidol)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Secondary objectives: The following parameters will be evaluated : - Evolution of CD4 cells and CD8 cells - Tolerance to treatment - Emergence of resistance mutations at time of virological failure - HIV viral load measured with ultrasensitive assay (threshold 1 copy/mL) at Day 0, Week 8, Week 32 and Week 56 - Influence of total DNA at Day 0 on the occurrence of virological failure or blip - Plasma levels of dolutegravir(Tivicay®) and lamivudine in participants with virological failure - Adherence to treatment - Quality of life - Medico-economic aspects - Dolutegravir(Tivicay®) and Nucleosidic Reverse Transcriptase Inhibitors (NRTIs) levels, and HIV viral load in semen in a subgroup of 20 participants. Methodology: Pilot trial, multicentric, national, prospective, no randomized and no comparative.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dolutegravir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lamivudine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HIV1 infected patient Age ≥ 18 years CD4 cell count nadir &gt; 200/mm3 Genotype on preHAART interpreted with the last version of the ANRS AC11 resistance group's algorithm which presents: no major mutation on protease among: D30N, V32I, M46I/L, I47A/V, G48V, I50L/V, 154M/L, L76V, V82A/F/T/S, I84V, N88D/S, L90M, no mutation on RT (except the mutation A98S if the patient is not infected by the virus subtype C), no mutation on integrase (if the genotype is available), Firstline treatment with suppressive triple HAART (2 NRTI + either 1 PI/r, 1 NNRTI or 1 INI). The initial treatment may have changed a maximum of two times but only once for toxicity (changes such Epivir / Ziagen to Kivexa, are not considered as a change of treatment). However, treatment has to be unchanged in the last 6 months Plasma HIV RNA ≤ 50 copies/mL for ≥ 2 years with at least 2 viral load determinations per year. Blips (HIV viral load between 50 and 200 copies/mL but ≤ 50 copies/mL on control sample) are allowed except in the last 6 months. The total number of blips must not exceed 3 in the last 2 years Negative Hepatitis Bs Antigen Effective contraception for women of childbearing potential Informed consent form signed by patient and investigator Patient enrolled in or a beneficiary of a Social Security programme (State Medical Aid ("Aide Médicale d'Etat" AME in France) is not a Social Security programme) HIV2 infection Positive HBc Ac isolated Hepatitis B Virus (HBV) coinfected patients (positive Hepatitis Bs Ag at inclusion) Chronic hepatitis C currently treated or needing therapy in the next 12 months History of HIVassociated neurocognitive disorders Current pregnancy or breastfeeding No effective contraception for the women of childbearing Previous treatment with chemotherapy (except bleomycin on Kaposi disease's treatment) or immunotherapy Grade &gt; 2 abnormality for usual biological parameters (liver function tests, blood cell count) ALT(Alanine Aminotransferase) ≥ 5 x upper limit of normal value (ULN) or AST (Aspartate Aminotransferase) ≥ 3 x ULN and bilirubinemia ≥ 1.5 x ULN (with 35% direct bilirubinemia) Unstable liver disease (ascitis, encephalopathy, coagulopathy, hypoalbuminemia, oesophageal or gastric varices or persistent jaundice) Known biliary abnormalities (with the exception of Gilbert's syndrome or asymptomatic gallstones) Creatininemia clearance below 50 mL/min (CockroftGault method) History or presence of allergy to the trial drugs or their components Severe hepatic insufficiency (Child Pugh Class C) Patients participating in another clinical trial including an exclusion period that is still in force during the screening phase Patients under "sauvegarde de justice" (judicial protection due to temporarily and slightly diminished mental or physical faculties) or under legal guardianship.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>dolutegravir(Tivicay®)</keyword>
	<keyword>lamivudine(Epivir®)</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV-1</keyword>
	<keyword>efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
</DOC>