<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02527772</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine that Liposomal Doxorubicin(LD) plus Gemcitabine(GEM) is superior to Oxaliplatin（OXA） Plus Fluorouracil/Leucovorin(FOLFOX4) in prolonging progression-free survival（PFS） in patients with Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Liposomal Doxorubicin Plus Gemcitabine Versus Oxaliplatin Plus Fluorouracil/Leucovorin for Hepatocellular Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Eligible patients were age 18 to 75 years; The patients had histologically, cytologically,or clinically diagnosed unresectable HCC;and were ineligible for local invasive treatment. Clinically diagnosed patients had to have: (1) evidence of HBV or HCV with hepatic cirrhosis; (2) afetoprotein levels 400g/L; and (3) morphologic evidence of hypervascular liver tumor. Patients had to have at least one measurable lesion according to RECIST (version 1.0; ≥2 cm on computed tomography [CT]; 1 cm on spiral CT or magnetic resonance imaging). Lesions that had undergone previous interventional or local therapy were not considered measurable lesions. ECOG score≤2; life expectancy 3 months; Barcelona Clinic liver cancer (BCLC) stage B or C disease; ChildPugh stage A or B disease; Adequate organ and marrow function, with neutrophil count≥1.5X10e9/L, platelet count≥75×10e9/L, AST or ALT﹤2.5×upper limit of normal (ULN), total bilirubin ＜1.5×ULN, international normalized ratio ＜1.5;normal baseline left ventricular ejection fraction_lower limit of normal for the institution. Patients with AST and ALT＜ 5 ×ULN could be recruited if total bilirubin was in the normal range. Patients had to provide signed informed consent to participate. documented allergy to platinum compounds or other study drugs; any previous OXA or DOX treatment, except adjuvant treatment ﹥12 months before random assignment; Previous liver transplantation; concomitant use of any other anticancer therapy, including interferon alfa and herbal medicine approved by the local authority to be used as anticancer medicine (except palliative radiotherapy to a nontarget lesion); CNS metastasis; Other serious illness or medical condition.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>