<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02527655</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Men on the Move Study is a randomized, controlled, feasibility study designed to address the health problem of physical inactivity in older men.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Men on the Move Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Men on the Move is a randomized, controlled, feasibility study to provide preliminary evidence of feasibility and efficacy for promoting mobility through the uptake of physical activity among men aged 65 years and older who are physically inactive. Specifically, Men on the Move will evaluate the effects of a choice-based physical activity model paired with an active transportation model. The choice-based physical activity model encourages older men to use existing community-based resources to create and implement actions plans for physical activity. It also provides ongoing face-to-face and telephone-based support from trained activity coaches. The active transportation model provides transit passes and active travel planning to promote use of transit and walking to destinations of interest. The feasibility of delivering the intervention will be assessed. Accelerometry and travel diaries will be used to measure the effects of the intervention on physical activity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Mobility Limitation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. 65 years of age and older; 2. identify as a man; 3. English speaking; and 4. demonstrate readiness for physical activity (by the PAR‐Q+ questionnaire or a letter of recommendation from their physician) 1. performed ≥75 minutes of moderate‐to‐vigourous intensity physical activity during the past week; 2. participated in any strength training in the past 3 months; 3. participated in any aerobic exercise class in the past 3 months; 4. live in a nursing home or assisted living facility; or 5. have plans to be out of town for more than 7 days during the 12‐week intervention period.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>