<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02947594</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Parenteral nutrition-associated cholestasis (PNAC) is one of the most common complications resulting from administration of parenteral nutrition in neonates. Excess intravenous intake of vegetable oil-based lipid emulsions containing phytosterols is felt to be a major contributing factor. To date, no information is available on plasma phytosterols half-lives in very-low-birth-weight (VLBW) preterm infants with PNAC. In a prospective cohort study, plasma phytosterols (campesterol, stigmasterol and sitosterol) of VLBW preterm infants with PNAC will be measured by gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS) during PN administration and also after the stop of intravenous lipid infusion. Plasma phytosterols half-lives will be calculated from the monoexponential decay curves. Blood samples will be weekly collected from 1st to 12th week of life during routine metabolic tolerance analysis or gas-analysis in order to avoid burden of additional phlebotomy. Samples will be collected in ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid-tubes and immediately centrifugated. Plasma will be stored in pyrogallol added-tubes at -20°C until analysis. Saponification reaction will be done using 5-alpha-cholestane as internal standard.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Half-life of Plasma Phytosterols in Very Low Birth Weight Preterm Infants With Parenteral Nutrition-associated Cholestasis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>24 weeks &lt; gestational age &lt; 32 weeks; 500 g ≤ birth weight &lt; 1250 g; parenteral nutrition with vegetable oilbased lipid emulsions from the first hours of life; diagnosis of cholestasis during vegetable oillipid infusion (plasma conjugated bilirubin value &gt; 1 mg/dl) parental consent; severe malformations; inborn errors of metabolism; severe congenital sepsis; normal liver functions (plasma conjugated bilirubin under 1 mg/dl during vegetable oillipid infusion).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>24 Weeks</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>32 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>