<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02947880</DOC>
	<brief_summary>During a previous therapeutic trial, investigators showed that the bumetanide improved significantly autism. This trial showed that a therapeutic response was obtained in 75% of cases. These first results were reinforced by a study led with adult patients for whom the eye tracking measurements as well as the functional MRI showed a diminution of the response time and a modification (amplification) of the cerebral response during an emotions recognition test. Finally, investigators confirmed the physiological mechanism behind the action of the bumetanide in a study in two mouse models of autism.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Efficiency of Treatment by BUMETANIDE on Autistic Children With a Known Ethiology</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bumetanide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children and teenager from age 5 to age 17, with a diagnosis of typical autism or Asperger syndrome according to the criteria of diagnosis of the WHO's classification (CIM10), With a known etiology, Patients for whom the CARS results are strictly Superior or equal to 30, Of whom the parents have given their free, informed and written consent, Affiliated or beneficiary of the French social security. Patients under treatment by inlet diuretic either at the time of the study or before, Patients with electrolytic disorders, Patients with a known hypersensitivity to sulfa drugs, Patients with a hepatic or renal failure, Patients with an epilepsy not controlled by a treatment (comitial crisis in the past 6 month at the time the trial starts despite a treatment), Patients under treatment by psychotropic exception made of the melatonin, Allergy to the bumetanide or one of its excipients, Patient under a treatment by lithium, diphemanil, erythromycin IV, halofantrine, pentamidine, sultopride, vincamine, aminoglycoside, Pregnant and lactating women. Secondary exclusion criteria: QT prolongation noticed on the ECG at Day0, Anomaly on the biological check up (Day 0) made before including the patient that would contraindicated the prescription of bumetanide, Patients for whom the CARS results are strictly inferior to 30.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>autism, Bumetanide</keyword>
</DOC>