<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02947438</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is aimed to comprehensively establish the bio-similarity/bioequivalence in EPIAO® and EPREX® in terms of 52-week comparisons in efficacy, safety and immunogenicity. The targeted population is anaemia patients with end-stage chronic renal disease who previously received epoetin treatment and on haemodialysis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Biosimilar Erythropoietin in Anaemia Treatment (Maintenance Phase Study)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, randomized, double blind, parallel group two arm study to establish the therapeutic equivalence, safety and tolerability of EPIAO® as compared to EPREX® in the treatment of CKD related anaemia in subjects who are on haemodialysis. A total of 264 subjects will be randomized into two groups in a 1:1 ratio. Treatment arm A will receive EPIAO® 1-3 times a week, intravenously for period of 52 weeks and treatment arm B will receive EPREX, 1-3 times a week, intravenously for period of 52 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female subjects between the age of 18 to 75 years Subjects with end stage renal disease (CKD stage 5) on hemodialysis and on epoetin treatment for at least 3 months prior to screening Subjects with haemoglobin between 10 g/dl to 12 g/dl Subjects who are on clinically stable haemodialysis (defined as no clinically relevant changes of dialysis regimen and/or dialyzer) for at least 3 months prior to screening Subjects willing to provide a written informed consent Subjects with serum ferritin ≥ 200 μg/L and/or transferrin saturation ≥ 20% Subjects with a life expectancy of more than at least study period in clinical judgment of the investigator Subjects with anaemia due to other reasons (that is not renal anaemia) Subjects who have undergone blood transfusion within the last 3 months Subjects with major complication such as severe/chronic infections or bleeding or aluminum toxicity Subjects with suspected or known pure red cell aplasia (PRCA) Subjects with a history of aplastic anaemia Subjects with uncontrolled diabetes (fasting blood glucose &gt; 240 mg/dl) or uncontrolled hypertension (systolic blood pressure &gt; 180 mm Hg, diastolic blood pressure &gt; 110 mm Hg) Subjects with known hypersensitivity to any of the ingredients of the investigational products, the mammalian cellderived product or human albumin products Subjects with history of seizure disorder Subjects with hematological disorder Subjects with hyperparathyroidism Subjects with congestive heart failure and/or angina (NYHA class III and IV) Subjects with myocardial infarction or stroke in the preceding 6 months of screening Subjects with active malignancy in the previous 5 years Subjects with gastrointestinal bleeding in the past 6 months Subjects with immunosuppressive therapy in the previous 3 months Subjects with active hepatitis B virus (HBsAg) (positive for HBsAg and IgM antiHBc) and hepatitis C virus (HCV) (positive for AntiHCV antibody) and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) Female subjects who are pregnant, breastfeeding, planning to be pregnant during the study, or women of childbearing potential (any woman who is not surgically sterile i.e. bilateral tubal ligation, total hysterectomy or &lt; 2 years post menopause) not using a reliable method of double contraception (e.g. condom plus diaphragm, condom or diaphragm plus spermicidal gel/foam, tubal ligation, or stable dose of hormonal contraception) throughout the study period Subjects participating in trials involving erythropoietin in the past 6 months before screening.Subjects currently participating or participation in an investigational study within 30 days prior screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Renal anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Haemodialysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Maintenance phase</keyword>
</DOC>