<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02974738</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to identify the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of PT2977 Tablets and/or the recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D) of PT2977 Tablets in patients with advanced solid tumors</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Trial of PT2977 Tablets In Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Part 1A: This is a Phase 1, multiple-dose, dose-escalation trial of PT2977 Tablets, where patients with advanced solid tumors will be assigned to sequential dose cohorts. Patient safety will be monitored with frequent physical examinations, vital sign measurements, electrocardiograms (ECGs), and hematology and chemistry laboratory studies, and by recording all adverse events (AEs). Blood will be obtained for analysis of the concentration of PT2977 and to assess biomarkers. Part 1B: Once the MTD and/or the RP2D is achieved, and expansion cohort of 25 patients with advanced clear cell renal cell carcinoma (ccRCC) will be enrolled. Part 2: After determination of the MTD/RP2D, up to 25 patients with other specified solid tumors may be enrolled. Up to 3 different tumor types may be included in this part of the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma, Clear Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Has a diagnosis of locally advanced or metastatic solid tumor Is of age ≥ 18 years Has a life expectancy of ≥ 3 months Has adequate organ function If a female patient, must be surgically sterile, postmenopausal, or must agree to use physicianapproved method of birth control during the study and for a minimum of 30 days after the last study drug administration, or if a male patient with a female partner, must agree to use physicianapproved method of birth control during the study and for a minimum of 30 days after the last study drug administration Able to swallow oral medications Has a history of untreated brain metastasis or history of leptomeningeal disease or spinal cord compression Has failed to recover from the reversible effects of prior anticancer therapy Has uncontrolled or poorly controlled hypertension Has malabsorption due to prior gastrointestinal (GI) surgery or GI disease Has had any major cardiovascular event within 6 months prior to study drug administration Has any other clinically significant cardiac, respiratory, or other medical or psychiatric condition that might interfere with participation in the trial or interfere with the interpretation of trial results Has had major surgery within 4 weeks before first study drug administration Has known HIV Has an active infection requiring systemic treatment Is participating in another therapeutic clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>