<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02974166</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether osteopathic manipulative treatment associated to Dentistry care and speech therapy improves pain and function in individuals with temporomandibular disorders.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Analysis of the Effects of the Osteopathic Manipulative Treatment in Carriers of Temporomandibular Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A standardized TMD examination was executed in all patients by a dentist following the Research Diagnostic Criteria for Temporomandibular Disorders (RDC/ TMD) questionnaire, Axis I and II, portuguese version. The RDC/ TMD is compound by a 31 items questionnaire and a ten items clinical exam. All these items are related to patients symptoms and signs; to mandibular functional impairment; and social-demographics, social-economics, psychological e psychosocial data. The first part as Axis I tend to clinical assess and classify the TMD and the second, as Axis II propose a chronic pain score that could quantify the psychosocial impairment and present a subjects profile. Others assessment instruments utilized on the research were the VAS consists in a 10 cm horizontal line with "no pain" on the left side and "worst pain" on right side, then the subjects were instructed to vertical risk the level of pain. The digital caliper with a 0,03 mm precision was used to measure the maximal mouth opening (MMO) as the maximal inter-incisal vertical distance of the incisors. The subjects were seated at 90° with neutral head position and solicited to open their mouths the maximum they can unassisted and without pain, maximum unassisted opening and maximum assisted opening. Also, a portable digital pressure algometer for measuring sensitivity to pressure before it became painful. The masseters and temporalis muscles trigger point location were used as reference to guarantee the reproducibility of the proceeding as well as to assess the always the same site. The statistical analysis was performed using the means comparisons for the parametric tests through Student T test and for the non-parametrical data, Wilcoxon. Also, it was made the descriptive statistical with frequencies analysis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temporomandibular Joint Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temporomandibular Joint Dysfunction Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ibuprofen</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclobenzaprine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amitriptyline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>subjects of both genders with TMD diagnosed and minimum pain intensity of 40 mm on a visual analogue scale (VAS) who need dental treatment. continuous use of analgesic medication, mouth opening above 40 mm, presence of any other orofacial pain not related to TMD and being under orthodontic or TMD treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Temporomandibular Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Osteopathic Manipulative Treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Rigid Splint</keyword>
	<keyword>Speech Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>