<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02974725</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To characterize safety and tolerability of LXH254 and LTT462 combination and identify a recommended dose and regimen.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of LXH254 and LTT462 in NSCLC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have advanced or metastatic NSCLC Presence of KRAS or BRAF mutation in tumor tissue All patients participating in this clinical trial must have progressed following standard therapy or, in the opinion of the Investigator, no effective standard therapy exists, is tolerated, appropriate or is considered equivalent to study treatment. ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) performance status ≤ 2 Dose expansion Group 1: Prior treatment with a RAFi (including any BRAFi and panRAFi), MEKi and/or ERKi. Group 2: Prior treatment with an ERKi and/or a panRAFi. History or current evidence of retinal vein occlusion (RVO) or current risk factors for RVO. Any medical condition that would, in the investigator's judgment, prevent the patient's participation in the clinical study due to safety concerns or compliance with clinical study procedures. Patients receiving proton pump inhibitors (PPI) which cannot be discontinued 3 days prior to the start study treatment and for the duration of the study. Patients with Gilbert's syndrome or other heritable diseases of bile processing. Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
	<keyword>KRAS</keyword>
	<keyword>BRAF</keyword>
	<keyword>LXH254</keyword>
	<keyword>LTT462</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-small cell lung carcinoma (NSCLC)</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment of lung cancer after first metastasis</keyword>
	<keyword>lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>lung adenocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Large-cell lung carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Non small cell lung carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Non small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Large cell lung carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Large cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell lung carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>