<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02974530</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The oropharyngeal junction participates in 3 interpenetrating functions: Swallowing, Breathing and Speech. In the context of ischemic or hemorrhagic stroke, these are altered, isolated or associated manner, causing major disorders and representing a source of handicap for patients. Understanding the swallowing mechanisms is therefore a major challenge to guide the rehabilitation and improve the initial and long-term prognosis of patients with stroke. The main objective of this study is to describe and modeling, thanks to a clinical, physiological and radiological knowledge base, swallowing, speech and breathing, in patients with stroke and in healthy subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Description and Modeling of Swallowing Disorders After a Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deglutition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For patients after stroke First stroke confirmed by MRI &lt; 15 days No severe leukoaraiosis Swallowing disorders identified (GUSS scale &lt; 20) Neurological deficit identified (NIHSS scale &lt;15) Patient able to cooperate for investigations Informed consent signed Cerebral hemorrhage History of neurological disease that can lead to swallowing disorders History of laryngological disease such as previous surgery or radiation neck Tracheotomy Vigilance disorders Pregnant, parturient or nursing woman Protected adult Simultaneous participation in another study Non registered to the French social security system For healthy subjects Inclusion Criteria : Age between 18 and 40 years old French native speaker Normal hearing with or without corrective No oral or written language disorders No neurological or psychiatric disorders Informed consent signed Exclusion Criteria MRI contraindication Pregnant, parturient or nursing woman Simultaneous participation in another study Non registered to the French social security system</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>