<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01281787</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to assess whether prophylactic treatment with metoprolol or losartan is able to reduce the incidence of atrial fibrillation (AF) in patients undergoing thoracic surgery for lung cancer, showing elevated plasma levels in NT probrain natriuretic peptide (NT-proBNP), measured in the perioperative period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PREvention of Atrial Fibrillation in patientS Undergoing thorAcic surGEry for Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Postoperative atrial fibrillation is one of the most common complication after thoracic surgery for lung cancer, with an incidence ranging from 8 to 20% after lobectomy and up to 42% after pneumonectomy. In a recent study we demonstrated that a high perioperative plasma levels of NT-proBNP is able to identify patients at risk for AF (incidence of 65%). It has also been demonstrated that the renin-angiotensin system may play an important role in the pathophysiology of atrial fibrillation and that angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors (ACEI) and angiotensin II receptor blockers (ARBs) are able to prevent atrial fibrillation in patients with heart failure, after myocardial infarction, in hypertensive patients and after electrical cardioversion.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metoprolol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Losartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiotensin II</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiotensin-Converting Enzyme Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients of both sexes with age ≥ 18 years Thoracic surgery for lung cancer Evidence of elevated perioperative NTproBNP Written informed consent Hypersensitivity and / or intolerance to metoprolol or losartan History of heart failure Left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;50% measured by echocardiographic techniques (Simpson rule) Permanent atrial fibrillation Antiarrhythmic therapy Current therapy with betablockers, angiotensin II receptor blockers and angiotensinconverting enzyme inhibitors Systolic blood pressure &lt;95 mmHg Pregnant and lactating women Additional exclusion criteria for therapy with betablocker: History of sick sinus syndrome, evidence of AVblock grade II or greater Heart rate &lt;65 b / m History of bronchial asthma, severe bronchopneumopathy, evidence of bronchospasm</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>FAP= post-surgery atrial fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>ACEI= angiotensin converting enzyme-inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>ARBs= angiotensin II receptor blockers</keyword>
	<keyword>NT-proBNP= brain natriuretic peptide</keyword>
</DOC>