<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01281397</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Use of whole blood impedance aggregometry and rotational thromboelastometry can reveal useful data about platelet function and viscoelastic properties of blood clot in patients undergoing cardiac surgery. The purpose of this study is to clarify whether it is possible to predict patients on excessive risk of perioperative bleeding using whole blood impedance aggregometry and rotational thromoelastometry. Antiplatelet therapy is the cornerstone in treatment of patients with coronary artery disease. Another research goal is to determine the degree of response to antiplatelet therapy before and after surgery and to investigate whether patients by level of response to antiplatelet therapy before surgery have a higher risk of perioperative bleeding.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bleeding Prediction in Patients Following Cardiac Surgery Using Whole Blood Aggregometry and Thromboelastometry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. &gt; 18 years old 2. Elective cardiac surgery patients 3. Coronary artery disease 4. Aortic valve disease 5. Mitral valve disease 6. Ascendent aorta aneurysm 7. Combine coronary and valve disease 8. Cardiac surgery procedures using cardiopulmonary bypass 1. Missing consent 2. Patients with emergent cardiac surgical procedures 3. Patients on antiplatelet therapy other than aspirin or clopidogrel 4. Patients with inaccurate antiplatelet therapy administration documentation 5. Missing data 6. Offpump procedures 7. Patients younger than 18 years old 8. Patients with severe mental disorders 9. Intrinsic coagulopathy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>cardiac surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>aggregometry</keyword>
	<keyword>thromboelastometry</keyword>
	<keyword>platelet function</keyword>
	<keyword>bleeding</keyword>
	<keyword>antiplatelet therapy</keyword>
</DOC>