<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00154232</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to assess the short-term benefit of the combination of basiliximab, EC-MPS and cyclosporine microemulsion with C2 monitoring on the prophylaxis of acute rejection in a population of de novo renal transplant patients at potential high risk of DGF.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Combination of Enteric-coated Mycophenolate Sodium (EC-MPS), Basiliximab, and C2-monitored Cyclosporine in de Novo Renal Transplant Recipients at Potential High Risk of Delayed Graft Function (DGF)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Delayed Graft Function</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Basiliximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1870 years old Patients receiving a primary or secondary cadaveric or living donor kidney Patients who have given written informed consent for study participation Females capable of becoming pregnant must have a negative pregnancy test at baseline and are required to practice birth control for the duration of the study and at least for four months following the last dose of basiliximab. Recipient of multiorgan transplants or previously transplanted organs other than kidney Recipient of dual kidney transplants Recipient of a transplanted kidney from a NonHeart Beating Donor (NHBD) Recipient of a HLA identical livingdonor kidney Patients with a PRA level (past or current level) greater than 20% Patients anticipated by investigators to require induction therapy with OKT3, ATGAM, or Thymoglobulin for any reason Patients with any medical condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, would preclude the patient from participating in the study Cold ischemia time larger than 36 hours. Patients who have received an investigational drug or therapy within one month prior to study entry or if such therapy is to be instituted posttransplantation. Female transplant candidates who are pregnant, lactating, or of childbearing potential and not willing to practice an acceptable method of contraception Patients with a known hypersensitivity to cyclosporine Patients with a known malignancy or a history of malignancy, other than successfully treated nonmetastatic basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin Known HIV positive antibody status Evidence of any clinically relevant (per investigator determination) active infection Patients unable to participate in the study for the full 3month study period Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Renal transplantation, DGF, basiliximab, EC-MPS, cyclosporine</keyword>
</DOC>