<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00871728</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the participants with toenail onychomycosis (fungal infection of the nail) confirmed positive by potassium hydroxide (KOH) and bacterial identification test after administration of itraconazole (ICZ) capsule, to identify the change in Scoring Clinical Index for Onychomycosis (SCIO) score and to determine the relationship between the change of SCIO score and mycological cure rate and clinical improvement.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Scoring Clinical Index For Onychomycosis in Toenail Onychomycosis Treating With Itraconazole Capsules</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label (all people know the identity of the intervention), multicenter (when more than one hospital or medical school team work on a medical research study) study of ICZ in participants with onychomycosis. The present study consists of 2 periods: Screening period (up to Week minus 2) and Treatment period (up to Week 49). The ICZ will be administered in 3 cycles (Week 1, Week 5 and Week 9) and each cycle will consist of taking 2 capsules of 100 milligram (mg) each, orally, twice daily, continuously for 1 week. Total duration of treatment will be of 49 weeks. Efficacy will primarily be evaluated by percentage of participants showing 10 percent or higher response in SCIO Score. Participants' safety will be monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Onychomycosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Itraconazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxyitraconazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Onychomycosis participants whose etiologic agent is identified by potassium hydroxide (KOH) smear and bacterial identification test Participants with Scoring Clinical Index for Onychomycosis (SCIO) greater than or equal to 9 Participants who are healthy in general in following items: medical and medication history, physical examination before administration time, vital signs (blood pressure and pulse) and clinical laboratory tests (clinical test results [liver function and renal function] are within 2 times the normal range) Female participants of childbearing age who use acceptable contraceptives Participants who can understand features of clinical study and signed informed consent form Participants with psoriasis (scaly skin rash) Diabetic participants who take an antidiabetic drug Pregnant or breast feeding female participants Participants with clinical evidence of arterial insufficiency or peripheral vascular disease and medical history of decreased ventricular function like congestive heart failure (heterogeneous condition in which the heart is unable to pump out sufficient blood to meet the metabolic need of the body) Participants who applied a topical antifungal agent (nail lacquer) on target nail within 1 month before the study medication administration and who took an oral antifungal agent within 3 month before the study medication administration</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Onychomycosis, Toe</keyword>
	<keyword>Itraconazole</keyword>
	<keyword>Sporanox</keyword>
</DOC>