<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02979743</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to explore the relationship between brain MRI-metrics and hand function observed in children with cerebral palsy (CP),compared between baseline and the third month, and thus determine the early MRI-based neuroimaging predictor of clinical improvement following therapy in children with CP.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>MRI-based Neuroimaging Predictors of Clinical Improvements Following Therapy in Children With Cerebral Palsy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cerebral palsy (CP) is the commonest cause of neurological disability in children. The upper limbs are often affected, with significant hand involvement from an early age.There are various methods of treatment for CP children with hand function disability. However, there is a lack of effective methods to predict the prognosis. This prospective cohort study will include children with occupational therapy (OT) or OT plus acupuncture and massage methods. Children with CP will be evaluated in terms of upper limb motor function using the manual ability classification system (MACS), fine motor function measure (FMFM). The Brain injuries of Children will be evaluated by MRI. The aim of this study is to explore the relationship between brain MRI-metrics and hand function, compared between baseline and the third month, and thus determine the early MRI-based neuroimaging predictors of clinical improvements following therapy in children with CP.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paralysis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Palsy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injury, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: 318 years Spastic cerebral palsy The complete clinical and MRI data previous acupuncture and massage methods botulinum toxin upper limb injections braces artifact, excessive motion, afraid to enter the MRI parents were not interested in the MRI sessions</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>