<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02979483</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study assessed the feasibility and effects of an early integrative supportive care program in patient with Advanced pancreatic adenocarcinoma (aPDAC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Management of Symptomatic Advanced Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Two-step cohort study: * Step 1 : A 14-day integrative supportive care program initiated as early as the clinical suspicion of aPDAC. According to the investigator's assessment of patient needs, this integrative supportive care program will include: - management of pain - nutritional support - pathologic diagnosis (endoscopy guides or percutaneous biopsies or ascitis cytology) - diagnostic computed imaging - endoscopic stenting of the bile duct and/or duodenum * Step 2 : Follow up after the integrative supportive care program. According to their Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status(ECOG PS) and/or chemotherapy - Group 1 : Patient becoming eligible for treatment with FOLFIRINOX or nab-paclitaxel + gemcitabine and / or clinical trial - Group 2 :Patient at the end of the 14-day program (Step 1) remaining with either : a - Persisting ECOG PS ≥ 2 b - Clinico-biological features that make them ineligible to receive the FOLFIRINOX or nab-paclitaxel + gemcitabine regimens c - Patient ineligible to other therapeutic clinical trial</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria STEP 1: 1. Pathologically confirmed or highly suspected aPDAC defined as a pancreatic mass on imaging, suspected distant metastases, no features suggestive of a neuroendocrine tumor, and/or clinicobiological abnormalities compatible with the diagnosis of aPDAC, 2. Age ≥ 18 years, 3. Patients with ECOG PS ≥ 2 and clinicobiological features precluding initial therapeutic clinical trial and/or treatment with FOLFIRINOX or gemcitabine + nabpaclitaxel, 4. No prior history of cancer, except: in situ breast, cervix cancer, or basal cell carcinoma and/or complete remission for more than 3 years from another cancer. 5. Registration in France with the French National Health Care System (CMU included) 6. Patient able to comply with study protocol requirements in the view of the investigator, 7. Before patient registration, written informed consent must be obtained according to ICH/GCP and national/local regulations, 8. Patients requiring at least two components of the integrative care program (pain management, nutritional management, pathological assessment or imaging, and endoscopy/stent). Exclusion Criteria STEP 1 : 1. Any medical, psychological, familial, sociological, or geographical condition potentially hampering compliance with the study protocol and followup schedule; those conditions should be discussed with the patient before registration in the trial, 2. Patient protected by law, 3. Pregnant or breast feeding women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>