<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02979574</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare two types of acupuncture with usual care on treating chronic pain. This study has three groups. Two groups will received acupuncture. One group will receive usual standard of care for 12 weeks and then will receive acupuncture. Acupuncture is an ancient Chinese technique of using very thin needles inserted in the skin to treat different symptoms and illness, and to promote healing. Each group will undergo a different method of needle administration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PEACE: Comparing Chronic Pain Treatment Options</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibromyalgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>English speaking Age &gt;/= 18 years or older Having musculoskeletal pain, defined as regional (joints, extremities, back, neck) or more generalized (fibromyalgia or chronic widespread pain) Having a pain rating of 4 or greater in worst pain on a 110 numerical rating scale in the preceding week (Patients with a neuropathic component to their pain that involves the extremities or back will be eligible) Having had pain for at least 3 months and at least 15 days with pain in the preceding 30 days A diagnosis of cancer with no restrictions placed on type of cancer, other than that patients with metastatic disease will be excluded. Eligibility criteria are not restricted to MSK confirmed biopsy/diagnosis. Participating institution's testing is sufficient for other study sites. Complete active treatment (surgery, chemotherapy, and/or radiotherapy) at least one month prior to study initiation (patients on continued hormone treatment will not be excluded). Have nonmusculoskeletal pain syndromes (headache, facial pain, chest pain, visceral abdominal pain) if these are the sole source of pain, but can be present as comorbid conditions as long as a patient has a primary musculoskeletal pain condition defined s above. Inflammatory arthritis that require disease modifying drugs (e.g. rheumatoid arthritis) Phantom limb pain Metastatic cancer Have a pending painrelated VA or social security or worker's comp disability claim by selfreport Patients on maintenance targeted therapies</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>acupuncture</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic pain</keyword>
	<keyword>pain management</keyword>
	<keyword>16-1579</keyword>
</DOC>