<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01949480</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall purpose of this research study is to compare the effectiveness of ultrasound assisted paravertebral block placement versus traditional "blind" technique for postoperative analgesia following thoracotomy or visually assisted thoracoscopic surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ultrasound-Assisted Paravertebral Block v. Traditional Paravertebral Block For Pain Control</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this project is to determine if there is a difference between paravertebral block performed with ultrasound assistance and paravertebral block performed with traditional technique in terms of twenty - four hour hydromorpone (dilaudid) consumption and visual analogue pain scores at rest or with deep breathing at twenty - four hours. This study will determine if ultrasound technique used for placement of paravertebral catheter facilitates safety of paravertebral catheterization and improves therapeutic effect of paravertebral blockade for pain control after thoracotomy. The investigators will also examine if ultrasound assisted paravertebral blockade improves pulmonary status in post-thoracotomy patient.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Acute Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. ASA IIII subjects 2. Ages 1875 years 3. BMI &lt; 40 4. Scheduled for elective thoracic surgery at UPMC Passavant and Shadyside Hospitals in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania 5. Patients willing and able to provide informed consent 1) Age younger than 18 years or older than 75 years (2) Any contraindication to the placement of unilateral thoracic paravertebral catheter, including local infection, hypocoaguable state. (3) American Society of Anesthesiologists physical status IV or greater (4) chronic painful conditions (5) preoperative opioid use (6) coagulation abnormalities or patients who are expected to be on therapeutic anticoagulants postoperatively (7) allergy to lidocaine, ropivacaine or bupivacaine (8) personal or family history of malignant hyperthermia (9) serum creatinine greater than 1.4 g/dl (10) pregnancy or lactating.The pregnancy status will be determined by history and prior pregnancy testing when appropriate (11) having an altered mental status (not oriented to place, person, or time) or emergency surgery (12) comorbid conditions such as sepsis, unstable angina, congestive heart failure, moderate to severe valvular heart disease, severe COPD (13) patient's inability to provide adequate informed consent (14) patient refusal to nerve blocks and/or participation in the study (15) respiratory support via ventilator post (16) non English speaking (17) allergy to contrast of iodine (18) emergency surgery or any other nonelective procedure (19) unstable vertebral and tranverse process fractures</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Peripheral nerve block</keyword>
	<keyword>Ultrasound guidance</keyword>
	<keyword>Postoperative pain management post status thoracotomy</keyword>
	<keyword>Postoperative pain management post status VATS</keyword>
</DOC>