<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01500018</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a single dose, crossover study to assess the abuse potential of TC-5214 compared to placebo, ketamine, and phentermine in healthy recreational polydrug users.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study in Healthy Recreational Polydrug Users to Measure the Abuse Potential of TC-5214</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Single-center, Single-dose, Double-blind, Randomized, Placebo- and Active-controlled Crossover Study to Evaluate the Abuse Potential of TC-5214 in Healthy Recreational Polydrug Users.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phentermine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Current recreational polydrug users with experience with at least 2 drug classes of abuse. At least 10 lifetime uses of stimulants drugs (eg, amphetamine, cocaine, methamphetamine) and 10 lifetime occasions of recreational use of psychedelic drugs (eg, cannabis, ketamine, dextromethorphan, PCP, MDMA [ecstasy], LSD, mesacline, or psilocybin). Recreational use of other classes of drugs is permitted, including opioids (eg, codeine, morphine, or heroin), minor tranquilizers, or sedatives (eg, benzodiazepines or barbiturates). Male or female volunteers aged 18 to 55, inclusive with a body mass index (BMI) within the range of 19.0 to 33.0 kg/m2, inclusive, and a minimum weight of 50.0 kg at screening. Must pass qualification phase eligibility criteria. Selfreported history of drug or alcohol dependence (except caffeine) in the past 12 months, including subjects who have ever been in a drug rehabilitation program (other than treatment for smoking cessation). Unwillingness or inability to abstain from recreational drug use for the duration of the study from screening until followup. Positive for hepatitis B, hepatitis C, or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) at screening. Any significant unstable hepatic, renal, pulmonary, cardiovascular, ophthalmologic, neurologic, or any other medical conditions that might confound the study or put the volunteer at greater risk during study participation. Currently smoking more than 20 cigarettes (or 2 cigars) per day, and/or unwillingness to abstain from smoking for durations of at least 12 hours. Use of tobacco cessation product within 1 month (eg, nicotine substitution products, bupropion, etc).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Phase I</keyword>
	<keyword>healthy recreational polydrug users</keyword>
	<keyword>abuse liability</keyword>
	<keyword>TC-5214</keyword>
	<keyword>Single dose crossover study to evaluate the abuse potential of TC-5214</keyword>
</DOC>