<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01771965</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this research plan is to test the effectiveness of a brief, cognitive behavioral (CB) intervention to promote behavioral health treatment engagement among at-risk Veterans who call the Crisis Line but are resistant to behavioral health services.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Increasing Treatment Seeking Among Suicidal Veterans Calling the Crisis Line</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The goal of this research plan is to test the effectiveness of a brief, cognitive behavioral (CB) intervention to promote behavioral health treatment engagement among at-risk Veterans who call the Crisis Line but are resistant to behavioral health services. This randomized controlled trial will recruit 80 Veterans who report current suicidal ideation at the time of the Crisis Line call and are resistant to seeking behavioral health treatment. Half of the participants will receive the brief, individualized CB intervention and half will receive standardized procedures from VA's Crisis Line (i.e., usual care). The effectiveness of the intervention will be tested on 1) attitudes toward behavioral health treatment rates, and 2) initiation of and adherence to treatment (assessed by the number of sessions attended). The investigators will also assess the impact of the intervention on suicidal ideation (SI) and explore the impact on the most common symptoms observed in Veteran suicide decedents (e.g., depression).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Suicide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for the study are as follows: individuals 18 and older who call the Veteran Crisis Line have a phone number where they can be reached, be it a land line or a cell phone deemed by the Crisis Line responder to be at risk for suicide, but not imminent risk refuse a referral to the SPC or to a behavioral health treatment provider during the call report current suicidal ideation (SI) during the call based on administration of a standard item have not been in behavioral health treatment in the past. Presence of SI will be subsequently confirmed by the research assistant using the Columbia Suicide Severity Rating Scale, a validated instrument. Exclusion criteria are being judged by the Crisis Line responder to show: debilitating cognitive impairment active psychosis or mania acute alcohol or drug intoxication</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>