<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01763359</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this prospective study is to compare hip adductor strength and obturator nerve palsy between acetabular fracture patients whose fracture was reduced and fixated using the modified Stoppa approach (subjects) and pelvic fracture patients (controls) using physical strength testing, radiographs, clinical assessment, and a validated functional outcome questionnaire. The investigators' research hypothesis is that there will be less strength and higher incidence of obturator nerve palsy in patients treated with the modified Stoppa approach (intervention) than in patients treated without the modified Stoppa approach (controls).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hip Strength and Nerve Palsy After the Modified Stoppa Approach to Acetabular Fracture Reduction and Fixation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for the subject patient population under study consists of male and female adults, at least 18 years old, who had an acetabular fracture that was treated with the modified Stoppa approach. Inclusion criteria for the control patient population under study consists of male and female adults, at least 18 years old, who had acetabular fractures with similar fracture patterns as the study group that were treated with any other approach than the Stoppa approach. Exclusion criteria for the subject and control patient population consist of: Patients who are nonambulatory. Patients less than 18 years of age. Patients who do not speak English. Patients who are unable to complete their followup in Utah.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>acetabular fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>pelvic fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>hip adductor strength</keyword>
	<keyword>obturator nerve palsy</keyword>
	<keyword>modified Stoppa approach</keyword>
</DOC>