<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02465866</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will compare the relative bioavailability of hydrocodone, acetaminophen, and promethazine in CL-108 (hydrocodone 7.5mg/ acetaminophen 325 mg/ promethazine 12.5 mg) manufactured by Charleston Laboratories, Inc. to hydrocodone in Vicoprofen (hydrocodone 7.5 mg /ibuprofen 200 mg), promethazine 12.5 mg, and acetaminophen in Ultracet (tramadol HCl 37.5 mg/acetaminophen 325 mg) under fasted and fed conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Four-Period, Four-Treatment, Four-Way Relative Bioavailability Study of CL-108 Under Fed and Fasted Conditions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hydrocodone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diphenhydramine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Promethazine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent Subject's body mass index (BMI) must be between 18 and 30kg/m2 (inclusive), and subject must weigh a minimum of 50 kg (110lb) Abide by study restrictions Acceptable birth control measures Ability to attend all study visits Vital signs as per protocol Willing to consume high calorie meals within designated time frame Clinically significant medical history Clinically significant abnormal findings History or presence of allergic or adverse response to hydrocodone, ibuprofen,acetaminophen, any nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), promethazine, or related drugs. Has smoked or used tobacco products within 60 days prior to the first dose of study medication Has donated blood or plasma within 30 days prior to the first dose of study medication Has participated in another clinical trial (randomized subjects only) within 30 days prior to the first dose of study medication.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Plasma concentration</keyword>
	<keyword>Time to plasma concentration</keyword>
	<keyword>Elimination rate constant</keyword>
	<keyword>Elimination half life</keyword>
	<keyword>Area under the curve</keyword>
</DOC>