<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01561313</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will compare injection site pain levels between current Humira® formulation versus a new formulation of Humira in patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA), who are either currently on a stable dose (minimum six consecutive doses) of on-label Humira or biological naïve who will be prescribed on-label Humira as treatment for their Rheumatoid Arthritis. The study is being conducted in two countries, Belgium (3 sites) and the Czech Republic (3 sites).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Crossover Study of Safety and Tolerability of Two Formulations of Adalimumab.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>64 participants were randomized, 63 received at least one dose of the study drug, and 62 participants were analyzed for injection site-related pain. 63 participants were analyzed for other safety analyses. Two participants, who were randomized to the Current formulation adalimumab/New formulation of adalimumab arm of the study were excluded from the analysis of injection site-related pain. One participant received one dose of study drug and discontinued because of an adverse event, while the other discontinued before receiving any study drug.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subject age 18 years or older, who requires Humira 40 mg SC every other week (eow) or every week (ew) for the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis, in accordance with the local Humira label. Subject must be a current, onlabel user of Humira who rates his/her average Humira injection site related pain as at least 3 cm on a pain Visual Analogue Scale and has had at least 6 consecutive doses of Humira prior to Screening, or a biologic naïve subject who requires initiation of onlabel treatment with Humira. Subject has diagnosis of rheumatoid arthritis (RA) as defined by the 1987 revised ACR classification criteria or the ACR/EULAR 2010 criteria, Female subjects are either not of childbearing potential, defined as postmenopausal for at least 1 year or surgically sterile (bilateral tubal ligation, bilateral oophorectomy and/or hysterectomy), or are practicing at least one method of birth control throughout the study and for at least 70 days after the last dose of study drug. All female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative test for pregnancy on a serum sample at Screening and prior to study drug dosing on a urine sample obtained at Visit 1. Subject has been treated with any investigational drug of a chemical or biologic nature within a minimum of 30 days or 5 halflives (whichever is longer) of the drug prior to Visit 1. Any infection(s) requiring treatment with intravenous (IV) antiinfectives within 30 days prior to Visit 1 or oral antiinfectives within 14 days prior to Visit 1. Prior exposure to natalizumab (Tysabri®) or efalizumab (Raptiva®). Known hypersensitivity to adalimumab or its excipients. History of demyelinating disease (including myelitis) or neurologic symptoms suggestive of demyelinating disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>On label Humira users</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Rheumatoid Arthritis,</keyword>
</DOC>