<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01732952</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This cross-sectional, non-interventional, and observational study will assess the lipid profile of patients who have been taking lipid-modifying drugs (i.e., proportion of patients achieving treatment to goal according to national and international lipid management guidelines) during a single visit to their physicians on an outpatient basis in 6 representative geo-economic regions in China: Northeast, North, East, South, Southwest, and Northwest; and within each region, in three tiers of hospitals: tier 3 (primary or teaching hospitals), tier 2 (secondary or city level hospitals), and tier 1 (community hospitals/health centers). The investigators will primarily be cardiologists, endocrinologists, neurologists, gerontologists, internists, or other physicians who are representative of the general population of physicians managing patients with dyslipidemia and/or at high risk for cardiovascular events likely to be treated with lipid-modifying drugs. Demographic data, cardiovascular risk factors, a history of cardiovascular disease and cardiovascular treatments will be documented in a single visit through patient clinical examination and chart review. DYSIS-China is part of a string of epidemiological studies that share the same master protocol, which has been conducted in different countries mainly in Europe and Canada. The analysis of the pooled studies including overall data and cross-country comparisons is the subject of a distinct protocol.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dyslipidemia International Survey-China</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Congenital Abnormalities</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyslipidemias</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patient is an outpatient &gt; 45 years of age 2. Patient is currently* treated with a statin 3. Patient has a documented fasting lipid profile (&gt; 1 lipid parameter within the last 12 months) performed while on lipidmodifying therapy for at least 3 months 4. Patient agrees to participate in the study by giving informed consent. Patient is already being treated with a lipidmodifying drug just before the visit. Patient for whom a lipidmodifying therapy is initiated at the time of the visit must not be included. 1. Patient is currently participating in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>the prevalence,lipid abnormalities,CV risks</keyword>
</DOC>