<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02933489</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized phase II trial studies how well abbreviated breast magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and digital tomosynthesis mammography work in detecting cancer in women with dense breast. Abbreviated breast MRI is a low cost procedure in which radio waves and a powerful magnet linked to a computer and used to create detailed pictures of the breast in less than 10 minutes. These pictures can show the difference between normal and diseased tissue. Digital tomosynthesis mammography is a procedure that uses multiple x-rays pictures of each breast to produce a 3-dimensional rendering of the entire breast. Combined screening with abbreviated breast MRI and digital tomosynthesis mammography may be a better method to screen women with dense breasts.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Abbreviated Breast MRI and Digital Tomosynthesis Mammography in Screening Women With Dense Breasts</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To compare the rates of detection of invasive cancers with abbreviated breast (AB)-magnetic resonance (MR) and digital tomosynthesis mammography (DBT). SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To compare the positive predictive value (PPV) of biopsies, call back rates, and short-term follow up rates after AB-MR and DBT on both the initial and 1 year follow up studies. II. To estimate and compare the sensitivity and specificity of AB-MR and DBT, using the 1 year follow up to define a reference standard. III. To compare patient-reported short-term quality of life related to diagnostic testing with AB-MR and DBT using the Testing Morbidities Index. IV. To compare willingness to return for testing with AB-MRI versus (vs) DBT within the recommended screening interval and explore factors associated with willingness to return for screening. V. To compare the tumor biologies of invasive cancers and ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) detected on AB-MR and DBT. VI. To estimate the incident cancer rate during 3 years following the year-1 AB-MR/DBT when patients return to standard screening. OUTLINE: Participants are randomized to 1 of 2 arms. ARM I (DBT, AB-MR): Participants undergo DBT followed by AB-MR for under 10 minutes on the same day at baseline and then after 1 year. ARM II (AB-MR, DBT): Participants undergo AB-MR for under 10 minutes followed by DBT on the same day at baseline and then after 1year. After completion of study, patients are followed up yearly for 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Patents must be scheduled for routine screening DBT Women must not be pregnant or breastfeeding; all females of childbearing potential must have a blood test or urine study within 2 weeks prior to randomization to rule out pregnancy; a female of childbearing potential is any woman, regardless of sexual orientation or whether they have undergone tubal ligation, who meets the following criteria: 1) has not undergone a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy; or 2) has not been naturally postmenopausal for at least 24 consecutive months (i.e., has had menses at any time in the preceding 24 consecutive months) Women of childbearing potential must be strongly advised to use an accepted and effective method of contraception or to abstain from sexual intercourse for the duration of their participation in the study Patient's breast density must be known; patients must have mammographically dense breasts (American College of Radiology [ACR] Breast Imaging [BI] Reporting and Data System Atlas [RADS] categories 3 or 4) on their mostrecent prior screening Patient must be asymptomatic for breast disease and undergoing routine screening Patient must have no known breast cancer (DCIS or invasive cancer), not currently undergoing treatment for breast cancer, or planning surgery for a high risk lesion (atypical ductal breast hyperplasia [ADH], atypical lobular breast hyperplasia [ALH], lobular breast carcinoma in situ [LCIS], papilloma, radial scar) Patient must not be taking chemoprevention for breast cancer Patient must not have undergone breast ultrasound within 12 months prior to randomization Patient must not have previously had a breast MRI Patient must agree to not undergo screening ultrasound (of breast) for the duration of the 1 year study period as screening ultrasound adds no benefit in women undergoing breast MRI Patient must not be suspected of being at highrisk for breast cancer, as defined by the American Cancer Society (ACS) breast MR screening recommendations (lifetime risk of &gt;= 2025%) Patient must be able to undergo breast MRI with contrast enhancement; patients unable to undergo breast MRI with contrast enhancement for any reason are ineligible No history of untreatable claustrophobia No presence of non MR compatible metallic objects or metallic objects that, in the opinion of the radiologist, would make MRI a contraindication No history of sickle cell disease No contraindication to intravenous contrast administration No known allergylike reaction to gadolinium or moderate or severe allergic reactions to one or more allergens as defined by the American College of Radiology (ACR); patient may be eligible if willing to undergo pretreatment as defined by the institution's policy and/or ACR guidance No known or suspected renal impairment; requirements for glomerular filtration rate (GFR) prior to MRI as determined by local site standard practice Weight lower than that allowable by the MRI table</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>