<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02933177</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In order to offer a non-drug intervention for caregivers in nursing home to respond promptly to a behavioral crisis with an appropriate response to each patient, a chariot has been developed by the Institute of Ageing Well Korian (Institut du Bien Vieillir Korian) to bring together eleven mediation activities. These activities lasting about 15 minutes are based on emotion (reminiscent, games) and sensory interventions (music, massage, touch) to decentralize patient stimulus that disturbs and focus on a subject not disruptive. This emergency intervention should provide a reduction in Behavioral and Psychological Symptom of Dementia (BPSD) of nursing home patients. The main objective is to measure its immediate effect on productive symptoms (agitation, aberrant motor behavior and disinhibition). The secondary objectives are to measure its immediate impact on the well-being and psychotropic treatments, and measure its effect after two months and after four months on all BPSD with a focus on agitation, the administration of psychotropic drugs, the hospitalizations and the number of falls.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Flash Mediation Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>People ability to object and does not oppose either by themselves or through a trusted person referred to in Article L. 11116 of the Code of Public Health, failing thereof, by the family, or, if a person talking to the person close and stable ties. For adults under guardianship, permission must be given by the legal representative of the person. The research will benefit from the backing of Persons Protection Committee (PPC) prior to its implementation; Man or woman over 60 years; patient living in one of the nursing homes participating in the project; Patient completing the diagnostic criteria for major neurocognitive disorder according to Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders V criteria (DSMV) The patient must have at least one of these productive symptoms (agitation, aberrant motor behavior, disinhibition) listed by the NPINH (score&gt; 2 at least one of these items) Deafness or blindness may compromise patient assessment or participation in the intervention</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dementia</keyword>
	<keyword>Alzheimer disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavioral and Psychological Symptoms of Dementia</keyword>
	<keyword>non-drug intervention</keyword>
</DOC>