<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02616562</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted globally. The aim of the trial is to investigate efficacy and safety of once-weekly NNC0195-0092 treatment compared to daily growth hormone treatment (Norditropin® FlexPro®) in growth hormone treatment naïve pre-pubertal children with growth hormone deficiency. The main trial period will consist of 26 weeks of treatment, followed by a 26 week extension period and a 104 weeks safety extension trial period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Investigating Efficacy and Safety of Once-weekly NNC0195-0092 Treatment Compared to Daily Growth Hormone Treatment (Norditropin® FlexPro®) in Growth Hormone Treatment naïve Pre-pubertal Children With Growth Hormone Deficiency</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Endocrine System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dwarfism, Pituitary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Boys: Tanner stage 1 for pubic hair and testis volume below 4 ml , age at least 2 years and 26 weeks and below or equal to 10.0 years at screening Girls: Tanner stage 1 for breast development (no palpable glandular breast tissue) and pubic hair, age at least 2 years and 26 weeks and below or equal to 9.0 years at screening Confirmed diagnosis of GHD (growth hormone deficiency) within 12 months prior to screening as determined by two different GH (growth hormone) stimulation tests, defined as a peak GH level of below or equal to 7.0 ng/ml. For children with three or more pituitary hormone deficiencies only one GH stimulation test is needed No prior exposure to GH therapy and/or IGFI (insulinlike growth factor I) treatment Height of at least 2.0 standard deviations below the mean height for chronological age (CA) and gender according to the standards of Centers for Disease Control and Prevention 220 years: Girls/Boys statureforage and weightforage percentiles CDC at screening Annualized height velocity (HV) below the 25th percentile for CA (chronological age) and gender or below 0.7 SD (standard deviation) score for CA and sex, according to the standards of Prader calculated over a time span of minimum 6 months and maximum 18 months Any clinically significant abnormality likely to affect growth or the ability to evaluate growth with standing measurements: Chromosomal aneuploidy and significant gene mutations causing medical "syndromes" with short stature, including but not limited to Turner syndrome, Laron syndrome, Noonan syndrome, or absence of GH receptors. Congenital abnormalities (causing skeletal abnormalities), including but not limited to RussellSilver Syndrome, skeletal dysplasias. Significant spinal abnormalities including but not limited to scoliosis, kyphosis and spina bifida variants Children born small for gestational age (SGA birth weight and/or birth length below2 SD for gestational age) Concomitant administration of other treatments that may have an effect on growth, including but not limited to methylphenidate for treatment of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) Prior history or presence of malignancy and/or intracranial tumour</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>