<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02258646</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research project aims to conduct a three-arm multi-center randomized controlled trial (RCT) on an innovative telerehabilitation intervention for patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). The overall purpose of the RCT is to demonstrate whether long-term integrated telerehabilitation involving exercise training at home, telemonitoring, and education/self-management will prevent hospital readmissions, thus reducing healthcare costs, for patients with COPD, and will improve patient status and quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-Term Integrated Telerehabilitation of COPD Patients. A Multi-Center Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of COPD At least one COPDrelated hospitalization or COPDrelated emergency department presentation in the previous 12 months to enrollment Capable to provide signed written informed consent Attendance to a rehabilitation program in the previous 6 months of enrollment Participation in another study that may have an impact on the outcome of this study Deemed by the health care team to be physically uncapable to perform the study procedures Presence of comorbidities wich might prevent the patient from safely undertake an exercise program at home Home environment not suitable for installation and use of rehabilitation and monitoring equipment (e.g. physical space, WiFI Internet or mobile Internet via 4G)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Telemedicine</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment Outcome</keyword>
	<keyword>Costs and Cost Analysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical Therapists</keyword>
	<keyword>Adaptation, Psychological</keyword>
</DOC>