<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01953926</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label, multicenter, multinational, Phase 2 study exploring the efficacy and safety of neratinib therapy in patients with solid tumors with activating HER2, HER3 or EGFR mutations or with EGFR gene amplification.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Open-label, Phase 2 Study of Neratinib in Patients With Solid Tumors With Somatic Human Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor (EGFR, HER2, HER3) Mutations or EGFR Gene Amplification</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label, multicenter, multinational, Phase 2 study exploring the efficacy and safety of neratinib therapy in patients with solid tumors with activating HER2, HER3 or EGFR mutations or with EGFR gene amplification. The trial will consist of a screening period, a treatment period, and an end of treatment visit occurring when neratinib is discontinued for any reason, a safety follow-up visit occurring 28 to 42 days after the last dose of neratinib and a survival follow-up period lasting for a maximum of 12 months for each patient after their last dose of neratinib or until initiation of additional anti -cancer therapy. Treatment will consist of neratinib alone 240 mg daily in all HER2 mutated cancers excluding hormone positive breast cancers and bladder cancers, or neratinib 240 mg daily and paclitaxel 80 mg/m^2 IV on Days 1, 8, and 15 of every 4 week cycle in bladder cancers , or neratinib 240 mg daily and fulvestrant 500 mg on Days 1, 15 of the first month, then Day 1 of every 4 week cycle in hormone positive breast cancers.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fulvestrant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed cancers for which no curative therapy exists. Documented HER2 mutation. Prior treatment with any panHER TKI (eg, lapatinib, afatinib, dacomitinib, neratinib). Patients who are receiving any other anticancer agents. Symptomatic or unstable brain metastases. Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding. Note: There are additional inclusion and exclusion criteria. The study center will determine if you meet all of the criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neratinib</keyword>
	<keyword>Fulvestrant</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast</keyword>
	<keyword>Gastroesophageal</keyword>
	<keyword>Endometrial Ovarian Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Biliary Tract</keyword>
	<keyword>Solid tumors</keyword>
	<keyword>HER2</keyword>
	<keyword>Paclitaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>Bladder/Urinary Tract</keyword>
</DOC>