<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01953029</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of our work to determine the mechanisms of myocardial infarction in women without obstructive coronary artery disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mechanisms of Myocardial Infarction in Women With Non Obstructive Coronary Artery Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cardiovascular disease is the leading cause of death for women. Acute coronary syndrome (ACS) is usually characterized by a sudden erosion of the endothelial wall or rupture of a plaque.However, women with ACS are less likely than men to have either classic symptoms or obstructive coronary artery disease but paradoxically have a worse prognosis. Different data from the literature indicate that there may be different pathophysiological mechanisms, afflicting men and women somewhat differently.Between 5% and 30% of patients with ACS undergoing coronary angiography are found to have non visible or non obstructive coronary disease (NOCD). This is 2-3 times more common in women than in men. Several pathogenetic mechanism of myocardial infarction (MI) in the absence of obstructive coronary artery disease (OCD) have been postulated, including among others atherosclerosis with plaque disruption that does not lead to luminal occlusion ,endothelial dysfunction, vasospasm , distal microembolization and microvascular dysfunction. However the data are extremely limited.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women ≥ 18 years old, not pregnant with acute non ST elevation myocardial infarction (admitted within 12 hours from beginning of symptoms) who are candidates for coronary arteriography during the hospitalization. *Women with troponin elevation caused by other causes</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>