<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01953523</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate for any adverse effects that may be related to the administration and reception of autologous adipose derived stromal vascular fraction (SVF). Secondarily, the study monitors the results of subjective and objective findings as it applies to the non-blinded deployment of autologous SVF for various inflammatory and/or degenerative conditions including select orthopedic, neurologic, urologic and cardio-pulmonary conditions. SVF deployments include intra-venous, intra-articular, and soft tissue injections.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Clinical Outcomes Study: SVF Deployment for Orthopedic, Neurologic, Urologic, and Cardio-pulmonary Conditions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>SVF Stromal Vascular Fraction is obtained by lipoharvesting, procurement, and lipo-transfer as a same day operative procedure</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erectile Dysfunction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autoimmune Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emphysema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Emphysema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neurodegenerative Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patient must be age 16 or older Patient must have a degenerative disease or inflammatory disease that meets criteria for treatment under the IRB which includes: Arthritis, Autoimmune disease,COPD, Cardiomyopathy, Peyronies Disease,Interstitial Cystitis, Erectile Dysfunction, and Neurodegenerative disease such as Parkinsons, ALS, Neuropathy. Patient must be healthy enough to tolerate a local anesthetic Patient must not have active cancer Patient must not have active infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>erectile dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>peyronies</keyword>
	<keyword>interstitial cystitis</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiomyopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>emphysema</keyword>
	<keyword>copd</keyword>
	<keyword>arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>multiple sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>parkinson's</keyword>
</DOC>