<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02140307</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to investigate health-promoting and stress-reducing psychological, physiological and hormonal effects of a 9-week meditation-based course in personal health and to examine potential baseline factors for any such effects. Thus, the investigators will investigate the course format (individual course or group-based course) as a potential factor the course outcome, and also individual background factors such as demographics and genetic variations.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Relaxation-Response-based Mental Health Promotion - Open and Calm 2013</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Experience of stress, defined as a Cohen's perceived stress scale score &gt; 12. Speaks and reads Danish fluently. Ability to use the internet to complete questionnaires. Participation in facetoface study information meeting. Signed agreement to the study conditions and informed consent form Exclusion Criteria Other current treatment (psychological, medical or other) for stress, depression, anxiety, phobias, traumas or other psychological problems. Other current treatment for bodily illnesses, such as pain, migraine, cancer. More than one diagnose with psychiatric disease (e.g. anxiety, depression) within the past 3 years. BodyMass Index &gt; 30. Major Depression Inventory score &gt; 25 at inclusion interview. Physical handicaps affecting life stress or quality of life chronically. Drug use (&gt; 50 times hash during the past two years; max 20 times harder drugs, max 2 times per month since the 18th birthday on average; no periods &gt; 3 years where the use of drugs exceeded two times per month). Alcohol use &gt; 21 drinks/week for men, and &gt; 14 drinks/week for women and AUDITscores (a scale of alcoholrelated problems) &gt;20. Serious head trauma.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Health Promotion</keyword>
	<keyword>Prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>Relaxation Response</keyword>
	<keyword>Meditation</keyword>
	<keyword>Cortisol</keyword>
</DOC>