<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00049088</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Phase I trial to study the effectiveness of combining bortezomib with docetaxel in treating patients who have advanced solid tumors. Bortezomib may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking the enzymes necessary for tumor cell growth. Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Combining bortezomib with docetaxel may kill more tumor cells</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bortezomib and Docetaxel in Treating Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the maximum tolerated dose of bortezomib and docetaxel in patients with advanced solid tumors. II. Determine the toxicity and tolerability of this regimen in these patients. III. Determine the biologic correlates of proteasome inhibition of bortezomib and determine the effects of this inhibition on the pharmacokinetics of docetaxel in these patients. IV. Determine the antitumor efficacy of this regimen in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study. For course 1, patients receive docetaxel IV over 1 hour on days 1 and 8 and bortezomib IV over 3-5 seconds on days 9 and 12. Patients then receive 1 week of rest. For course 2 and all subsequent courses, patients receive docetaxel on days 1 and 8 and bortezomib on days 2, 5, 9, and 12. Courses repeat every 3 weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Cohorts of 2-6 patients receive escalating doses of bortezomib and docetaxel until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose at which no more than 1 of 6 patients experiences dose-limiting toxicity. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A minimum of 24 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed solid tumor for which standard curative or palliative measures do not exist or are no longer effective Metastatic or unresectable disease No known brain metastases Performance status ECOG 02 Performance status Karnofsky 50100% More than 12 weeks WBC at least 3,000/mm^3 Absolute neutrophil count at least 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin at least 8 g/dL Bilirubin normal AST and ALT no greater than 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) and alkaline phosphatase no greater than 2.5 times ULN Alkaline phosphatase no greater than 5 times ULN (unless bonederived) and AST and ALT less than 1.5 times ULN Creatinine normal Creatinine clearance at least 60 mL/min No symptomatic congestive heart failure No unstable angina pectoris No cardiac arrhythmia Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 3 months after study No prior allergic reactions attributed to taxanes (e.g., docetaxel or paclitaxel) or compounds of similar chemical or biological composition No prior allergic reactions to compounds similar to bortezomib or other study agents No known hypersensitivity to corticosteroids No predicted intolerance to regular, repeated administration of corticosteroids (e.g., poorly controlled diabetes or significant osteoporosis/osteopenia) No ongoing or active infection No other uncontrolled concurrent illness that would preclude study participation No psychiatric illness or social situation that would preclude study participation No peripheral neuropathy grade 2 or greater At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy (6 weeks for carmustine, nitrosoureas, or mitomycin) and recovered No more than 3 courses of mitomycin Prior taxanes allowed At least 6 months since prior docetaxel administered on a weekly schedule At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy and recovered No other concurrent investigational agents No concurrent combination antiretroviral therapy for HIVpositive patients No other concurrent anticancer agents or therapies (commercial or investigational)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>