<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02524704</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this feasibility study is to evaluate the ability of Electrical Impedance Tomography (EIT) for providing regional and quantitative information about the extent and nature of bronchial obstruction in patients with cystic fibrosis. It is not being conducted to diagnose, treat, prevent, or cure any kind of disease. In electrical impedance tomography low amplitude, low frequency current is applied on electrodes, and the resulting voltage is measured and used to computed the electrical properties of the interior of the chest as they change in time. The computed properties are used to form an image, which can then be used for monitoring and diagnosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Electrical Impedance Imaging of Patients With Cystic Fibrosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The goal of this study is to evaluate the ability of Electrical Impedance Tomography (EIT) hardware and software in patients with cystic fibrosis (CF) for providing regional and quantitative information for identifying regions of obstruction and consolidation, and determine whether these measures will correlate with improvements seen after hospitalized treatment for a pulmonary exacerbation (PE). In particular, EIT will be used to identify regions of obstruction (air trapping) and consolidation comprised of atelectasis and airway occlusion (consequences of mucus plugging) in CF patients, and to determine whether EIT can demonstrate the beneficial effects of antibiotic treatment for CF patients with an acute PE by correlating changes in quantitative EIT measures with clinical measures known to improve following therapy, with patients serving as their own controls. Regional changes in air trapping and consolidation from pre to post treatment as indicated by the EIT images will be calculated, with subjects serving as their own control.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Between the ages of 2 and 21 years (Groups 1 and 2) Between the ages of 8 and 21 years (Group 3) Healthy lungs (Group 1) Clinical diagnosis of cystic fibrosis (Groups 2 and 3) Clinically indicated for a pulmonary CT scan or will receive one as part of their routine care (Group 2) Receiving IV antibiotics for a clinically diagnosed pulmonary exacerbation (Group 3) Under age 24 months or over age 21. No informed consent Known congenital heart disease, arrythmia, or history of heart failure, admission to the intensive care unit, wearing a pacemaker or other surgical implant. Pregnant or lactating</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cystic fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Electrical Impedance Tomography</keyword>
</DOC>