<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02524054</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this protocol is to develop and test aerosol furosemide, as a treatment that has the potential to significantly improve symptom management and enhance the quality of care for patients with intractable dyspnea.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aerosol Inhalation Treatment for Dyspnea - Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is the second study in a series of studies investigating the treatment effect of aerosolized furosemide on hospitalized patients and outpatients with intractable dyspnea. The study will focus on patients who experience intractable dyspnea at rest or with minimal activity, e.g., dressing, bathing, cooking, or walking stairs or short distances. There are two parts to this study: Study 2a is a pilot study on 5-10 patients. These trials are not blinded or placebo controlled; the investigators will use them to discover practical problems, and take the information back to the laboratory to develop solutions. Study 2b will a randomized, placebo - controlled, double- blind study on 25 - 40 patients. The two planned treatments will be aerosolized furosemide and aerosolized saline, and will be given to each patient on two separate days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dyspnea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Furosemide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Intractable dyspnea at rest or with minimal activity Chronic congestive heart failure Liver or kidney disease Systemic lupus erythematosis (SLE) Receiving potassium supplementation or other indication of hypokalemia Major psychiatric disorders Furosemide hypersensitivity Not mentally competent and/or alert (unable to grant informed consent) Under 18 years old Not fluent in English Inadequate birth control</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dyspnea</keyword>
	<keyword>Hospitalized patients</keyword>
	<keyword>Ambulatory outpatients</keyword>
	<keyword>Shortness of breath</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulmonary disease</keyword>
</DOC>