<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01541761</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The proposed study is a randomized controlled trial to test the effectiveness of a primary care, family-centered child obesity prevention program beginning in pregnancy and continuing throughout the first three years of life compared to routine standard of care. The study aims to reduce the prevalence of obesity at age three, improve child diet composition and healthy lifestyle behaviors. Pregnant women will be enrolled from a large urban medical center serving primarily low-income immigrant Latino families. The intervention "Starting Early" will consist of three components. 1) Family Groups: interactive groups coordinated with the child's primary care visits and led by a Nutritionist/ Child Developmental Specialist. 2) Nutritional Video: a culturally-specific bilingual early nutrition video will be incorporated into family group discussions. 3) Plain Language Handouts: given to reinforce the curriculum from the family groups. Hypothesis: Compared to controls, the intervention group will show reduced obesity and improved parent feeding knowledge and increased healthy feeding attitudes, styles and practices</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Starting Early Obesity Prevention Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Expected outcomes include: (1) Reduction in the prevalence and degree of obesity. (2) Improvement in child diet composition. (3) Improvement in parent feeding knowledge, attitudes, styles and practices including. (4) Improvement in lifestyle behaviors, such as sleep, screen time and physical activity, associated with increased risk of obesity. (5) Improvement in parent diet. Our secondary objective is to understand the mechanisms by which changes in parent knowledge and behavioral factors mediate impacts of the intervention on childhood obesity. We will also study relationships between potential moderators and intervention impacts.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Latina mother &gt; 18 years with singleton uncomplicated pregnancy Receiving prenatal care and the intention to receive pediatric care at Bellevue Hospital Center or Gouverneur Healthcare Services Mother to be primary caregiver of child Mother speaks fluent English or Spanish Maternal history of serious medical or psychiatric illness or drug or alcohol abuse Family does not have a phone Infants with severe medical problems that may affect feeding</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Child</keyword>
	<keyword>Hispanic</keyword>
	<keyword>Prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>Nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>Parenting</keyword>
</DOC>