<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02596243</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to access the efficacy and safety of GX-188E according the protocol in patients with Cervical Intraepithelial Neoplasia 2, 2/3 or 3 (CIN3)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 2 Clinical Trial to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of Plasmid DNA Therapeutic Vaccine(GX-188E)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Not provided</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma in Situ</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cervical Intraepithelial Neoplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Female subjects age 1860 years 2. Histologically confirmed HPV16 or HPV18 asspcoated CIN2, CIN 2/3 or CIN3 from tissue collected less than 10 weeks prior to Vaccination/EP #1 with overall lesion sizes less than 50% of the cervix area and no evidence of invasive cancer in any specimen; 3. Colposcopy is satisfactory based on visualization of the entire squamocolumnar junction and the upper limit of the entire acetowhite or suspected CIN disease area; 4. Healthy subjects as judged by the Investigator based on medical history, PE, and normal results for an ECG, CBC, Serum Chemistries, CPK and urinalysis done up to 4 weeks prior to enrolment; 5. For women who are not postmenopausal (at least 12 months of nontherapy induced amenorrhea) or surgically sterile (absence of ovaries and/or uterus): agreement to remain abstinent or use a highly effective method of contraception during the treatment period and throughout Week 36 response evaluation visit. 6. Able and willing to comply with all study procedures and voluntarily signs informed consent form. 1. Unsatisfactory colposcopy defined as incomplete visualization of the entire squamocolumnar junction and the upper limit of the entire acetowhite or suspected CIN disease area; 2. Pregnancy or breastfeeding; 3. Immunosuppression including any concurrent condition requiring the continued use of systemic or topical steroids at or near the injection site [deltoid, upper arm] (excluding inhaled and eye dropcontaining corticosteroids) or the use of immunosuppressive agents. All other corticosteroids must be discontinued &gt; 4 weeks prior to Day 0 of study vaccine administration; autoimmune disorders, transplant recipients; 4. History of previous therapeutic HPV vaccination (individuals who have been immunized with licensed prophylactic HPV vaccines (e.g. Gardasil®, Cervarix®) are not excluded); 5. Positive serological test for hepatitis C virus or hepatitis B virus surface antigen (HBsAg) or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV); 6. Administration of any blood product within 3 months of enrollment; 7. Administration of any licensed vaccine within 2 weeks of enrollment (4 weeks for measles vaccine); 8. Participation in a study with an investigational compound or device within 30 days prior to signing informed consent; 9. Cardiac preexcitation syndromes (such as WolffParkinsonWhite); 10. History of seizures (unless seizure free for 5 years); 11. Tattoos, scars, active lesions/rashes or any implantable leads within 3 cm of the intended site of vaccination/EP; 12. Any electronic medical implants (such as cardiac pacemaker); 13. Active drug or alcohol use or dependence that, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with adherence to study requirements; 14. A tendency for severe haemorrhage following acute trauma; 15. Prisoners or subjects who are compulsorily detained (involuntarily incarcerated) for treatment of either a psychiatric or physical (i.e. infections disease) illness must not be enrolled into this study; 16. Any other conditions judged by the investigator that would limit the evaluation of a subject.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>CIN2, CIN2/3, CIN3</keyword>
	<keyword>Cervical Intraepithelial Neoplasia</keyword>
	<keyword>High-Risk HPV</keyword>
	<keyword>HPV infection</keyword>
	<keyword>precancer Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Double Blind</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety/Efficacy</keyword>
</DOC>