<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02596906</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Individuals aged 55 and older may experience negative effects of cognitive decline. The proposed research seeks to evaluate the benefits of different types of interventions: reasoning training following transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) and reasoning training following sham transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) on frontal- lobe mediated cognitive measures of executive control in adults with memory complaints, in the absence of dementia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Brain and Cognitive Changes After Reasoning Training in Individuals With Mild Cognitive Impairment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the impact of reasoning training on individuals with complaints of changes in memory or thinking in the absence of dementia, when combined with transcranial current stimulation (tDCS). The reasoning training being studied is a strategy based program where individuals are taught strategies designed to engage the frontal lobes. Participants will randomly be placed into one of two groups (1) reasoning training following transcranial current stimulation (tDCS) as compared to (2) reasoning training following sham tDCS. The study will be done with adults between the ages of 50 and 80 with consistent memory complaints or lower baseline performance on memory measures. The primary hypothesis is that individuals receiving tDCS prior to brain training will have a stronger response to brain training than those in the sham tDCS group. Response to training will be measured by improved cognitive function and neural changes as measured by neuropsychological testing, MRI, and EEG. MRI will be used to evaluate the impact of reasoning training on brain blood flow, structure and function, and to measure changes in brain energy metabolism and electroencephalogram (EEG) to evaluate intervention outcomes. The reasoning training program will be conducted in small groups at the Center for BrainHealth.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Safely have an MRI Cognitive complaints in the absence of dementia Participate in tasks involving motor abilities such as use of at least one arm and hand Read, speak, and comprehend English 5080 years of age Comprehend simple instructions, perform tasks, and take part in intervention Not proficient in reading, comprehending, or speaking English Individuals who have any significant health, neurological, or psychiatric illness, or history of substance abuse Individuals with any MR contraindications (i.e., nonremovable metal within/on the body) Individuals taking medications which are contraindicatory for the tDCS procedure Individuals who are lefthanded Not proficient in reading,comprehending, and speaking English Females who are not postmenopausal Preexisting cerebral palsy, autism, epilepsy, schizophrenia, pervasive developmental disorder, thyroid diseases, diabetes, claustrophobia, noncorrectable vision problems, major depression, psychosis, active behavioral disorder, or uncontrolled epilepsy. Women who are pregnant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>