<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02981238</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to evaluate the effect of a one-month supplementation with Phytostandard® Eschscholtzia and valerian on the Insomnia Severity Index (ISI), in insomniac so-called adjustment subjects (occasional or short-term insomnia)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Descriptive Study of a Phytotherapy Strategy for Sleep Disorders Related to Anxiety With Phytostandard® Eschscholtzia and Valerian, a Dietary Supplement Based on Eschscholtzia and Valerian Extracts</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>For this study, 40 patients are going to be included. They will have a supplementation of Phytostandard® Eschscholtzia and valerian, from 2 to 4 tablets per day during 28 days. on the one hand, during the two visits (inclusion and follow-up), the investigator completes the Hamilton Anxiety Scale (HAM-A). During the inclusion visit, he completes with his patient the epworth scale. on the other hand, patients complete ISI twice : just after the inclusion visit and just before the follow-up visit. He completes two sleep schedules, the first one during the first week of complement and the second one during the fourth.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria of patients: Currently having sleep disorders related to an anxiety and / or having some in the last 3 months Having an alteration of sleep on the previous month which results in a score strictly greater than 7 according to the index of Severity of Insomnia (ISI) For which the investigator freely advises his patient a complement with Phytostandard® Eschscholtzia and Valerian For which the patient freely agrees to complement itself after advice of his doctor with Phytostandard® Eschscholtzia and Valerian Having been informed of the study and accepting the collection and processing of their data Suffering from an anxiety resulting in a HAMA score (Hamilton Anxiety Rating Scale) greater than or equal to 30 With a score on Epworth's sleepiness scale strictly greater than 10 (suggestive of a major hypersomnia) Presenting symptoms of sleep apnea syndrome Presenting symptoms of a restless legs syndrome Presenting a chronic pain syndrome requiring the daily intake of analgesic(s) Under psychotropic treatment (neuroleptic, anxiolytic, antidepressant or hypnotic) or under treatment to alter the waking state (antihistamines, betablockers, some cough syrups, etc.)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>68 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>