<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02981329</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether metformin is effective in the treatment for sickle cell anemia (SCA) and non-transfusion dependent thalassemia (NTDT).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fetal Hemoglobin Induction Treatment Metformin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single center, dose escalation, pilot study for subjects with sickle cell anemia (SCA) disease and non-transfusion dependent thalassemia (NTDT) to determine if metformin has a beneficial effect on the treatment of SCA and NTDT patients. In addition the following items will also occur: Data Collection will occur from subject's medical records in regards to their SCA or NTDT medical history. Subjects will be asked to completed questionnaires to access increase or decrease of quality of life. Biological samples (blood and urine) will be collected throughout the study to access the effects the study drug has on SCA and NTDT disease treatment, general health, and genetic analysis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thalassemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemoglobinopathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxyurea</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Confirmed diagnosis of sickle cell anemia or nontransfusion dependent thalassemia 2. Age greater than or equal to 16 and less than or equal to 40 years of age. 3. If on hydroxyurea, fetal hemoglobin less than 20% at maximum tolerated dose 4. Creatinine less than or equal to 1.4mg/dL and estimated glomerular filtration rate greater than 45 ml/min/1.73 m2 5. Liver function tests less than or equal to 1.5 times upper limits of normal 1. Failure to meet inclusion criteria 2. Chronic red blood cell transfusion therapy in the last 3 months 3. Packed red blood cell transfusion in the last 3 months (temporary exclusion). 4. Pregnancy 5. Refusal to use medically effective birth control if female and sexually active. 6. If on hydroxyurea, not at stable maximum tolerated dose for a minimum of 6 months (temporary exclusion). 7. Creatinine greater than 1.4mg/dL, 8. Liver function tests greater than 1.5x upper limits of normal</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metformin</keyword>
	<keyword>Sickle Cell Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Sickle Cell Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemoglobinopathies</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemoglobin Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Blood Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemoglobin Disease; Sickle-Cell, Thalassemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemoglobin Disease</keyword>
</DOC>