<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02981745</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase I study of BTK inhibitor CT-1530 in patients with relapsed or refractory B cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma (B-NHL), chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) or Waldenstrom's macroglobulinemia (WM). The purpose of the study is to determine the MTD/RP2D of CT-1530, and evaluate its safety and tolerability as monotherapy in subjects with relapsed or refractory B cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma (B-NHL), chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) or Waldenstrom's macroglobulinemia (WM).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Safety,Efficacy and Pharmacokinetics of CT-1530 in Patients With Relapsed or Refractory B Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma, Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia, and Waldenstrom's Macroglobulinemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Waldenstrom Macroglobulinemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Follicular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Mantle-Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed diagnosis of B cell NonHodgkin Lymphoma(according to World Health Organization [WHO] classification)including Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia/Small cell Lymphocytic Leukemia (International Workshop),or Waldenstrom's Macroglobulinemia(Second International Workshop). Have failed ≥1 previous treatment for BNHL/CLL/WM, and have relapsed or refractory disease following last prior treatment. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of ≤ 1 and a life expectancy of at least 3 months. Measurable disease as per RECIST v1.1 Availability of tumor sample Adequate hematologic function, as defined by neutrophils ≥ 1.0 x 10^9/L and platelets ≥ 50 x 10^9/L; patients with neutrophils &lt; 1.0 x 10^9/L due to marrow infiltration are allowed to receive growth factors to bring pretreatment neutrophils to ≥ 1.0 x 10^9/L. Adequate renal function, as defined by creatinine clearance of ≥ 50 ml/min (as estimated by the CockcroftGault equation or as measured by nuclear medicine scan or 24 hour urine collection). Adequate liver function, as defined by AST and ALT ≤ 3 x ULN, and bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN (unless documented Gilbert's syndrome). Prior allogeneic bone marrow transplant Autologous stem cell transplant within 3 months of screening Active central nervous system involvement Subjects with autoimmune hemolytic anemia or immune thrombocytopenia Prior treatment with a Btk inhibitor Active uncontrolled infection History of malabsorption Uncontrolled illness, i.e cardiac, endocrine, respiratory, etc. History of myocardial infarction, acute coronary syndromes, coronary angioplasty and/or stenting with in the previous 6 months History of another currently active cancer History of major surgery within 4 weeks or minor surgery within 1 week Other medical or psychiatric illness or organ dysfunction HIV positive Positive for Hepatitis B surface antigen or Hepatitis Cvirus Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>