<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01145105</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Low back pain ( LBP) is a significant health problem which affects about 70%-80% of the population during the course of their life . The majority of LBP is resolved within 3 months; however, up to 40% of LBP becomes chronic. One subgroup of chronic LBP is patients with sciatica. Sciatica is characterized by radiating pain to the buttock and lower limb, with or without low back pain. It has been shown in the upper limb that by positioning the contra-lateral arm in tension the investigators actually reduce tension in the ipsilateral arm. Patients, who present with symptoms like sciatica, can benefit from this maneuver (neural dynamics techniques) that reduces tension through the contra-lateral leg. Working Hypothesis: Compared with a placebo maneuver of the upper limb, the neural dynamics techniques will result in better rehabilitation of individuals with radicular LBP.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neural Dynamics Technique for the Treatment of Chronic Radicular Low Back Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objectives: To evaluate the efficacy of neural dynamics techniques, using the contra-lateral leg, in the treatment of sub-acute/chronic Low back pain with radiation to the leg. Study Methodology: Eligible individuals will be assessed by a physiotherapist that will be blinded to the treatment allocation; treatment (either intervention or placebo) will be provided by a physiotherapist that will be blinded to the patient's assessment. The treated individuals and the referring physician will also be blinded to the treatment allocation;</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sciatica</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written consent LBP with radiation to one leg, that lasts more than 6 weeks Abnormal response to SLR test With or without neurological signs History of spinal surgery Patient with FUO History of malignancies Patient with saddle anesthesia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Low back pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Sciatica</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Physiotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>