<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01145066</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will compare how well a combination of borage and echium oils will reduce inflammation compared to fish oils and placebo oil in subjects that are diabetic or have metabolic syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Botanical Oil Supplementation in Diabetic and Metabolic Syndrome Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<criteria>adults, aged 21 years or more with either diabetes or metabolic syndrome. metabolic syndrome defined by NCEP/ATPIII criteria; must have 3 out of 5 of the following risk factors: 1.central obesity, mengreater than or equal to 40 inches, womengreater than or equal to 35 inches; 2.fasting blood TG greater than or equal to 150mg/dl or be taking TG lowering medications; 3. blood HDL cholesterol, men less than 40 mg/dl, women less than 50 mg/dl; 4. blood pressure greater than or equal to 130/85 or on HTN medication 5. fasting glucose greater than or equal to 100 mg/dl. participants on statins or glucose lowering drugs if dosages are stable for 3 months Exclusion criteria children/young adults less than 21 years of age currently using antiinflammatory drugs including NSAIDS, oral/IV steroids or injection antiinflammatory drugs(for RA), aspirin greater than 100mg/day taking leukotriene receptor antagonists ( montelukast), tylenol or nasal/inhaled steroids OK. currently using niacin, fibrates or fish oil blood pressure greater than 170/100 HB1Ac greater than 10% TG greater than 500 mg/dl myocardial infarction/vascular surgery/stroke within the past year any stage II,III,IV heart failure prior cholecystectomy end stage renal disease BMI less than 23 or greater than 45 pregnancy alcohol use greater than 14 drinks per week current self reported tobacco or illicit drug use intolerance or allergy to fish oil participants taking insulin on QD or BID doses, stable for 3 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>botanical oils</keyword>
</DOC>