<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03056937</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The hypothesis of this study is that reductions in body weight could improve inspiratory muscle function attenuating the inspiratory metaboreflex in metabolically healthy obese individuals and obese individuals with metabolic syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Bariatric Surgery on Inspiratory Metaboreflex in Obese Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Introduction: Peripheral metaboreflex activation appears to be exacerbated in obese individuals with metabolic syndrome. Interestingly, bariatric surgery attenuates the peripheral metaboreflex. Obese individuals have impaired inspiratory muscle function, which can be reversed by the reduction in body weight. Therefore, bariatric surgery could attenuate inspiratory metaboreflex in metabolically healthy obese individuals and obese individuals with metabolic syndrome. Objectives: To investigate the effects of bariatric surgery on inspiratory metaboreflex in metabolically healthy obese individuals and in obese patients with metabolic syndrome. Patients and Methods: A sample comprising of 15 obese subjects with metabolic syndrome, 15 obese subjects without metabolic syndrome and 15 healthy nonobese individuals. These subjects will be submitted to pulmonary function, respiratory muscle strength, inspiratory muscle resistance, exercise tolerance, quality of life, autonomic cardiovascular control and the inspiratory metaboreflex evaluation. The evaluations performed in obese patients with and without metabolic syndrome pre-surgery will be repeated 6 months after bariatric surgery.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Obese with Metabolic Syndrome Body mass index (BMI)&gt; 35 kg / m² Diagnosis of metabolic syndrome Acute health problems in the last month (viral or bacterial infections, accidents, allergic reactions) Diseases of the nervous system or conditions that affect the understanding or participation in the study Pregnancy Type I diabetes mellitus Arterial hypertension Dyslipidemias Coronary artery disease Left ventricular dysfunction Any condition interfering with locomotion Bronchial asthma Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease Chronic neuropathies Use of drugs such as corticosteroids or bronchodilators Smokers. Obese without Metabolic Syndrome Body mass index (BMI)&gt; 35 kg / m² Metabolic Syndrome Acute health problems in the last month (viral or bacterial infections, accidents, allergic reactions) Diseases of the nervous system or conditions that affect the understanding or participation in the study Pregnancy Type I diabetes mellitus Arterial hypertension Dyslipidemias Coronary artery disease Left ventricular dysfunction Any condition interfering with locomotion Bronchial asthma Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease Chronic neuropathies Use of drugs such as corticosteroids or bronchodilators Smokers. Healthy nonobese subjects BMI &lt;25 kg / m² Nonsmokers Any diagnosed disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>