<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02073266</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of the study was to compare the macular hole closure and visual acuity gain following vitrectomy using SF6 gas tamponade with 7 days of face-down positioning versus C3F8 gas tamponade with 14 days of face-down positioning. The secondary purpose was to report, in each group, the cumulative incidence of cataract development 1 year following macular hole surgery and the proportion of complications (*). ((*) hypertony, hypotony, retinal tear, retinal detachment and endophthalmitis) This prospective randomized study examined a 3 year period. The first patient was included in January 2010 and the last in November 2011. The 12-month follow-up spread out from March 2011 to December 2012. The first group included 31 patients who had undergone macular hole surgery using SF6 gas and who were advised to stay in face-down position for 7 days postoperatively (SF6 group). These patients were compared to 28 patients who had undergone macular hole surgery with C3F8 gas and who were advised to maintain a face-down position for 14 days. Patients in both groups underwent vitrectomy, internal limiting membrane peeling, and fluid-gas exchange using either SF6 or C3F8. Preoperative data included the characterization of the hole with Optical Coherence Tomography (OCT), the best correct visual acuity (VA) recorded in number of letters using the Early Treatment Diabetic Retinopathy Study (ETDRS) chart, classification of the cataract according to the LOCS III and the intraocular pressure IOP. Postoperative data included OCT confirmation of the closure at 6 weeks and 1 year, 1 year's best corrected VA recorded in number of letters (EDTRS chart) and determination of cataract development and extraction as needed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of C3F8 or SF6 Use and Length of Face-down Positioning (7 vs 14 Days Respectively) in Macular Hole Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cataract</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Perforations</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temazepam</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Idiopathic MH of stage 24 according to Gass classification (confirmed by fundoscopic examination and OCT) was included. Exclusion criteria includes: patients with a chronic macular hole (symptoms more than 12 months duration), base diameter of the hole larger than 0.5 disc area diameter, medias opacities that prevent fundus visualisation until the second branches of central retinal artery, agerelated macular degeneration ARMD, diabetic retinopathy, past history of retinal detachment or vitrectomy and corneal pathology disrupting vision.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>51 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>83 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>