<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02073227</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the bioequivalence of the fixed dose combination (two components combined in one tablet) of canagliflozin and metformin extended release (XR) tablet (dose of 2 X 150 mg/1,000 mg) with respect to the individual components of canagliflozin (1 x 300 mg) and metformin XR tablet (4 x 500 mg) in healthy fed participants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Bioequivalence Study of the Fixed Dose Combination Tablets of Canagliflozin and Metformin Extended Release (XR) With Respect to the Individual Components</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized (the study medication is assigned by chance), open-label (physicians and participants know the identity of the assigned treatment), single-center, single-dose, 3-treatment, 3-way crossover (the same medications are provided to all participants but in different sequence) study of canagliflozin (CANA) and metformin extended release (MET XR) combined in one tablet, in comparison with tablets containing the individual components. Two Fixed Dose Combinations (FDCs) will be evaluated during the study (two types of tablets). The tablets will be of the same strength (150 mg CANA/1,000 mg MET XR) and will be compared with equal doses of the individual drugs: canagliflozin (1 x 300 mg tablet) and metformin XR (4 x 500 mg tablets). Thus, there will be 3 treatment periods in the study: Treatment A: "Reference" treatment of individual components administered concurrently; Treatment B: CANA/MET XR FDC, formulation 1; and Treatment C: CANA/MET XR FDC, formulation 2. Approximately 42 healthy adult participants will be randomly assigned to 1 of the 3 treatments groups, and then each group will receive all three treatments in different sequences (3-way crossover). The study will consist of 3 phases: a Screening Phase of approximately 3 weeks, an Open-Label Treatment Phase consisting of 3 single-dose Treatment Periods of 5 days each separated by a washout period of 10 to 14 days and a Follow-up Phase occurring 7 to 10 days after the last study-related procedure of Treatment Period 3. The total duration of the study will be about 70 days for each participant.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Canagliflozin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must sign an informed consent document indicating they understand the purpose of the study and procedures Must have a body mass index (BMI) of between 18 and 30 kg/m2, inclusive Must have a body weight of not less than 50 kg Must have a blood pressure between 90 and 140 mmHg inclusive, systolic, and no higher than 90 mmHg diastolic at screening Must have normal renal function and no evidence of kidney damage (including abnormalities in blood or urine tests) History of or current clinically significant medical illness Use of any prescription or nonprescription medication (including vitamins and herbal supplements) History of clinically significant allergies, especially known hypersensitivity or intolerance to drugs or lactose Known allergy to heparin or history of heparin induced thrombocytopenia Donated blood or blood products or had substantial loss of blood within 3 months before screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Healthy Volunteers</keyword>
	<keyword>Canagliflozin</keyword>
	<keyword>Metformin</keyword>
	<keyword>Type 2 diabetes mellitus</keyword>
</DOC>