<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02073188</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate the superiority of iBGstar as a component of the diabetes treatment vs. traditional blood glucose self-monitoring system for improving glycemic control after 6 months in young patients with type 1 diabetes. The study is intended also to demonstrate the superiority of iBGStar as a component of the diabetes treatment vs. usual blood glucose self-monitoring system for improving the compliance to self monitoring of blood glucose after 6 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparative Study of a Smartphone-Linked Self-Monitoring System Versus a Traditional One for Improving Metabolic Control and Compliance to Self-Monitoring of Blood Glucose</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The planned study duration will be 20 months (5 quarters) with screening/enrollment of 7 months, followed by 2-3 weeks of a qualification phase, a 6 month experimental phase, plus a 6 month follow-up in the post-trial observational phase.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 1 diabetes Males and females Age between 1424 years Any diabetes duration Cared for by the diabetes center for at least 1 year HbA1c ≥ 8% Basal bolus treatment (any insulin) Poor compliance with SelfMonitoring of Blood Glucose (less than 30% of the recommended Blood Glucose measurements recorded in the glucose meter in the two previous weeks, i.e. &lt;16 Blood Glucose measurements in the last two weeks) Written informed consent obtained from patient or legal representative (for minor) Treatment with other insulin regimen or Continuous Subcutaneous Insulin Infusion Refusal or inability to give informed consent to participate in the study Patients with short life expectancy Patients with conditions/concomitant diseases making them non evaluable for the primary efficacy endpoint according to physician's judgment Requirement for concomitant treatment that could bias primary evaluation Patients with high likelihood of being unavailable for 6 and/or 12 months visits Subject is the investigator, subinvestigator, research assistant, pharmacist, study coordinator, other study site staff or relative of study site staff thus considered directly involved in the conduct of the study Current addition/abuse of alcohol or drugs Severe visual or dexterity impairment Patients with any mental condition rendering them unable to understand the nature, scope, and possible consequences of the study Pregnant or breastfeeding women Subjects unlikely or unable to comply with the Protocol requirements</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>