<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02073500</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to identify biomarkers of disease recurrence and prognosis to optimize patient selection for treatment with cytoreductive surgery (CRS) with hyperthermic intraperitoneal chemotherapy (HIPEC), and through animal models to explore different treatment strategies for peritoneal surface malignancies (PSM).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Peritoneal Surface Malignancies - Characterization, Models and Treatment Strategies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The handling of patients with PSM involves multimodal and multidisciplinary treatment strategies such as CRS, the removal of all macroscopically detectable tumor, and HIPEC, instillation of heated chemotherapy in the abdominal cavity to remove residual cancer disease. The treatment is challenging and complex and associated with significant morbidity. Only patients with limited disease will benefit from the treatment, and better methods for patient selection are needed. The project group has a unique opportunity to address key questions because of acquired experience, an exceptional biobank and institutional database and novel animal models established at the Norwegian Radium Hospital.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mesothelioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pseudomyxoma Peritonei</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age &gt; 18 years confirmed diagnosis of peritoneal surface malignancy candidate for CRSHIPEC written informed consent Approximately 80 patients per year will be eligible for inclusion, as this is the number of patients that annually receive surgical treatment for PSM.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Peritoneal carcinomatosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Peritoneal surface malignancy</keyword>
	<keyword>Cytoreductive surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperthermic intraperitoneal chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>CRS</keyword>
	<keyword>HIPEC</keyword>
	<keyword>Prognostic biomarker</keyword>
	<keyword>Predictive biomarker</keyword>
</DOC>