<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02073487</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose: The purpose of this study is to evaluate the Pathological Complete Response (pCR) of the breast when trastuzumab emtansine (TDM-1) plus Lapatinib plus Abraxane is combined in newly diagnosed HER2 positive breast cancer. This is a randomized, open label Phase II neo-adjuvant study comparing the efficacy of neoadjuvant Trastuzumab Emtansine (TDM1) plus lapatinib follow by Abraxane, versus trastuzumab (herceptin) plus Pertuzumab follow by paclitaxel.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neoadjuvant TDM1 With Lapatinib and Abraxane Compared With Trastuzumab Plus Pertuzumab With Paclitaxel</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Maytansine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ado-trastuzumab emtansine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pertuzumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lapatinib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trastuzumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female gender; Age ≥18 years; Performance Status Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) 01 Histologically confirmed invasive breast cancer: Primary tumor greater than 1 cm diameter, measured by clinical examination and mammography or ultrasound. Any N, No evidence of metastasis (M0) (isolated supraclavicular node involvement allowed); Over expression and/or amplification of HER2 in the invasive component of the primary tumor and confirmed by a certified laboratory prior to randomization. Known hormone receptor status. Hematopoietic status: CBC not less than .75 of institutional lower limit. Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,5 x 10^9/L, Platelet count ≥ 100 x 10^9/L, Hemoglobin at least 9 g/dl, Hepatic status: Serum total bilirubin ≤ 2 x upper limit of normal (ULN). In the case of known Gilbert's syndrome, a higher serum total bilirubin (&lt; 1.5 x ULN) is allowed, Aspartate Aminotransferase (AST) and Alanine Aminotransferase (ALT) ≤ 3.5 times ULN, Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2.5 times ULN, • Renal status: Creatinine ≤ 1.5mg/dL, • Cardiovascular: Baseline left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ³ ≥50% measured by echocardiography (ECHO) or Multiple Gate Acquisition (MUGA) scan, Negative serum or urine βhCG pregnancy test at screening for patients of childbearing potential within 2weeks (preferably 7 days) prior to randomization. Fertile patients must use effective contraception (barrier method condoms, diaphragm also in conjunction with spermicidal jelly, or total abstinence. Oral, injectable, or implant hormonal contraceptives are not allowed) Signed informed consent form (ICF) Patient accepts to make available tumor samples for submission to central laboratory to conduct translational studies as part of this protocol. Previous (less than 5 years) or current history of malignant neoplasms, except for curatively treated: Basal and squamous cell carcinoma of the skin; Carcinoma in situ of the cervix. Patients with a prior malignancy diagnosed more than 5 years prior to randomization may enter the study. Preexisting peripheral neuropathy ≥ grade 2 Known history of uncontrolled or symptomatic angina, clinically significant arrhythmias, congestive heart failure, transmural myocardial infarction, uncontrolled hypertension (≥180/110), unstable diabetes mellitus, dyspnea at rest, or chronic therapy with oxygen; Concurrent disease or condition that would make the subject inappropriate for study participation or any serious medical disorder that would interfere with the subject's safety; Unresolved or unstable, serious adverse events from prior administration of another investigational drug; Dementia, altered mental status, or any psychiatric condition that would prevent the understanding or rendering of ICF; Malabsorption syndrome, disease significantly affecting gastrointestinal function, or resection of the stomach or small bowel. Subjects with ulcerative colitis are also excluded; Concurrent neoadjuvant cancer therapy (chemotherapy, radiation therapy, immunotherapy, biologic therapy other than the trial therapies); Concurrent treatment with an investigational agent or participation in another therapeutic clinical trial; Known immediate or delayed hypersensitivity reaction or idiosyncrasy to drugs chemically related to trastuzumab Emtansine, trastuzumab, lapatinib, paclitaxel, abraxane or their components; Pregnant or lactating women; Concomitant use of CYP3A4 inhibitors or inducers Other concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled concomitant medical conditions (e.g. active or uncontrolled infection, uncontrolled diabetes) that could cause unacceptable safety risks or compromise compliance with the protocol Patients have an active infection and require IV or oral antibiotics. Pregnant or breastfeeding women Patients unwilling or unable to comply with the protocol</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neoadjuvant Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>HER2 positive Breast Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>