<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01160172</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, reactogenicity and immunogenicity of several formulations of an investigational Staphylococcal vaccine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety, Reactogenicity and Immunogenicity of GSK Biologicals' Staphylococcal Investigational Vaccine in Healthy Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who the investigator believes can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol. A male or female between 18 and 40 years of age, inclusive, at the time of first vaccination. Written informed consent obtained from the subject. Healthy subjects as established by medical history, clinical examination and laboratory assessment before entering into the study. Female subjects of nonchildbearing potential may be enrolled in the study. Female subjects of childbearing potential may be enrolled in the study, if the subject: has practiced adequate contraception for 30 days prior to vaccination, and has a negative pregnancy test at Screening, and has agreed to continue adequate contraception during the entire treatment period and for 2 months after completion of the vaccination series Use of any investigational or nonregistered product other than the study vaccines within 30 days preceding the first dose of study vaccine, or planned use during the study period. Chronic administration of immunosuppressants or other immunemodifying drugs within 6 months prior to the first vaccine dose. Any clinically significant acute or chronic, local or systemic infection, proven or suspected to be caused by Staphylococcus aureus and requiring antibiotic treatment, within the 6 months preceding the first vaccination. Previous administration of any investigational Staphylococcus aureus vaccine/antibodies. History of; or current bleeding or coagulation disorder. Known or suspected reaction or hypersensitivity likely to be exacerbated by any component of the vaccines. History of; or current autoimmune or other immunemediated disease. Administration or planned administration, of any vaccine not foreseen by the study protocol within 30 days of the first dose of vaccines up to 1 month after the last vaccine dose. Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within the last 3 months preceding the first dose of study vaccine or planned administration during the study period. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, including human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. Any clinically relevant abnormal haematological or biochemical or urine laboratory values at screening. Any acute or chronic, clinically significant disease, as determined by physical examination or laboratory screening tests. Acute disease and/or fever at study entry. Pregnant or lactating female. Female planning to become pregnant or planning to discontinue contraceptive precautions. History of; or current alcoholism and/or drug abuse. Any other condition that the principal investigator judges may interfere with study findings.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>young adults</keyword>
	<keyword>Staphylococcus aureus</keyword>
</DOC>