<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02920723</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sleep apnoea affects more than 20% of people over 65 years and is largely underdiagnosed. It does multiply tenfold the occurrence of vascular events, particularly stroke. While Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) is currently the Gold standard treatment to prevent cerebrovascular and cardiovascular events, with a major clinical benefit, long term adherence to CPAP is a significant problem and search for alternative treatment is essential.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Follow-up of the Patients Included in the EXESAS Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In the previous EXESAS study (NCT02463890) the investigators compare evolution of Apnea Hypopnea Index (AHI) in an exercise trained group performed through in a national based non-profit organization (Fédération Française d'éducation Physique et de Gymnastique Volontaire (FFEPGV)) using a medical established program (NeuroGyV) during nine months against a control group receiving only standard dietetic and physical activity counseling. The first partial observations of the study EXESAS seem encouraging in the term of 3 months of training. However, in the longer term, there is not a coverage in the treatment of the moderate Sleep Apnea: Obstructive Syndrome (SAOS). Thus they can logically expect that the possible therapeutic effect of the exercise is not maintained in the long term after the stop of the training. This nex study suggests studying the profit of the exercise on sleep apneas for the patients who were initially in the control group in the EXESAS study and to observe if the preservation of a regular physical activity for the group which was trained in EXESAS study is associated with a preservation of the AHI after the additional year of follow-up without additional intervention</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Included in the previous EXESAS study Signature of consent Patients being already treated for sleep apnea or clinical status (cardiovascular comorbidities) justifying an immediate initiation of CPAP Daytime sleepiness (ESS score &gt; 10) Known respiratory or heart disease (or discovering during stress test) contraindicated exercise training Patients with Parkinson's disease AHI &gt; 30</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</keyword>
	<keyword>Sleep Apnea, Obstructives</keyword>
	<keyword>Training</keyword>
</DOC>