<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02920892</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall goals are to change the paradigm for development of mechanism targeted pharmacotherapy in neurodevelopmental disorders and provide a definitive test of the mGluR theory in humans by determining whether AFQ056, an mGluR5 negative modulator, can enhance neural plasticity in the form of language learning during an intensive language intervention in very young children with fragile X syndrome. This trial therefore will use an innovative but exploratory new trial design to develop a different way to examine efficacy of an agent with substantial support as a drug targeting CNS plasticity in preclinical models of a developmental disorder. If the design is successful, this trial can serve as a model for future trials of mechanistically-targeted treatments operating on neural plasticity in other neurodevelopmental disorders.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>AFQ056 for Language Learning in Children With FXS</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The trial will use a double blind placebo-controlled parallel-group flexible-dose forced titration design in which 100 subjects with FXS, age 32 months to 6 years of age will enter a 8-month placebo-controlled phase in which they are randomized 1:1 to AFQ056 or placebo followed by an 8-month (open label) extension phase in which all participants will be treated with active drug. The flexible dose design will mimic practice, take into account differential responsiveness and the known inter-child variability in drug levels with AFQ056, and allow use of maximum tolerated dose (MTD) which is likely to be most effective.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fragile X Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 32 months to 6 years inclusive. 2. Has an FMR1 full mutation. 3. DQ&lt;75 on the Mullen Early Learning Composite (ELC) at time of screening. 4. Parent or legal guardian is available and able to communicate well with the investigator, comply with study requirements and provide written informed consent. **Note**The Parent or legal guardian who will be signing consent form, should be the individual administering the language intervention 5. English is the primary language spoken in the home and the subject's first language is English. 6. Meet criteria indicating evidence of intentional communication based on parent interview via a communication eligibility screening tool. **Note** On the Eligibility Screening Tool Communication, the child must have at time of screening: a) Section 1: Answer of YES; the child uses at least 5 spoken words to label items on a daily basis. OR b) Section 2: At least 3 YES answers to items 110 if child does not have at least 5 spoken words. 7. Produces 3 or more intentional acts of communication on the structured portion of the Weighted Communication play sample at time of screening. 8. Stable behavioral and other therapy regimen for 30 days prior to screening. **Note** Patients will be allowed to continue their standardofcare therapies throughout the trial but these will not be changed during the placebo leadin or placebocontrolled portion of the trial, outside of standard changes occurring from school schedules. 9. Stable dosing of all concurrent psychotropic medications for at least 60 days prior to screening. Note** Medications impacting GABA, glutamate and/or mGluR5 pathway receptors are exclusionary and not permitted during study participation. 1. Use of medications impacting GABA, glutamate and/or mGluR5 pathway receptors or transmission. Note** Treatment with acamprosate, amantadine, budipine, carbetocin, cycloserine, dextromethorphan, felbamate, ketamine, lithium, minocycline, memantine, oxytocin, remacemide, racemic baclofen, riluzole, fycampa, investigational mGluR5 medications, and/or statins are exclusionary. 2. Unstable seizure disorder as defined by any seizure in the 6 months prior to the screening visit, and/or any change in anticonvulsant drug dosing in the 60 days prior to screening. **Note** Use of levetiracetam and oxcarbazepine are among permitted anticonvulsants. 3. Use of any other investigational drug at the time of enrollment or within 30 days or 5 half lives (whichever is longer) of the investigational drug prior to screening until end of study visits (or longer if required by local regulations). 4. History of hypersensitivity to AFQ056 or any mGluR antagonist. 5. History or presence of any clinically significant disease of any major system organ class, within the past 2 years prior to screening including but not limited to neurological, cardiovascular, endocrine, metabolic, renal, or gastrointestinal disorders. This does not include typical features of FXS such as psychological symptoms or history of epileptic seizures. 6. Significant acute illness that did not completely resolve at least four weeks prior to the first baseline visit. 7. Abnormal laboratory values at screening or first baseline that are in the opinion of the investigator are clinically significant and may jeopardize the safety of the study subject. 8. Use of (or use within at least 5 half lives before dosing) concomitant medications that are strong/moderate inhibitors or inducers of CYP1A1/2, CYP2C9/19 or CYP3A4 (see Appendix B). 9. Subjects who are, in the opinion of the investigator, unable to comply with the requirements of the study. 10. History or presence of immunodeficiency diseases, including a positive HIV test result. 11. A positive Hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) or Hepatitis C result at time of screening. 12. History or presence of suicidal thoughts and/or suicide attempts.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>32 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>