<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01290952</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Compare completeness and modality of revascularization, operative and postoperative results and 1 year clinical outcomes in unselected high risk patients referred for primary coronary artery bypass surgery. Patients will be randomized to undergo off-pump coronary artery bypass graft (OPCAB) or coronary artery bypass graft with cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB/CAB).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>On Versus Off Pump Myocardial Revascularization Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The initial application of off-pump coronary artery bypass in the early nineties was mainly directed to highly selected and relatively low risk surgical patients. Since then there has been a growing body of evidence suggesting many potential advantages of the OPCAB technique over the conventional cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB) technique in different groups of high-risk patients. On-off study is a multicentre, prospective, randomized, parallel, trial.Patients indicated for elective or urgent isolated coronary artery bypass graft with additive European System for Cardiac Operative Risk Evaluation ≥ 6 were enrolled. Patients in cardiogenic shock were excluded. Patients were randomly assigned either to coronary artery bypass surgery with cardiopulmonary bypass (ON arm) or to off-pump coronary artery bypass graft (OFF arm). The composite primary end point included operative mortality, myocardial infarction, stroke, renal failure, re-operation for bleeding and adult respiratory distress syndrome, within 30 days after surgery. The total planned sample size was 693 patients; the actual number of enrolled patients was 411,according to the results of the interim analysis scheduled at 400 enrollments (alfa-spending=0.029, Pocock method).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pts candidate to a myocardial revascularization for any patter of coronary artery disease, ventricular dysfunction or any other comorbidity EUROSCORE ≥ 6 Pts who signed the Informed Consent Age ≥ 18 years Patients in cardiogenic shock requiring emergency surgery or preoperative intraaortic balloon pump Patients requiring additional surgical procedures Porcelain Aorta Lack of informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>off-pump</keyword>
	<keyword>bypass</keyword>
	<keyword>coronary artery surgery</keyword>
</DOC>