<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01430585</DOC>
	<brief_summary>PF-04691502 is an inhibitor of PI3K and mTOR kinase. Published data support the hypothesis that a PI3K/mTOR antagonist in combination with letrozole might mitigate the intrinsic or acquired resistance to hormonal therapy and restore hormone sensitivity in high risk (high Ki-67) patient population of hormone-sensitive breast cancers. In addition, Ki-67, a marker of cellular proliferation, could be used to select those patients who benefit from treatment with a PI3K-pathway inhibitor.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pre-Operative Study of PF-4691502 With Letrozole Compared To Letrozole Alone In Patients With Early Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study was prematurely discontinued on 09Oct2012 due to the tolerability findings in 2 clinical studies testing PF-04691502 that have prompted the Sponsor to re-evaluate the strategic goals of the program. In the study B1271003 an unexpected frequency of severe skin toxicity was observed and in the study B1271004 5 cases of drug induced pneumonitis were reported.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Letrozole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Phase 1 Postmenopausal women with diagnosis of breast cancer, metastatic disease or locally advanced disease / Estrogen Receptor positive and HER2 negative / candidate to receive Letrozole Phase 2 Postmenopausal women with newly diagnosed primary breast cancer / Estrogen Receptor positive and HER2 negative / Ki67 levels &gt;10% positive cells Phase 1 &amp; 2 Glucose control, adequate bone marrow, liver, renal, and cardiac function Inflammatory carcinoma / Prior therapy with an agent active on PI3K and/or mTOR / Significant gastrointestinal abnormalities, which may impair intake, transit or absorption of the study drugs / Current or anticipated need for food or drugs that are known inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ki-67</keyword>
	<keyword>postmenopausal early breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>ER positive/HER2 negative early breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>