<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01430390</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test the safety of giving the patient special cells from a donor called "Modified T-cells". The goal is to find a safe dose of modified T-cells for patients with relapsed B cell leukemia or lymphoma after a blood SCT. The investigators also want to find out what effects these T-cells have on the patient and the disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>In Vitro Expanded Allogeneic Epstein-Barr Virus Specific Cytotoxic T-Lymphocytes (EBV-CTLs) Genetically Targeted to the CD19 Antigen in B-cell Malignancies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>History of CD19+ leukemia with evidence of bone marrow relapse or persistent MRD following allogenic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Bone marrow relapse on this protocol is &gt; 5% blasts by morphology and/or flow cytology. Persistent minimal residual disease after transplantation must be demonstrated by morphology, FISH, flow cytometry or RTPCR with at least 2 sequential testings separated by at least 1 week. History of relapsed or refractory CD19+ malignancies (e.g. Non Hodgkin Lymphoma) who have failed prior treatment and require autologous hematopoietic stem cell transplant. Evidence of disease not required. No age restriction for patients KPS or Lansky score &gt; or = to 40 Renal function (measured prior to conditioning chemotherapy) Hepatic function (measured prior to conditioning chemotherapy): AST ≤ 5 x the institutional ULN Elevation secondary to leukemic involvement is not an exclusion criterion. Leukemic involvement will be determined by the presence of progressive relapse defined by escalating bone marrow or peripheral blood leukemia blasts within the previous month and the absence of initiation of know hepatotoxic medication (e.g. azoles). Total bilirubin ≤ 2.5 x the institutional ULN Adequate cardiac function (e.g. LVEF ≥ 40%) as assessed by ECHO or MUGA or other similar cardia imaging performed within 1 month of enrollment. Pulmonary function (measured prior to conditioning chemotherapy): Oxygen saturation ≥ 90% on room air Donor Eligibility: The patient's HSCT donor, or if HSCT donor is not available a third party donor, must consent to a leukapheresis or whole blood donation(s) obtained at one or more phlebotomies which, in aggregate, will total approximately 250 ml for adults and no more than 5ml/kg per draw from pediatric donors. Related donors &lt;18 years of age requiring placement of a leukapheresis catheter will donate peripheral blood collected by phlebotomy (including a unit of blood if weight permits) and shall not undergo catheter placement for leukapheresis as this is considered above minimal risk to the donor. There is no upper age limit for a donors. However, the minimum age for a related donor is 7 years as this is the youngest age a person can be considered capable of giving assent to participate in a research study. Evidence of prior sensitization to EBV by EBV serology testing (seropositive) Donor's high resolution HLA typing must be available for review CBC within one week of donation. Results of tests must be within a range that would not preclude donating blood or undergoing leukapheresis. Serologic testing for transmissible diseases will be performed as per institutional guidelines adopted from extant NMDP and FACT guidelines. Donors should be considered eligible to donate leukapheresis or blood based on these guidelines (i.e. blood donation guidelines) Patients with active HIV, hepatitis B or hepatitis C infection. Patients with any concurrent active malignancies as defined by malignancies requiring any therapy other than expectant observation. Females who are pregnant. Patients will be excluded if they have isolated extramedullary relapse of ALL. Previous infusion of CD19 CAR T cells at another institution Patients with active (grade 24) acute graft versus host disease (GVHD), chronic GVHD or an overt autoimmune disease (e.g. hemolytic anemia) requiring glucocorticosteroid treatment (&gt;0.5 mg/kg/day prednisone or its equivalent) as treatment Active central nervous system (CNS) leukemia, as defined by unequivocal morphologic evidence of lymphoblasts in the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) or symptomatic CNS leukemia (i.e. cranial nerve palsies or other significant neurologic dysfunction) within 28 days of treatment. Prophylactic intrathecal medication is not a reason for exclusion. Adult patients (≥18 years old) with the following cardiac conditions will be excluded: New York Heart Association (NYHA) stage III or IV congestive heart failure Myocardial infarction ≤ 6months prior to enrollment History of clinically significant ventricular arrhythmia or unexplained syncope, not believed to be vasovagal in nature or due to dehydration. History of severe nonischemic cardiomyopathy with EF ≤20%</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>In Vitro Expanded Allogeneic Epstein-Barr Virus Specific Cytotoxic</keyword>
	<keyword>T-Lymphocytes (EBV-CTLs)</keyword>
	<keyword>CD19 specific T-cells</keyword>
	<keyword>11-038</keyword>
</DOC>