<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02315898</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Plastic bronchitis (PB) is a rare, most often pediatric disease characterized by the formation of obstructive airway casts primarily composed of fibrin. There is presently no FDA-approved pharmacotherapy for PB, but acute exacerbations of the illness are often treated with inhaled tissue plasminogen activator (tPA). To date, this is done somewhat anecdotally because there has been no safety or efficacy testing of this treatment. In addition, there is presently no reliable surrogate marker of adverse drug events. Nevertheless, in the absence of inhaled tPA treatment, PB-induced respiratory distress can be severe, often warranting urgent or emergent bronchoscopy for cast removal, or can sometimes result in respiratory failure. As such there is a significant unmet need for safety and efficacy testing of inhaled tPA and for biomarkers of drug response. Objectives and Endpoints: The objectives of this protocol are to: 1) test the safety and efficacy of an inhaled tPA regimen in children with PB; and 2) identify potential candidate biomarkers of inhaled tPA drug response. Safety endpoints will consist of the development of new, active bleeding that is systemic and/or pulmonary and/or new hematuria (defined as gross hematuria or 2+ microscopic hematuria). Secondary endpoints of efficacy will also be measured (e.g., frequency of cast production). Urine and blood will also be collected for the development of potential biomarkers of inhaled tPA drug response.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Inhaled Tissue Plasminogen Activator for Acute Plastic Bronchitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Bronchitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Plasminogen</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tissue Plasminogen Activator</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. greater than or equal to 5years of age but less than or equal to16 years of age 2. Patients presenting with acute exacerbation of PB or a history of PB with previous pathologic evidence of fibrin airway cast production 3. Must be able to use a mouthpiece nebulizer 4. Informed consent (with parental if age &gt; 14 years) or assent for age &gt; 10 and &lt; 14 years old with parental informed consent 1. Known contraindication(s) to the use of tPA, including: active internal bleeding; history of cerebrovascular accident; recent intracranial or intraspinal surgery or trauma; intracranial neoplasm, arteriovenous malformation or aneurysm; • known bleeding diathesis; and/or severe uncontrolled hypertension 2. Known cystic fibrosis 3. Currently receiving inhaled tPA and/or dornasealpha 4. Protein losing enteropathy 5. Liver dysfunction (defined as &gt;3X the normal levels of liver function tests) 6. Need for concomitant intravenous or subcutaneous anticoagulation with resulting anti Xa levels &gt; 0.5 (low molecular weight heparins) or &gt; 0.3 (unfractionated heparin) 7. International normalized ratio (INR) &gt; 2.0 if not receiving warfarin 8. Patients being actively treated for thrombosis 9. Concomitant use of a thienopyridine class antiplatelet agent (e.g., clopidogrel) 10. A platelet count of &lt; 100,000 platelets/μL 11. A hematocrit &lt;35% (females) or &lt;40% (males) 12. Gross hematuria or 2+ microscopic hematuria on screening urinalysis 13. Pregnant or lactating women (negative pregnancy test required for girls/women of</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>