<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02575482</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the safety, tolerability and pharmacokinetics of SUVN-D4010 in healthy male subjects following single or multiple ascending doses.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Investigate the Safety, Tolerability and Pharmacokinetics of SUVN-D4010 in Healthy Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single and multiple ascending dose study to assess the safety, tolerability and pharmacokinetics of SUVN-D4010 administered orally once a day to healthy male subjects. The study will be conducted under double blind conditions. The primary objective is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of SUVN-D4010 following oral administration of single or multiple ascending doses and estimate the maximum tolerated dose of SUVN-D4010,if possible. The secondary objectives are to evaluate the single and repeat dose plasma pharmacokinetics following oral administration of single and multiple ascending doses of SUVN-D4010 in healthy male subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy male aged 18 to 45 years with a BMI between 18 and 30 kg/m2, (inclusive). Standard exclusion criterion for Phase 1 clinical trial in healthy subjects. History of any clinically significant disease or disorder which, in the opinion of the Investigator, may either put the volunteer at risk because of participation in the study, or influence the results or the volunteer's ability to participate History or presence of GI, hepatic, or renal disease or any other condition known to interfere with absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of drugs as judged by Investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>SUVN-D4010</keyword>
	<keyword>serotonin 4 (5-HT4) receptor</keyword>
	<keyword>first in human</keyword>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>tolerability</keyword>
	<keyword>single dose</keyword>
	<keyword>repeat dose</keyword>
</DOC>