<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02575742</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The reason chronic constipation (CC) becomes commoner with age is not fully understood. New studies suggest that bowel contraction patterns, dietary fibre and gut bacteria are important and may differ in older people. Since CC reduces quality of life and is a major reason why elderly are admitted to hospitals and residential care, there is a need to understand how these factors change with age. Currently, placing a pressure sensing catheter inside the large intestine (pancolonic manometry) is the gold standard way to measure how well it contracts. However this involves a camera test (colonoscopy) which is invasive with risks of bowel perforations (~80/100,000). The risk is higher with age (64-80yr: ~90/100,000; 80+yrs: ~120/100,000), making it unethical for elderly. A technique called the 3D-Transit System has been developed, involving a small ingestible capsule, containing a 'trackable' electromagnet. By tracking movements of the capsule swallowed by participants, it provides precise detailed information on the capsule progression inside the whole gut and large bowel's contractile activity in real-time. It is minimally-invasive and radiation-free, making it possible to assess elderly for the first time. This study aims to assess how bowel contraction patterns, dietary fibre intake and gut bacteria differ between young and older adults (with and without CC), to better understand why CC is more common in elderly. It is a pilot, 4 arm, single centre, observational study involving 60 women aged 18-40 years and 70-90 years (15 non-constipated and 15 with CC for each age group). The study lasts 3 weeks, containing 2 weeks of run-in period and 1 week of study period. The four groups participants will be asked to: swallow 2 capsules to assess their large bowel's contractile function using the 3D-transit system; provide stool samples to analyses their gut bacteria; and complete questionnaires to assess their gastrointestinal symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Colonic Motility in Constipation and Ageing</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Constipation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for constipated group Aged 1840 or 7090 years of age Barthel index ≥11 [for elderly women only] No coexisting acute or chronic diseases at the time of recruitment (except hypertension and hypercholesterolemia for elderly women) Patients with selfreported problematic constipation Cleveland Clinic Constipation Score ≥8 Bowel movement frequency &lt;3 per week Stool consistency of 13 on the Bristol Stool Chart No evidence of organic causes of constipation Symptoms of constipation (unsatisfactory defaecation characterized by infrequent stool, difficult stool passage or both for at least the previous 3 months) Inclusion criteria for nonconstipated group Healthy women aged 1840 or 7090 years of age No coexisting acute or chronic diseases at the time of recruitment (except hypertension and hypercholesterolemia for elderly women) Barthel index ≥11 [for elderly women only] Cleveland Clinic Constipation Score &lt;8 Inability to understand written and spoken English Lacking capacity to understand subject information sheet and give informed consent Vulnerable subject groups (e.g. elderly with dementia) Pregnancy, intention to become pregnant, or breastfeeding during study period Recent childbirth in the last 6 months Other causes of reduced / dysregulated GI motility and secondary constipation Conditions which make it unsafe to use the capsules</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>