<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01881958</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Type 1 diabetes is caused by an autoimmune process resulting in a selective destruction of the pancreatic insulin-secreting beta-cell. DiaPep277® is a small, lyophilized powder containing 24 Amino-acids. We have proved in former studies that DiaPep277® can slow down beta cells destruction in the pancreas and therefore decelerate the progress of Diabetes. The objective of the study is to assess the efficacy and safety of administrating DiaPep277® in type 1 diabetes patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Safety and Efficacy of Administrating DiaPep277® Vaccination in Type 1 Diabetes Patients.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>1. Fasting Cpeptide levels &gt;= 0.2nmol/L. 2. Diagnosis of type 1 diabetes 3. No pregnancies or planned pregnancies of female subjects 1. The subject has any significant diseases or conditions, including psychiatric disorders and substance abuse that, in the opinion of the Investigator, are likely to affect the subject's response to treatment or the ability to complete the study. 2. The subject has a history of any kind of malignant tumor (not including basal cell skin cancer). 3. The subject has clinical evidence of any diabetesrelated complication that in the opinion of the Investigator would interfere with the subject's participation in and/or completion of the study. 4. Subject has history of endogenous allergic reactivity: Severe allergic reaction or severe exacerbation of allergic asthma within 12 months prior to the ScreeningExt Visit. Ongoing systemic asthma treatment. Subjects with history of life threatening or severe allergy, reoccurrence of which cannot be ruled out based on the Investigator's judgment. 5. The subject has known allergy to lipid emulsions. 6. The subject has a known immune deficiency from any disease, or a condition associated with an immune deficiency. 7. The subject is receiving immunosuppressive or immunomodulating agents or cytotoxic therapy or any medication that in the opinion of the Investigator might interfere with the study. 8. The subject has any of the following clinically significant laboratory abnormalities: Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) greater than three times the upper limit of the normal (ULN) at the ScreeningExt Visit. Total bilirubin greater than 1.3 times the ULN at the ScreeningExt Visit. Subjects with severe renal failure at the ScreeningExt visit (as defined by glomerular filtration rate &lt; 30 mL/min/1.73 m2 by Cockroft und Gault calculation • Clinically significant laboratory abnormalities, confirmed by repeat measurement, which may interfere with the assessment of safety and / or efficacy of the study drug, other than hyperglycemia and glycosuria at the ScreeningExt Visit. Fasting triglycerides &lt;1000 mg/dL (11.3 mmol/L) at the ScreeningExt Visit. Suitable medical therapy for treatment of hyperlipidemia is allowed. 9. The subject is a known or suspected drug abuser. 10. The subject is known to test positive for HIV antibodies. 11. The subject has chronic hematologic disease. 12. The subject has liver disease such as cirrhosis or chronic active hepatitis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>