<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01881347</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present study is designed to test the hypothesis that resveratrol supplementation will improve the function of the endothelium in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. The function of the endothelium will be tested with a non-invasive technique that uses ultrasound to measure the amount of dilation that occurs in the brachial artery following 5-minute cuff occlusion. To help us understand potential mechanisms of benefit, we will also collect blood, urine, and cell samples and test the effects of treatment on protein expression, nitric oxide production, and function of mitochondria.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Resveratrol on Endothelial Function in Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Resveratrol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female subjects Age over 21 years old Body mass index less than 38 kg/m2 Clinical stable type 2 diabetes mellitus Women who are lactating or pregnant Treatment with an investigations product within 30 days of screening Clinically evident major illness of other organ systems, including cancer, renal failure, or other conditions in the opinion of the investigators that would make clinical study inappropriate Liver transaminase levels greater than 3 times the upper limit of normal History of psychological illness or condition that would interfere with the subject's ability to understand the requirements of the study Vitamin supplements exceeding two times the recommended daily allowance Resveratrol or other dietary supplements except for a daily multivitamin</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>endothelium</keyword>
	<keyword>mitochondria</keyword>
	<keyword>reactive oxygen species</keyword>
	<keyword>vascular biology</keyword>
	<keyword>arterial stiffness</keyword>
	<keyword>nitric oxide</keyword>
</DOC>