<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01475812</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Introduction: Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease is a condition characterized by airflow limitation usually progressive and associated with inflammatory response of lung noxious particles. During a physical activity chronic obstructive pulmonary disease patients may develop dynamic pulmonary hyperinflation, increased dyspnea perception and decreased activity performance. The investigators hypothesize that some specific activities of daily living induce dynamic pulmonary hyperinflation in COPD patients. Objective: To measure dynamic lung hyperinflation and its influence in dyspnea perception in moderate and severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease patients after activities of daily living. Methods: The investigators measured inspiratory capacity, dyspnea sensation, peripheral oxygen saturation, heart rate and respiratory rate in 19 chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) patients. These measurements were taken at rest and after daily living activities (such as going up and down a set of stairs, going up and down a ramp and sweeping and mopping a room).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Daily Activities Are Sufficient to Induce Dynamic Pulmonary Hyperinflation and Dyspnea in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>COPD patients diagnosed with moderate to very severe airway obstruction according to GOLD classification (9) clinical stability with no clinical exacerbation during the previous 30 days prior to the beginning of the study and to sign an informed consent form Inability to perform the slow vital capacity maneuver excessive perceived dyspnea during the test arterial oxyhemoglobin saturation (SpO2) lower than 80% during activities and/or need of oxygen supplementation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
	<keyword>activities of daily living</keyword>
	<keyword>pulmonary hyperinflation</keyword>
	<keyword>exercise</keyword>
</DOC>