<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01475513</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Birth control pills are the most commonly used method of birth control. The purpose of this research study is to examine whether birth control pills change heart disease risk and how the body handles blood sugar when given to different women.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Oral Contraceptives, Insulin Resistance and Cardiovascular Risk Profile in Pre-Menopausal Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The oral contraceptive pill is the most commonly used birth control method. It is debated whether the birth control pill affects how the body handles insulin and sugar, or whether the pill changes heart disease risk. The goal of this study is to evaluate whether certain factors, such as how the body processes hormones, and demographic factors (e.g. body weight and race), influence how the pill affects the handling of insulin and sugar, and heart health.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Norgestimate, ethinyl estradiol drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Contraceptive Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Contraceptives, Oral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Moxifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Premenopausal, regularcycling women 1835 years Either AfricanAmerican or Caucasian (AfricanAmerican and Caucasian women will be BMImatched) nonsmoker. Diabetes Clinically significant pulmonary, cardiac, renal, hepatic, neurologic, psychiatric, infectious, and malignant disease Contraindications to oral contraceptive use (history of blood clots, heart attacks or stroke, vascular disease, coagulopathy, prolonged immobilization, breast cancer, migraine headaches, major surgery within past 6 months, blood pressure &gt;160/100 mmHg, pregnancy or lactation) Use of hormonal contraceptives, glucoselowering medications, antihyperlipidemic, antihypertensive or other vasoactive drugs within previous 3 months</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>oral contraceptive</keyword>
	<keyword>birth control pill</keyword>
	<keyword>women</keyword>
	<keyword>healthy volunteer</keyword>
	<keyword>insulin sensitivity</keyword>
	<keyword>insulin resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiovascular risk factors</keyword>
	<keyword>endothelial function</keyword>
	<keyword>estrogen metabolism</keyword>
	<keyword>racial difference</keyword>
	<keyword>glucose intolerance</keyword>
</DOC>