<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01768858</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this study is to assess patients` adherence attitudes (beliefs) to the maintenance therapy with a scheduled Adalimumab monotherapy or a combination therapy with methotrexate and to investigate whether there are correlations between such beliefs and adherence to maintenance treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of Rheumatoid Arthritis, Psoriatic Arthritis, Ankylosing Spondylitis, Plaque Psoriasis, Crohn's Disease and Ulcerative Colitis Patients´ Adherence Attitudes to Maintenance Therapy With a Scheduled Adalimumab Treatment in Routine Clinical Practice</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a non-interventional, observational study in which Humira (adalimumab) is prescribed in the usual manner in accordance with the terms of the local marketing authorization with regards to dose, population and indication. The assignment of the patient to a Humira-containing regimen has to be decided in advance and has to be current practice. The prescription of Humira is clearly separated from the decision to include the participant in this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spondylitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spondylitis, Ankylosing</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Psoriatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients aged &gt;=18 years with RA, PsA, AS, PsO, CD, UC Patients must fulfill international and national guidelines for the use of a BDMARD in RA, PsA, AS, PsO, CD, UC (Chest Xray and IGRA interferon gamma release assay or PPDskin test negative for tuberculosis). In addition one of the following criteria must be fulfilled: 1. unsatisfactory DMARD response defined as failure to treatment with at least two DMARDs including Methotrexate in patients with RA or PsA 2. unsatisfactory NSAID response in patients with AS 3. unsatisfactory response to prior BDMARDs in patients with RA or PsA or AS. 4. unsatisfactory response to or contraindication to, or intolerance to other systemic therapy including cyclosporine, methotrexate or PUVA in patients with PsO. Unsatisfactory response despite a full and adequate course of therapy with a corticosteroid and/or an immunosuppressant; or intolerance or medical contraindications for such therapies in CD. 5. unsatisfactory response to conventional therapy including corticosteroids and 6mercaptopurine (6MP) or azathioprine (AZA), or intolerance to or medical contraindications for such therapies in UC. Patients who are not covered in the latest version of the Humira syringe® SPC and Humira Pen® SPC; Patients participating in another study program or clinical trial. Patients who have been treated with Adalimumab before</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>Morbus Crohn</keyword>
	<keyword>Adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>Spondylitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Ulcerative colitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Monoclonals</keyword>
	<keyword>Rheumatoid</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibodies</keyword>
	<keyword>Ankylosing</keyword>
	<keyword>Plaque psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Psoriatic</keyword>
	<keyword>Crohn´s disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Antirheumatic Agents</keyword>
</DOC>