<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01924611</DOC>
	<brief_summary>AIM: To evaluate influence of two methods to avoid saliva contamination on the survival rate of atraumatic restorations in primary molars. 232 children, aged between 6-7 years, of both genders, were selected having one primary molar with a proximal dentine lesion. The children were randomly divided into two groups: a control group with class II ART restoration made using cotton rolls and an experimental group using rubber dam. The restorations were made and they were followed up every six months. After two years, the results were compilated and analyzed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Two Years Survival Rate of Class II ART Restorations in Primary Molars Using Two Ways to Avoid Saliva Contamination</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To evaluate influence of two methods to avoid saliva contamination on the survival rate of atraumatic restorations in primary molars. 232 children, aged between 6-7 years, of both genders, were selected having one primary molar with a proximal dentine lesion. The children were randomly divided into two groups: a control group with class II ART restoration made using cotton rolls and an experimental group using rubber dam. The restorations were made and they were followed up every six months. After two years, the results were compilated and analyzed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dental Caries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children of both genders enrolled in school, Children aged between 6 and 7 years, having cavity with access to ART hand instruments, cavity with a mesiodistal maximum dimension of 1mm and a buccallingual maximum dimension of 2mm length, measured on the oclusal surface, proximal surface of the adjacent tooth should be unimpaired, without visible lesions, Cavity lesions having pulpal involvement, swelling, fistula or pain were not included in the study, Children out of the age range,</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>7 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dental caries</keyword>
	<keyword>Atraumatic Restorative Technique</keyword>
</DOC>