<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01924533</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a phase III, multi-centre study of olaparib in combination with paclitaxel, compared with placebo in combination with paclitaxel in patients with advanced gastric cancer who have progressed following first-line therapy. Patients will be from China, Japan , Korea and Taiwan.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Study of Olaparib in Combination With Paclitaxel to Treat Advanced Gastric Cancer.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A randomized, double-blinded, multicentre phase III study to access the efficacy and safety of olaparib in combination with paclitaxel, compared with placebo in combination with paclitaxel in Asian patients with advanced gastric cancer (including gastro-oesophageal junction) who have progressed following first line therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Olaparib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Advanced gastric cancer (including GEJ) that has progressed following firstline therapy. Patients must be ≥18 years of age. Age ≥20 if Japanese Provision of tumour sample (from either a resection or biopsy). At least one lesion (measurable and/or nonmeasurable) that can be accurately assessed by imaging (CT/MRI) at baseline and following up visits. More than one prior chemotherapy regimen (except for adjuvant/neoadjuvant chemotherapy with more than 6 month wash out period) for the treatment of gastric cancer in the advanced setting. Any previous treatment with a Polyadenosine 5'diphosphoribose [poly(ADPribose)] polymerisation (PARP) inhibitor, including olaparib. Patients with second primary cancer, except: adequately treated nonmelanoma skin cancer, curatively treated insitu cancer of the cervix, or other solid tumours curatively treated with no evidence of disease for ≥5 years. Human Epidermalgrowth Factor Receptor2 (HER2) positive patients.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>