<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01924078</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present study is to determine the adverse effects and clinical efficacy of AI combined with Capecitabine metronomic chemotherapy in postmenopausal breast cancer patients with Estrogen receptor and/or Progestrogen receptor positive.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Capecitabine Metronomic Chemotherapy Plus Aromatase Inhibitor for Postmenopausal Hormone Receptor Positive Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Capecitabine (Xeloda ®) is currently the most biologically active oral fluoropyrimidine drug, and is widely used as first-line and second-line rescue therapy for advanced breast cancer ,third-generation aromatase inhibitors (AI) is the preferred adjuvant endocrine therapy for Postmenopausal hormone-sensitive breast cancer. Study showed that AI combined with metronomic chemotherapy could improve the objective response and clinical benefit in neoadjuvant therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aromatase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Hormone receptor positive; 2. previously untreated patients who do not receive hormonal therapy, or initial endocrine treatment failure or first line endocrine treatment of relapse and metastasis failure; 3. patients who do not receive hormonal therapy must be histologically confirmed invasive ductal carcinoma, can be surgery, but must be satisfied one of the following: (1) elderly (≥70 years), or with severe heart or other systemic complications, belonging to high risk of general anesthesia, (2) have will of conserving the breast,but larger tumors (≥3cm) not suitable for breastconserving surgery. 4. patients with metastatic breast cancer must have evaluable lesions 5. normal laboratory values: 6. informed consent (ethical approval document No. :11121051); 7. life expectancy of at least 3 months; 8. Postmenopausal or premenopausal with bilateral oophorectomy. 1. have had radiotherapy or other local treatment for measurable lesions before the start of study received within 3 months 2. organ transplant (except for autologous or allogeneic bone marrow transplantation); 3. have evidences of central nerve system metastases or have a history of mental illness that uncontrol; 4. unable to swallow tablets, or malabsorption patients, or patients with poor upper gastrointestinal integrity; 5. unwilling or unable to comply with study protocol or unable to meet the follow up; 6. patients who researchers considered were not suitable to participate.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>metronomic chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>aromatase inhibitors</keyword>
</DOC>