<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02788929</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Design: Single center, prospective, randomized study that will compare activity levels in patients who complete cardiac rehabilitation after clinically indicated percutaneous coronary intervention with and without use of the wrist-worn Fitbit Charge HR device and mobile platform application. Primary Endpoint: The average number of steps taken per day will serve as the main marker of daily physical activity. Control: Patients who do not receive the device (Fitbit Charge HR). Secondary Endpoints: (1) change in daily energy expenditure (2) change in number of activity and sedentary bouts (3) change in sleep efficiency (4) change in weekly time of moderate/vigorous physical activity (5) change in quality of life (6) change in indicators of depression (7) change in medication adherence(8) change in HDL and LDL cholesterol (9) change in BMI and waist circumference (10) change in resting heart rate and blood pressure (11) change in exercise stress test performance (timeframe for all: baseline - 12 weeks)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Increasing Exercise Adherence After Percutaneous Coronary Intervention With the Fitbit Charge HR Device</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 years or greater Willing and able to give informed consent Successful, clinicallyindicated PCI with no plan for staged procedure Clinically stable and able to exercise Access to smartphone (Apple or Android platform) Completed 10 weeks of CR and is expected to graduate program. Plan for PCI or other major surgical procedure, which would limit exercise capability, within the 14 weeks following study enrollment. Home oxygen requirement Amputation, peripheral arterial disease, other musculoskeletal or neurological disease affecting mobility Endstage renal disease Ongoing Unstable angina or CCS IV angina NYHA IV heart failure Terminal illness Dementia Fall risk (inability to hold semitandem stance for 10 seconds) Pregnant women and prisoners Any other criteria that in the opinion of the investigator would preclude patient participation in the study and/or impact exercise capability.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Percutaneous Transluminal Coronary Intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac Rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Fitbit Charge HR</keyword>
</DOC>