<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02788084</DOC>
	<brief_summary>1. Develop a Next-Generation Sequencing (NGS) workflow for mutation profiling of formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded (FFPE) tissue and cell-free DNA (cfDNA) specimens. 2. Calculate the proportion of cases in a test series of B-cell non-Hodgkin Lymphomas (BNHL) with somatic mutations or immunoglobulin heavy chain (IGH) gene rearrangements common to both FPPE and cfDNA specimens. 3. Determine if certain types of BNHL are more likely to have mutation profiles common to both FFPE &amp; corresponding cfDNA ("FFPE-cfDNA dyads") 4. Determine if specific mutations or mutation profiles in FFPE or cfDNA specimens (or both) are of prognostic value after a clinical follow-up of 2 years from the time of diagnosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Development of a Tissue-Based &amp; Cell Free DNA Next-Generation Sequencing Workflow</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with newly diagnosed B cell NHL will be identified. Samples will be cored from their diagnostic FFPE blocks and assayed to find lymphoma specific variants and immunoglobulin heavy chain gene rearrangements. Blood samples collected at baseline will be compared to see if variants and rearrangements can be detected in tumor specific DNA based on previous studies. Participant data will be collected, and clinical outcomes will be assessed to determine effect of mutation profiles on outcomes over 2 year follow up. Blood samples will be prospectively collected at scheduled follow up and if primary objectives of this study are met, will be assessed for presence of cfDNA and impact of variation on clinical outcomes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>New diagnosis of B cell NHL Willing to have blood collected at timepoints of regularly scheduled follow up Formalin fixed paraffin embedded (FFPE) diagnostic specimen sufficient for further testing Unwilling or unable to participate in follow up</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Next Generation Sequencing</keyword>
	<keyword>Cell free DNA</keyword>
</DOC>