<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00836459</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Adults that increase their physical activity can improve their health, and reduce future risks to health, but long−term changes are difficult to sustain. This study assesses whether it is worth providing further support, 3 months after giving initial advice, to those who have managed to do more physical activity. All participants will initially be given an interactive DVD. A researcher from Sheffield Hallam University will provide two telephone follow ups at one month intervals to assess physical activity levels. Only those that have increased their physical activity at this point will remain in the study. These participants will receive a "mini booster", a "full booster" or no booster. The "mini booster" consists of a two telephone calls one month apart to discuss physical activity and usage of the DVD. A "full booster" consists of a face−to−face meeting with the facilitator at the same intervals. The purpose of these booster sessions is to help the individual to maintain their increase in physical activity. The investigators will measure the differences in physical activity, quality of life and costs, associated with the booster interventions, 3 months and 9 months from randomisation. The research will be carried out in 20 of the most deprived neighbourhoods in Sheffield. These locations have large, ethnically diverse populations, high levels of economic deprivation, low levels of physical activity, poorer health and shorter life expectancy. Participants will be recruited through general practices and community groups, as well as by postal invitation to ensure the participation of minority ethnic groups and those with lower levels of literacy. Sheffield City Council and Primary Care Trust fund a range of facilities and activities to promote physical activity and variations in access to these between neighbourhoods will make it possible to examine whether the effectiveness of the intervention is modified by access to community facilities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sheffield Physical Activity Booster Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Residents of the 20 most deprived neighbourhoods in the city of Sheffield Aged 40 to 64 years Not achieving the current recommended activity level (30 mins of moderate activity on at least 5 days) assessed using the SPAQ (Lowther, 1999) and wishing to have support to become more active Have increased their physical activity level by at least 30 mins of moderate or vigorous activity per week (assessed using the SPAQ) since initial assessment of activity level Capacity to give written informed consent to trial participation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Humans</keyword>
	<keyword>Middle Aged</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavior Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Directive Counseling</keyword>
	<keyword>Health Behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>Interview, Psychological</keyword>
	<keyword>Motivation</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical Fitness</keyword>
	<keyword>Self Efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Life Style</keyword>
	<keyword>Health Promotion</keyword>
	<keyword>Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</keyword>
	<keyword>Body Mass Index</keyword>
	<keyword>Monitoring, Ambulatory</keyword>
	<keyword>Walking</keyword>
</DOC>