<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01173510</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) infection is permanently established by integrating a deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) copy into the human chromosome, a step also necessary to complete the Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV)replication cycle. Standard treatment of HIV infection suppresses Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV)replication and has not been able to eliminate Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV)from an infected person because of the integrated Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV). Raltegravir (RAL), the first approved antiretroviral (ARV) in a new class called integrase inhibitors, works by preventing integration of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV). For participants with Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV)who have never taken antiretroviral medications, this research study will test whether Raltegravir (RAL), a recommended first-line ARV, can eliminate Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV)from key immune system cells.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pilot Study to Determine if Raltegravir Eradicates HIV From Peripheral Blood Mononuclear Cells</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase IV study comparing RAL to EFV ability to clear the HIV from mononuclear cells. Participants will be randomized 2:1 to either RAL plus co-formulated FTC/TDF or EFV/FTC/TDF (Atripla). The study will last a minimum of 24 weeks. Participants will come in three days before the weeks 4 and 24 visits to receive a subcutaneous injection of G-CSF, an FDA-approved medication that mobilizes certain cells. A minimum of 5 visits will be required after baseline for blood draws, safety monitoring, or G-CSF injections.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine, Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Efavirenz, Emtricitabine, Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Raltegravir Potassium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subjects age 18 or older with HIV1 infection CD4 cell counts greater than 200 cells/mm at screening Plasma HIV RNA &gt; 1000 copies/mL Women of childbearing potential must be using an adequate method of contraception to avoid pregnancy throughout the study and for up to eight weeks after the last dose of study drug. Women of childbearing potential includes any woman who has experienced menarche and who has not undergone successful surgical sterilization or who is not postmenopausal. Previous exposure to antiretroviral medications used in the treatment of HIV1 infection Evidence of genotypic or phenotypic resistance to most of the medications that will be used in the study (tenofovir, emtricitabine, and efavirenz) on a resistance assay obtained through the patient's primary care physicians as a standard of care test Women with a positive pregnancy test, who are pregnant, or who are breast feeding Sexually active nonsterilized men not using effective birth control if they have female partners who are of childbearing potential Women of childbearing potential who are unwilling or unable to use an acceptable method to avoid pregnancy for the entire study period and for up to eight weeks after the last dose of study drug Presence of any currently active AIDSdefining category C conditions according to the CDC Classification System for HIV Infection with the exception of stable cutaneous Kaposi's sarcoma Any active, clinically significant disease that in the opinion of the Principal Investigator may compromise the subject's safety during the trial Grade 3 or 4 Laboratory abnormalities as defined by a standardized grading scheme based on the DAIDS table ACTG Toxicity Grading Scale elevations (except preexisting diabetes mellitus with asymptomatic, nonfasting glucose grade 3 elevations, asymptomatic ≥ grade 3 fasting triglyceride or cholesterol elevations, and subjects with elevated indirect bilirubin) Active substance abuse or significant psychiatric illness that in the opinion of the Principal Investigator may interfere with study compliance Prisoners or subjects who are involuntarily incarcerated Subjects who are compulsorily detained for treatment of either a psychiatric or physical (e.g. infectious disease) illness Known hypersensitivity to GCSF</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS</keyword>
	<keyword>Atripla</keyword>
	<keyword>Truvada</keyword>
	<keyword>Raltegravir</keyword>
	<keyword>Human Immunodeficiency Virus</keyword>
	<keyword>Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome Virus</keyword>
</DOC>