<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01173094</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this trial is to find out the appropriate way to treat DM patients with critical limb ischemia. This trial includes two parts. Part I focuses on the treatment of femoral arterial lesion and part II focuses on the treatment of below-knee arterial lesion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Optimized Strategy for Diabetic Patients With Critical Limb Ischemia(Part II) (DCLI-II)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The trial includes two parts and here is part II. This part is a multi-center, prospective, registration study which focuses on the treatment of below-knee arterial lesion. Totally 130 patients will be entered into this part. They should suffer ischemic symptom with Rutherford 3-6 for the occlusion of the below-knee arteries(anterior tibial、posterior tibial or peroneal artery). According to the lesion length, the patients will accept transluminal angioplasty or below-knee arterial bypass. They will be followed up for 3 years. Study examinations will be done at screening, procedure time, 1, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months after procedure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patients volunteer to join the trial and sign the formal consent. The patients are ≥55 yearold and ≤75 yearold. The patients suffer from symptomatic leg ischemia with rutherford classification3, 4 , 5 or 6. Obvious stenosis or occlusion in belowknee popliteal artery No obvious stenosis or occlusion in the aortoiliac artery; or the lesion could be treated simultaneously or has already been cured. No surgical contraindications;no infection in operation region. Be diagnosed with DM for at least 1 year. Refuse random treatment. Previous operations on the target artery. Acute lower extremity arterial thrombosis. Serious major organ failure. Allergic to the contrast agent or has contrast nephropathy. No clinical compliance or unfit to join the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Critical limb ischemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes foot</keyword>
</DOC>