<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01419444</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research is to determine whether treatment of voice disorders can be provided just as effectively using telemedicine as it can using on-site, traditional therapy. An exercise protocol for improving airflow with voicing has been demonstrated to be effective in a prior UAMS investigation (Protocol 107454). These exercises are used as part of the normal clinic routine at UAMS working with individuals with voice problems. The three exercises used are: gargling with and without voicing; cup bubble blowing with and without voicing; and, stretch and flow exercises, which involves the use of a piece of tissue to provide visual biofeedback on the ability to use proper airflow with voicing. The purpose of the exercises is to increase airflow and breathiness in the voice and reduce muscle tension. In addition, patients will be taught to use a "confidential voice" or gentle voice during speaking. The investigators voice patients come from all over the state and many cannot return for regular treatment. Developing a way to provide treatment to them closer to home could greatly improve quality of care and quality of life. Twenty participants will participate for 12 sessions each. All participants will be evaluated at UAMS before and after treatment as part of standard care and will, upon consent, be randomized to receive treatment via telemedicine at an AHEC site or at UAMS Medical Center. Homework will be provided along with log sheets. Results of airflow measures using an airflow-recording device (Viasys, KAY/PENTAX) pre- and post treatment will determine whether telemedicine results are equal to results of traditional, on-site treatment. The investigators hypothesize that results from treatment using telemedicine will be equivalent to results for onsite, traditional treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Telemedicine Versus Traditional Treatment of Muscle Tension Dysphonia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dysphonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hoarseness</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Primary or Secondary Muscle Tension Dysphonia Head and Neck Cancer Spasmodic Dysphonia Tremor Respiratory Compromise Dysphagia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Voice</keyword>
	<keyword>Muscle Tension Dysphonia</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment</keyword>
</DOC>