<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01419496</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Studying samples of tissue from patients with cancer in the laboratory may help doctors learn more about cancer and development of drug resistance in patients. PURPOSE: This research trial is studying proteins that may promote chemotherapy resistance in samples from patients with acute myeloid leukemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Proteins in Promoting Chemotherapy Resistance in Samples From Patients With Acute Myeloid Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Investigate whether changes in prosurvival signaling occur by comparing activation of the signal transducer and activator of transcription-3 (Stat3) and Stat5 pathways in paired diagnostic and relapse samples. - Investigate changes in leukemia cell responses to extrinsic cues from the environment change, using a bone marrow stromal-cell co-culture model of chemotherapy resistance. OUTLINE: Cryopreserved samples are analyzed for Stat3 and Stat5 expression by flow cytometry and in vitro chemotherapy sensitivity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Paired diagnostic and relapsed cryopreserved samples from patients with acute myeloid leukemia PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Not specified PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent adult acute myeloid leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent childhood acute myeloid leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with 11q23 (MLL) abnormalities</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with inv(16)(p13;q22)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with t(15;17)(q22;q12)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with t(16;16)(p13;q22)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with t(8;21)(q22;q22)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with del(5q)</keyword>
</DOC>