<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01338506</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In comparison to the general population, U.S. military and Veterans are at an increased risk for developing both substance use disorders (SUD) and Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD). Current research has shown that there is a high comorbidity of SUD and PTSD, and although there are a number of treatments for SUD and PTSD independently, there are very few effective methods to simultaneously treat both disorders. Because of this substantial gap in the treatment of both SUDs and PTSD, it has become essential to develop a combined treatment that would address and treat both disorders. Individuals, specifically U.S. military and Veterans, with SUD/PTSD have unique needs that require a specialized treatment approach. This designed approach would employ cognitive-behavioral therapy (CBT) to treat the SUD, in conjunction with Prolonged Exposure therapy to treat the PTSD. Prolonged Exposure (PE) is an empirically supported and evidence-based treatment that is currently regarded as the "gold standard" psychosocial treatment for PTSD. In combination with CBT, this treatment would address both disorders in hopes of reducing substance use and PTSD symptomatology.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Integrated Treatment of OEF/OIF Veterans With PTSD &amp; Substance Use Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>As a result of sustained operations in Afghanistan and Iraq, there are an increasing number of U.S. military personnel and Veterans at risk of developing both substance use disorders (SUDs) and Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD). If left untreated, individuals with SUDs and/or PTSD are at risk for other mental health problems (e.g., depression), suicidal ideation and attempts, physical health problems, reduced resiliency, lost productivity, and family/relationship impairment. While mental health services are in place for U.S. military personnel, substantial gaps in the treatment of co-occurring SUDs and PTSD exist and there is little scientific evidence available to guide the provision of care. The proposed study directly addresses this knowledge gap by testing the feasibility and preliminary efficacy of an integrative behavioral intervention for the treatment of co-occurring SUDs and PTSD modified for use among U.S. military personnel (including National Guard and Reservists) who have served in Operation Enduring Freedom and/or Operation Iraqi Freedom (OEF/OIF). The intervention, called "Concurrent Treatment with Prolonged exposure" or "COPE," represents a novel treatment that integrates cognitive-behavioral therapy for SUDs with prolonged exposure therapy for PTSD. In earlier studies with civilians, COPE has demonstrated efficacy in reducing alcohol and drug use severity, PTSD symptoms, and associated mental health problems (e.g., depression, anxiety). In this hybrid Stage Ib/Stage II study, we will (1) use a manualized, well-tolerated behavioral treatment for SUDs and PTSD (COPE); (2) employ a two-arm randomized between-groups experimental design (COPE versus a modified treatment-as usual (TAU); and (3) examine standardized, repeated dependent measures of clinical outcomes and process variables at 5 time points (pre-, mid-, and post-treatment; 3 and 6 month follow-up). The proposed project is directly responsive to the mission of the National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA) and the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA) in that it seeks to enhance and accelerate research on the prevention and treatment of alcohol and drug use disorders (including illicit and prescription drugs) and comorbid conditions (e.g., PTSD, depression, sleep disturbances, HIV risk behaviors). The findings of this study will provide empirical evidence to inform policies and programs to better serve the needs of U.S. military personnel, Veterans, and their families.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Combat Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult male and female activeduty OIF/OEF military personnel and separated OIF/OEF veterans ages 1865. Diagnosis of PTSD determined by a clinicianadministered study interview. Current bipolar disorder or other psychotic disorder (as determined by the evaluator conducting the patient interview and medical record review) subjects with a current eating disorder or with dissociative identity disorder currently in ongoing therapy for SUDs or PTSD, who are not willing to discontinue these therapies for the duration of the trial recently prescribed maintenance anxiolytic, antidepressant, or mood stabilizing medications (must be stabilized for four weeks on meds before entry into study) Evidence of a moderate or severe traumatic brain injury (as determined by the inability to comprehend the baseline screening questionnaires)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Military</keyword>
	<keyword>Posttraumatic Stress Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>PTSD</keyword>
	<keyword>PostTraumatic Stress Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Combat</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychological Treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Trauma</keyword>
	<keyword>Posttraumatic Stress</keyword>
	<keyword>Prolonged Exposure</keyword>
	<keyword>Exposure therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavior Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive Behavior Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Stress Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Abuse</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Dependence</keyword>
	<keyword>Alcohol Abuse</keyword>
	<keyword>Alcohol Dependence</keyword>
	<keyword>Substance Use Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Alcoholism</keyword>
</DOC>