<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02359669</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of the study is to explore the impact of a combined intervention including a growing up milk (GUM) fortified in micronutrients and cognitive stimulation on cognitive abilities, mother-child- interaction and behavior in children of 3 to 5 years from less enriched home environments.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of a Nutritional Approach in Combination With Cognitive Stimulation on Child Cognitive Abilities</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of the study is to explore the impact of a combined intervention including a growing up milk (GUM) fortified in micronutrients and cognitive stimulation on cognitive abilities, mother-child- interaction and behavior in children of 3 to 5 years from less enriched home environments with HOME score less than 26. The control group will receive skimmed milk but no extra stimulation materials ( however, no restrictions on normal mother-child interaction). The cognitive abilities, mother-child interaction and child behavior will be assessed after a 6 months intervention.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Male or Female children, age 3;04;11 years Having obtained their legal representative's informed consent Level of stimulation in their home environment score below 26 in HOME inventory Normal cognitive development Neurological disorders Food allergies (especially milk and soy allergy) Documented lactose intolerance Children with special nutritional needs Children under chronic (more than 7 consecutive days) medications which may impact cognitive performance Children not living in a family/children in foster homes Subject who cannot be expected to comply with study procedures Currently participating or having participated in another clinical study during the last 4 weeks prior to the beginning of this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>36 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>59 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>