<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02359045</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a randomized, open-label, cross-over study in healthy subjects performed at a single study center. The study is divided into two parts, Part 1 and Part 2. The purpose of the study is to compare the pharmacokinetics (PK) of three different prototype capsule formulations (omega-3-carboxylic acids test formulations) with Epanova® capsules 1000 mg under fasted conditions in Part 1 and under fed conditions in Part 2. The results will be used as basis for choice of formulation for further pharmaceutical development.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study in Healthy Subjects to Compare the Concentrations of the Omega-3 Fatty Acids EPA and DHA in Blood When Delivered as Three New Capsules in Relation to the Epanova® Capsule Under Fasting and Fed Conditions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To assess the relative bioavailability of the different omega-3-carboxylic acids prototype capsule formulations in relation to Epanova® capsules 1000 mg under fed and fasted conditions.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Provision of signed and dated written informed consent prior to any study specific procedures. Healthy male and female (nonchildbearing potential) subjects aged 18 to 55 years with suitable veins for cannulation or repeated venipuncture. Females must have a negative pregnancy test at screening and on admission to the clinical unit, must not be lactating and must be of nonchildbearing potential, confirmed at screening by fulfilling one of the following criteria: Postmenopausal, defined as amenorrhea for at least 12 months or more following cessation of all exogenous hormonal treatments, and folliclestimulating hormone (FSH) levels in the postmenopausal range. Documentation of irreversible surgical sterilization by hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy or bilateral salpingectomy or tubal ligation. Have a body mass index (BMI) between 18.5 and 29.9 kg/m2 inclusive and weigh at least 50 kg and no more than 100 kg inclusive. History of any clinically significant disease or disorder which, in the opinion of the investigator, may either put the potential subject at risk because of participation in the study, or influences the results or the potential subject's ability to participate in the study. History or presence of gastrointestinal, hepatic or renal disease, or any other condition known to interfere with absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of drugs. Current smokers or those who have smoked or used nicotine products within the previous 3 months. Consumption of poppy seeds within 7 days of first administration of IMP. Consumption of fish within 7 days prior to admission to the clinical unit. Used fish oil, other omega3 fatty acids (EPA and/or DHA) containing supplements within 1 month of admission to the clinical unit. Have a known sensitivity or allergy to soybeans, fish and/or shellfish.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Omega-3-carboxylic acids,</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase I,</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy Subjects,</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics,</keyword>
	<keyword>Relative bioavailability</keyword>
</DOC>