<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="148809">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01163149</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ENB-009-10</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01163149</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of Asfotase Alfa in Adolescents and Adults With Hypophosphatasia (HPP)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Open-Label, Multicenter, Multinational, Dose-Ranging, Concurrent Control Study of the Safety, Efficacy, Pharmacokinetic of ENB-0040 (Human Recombinant Tissue Nonspecific Alkaline Phosphatase Fusion Protein) in Adolescents and Adults With Hypophosphatasia (HPP)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Alexion Pharma GmbH</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Alexion Pharma GmbH</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This clinical trial is being conducted to study hypophosphatasia (HPP), a bone disorder
      caused by gene mutations or changes. These gene mutations cause low levels of an enzyme
      needed to harden bone. The purpose of this study is to test the safety and efficacy of two
      doses of the study drug called asfotase alfa as compared to a control group to see what
      effects it has adolescents and adults with HPP.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Asfotase alfa was formerly referred to as ENB-0040

      Hypophosphatasia (HPP) is a life-threatening, genetic, and ultra-rare metabolic disease
      characterized by defective bone mineralization and impaired phosphate and calcium regulation
      that can lead to progressive damage to multiple vital organs, including destruction and
      deformity of bones, profound muscle weakness, seizures, impaired renal function, and
      respiratory failure. There are no approved disease-modifying treatments for patients with
      this disease. There is also limited data available on the natural course of this disease
      over time, particularly in patients with the juvenile-onset form.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of asfotase alfa on reduction in plasma inorganic pyrophosphate (PPi) and plasma pyridoxal-5' phosphate (PLP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 24</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected to evaluate the effect of Asfotase Alfa on reduction in plasma inorganic pyrophosphate (PPi) and plasma pyridoxal-5' phosphate (PLP)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and Tolerability of asfotase alfa</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 96 weeks or until regulatory approval</time_frame>
    <description>The safety and tolerability of daily subcutaneous (SC) injections of asfotase alfa will be assessed by routine monitoring of patients for adverse events (AEs) and injection-associated reactions (IARs) and monitoring changes from Baseline in physical examination findings, vital signs, clinical laboratory evaluations, renal ultrasound findings, funduscopic examinations, antibody evaluations, and results of pregnancy testing (in women of childbearing potential only). Monitoring for changes in concomitant medications and therapies will also occur.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in bone mineral content and density as measured by dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>A DXA scan will be performed to evaluate bone mineral content and density of the spine, hip, and whole body.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in walking ability as measured by the Six-Minute Walk Test (6MWT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The patient will be instructed to walk the length of a pre-measured hallway for 6 minutes. The primary measurement will be the distance walked (in meters).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in HPP-related osteomalacia as measured by trans-iliac crest bone biopsy</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 24, Week 48</time_frame>
    <description>A trans-iliac crest bone biopsy will be performed to quantify osteomalacia severity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">19</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypophosphatasia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cohort 1: Daily SC injections of 0.3 mg/kg asfotase alfa (2.1 mg/kg/week total)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cohort 2: Daily SC injections of 0.5 mg/kg asfotase alfa (3.5 mg/kg/week total)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Concurrent Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Following completion of the Week 24 visit, all patients (including those randomized to the concurrent control cohort) may be eligible to participate in an open-label extension study of asfotase alfa. In this extension period, all patients will be treated with daily SC injections of 0.5 mg/kg/day asfotase alfa (a total of 3.5 mg/kg/week) for approximately 24 weeks, then subjects will receive 1 mg/kg/day 6 days/week for an additional 48 weeks or until regulatory approval of the drug.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>asfotase alfa</intervention_name>
    <description>Cohort 1: Daily SC injections of 0.3 mg/kg asfotase alfa (tota1 of 2.1 mg/kg/week)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>asfotase alfa</intervention_name>
    <description>Cohort 2: Daily SC injections of 0.5 mg/kg Asfotase Alfa (3.5 mg/kg/week total)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:

        Patients must meet all of the following inclusion criteria to be eligible for
        participation in this study:

          -  Patients or their legal representative(s) must provide written informed consent prior
             to undergoing any study-related procedures

          -  Patients must be ≥ 13 and ≤ 65 years of age at the time of study enrollment

          -  Female patients of childbearing potential and sexually mature males must agree to use
             a medically acceptable form of birth control; for the purposes of this study, females
             are considered of non-childbearing potential if they are surgically sterile (i.e.,
             have undergone a total hysterectomy, bilateral salpingo-oophorectomy or tubal
             ligation) or are post-menopausal, defined as having complete cessation of
             menstruation for at least 1 year after 45 years of age

          -  Patients must have a pre-established clinical diagnosis of HPP as indicated by:

               -  Serum alkaline phosphatase (ALP) below the age-adjusted normal range

               -  Plasma PLP at least twice the upper limit of normal (no vitamin B6 administered
                  for at least 1 week prior to determination)

               -  Evidence of osteopenia or osteomalacia on skeletal radiographs

          -  Patients must have osteomalacia on bone biopsy, characterized by an MLT z-score of +2
             or more (results from ENB-001-08 may be used)

          -  Patients must be willing to comply with study procedures and the visit schedule

        Exclusion criteria:

        Patients will be excluded from participation in this study if they meet any of the
        following exclusion criteria:

          -  Women who are pregnant or lactating

          -  History of sensitivity to tetracycline

          -  Serum calcium or phosphate levels below the normal range

          -  Serum 25(OH) vitamin D below 20 ng/mL

          -  Serum creatinine or parathyroid hormone (PTH) levels above the upper limit of normal

          -  Medical condition, serious intercurrent illness, or other extenuating circumstance
             that, in the opinion of the Investigator, may significantly interfere with study
             compliance, including all prescribed evaluations and follow-up activities

          -  Orthopedic surgery within 12 months prior to study entry that may interfere with the
             ability to perform functional assessments for the study

          -  Prior treatment with bisphosphonates within 2 years of study entry for any length of
             time or for more than 2 years at any time point; for patients with prior
             bisphosphonate use that is allowed, the bone resorption markers serum C-telopeptide
             and urine N-telopeptide or urine deoxypyridinoline must also be within the normal
             range or elevated to be eligible for study participation

          -  Treatment with PTH within 6 months prior to the start of asfotase alfa administration

          -  Participation in an interventional or investigational drug study within 30 days prior
             to study participation
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shriner's Hospital for Children</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63131</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Health Sciences Centre Winnipeg, University of Manitoba</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winnipeg</city>
        <state>Manitoba</state>
        <zip>R3A 1S1</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.hypophosphatasie.com</url>
    <description>Hypophosphatasie Europe</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.magicfoundation.org</url>
    <description>HPP support group</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://health.groups.yahoo.com/group/Hyphosphatasia</url>
    <description>Yahoo health group for HPP with an international list serve where patients can correspond and post questions to the group</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.softbones.org</url>
    <description>US Hypophosphatasia Group (Soft Bones)</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.hypophosphatasia.com</url>
    <description>Hypophosphatasia Website</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.hypophosphatasia.com/hcp/</url>
    <description>Hypophosphatasia Website for Healthcare Providers</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Millán JL, Narisawa S, Lemire I, Loisel TP, Boileau G, Leonard P, Gramatikova S, Terkeltaub R, Camacho NP, McKee MD, Crine P, Whyte MP. Enzyme replacement therapy for murine hypophosphatasia. J Bone Miner Res. 2008 Jun;23(6):777-87.</citation>
    <PMID>18086009</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>August 3, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>June 24, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hypophosphatasia</keyword>
  <keyword>HPP</keyword>
  <keyword>Bone Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Soft Bones</keyword>
  <keyword>Low Alkaline Phosphatase</keyword>
  <keyword>genetic metabolic disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>alkaline phosphatase</keyword>
  <keyword>tissue-specific alkaline phosphatase (TNSALP)</keyword>
  <keyword>rickets</keyword>
  <keyword>osteomalacia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hypophosphatasia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulin G</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
