<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02599818</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will examine the clinical effectiveness and health economic profile of services to link hospital patients with substance use disorders to addiction treatment, promote their medical stabilization, and reduce hospital re-admissions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Navigation Services to Avoid Rehospitalization (NavSTAR)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In recent years, the problem of rehospitalization has come under intense focus as a major contributor to preventable morbidity and escalating healthcare costs. Substance use disorders are strongly associated with poor health outcomes and highly inefficient use of healthcare services, including repeat hospitalizations. Interventions that increase adherence to recommendations for outpatient medical care and substance abuse treatment could potentially help recently-hospitalized individuals with substance use disorders to avoid unnecessary rehospitalization, associated morbidity, and medical expenses. The current study is a randomized controlled trial comparing the effectiveness of Navigation Services to Avoid Rehospitalization (NavSTAR) vs. Treatment-as-Usual (TAU) for hospital patients with co-occurring medical problems and substance use disorders. Applying Andersen's theoretical model of health service utilization, NavSTAR will employ the promising strategies of Patient Navigation and motivational interventions to facilitate engagement in outpatient medical and substance abuse treatment, thereby lowering the likelihood of rehospitalization. Patient Navigators embedded within the substance abuse consultation liaison service at a large urban hospital will deliver patient-centered, proactive navigation and motivational services initiated during the hospital stay and continued for 3 months post-discharge. Participants randomized to TAU will receive usual care from the hospital and the substance abuse consultation liaison service, which includes referral to substance abuse treatment but no continued contact post-hospital discharge. Participants will be assessed at study entry and again at 3-, 6-, and 12-months follow-up on various measures of healthcare utilization, substance use, and functioning. The primary outcome of interest is time-to-rehospitalization through 12 months. In addition, a range of secondary outcomes spanning the medical and substance abuse service areas will be assessed. The study will include an economic evaluation of the cost, incremental cost-effectiveness, and cost-benefits of NavSTAR from the service provider perspective.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. adult (ages 18 and older) hospital patients; 2. current DSM5 SUD (not in remission) for alcohol, cocaine, or opioids 3. willing and able to provide informed consent. 1. current enrollment in SUD treatment; 2. primary residence outside of Baltimore City; 3. pregnant; 4. planned discharge to an inpatient care facility (e.g., hospice); 5. hospitalized for a suicide attempt.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>