<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02599285</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In AO Weber type C fractures, there is a combination of a proximal fibular fracture, a medial fracture or ruptured deltoid ligament, and a syndesmotic injury. Anatomical repair and reduction of the syndesmosis is essential to prevent diastasis in the ankle-joint. Widening and chronical instability of the syndesmosis is related to worse functional outcome and development of posttraumatic osteoarthritis in the ankle. There is limited biomechanical and clinical evidence that syndesmotic stability in AO Weber type C fractures with an additional posterior malleolar fracture can also be reached by fixation of the posterior malleolar fragment. Maybe, this is even superior to the usual treatment with syndesmotic positioning screws. Some authors concluded that stability of the syndesmosis in these fractures can be much more achieved by fixation of the posterior malleolar fragment than by placement of syndesmotic positioning screws alone. Another additional benefit of open reduction and fixation of the posterior malleolar fragment is that this will lead to an anatomical reconstruction of the syndesmosis. Although there is no current evidence, it is likely that a malreduction of the fibula in the tibial incisura will lead to a worse functional outcome on the long-term. No clear consensus in the literature is found as to which fragment size of the posterior malleolus should be internally fixed. The general opinion is that displaced fragments that involve more than 25% of the distal articular tibia should be fixed. Traditionally, reduction of these larger fragments is indirectly, followed by percutaneous screw fixation in anterior-posterior direction. Disadvantages are that it is hard to achieve an anatomical reduction, and that percutaneous fixation of smaller fragments is very difficult. Recently, a direct exposure of the posterior tibia via a posterolateral approach in prone position, followed by open reduction and fixation with screws in posterior-anterior direction or antiglide plate is advocated by several authors. This approach allows perfect visualization of the fracture, articular anatomical reduction, and strong fixation. Another advantage is that even small posterior fragments can be addressed. Several case series are published, which describe minimal major wound complications, good functional outcomes, and minimal need for reoperation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fixation of the Posterior Malleolus in Trimalleolar AO Weber C Fractures.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ankle Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age between 18 and 70 years 2. First ankle fracture of the affected side 3. Isolated, fibular fracture proximal to the syndesmosis with a posterior malleolar fragment between 5 and 25% of the involved articular surface(AO type 44C1, 44C2, 44C3). 1. Multiple injuries 2. Ankle fracture of the same ankle in the history 3. Patients with preexistent mobility problems 4. Preexistent disability like wheelchair or walking aid dependency. 5. Patients living in another region of whom followup will take place in another hospital 6. Insufficient understanding of the Dutch language</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>