<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02997540</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate that BVN G-1000 can precisely and consistently measure the position of female breast lesions regardless of patient rotation and probe angle during ultrasound examination.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Body Position and Probe Position on the Localization of Breast Mass</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The proposed research consists of quantitatively detecting and reporting the effect of body rotation and ultrasound probe position on the breast on the position of breast lesions relative to the breast nipple and body orientation planes, required for positional annotations, in female subjects at one study visit. Measurements will be manually and automatically recorded by two ultrasound operators with each image and will be compared among these conditions to detect effects of probe position and probe orientation and patient's body position relative to the exam table. The manual and automated measurements will be compared to determine the differences between the data obtained using the two different methods.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Female 2. 2170 years of age 3. Known palpable or nonpalpable benign or probably benign breast mass or masses, less than 2 cm in maximum diameter and at least 4 cm away from the nipple, from a previous ultrasound examination 1. Women with cardiac pacemaker or portable defibrillator 2. Women with known breast cancer or suspicious lesions 3. Pregnant and lactating women 4. Women who have breast implant(s) 5. Women who have had prior breast surgical intervention not including breast needle biopsy, in the same breast with the qualifying target mass. 6. Women with the target finding to be mapped within a distance of 4 cm from patient's nipple. 7. Women with multiple similar qualifying targets in close proximity (less than 4 cm between targets). 8. Women with history of allergy to medicalgrade adhesive tape or ultrasound gel 9. Women whose weight is over 250 pounds</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>female breast lesion</keyword>
	<keyword>ultrasound examination</keyword>
</DOC>