<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02997228</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized phase III trial studies how well combination chemotherapy, bevacizumab, and/or atezolizumab work in treating patients with microsatellite instability-high colorectal cancer that has spread to other places in the body. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as fluorouracil, oxaliplatin, and leucovorin calcium, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells, by stopping them from dividing, or by stopping them from spreading. Monoclonal antibodies, such as bevacizumab and atezolizumab, may interfere with the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Giving combination chemotherapy, bevacizumab, and atezolizumab may work better in treating patients with colorectal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination Chemotherapy, Bevacizumab, and/or Atezolizumab in Treating Patients With Microsatellite Instability-High Metastatic Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the efficacy, based on progression-free survival (PFS), of fluorouracil, oxaliplatin, and leucovorin calcium (mFOLFOX6)/bevacizumab plus atezolizumab (combination) and atezolizumab (single agent) as compared to mFOLFOX6/bevacizumab (control). SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To compare the overall survival (OS). II. To compare the objective response rates (ORR) per RECIST 1.1. III. To determine the safety profiles of the combination of mFOLFOX6/bevacizumab/atezolizumab and atezolizumab monotherapy in patients with microsatellite instability-high metastatic colorectal cancer (MSI-H mCRC). IV. To compare the surgical conversion rate. V. To compare disease control rate (complete response [CR] + partial response [PR] + stable disease [SD]) at 12 months. VI. To determine the duration of response and stable disease. VII. To compare the health-related quality of life and symptom burden. TERTIARY OBJECTIVES: I. To bank tissue and blood samples for other future correlative studies from patients enrolled on the study. OUTLINE: Patients are randomized to 1 of 3 arms. ARM I: Patients receive bevacizumab intravenously (IV) over 30-90 minutes on day 1, oxaliplatin IV over 2 hours on day 1 of courses 1-10, leucovorin calcium IV over 2 hours on day 1, and fluorouracil IV over 46-48 hours on days 1 and 2. Courses repeat every 2 weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. ARM II: Patients receive atezolizumab IV over 30-60 minutes on day 1. Treatment repeats every 2 weeks for up to 48 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. ARM III: Patients receive atezolizumab IV over 30-60 minutes on day 1. Courses with repeat every 2 weeks for up to 48 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients also received bevacizumab IV over 30-90 minutes on day 1, oxaliplatin IV over 2 hours on day 1 courses 1-10, leucovorin calcium IV over 2 hours on day 1, and fluorouracil IV over 46-48 hours on day 1. Courses repeat every in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up periodically.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Microsatellite Instability</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leucovorin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endothelial Growth Factors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulin G</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levoleucovorin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient must have signed and dated an Institutional Review Board (IRB)approved consent form that conforms to federal and institutional guidelines Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0, 1 or 2 Diagnosis of metastatic adenocarcinoma of colon or rectum without previous chemotherapy or any other systemic therapy for metastatic colorectal cancer Tumor determined to be mismatchrepair deficient (dMMR) or hMSIH by Clinical Laboratory Improvement Act (CLIA)certified assay Documentation by positron emission tomography(PET)/computed tomography (CT) scan, CT scan, or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) that the patient has untreated measurable metastatic disease per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1 No immediate need for surgical intervention for the primary tumor or palliative diversion/bypass Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) must be &gt;= 1500/mm^3 Platelet count must be &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin must be &gt;= 10 g/dL Total bilirubin must be =&lt; 1.5 x ULN (upper limit of normal) for the lab unless the patient has a bilirubin elevation &gt; 1.5 x ULN to 3 x ULN due to Gilbert's disease or similar syndrome involving slow conjugation of bilirubin Alkaline phosphatase must be =&lt; 3 x ULN for the lab with the following exception: patients with documented liver metastases or bone involvement alkaline phosphatase must be =&lt; 5 x ULN Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) must be =&lt; 3 x ULN for the lab with the following exception: for patients with documented liver metastases, AST and ALT must be =&lt; 5 x ULN Serum creatinine =&lt; 1.5 x ULN for the lab or measured or calculated creatinine clearance &gt;= 30 mL/min A urine sample tested for proteinuria by the dipstick method must indicate 0 1+ protein; if dipstick reading is &gt;= 2+, a 24hour urine specimen must demonstrate &lt; 1.0 g of protein per 24 hours International normalized ratio of prothrombin time (INR) and prothrombin time (PT) must be =&lt; 3 x ULN for the lab within 28 days before randomization; patients who are therapeutically treated with an agent such as warfarin may participate if they are on a stable dose and no underlying abnormality in coagulation parameters exists per medical history Pregnancy test done within 14 days prior randomization must be negative (for women of childbearing potential only); pregnancy testing should be performed according to institutional standards Women of childbearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry, for the duration of study participation, and for 5 months after the last dose of atezolizumab; 6 months after the last dose of bevacizumab; and 6 months after the last dose of FOLFOX; should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while she or her partner is participating in this study, she should inform her treating physician immediately; men treated or enrolled on this protocol must also agree to use adequate contraception prior to the study, for the duration of study participation, and for 6 months after the last dose of bevacizumab and 6 months after the last dose of FOLFOX Patients with central nervous system (CNS) metastases are excluded, with the following exception: Patients with asymptomatic treated CNS metastases may be enrolled, provided all eligibility criteria are met, as well as the following: Radiographic demonstration of improvement upon the completion of CNSdirected therapy and no evidence of interim progression between the completion of CNSdirected therapy and the screening radiographic study No stereotactic radiation or wholebrain radiation within 28 days prior to cycle 1, day 1 Screening CNS radiographic study &gt;= 4 weeks from completion of radiotherapy and &gt;= 2 weeks from discontinuation of corticosteroids Known hypersensitivity to Chinese hamster ovary cell products or other recombinant human antibodies, fluoropyrimidines, folic acid derivatives or oxaliplatin Uncontrolled high blood pressure defined as systolic blood pressure (BP) &gt; 160 mmHg or diastolic BP 100 mmHg with or without antihypertensive medication; patients with initial BP elevations are eligible if initiation or adjustment of BP medication lowers pressure to meet entry criteria Any of the following cardiac conditions: Documented New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III or IV congestive heart failure Myocardial infarction within 6 months prior to randomization Unstable angina within 6 months prior to randomization Symptomatic arrhythmia Serious or nonhealing wound, skin ulcer, or bone fracture History of transient ischemic attack (TIA), cerebrovascular accident (CVA), gastrointestinal (GI) perforation or arterial thrombotic event within 6 months prior to randomization or symptomatic peripheral ischemia Other malignancies unless the patient is considered to be diseasefree and has completed therapy for the malignancy &gt;= 12 months prior to randomization; patients with the following cancers are eligible if diagnosed and treated within the past 12 months: in situ carcinomas or basal cell and squamous cell carcinoma of the skin Known DPD (dihydro pyrimidine dehydrogenase) deficiency Symptomatic peripheral sensory neuropathy &gt;= grade 2 (Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events [CTCAE] version [v] 4.0) in patients with no prior oxaliplatin therapy Prior treatment with oxaliplatin chemotherapy within 6 months prior to randomization and any prior treatment with an antiPD1 or antiPDL1 therapeutic antibody Treatment with systemic immunosuppressive medications (including, but not limited to, prednisone, cyclophosphamide, azathioprine, methotrexate, thalidomide, and antitumor necrosis factor [antiTNF] agents) within 14 days prior to randomization; however, Patients who have received acute, low dose, systemic immunosuppressant medications (e.g., a onetime dose of dexamethasone for nausea; or chronic daily treatment with corticosteroids with a dose of =&lt; 10 mg/day methylprednisolone equivalent) may be enrolled The use of inhaled corticosteroids and mineralocorticoids (e.g., fludrocortisone) for patients with orthostatic hypotension or adrenocortical insufficiency is allowed Known clinically significant liver disease; however, Patients with past or resolved hepatitis B infection (defined as having a negative hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg] test and a positive antiHBc [antibody to hepatitis B core antigen] antibody test) are eligible Patients positive for hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody are eligible only if polymerase chain reaction (PCR) is negative for HCV ribonucleic acid (RNA) History or risk of autoimmune disease, including, but not limited to, systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, inflammatory bowel disease, vascular thrombosis associated with antiphospholipid syndrome, Wegener's granulomatosis, Sjogren's syndrome, Bell's palsy, GuillainBarre syndrome, multiple sclerosis, autoimmune thyroid disease, vasculitis, or glomerulonephritis; however, Patients with a history of autoimmune hypothyroidism on a stable dose of thyroid replacement hormone may be eligible Patients with controlled type 1 diabetes mellitus on a stable insulin regimen may be eligible Patients with eczema, psoriasis, lichen simplex chronicus or vitiligo with dermatologic manifestations only (e.g., patients with psoriatic arthritis would be excluded) are permitted provided that they meet the following conditions: Patients with psoriasis must have a baseline ophthalmologic exam to rule out ocular manifestations Rash must cover less than 10% of body surface area (BSA) Disease is well controlled at baseline and only requiring low potency topical steroids (e.g., hydrocortisone 2.5%, hydrocortisone butyrate 0.1%, fluocinolone 0.01%, desonide 0.05%, alclometasone dipropionate 0.05%) No acute exacerbations of underlying condition within the last 12 months (not requiring psoralen plus ultraviolet A radiation [PUVA], methotrexate, retinoids, biologic agents, oral calcineurin inhibitors; high potency or oral steroids) History of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, pneumonitis (including drug induced), organizing pneumonia (i.e., bronchiolitis obliterans, cryptogenic organizing pneumonia, etc.), or evidence of active pneumonitis on screening chest computed tomography (CT) scan; history of radiation pneumonitis in the radiation field (fibrosis) is permitted Patients with known active tuberculosis (TB) are excluded Severe infections requiring oral or intravenous (IV) antibiotics within 14 days prior to randomization Major surgical procedure, open biopsy, or significant traumatic injury within 28 days prior to randomization Administration of a live, attenuated vaccine within 28 days prior to randomization Pregnant women are excluded from this study; breastfeeding should be discontinued if the mother is treated with atezolizumab; (Note: Pregnancy testing should be performed within 14 days prior to randomization according to institutional standards for women of childbearing potential) Patients positive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) are NOT excluded from this study, but HIVpositive patients must have: A stable regimen of highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART); and No requirement for concurrent antibiotics or antifungal agents for the prevention of opportunistic infections; and A CD4 count above 250 cells/uL and an undetectable HIV viral load on standard PCRbased tests</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>