<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00571428</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the efficacy and safety of arformoterol tartrate inhalation solution 30μg/4mL QD (two 15μg/2mL dosed in combination) over a 24-hour period compared to arformoterol tartrate inhalation solution 15μg/2 mL BID in subjects with COPD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Safety Study of Arformoterol QD Dosing Versus BID Dosing in COPD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a modified blind, randomized, multicenter, single dose two-way crossover study to assess the efficacy and safety of arformoterol 15μg BID versus arformoterol 30μg QD in subjects with COPD. Subject participation will last approximately three weeks and will include a screening visit, two 24-hour visits, and a follow up telephone call. This study was previously posted by Sepracor Inc. In October 2009, Sepracor Inc. was acquired by Dainippon Sumitomo Pharma., and in October 2010, Sepracor Inc's name was changed to Sunovion Pharmaceuticals Inc.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Formoterol Fumarate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female subjects must be at least 45 years old at the time of consent. Subjects must have a preestablished primary clinical diagnosis of COPD. Subjects must have a baseline FEV1 of ≤ 65% of predicted normal value at Visit 1. Subjects must have a FEV1 ≥ 0.70L at Visit 1. Subjects must have a FEV1/forced vital capacity (FVC) ratio of ≤ 70% at Visit 1. Subjects who do not have a 15 packyear smoking history and a baseline breathlessness severity grade of 2 (as measured by the Modified Medical Research Council [MMRC] Dyspnea Scale Score) at Screening. Subjects with lifethreatening/unstable respiratory status, including upper or lower respiratory tract infection, within the previous 30 days prior to Visit</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Bronchitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Emphysema</keyword>
</DOC>