<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00571649</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate if extended therapy with oral rivaroxaban can prevent blood clots in the leg and lung that can occur with patients hospitalized for acute medical illness, and compare these results with those of the standard enoxaparin dose and duration regimen. The safety of rivaroxaban will also be studied.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Venous Thromboembolic Event (VTE) Prophylaxis in Medically Ill Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The treatment period was followed by a follow-up period starting the day after the last intake of study medication, regardless of the actual duration of study drug administration and ended on Day 90 (+ 7 days). Participants who did not complete the treatment period also entered the follow-up period. It was also possible that participants did not enter the follow-up period, e.g. due to withdrawal of consent or termination of study participation. Within the US 'Johnson &amp; Johnson Pharmaceutical Research &amp; Development, L.L.C.' is sponsor.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female patients aged 40 years or more Patients at risk of venous thromboembolic events being hospitalized for acute medical conditions as follows: Heart failure, New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III or IV Active cancer Acute ischemic stroke Acute infectious and inflammatory diseases, including acute rheumatic diseases Acute respiratory insufficiency Additional risk factor for VTE, including reduced mobility Conditions that contraindicate the use of antithrombotic therapy with the Low MolecularWeight Heparin (LMWH) enoxaparin Conditions that may increase the risk of bleeding, including intracranial hemorrhage Required drugs or procedures which may interfere with the study treatment Concomitant conditions or diseases which may increase the risk of study subjects or interfere with the study outcome General conditions in which subjects are not suitable to participate in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute medical illnesses with increased risk for VTE.</keyword>
	<keyword>Deep vein thrombosis (DVT)</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulmonary embolism (PE),</keyword>
	<keyword>Venous Thromboembolic disease (VTE),</keyword>
	<keyword>Medical illness</keyword>
</DOC>