<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02506439</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Randomised, placebo-controlled dose-response intervention study with vitamin D3 in pregnant women.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nutritional Requirements for Vitamin D in Pregnant Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a four-arm, parallel, double-blind, placebo-controlled dose-response intervention study with vitamin D3. Women will be recruited during the first trimester and followed-up throughout their pregnancy. White women will be randomised to receive placebo, 10 or 20 mcg/d of vitamin D3 from baseline visit in their first trimester until delivery. Dark skinned women will receive 20 mcg/d. Blood samples will be taken once in each trimester and also from the cord at delivery. A 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration of 30 nmol/L will be used to denote clinical deficiency and 50 nmol/L to indicate sufficient vitamin D status. Information on maternal anthropometry, diet, lifestyle, sun exposure, blood pressure and serum total calcium will also be reported.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult (&gt;18 years) No more than 18 weeks gestation In good general health Low risk pregnancy Not consuming &gt;10 mcg/d vitamin D from supplements Current smokers Diagnosed hypertension Known highrisk pregnancy Diagnosed medical illness including diabetes mellitus (Types 1 &amp; 2), chronic kidney disease or gastrointestinal diseases or any illness known to interfere with calcium metabolism (e.g. sarcoidosis). Consumption of medications known to interfere with vitamin D metabolism Consumption of vitamin D (≥ 10 µg/day) or calcium (≥ 650 mg/d) supplements prior to randomization</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>Cholecalciferol</keyword>
	<keyword>Dose-response</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized Controlled Trial</keyword>
	<keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>Cord blood</keyword>
	<keyword>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitamin D Deficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>Dietary intervention study</keyword>
</DOC>