<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02499679</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of the HeartFlow ADVANCE Registry is to evaluate utility, clinical outcomes and resource utilization of FFRCT-guided evaluation in clinically stable, symptomatic patients with coronary artery disease (CAD) in order to further inform patients, health care providers, and other stakeholders about which technologies are most effective and efficient in the diagnosis and management of CAD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessing Diagnostic Value of Non-invasive FFRCT in Coronary Care</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>REGISTRY OBJECTIVE The objective of the HeartFlow ADVANCE Registry is to evaluate utility, clinical outcomes and resource utilization of FFRCT-guided evaluation in clinically stable, symptomatic patients with CAD in order to further inform patients, health care providers, and other stakeholders about which technologies are most effective and efficient in the diagnosis and management of CAD. SPECIFIC OBJECTIVES: 1. To determine if the availability of FFRCT, in addition to coronary anatomy from the cCTA, will lead to a significant change in the coronary management plan. 2. To assess the real world outcomes of utilizing FFRCT to guide invasive management and/or medical treatment. 3. To assess resource utilization, following standard practice for diagnostic and treatment pathways incorporating FFRCT as the preferred CAD diagnostic test. 4. To provide society including patients, health care providers, and other stakeholders with information about which diagnostic technologies are most effective and efficient in managing patients with CAD.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Provide written informed consent 2. Clinically stable, symptomatic patients who undergo cCTA and are diagnosed with CAD and meet eligibility criteria for FFRCT. 1. cCTA showing no CAD 2. Uninterpretable cCTA by site assessment, in which severe artifacts prevent angiographic evaluation 3. Any active, serious, lifethreatening disease with a life expectancy of less than 1 year 4. Inability to comply with followup requirements</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>