<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02499094</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to validate the effectiveness of using an integrated mobile sensing platform to deliver large-scale data-driven interventions to patients with depression.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Modeling and Predicting Real World Behavior Using Mobile Sensor Data on Patients With Major Depressive Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a smartphone-based, randomized, single-blind, controlled parallel- design study with two intervention arms and one control arm. The two intervention arms will receive in-app messages and phone-based support, which will be triggered by participant's self-reported surveys and passive behavioral data gathered through a smartphone app. The study will include a nationwide sample of adult (18 years or older) smartphone users, who are currently experiencing depressive symptoms. The primary outcome will be decrease in depression symptom severity, as measured by the 9-item Patient Health Questionnaire, over 6 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Currently suffering from depression (as measured by a PHQ9 score of 10 or more at the time of screening) Own an iPhone or Android smartphone with a mobile voice calling plan with a US carrier Fluency in English Participants with visual or hearing impairment Recent history of pregnancy (currently pregnant or those who have given birth within the past four months at the time of screening) Recent loss of a loved one (within the past two months at the time of screening) Unable or unwilling to accept End User License Agreement, or to provide information regarding their demographic characteristics and mental health history</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>