<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02669953</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Age-related macular degeneration (AMD) is one of the most common disorders causing visual disability in elderly people. AMD leads to dysfunction and loss of photoreceptors in the central retina. Neovascular AMD (nAMD) affects visual function early in the disease process. The purpose of the study is to evaluate the effect of switching from ranibizumab therapy to the current routine therapy using aflibercept in eyes with recurrent or persistent nAMD. 20 patients with recurrent or persistent nAMD, previously treated with intravitreal ranibizumab for up to one year will be included in this trial. Patients will be examined in monthly intervals over 12 months follow-up. Examinations carried out will include: Best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA) using ETDRS charts at 4m distance, Reading Performance (RP), Standard ophthalmic examinations (SOE incl. funduscopy and applanation tonometry), Optical coherence tomography (OCT), Autofluorescence fundus image (AF) &amp; red-free autofluorescence fundus image (RF), Color fundus photography (CFP), Fluorescein angiography and indocyaningreen angiography (FLA/ICG), Microperimetry (MP), as well as Non-invasive OCT based optical angiography (AngioVue).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aflibercept in Recurrent or Persistent CNV</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults ≥ 50 years Patients who have been treated with ranibizumab due to wet agerelated macular degeneration for up to one year BCVA &gt;= 20/400 in the study eye using ETDRS Willingness and ability to comply with regular visits Signed informed consent Any surgical treatment of the eye within 3 months prior to baseline in the study eye History of uncontrolled glaucoma in the study eye (defined as intraocular pressure ≥ 25 mmHg despite treatment with antiglaucoma mediation) Aphakia or absence of the posterior capsule (excluding YAGcapsulotomy) in the study eye Retinal pigment epithelial tear involving the macula in the study eye</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>