<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00893659</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to determine the effect of the potential prebiotic beta-glucan on the intestinal microflora, the bacterial enzyme activity (beta-glucuronidase and beta-glucosidase) in the feces, the fecal pH and the concentration of fecal short-chain fatty acid in polypectomized patients. Also the in vitro anti-cyto- and anti-genotoxicity of fecal water will be examined on human cell culture (HT29). During the trial, patient's clinical symptoms (intestinal habits), physical activity, well-being and food intake will be recorded.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Beta-glucan on Fecal Microflora in Polypectomized Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Prebiotics, such as short- and long-chain fructo-oligosaccharides are fermented by the microflora colonizing the gastrointestinal tract, and they selectively stimulate the growth or the activity of one or limited number of bacteria within the intestine. Beta-glucans are polysaccharides occurring in the bran of cereal grains, the cell wall of Saccharomyces cerevisiae and bacteria, certain types of fungi, seaweed and many kinds of mushrooms. The aim of this study is to determine the effect of the potential prebiotic beta-glucan on the intestinal microflora, the bacterial enzyme activity (beta-glucuronidase and beta-glucosidase) in the faeces, the faecal pH, and the concentration of faecal short-chain fatty acid in polypectomized patients.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>The subjects must have biopsy and histologically confirmed adenomatous polyps ≥ 1cm in size or ≥ 3 in number with moderate or severe dysplasia Subjects ≥ 75 years of age Subjects who are pregnant or desire to become pregnant during the study period Subjects who are considered to be poor clinic attendees Subjects who have been on antibiotics within the previous month or are likely to require antibiotics during the trial Subjects who consume prebiotics or probiotics within the previous month or are likely to require antibiotics during the trial Subjects with colon cancer Subjects with additional gastrointestinal disorders (e.g., Crohn's disease or ulcerative colitis) Subjects with malignancy or any endstage organ disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Beta-glucan</keyword>
	<keyword>faecal microflora</keyword>
	<keyword>polypectomized</keyword>
	<keyword>Precancerous Nonmalignant Condition</keyword>
</DOC>