<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02953821</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Subjects with active systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) will be randomized to receive Acthar or placebo. Active treatment will continue for 24 weeks. Efficacy will be assessed at multiple timepoints using the SLE Responder Index (SRI), SLEDAI-2K, BILAG, PGA, CLASI and 28 Joint Count</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess the Efficacy and Safety of H.P. Acthar® Gel in Subjects With Active Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, placebo controlled, double blind study. Following a screening period of up to 28 days, subjects with active systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) including moderate to severe rash and/or arthritis despite corticosteroid therapy will be randomized in a 1:1 ratio to receive 1 mL (80 Units [U]) of Acthar or matching placebo. During Weeks 1 to 4, 1 mL (80 U) of Acthar or volume matched placebo will be administered subcutaneously (SC) every other day. For the remainder of the study (Weeks 5 to 24), Acthar 1 mL (80 U) or volume matched placebo will be administered SC 2x/week.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adrenocorticotropic Hormone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subjects must be ≥ 18 years of age at Screening Visit 2. Subjects must have a diagnosis of SLE according to the American College of Rheumatology revised criteria (fulfilled ≥ 4 criteria). 3. Subjects must have active SLE as demonstrated by a SLEDAI2K score of ≥ 6 at the Screening Visit and a clinical SLEDAI (excluding laboratory results) score ≥ 4 at the Screening and Randomization Visits. Points for arthritis and/or rash must be present at both the Screening and Randomization Visits. 4. Subjects must have a documented history of positive antinuclear antibody. 5. Subjects must have a documented history of autoantibodies to at least 1 of the following: antids DNA, antiSmith, or anticardiolipin. 6. Subjects must have been on prednisone (or prednisone equivalent) for ≥ 8 weeks prior to the Screening Visit and on a stable dose of 7.5 mg to 30 mg of prednisone (or prednisone equivalent) for ≥ 4 weeks prior to the Screening Visit. Exclusion criteria: 1. Subject has a history of sensitivity to ACTH preparations or porcine products 2. Subject has active lupus nephritis 3. Subject has active CNS manifestations of SLE</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>