<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02953548</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial consists of 3 parts: a pilot safety phase, a pivotal randomized controlled phase, and an open-label extension phase. The pilot phase only will be described in this record. 2 cohorts of 5 participants will be enrolled sequentially. All participants will receive GWP42003-P.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial of Cannabidiol (CBD; GWP42003-P) for Infantile Spasms (GWPCARE7)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Spasm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spasms, Infantile</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Participant is diagnosed with IS and has failed to respond adequately following treatment with 1 or more approved IS therapies. Key Participant is currently taking or has taken clobazam or any mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) inhibitor within the 2 weeks prior to the screening visit. Participant has a QT interval, corrected for heart rate with Bazett's formula (QTcB), of 460 msec or greater on ECG. Participant's caregiver is currently giving or has given recreational or medicinal cannabis, or synthetic cannabinoidbased medications, within the 1 month prior to the screening visit. Participant's caregiver is unwilling to abstain from giving the participant (including the participant's mother abstaining themselves, if breastfeeding)recreational or medicinal cannabis, or synthetic cannabinoidbased medications (other than the study drug) during the trial. Participant has any known or suspected hypersensitivity to cannabinoids or any of the excipients of the study drug, such as sesame oil. Participant has significantly impaired hepatic function at the screening visit. Participant has received an investigational medicinal product as part of a clinical trial within a minimum of 5 halflives prior to the screening visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>GWP42003-P</keyword>
	<keyword>Cannabidiol</keyword>
</DOC>