<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02953990</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will provide information about the feasibility, acceptability, and preliminary effects of a biobehavioral self-management approach for perinatal depressive symptoms. This line of research will contribute to the body of knowledge about adjunctive therapies for depressive symptoms in pregnancy, a serious problem which contributes to poor maternal-child outcomes. Ultimately, this will contribute to the development and implementation of theoretically driven depression prevention/ resiliency building interventions and measurement of appropriate biobehavioral outcomes to determine the effectiveness of interventions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Self-Management of Chronic Depressive Symptoms in Pregnancy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators longitudinal mixed-methods study will use a one-group repeated measures intervention design coupled with qualitative methods to provide a comprehensive view of the feasibility, acceptability, and preliminary effects of the MOMS intervention. Semi-structured interviews, recruitment and retention numbers, and participant logs will be used to evaluate feasibility and acceptability of the intervention (Specific Aim 1). Recently collected archival comparison group data from an existing study will be used to contribute to explorations of preliminary effects of the intervention by comparing longitudinal psychobehavioral data, birth weight data, and genome-wide and gene-specific DNAm data (Specific Aims 2 and 3).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<criteria>≥ age 18; selfreport of depressive symptoms prior to pregnancy; current depressive symptoms at a moderatetosevere level, as defined by a score ≥10 on the Patient Health Questionnaire9; able to read, write, and understand English; selfidentify as black/African American (AA) or White; absence of suicidal ideations (measured as low risk on the M.I.N.I. Neuropsychiatric Interview tool); absence of pregnancy complications/physical conditions making physical activity (PA) inadvisable; has not engaged in a consistent mindfulnessbased PA routine during the pregnancy (such as yoga or similar activities more than once per month). If individual does not meet the inclusion criteria listed above, they are ineligible for the study.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Yoga</keyword>
</DOC>