<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00519545</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to help determine the biochemical mechanisms underlying previously demonstrated health benefits of prayer, and to track humoral changes in various prayer activities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prayer as a Possible Adjuvant Treatment for Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this pilot study is to investigate certain biological mechanisms that may underlie the beneficial effects seen among cancer patients who pray. It will evaluate the effect of prayer on humoral (including biochemical/physiological inflammatory/immune) parameters, monitor changes in cancer related biomarkers and evaluate the effect of prayer on blood pressure, quality of life, health and dietary habits in relation to prayer activities, using validated questionnaires.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Primary histological diagnosis of Stage IIV breast cancer. 2. Initial diagnosis of breast cancer within 5 year of study enrollment. 3. Not currently receiving chemotherapy or radiation therapy. Hormone therapy is allowed. 4. Life expectancy of at least 12 months. 5. ECOG performance status of 0, 1, or 2. 6. Willing to sign informed consent indicating that they are aware of the investigational nature of the study and the randomized study design. 7. Willing to comply with monthly followup phone calls. 8. Willing to complete questionnaires at regular oncology clinic visits. 9. Able to read write &amp; understand English. 1. Concurrent treatment with chemotherapy or radiation therapy 2. Less than 3 months since last dose of chemotherapy or radiation therapy. 3. Breast cancer diagnosis more than 5 years prior to study enrollment 4. Less than 21 or greater than to 80 years old. 5. Life threatening or severe concurrent nonmalignant conditions. 6. Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus. 7. Severe heart disease. 8. Severe liver disease. Severe lung disease. 9. History of smoking within 5 years of study enrollment. 10. Psychological or psychiatric disorder that would interfere with study compliance. 11. History of missed appointments or poor medical compliance. 12. Inability to understand instructions on how to complete a questionnaire. 13. No access to a phone.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>breast</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage</keyword>
	<keyword>one</keyword>
	<keyword>four</keyword>
</DOC>