<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01862978</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to show the efficacy and safety of heparin and nadroparin in the acute phase of ischemic stroke. Therapeutic agents are administered at intervals of 4.5 to 2 hours after onset of clinical signs. Overall administration of anticoagulant agents will test 72 hours. Randomized patients will be divided into three groups. The first group of patients will receive heparin intravenously at the beginning of 2500 UI bolus intravenously, followed by intravenous pump 1000 UI / h (18-20 IU / kg / hr) to reach 2-2.5 times the baseline aPTT. After 24 hours, patients will receive the group Nadroparin subcutaneously in the therapeutic dose. Second group of patients will be administered subcutaneously Nadroparin the therapeutic dose as recommended. The third group of patients are those who will receive placebo intravenously and 24 hours after receiving nadroparin subcutaneously in the therapeutic dose. All patients will receive after 24 hours of starting treatment 100 mg of aspirin per orally. For initiation of treatment will be assessed: - Modified Rankin Scale, National Institutes of Health Stroke Scale, inclusion, exclusion criteria - Sign the informed consent and patient randomization - Laboratory parameters: glucose, creatinine, GGT, K, Na, Cl, blood count, basic coagulation - Women of childbearing age (pregnancy test) - History, clinical presentation, medical history, basic internal review of the status (blood pressure, pulse, body temperature, etc.). - Initial CT examination of the brain - EKG - USG sections of extracranial carotid and vertebral arteries - special hematology factors If a patient meets all the necessary criteria, he may be given the test substance. During the first 24 hours will be monitored at regular intervals vital functions. After 24 hours, each patient received subcutaneous Nadroparin the therapeutic dose and also 100 mg of aspirin per orally. In the interval from 24 to 30 hours of starting treatment the patient will be made: - Control CT brain - EKG - Basic coagulation - Reduction to stop treatment for newly identified haemorrhage or severe and extensive focal cerebral ischemia by CT scan - special hematology factors 72 hours, 7, 30 and 90 days after starting treatment, the patient's clinical evaluation using the Modified Rankin Scale, National Institutes of Health Stroke Scale and Barthel Index. Safety endpoints: mortality, adverse side effects, bleeding</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Heparin and Nadroparin in the Acute Phase of Ischemic Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium heparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nadroparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heparin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ischemic stroke female or male gender mRS (modified Rankin Scale) 01 (min one month before the event) NIHSS ≥ 6 and ≤ 25 Age: 1880 years initiation of therapy in the interval from 4.5 to 24 hours from onset of symptoms of ischemic stroke focal neurological deficit of at least 30 min, which was significantly obviously does not disappear before treatment patient will participate voluntarily and signed informed consent. Informed consent will be obtained from each patient, guardian or close relative patients who are unable to sign, but who are able to understand what means to participate in the study, may give informed consent through eyewitness willingness and ability to comply with the protocol intracranial hemorrhage confirmed by CT scan CT image heavy and extensive focal cerebral ischemia lacunar syndrome epileptic seizure at the beginning of ischemic stroke previous or planned treatment with intravenous, intraarterial thrombolysis, mechanical recanalization or ultrasound assisted thrombolysis stroke, myocardial infarction, head trauma in the last 3 months tromboctov count below 100 000/mm ³ therapeutically uncontrolled blood pressure: systolic blood pressure&gt; 185 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure&gt; 110 mmHg therapeutically uncontrolled blood glucose ˂ 2.77 or&gt; 22.15 mmol / l Known bleeding diathesis, other coagulopathies, severe hepatopathy, severe nephropathy patients receiving oral anticoagulants current or previous lifethreatening bleeding major surgery less than 2 weeks ago known malignancy active TB pregnancy allergy to Heparin or Fraxiparine known alcohol abuse and / or drugs active participation in another clinical study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Heparin</keyword>
	<keyword>Nadroparin</keyword>
</DOC>