<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01728740</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To establish the bioequivalence between Acarbose / Metformin FDC (50mg / 500mg) and loose combination of Acarbose (Glucobay) (50mg) and Metformin (Glucophage) (500mg).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bioequivalence Study for Acarbose / Metformin FDC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acarbose</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Body Mass Index (BMI): 18 to 28 kg/m2 (inclusive) Results of Glycosylated Hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) value are within the normal range (4.35.6%, inclusive) Results of the 75 g oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT) during screening show: Blood glucose before OGTT &lt;110 mg/dL. Blood glucose 1 hour after glucose loading &lt;180 mg/dL Blood glucose 2 hours after glucose loading &lt;140 mg/dL A history of relevant diseases of internal organs (diabetes mellitus, Ileus, Ileuslike symptoms, diseases that may significantly jeopardize body systems Febrile illness within 1 week before drug administration Family history of diabetes (within the second degree of relationship) Known drug hypersensitivity or idiosyncrasy Known severe allergies, nonallergic drug reactions, or multiple drug allergies Habitual medication including Chinese herbal drugs Intake of any drugs within 2 weeks of drug administration of period 1 Regular daily consumption of more than 1 L of usual beer or the equivalent quantity of approximately 40 g of alcohol in another form Donation of more than 150 mL of blood within 4 weeks before the screening examination Participation in another clinical trial within 4 weeks before the screening examination</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bioequivalence</keyword>
	<keyword>Acarbose</keyword>
	<keyword>Metformin</keyword>
	<keyword>FDC</keyword>
</DOC>