<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02383849</DOC>
	<brief_summary>P1106 is Phase IV prospective pharmacokinetic (PK) study of low birth weight infants who are receiving or will be receiving as part of clinical care nevirapine (NVP) prophylaxis, tuberculosis (TB) prophylaxis or treatment and/or combination antiretroviral (ARV) treatment containing lopinavir/ritonavir (LPV/r). The study is designed to describe the pharmacokinetics and safety of NVP, INH, RIF, and LPV/r in these infants receiving the drug(s) as part of clinical care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>IMPAACT P1106: Pharmacokinetic Characteristics of Antiretrovirals and Tuberculosis Medicines in Low Birth Weight Infants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Birth Weight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria for Arms 1, 2 and 3 (HIVexposed infants): Breastfeeding infants born to HIVinfected mothers who are receiving either no ARV therapy or ARV therapy that does not include NVP Age 7 to 14 days Birth weight less than or equal to 2500 grams Receiving or will be receiving prophylaxis as prescribed by clinical care provider as follows: NVP (Arm 1), NVP plus INH (Arm 2), NVP plus INH plus RIF (Arm 3) Parent or legal guardian able and willing to provide written informed consent. [Note to sites: modify per locally relevant language]. Inclusion Criteria for Arm 4 (HIVunexposed but TB exposed infants): Age 7 to 14 days Birth weight less than or equal to 2500 grams Receiving prophylaxis with INH alone or INH plus RIF as prescribed by clinical care provider Not receiving any therapy for HIV prophylaxis or treatment Parent or legal guardian able and willing to provide written informed consent. [Note to sites: modify per locally relevant language]. Inclusion Criteria for Arms 5 and 6 (HIVinfected infants): Documentation of HIV1 infection defined as positive HIV DNA PCR done as part of clinical care. An HIV RNA confirmatory test must be done at study entry but results may be pending at time of enrollment. Birth weight less than or equal to 2500 grams Age less than or equal to 12 weeks (defined as 84 days) Intention by clinical care provider to prescribe LPV/r plus 2 NRTIs and no RIF (Arm 5) or LPV/r plus 2 NRTIs plus RIF (Arm 6) Parent or legally acceptable representative able and willing to provide written informed consent. [Note to sites: modify per locally relevant language]. Any severe congenital malformation or other medical condition incompatible with life or that would interfere with study participation or interpretation, as judged by the examining clinician.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>84 Days</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>