<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01074931</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This post-marketing observational study is conducted for obtaining data on clinical, biological and virological outcomes, compliance and tolerability of using a lopinavir/ritonavir (LPV/r) -containing regimen for the treatment of naïve or experienced patients infected with human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) in China. Although LPV/r is frequently used world-wide, the evaluation of the outcomes, compliance, and tolerance of anti-HIV strategies in real life is still a major challenge in the management of HIV-infected patients who are on a life-long therapy, especially in China. This study will help to develop effectiveness and safety profile of the lopinavir/ritonavir containing regimen in Chinese HIV-1 infected patients, provide more choices of anti-HIV-1 strategies to Chinese experts and benefits Chinese HIV-1 infected patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical, Virological and Safety Outcomes of a Lopinavir/Ritonavir-Based Regimen in HIV-1 Infected Patients in Routine Clinical Use in China</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>It is planned to enroll approximately 100 patients in total. This will be a multicenter post-marketing observational study in China mainland. Each patient will be observed during his/her lopinavir/ritonavir - containing treatment regimen for a maximum period of 18 months. If the physician decides to permanently discontinue lopinavir/ritonavir before the end of the planned observational period of 18 months, the reason for the discontinuation and the new treatment regimen prescribed will be documented. The next routine follow-up visit will be the termination visit for this patient in this study. This post-marketing observational study will be conducted in a prospective, single-arm, multicenter format. As this study is observational in nature, its follow-up is not interventional and is left to the judgment of each physician within the 18-month period, which defines the survey for each patient. For indicative purpose, follow-up of patients should enable approximately 4 patient visits during this period. These visits will take place at average intervals of 6 months, apart from the first visit following inclusion (usually at the end of the first 3 treatment months) and apart from visits required because of an intercurrent event. If treatment with lopinavir/ritonavir is discontinued, standard practice is to review the patient after a period of 3 months. For these reasons, the most likely visits are defined as "V1", "V2", "V3", "V4" although numbers and dates will depend only on the decision of the physician. As a result, failure to meet these suggested dates will not constitute a deviation of the protocol.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lopinavir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients infected by HIV1 who are over 18 years old Patients who belong to one of the following cohorts: Antiretroviral naïve patients Antiretroviral experienced patients, irrespective to their immune and viral status and current antiretroviral therapy Patients who have been treated with lopinavir/ritonavir Patients who are being treated or will be treated with drugs at risk of interactions with lopinavir/ritonavir Patients who are not tolerant to lopinavir/ritonavir Patients who have uncontrolled AIDS defining disease Patients participating in another clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lopinavir/ritonavir</keyword>
</DOC>