<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01074424</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Studying samples of blood from patients with cancer in the laboratory may help doctors identify and learn more about biomarkers related to cancer. It may also help doctors predict how well patients will respond to treatment. PURPOSE: This research study is looking at biomarkers in blood samples from patients with invasive cervical cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Studying Biomarkers in Blood Samples From Patients With Invasive Cervical Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - To develop a serum proteomic profile for cervical cancer using banked pre-treatment serum specimens from patients with invasive cervical cancer and to determine if this serum proteomic profile has possible utility in cervical cancer prognosis. Secondary - To develop a serum proteomic profile for cervical cancer using banked post-treatment serum specimens from these patients and to determine if this serum proteomic profile has possible utility in cervical cancer prognosis. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Banked serum specimens are used to generate proteomic profiles.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed invasive adenocarcinoma, squamous cell carcinoma, or adenosquamous cell carcinoma of the cervix Stage IIB, III, or IVA disease Eligible and evaluable for GOG0191 Pre and/or posttreatment serum specimens available for proteomic analysis PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Patient has given consent to allow their specimen(s) to be used for future cancer research PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IIB cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IVA cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>cervical adenocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>cervical adenosquamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>cervical squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>