<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01074216</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out what effects, good and/or bad, vitamin D blood levels has on stage IV colorectal cancer. Tbe doctors want to see if it is possible to increase low vitamin D levels into normal range using vitamin D supplements taken by mouth. Low vitamin D levels have been associated with worse outcomes in persons who have cancer. Low vitamin D may also cause people to have symptoms such as pain and fatigue. We want to see if increasing low vitamin D levels will help improve cancer outcomes. Vitamin D is routinely repleted in all subjects known to be vitamin D deficient. Therefore, the treatment given would be considered standard of care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vitamin D Levels in Stage IV Colorectal Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with Stage IV (metastatic) colorectal cancer Baseline 25hydroxy vitamin D level &lt; 30 ng/ml Age ≥18 years of age Current or previous malignancy except adequately treated nonmelanoma skin cancer, curatively treated insitu cancer of the cervix, or other solid tumors curatively treated with no evidence of disease for &gt; 3 years Albumin &lt; 3.2 Patients on concurrent chronic steroids, other than those allowed for routine antiemetics, or inhaled steroids Patients receiving phenobarbital, phenytoin, orlistat and cholestyramine Hypercalcemia (Calcium &gt;10.5 mg/dl) Calcium x Phosphorus &gt; 70 mg2/dL2</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitamin D3</keyword>
	<keyword>colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>rectum cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Cholecalciferol</keyword>
	<keyword>09-143</keyword>
</DOC>