<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00762892</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a pilot that will evaluate two regimens for treating HIV infected patients that haven't been on treatment before. HIV/AIDS patients may have an increased risk of myocardial infarction and antiretroviral therapy used may contribute to this. We will evaluate virological, immunological and cardiovascular effects of two HIV treatment regimens.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Raltegravir vs. Atazanavir in Combination With Truvada速 for the Treatment of Antiretroviral na誰ve HIV Infected Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We will check blood studies used to evaluate HIV patients response to therapy including CD4 count and HIV viral load test. We will check routine safety labs done on HIV patients and also check homocysteine levels and creatine kinase level. We will evaluate homocysteine and IL6 levels at baseline, week 48, and week 96.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine, Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atazanavir Sulfate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Raltegravir Potassium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must be HIV1 positive and na誰ve to HIV therapy. Patients must plan to participate and be available for the trial for the 96week study period. Patients followed at Thomas Street Clinic. Patients must be over 18 years old. Patients must not be pregnant or plan to become pregnant over the 96week study period. Patients cannot be on a proton pump inhibitor. Patients cannot be undergoing treatment for active tuberculosis. Renal Insufficiency with a creatinine clearance &lt; 50 ml/min/1.73 m2 by the MDRD GFR calculation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Raltegravir</keyword>
	<keyword>Integrase inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Protease inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Naive patients</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Lipids</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment Na誰ve</keyword>
</DOC>