<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02763852</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the tolerability, pharmacokinetic profile of BIA 3-202 and its metabolites, and the pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic interaction between 4 different single doses of BIA 3-202 (50 mg, 100 mg, 200 mg and 400 mg) and a single dose of standard levodopa 100 mg/benserazide 25 mg (Madopar® 125) in adult male and female healthy volunteers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetic-Pharmacodynamic Interaction Between Four Different Single Doses of BIA 3-202 and a Single Dose of Levodopa/Benserazide (100/25 mg)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This was a single centre, double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, single-graded-dose, crossover study with five single-dose treatment periods. The washout period between doses was 15±2 days. For each of the five treatment periods, volunteers were to be admitted at the UFH on the day before the treatment day. On each treatment period, the pre-dose assessment were to be completed, BIA 3-202/Placebo was to be administered concomitantly with the dose of Madopar® 125 and post-dose assessments were to be completed. Subjects were discharged 30 h post-dose. Subjects should attend five treatment periods and were to receive a different dose of BIA 3-202 or placebo during each of these treatment periods.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Benserazide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levodopa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Benserazide, levodopa drug combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female subjects aged between 18 and 45 years, inclusive. Subjects of body mass index (BMI) between 19 and 28 kg/m2, inclusive. Subjects who were healthy as determined by pre study medical history, physical examination, and 12 lead ECG. Subjects who had clinical laboratory tests acceptable to the investigator. Subjects who were negative for HBsAg, antiHCV Ab and HIV1 and HIV2 Ab tests at screening. Subjects who were negative for drugs of abuse at screening and admission. Subjects who were nonsmokers or who smoked less than 10 cigarettes or equivalent per day. Subjects who were able and willing to give written informed consent. (If a woman) She was not of childbearing potential by reason of surgery or, if of childbearing potential, she used one of the following methods of contraception: double barrier, intrauterine device or abstinence. Subjects who did not conform to the above inclusion criteria, OR Subjects who had a clinically relevant history or presence of respiratory, gastrointestinal, renal, hepatic, haematological, lymphatic, neurological, cardiovascular, psychiatric, musculoskeletal, genitourinary, immunological, dermatological, connective tissue diseases or disorders. Subjects who had a clinically relevant surgical history. Subjects who had a clinically relevant family history. Subjects who had a history of relevant atopy. Subjects who had a history of relevant drug hypersensitivity. Subjects who had a history of alcoholism or drug abuse. Subjects who consumed more than 28 units of alcohol a week. Subjects who had a significant infection or known inflammatory process on screening and/or admission. Subjects who had acute gastrointestinal symptoms at the time of screening and/or admission (e.g., nausea, vomiting, diarrhoea, heartburn). Subjects who had an acute infection such as influenza at the time of screening and/or admission. Subjects who had used prescription drugs within 4 weeks of first dosing. Subjects who had used oral contraceptives or over the counter medication excluding oral routine vitamins but including mega dose vitamin therapy within one week of first dosing. Subjects who had used any investigational drug and/or participated in any clinical trial within 3 months of their first admission to the study. Subjects who had previously received BIA 3202. Subjects who had donated and/or received any blood or blood products within the previous 3 months prior to screening. Subjects who were vegetarians, vegans and/or had medical dietary restrictions. Subjects who could not communicate reliably with the investigator. Subjects who were unlikely to cooperate with the requirements of the study. (If woman) She was pregnant or breastfeeding. (If woman) She was at childbearing potential and she did not use an approved effective contraceptive method or she used oral contraceptives. Subjects who were unwilling or unable to give written informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Parkinson's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Nebicapone</keyword>
</DOC>