<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02763592</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to evaluate the impact of 5% lidocaine medicated plaster on allodynic symptoms of localized neuropathic pain after knee surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of 5% Lidocaine Medicated Plaster on Allodynic Symptoms of Localized Neuropathic Pain After Knee Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, parallel-group clinical trial comparing 5% lidocaine medicated plaster (5LP) and placebo whether neuropathic pain symptoms (dynamic mechanical allodynia, pressure, hot and cold) have a different chronological improvement with 5LP compared to placebo. Pain intensity and pain relief, sleep and quality of life and osteoarthritis severity are also assessed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged from 18 to 80 years Male or female, for women of childbearing potential, a negative pregnancy test Patients with PONP following knee surgery Patients with neuropathic pain DN4 ≥ 4 Patients at least 3 months postsurgery Patients suffering from at least the allodynic brushinduced mechanical allodynia symptom (DMA) rated as ≥ 5/10 on the numerical scale Patient with no localized neuropathic pain symptoms (DN4&lt;4) on the contralateral knee Intact skin besides the scar of surgery (absence of skin disease, skin irritation, inflammation or injury, such as active herpes zoster lesions, atopic dermatitis, wounds) in the area where the medicated plasters will be applied Naive from Versatis® treatment Treated with stable systemic analgesic and planned to remain stable all over the duration of the study Insured by French social security Included or agreement to be included in the national register of participants in biomedical research</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Localized Neuropathic pain</keyword>
	<keyword>5% lidocaine medicated plaster</keyword>
	<keyword>Knee surgery</keyword>
</DOC>