<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="202431">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00454324</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LCCC 0519</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>CDR0000542753</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00454324</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT00521313</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Abraxane and Carboplatin to Treat Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>NRR</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase II Clinical Trial of Carboplatin and Abraxane in Patients With Extensive Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>UNC Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Celgene Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>UNC Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase II trial of abraxane and carboplatin in extensive stage small cell lung
      cancer to examine overall response rate, time to progressive disease, survival time, and
      assessment of toxicity profile for Carboplatin and Abraxane.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients are being asked to be in this study because they have extensive disease small cell
      lung cancer. All eligible participants who agree to be in the study will receive both
      abraxane and carboplatin. The researchers want to evaluate the activity and safety of the
      combination of abraxane and carboplatin, and if this combination can help people with
      extensive disease small cell lung cancer.

      Carboplatin is a chemotherapy drug that has been approved by the Food and Drug
      Administration (FDA) to treat ovarian cancer. It is in a class of drugs known as
      platinum-containing compounds. It slows or stops the growth of cancer cells in your body.
      Carboplatin is not approved by the FDA for use in the treatment of small-cell lung cancer,
      either alone or combined with other anti-cancer drugs. However, carboplatin given with
      paclitaxel is a standard or active treatment in patients with small cell lung cancer,
      non-small cell lung cancer, breast cancer, and ovarian cancer. Abraxane is a chemotherapy
      drug that was approved by the FDA to treat metastatic breast cancer after other chemotherapy
      has already been tried. Abraxane is a new preparation of the active ingredient in the
      chemotherapy drug, paclitaxel. In a study done in breast cancer patients, Abraxane was
      compared to paclitaxel. Abraxane has been shown to be more effective than paclitaxel in
      tumor response and tumor progression, in addition to having fewer side effects than
      paclitaxel. Abraxane was shown to cause less damage to a person's white blood cells (the
      cells that fight infection) and cause fewer allergic reactions; however, more patients
      developed numbness of their hands and feet.

      Carboplatin and Abraxane are intravenous (IV) medications. Patients will begin treatment
      with 2 cycles (1 cycle = 21 days) of abraxane and carboplatin. Then there will be a disease
      assessment at cycles 2 and 4. Patients with stable disease, partial response, or complete
      response will get additional cycles. Patients with progressive disease no will be taken off
      the study treatment. A maximum of 6 cycles will be given.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    slow accrual
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>April 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Radiological imaging should be performed every 12 weeks, to ascertain the overall (or objective) response rate (Complete Response or Partial Response) according to the RECIST guidelines</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response</measure>
    <time_frame>every 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the time from when a response was first documented until the time when progression was documented, per RECIST criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>every 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the time between trial enrollment to disease progression or death (whichever occurs first) or date of last contact</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of individuals with adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>10 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Drug toxicities will be evaluated during treatment period and 30 days post treatment. Toxicities will be assessed using CTCAE criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Carboplatin + Abraxane (240mg/m2) on Day 1 of a 21 Day cycle, up to 6 cycles</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Carboplatin + Abraxane (80mg/m2)given on Days 1, 8 and 15 of a 21 Day Cycle, up to 6 cycles</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carboplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>Carboplatin will be given at a dose of AUC=6, on Day 1 of a 21 Day Cycle</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Paraplatin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Abraxane</intervention_name>
    <description>Abraxane will be given at a dose of 240mg/m2 on Day 1 of a 21 Day Cycle (Arm A)
Abraxane will be given at a dose of 80mg/m2 on Days 1, 8, and 15 of a 21 Day Cycle (Arm B)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Paclitaxel</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Histological or cytological diagnosis of ES-SCLC,* including malignant pleural
             effusion

          2. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) 0-2

          3. No prior systemic chemotherapy, immunotherapy, or biological therapy for SCLC

          4. Measurable disease as defined by the RECIST criteria

          5. Adequate organ function as defined by the protocol

          6. Female patients of child bearing potential (CBP) must agree to use of reliable method
             of birth control during and for 3 months following treatment

          7. Patients must sign informed consent document

          8. Patients must be ≥ 18 years of age

          9. Patients with brain metastases that have been adequately treated and are determined
             to be controlled by the attending physician are eligible

         10. Patients who have had prior malignancies are eligible if they are ≥ 5 years from
             diagnosis free of disease or the attending physician believes the patient's prognosis
             is best defined by the ES-SCLC (if questions concerning this eligibility criteria
             arise, please contact the principal investigator)

        (*)ES-SCLC defined as metastases outside the chest, pulmonary metastases, or contralateral
        metastases (supraclavicular or hilar) nodes that could not be included with a reasonable
        single radiation port. Patients with malignant pleural effusions are considered extensive
        stage.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Received treatment within the last 30 days with a drug that has not received Food and
             Drug Administration (FDA) approval for any indication at the time of study entry

          2. Pregnancy or breast feeding

          3. Serious active infection that would require a prolonged course (4-6 weeks) of
             antibiotics or would compromise the safety of the patient or compromise the patient's
             ability to complete the study

          4. Symptomatic brain metastases

          5. Grade ≥ 2 neuropathy using NCI CTCAE version 3.0 criteria

          6. Previous anaphylactic reaction to carboplatin, paclitaxel, and docetaxel

          7. Severe or uncontrolled cardiac disease, defined as uncontrolled or unstable angina,
             myocardial infarction in the last month, uncontrolled congestive heart failure (≥ 3
             admissions for congestive heart failure in the 3 months prior to diagnosis)
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas Stinchcombe, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of North Carolina Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27599-7295</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.cancer.gov/</url>
    <description>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 20, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 28, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Small cell lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Abraxane</keyword>
  <keyword>Paclitaxel</keyword>
  <keyword>Carboplatin</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase II</keyword>
  <keyword>Randomized</keyword>
  <keyword>Lineberger</keyword>
  <keyword>LCCC</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
