<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01694784</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Most prevention efforts focus on promoting services (e.g. vaccination, screening tests). While some of these services have clear net benefit, many instead have possible or clear net harm. Currently, three quarters of services graded by the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force (USPSTF) have possible or clear net harm (C, I, and D services). Many of these services are delivered in healthcare settings at higher rates than what might be expected based on their potential for harm. This leads to adverse outcomes, excess costs, and missed opportunities to deliver more quality care. An important issue in delivering prevention messages is how to shift toward a focus on the appropriateness of prevention: encouraging services with clear net benefit and either discouraging or reducing demand for services with possible or clear net harm. Unfortunately, little is known about what drives overuse of potentially harmful screening services or how to make harms relevant to patients. This randomized controlled trial (RCT) of 775 patients at 4 primary care practices aims to 1) assess factors associated with intent to receive possibly or clearly harmful screening services and 2) determine whether and how patients' plans to get screened change with various presentations of information about harms (e.g. qualitative, quantitative, narrative, framed). The investigators will focus on three types of screening services: osteoporosis screening (previous C recommendation and now no recommendation for women &lt; 65 years old with no fracture risk factors), prostate-specific antigen (PSA) screening (D recommendation for all men, regardless of age), and colorectal cancer (CRC) screening (C for ages 76-85).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Understanding and Discouraging Overuse of Potentially Harmful Screening Tests</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women between ages 50 to 85 Men between ages 50 to 85 Eligible for exemplar service of interest (see below for specifics of inclusion/exclusion for specific services) Current treatment of psychosis History of alcohol or substance abuse within the last 2 years Dementia or other severe cognitive dysfunction serious medical illnesses with a life expectancy of less than 2 years (e.g., metastatic cancer) inability to speak and understand English blindness presentation for an acute medical visit no telephone number Osteoporosis Screening (women aged 5064) a personal history of osteoporosis a personal history of moderate or severe osteopenia BMI (body mass index) &lt; 18.5 personal history of nontraumatic fracture family history of hip fracture current smoking current use of prednisone (&gt;30 consecutive days) alcohol use of 3 or more drinks/day. Prostate Cancer screening (men aged 5069) a prior history of prostate cancer Colorectal Cancer Screening (men and women aged 7685) prior history of colorectal cancer adenomatous colon polyps &gt; 6mm (or 2 or more &lt; 6mm) symptoms referable to colorectal cancer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>