<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01850134</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this trial is to evaluate a nutritional supplement for people with Diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of a Nutritional Supplement for People With Type 2 Diabetes.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects will be eligible for the study if they meet all of the following inclusion criteria: 1. Diagnosis of Type 2 Diabetes. 2. Age between 18 and 75 years. 3. HbA1c &gt; 6.0 but ≤ 8.5 4. If female and of childbearing potential , subject is nonpregnant, non lactating, at least 6 weeks postpartum and agrees to practice birth control throughout study duration. 5. BMI &gt; 18.5 kg/m2 and &lt; 40.0 kg/m2. 6. Chronic medication dosage must be stable for at least two months prior to Screening Visit. 7. Subject states that they are a habitual consumer of a morning meal. Subjects will be excluded from the study if they meet any of the following criteria: 1. Use of exogenous insulin or GLP1 agonists for glucose control. 2. Diagnosis of Type 1 diabetes. 3. History of diabetic ketoacidosis. 4. Current infection (requiring medication or hospitalization), has received corticosteroid treatment in the last 3 months, or has had surgery or received antibiotics in the last 3 weeks. 5. Active malignancy. 6. Significant cardiovascular event &lt; 12 weeks prior to study entry. 7. End stage organ failure or status post organ transplant. 8. Active metabolic, hepatic, or gastrointestinal disease. 9. Chronic, contagious, infectious disease. 10. Currently taking herbals, dietary supplements, or medications (other than antihyperglycemic medications) that could profoundly affect blood glucose. 11. History of fainting or other adverse reactions in response to blood collection. 12. Clotting or bleeding disorders. 13. Allergy or intolerance to study product ingredient.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>