<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01850108</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Allogeneic blood or marrow transplantation (alloBMT) is a curative therapy for a variety of hematologic disorders, including sickle cell disease and thalassemia. Even when it is clear that alloBMT can give to these patients an improvement in their disease, myeloablative transplants have important toxicities and mortalities associated. The lack of suitable donors continues to be a limit to access to transplantation. Substantial progress has been made recently in the development of pre-treatment regimens that facilitate the sustained engraftment of donor marrow with reduced toxicity. Most of these regimens incorporate highly immunosuppressive drugs, which allow the reduction or elimination of myeloablative agents or total body irradiation without endangering the sustained engraftment of HLA-identical allogeneic stem cells. Preliminary results of non-myeloablative allogeneic stem cell transplantation suggest that the procedure can be performed in patients who are ineligible for myeloablative alloBMT, and that sustained remissions of several hematologic malignancies can be obtained.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Non-Myeloablative Conditioning and Bone Marrow Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemoglobinopathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who are ineligible for BMT from an HLAmatched sibling donor can proceed to a haploBMT. Patients with an HLAmatched related donor will proceed to a matched BMT. Age 270 years Good performance status (ECOG 0 or 1; Karnofsky and Lansky 70100) Patients and donors must be able to sign consent forms. First degree relative should be willing to donate Patients must be geographically accessible and willing to participate in all stages of treatment. Eligible diagnoses: Patients with sickle cell anemia such as sickle cell anemia (Hb SS), Hb Sβ° thalassemia, Hb Sβ+ thalassemia, Hb SC disease, Hb SE disease, Hb SD disease, Hemoglobin SO Arab disease HbS with hereditary persistence of fetal hemoglobin. Other significant hemoglobinopathies that also fulfill criterion from below. Plus one of the following: 1. Stroke or central nervous system event lasting more than 24 hours. 2. MRI changes indicative of brain parenchyma damage. 3. MRA evidence of cerebrovascular disease. 4. Acute chest syndrome requiring exchange transfusion or hospitalization. 5. Recurrent vasoocclusive pain episodes and hospitalization crisis (more than 2/year for the last 2 years). 6. Stage I or II sickle lung disease. 7. Transfusion dependent thalassemia Poor performance status (ECOG&gt;1). Poor cardiac function: left ventricular ejection fraction&lt;35%. Poor pulmonary function: FEV1 and FVC&lt;40% predicted. Pulmonary hypertension moderate to severe by echocardiographic standards. Poor liver function: direct bilirubin &gt;3.1 mg/dl HIVpositive Minor (donor antirecipient) ABO incompatibility if an ABO compatible donor is available. Prior transfusions from donor or recipient if caused alloimmunization vs. donor cells. Women of childbearing potential who currently are pregnant (BetaHCG+) or who are not practicing adequate contraception. Patients who have any debilitating medical or psychiatric illness that would preclude their giving informed consent or their receiving optimal treatment and followup. Criteria for donor eligibility Weight ≥ 20kg and age ≥ 18 years Donors must meet the selection criteria as defined by the Foundation for the Accreditation of Hematopoietic Cell Therapy (FAHCT) and will be screened per the American Association of Blood Banks (AABB). (AABB guidelines and the recipients will be informed of any deviations.) When more than one donor is available, the donor with the lowest number of HLA allele mismatches will be chosen, unless there is HLA crossmatch incompatibility or a medical reason to select otherwise, in which case donor selection is the responsibility of the PI, in consultation with the immunogenetics laboratory. In cases where there is more than one donor with the least degree of mismatch,donors will be selected based on the most favorable combination of (i) HLA compatibility in crossmatch testing and (ii) ABO compatibility: HLA crossmatching (in order of priority) 1. Mutually compatible (no crossmatching antibodies) 2. Recipient noncrossreactive with donor, donor crossreactive with recipient 3. Mutually crossreactive ABO compatibility (in order of priority) Compatible Major incompatibility Minor incompatibility Major and minor incompatibility Donors will be selected to minimize HLA mismatch in the hostversusgraft direction. Donor must have a hemoglobin S =/&lt; ~50%.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>