<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="164399">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00957801</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>09-070</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00957801</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Anabolic and Inflammatory Responses to Short-Term Testosterone Administration in Older Men</brief_title>
  <official_title>Anabolic and Inflammatory Responses to Short-Term Testosterone Administration in Older Men</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Skeletal muscle loss is a common consequence of aging and in some individuals reaches a
      level that compromises health and quality of life. Age-associated increases in cytokine and
      inflammatory signaling may be important contributors to this process. In this project the
      investigators will test the hypotheses that 1) testosterone will inhibit cytokine and
      inflammatory signaling in skeletal muscles of older adults and 2) will augment the anabolic
      response to increased skeletal muscle activity. The investigators will also assess the
      practical question of whether testosterone injection and gel application elicit similar
      responses. Resistance exercise will be used as a means of stimulating both inflammatory and
      anabolic responses in skeletal muscle. In order to assess the effects of testosterone on
      these responses, fourteen subjects will perform resistance exercise on two occasions
      separated by 7 days. The first session will be performed prior to the initiation of
      testosterone therapy and the second session will be performed after receiving testosterone
      for 7 days.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this project we will study the acute response to testosterone treatment between two
      groups of seven subjects each, comparing two methods of administration (injection vs.
      topical gel) in a sequential fashion in order to obtain pilot information for a subsequent,
      randomized, blinded long-term investigation.

      The first session will be performed prior to the initiation of testosterone therapy and the
      second session will be performed after receiving testosterone for 7 days. Because dietary
      intake, particularly protein intake, can influence muscle metabolism, subjects will be
      placed on standardized diets for the twenty four hour period preceding muscle metabolism
      studies in order to reduce the likelihood of skewed results due to variations in nutritional
      intake just prior to these studies. In addition, subjects will be asked to maintain a food
      intake diary for the three day period prior to metabolism studies in order to document
      dietary intake in the days leading up to muscle metabolism studies. Subjects will also be
      asked to complete a fatigue questionnaire at baseline and at the final study to assess
      perceived changes in fatigue between the two treatment groups over the treatment period.
      Subjects will also collect their urine over a twenty four hour period prior to baseline and
      final studies to measure cortisol levels, which can influence the rate of protein breakdown.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Muscle protein synthesis and breakdown with and without testosterone treatment following resistance exercise</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum and skeletal muscle cytokine levels and inflammatory signaling will be measured before and after a standardized bout of resistance exercise, both with and without testosterone treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of anabolic response and inflammatory response in muscle treated with injected testosterone versus testosterone gel</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">29</enrollment>
  <condition>Sarcopenia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Testosterone injection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Testosterone enanthate given as a single 150 mg Intramuscular (IM) injection</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Testosterone gel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Testosterone topical gel 10 mg administered daily for seven days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Testosterone injection</intervention_name>
    <description>150 mg single IM injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Testosterone injection</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Testosterone enanthate</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Testosterone gel</intervention_name>
    <description>Testosterone gel 10 mg. administered topically daily for seven days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Testosterone gel</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Androgel</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Age: 60-85

          -  Gender: Male

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Exclusionary medications will be an anticoagulant (Coumadin) because of the risk of
             bleeding during the biopsy procedure. Additional medications which will be disallowed
             for participation include: anabolic steroids, nitrates, antihistamines, and
             glucocorticoids.

          -  The subjects must be able to successfully complete an exercise stress test using the
             Bruce protocol . Subjects will be excluded without exercise testing, with a history
             of angina that occurs with exertion or at rest, or a myocardial infarction within the
             last 12 months. Subjects that demonstrate ³0.1 milliVolts (mV) horizontal or
             downsloping ST segment depression, a drop in systolic blood pressure of ³10 mm Hg,
             and/or frequent or repetitive arrhythmias (defined as ³10 premature ventricular
             contractions (PVC)/min, or couplets) during the stress test will be excluded.

          -  Subjects with LDL cholesterol above 200 mg/dL will be excluded .

          -  Any man with a history of breast cancer or prostate cancer, or any indication of an
             occult carcinoma from an elevation of prostate specific antigen (PSA) above 4.0 mg/L
             (53), or severe benign prostatic hypertrophy (BPH) by history (frequent urination,
             reduced stream) will be excluded.

          -  Subjects with liver dysfunction evidenced by a history of hepatitis B or hepatitis C,
             or by a three-fold elevation of liver enzymes (Alk phos, alanine aminotransferase
             (ALT), aspartate amino-transferase (AST) above normal on screening will be excluded
             from the study.

          -  Any subject with a blood pressure on three consecutive measurements taken at one week
             intervals that has a systolic pressure ³ 140 or a diastolic blood pressure ³ 90 will
             be excluded.

          -  Any subject who has a major medical illness such as diabetes, chronic obstructive
             pulmonary disease, or sleep apnea will be excluded. Moreover, subjects will not have
             a recent history of smoking tobacco. Morbidly obese older men (BMI &gt; 35) will also be
             excluded.

          -  Subjects will evidence of kidney disease (serum creatinine &gt; 2.0mg/dl) will be
             excluded from participation.

          -  Any subject with thyroid disease as determined by an abnormal thyroid stimulating
             hormone (TSH) level will be excluded from participation.

          -  Any subject testing positive for HIV will be excluded .

          -  Allergy to iodine, a component of Betadine which is used to prepare the subject's
             skin for invasive procedures, will be cause for exclusion from this study.

          -  Men with serum total testosterone concentrations greater than 500 ng/dL will be
             excluded.

          -  Subjects who engage in high intensity resistance training on a regular basis will be
             excluded.

          -  Subjects with a known coagulation disorder or with clinical evidence indicative of a
             bleeding disorder (easy bruising, &quot;free bleeders&quot;) will not be enrolled in this study
             due to potential problems that could arise from muscle biopsy procedures.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Randall J Urban, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston</name>
      <address>
        <city>Galveston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77555-0567</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 10, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 10, 2009</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Sarcopenia</keyword>
  <keyword>Aging muscle</keyword>
  <keyword>Androgen</keyword>
  <keyword>Cytokines</keyword>
  <keyword>Muscle metabolism</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Sarcopenia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Testosterone enanthate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Testosterone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Testosterone undecanoate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Testosterone 17 beta-cypionate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methyltestosterone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
