<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02492763</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicenter randomized, double-blind, placebo- and active-controlled (liraglutide; Victoza®), parallel-group, clinical trial of MK-8521 in participants with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) with inadequate glycemic control while on a stable dose of metformin (≥1000 mg/day). The trial will include a 1-week screening period; an 8-week antihyperglycemic agent (AHA) washout period, if required; a 14-week blinded therapy period (which includes single-blind run-in and double-blind therapy); and a 14-day post-treatment visit, 2 weeks after the last dose of investigational product. The primary hypotheses of the trial are to assess the hemoglobin A1c (HbA1C)-lowering efficacy of the addition of MK-8521 relative to placebo and to evaluate safety and tolerability of MK-8521.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Preliminary Study of the Efficacy and Safety of MK-8521 for Type 2 Diabetes (MK-8521-004)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have T2DM in accordance with American Diabetes Association guidelines Be on metformin monotherapy (&gt;1000 mg/day: metformin IR or metformin XR) for at least 12 weeks prior to study start with a hemoglobin A1C (A1C) &gt;7.5 and &lt;10.5% OR Be on dual therapy with metformin (&gt;1000 mg/day: dose stable for at least 4 weeks prior to study start) with an A1C of &gt;7.0% and &lt;10.0% and a second AHA and be willing to washout the second AHA. Allowable AHAs are dipeptidyl peptidase 4 (DPP4 inhibitors), alphaglucosidase inhibitors, sulfonylureas, and glinides. Have a body mass index (BMI) ≥23 kg/m2 and ≤40 kg/m2 Is a female who is not of reproductive potential, or is a female of reproductive potential who agrees to avoid becoming pregnant: while receiving study drug and for 14 days after the last dose of study drug Have a history of type 1 diabetes or a history of diabetic ketoacidosis Has a history of other specific types of diabetes (e.g., genetic syndromes, secondary pancreatic diabetes, diabetes due to endocrinopathies, drug or chemicalinduced, and postorgan transplant) Has been treated with any gutderived incretin hormone glucagonlike peptide 1 (GLP1) receptor agonist (e.g. Byetta™, Victoza™ or investigational agents) within the last 6 months or has had GLP1 receptor agonist discontinued due to gastrointestinal intolerance or lack of efficacy. Note: treatment with a GLP1 receptor agonist that was discontinued &gt;6 months prior to study start is not an exclusion if the GLP1 receptor agonist was discontinued for reasons other than gastrointestinal intolerance or lack of efficacy. Has a history of clinically significant gastrointestinal disorder (including diabetic gastroparesis; irritable bowel disease; recurrent episodes of nausea, vomiting, diarrhea and abdominal pain) Has a history of clinically significant and active, immunological, respiratory, genitourinary or major neurological (including stroke, transient ischemic attack and chronic seizures) abnormalities or diseases Has a history of cardiovascular disease (including diabetic cardiomyopathy) or significant cardiac condition (including a history of myocardial infarction, stable or unstable angina, arterial revascularization, pathologic, symptomatic or sustained tachyarrhythmia [e.g. atrial fibrillation, sustained supraventricular tachycardia, symptomatic nonsustained supraventricular tachycardia, ventricular tachycardia, ventricular fibrillation, WolfParkinsonWhite syndrome, congenital long QT syndrome, etc.]) or heart failure Has a family history of medullary carcinoma of the thyroid or multiple endocrine neoplasm type2 syndrome Has active diabetic proliferative retinopathy or a history of maculopathy Has human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) Has a medical history of active liver disease (other than nonalcoholic hepatic steatosis), including chronic hepatitis B or C (assessed by medical history), primary biliary cirrhosis, or active symptomatic gallbladder disease Is on a weight loss medication or has undergone bariatric surgery Has a history of acute or chronic pancreatitis of any etiology Had an event of severe hypoglycemia with neuroglycopenia in the past 12 months Has a positive urine pregnancy test Is pregnant or breastfeeding, or is planning to conceive during the trial, including 14 days following the last dose of investigational product Routinely consumes &gt;1 alcoholic drinks per day or &gt;7 alcoholic drinks per week or engages in binge drinking Routinely consumes ≥480mg /day caffeine in caffeinated beverages (1 cup of coffee contains approximately 120 mg of caffeine Is taking a beta blocker or medications with sympathomimetic activity (e.g. pseudoephedrine, phenylpropanolamine, etc.) Is currently a user of nicotine or nicotine containing products or does not agree to refrain from using nicotine during the trial, including 14 days following the last dose of investigational product Is currently a user of any illicit drugs (including any marijuana use) or has a history of drug (including alcohol) abuse within approximately 5 years has other severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory abnormality that may increase the risk associated with study participation or blinded investigational product administration</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>