<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01302587</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is evaluating the effectiveness of a dose counter for an inhaler device used to deliver medication to people diagnosed with asthma or COPD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Integrated Dose Counter on an Albuterol Hydrofluoroalkane (HFA) Metered Dose Inhaler (MDI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bronchitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emphysema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bronchitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albuterol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent/assent General good health Asthma or COPD Capable of understanding the requirements, risks, and benefits of study participation. Able to demonstrate proper metereddose inhaler use and technique. Other inclusion criteria apply History of lifethreatening asthma or COPD that is defined for this protocol as an asthma or COPD episode that required intubation and/or was associated with hypercapnia, respiratory arrest or hypoxic seizures. Culturedocumented or suspected bacterial or viral infection of the upper or lower respiratory tract, sinus, or middle ear that is not resolved within 2 weeks of Screening Visit. Is being treated with a longacting β2agonist alone. Is currently being treated with Ventolin HFA. Any asthma or COPD exacerbation requiring oral corticosteroids within 2 months of Screening Visit. A subject must not have had any hospitalization for asthma or COPD within 4 months prior to Screening Visit. Historical or current evidence of a clinically significant nonasthmatic acute or chronic condition. Uncontrolled hypertension History of any adverse reaction to any component of the HFAMDI formulation. Participation in any investigational drug study within the 30 days preceding the Screening Visit. Other exclusion criteria apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>