<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01936896</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Acute myocardial infarction is characterized by an intense inflammatory response. The degree of the response influences clinical outcome, with 'more' inflammation promoting heart failure. In this study we plan to determine whether treatment with plasma derived alpha-1 antitrypsin will quench the inflammatory response in patients with acute ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Alpha-1 Anti-Trypsin (AAT) Treatment in Acute Myocardial Infarction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alpha 1-Antitrypsin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Protein C Inhibitor</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Acute STEMI defined as chest pain (or equivalent) with an onset within 12 hours and ECG evidence of ST segment elevation (&gt;1 mm) in 2 or more anatomically contiguous leads that is new or presumably new Planned or completed coronary angiogram for potential intervention Age&gt;21 Inability to give informed consent Hemodynamic instability as defined as need for inotropic or vasoactive agents, or need for mechanical support devices (including intraaortic balloon pump) Pregnancy Preexisting congestive heart failure (American Heart Association/American College of Cardiology class CD, New York Heart Association IIIIV) Preexisting severe left ventricular dysfunction (EF&lt;20%) Preexisting severe valvular heart disease Known active infections (acute or chronic) Recent (&lt;14 days) or active use of antiinflammatory drugs (not including NSAIDs or corticosteroids used for IV dye allergy only) Known chronic inflammatory disease (including but not limited to rheumatoid arthritis, systemic lupus erythematosus) Known active malignancy of any type, or prior diagnosis in the past 10 years Anticipated need for cardiac or major surgery Known active cancer (or prior diagnosis of cancer within the past 10 years) Known Immunoglobulin A (IgA) deficiency</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute myocardial infarction</keyword>
	<keyword>Heart Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammation</keyword>
</DOC>