<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01936233</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sustained chronic hepatitis B virus inflammation is a major cause of liver cancer occurrence and development. Antiviral treatment can block the persistent infection. Aspirin can inhibit platelet function and CD8 + T cell mediated liver cell necrosis and inflammation. Aspirin also can inhibit liver cancer cells metastasis through inhibit COX2.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Study of Antiviral and Aspirin Treatment in Liver Cancer After Radical Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lamivudine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Hepatocellular carcinoma confirmed with pathology or identified with radiological images with typical features Age ≥ 18 years and ≤ 75 years At least one tumor nodule with one unidimension of ≥ 2 cm ChildPugh Class A or B HBVDNA&gt;10^4 Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal ALT and AST ≤ 2.0 x the upper limit of normal PTINR&lt;2.3,PTT &lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5x upper limit of normal Peripheral white blood cell count of or more than 3×10(9)/L Peripheral platelet of or more than 50×10(9)/L Expected survival time not less than 3 months ECOG score 02 Tumor thrombi in main branch of portal vein Tumor involvement more than 70% of whole liver With extrahepatic metastasis Prior systemic chemotherapy or chemoembolization Congestive heart failure &gt; NYHA class 2 History of HIV infection Active clinically serious infections (&gt; 2 NCICTC Version 3.0) Recurrence of HCC after liver transplantation Pregnant or breastfeeding Substance abuse, medical, psychological or social conditions that may interfere with the patient's participation in this study Known or suspected allergy to any agent given in association with this trial Patients unable to swallow oral medication Inclined to thrombosis Inclined to hemorrhage or active hemorrhage with 1 month</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Aspirin</keyword>
	<keyword>antiviral treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrence free survival</keyword>
	<keyword>radical therapy</keyword>
</DOC>