<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01891227</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients with pretreated, Her2-negative, advanced breast cancer will receive chemotherapy with capecitabine and bendamustine for a maximum of eight cycles and afterwards capecitabine alone until disease progression or unacceptable toxic effects. Safety assessments will be conducted in 3-weekly intervals, efficacy assessments (CT or MRI) will be conducted every 9 weeks. Aim of this study is to determine whether treatment with capecitabine in combination with bendamustine is efficacious and safe.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Capecitabine + Bendamustine in Women With Pretreated Locally Advanced or Metastatic Her2-negative Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>40 eligible patients will be enrolled. A two-stage design efficacy and safety of bendamustine and capecitabine will be evaluated following recruitment of the first 20 patients. Upon favorable results a further 20 patients will be recruited to reach the target population of 40 evaluable patients. Pretreatment for eligible patients must include anthracyclines and/or taxanes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bendamustine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed informed consent Female patients, age ≥ 18 years (women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test at screening and must use effective contraception) Advanced or metastatic Her2negative breast cancer, histologically confirmed At least one measurable lesion according to RECIST criteria (Version 1.1) Documented disease progression Patients with progression after anthracycline and/or taxane treatment(palliative or adjuvant) Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks Performance status 02 Hematologic: ANC (absolute neutrophil count) ≥ 1.5 x 109/L Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL Platelets ≥ 100 x 109/L Liver Function: Albumin ≥ 2.5 g/dL Serum bilirubin ≤ 2 mg/dL AST (Aspartate aminotransferase) and ALT (Alanine aminotransferase) ≤ 3 x ULN (Upper limit of Normal) without liver metastases 5 x ULN if documented liver metastases Renal Function: Serum Creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL OR Calculated Creatinine Clearance ≥ 40 mL/min Pregnant or lactating women Serious medical or psychiatric disorders that would interfere with the patient's safety or informed consent Radiation of the target lesion within the last 4 weeks Active bacterial, viral or fungal infection Patients with clinically apparent brain metastases Known Positivity for HIV Positivity for Hepatitis B or C History of other malignancy; patients who have been diseasefree for 5 years or patients with a history of completely resected nonmelanoma skin cancer or successfully treated in situ carcinoma are eligible. Concurrent cancer therapy (chemotherapy, immunotherapy, antihormonal or biologic therapy) or concurrent treatment with an investigational drug Antihormonal therapy must have been discontinued prior to start of treatment (if possible at least 3 weeks before) Known hypersensitivity to the study drugs capecitabine and bendamustine or their excipients Pretreatment with capecitabine (pretreatment with infusional 5FU (Fluorouracil) in the adjuvant or neoadjuvant setting is allowed) or bendamustine Treatment with sorivudine or derivates e.g. brivudin (Mevir©) within the last 4 weeks before and during study treatment with capecitabine</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bendamustine</keyword>
	<keyword>Capecitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>Pretreated</keyword>
	<keyword>Her2 negative</keyword>
	<keyword>Advanced breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Anthracycline pretreatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Taxane pretreatment</keyword>
</DOC>