<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03077919</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multisite, randomized, blinded, sham-procedure-controlled study to evaluate the efficacy of right-sided stellate ganglion block (SGB) on the acute symptomatology of Post traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD), evaluated by the Clinician-Administered PTSD Scale (CAPS-5) clinical interview at pre-treatment and at 8 weeks. This entry describes the effectiveness study.The acceptability study is described in a separate entry.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness and Acceptability of Stellate Ganglion Block for Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Symptoms - Effectiveness</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study intervention will be administered at week 0 and at week 2. Injections will be performed under ultrasound visualization. The study medication will be either 7-10 mL 0.5% ropivacaine injected ventral to the right longus coli muscle (around and into the ventral fascia) and into the longus coli immediately dorsal to the presumed ventral fascia at the level of the C6 anterior tubercle (landmarks for the stellate ganglion) (active study medication) or 1-2 mL preservative free normal saline injected anterolateral to the anterior tubercle of C6 (sham procedure). The participant will not be informed which treatment he or she has received and the interaction of the participant and treating physician will be scripted as much as possible. Following the intervention, the treating physician should have no further contact with the participant except as required for participant safety. Participants will be evaluated for posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) symptomatology prior to week 0 and at 8 weeks using the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual (DSM-5) Clinician-Administered PTSD Scale (CAPS-5). They will complete the PTSD Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5), the PTSD Checklist - Civilian Version (PCL-C), and the Mini-international Neuropsychiatric Interview (M.I.N.I.-Plus) Suicidality Items at 0, 2, 4, 6, and 8 weeks; they also will complete the M.I.N.I.-Plus items at screening. The 12 item short form survey (SF-12), generalized anxiety disorder 7-item (GAD-7), patient health questionnaire (PHQ-9), K6, Alcohol Use Disorder Identification Test (AUDIT-C/AUDIT), and a short pain scale will be completed at weeks 0, 4, and 8.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Member of the Army on active duty status Personal access to Internet Anticipated stable assignment to installation for at least 2 months Stable dosing for ≥3 months, if receiving psychotropic medications Prior to enrollment, offered PTSD treatment using Alevel modality (as defined by U.S. Army Medical Command (MEDCOM) policy 14094; 18 Dec 2014). PTSD Checklist Civilian (PCLC) score of 32 or greater at screening Acceptable clinically indicated preoperative laboratory studies, per standard sitespecific protocols Prior Stellate Ganglion Block (SGB) Allergy to amide local anesthetics (e.g., ropivacaine, bupivacaine) Pregnancy (evaluated by urine test preprocedure) Current anticoagulant use History of a bleeding disorder Infection or mass at injection site Myocardial infarction within 6 months of procedure Phrenic or laryngeal nerve palsy (hoarseness) History of glaucoma History of schizophrenia, other psychotic disorder, bipolar disorder, or personality disorder (axis 2) Moderate or severe traumatic brain injury Symptoms of moderate to severe substance use disorder in past 30 days Suicidal ideation in the past 2 months, documented by the M.I.N.I.Plus Suicidality Items Any ongoing other major life stressor or condition not listed here that the site Investigator believes clearly would place the participant at risk for injury or a poor outcome</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Posttraumatic Stress Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Generalized Anxiety Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Distress</keyword>
	<keyword>Alcohol Use</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
</DOC>