<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02006940</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is devoted to the comparative analysis of the data received in patients with lung pathology using new method of probe-based confocal laser endoscopy of distal airways and two reference methods: high resolution computed tomography and morphology.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Study Of Probe-Based Confocal Laser Endomicroscopy Of Distal Airways In Diagnostics Of Lung Diseases</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A relatively new technology in pulmonary medicine, probe-based confocal laser endomicroscopy of distal airways, which is also called alveoscopy, allows for real-time minimally invasive intraacinar imaging. This method has been developed that special miniprobe can be passed into the distal airway via the working channel of the bronchoscope and provide so called "optical biopsy". The method is based on the natural autofluorescence of pulmonary structures, detecting the elastin scaffold of central and peripheral airways, the structure of alveoli, blood vessels and alveolar macrophages. Taking into account the fact that in vivo endomicroscopy of distal airways is a novel diagnostic technique it needs correlating the obtained data at certain disease with the reference methods for the challenges of our current understanding of interpreting endomicroscopic images. We choose high resolution computed tomography and morphology as such reference methods.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient Informed Consent; patients' fitness; the diagnosis of one of the following lung diseases: COPD, pneumonia, solitary nodule, pulmonary sarcoidosis, idiopathic interstitial pneumonia, hypersensitivity pneumonitis, pulmonary vasculitis, pulmonary eosinophilia, hemochromatosis, histiocytosis X, pulmonary lymphangioleiomyomatosis; alveolar proteinosis, other rare lung disease high resolution computed tomography scans performed not later than one month before pCLE; planned or performed histology Severe respiratory failure, pregnancy or breast feeding, lung bleeding, any acute or chronic disease that may be a contraindication to bronchoscopy, any significant blood coagulation disorder, any diseases of hematopoietic system, alcoholism or toxic addiction, taking part in other clinical trials,</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>alveoflex</keyword>
	<keyword>probe-based confocal laser endomicroscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>pCLE</keyword>
	<keyword>alveoscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>morphology</keyword>
	<keyword>high resolution computed tomography</keyword>
</DOC>