<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02006277</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is intended to evaluate the sensory attributes and estimate the relative bioavailability of three prototype oral formulations. Subjects will either taste 75-mg doses by "swirl and spit" (Cohort 1) or will receive five oral single 250-mg doses with a washout period of at least 14 days (Cohort 2).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study To Taste Three New Types Of Crizotinib Formulation In Comparison Of An Oral Solution And To Measure The Amount Of Crizotinib In The Body After These Formulations Are Orally Given, Relative To Capsule Formulation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Crizotinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy male and/or female subjects of nonchildbearing potential between the ages of 18 and 55 years, inclusive. Healthy is defined as no clinically relevant abnormalities identified by a detailed medical history, full physical examination, including blood pressure and pulse rate measurement, 12 lead ECG or clinical laboratory tests. Female subjects of non child bearing potential must have a Body Mass Index (BMI) of 17.5 to 30.5 kg/m2; and a total body weight &gt;50 kg (110 lbs). Evidence or history of clinically significant hematological, renal, endocrine, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, hepatic, psychiatric, neurologic, or allergic disease (including drug allergies, but excluding untreated, asymptomatic, seasonal allergies at time of dosing). Pregnant or nursing females; females of childbearing potential. Use of prescription or nonprescription drugs and dietary supplements within 7 days or 5 half lives (whichever is longer) prior to the first dose of study medication. Limited use of non prescription medications that are not believed to affect subject safety or the overall results of the study may be permitted on a casebycase basis following approval by the sponsor.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>healthy volunteers</keyword>
	<keyword>taste</keyword>
	<keyword>bioavailability</keyword>
</DOC>