<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00964717</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims to examine the efficacy of an Integrative approach utilizing Chiropractic as an add-on therapy for the treatment back and neck pain in an emergency department setting Chiropractic is well established as an effective treatment for back pain. The investigators cumulative experience in Asaf Harofeh Medical Center has shown Chiropractic to be an effective therapy for simple back and neck pain in an emergency room (ER) setting. This study will examine weather Chiropractic can decrease pain, increase range of motion and decrease anxiety in patients admitted to the Emergency Room with simple back and neck pain without neurological findings. Chiropractic will be performed as an add on therapy on top of analgesic therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chiropractic for Back and Neck Pain in an Emergency Department Setting</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neck Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult male and females age 1860 with acute or sub acute/chronic simple back or neck pain Agreed to a physical examination and by an orthopedic physician and Xray Diagnosis of simple back pain with levels of 4 &lt; NRS at least Agreed and able to fill pain, anxiety and satisfactory questioners Agreed and able to sign informed consent Fracture, sprain or neurological deficit during physical examination Pain scale of NRS &lt; 4 Active pregnancy Active inflammatory arthritis History of CVA Open wounds Acute malignancy with life expectancy of less than 5 years Experience with acupuncture treatments History of drug addiction History of osteoporosis Declined or unable to sign informed consent Soldiers in active military service Received a chiropractic treatment in the past</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>back pain</keyword>
	<keyword>neck pain</keyword>
	<keyword>anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>range of motion</keyword>
</DOC>