<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02033148</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase I trial studies the side effects and best dose of icotinib hydrochloride in treating patients with advanced cancers. Icotinib hydrochloride may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Icotinib Hydrochloride in Treating Patients With Advanced Cancers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the pharmacokinetic (PK) profiles of icotinib (icotinib hydrochloride) in patients with advanced cancers. II. To determine the safety, tolerability and maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of icotinib in patients with advanced cancers. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To preliminarily assess the anti-tumor activity of icotinib in patients with advanced cancers. II. To characterize the effect, if any, of icotinib on corrected QT interval using Bazett's formula (QTcB). TERTIARY OBJECTIVES: I. To evaluate single nucleotide polymorphisms in genes encoding for icotinib's target (epidermal growth factor receptor [EGFR]), putative transport protein (ATP-binding cassette, sub-family G [WHITE], member 1 [ABCG1]) and major metabolizing enzyme (cytochrome P450 3A4 [CYP3A4]) as well as other genes that may be found to be important in icotinib activity, and correlate these single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) with clinical activity and toxicity. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study. Patients receive icotinib hydrochloride orally (PO) twice daily (BID) on days 1-28. Courses repeat every 4 weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 30 days.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of =&lt; 2 Histologically or cytologically confirmed locally advanced, inoperable or metastatic solid tumor Have received at least one standard therapy for metastatic disease or have a disease in which no standard therapies exist Platelet count &gt;= 100 x 10^9/L Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1.5 x 10^9/L Hemoglobin (Hgb) &gt;= 9 gm/dL Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) Alanine transaminase (ALT) and aspartate transaminase (AST) =&lt; 3 x ULN (=&lt; 5 x ULN if liver metastasis is present) Creatinine clearance &gt;= 40 mL/min; use the Cockroft and Gault formula QTcB is &lt; 480 msec International normalized ratio (INR) =&lt; 1.5 Activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN if not on anticoagulants; patients who are receiving therapeutic anticoagulation with heparin are allowed to participate provided that no prior evidence of underlying abnormality exists in these parameters; patients on warfarin should have stable doses with INR between 23 in the 2 months prior to study registration Have measurable disease per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1 criteria present Demonstrate the ability to swallow and retain oral medication Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test performed within 7 days prior to the start of study drug Male and female subjects of childbearing potential must agree to use doublebarrier contraceptive measures, oral contraception, or avoidance of intercourse during the study and for 90 days after last investigational drug dose received Subject or legal representative must understand the investigational nature of this study and sign an Independent Ethics Committee/Institutional Review Board approved written informed consent form prior to receiving any study related procedure Written informed consent granted prior to initiation of any studyspecific screening procedures, given with the understanding that the patient has the right to withdraw from the study at any time, without prejudice Previous anticancer chemotherapy, immunotherapy or investigational agents =&lt; 4 weeks prior to the first day of study defined treatment; palliative radiation =&lt; 2 weeks; patients who receive gamma knife radiosurgery for brain metastases are eligible if procedure was performed &gt;= 7 days before treatment is started; ongoing hormonal therapies (luteinizing hormonereleasing hormone [LHRH] antagonists, megestrol, octreotide, calcitonin, etc.) are allowed History of cardiac disease: congestive heart failure defined as class II to class IV per New York Heart Association (NYHA) classification; active coronary artery disease (CAD); previously diagnosed bradycardia or other cardiac arrhythmia defined as &gt;= grade 2 according to National Cancer Institute (NCI)Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) (version 4.0), or uncontrolled hypertension; myocardial infarction occurred within 6 months prior to study entry (myocardial infarction occurred &gt; 6 months prior to study entry is permitted) Active clinically serious infections defined as &gt;= grade 2 according to NCI CTCAE version 4.0 Substance abuse, medical, psychological or social conditions that may, in the opinion of the investigator, interfere with the patient's participation in the study or evaluation of the study results Any condition that is unstable or which could jeopardize the safety of the patient and his/her protocol compliance Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection Pregnancy or breastfeeding Significant gastrointestinal disorder, in the opinion of the investigator, could interfere with the absorption of icotinib (e.g., significant, uncontrolled inflammatory bowel disease, history of abdominal fistula or gastrointestinal [GI] perforation within 6 months, extensive small bowel resection and requirement for tube feeding or parenteral hydration/nutrition) Concomitant use of strong inhibitors or inducers of cytochrome P450 2C19 (CYP2C19) and CYP3A4 should be avoided Untreated, symptomatic or unstable brain metastases Major surgery &lt; 4 weeks or minor surgery (e.g., talc pleurodesis, excisional biopsy, etc) &lt; 2 weeks prior to the first day of study defined treatment Unwilling or unable to follow protocol requirements Any condition which in the investigator's opinion deems the subject an unsuitable candidate to receive study drug</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>