<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01059955</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an initial clinical trial evaluating whether different doses of iontophoresis for delivery of dexamethasone phosphate can be tolerated by eyes of patients with non-infections, non-necrotizing scleritis. A secondary goal is to get preliminary information about whether the treatment is likely to be an effective treatment for scleritis. If the results are favorable, further trials evaluating the treatment may be pursued. Funding sources: FDA OOPD, Eyegate Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Iontophoresis Delivery of Dexamethasone Phosphate for Non-infectious, Non-necrotizing Anterior Scleritis, Phase 1 Dose-varying Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Scleritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female age at least 18 years 2. A diagnosis of active noninfectious, nonnecrotizing anterior scleritis (nodular or diffuse is acceptable) 3. Not planning to undergo elective ocular surgery during the study 4. Provide written informed consent 5. Be able and willing to follow instructions, return for all study visits, and willing to comply with all studyrelated instructions 6. If female and of childbearing potential; submit a urine sample and have a negative pregnancy test at Visit 1; agree to use an acceptable method of contraception during the study. A woman is considered of childbearing potential unless she is surgically sterile (hysterectomy or tubal ligation) or is postmenopausal (has not had a menstrual cycle for &gt;2 years or has laboratory evidence of a postmenopausal state). Acceptable methods of contraception include: spermicide with barrier, hormonal contraception, IUD, or surgical sterilization of partner. Complete abstinence throughout the study period also is acceptable. 1. Contraindications to the use of the test articles 2. Known allergy or sensitivity to any medication used in this study, including the study medication or its components (e.g., corticosteroids) 3. For patients not taking systemic corticosteroids or immunosuppressants, any condition constituting conferring a likelihood that systemic corticosteroids or immunosuppressants would need to be started during the 56day study period 4. For patients already taking systemic corticosteroids and/or immunosuppressants, any condition conferring a likelihood that systemic corticosteroid or immunosuppressant dosage would need to be changed during the 56day study period 5. Intraocular pressure high enough that intraocular pressurelowering medications are likely to be needed (≥25 mmHg or IOP&gt;target pressure for patients with glaucoma); and/or more than two ocular antihypertensive medications (prior IOPlowering surgery is acceptable; combinations of two agents such as Cosopt or Combigan are considered two medications) 6. Glaucoma sufficiently advanced that an intraocular pressure spike would potentially put the patient at substantial risk of vision loss, per the clinicianinvestigator's judgment. 7. Cancer 8. Subject is planning to undergo elective surgery during the study period 9. Any active ocular infections (bacterial, viral, or fungal), active ocular inflammation other than scleritis (i.e., follicular conjunctivitis, iritis), or preauricular lymphadenopathy 10. History or diagnosis of ocular herpes or corneal lesion of suspected herpetic origin 11. Severe eyelid or ocular surface lesions impeding application of the iontophoresis applicator 12. Severe / serious ocular pathology or medical condition which may preclude study completion 13. Any condition conferring a likelihood that topical ophthalmic medications in use at baseline would need to be changed during the 56day study period. 14. History of StevensJohnson Syndrome or mucous membrane pemphigoid 15. Unwilling to discontinue use of contact lenses for the duration of the study 16. Any open wounds / skin disease on the forehead where the iontophoresis return electrode will be applied 17. Pacemakers and/or any other electrical sensitive support system 18. Any significant illness or condition that could, in the investigator's or subinvestigator's opinion, be expected to interfere with the study parameters or study conduct; or put the subject at significant risk 19. Be currently pregnant, nursing, or planning a pregnancy; or woman who has a positive pregnancy test 20. Participation in an investigational drug or device study within 30 days of entering the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>scleritis</keyword>
	<keyword>anterior scleritis</keyword>
	<keyword>nodular anterior scleritis</keyword>
	<keyword>diffuse anterior scleritis</keyword>
</DOC>