<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00718965</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present study is aiming at assessing the efficacy and safety of AVE5530 (25mg and 50mg) in a double-blind comparison with placebo in the management of patients with primary hypercholesterolemia. The main objective is to evaluate the effects of AVE5530 on LDL-C level reduction as adjunct to a controlled diet. The effects of AVE5530 on other lipid parameters will be assessed as secondary objectives.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Efficacy and Safety of AVE5530 in Patients With Primary Hypercholesterolemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will include a 2-week pre-randomization placebo lead-in phase and a double-blind treatment period of at least 12 months and can be variably extended up to approximately 18 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypercholesterolemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults with high cholesterol levels either not receiving or willing and able to discontinue ongoing lipidlowering therapy LDLC levels &gt; 250 mg/dL (6.48 mmol/L) Triglycerides levels &gt; 350mg/dL (3.95 mmol/L) Conditions / situations such as: presence of any clinically significant uncontrolled endocrine disease known to influence lipids levels Active liver disease High estimated risk of Coronary Heart Disease Recent history of congestive heart failure , of unstable angina pectoris, myocardial infarction, coronary bypass surgery or angioplasty, or Unstable or severe peripheral artery disease Positive test for Hepatitis B surface antigen and/or Hepatitis C antibody or Known to be Human Immunodeficient Virus (HIV) positive Pregnant or breastfeeding women, Women of childbearing potential not protected by effective contraceptive method of birth control (including oral contraceptives) and/or who are unwilling or unable to be tested for pregnancy prior to exposure to the Investigational Product. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Primary hypercholesterolemia</keyword>
</DOC>