<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT01656733</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial determine nicotine inhaler combination counsel help pregnant woman quit smoking , whether safe compare placebo ( inactive inhaler ) .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nicotine Replacement Smoking Cessation During Pregnancy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This project examine safety efficacy nicotine inhaler aid smoking cessation pregnancy . The specific aim : ( 1 ) To examine efficacy nicotine inhaler compare match placebo smoke cessation pregnancy ; ( 2 ) To compare nicotine inhaler placebo overall nicotine exposure ( i.e. , serum cotinine concentration ) , birth outcome ( i.e. , birth weight gestational age ) ; ( 3 ) To identify factor determine woman benefit use nicotine inhaler smoking cessation pregnancy ; ( 4 ) To explore mechanism nicotine inhaler increase birth weight gestational age . Subjects recruit two prenatal clinic serve primarily low-income , minority population . Pregnant smoker ( n=270 ) smoke least 5 cigarettes/ day receive nurse-delivered behavioral counseling randomize receive 6-week course treatment either nicotine inhaler placebo , follow 6-week taper . Birth outcome obtain participant</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tobacco Use Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nicotine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>smoke least 5 cigarette per day precede 7 day previous attempt quit smoking pregnancy self report 1326 week gestation least 16 year age able speak English Spanish intent carry pregnancy term stable residence current drug alcohol abuse dependence ( methadone maintenance ) twin multiple gestation unstable psychiatric disorder unstable medical problem ( e.g. , preeclampsia , threaten abortion , hyperemesis gravidarum ) know congenital abnormality</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Smoking Cessation</keyword>
	<keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>Nicotrol Inhaler</keyword>
	<keyword>Placebo Inhaler</keyword>
	<keyword>Nicotine Inhaler</keyword>
</DOC>