<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02445937</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a comparative, effectiveness trial with the overarching goal of this research project to ensure patient-centered decisions about the use of intensive treatments for patients with advanced critical illness. In a prior project, the investigators developed the PARTNER program (PAiring Re-engineered ICU Teams with Nurse-driven Education and OutReach), a 4-facet, team-based intervention that re-engineers how surrogates are supported in ICUs, including: 1) changing care "defaults" to ensure clinician-family meetings within 48 hours of enrollment and frequently thereafter; 2) protocolized, nurse-administered coaching and emotional support of surrogates before and during clinician-family meetings, 3) increased use of palliative care services for patients with a poor prognosis; and 4) structured communication at care transitions about patient's health care preferences and goals. The investigators propose to begin deployment of the PARTNERII program in the spring of 2015 enrolling 690 patients and 690 surrogate decision makers in 5 ICUs using a stepped wedge design. The investigators expect to achieve the following project goals: 1. To increase the patient-centeredness of end-of-life decisions, and to increase the quality of clinician-family communication. 2. To decrease the psychological burden on family members acting as surrogates. 3. Lower costs: To reduce total health care costs by increasing the use of palliative care and hospice services and decreasing unwanted readmissions near the end of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PARTNER II: Improving Patient and Family Centered Care in Advanced Critical Illness</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>18 years of age or older Surrogate decision maker for ICU patient in one of 5 UPMC ICU's NonEnglish Speaking Surrogate's loved one is for organ transplantation Not physically able to participate in family meeting</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>decision making for incapacitated patients</keyword>
	<keyword>intensive care</keyword>
	<keyword>surrogate decision making</keyword>
	<keyword>patient centered care</keyword>
	<keyword>palliative care</keyword>
</DOC>