<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01802684</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluation of feasibility of adding aflibercept to an oxaliplatin-based regimen rather than a continuous administration of chemotherapy until progression, in order to decrease the risk of severe toxicities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>OPTIMOX-aflibercept as First-line Therapy in Patients With Unresectable Metastatic Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The addition of aflibercept to the standard FOLFIRI regimen as second-line therapy was evaluated in a large phase III study (EFC10262-VELOUR). This new combination significantly improved both PFS (4.7 to 6.9 months, HR=0.76; P=.00007) and OS (12.1 to 13.5 months, HR=0.82; P=.0032). In the evaluable population (86.5%), the tumor response rate was also improved when adding aflibercept (ORR=19.8% [16.4-23.2]) to the FOLFIRI regimen (ORR=11.1% [8.5-13.8]). This trial will evaluate the feasibility of adding aflibercept to an oxaliplatin-based regimen as a first-line therapy , using the OPTIMOX strategy rather than a continuous administration of chemotherapy until progression, in order to decrease the risk of severe toxicities.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Signed and dated informed consent, and willing and able to comply with protocol requirements, 2. Histologically proven adenocarcinoma of the colon and/or rectum, 3. Metastatic disease confirmed, 4. No prior therapy for metastatic disease (in case of previous adjuvant therapy, interval from end of chemotherapy to relapse must be &gt;6 months for fluoropyrimidine alone or &gt;12 months for oxaliplatinbased, bevacizumabbased, cetuximabbased therapy, 5. Duly documented inoperable metastatic disease, ie not suitable for complete carcinological surgical resection, 6. At least one measurable or evaluable lesion as assessed by CTscan or MRI (Magnetic Resonance Imaging) according to RECIST v1.1, 7. Age ≥18 years, 8. ECOG Performance status (PS) 02, 9. Hematological status: neutrophils (ANC) ≥1.5x109/L; platelets ≥100x109/L; haemoglobin ≥9g/dL, 10. Adequate renal function: serum creatinine level &lt;150µM, 11. Adequate liver function: serum bilirubin ≤3 x upper normal limit (ULN), alkaline phosphatase &lt;5xULN, 12. Proteinuria &lt;2+ (dipstick urinalysis) or ≤1g/24hour, 13. Baseline evaluations: clinical and blood evaluations performed no more than 2 weeks (14 days) prior to confirmation of eligibility, tumor assessment (chest X ray, CTscan or MRI, evaluation of nonmeasurable lesions) no more than 3 weeks (21 days) prior to confirmation of eligibility, 14. For female patients of childbearing potential, negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 1 week (7 days) prior of starting study treatment, 15. Female patients of childbearing potential must commit to using reliable and effective methods of contraception during the trial and until at least six months after the end of study treatment. Females are neither pregnant nor in breastfeeding. Male patients with a partner of childbearing potential must agree to use effective contraception in addition to the contraceptive method used by their partner during the trial and until at least six months after the end of study treatment. 16. Registration in a national health care system (CMU included for France). 1. History or evidence upon physical examination of CNS metastasis unless adequately treated (e.g. non irradiated CNS metastasis, seizure not controlled with standard medical therapy), 2. Exclusive bone metastasis, 3. Uncontrolled hypercalcemia, 4. Preexisting permanent neuropathy (NCI grade ≥2), 5. Uncontrolled hypertension (defined as systolic blood pressure &gt;150 mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure &gt;100 mmHg despite optimal medical therapy), or history of hypertensive crisis, or hypertensive encephalopathy, 6. Concomitant unplanned antitumor therapy (e.g. chemotherapy, molecular targeted therapy, immunotherapy/ radioimmunotherapy), 7. Treatment with any other investigational medicinal product within 28 days prior to study entry, 8. Other serious and uncontrolled nonmalignant disease, 9. Other concomitant or previous malignancy, except: i/ adequately treated insitu carcinoma of the uterine cervix, ii/ basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, iii/ cancer in complete remission for &gt;5 years, 10. Any other serious and uncontrolled nonmalignant disease, major surgery or traumatic injury within the last 28 days 11. Patients with known allergy to any excipient to study drugs, 12. History of myocardial infarction and/or stroke within 6 months prior to study entry, 13. Bowel obstruction.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>unresectable</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic</keyword>
	<keyword>colorectal</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>OPTIMOX</keyword>
	<keyword>aflibercept</keyword>
</DOC>