<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01802541</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Diacylglycerol oil has been shown to lower postprandial and fasting serum triacylglycerol levels and reduce body fat. The investigators hypothesize that replacing dietary fat with diacylglycerol oil reduces excess body fat in type 2 diabetic patients and that diacylglycerol oil has a beneficial effect on cardiovascular risk factors in Chinese type 2 diabetic patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Diacylglycerol Oil on Risk Factors of Type 2 Diabetes and Complicating Disease, and Mechanism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Type 2 diabetic patients, blood sugar levels were stabilized between 7.0－10.0 mmol/L 2. Male, aged 40 70 years old, Female, aged postmenopausal 70 years old. 3. Overweight/obese patients (BMI 25 40 kg/m2) 4. Currently under diet therapy for diabetes mellitus 5. Understands the procedures and willing to participate in the study 1. Patients who unwilling to give informed consent 2. Type 1 diabetic patients 3. Familial hyperlipemia patients or blood triacylglycerol concentration &gt; 400 mg/dl 4. Patients with a history of cardiovascular disease and/or arteriosclerotic disease 5. Patients with a history of cerebrovascular disease 6. Patients with serious hepatic disease and/or renal disease 7. Patients with malignancy 8. Participation in another clinical study within 30 days prior to screening period. 9. Has a condition the doctor in charge believes would interfere with evaluation of the subject, or may put subject at undue risk</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>diacylglycerol oil</keyword>
	<keyword>insulin sensitivity</keyword>
	<keyword>type 2 diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiovascular disease</keyword>
	<keyword>risk factors</keyword>
</DOC>