<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01802879</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study allows continued use of single agent panobinostat in patients who are on single agent panobinostat treatment in a Novartis-sponsored study which has met its endpoint and are benefiting from the treatment as judged by the investigator.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Allow Access to Single Agent Panobinostat for Patients Who Are on s.a. Panobinostat Treatment in a Novartis-sponsored Study and Are Benefiting From the Treatment as Judged by the Investigator</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multi-center open label study to provide continued use of single agent oral panobinostat to patients currently treated in a Novartis-sponsored study (parent study) which has met its endpoint and are benefiting from continuation of the treatment with single-agent panobinostat as judged by the investigator. Patients from multiple parent studies will be transferred over to this protocol and will be continuing to receive single agent panobinostat at the last assigned dose and regimen of the parent protocol. There will be no screening period, and patients will have to visit the study center at least on a quarterly basis. During these visits limited information on study treatment and occurrence of SAEs will be collected for the clinical database. SAEs will be only reported to the Novartis safety database.Other assessments and possibly more frequent visits will occur as per standard of care at the site. Patients will continue treatment until they are no longer benefiting from panobinostat treatment develop unacceptable toxicities, withdraw consent, are non-compliant to the protocol, the investigator feels it is no longer in the best interest to continue, the patient dies, or for other administrative reasons. An end of treatment visit and a safety follow-up for 30 days after the last dose will be performed. The study is expected to remain open for 5 years or until such time that enrolled patients no longer need treatment with panobinostat, whichever comes earlier.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hematologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Panobinostat</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patient is currently enrolled in Novartis sponsored study, which has met its endpoint and is receiving single agent oral panobinostat patient is currently benefiting from treatment with single agent oral panobinostat as determined by the guidelines of the parent protocol and according to the investigator's clinical judgment. patient has demonstated compliance patient has given written informed consent. patient has been permanently discontinued from single agent oral panobinostat study treatment in the parent study patient has participated in a Novartis sponsored combincation trial where panobinostat was dispensed in combination with another study medication and is still receiving combination therapy patient is pregnant or nursing at the time of entry women of childbearing potential and male patients with sexual partners of childbearing potential unwilling to use highly effective methods of contraception during dosing and for a specified duration after stopping study treatment Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hematologic Neoplasms, LBH589,</keyword>
	<keyword>Panobinostat,</keyword>
</DOC>