<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02331810</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: Assess in systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) patients the effect of SAR113244 on B-cell subsets compared to placebo. Secondary Objectives: Assess in male and female lupus patients after SC single dose of SAR113244 the tolerability and safety of SAR113244. Assess in male and female lupus patients: - The pharmacokinetics of SAR113244. - The pharmacodynamics of SAR113244 for the following disease parameters: - Safety of Estrogens in Lupus Erythematosus National Assessment Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Disease Activity Index (SELENA-SLEDAI) score, British Isles Lupus Assessment Group (BILAG) score (if applicable), BILAG-Based Composite Lupus Assessment (BICLA) (if applicable), systemic lupus erythematosus responder index (if applicable), Lupus-quality of life and Functional Assessment of Chronic Illness Therapy-Fatigue, anti-double stranded deoxyribonucleic acid antibody and anti-nuclear antibody levels and plasma complement levels (C3, C4), erythrocyte sedimentation rate and C-reactive protein. - Peripheral blood B and T cell subsets.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacodynamics Assessment Study After Single Subcutaneous Dose Of SAR113244 Versus Placebo In Lupus Male And Female Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The total duration of screening to end of study per subject is 16 weeks with post-study observation on Day 198 for anti-drug antibody assessment (for patients with positive anti-drug antibody at end of study only).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Male or female patients, between 18 and 75 years of age, inclusive. Clinical diagnosis of SLE by American College of Rheumatology (ACR) criteria. Autoantibodypositive. On active and stable SLE disease. B cell subsets expressed as percentage of total B cells above normal. Exclusion criteria: Pregnant and nursing. Have received treatment with investigational drugs in the 4 months prior to the screening or 5 halflives of the drug, which ever is longer. Have received intravenous or oral cyclophosphamide within 180 days of Day 0. Severe active lupus nephritis or chronic renal insufficiency. Active or chronic, severe neuropsychiatric lupus. Acute, recent (within 4 weeks of screening), chronic or frequently recurring infection(s), except minor infection. Have current drug or alcohol abuse or dependence. Have a historically positive test or test positive at screening for HIV, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>