<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00714571</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Memory deficits are common after traumatic brain injuries (TBI) and are characteristic of various forms of dementia, such as Alzheimer's disease and its common precursor mild cognitive impairment (MCI). This project intends to assess the efficacy of cognitive rehabilitation in these patient populations. We will also use neuroimaging (functional magnetic resonance imaging - fMRI) to assess changes in brain activity that occur following cognitive rehabilitation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Behavioral and Neuroimaging Changes After Cognitive Rehab in Traumatic Brain Injuries (TBI) and Mild Cognitive Impairment (MCI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<criteria>General inclusion criteria (all patients): A minimum of 12 years of education or attainment of a Graduation Equivalency Diploma; All medications stable for approximately 3 months; No history of severe mental illness; No current untreated alcohol or substance abuse/dependence; English as native and preferred language; MRIcompatible if taking part in fMRI studies 7) Able to give informed consent. MCI Diagnosis of amnestic MCI based on criteria set forth by Petersen (2004). Additionally, other potential causes of cognitive deficit ruled out by the referring physician; 55 years of age or older. TBI Inclusion criteria: History of a mild to moderate TBI; No history of other neurological disease or injury; A minimum of 6 months and maximum of 5 years postonset of TBI; 18 45 years old. History of neurological disease or injury (other than TBI) History of severe mental illness Current untreated alcohol or substance abuse Other conditions may exclude; please discuss with contact</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>88 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cognitive rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>explicit memory training</keyword>
	<keyword>mild cognitive impairment</keyword>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's disease</keyword>
	<keyword>traumatic brain injury</keyword>
	<keyword>veterans</keyword>
</DOC>