<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01958177</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cerebellar ataxia is a complex motor disturbance, which, can occur as a result of many diseases and presents with symptoms of an inability to coordinate balance, gait, extremity and eye movements. Lesions to the cerebellum can cause dyssynergia, dysmetria, dysdiadochokinesia, dysarthria and ataxia of stance and gait. Deficits are observed with movements on the same side of the body as the lesion (ipsilaterally).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy BMMNC in Cerebellar Ataxia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ataxia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebellar Ataxia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age limit: 18 65 Diagnosed as Cerebellar ataxia Willingness to undergo Bone marrow transplantation BMMNC. To give an informed consent as well as sign the required Informed Consent Form (ICF) for the study. willingness to regularly visit the hospital / clinic for follow up during the follow up period / on prior agreed time points as per the protocol. Patients with preexisting or current systemic disease such as lung , liver (exception: history of uncomplicated hepatitis A) gastrointestinal , cardiac, immunodeficiency (including HIV) or any other condition determined by history or laboratory investigation that could cause a neurological defect (including syphilis, clinically relevant polyneuropathy) etc. Women who are pregnant or lactating Chronic kidney disease due to autoimmune aetiology, connective tissue disease, amyloidosis and storage disorders. Suffering from Severe comorbidities like cardiac insufficiency, congestive cardiac failure, malignancy, infection, sepsis and bed sores. Positive test results for HIV and AIDS complex ,HCV , HbsAg and Syphilis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>stem cell</keyword>
	<keyword>cerebellar ataxia</keyword>
	<keyword>BMMNC</keyword>
</DOC>