<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01480284</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of GSK548470 administered once daily at a dose level of 300 mg to Japanese patients with compensated chronic hepatitis B untreated with any nucleic acid analogue. In efficacy, the non-inferiority of GSK548470 to ETV will be verified using the antiviral effect as the index.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 3 Study of GSK548470 in Patients With Compensated Chronic Hepatitis B Untreated With Nucleic Acid Analogue</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a multicenter, randomized, active comparator-controlled, double-blind, parallel-group comparison study in Japanese patients with compensated chronic hepatitis B untreated with any nucleic acid analogue and its subsequent open-label study. Efficacy and safety will be compared between once-daily dosing of GSK548470 300 mg and once-daily dosing of ETV 0.5 mg, and subsequently the efficacy and safety of GSK548470 administered long term will be investigated. A total of 165 subjects will be assigned to the GSK548470 group or the ETV group at a ratio of 2:1. The subjects will be assigned by stratified randomization in terms of HBe antigen and serum HBV-DNA level. The primary purpose is to verify the non-inferiority of GSK548470 to ETV using as an index the change amount of HBV-DNA level at Week 24 from the baseline level. The secondary purpose is to investigate the efficacy and safety of GSK548470 300 mg administered once daily for a long term.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The ability to understand and sign a written informed consent form 16 to 69 years of age at the time of informed consent Females of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test and agree to avoidance of pregnancy Subject must show QTc &lt; 450 millisecond (msec) or &lt; 480 msec with Bundle Branch Block Chronic HBV infection, defined as positive serum HBsAg for at least 6 month, or negative serum IgMHBc antibody HBeAg positive; HBVDNA &gt;= 6 log10 copies/mL, HBeAg negative; HBVDNA &gt;= 5 log10 copies/mL Serum ALT &gt;= 31 U/L and &lt;= 10 × ULN Creatinine clearance &gt;= 70 mL/min Haemoglobin &gt;= 8 g/dL WBC &gt;= 1,000 /mm3 Nucleic acid analogue naïve, i.e., no prior therapy for over 6 months in the past No mutation that shows resistance in LAM, ETV and/or TDF at screening Decompensated liver disease Coinfection with HIV or HCV Autoimmune hepatitis rather than chronic hepatitis B Subject with serious complication Received or have a plan for solid organ or bone marrow transplantation Has proximal tubulopathy History of hypersensitivity to nucleoside and/or nucleotide analogues Evidence of hepatocellular carcinoma by diagnostic imaging at screening and/or serum αfetoprotein &gt; 50 ng/mL at screening History of HCC Received any nucleoside, nucleotide, interferon or HB vaccine therapy within 24 weeks prior to initiation Received overdose NSAIDs, excluding temporary or topical use, within 7 days prior to initiation Received drugs for injection containing glycyrrhizin as the main component within 4 weeks prior to initiation Received drugs causing renal impairment, competitors of renal excretion, immunosuppressants, chemotherapeutics and/or corticosteroids within 8 weeks prior to initiation Participation in another clinical study within 6 months of study entry or planned participation in another clinical study after entry to this study Woman who is pregnant, lactating, possibly pregnant or planning a pregnancy during the study period Psychiatry disorder or cognitive disorder that may affect the subject ability to give informed consent or to follow specified study procedures History of alcohol or drug abuse Any condition or situation that may interfere with the subject's participation in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>69 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Hepatitis B</keyword>
</DOC>