<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01480869</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare normalization of vitamin D serum level after 6 months of vitamin D supplementation adjusted to baseline vitamin D serum level vs.conventional vitamin D supplementation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Vitamin D Supplementation Tailored to Vitamin D Deficiency in Breast Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Breast adenocarcinoma treated by neoadjuvant or adjuvant chemotherapy within 12 months prior to study enrollment WHO performance status 01 Age ≥18 years old Affiliation to a social security regime or beneficiary of equivalent social protection Written informed consent provided before any study specific procedures Complementary inclusion criterion for randomization Proved vitamin D deficiency as defined by serum vitamin D level lower than 30 ng/ml (75 nmol/L). Metastatic disease History or presence of any other malignancy (except curatively treated nonmelanoma skin cancer or in situ cervix carcinoma) …………. traités dans les 5 ans précédents. Contraindication to calcium or cholecalciferol Known severe hypersensitivity to vitamin D or to calcium supplementation or to one of the excipients. Disease and/or medical conditions accompanied by hypercalcaemia and/or hypercalciuria Calcium lithiasis and tissue calcification Hypervitaminosis D Presence of significant comorbidities: i) Uncontrolled endocrine disease ii) Known disorders of calcium phophorus laboratory testing iii) Proved osteopenia or osteoporosis requiring vitamin D and calcium supplements Concomitant treatment with other experimental products or another vitamin D calcium treatment Pregnancy, breastfeeding or of reproductive potential not using an effective contraceptive method Legal inability or restricted legal ability. Medical or psychological conditions not allowing proper study completion or informed consent signature</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitamin D supplementation</keyword>
	<keyword>in neoadjuvant</keyword>
	<keyword>adjuvant setting</keyword>
</DOC>