<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01480050</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Mibefradil dihydrochloride may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as temozolomide, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. PURPOSE: This phase I trial is studying the best dose of mibefradil dihydrochloride when given together with temozolomide in treating patients with glioma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mibefradil Dihydrochloride and Temozolomide in Treating Patients With Recurrent Glioma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the maximum-tolerated dose (MTD) of mibefradil dihydrochloride administered prior to five days of temozolomide (TMZ) at 150-200 mg/m² in subjects with progressive or recurrent high-grade glioma. Secondary - Assess the safety of mibefradil dihydrochloride administered prior to five days of TMZ at 150-200 mg/m² when the mibefradil dihydrochloride dose is escalated from a starting dose of 100 mg/day, given four times a day for seven consecutive days. - Determine the pharmacokinetic profile of mibefradil. - Determine the steady state levels of mibefradil dihydrochloride on the last day of dosing. - Assess the severity and frequency of adverse events for tested mibefradil dihydrochloride dose levels including cumulative toxicity and/or tolerance to adverse effects. - Estimate the number and type of radiographic responses to treatment with mibefradil dihydrochloride and temozolomide. - Assess the potential effect of mibefradil dihydrochloride on tumor metabolism as determined by Fluorothymidine Positron Emission Tomography (FLT PET) scans with the radiotracer [18F]-3'-fluoro-3'-deoxy-L-thymidine (dose-expansion cohort only). OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study of mibefradil dihydrochloride followed by a dose-expansion study. Patients receive mibefradil dihydrochloride orally (PO) 4 times a day on days 1-7 (days 1-8 on first course) and temozolomide PO on days 8-12 (days 9-13 on first course). Treatment repeats every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Blood samples are collected during the first course for pharmacokinetic studies. Patients in the dose-expansion cohort undergo [18F]-3'-fluoro-3'-deoxy-L-thymidine (FLT)-positron emission tomography (PET) at baseline and on day 7 of the first course of therapy. After completion of study therapy, patients are followed up every 2 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mibefradil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dideoxynucleosides</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alovudine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically proven highgrade glioma (glioblastoma, anaplastic astrocytoma, anaplastic oligodendroglioma, mixed anaplastic oligoastrocytoma, anaplastic ependymoma) that is progressive or recurrent following standard upfront radiation therapy + temozolomide Measurable contrastenhancing progressive or recurrent highgrade glioma (single or multiple lesions) by MRI imaging within 30 days of starting treatment Must have a plan for retreatment with temozolomide at 150200 mg/m² for 5 days per cycle; each cycle = 28 days Must have previously tolerated at least one cycle of adjuvant temozolomide therapy in the prior treatment of the glioma PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Karnofsky performance status ≥ 60% Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/µL Platelets ≥ 100,000/µL Total bilirubin &lt; or equal to 3 times institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) AST(SGOT)/ALT(SGPT) &lt; or equal to 3 times ULN Creatinine normal OR creatinine clearance ≥ 50 mL/min Serum potassium, magnesium, and calcium levels normal (may be corrected to those levels by supplementation during screening period) Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Women of childbearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception Able to tolerate MRIs CT scans cannot be substituted for MRIs in this study No concurrent malignancy except curatively treated basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix, breast, or bladder Subjects with prior malignancies must be diseasefree for ≥ five years MiniMental State Exam score of ≥ 15 Patients must identify a caregiver/support person who will agree to assist with the remote cardiac monitor and taking/recording blood pressure at home No serious concurrent infection or medical illness, which would jeopardize the ability of the subject to receive the treatment outlined in this protocol with reasonable safety No uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, hypertension, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements No history of known, active hepatitis No screening QTc interval ≥ 450 mSec for males or 470 mSec for females No PR interval &gt; 250 mSec No systolic blood pressure &lt; or equal 100 mm Hg at baseline No history (within six months) of myocardial infarction, unstable angina, uncontrolled hypertension, or congestive heart failure No highgrade (second degree or above) AV block or persistent sinus bradycardia of less than 50 BPM No known HIVpositivity PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics Recovered to CTCAE grade &lt; or equal 2 from toxicities related to prior therapy An interval of at least 3 months must have elapsed since the completion of the most recent course of radiation therapy, the last dose of temozolomide (TMZ), or placement of Gliadel wafers No prior cytotoxic therapies other than temozolomide and Gliadel wafers Prior antiVEGF therapies are allowed if more than four months have elapsed from the end of prior treatment 30 days must have elapsed since previous treatment of the brain tumor with any other agents Must be maintained on a stable or decreasing corticosteroid regimen (no increase for 7 days) prior to the start of treatment Patients may not be receiving any other investigational agents or chemotherapeutic agents other than temozolomide No antiarrhythmia medication other than betablockers or digoxin No requirement for a calcium channel blocker for blood pressure control that cannot be switched to an antihypertensive with an alternative mechanism of action Permitted antihypertensive medications include: chlorothiazide, hydrochlorothiazide, atenolol, nadolol, enalapril, lisinopril, eprosartan, and irbesartan Patients cannot receive any statin while on trial except pravastatin No treatment with an H2 blocker, other than famotidine If the patient requires a proton pump inhibitor (PPI), then esomeprazole, pantoprazole, or rabeprazole may be given No concurrent enzymeinducing antiepileptic drugs (EIAEDs) Patients previously treated with EIAEDs may be enrolled if they have been off the EIAED for 10 days or more prior to the first dose of mibefradil Patients taking an anticoagulant must use warfarin or a low molecular weight heparin Unfractionated heparin is not permitted No drugs that are substrates of CYP3A4, CYP2D6, and CYP1A2 except for the ones that are explicitly permitted No drugs that have potential to interfere with metabolism or excretion of mibefradil Patients who are taking and cannot discontinue overthecounter (OTC) medications and nutritional supplements, including herbal or "Chinese" medications, are not eligible, except for the following: OTC medications that are allowed at labeled doses during dosing with mibefradil are acetaminophen, aspirin, diphenhydramine, calcium carbonate antacids, branded multiple vitamin supplements and pseudoephedrine Topical preparations and decongestant nasal sprays are allowed</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult giant cell glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic ependymoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic oligodendroglioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult mixed glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult brain tumor</keyword>
</DOC>