<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00592293</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this study is to assess the short term and the long term side effects of proton beam radiation for pediatric bone and non-rhabdomyosarcoma soft tissue sarcomas.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Proton Radiation for the Treatment of Pediatric Bone and Non-Rhabdomyosarcoma Soft Tissue Sarcomas</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>- Participants will receive radiation treatments once per day, 5 days a week for a total of 4 to 6 weeks, depending on how much total dose the tumor requires. The radiation doctor will see the participant once each week to monitor and record any side effects they may have from radiation treatment. - A special device will be made for each participant to help them hold still during the treatment. This may either be a mask or foam cradle, depending on the area to be treated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Biopsy proven NRSTS or bone sarcoma Less than or equal to 30 years of age Patients must have been treated with a standardly accepted chemotherapy regimen if chemotherapy is indicated Patients must be willing to receive followup care for a minimum of five years after treatment at MGH and annual visits unless it is too difficult to return to MGH for followup care. In that event, the patient or guardian must be willing to have their outside medical information released in order to track the results of treatment They or their legal guardian must give their informed consent Timing of radiation may be according to concurrent protocol Comorbidities that would make the use of radiation too toxic to deliver safely, such as serious local injury of collagen vascular disease Patients who are pregnant Previous treatment with radiation therapy Concurrent adriamycin or gemcitabine chemotherapy is planned, unless on a concurrent protocol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>proton beam radiation</keyword>
</DOC>