<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00710567</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Specific Aims The aims of this trial are to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of the DuraHeart™ LVAS in patients with advanced heart failure who require LVAS support as a bridge to cardiac transplantation. Study Population The patient population for this trial consists of patients with end stage heart failure awaiting cardiac transplantation. Patients must be listed for transplant with UNOS with status 1A or 1B. All patients who meet the eligibility criteria may be included in the study regardless of gender, race or ethnicity. Study Design This is a multi-center, prospective, single arm study in which the lower one-sided confidence interval exceeds the performance goal. Enrollment is expected to occur within an 18-month time period at up to 40 centers. All patients will be followed for all endpoints for 6 months while on DuraHeart™ LVAS support, or until cardiac transplantation or death, whichever occurs first. For those patients who remain on support after 180 days, survival and device reliability data will continue to be collected on a regular basis. If patients are transplanted, survival at day 30 post cardiac transplantation will also be assessed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Safety and Effectiveness of the DuraHeart™ LVAS</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The following are general criteria; more specific conditions are included in the study protocol: 1. Approved for cardiac transplantation 2. Listed with UNOS on the Status 1 list 3. Patient for whom LVAS implantation is planned as a clinically indicated bridge to cardiac transplantation The following are general criteria; more specific conditions are included in the study protocol: 1. Contraindication to the administration of warfarin or antiplatelet agents 2. Primary coagulopathy or platelet disorder 3. Acute myocardial infarction within 48 hours prior to enrollment 4. Anticipated need for RVAD support or ECMO at the time of LVAS implantation 5. Prior cardiac transplantation, left ventricular reduction surgery, cardiomyoplasty, passive restraint device (i.e., CorCapTM Cardiac Support Device) or surgically implanted left ventricular assist device</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Heart Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>LVAS</keyword>
	<keyword>LVAD</keyword>
	<keyword>Rotary Pump</keyword>
</DOC>