<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00710463</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Hypothesis: Hospital based, comprehensive pulmonary rehabilitation of patients with COPD in GOLD stage IV can be optimized by application of nocturnal non invasive ventilation. This hypotheses shall be tested by an observational trial, comparing rehabilitation effects of a prospectively observed group receiving non invasive ventilation, compared wiht a historical control group of patients who did received the same treatment without non invasive ventilation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Role of Nocturnal Non-Invasive Ventilation in Pulmonary Rehabilitation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Non invasive ventilation is known to allow improvements if applied during endurance training, but this is technically difficult. Nocturnal application of non invasive ventilation is known to unload the ventilatory pump, reset the control of breathing, and improve sleep quality. The protocol also aimed to evaluate the acceptance of non invasive ventilation in patients undergoing a four week inpatient pulmonary rehabilitation programme.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed diagnosis of COPD in stages GOLD IV Receiving optimized medical treatment and long term oxygen treatment, if indicated Patient's consent to participate in this trial Previous treatment with NIPPV Unwillingness or intolerance to perform NIPPV Acute exacerbation of COPD at baseline or during pulmonary rehabilitation, Significant orthopaedic or neurologic problems that reduce mobility or cooperation with physical training Poor controlled coexisting psychiatric or unstable cardiac disease, Inability to perform a six minute walk test Extreme hypercapnia (pCO2 &gt; 74 mmHg)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
	<keyword>non invasive ventilation</keyword>
	<keyword>pulmonary rehabilitation</keyword>
</DOC>