<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02610127</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall objective is to enroll patients with acquired hemophilia A (AHA) who are prescribed and treated with Obizur, to assess safety, and to describe factors related to safety, utilization and effectiveness in a real-world setting.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Post-Marketing Non-Interventional Safety Evaluation of Obizur in the Treatment of Bleeding Episodes for Patients With Acquired Hemophilia A</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a multi-center, uncontrolled, open-label, non-interventional post-marketing safety surveillance study to describe the use of Obizur in patients with acquired hemophilia A (AHA), and secondarily, where data are available, to describe the hemostatic effectiveness and immunogenicity of Obizur. Patients should be enrolled at the earliest possible time point, but within ten days of initiating Obizur to ensure unbiased prospective observation. In addition, in an attempt to collect all safety and utilization data on patients treated with Obizur since Food and Drug Administration approval, Baxalta will conduct a retrospective chart review on persons treated with Obizur prior to the prospective study start date (Retrospective study participants may or may not also participate in the prospective portion of the study).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Factor VIII</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Participant is ≥18 years of age at the time of informed consent. 2. Participant has AHA, and is being treated/was treated with Obizur. 3. Participant is willing and able to provide informed consent, unless informed consent is not required 1. Participant has a known anaphylactic reaction to the active substance, to any of the excipients, or to hamster protein. 2. Participant has a concomitant bleeding disorder(s) other than acquired hemophilia A (AHA). 3. Participant has participated in another clinical study involving a medicinal product or device within 30 days prior to enrollment or is scheduled to participate in another clinical study involving a medicinal product or device during the course of the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>