<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02610803</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to estimate the clinical relevance of monitoring patients with acute ischemic stroke with 48 hours' inpatient cardiac telemetry in relation to evaluate the presence of brief runs of premature atrial complexes and new diagnosed atrial fibrillation. Furthermore to evaluate the prognostic significance of brief runs of premature atrial complexes in relation to develop atrial fibrillation, recurrent stroke/transient ischemic attack and death.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Paroxysmal Atrial Fibrillation in Patients With Acute Ischemic Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Stroke is the second leading cause of death worldwide and it is well known that atrial fibrillation(AF) is a major risk factor for ischemic stroke. Paroxysmal AF can be difficult to detect because many cases are asymptomatic. In recent years prolonged cardiac rhythm monitoring of patients with ischemic stroke has showed an underestimated prevalence of AF. However, no optimal monitoring strategy is implemented in the clinic yet. This is the reason why research currently is focused on finding predictive risk markers of AF. Cohort studies of healthy individuals and stroke patients have shown that excessive premature atrial complexes (PACs) and brief runs of PACs are an emerging risk marker in helping to identifying patients in risk of having or developing AF. Despite this brief runs of PACs less than 30 s are today in everyday clinical practice perceived to be of no clinical significance. The study population of ischemic stroke patients have all without known AF underwent ECG and 48 hours' inpatient cardiac telemetry as a clinical routine. In the medical record it is registered if patients had runs of PACs or new diagnosed AF. All patients are registered in the Danish Stroke Registry, and all the baseline data on patients will be obtained from the registry. The follow-up end August 2015 and information on AF, recurrent stroke and death will be obtained from medical records and the Funen Patient Administrative System, which is linked to the national Civil Registration System. The purpose of this study is to estimate the clinical relevance of monitoring patients with acute ischemic stroke with 48 hours' inpatient cardiac telemetry in relation to evaluate the presence of brief runs of PACs and new diagnosed AF. Furthermore to evaluate the prognostic significance of brief runs of PACs in relation to develop AF and the prognostic significance of brief runs of PACs and AF in relation to recurrent stroke and death.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Premature Complexes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>admitted with ischemic stroke from August 2008April 2011 Registered in the Danish Stroke Registry Hemorrhagic stroke No Danish civil registration no permanent address in Denmark during followup. patients with lack of telemetry data</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>ischemic stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>atrial fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>premature atrial complexes</keyword>
	<keyword>heart rhythm monitoring</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiac telemetry</keyword>
</DOC>