<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01304173</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an observational study involving a retrospective review of medical records of adult patients who have been treated with intravesical valrubicin for bladder carcinoma in situ (CIS) since October 2009.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Retrospective Chart Review of Valstar</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Initial treatment for bladder CIS is TURBT followed by intravesical immunotherapy with BCG. Valrubicin is approved by the FDA for the treatment of BCG-refractory bladder CIS in patients for whom immediate cystectomy would be associated with unacceptable morbidity or mortality. The recommended course of therapy is 6 doses of 800 mg each administered intravesically once a week. While the benefit risk profile of valrubicin has been established in several clinical trials, current data on effectiveness and tolerability when used in clinical practice are lacking. This protocol outlines a retrospective study to evaluate the effectiveness, safety and tolerability of intravesical valrubicin in the treatment of NMIBC in a clinical practice setting.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma in Situ</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age 18 years old or greater diagnosis of CIS (physician defined in the medical record) treated with at least one IVe dose of valrubicin since 10/2009 and completed prescribed therapy or no longer receiving therapy at time of study enrollment willing and able to provide informed consent (unless waiver of informed consent is applicable and in place at that clinical site per Chapter 45 CFR part 46 Subpart A 46.117 route of administration of valrubicin other than intravesical</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>BCG</keyword>
	<keyword>refractory</keyword>
	<keyword>NMIBC</keyword>
	<keyword>CIS</keyword>
	<keyword>non-muscle invasive</keyword>
</DOC>