<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01304108</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Preventing the formation of blood clots in the veins so they do not injure leg veins or travel to the lungs, also called venous thromboembolism prophylaxis (VTE-P) is an essential component of safe in-patient care, yet it is deployed sub-optimally in many hospitals, including The investigators own. Two prior VTE-P improvement projects were completed at Mayo Clinic hospitals, one in the Department of Medicine, and the other in selected divisions of the Department of Surgery. Both projects resulted in marked improvement in the percentage of patients receiving appropriate VTE-P. This project seeks to utilize the lessons learned from these two pilots along with known best practices for &amp;quot;spreading&amp;quot; to deploy methods that enhance VTE-P to the entire hospitalized population. The investigators seek appropriate VTE-P rates exceeding 95%.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Venous Thromboembolism Prophylaxis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Venous thromboembolism prophylaxis (VTE-P) is an essential component of safe in-patient care, yet it is deployed sub-optimally in many hospitals, including our own. Two prior VTE-P improvement projects were completed at Mayo Clinic hospitals, one in the Department of Medicine, and the other in selected divisions of the Department of Surgery. Both projects resulted in marked improvement in the percentage of patients receiving appropriate VTE-P. This project seeks to utilize the lessons learned from these two pilots along with known best practices for &amp;quot;spreading&amp;quot; to deploy methods that enhance VTE-P to the entire hospitalized population. The investigators seek appropriate VTE-P rates exceeding 95%. This began as a quality improvement project. The investigators have taken baseline measures of VTE-P rates in our hospitals, intervened with various electronic prompts to use appropriate VTE-P, and have and will re-measure VTE-P rates. The investigators intend to present and publish our methods and results so that lessons learned may be shared and applied elsewhere.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inpatients with age &gt; 17 years old Outpatients Inpatients with age less than or equal to 17 years old</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Venous Thromboembolism</keyword>
	<keyword>Delivery of Health Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality Improvement</keyword>
	<keyword>Evidence-Based Practice</keyword>
</DOC>