<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01304810</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to obtain two year follow up data for subjects that received six vaccinations of NicVAX in prior phase III studies. No treatment will be administered. Anti-nicotine antibody levels and safety data will be collected.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Follow-up Study to Assess Long-term Immunogenicity and Safety of NicVAX/Placebo as an Aid to Smoking Cessation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will follow subjects that participated in the NicVAX phase III studies for a second year. These predecessor studies, Nabi-4514 (NCT#00836199) and Nabi-4515 (NCT#01102114) evaluate the efficacy and safety of 6 vaccinations of NicVAX or placebo as an aid to smoking cessation. The two phase III studies are one year in duration, and subjects who complete these studies are eligible to enroll in Nabi-4522. As the phase III studies are ongoing, subject assignment to NicVAX or placebo will remain masked. No intervention will be administered in Nabi-4522. Subjects will be followed for immunogenicity (anti-nicotine antibody level)and for safety.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tobacco Use Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who agree and sign consent to participate in this followup study. Subjects randomized and completed month 12 of the Nabi4514 or Nabi4515 study. Subjects who have received a total of 6 injections in Nabi4514 or Nabi4515. Anticipated inability to follow the study protocol throughout the study period. Known history of any condition or factor judged by the investigator to preclude participation in the study or which might hinder compliance or failure to sign informed consent. Subjects who intend to receive, or who are receiving an Investigational New Drug/Device during the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>NicVAX</keyword>
	<keyword>Smoking cessation</keyword>
</DOC>