<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00295425</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Psoriasis is an immuno-mediated skin disorder, which affects about 2-3% of the population worldwide. For moderate-severe forms of psoriasis systemic immunosuppression is the treatment of choice. This clinical trial was initiated to compare the safety and effectiveness of mycophenolate mofetil and cyclosporine A for the treatment of psoriasis. Patients are randomized to receive either 2.5 mg/kg BW cyclosporine A or 1 g bid mycophenolate mofetil. If after six weeks no decrease in the PASI score occures cyclosporine A doses are increased to 5 mg/kg BW for additional six weeks. In the other arm mycophenolate mofetil is increased to 1 g tid for additional six weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CYA Versus MMF for Treatment of Moderate-Severe Psoriasis.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Not needed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>moderatetosevere psoriasis (PASI Score equal and greated 10) written informed consent for female patients effective birth control psoriasis arthritis psoriasis palmoplantaris erythrodermic psoriasis druginduced psoriasis pregnancy previous treatment with cyclosporine A or mycophenolate mofetil pregnancy reduced liver function high blood pressure reduced kidney function severe viral or bacterial infection 2 weeks before or after vaccinations innate or acquired immunodeficiency severe neurologic or psychiatric symptoms participation in other trials other reasons voiced by the treating physician</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>randomized clinical trial</keyword>
	<keyword>cyclosporine A</keyword>
	<keyword>mycophenolate mofetil</keyword>
	<keyword>immunosuppression</keyword>
</DOC>