<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="55137">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02388347</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D5450C00001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02388347</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Assess the Safety of MEDI7836 in Healthy Adults.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1a, Randomised, Placebo-controlled, Single-ascending Dose Study to Evaluate the Safety and Tolerability of MEDI7836 in Healthy Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>MedImmune LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>MedImmune LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To assess the safety of a single ascending dose of MEDI7836 in healthy adult male subjects
      and healthy adult female subjects of non-childbearing potential.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 1a, randomised, blinded (the investigator and subject will be blinded to
      treatment assignment and sponsor will be unblinded to treatment assignment),
      placebo-controlled study to evaluate the safety of single-ascending SC doses of MEDI7836 in
      healthy adult males subjects and healthy adult female subjects of non-childbearing
      potential. The study will be conducted at a single site in the United Kingdom (UK). Four
      dosing cohorts of MEDI7836 or placebo are planned for this study for a total of 32 subjects
      (24 subjects receiving MEDI7836, 8 subjects receiving placebo).
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events as a Measure of Safety and Tolerability of MEDI7836</measure>
    <time_frame>281 days post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events, serious adverse events, adverse events of special interest, and new onset of chronic disease.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events as a Measure of Safety and Tolerability of MEDI7836</measure>
    <time_frame>281 days post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical laboratory assessments (serum chemistry, hematology, urinalysis)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events as a Measure of Safety and Tolerability of MEDI7836</measure>
    <time_frame>281 days post dose</time_frame>
    <description>12 Lead electrocardiogram (including QTc, QRS, PR intervals and ventricular rate)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events as a Measure of Safety and Tolerability of MEDI7836</measure>
    <time_frame>281 days post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Vital signs (systolic and diastolic BP), heart rate</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of MEDI7836 in Serum</measure>
    <time_frame>281 days post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the plasma drug concentration versus time curves from zero to infinity and to last observation (AUC0-inf; AUC0-t). This variable will be estimated for MEDI7836 in the subcutaneous cohorts where data allow.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of MEDI7836 in Serum</measure>
    <time_frame>281 days post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum observed plasma drug concentration (Cmax). This variable will be estimated for MEDI7836 in the subcutaneous cohorts where data allow.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of MEDI7836 in Serum</measure>
    <time_frame>281 days post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Time to maximum observed plasma drug concentration (Tmax). This variable will be estimated for MEDI7836 in the subcutaneous cohorts where data allow.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of MEDI7836 in Serum</measure>
    <time_frame>281 days post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal plasma elimination half-life (t1/2). This variable will be estimated for MEDI7836 in the subcutaneous cohorts where data allow.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of MEDI7836 in Serum</measure>
    <time_frame>281 days post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Apparent systemic clearance (CL/F). This variable will be estimated for MEDI7836 in the subcutaneous cohorts where data allow.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of MEDI7836 in Serum</measure>
    <time_frame>281 days post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Apparent terminal-phase volume of distribution (Vz/F). This variable will be estimated for MEDI7836 in the subcutaneous cohorts where data allow.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The presence of anti-drug antibodies (ADAs) to MEDI7836</measure>
    <time_frame>281 days post dose</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence of anti-drug antibodies (a measure of the body's immune response to the drug). This variable will be estimated for MEDI7836 in the subcutaneous cohorts where data allow.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">79</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Adults</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subcutaneous (under the skin) injection on Day 1</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MEDI7836 Dose 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subcutaneous (under the skin) injection on Day 1</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MEDI7836 Dose 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subcutaneous (under the skin) injection on Day 1</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MEDI7836 Dose 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subcutaneous (under the skin) injection on Day 1</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MEDI7836 Dose 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subcutaneous (under the skin) injection on Day 1</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo SC</intervention_name>
    <description>Liquid formulation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MEDI7836 SC Cohort 1</intervention_name>
    <description>Liquid Formulation</description>
    <arm_group_label>MEDI7836 Dose 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MEDI7836 SC Cohort 2</intervention_name>
    <description>Liquid Formulation</description>
    <arm_group_label>MEDI7836 Dose 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MEDI7836 SC Cohort 3</intervention_name>
    <description>Liquid Formulation</description>
    <arm_group_label>MEDI7836 Dose 3</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MEDI7836 SC Cohort 4</intervention_name>
    <description>Liquid Formulation</description>
    <arm_group_label>MEDI7836 Dose 4</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Vital signs, ECG, and laboratory parameters within normal range at screening and Day
             -1

          2. Negative alcohol and drug screen at screening and Day -1

          3. Able and willing to comply with the requirements of the protocol

          4. Females subjects must have been surgically sterilised or be postmenopausal

          5. Nonsterilised males who are sexually active with a female partner of childbearing
             potential or a female partner who has been surgically sterilised by bilateral tubal
             ligation must use a condom with spermicide with their partner from screening until
             the end of the study follow-up period

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Concurrent enrolment in another clinical study where the subject is receiving an
             investigational product

          2. Individuals who are legally institutionalised

          3. Receipt of any marketed or investigational biologic agent within 4 months

          4. Receipt of any investigational non-biologic agent within 3 months or 5 half-lives
             prior to screening, whichever is longer

          5. Use of any medication (prescription or over the counter, including herbal remedies)
             within 14 days or 5 half-lives of Day 1,

          6. Known history of allergy or reaction to any component of the investigational product
             formulation

          7. History of anaphylaxis following any biologic therapy

          8. History of chronic alcohol or drug abuse within 12 months prior to screening,

          9. Presence of a positive drug or alcohol screen at screening and Day -1.

         10. Current smoker, or history of smoking within 6 months of screening

         11. Pregnant or breastfeeding women

         12. Any active medical or psychiatric condition or other reason which, in the opinion of
             the investigator or medical monitor, may compromise the safety of the subject in the
             study or interfere with evaluation of the investigational product or reduce the
             subject's ability to participate in the study

         13. Any clinically relevant abnormal findings in physical examination, ECG, vital signs,
             haematology, clinical chemistry or urinalysis during screening or Day -1,

         14. History of any known primary immunodeficiency disorder or use of immunosuppressive
             medication within 12 months of screening

         15. History of a clinically significant infection requiring antibiotics or antiviral
             medication from 30 days prior to screening, up to and including Day 1

         16. Diagnosis of a helminth parasitic infection within 6 months prior to screening that
             has not been treated with, or has failed to respond to, standard of care therapy

         17. History of cancer, except for basal cell carcinoma or in situ carcinoma of the cervix
             treated with apparent success with curative therapy ≥ 12 months prior to screening or
             other malignancies treated with apparent success with curative therapy ≥ 5 years
             prior to screening

         18. Positive tuberculosis (TB) test (Quantiferon-TB Gold) at screening or TB requiring
             treatment within the 12 months prior to the screening visit

         19. Positive hepatitis B surface antigen, hepatitis B anti-core antibody, or hepatitis C
             virus antibody serology at screening.

         20. Subjects with a history of hepatitis B vaccination without history of hepatitis B are
             allowed to enter the study.

         21. A positive human immunodeficiency virus test at screening or subject taking
             antiretroviral medications, as determined by medical history and/or subject's verbal
             report

         22. Evidence of active liver disease, including jaundice or aspartate transaminase (AST),
             alanine transaminase (ALT), or alkaline phosphatase greater than twice the upper
             limit of normal (ULN)

         23. Major surgery within 8 weeks prior to screening, or planed in-patient surgery or
             hospitalisation during the study period

         24. Receipt of live attenuated vaccines 30 days prior to the date of screening Where
             participation in the study would result in donation of blood or blood products in
             excess of 500 mL within an 8-week period
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Annelize Koch, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Parexel</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 16, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 9, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
