<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01386658</DOC>
	<brief_summary>HGT-FIR-086 is a multicenter, open-label, non-randomized, single-arm study to evaluate the Pharmacokinetics, tolerability,safety, and efficacy on reproductive hormones, of a single subcutaneous (SC) administration of icatibant in approximately 30 pediatric subjects with Hereditary Angioedema (HAE) during an initial acute attack.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pharmacokinetic, Tolerability and Safety Study of Icatibant in Children and Adolescents With Hereditary Angioedema</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study HGT-FIR-086 will enroll 30 subjects from 2 to less than 18 years of age, divided into 2 groups: prepubertal and pubertal/postpubertal. At least 10 prepubertal children and at least 20 adolescents (including 10 treated during a HAE attack) must be enrolled in the study. After a qualifying screening period, the PK, safety/tolerability, and efficacy of treatment with SC icatibant will be evaluated in at least 20 subjects (10 prepubertal and 10 pubertal/postpubertal subjects) who present with cutaneous, abdominal, or laryngeal symptoms of an acute attack of HAE. The PK and safety/tolerability of SC icatibant will be evaluated in at least 10 additional pubertal/postpubertal subjects who meet screening criteria and receive treatment with SC icatibant in the absence of a current acute HAE attack. The planned duration of active participation for subjects who present with an initial attack of acute HAE will consist of treatment with a single subcutaneous injection of icatibant on Day 1 through follow up at day 90. After having received initial treatment with icatibant, either during or in the absence of an attack, at least 10 pubertal/postpubertal subjects who subsequently experience an acute HAE attack may continue to receive treatment with icatibant as a single SC administration per attack for a total of 3 eligible icatibant-treated attacks. The period of active participation in the study for prepubertal subjects will be approximately 90 days, while that for pubertal/postpubertal subjects could be a maximum of approximately 270 or 360 days (3 separate active periods of approximately 90 days for those treated with icatibant during an attack; 4 separate active periods for those treated without an attack), with each active period separated by periods of inactive participation of variable duration.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Angioedema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angioedemas, Hereditary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Icatibant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bradykinin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Two through &lt;18 years of age at the time of first HAE attack. Prepubertal and pubertal/postpubertal subjects experiencing and acute cutaneous, abdominal, or laryngeal HAE attack treated with icatibant as part of this study. Pubertal/postpubertal subjects with HAE who are treated with icatibant, but not during an attack. 2. Documented diagnosis of HAE Type I or II. 3. Informed consent (and subject assent as appropriate) signed by the subject's parent(s)or legal guardian(s). 1. Diagnosis of angioedema other than HAE. 2. Participation in another clinical trial that involves the use of any investigational product (drug or device)within 30 days prior to study enrollment or at any time during the study. 3. Any known factor/disease that might interfere with the treatment compliance, study conduct,or result interpretation. 4. Congenital or acquired cardiac anomalies that interfere significantly with cardiac function. 5. Treatment with ACE inhibitors within 7 days prior to treatment. 6. Use of hormonal contraception within the 90 days prior to treatment. 7. Androgen use (eg, stanozolol, danazol, oxandrolone, methyltestosterone, testosterone) within the 90 days prior to treatment. 8. Pregnancy or breastfeeding. 9. A physical condition that interferes with pubertal status determination.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Hereditary angioedema</keyword>
	<keyword>HAE</keyword>
	<keyword>Pediatric</keyword>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Firazyr</keyword>
	<keyword>icatibant</keyword>
</DOC>