<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01154985</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a controlled study to determine the effectiveness and safety of ethyl icosapentate (EPA-E) in the treatment of adult patients with non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study of Two Doses of EPA-E in Patients With Non Alcoholic Steatohepatitis (NASH)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase II, double-blinded, placebo-controlled study to investigate the safety, efficacy, and pharmacokinetic profile of two doses of EPA-E in adult subjects with NASH. Subjects are required to have a liver biopsy with proven NASH in the 6 month period prior to screening. Up to 70 subjects will be enrolled into each treatment arm in a 1:1:1 ratio, for a total of 210 subjects. Subjects will be stratified at randomization by presence or absence of diabetes. Duration of treatment is 12 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eicosapentaenoic acid ethyl ester</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of definite NASH Patients with diabetes taking stable doses of antidiabetic agents are eligible No significant concomitant medical illness Diagnosis of cirrhosis. Serum ALT &gt; 300 U/L Use of drugs associated with steatohepatitis Use of the following anitNASH agents: 1. Vitamin E &gt; 60 IU per day 2. Omega3acid ethyl esters or omega3polyunsaturated fatty acid (PUFA)containing supplements &gt; 200 mg per day 3. Thiazolidinediones (e.g. pioglitazone) Use of nonstable doses of the following antiNASH agents: HMGCoA reductase inhibitors (statins), fibrates, probucol, ezetimibe, ursodiol (UDCA), taurine, betaine, Nacetylcysteine, sadenosylmethionine (SAME), milk thistle, antiTNF therapies, or probiotics. Other liver disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>omega-3 fatty acids</keyword>
	<keyword>alanine transaminase</keyword>
	<keyword>triglycerides</keyword>
	<keyword>lipids</keyword>
	<keyword>EPA</keyword>
	<keyword>ethyl-EPA</keyword>
	<keyword>ethyl icosapentate</keyword>
	<keyword>Non Alcoholic steatohepatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Non Alcoholic fatty liver disease</keyword>
	<keyword>fatty acids</keyword>
</DOC>