<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01554904</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will test the hypothesis that training with the Facial-Flex exercise device for six weeks will improve snoring in patients with primary snoring or very mild sleep apnea.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Will Test the Theory That Training With the Facial-Flex Exercise Device Will Improve Snoring in Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Subjects will be studied before and after 6 weeks of Facial-Flex training using portable monitoring. There will be 8 patient visits and 2 additional trips to the sleep center to return the portable sleep monitor.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Snoring</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with a history of loud snoring but no observed breathing pauses by bed partner (or only very mild obstructive sleep apnea on a previous sleep study within the prior year) will be enrolled. Very mild sleep apnea is defined here as an apneahypopnea index (AHI) &lt; 10/hour). This assumes that the AHI is computed using hypopnea defined as a 30% drop in the flow signal associated with a 4% or greater arterial oxygen desaturation. Prior upper airway surgery Daytime sleepiness (Epworth sleepiness scale &gt;12/24), (obesity BMI &gt; 35 kg/M2) Significant arterial oxygen desaturation defined as 5 minutes or more with an arterial oxygen desaturation less than 88% Severe insomnia with less than 4 hours of sleep per night Uncontrolled psychiatric disorder Any disorder causing facial weakness Pregnancy Temporal mandibular joint problems.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sleep Study</keyword>
	<keyword>Snoring</keyword>
	<keyword>Sleep Apnea</keyword>
	<keyword>Muscle Laxity</keyword>
	<keyword>Oral Appliance</keyword>
	<keyword>Facial Muscles</keyword>
	<keyword>Neck Muscles</keyword>
	<keyword>Upper Airway</keyword>
	<keyword>Muscle Strength</keyword>
	<keyword>Dynamic Resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>Oral Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Facial Toning</keyword>
	<keyword>Facial Muscle Strength</keyword>
	<keyword>Strap Muscles of the Neck</keyword>
	<keyword>Apnea-Hypopnea</keyword>
</DOC>