<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01554189</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being done to assess the safety, pharmacokinetics (PK) and pharmacodynamics (PD) of MK-8325 in male hepatitis C virus (HCV)-infected participants. There will be 3 parts to this study. Part I will enroll only genotype 1 (GT1) HCV patients, Part II will enroll only genotype 3 (GT3) HCV-infected participants, and Part III will enroll only GT1a HCV-infected participants. All parts may run concurrently, or may be staggered as needed by the clinical sites.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety, Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of MK-8325 in Hepatitis C-Infected Males (MK-8325-002)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Body mass index (BMI) of 18 to ≤37 kg/m^2 Diagnosis of chronic HCV infection Must be infected with HCV GT1a, GT1b, or GT3 Exclusion criteria: Coinfection with GT1 and GT3 HCV History of stroke, chronic seizures, or major neurological disorder History of clinically significant endocrine, gastrointestinal (excepting HCV infection), cardiovascular, hematological, immunological, renal, respiratory, or genitourinary abnormalities or diseases History of neoplastic disease Positive Hepatitis B surface antigen History of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection or positive HIV serology Major surgery, donated or lost 1 unit of blood (approximately 500 mL) or participated in another investigational study within 4 weeks prior History of significant multiple and/or severe allergies (including latex allergy), or anaphylactic reaction or significant intolerability to prescription or nonprescription drugs or food Current regular user (including "recreational use") of any illicit drugs or history of drug (including alcohol) abuse within approximately 2 months Evidence or history of chronic hepatitis not caused by HCV including but not limited to nonHCV viral hepatitis, nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH), druginduced hepatitis, autoimmune hepatitis Previous treatments(s) with nonstructural 5A (NS5A) protein inhibitors Treatment with protease inhibitor(s) &lt;30 days prior to study enrollment Previous exposure to interferonalpha and/or ribavirin within 3 months prior to the first dose of MK8325 in the study Clinical or laboratory evidence of advanced or decompensated liver disease; evidence of bridging fibrosis or higher grade fibrosis (Metavir score ≥3) from prior liver biopsy</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>