<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01264198</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to evaluate the effect of RT on clinical and metabolic parameters in patients with NAFLD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Role of Resistance Training in Non Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: Non Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD) is the most prevalent liver disease in developed countries with a prevalence rate of 20-30 % of adults. About 10-25% of these individuals are estimated to meet the current diagnostic criteria for Non Alcoholic Steatohepatitis (NASH) and some may progress to Cirrhosis and liver failure. NAFLD is now recognized as the hepatic manifestation of the metabolic syndrome. Recent data shows that NAFLD might also predict the tendency to develop diabetes mellitus and coronary artery disease. The drug of choice for NAFLD is yet to be found. The recommended treatment of NAFLD includes weight reduction and Physical Activity (PA), but the data of the effect of Resistance Training (RT) PA on NAFLD is scant. Aim of the study: To evaluate the effect of RT on clinical and metabolic parameters in patients with NAFLD. Study design: Randomized Clinical Trial. Patients will be randomly allocated to 2 arms (intervention and control). The intervention arm will perform RT, whereas control arm will be advised to perform home stretching. Medical examination will be performed at week 0 (baseline) and at week 13 using uniform protocols.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ultrasound diagnosed fatty liver. Presence of HBsAg or antiHCV antibodies (will be obtained from blood tests at the liver clinic). Patients with known diabetes treated with antidiabetic medications. Patients with known kidney disease, CHD, lung disease, inflammatory bowel disease. Excessive alcohol consumption ≥ 30 g/day in men or 20 g/ day in women.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>