<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01216059</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Atopic dermatitis is a common problem faced by patients of all ages and backgrounds. Treatment regimens and specific therapies may be time consuming and multiple studies have documented a parallel decrease in compliance as time after an office visit increases. The adolescent population is an extremely challenging sub-group of patients in terms of complying with a treatment regimen. Not only are they striving for independence and thus lacking supervision of a regimen by a parent, but their complex thinking skills are immature, leading to forgetful behavior. By introducing a reminder system for these vulnerable patients that is easily incorporated into their daily lives, the investigators propose that patients will have better compliance at applying their medication and thus improving their atopic dermatitis. Text-messaging via cell phones has become very popular among teenagers and adults and provides a non-obtrusive method of sending a treatment reminder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Text Messaging and Atopic Dermatitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We propose to conduct a randomized, controlled 6-week trial to evaluate the impact of a text message-based reminder program on adherence to health maintenance behaviors among adolescents diagnosed with Atopic Dermatitis. After obtaining informed consent, subjects will be randomized into either an intervention or control group. Subjects in the intervention group will receive a daily text message with a tailored message regarding atopic dermatitis, while control group subjects will receive a weekly text message with information on local weather, sport or news without any reference to atopic dermatitis. Of note, the decision to send a weekly text message to the control group reflects the expectation that a message will be sent, although the frequency and content of the message will not be revealed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis, Atopic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eczema</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1017 inclusive Capable of giving informed consent/assent. Of note, all subjects will sign an assent form and parents will sign a parent consent form. Diagnosed with Atopic Dermatitis by a physician (self report) IGA score fo 2 or greater Currently using at least one prescribed topical therapy for atopic dermatitis Have a mobile phone capable of receiving text messages Able to retrieve text messages from mobile phone Able to adhere to study visit schedule and other protocol requirements. Younger than 10 years of age or 18 years and older at the time of enrollment No diagnosis of atopic dermatitis by a physician IGA score of 0 or 1 Currently on no prescribed topical treatment for atopic dermatitis UV therapy or climatotherapy is a part of treatment for atopic dermatitis Does not have a mobile phone capable of receiving text messages Unable to retrieve text message NonEnglish speaking individuals (text messages are in English)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>text message</keyword>
	<keyword>reminder</keyword>
	<keyword>adolescents</keyword>
</DOC>