<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02336750</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Comparing Dexamethasone, Aprepitant and Mirtazapine With Dexamethasone and Aprepitant in Delayed Emesis Control and Appetite Improvement</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adding Mirtazapine to Dexamethasone and Aprepitant for Delayed Emesis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Phase III Trial Comparing Efficacy and Safety of Dexamethasone, Aprepitant and Mirtazapine With Dexamethasone and Aprepitant in Delayed Emesis Control and Appetite Improvement</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aprepitant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fosaprepitant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mirtazapine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mianserin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients who had delayed emesis after receiving AC regimen or regimens including cisplatin, and will subsequently accept the same chemotherapy regimens 2. Karnofsky Performance Status ≥60. 3. Life expectancy of more than 3 months. 4. Hemoglobin ≥ 90 g/L (No blood transfusion within 14 days), Absolute Neutrophil Count ≥ 1.5×10^9/L, Platelet Count ≥ 75×10^9/L, Serum Bilirubin ≤ 1.5×ULN, ALT and AST ≤ 3.0×ULN (without liver metastases), ALT and AST ≤ 5.0×ULN (with liver metastases), Serum Creatinine ≤ 1×ULN, Endogenous Creatinine Clearance＞60ml/min 5. Be able to read, understand and complete the questionnaire and diary, including FLIE and Food Diary. Note: Must be able to understand written Chinese. 6. Be able to understand the study procedures and sign informed consent. 7. Meet one of the followings about contraception: For fertile women： 1. Urine pregnancy test in screening should be negative. If urine pregnancy test is positive, the patient could be enrolled only when serum pregnancy test is negative. 2. They should agree to abstinence or use double barrier methods of contraception during the research, within at least 14 days before enrolling and one month after the last dose of study medicine. 3. If taking oral contraceptives, the patient should agree to add a barrier method of contraception during the research, within at least 14 days before enrolling and one month after the last dose of study medicine. Unfertility is defined as anyone of the followings: 1. Natural menopausal (natural menopausal ≥6 months and the serum FSH in the Postmenopausal range, or natural menopausal ≥12 months and age ＞45) 2. Bilateral tubal ligation 3. 6 weeks after the bilateral oophorectomy (with or without hysterectomy ) 1. Treatment with any other study medicine within 4 weeks before enrollment and with unrecovered toxicities. 2. Women of reproductive age (including gestation period, lactation, a desire of pregnancy, oral contraceptives only) 3. Severe visceral disease: such as history of myocardial infarction or serious epilepsy needing medicine. 4. Mental disabilities or emotional or mental disorders. 5. Another malignancy within 5 years (except for cured basal cell carcinoma of the skin and cervical carcinoma). 6. Uncontrolled disease, such as active infections (pneumonia), diabetic ketoacidosis, gastrointestinal obstruction. And other cases which would cause bias or make patients exposed to unnecessary risks. 7. Receiving any dose of systemic glucocorticoid treatment, but local or inhaled corticosteroids is allowed. 8. Benzodiazepines or opioids treatment within 48 hours before the first day of the study, except for a single daily taking of triazolam, temazepam or midazolam. a)Benzodiazepines or opioids given 48 hours or longer before the first day of the study are allowed and patients can continue the medication. 9. Having vomiting, retching or nausea within 24 hours before cisplatin treatment on the first day of the study. 10. Patient will receive abdominal or pelvic radiation between a week before and 6 days after the initiation of the study. 11. Prior aprepitant treatment or hypersensitivity history to any components of the study drug. 12. Cannot swallow capsules. 13. Not eligible for the study based on the investigators. 14. Patients receiving strong inducers of CYP3A4, such as carbamazepine, dipheninum, phenobarbitone, etc..</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>