<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02023957</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The current protocol pertains to the evaluation of the interactive computer-assisted screening (iCAS) tool through a pilot randomized control trial. The purpose of this evaluation is to determine the efficacy of the iCAS tool in improving clinician's detection of common mental health conditions (i.e. major depression/generalized anxiety/post-traumatic stress disorder/alcohol dependence), and patients' discussion on mental health.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pilot With Interactive Computer-assisted Screening for Mental Health in Primary Care</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The iCAS tool is a health-risk assessment survey that is completed by adult patients using touch-screen iPad device in their waiting time before seeing their clinician (family physician or nurse practitioner). The computer program generates tailored risk-report for the clinician and a simple recommendation sheet for the patient, with community resources and health information, at the point of care. The iCAS tool currently includes validated screening scales for depression, generalized anxiety, posttraumatic stress disorder and alcohol abuse. There are some questions on the social determinants of mental health as well. The current versions of the tool are in English and Spanish; a Chinese language version will also be developed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 18 years of age Speak/read Spanish Speak/read English Visiting the consenting clinician Patient accompanied by a family member for interpretation New patients coming for first visit Patients feeling unwell (selfreport) Inability of the research staff to offer study details in privacy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Interactive Health-risk assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized</keyword>
	<keyword>Open Label</keyword>
	<keyword>Efficacy Study</keyword>
</DOC>