<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02023749</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aimed to investigate the effects of nut consumption on metabolic parameters and biomarkers related to inflammation, oxidative stress, and endothelial function in Korean adults with metabolic syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Nut Consumption on Metabolic Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A randomized, controlled, parallel, dietary intervention study was designed. Subjects with metabolic syndrome and body mass index ≥23 kg/m2 were randomized to the Nut group, which were supplemented with 30 g of mixed nuts including walnuts, peanuts, and pine nuts for 6 weeks; or allocated to the Control group. Metabolic markers were evaluated at baseline and at the end of the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects were enrolled if their body mass index (BMI) was ≥23 kg/m2 and they met the criteria for metabolic syndrome. Subjects were excluded if they had a nut allergy, peptic disorder, a history of cancer or cardiovascular disease including coronary artery disease, heart valve disease, or stroke, or established chronic diseases such as chronic renal insufficiency or cirrhosis. Subjects were also excluded if they:1) were receiving treatment with hypoglycemic agents for diabetes or had HbA1c &gt;7%; 2) were receiving corticosteroid treatment; 3) had started antihypertensive or lipidlowering agents, or changed their doses within the previous month; 4) had a weight change ≥5 % of body weight during the three months prior to the study; 5) were pregnant; or 6) were regular nut consumers (&gt;15g/day of nuts at least three times a week).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>nuts</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>lipid profile</keyword>
	<keyword>inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>oxidative stress</keyword>
	<keyword>endothelial function</keyword>
</DOC>