<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02583191</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to show feasibility (efficacy and safety) of Rivaroxaban in the treatment of VTE in cancer patients in comparison to the standard treatment with low molecular weight heparin (LMWH). Tumor patients with active cancer and newly diagnosed thromboembolic events are randomised to receive either Rivaroxaban or the standard treatment with low-molecular heparin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rivaroxaban in the Treatment of Venous Thromboembolism (VTE) in Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Newly diagnosed and objectively confirmed acute venous thromboembolism Active malignancy Life expectancy of at least 6 months PerformanceStatus according to Karnofsky Performance Scale ≥ 70 % Patient's compliance and geographical situation allowing an adequate follow up platelets ≥ 100.000 /μl, INR &lt; 1.5, PTT &lt; 40 sec. written informed consent of the patient prior to any procedure in connection with the study male and female patients with an age of at least 18 years therapeutic anticoagulation &gt; 96 hours prior to study treatment known allergic reactions against the study drugs or the substances included therein known conditions associated with high risk of bleeding, known history of hemorrhagic diathesis acute clinically relevant bleeding in the last 2 weeks any history of spontaneous major/cerebral bleeding history of heparin induced thrombocytopenia II pregnant or breastfeeding women. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test performed &lt; 7 days prior to start of the treatment severe renal insufficiency (GFR &lt; 30 ml/min) liver disease with coagulation impairment, including Child B and C cirrhosis acute medical illness treatment of the underlying cancer with experimental therapies</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>