<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02583997</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to evaluate postoperative pain (measured by visual analogue scale (VAS) on day 2 post surgery) in patients operated for avulsion of four wisdom teeth under general anesthesia and for whom the resulting alveoli were NOT sutured versus a similar group of patients undergoing standard care (suturing for lower alveoli).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Non-closure of Alveoli After Avulsion of Wisdom Teeth</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The secondary objectives of this study are to compare the following between the two study arms: A. Pain at day 31 B. Operative time C. Edema D. Trismus E. The occurrence of complications F. Alveolar flap healing G. The impact of smoking on the occurrence of complications H. The consumption of analgesics and use of local pain remedies I. Impact on quality of life</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tooth Avulsion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient was correctly informed about the implementation of the study, its objectives, constraints and patient rights The patient gave his/her free and informed signed consent For patients under 18 years of age, the patient's parents (or legal guardian) must have given their free and informed signed consent The patient must be affiliated with or the recipient of a health insurance program The patient is available for 31 days of followup The patient is a candidate for avulsion of all 4 wisdom teeth under general anesthesia The patient is participating in another study The patient has participated in another study in the last 3 months The patient is in an exclusion period is determined by a previous study The patient is an adult under guardianship The patient is under judicial protection The patient refuses to sign the consent It is impossible to correctly inform the patient For patients under 18 years of age, his/her parents (or legal guardian) refuse to sign the consent The patient is pregnant, breastfeeding or parturient The patient has a contraindication (or an incompatible combination therapy) for a treatment in this study The patient is taking antiplatelet agents The patient is taking anticoagulants The patient has a coagulation disorder The patient suffers from immunosuppression The patient's wisdom teeth are in a normal, functional, healthy position Other orofacial surgical procedures are planned during the study period Active pericoronitis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>To suture or not to suture....</keyword>
	<keyword>Tooth extraction</keyword>
	<keyword>Third molar</keyword>
</DOC>