<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02082015</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to Evaluate Efficacy and Safety of rTMS 『TMS』 for Upper Extremity Motor Function Recovery in Patients with Ischemic Stroke</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Study of rTMS for Upper Extremity Motor Function Recovery in Ischemic Stroke Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) can modulate the excitability of cortex but exact efficacy and safety of rTMS is not well established. Eighty four patients will be recruited and will be divided into two groups. Each group will receive the real rTMS or sham rTMS, respectively, over the primary motor cortex of the dominant hand. Individual subject will receive ten sessions of rTMS. Each rTMS session is low frequency (1Hz), total 1800 stimulations. The purpose of this study is to evaluate efficacy and safety of rTMS 『TMS』 for upper extremity motor function recovery in patients with ischemic stroke.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemiplegia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>2080 yrs old Radiologically confirmed ischemic stroke within 90 days Brunnström stage 35 in the affected hand (ischemic strokeinduced hemiplegic side) Patients received stroke treatment and on secondary prevention medication Written informed consent Previous medical histories of stroke, cerebral vascular operation, seizure Pregnancy, Breastfeeding Patients with hemorrhagic stroke, traumatic brain injury Skin lesion in the stimulation site of scalp Metal implants in the body (cardiac pacemaker or aneurysm clip) Unable to have regular physical and occupational therapies on the affected hand</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neuronal plasticity</keyword>
	<keyword>Transcranial magnetic stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Upper extremity</keyword>
	<keyword>Function</keyword>
	<keyword>Recovery</keyword>
</DOC>