<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00153114</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Assess the safety and efficacy of polyethyleneglycol3350 laxative as compared to placebo therapy in pediatric patients with a history of constipation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PolyethyleneGlycol3350 Laxative vs Placebo in Constipated Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Constipation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Laxatives</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polyethylene glycol 3350</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female outpatients between the ages of 4 to 16 years. Adolescent female patients must not be pregnant or lactating. constipated according to ROME I definition Two or fewer bowel movements during the initial observation week. Absence of a stool impaction Bowel movement after receiving enema Are otherwise in good health, as judged by a physical examination. Parent or guardian is mentally competent to sign an instrument of informed consent Patients with heme positive stool at baseline exam. Patients with fecal impaction at baseline, or after the observation period, as indicated by physical exam Patients with known or suspected perforation or obstruction other than fecal impaction. Patients who are breastfeeding, pregnant or intend to become pregnant during the study. Female patients of childbearing potential who refuse a pregnancy test. Patients with a known history of organic cause for their constipation. Patients with congenital malformations that produce constipation (Hirschsprung's disease, imperforate anus, children with cerebral palsy or other neurologic abnormalities, or systemic diseases). History of gastric retention, inflammatory bowel disease, bowel resection, or colostomy. Use of concomitant medications that cause constipation Patients who, in the opinion of the investigator, should not be included in the study for any reason, including inability to follow study procedures. Patients with known allergy to polyethyleneglycol or polyethyleneglycol containing medications. Patients with clinically significant elevations of TSH or abnormal plasma electrolytes. Patients who, within the past 30 days have participated in an investigational clinical study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>