<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00242580</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the safety and efficacy of the combination treatments in wet age-related macular degeneration. The combination treatment consists of verteporfin photodynamic therapy and either triamcinolone acetonide or pegaptanib added as an intravitreal injection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Safety and Efficacy Study Comparing the Combination Treatments of Verteporfin Therapy Plus One of Two Different Doses of Intravitreal Triamcinolone Acetonide and the Verteporfin Therapy Plus Intravitreal Pegaptanib</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Choroidal Neovascularization</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neovascularization, Pathologic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone hexacetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone Acetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone diacetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Verteporfin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age &gt;50 all types of untreated subfoveal choroidal neovascularization secondary to AMD lesion size &lt;5400 microns in greater linear dimension (GLD) have a history of prior photodynamic therapy, external beam radiation, subfoveal focal laser photocoagulation, submacular surgery, or transpupillary thermotherapy known allergy to verteporfin, triamcinolone or pegaptanib have received prior treatment with Macugen, or other antiangiogenic compound or any investigational treatment (e.g. Ruboxistaurin, Lucentis [ranibizumab], Retaane [anecortave acetate], squalamine, siRNA, VEGFTrap etc.) for neovascular AMD have the presence of fibrosis, hemorrhage, pigment epithelial detachments, tear (tip) of the retinal pigment epithelium or other hypoflourescent lesions obscuring greater than 50% of the CNV lesion have had previous pars plana vitrectomy in the study eye Other protocolspecified inclusion/exclusion criteria applied.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>AMD</keyword>
	<keyword>age-related macular degeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>choroidal neovascularization</keyword>
</DOC>