<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02686658</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objectives of this study are to evaluate the safety and efficacy of intravitreous administration of Zimura® when administered in subjects with geographic atrophy (GA) secondary to dry age-related macular degeneration (AMD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 2/3 Trial to Assess the Safety and Efficacy of Intravitreous Administration of Zimura® (Anti-C5 Aptamer) in Subjects With Geographic Atrophy Secondary to Dry Age-Related Macular Degeneration</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Approximately 300 subjects will be randomized in a 1:1:1 ratio to the following dose groups: - Zimura® Dose 1 - Zimura® Dose 2 - Sham Subjects will receive monthly intravitreal injections of Zimura® or Sham for 24 months. An interim analysis will be conducted, following which, the study may be expanded to include more subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Geographic Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects of either gender aged ≥ 50 years Diagnosis of Nonfoveal GA secondary to dry AMD Retinal atrophy involving the fovea Evidence of Choroidal Neovascularization (CNV) Any prior treatment for AMD or any prior intravitreal treatment for any indication in either eye, except oral supplements of vitamins and minerals Any intraocular surgery or thermal laser within three (3) months of trial entry Any prior thermal laser in the macular region, regardless of indication Any ocular or periocular infection in the twelve (12) weeks prior to entry Previous therapeutic radiation in the region of the study eye Any sign of diabetic retinopathy in either eye</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Geographic Atrophy</keyword>
	<keyword>Dry age-related macular degeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>AMD</keyword>
	<keyword>Zimura®</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-inflammatory</keyword>
	<keyword>Complement C5 inhibition</keyword>
</DOC>