<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00926263</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is primarily to evaluate the single dose pharmacokinetics of CP-751,871 and its effect on QT interval prolongation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pharmacokinetic And QT Study Of CP-751,871 In Healthy Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study was terminated on October 30th, 2009. While the study was terminated due to adverse events and altered benefit/risk ratio in healthy subjects, the findings in healthy volunteers are not considered to alter the benefit/risk evaluation of figitumumab in cancer patients. No changes due to the termination of this study are anticipated in the conduct of the ongoing cancer patient studies with figitumumab at this time.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Moxifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy male subjects and/or healthy female subjects of nonchildbearing potential between the ages of 18 and 55 years, inclusive Body Mass Index (BMI) of 17.5 to 30.5 kg/m2; and a total body weight &gt;50 kg (110 lbs). Evidence or history of clinically significant hematological, renal, endocrine, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, hepatic, psychiatric, neurologic, or allergic disease (including drug allergies, but excluding untreated, asymptomatic, seasonal allergies at time of dosing). 12lead ECG demonstrating QTc &gt;450 msec at screening or other clinically significant abnormalities at screening. History or family history of risk factors for QTc interval prolongation or torsades de pointes (eg, organic heart disease, congestive heart failure, hypokalemia, hypomagnesemia, congenital long QT syndrome, myocardial ischemia or infarction); family history of sudden death.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacodynamics</keyword>
	<keyword>QTc interval prolongation</keyword>
</DOC>