<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02554409</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Sanofi Pasteur Fluzone Intradermal Quadrivalent vaccine (Fluzone QIV-ID) Pregnancy Registry will be a prospectively recruited pregnancy surveillance program designed to collect to collect and analyze information on vaccine exposures, pregnancy outcomes, and fetal and offspring outcomes on pregnant women exposed to Fluzone QIV-ID vaccine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sanofi Pasteur Quadrivalent Intradermal Influenza Vaccine Pregnancy Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Sanofi Pasteur will encourage registration of pregnant women exposed to Fluzone QIV-ID in the Sanofi Pasteur Pregnancy Registry by providing the registry's toll-free number, 1-800-VACCINE (1-800-822-2463), in the USPI. The toll-free number will also be available through the Sanofi Pasteur-sponsored Website for the Pregnancy Registry. Both the United States product insert (USPI) and Website will advise health care providers to register women who are pregnant or became aware they were pregnant at the time of Fluzone QIV-ID immunization. Descriptive statistical methods will be the primary approach for summarizing data from the Fluzone QIV-ID Pregnancy Registry. No vaccine products will be provided or administered as part of this registry protocol.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pregnant women will be enrolled in the registry prospectively (after exposure to a product but before the conduct of any prenatal tests that could provide knowledge of the outcome of pregnancy). If the condition of the fetus has already been assessed through prenatal testing (e.g., targeted ultrasound, amniocentesis, etc.), such reports will be considered retrospective reports. Retrospective reports are also eligible for the registry, but they will be analyzed separately from prospective reports.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fluzone Quadrivalent Intradermal Influenza Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Pregnancy Registry</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza</keyword>
</DOC>