<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02826577</DOC>
	<brief_summary>No studies to date have examined the effects of pregnenolone on hypervigilance for social threat in individuals with perceived social isolation (PSI). We therefore are conducting a double-blind randomized research study combining three validated behavioral paradigms on social threat attention, perception of others, and emotion regulation with high-density electrical neuroimaging to probe the neuro-circuitry of social threat processing in young adults high in perceived social isolation two hours after the oral administration of 175mg pregnenolone (N = 24), 400mg of pregnenolone (N = 24), or placebo (N = 24). Such research has the potential to yield important insights into the neurobehavioral mechanisms of pregnenolone on hypervigilance for social threat and perception of others--- a first key step toward the development of adjunctive pregnenolone therapy in individuals with PSI.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Pregnenolone on Perceived Social Isolation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Male Age 2132 At least a score of 42 on the UCLA Loneliness scale. Right handed Normal or corrected eye sight Medical history of cancer Steroid use Psychotropic drugs History of heart irregularities Have a counter indication to EEG BMI &lt;30 Female Age &lt;21 or &gt;32 Score less than 42 on UCLA loneliness scale Left handed Meet MINI criteria for anything but untreated major depressive disorder Uncorrected vision Current or past neurological disorder including epilepsy or traumatic brain injury Have a counter indication to electrical neuroimaging Under hormonal therapy (including, but not limited to, testosterone) Unstable mental illness History of bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, or psychotic disorder Current or recent (past 3 months) substance use or dependence Currently taking any medications that may have unfavorable interactions with pregnenolone</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>32 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>