<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01866566</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Through evaluating the immunogenicity and safety for Varicella vaccine two doses immune procedure we could supply scientific and practical evidence for this two doses immune procedure promotion and management.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Safety and Immunogenicity Research of Live Attenuated Varicella Vaccine After the 2 Doses Vaccination</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Healthy participants aged 1 to 12 years old who had never received Varicella Vaccine are divided into three age groups, 1 to 3 years old group, 4 to 6 years old group and 7-12 years old group. In each age group, participants are randomly divided into experiment group and control groups.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Chickenpox</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Herpes Zoster</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants from Shanxi province are between 112 years old are in good healthy determined through medical inquiry, physical examination, clinical judgment of the investor. 1. Having a fever (axillary temperature＞37.0℃) before enrollment; 2. Having a disease history of seizures, brain disease and the vaccination history of allergies and convulsions; 3. Antibiotics allergy; 4. Having a problem of intramuscular injection because thrombocytopenia or other blood coagulation disorder; 5. Having immunodeficiency or under immunosuppression therapy, radiation therapy; 6. Having respiratory diseases, acute infection, chronic disease and HIV infection; 7. Having systemic skin rash, skin tinea, herpes; 8. Chronic liver and kidney disease; 9. Heart disease, and severe hypertension; 10. Have received whole blood, plasma or immunoglobulin therapy 3 months before enrollment; 11. Have received other live attenuated vaccine vaccination in 30 days before enrollment; 12. Had been infected with Varicella virus and displayed symptom; 13. Have received one or two dose of Varicella vaccine before enrollment; 14. Congenital malformations, growth disorders such as Down's syndrome, diabetes, sickle cell anemia and nervous disorders 15. Guillainbarre syndrome 16. Thyroid resection history or thyroid disease treatment in the past 12 months; 17. Asthma 18. Have participated in other clinical research; 19. Have serious adverse reactions after vaccination, such as allergies, hives, breathing difficulties, angioneurotic edema.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>