<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01866371</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Studying the morphology and function of the normal and diseased retina in vivo is needed for advancing the detection, diagnosis, and treatment of retinal disease. This protocol uses an adaptive optics scanning laser ophthalmoscope (AOSLO) to image the normal and diseased retina with individual cellular resolution non-invasively. The primary objective of this study is to obtain and analyze high-resolution images of the retina, in particular by imaging the cone photoreceptor mosaic, the retinal vasculature and other retinal layers. The study design will involve case-control studies, where cases are followed over time. Subjects age 7 and older may be invited to participate. The main research procedure involves retinal imaging with the AOSLO. The primary endpoint is the observation of differences in retinal images between subjects with and without retinal diseases. These changes will be quantified by examining the cell density, size, spacing and regularity of the cone photoreceptor mosaic, as well as examining the differences between other retinal layers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>High Resolution Retinal Imaging</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinitis Pigmentosa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Geographic Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Choroideremia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males or females age 7 years or older. Parental/guardian permission (informed consent) and if appropriate, child assent. Child subjects age 717 must give assent. Reasonable compliance with an imaging protocol as determined by the study personnel. Individuals that are at risk to acute glaucoma. Individuals that are photophobic and experience adverse psychological reactions to flashes of light. Ocular opacities, high refractive error, and high frequency of nystagmus as determined by the study team.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Retina</keyword>
	<keyword>imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>retinal degeneration</keyword>
</DOC>