<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00728286</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess platelet dependent thrombogenicity in patients after acute coronary syndrome using an ex vivo arterial injury model.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of Thrombogenicity in Acute Coronary Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Abnormal platelet activity seen in patients with Type2 Diabetes Mellitus (T2DM) may be an important contributor to their enhanced cardiovascular risk and higher rates of cardiovascular events following acute coronary syndrome, despite dual antiplatelet therapy with aspirin and clopidogrel. We have earlier demonstrated high thrombogenicity in individuals with T2DM and CAD in the absence of acute ischaemic events, despite therapeutic doses of aspirin.We hypothesise that patients with T2DM will have increased thrombogenicity after acute coronary syndrome despite optimal secondary prevention medication.Measuring ex vivo thrombus area using an arterial injury model simulates plaque rupture and reflects the summative effect of all haemostatic abnormalities. The thrombus area of patients with ACS and T2DM will be compared to the controls without T2DM.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Acute coronary syndrome (WHO criteria) with raised cardiac troponin T Aged 1880 years Stable Acute coronary syndrome On aspirin and clopidogrel Willing to participate in the study Smoking (current smokers or smokers who quit in the last 6 months preceding recruitment) Malignancy (any suspected or proven) Haematological disorders (bleeding disorders) Premenopausal women Use of corticosteroids/other antithrombotic agents (warfarin) Chronic liver disease Unable to consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute Coronary Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Platelet dependent thrombogenicity</keyword>
</DOC>