<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00757991</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Studying samples of blood from healthy volunteers in the laboratory may help doctors learn more about changes that occur in DNA and identify biomarkers related to cancer. PURPOSE: This study is looking at genetic susceptibility to cancer and interactions between genes and the environment in healthy volunteers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Blood Samples From Healthy Volunteers for Genetic Studies in the East Anglia Region of the United Kingdom</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - To obtain blood samples and simple epidemiological information on a population-based series of adult individuals without cancer. - To establish whether polymorphisms in putative cancer predisposition genes are associated with an increased risk of cancer by comparing the frequency of alterations in these genes with the corresponding frequency in a comparable series of cancer patients. - To examine the interactions between genetic and non-genetic risk factors. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Participants complete a simple epidemiological questionnaire. Participants undergo blood sample collection. DNA is extracted from these samples for polymorphism analysis of low penetrance cancer susceptibility genes in the following related clinical trials: MREC-SEARCH-CANCER, MREC-SEARCH-PROSTATE, and MREC-SEARCH-BREAST. They may also be used in the analyses of the following related clinical trials: MREC-SEARCH-OVARIAN, MREC-SEARCH-ENDOMETRIAL, MREC-SEARCH-COLORECTAL. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 2,000 male and 2,000 female participants will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Cancerfree participants randomly selected from the agesex registry of a general practice in the East Anglia region of the United Kingdom Two general practices from each district within East Anglia participate (up to 10 total participating practices) PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Identified by the participant's general practitioner as fit to contact for this study No prior diagnosis of cancer No serious mental illness or retardation PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>69 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>healthy, no evidence of disease</keyword>
</DOC>