<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="114941">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01606852</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IND 111693</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R21NR012795</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01606852</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Testing the Feasibility of Patient Controlled Sedation for Ventilated ICU Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>PCS</acronym>
  <official_title>Testing the Feasibility of Patient Controlled Sedation for Ventilated ICU Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Minnesota - Clinical and Translational Science Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Nursing Research (NINR)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospira, now a wholly owned subsidiary of Pfizer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Minnesota - Clinical and Translational Science Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Mechanical ventilation (MV) is the most frequently used life-support modality in intensive
      care units (ICUs). To reduce anxiety, stress and promote tolerance of MV, nurses frequently
      administer a variety of sedative medications to their patients based on subjective
      observations.

      The investigators hypothesize that patient-controlled sedation, compared to
      clinician-directed sedation, will decrease sedative exposure while decreasing patient
      anxiety during the episode of mechanical ventilation.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A study to determine whether critically ill patients, during a substantial portion of their
      time on mechanical ventilation, can reduce anxiety symptoms better with PCS than their
      caregivers while reducing over-sedation, duration of mechanical ventilation and length of
      ICU stay will require hundreds of subjects enrolled on a multi-day protocol. However,
      patient-controlled sedation has been used in less than 20 patients and only for less than 24
      hours. Therefore this study is designed to:

        1. Establish the feasibility of subject recruitment and protocol adherence in a randomized
           pilot trial that compares patient-controlled sedation (PCS) using dexmedetomidine to
           usual sedation practice in mechanically ventilated patients. Feasibility will be
           defined by: a) number and proportion of patients or proxies who consent to enrollment,
           b) proportion of eligible subjects enrolled on Days 1,2,3,4 etc, of mechanical
           ventilation, c) number of days on protocol, up to five days, that subjects successfully
           use the PCS device, d) ability of ICU nurses to adjust the pump and adhere to the
           infusion rates of the PCS protocol.

        2. Develop and refine the study protocol including: a) improving the proportion of patient
           daily assessments actually completed such as anxiety and delirium scales, b) develop a
           protocol to reliably determine when the subject is not able to self-manage their
           sedation due to weakness, confusion or severe illness; c) create rules for suspending
           PCS therapy and d) develop a post-ICU symptom interview.

        3. Estimate effect sizes on key variables to inform the design of a future randomized
           trial to compare: a) sedative exposure, anxiety levels, and delirium occurrence between
           groups, b) adverse event rates and protocol violations related to the drug, pump or
           both; and c) duration of mechanical ventilation and ICU stay.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Aggregate sedative exposure during PCS use (up to 5 days).</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days after enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Will use the sedation intensity score (SIS; described in Weinert C, Calvin A. Epidemiology of sedation for mechanically ventilated patients. Critical Care Medicine 2007;35:393-401) and a similar dose frequency score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analogue scale for anxiety (0-100).</measure>
    <time_frame>daily for up to 5 days after enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>VAS-A is a 100 mm vertical line anchored at 'not anxious at all' (0) to 'the most anxious I have ever been'(100). Subjects mark the scale in response ti the question &quot;How are you feeling today?&quot; The scale is discussed in: Cline ME, Herman J, Shaw ER, Morton RD. Standardization of the visual analogue scale. Nursing Research 1992;4(6):378-80 and Chlan L. Relationship between two anxiety instruments in patients receiving mechanical ventilatory support. Journal of Advanced Nursing 2004;48(5):493-9</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Delirium incidence</measure>
    <time_frame>Daily up to 5 days</time_frame>
    <description>Will use the Confusion Assessment Method-ICU (CAM-ICU) daily to assess for delirium. (Ely E, Inouye S, Bernard G. Delirium in mechanically ventilated patients: Validity and reliability of the Confusion Assessment Method for the Intensive Care Unit (CAM-ICU). JAMA. 2001;286(21):2703-10)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Initiation of Weaning</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>Time to Initiation of Weaning. Time to initiation of spontaneous breathing trials (SBTs) is the period from intubation to when the subject begins standard pressure-support trials managed by the unit respiratory therapists.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of mechanical ventilatory support</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 30 days after enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Length of mechanical ventilatory support. This will be calculated using two different start times: First, from the time of intubation to clinician-ordered extubation, withdrawal of ventilatory support or death; and second, from the time of study enrollment to the same endpoint</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of ICU Stay</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 30 days after enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Two different ICU length-of-stay variables will be recorded in a similar manner as ventilatory support duration. First, from the time of ICU admission to ICU discharge or death and second, from the time of study enrollment to the same endpoint.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>During 5 days of study protocol</time_frame>
    <description>arterial hypotension, bradycardia, self-extubations, and protocol violations related to drug, pump or both.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">38</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Respiratory Failure</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>usual sedative practice</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will have &quot;usual care&quot; sedation directed by their patient care team with no protocolized restriction on drug doses, selection or duration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patient controlled sedation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be given the hand actuator connected to a Lifecare PCA Infusion System in the PCA + continuous mode with the syringe filled with 4 ucg/ml of dexmedetomidine. A loading dose (0.5 mcg/kg) will be given followed by a continuous basal infusion (0.2-0.7 mcg/kg/hr) with 3 allowable patient-controlled self-boluses per hour (0.25 mcg/kg) each with a 20-minute lock-out. Bedside RNs will adjust the basal rate to a maximum of based on the number of bolus requests in the prior two hours. Subjects can also receive bolus supplemental sedative medications (benzodiazepines and/or opioids)if needed in the judgment of the patient-care nurse.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexmedetomidine</intervention_name>
    <description>loading dose (0.5 mcg/kg i.v.), followed by a continuous basal infusion (0.2-0.7 mcg/kg/hr) with 3 allowable patient-controlled self-boluses per hour (0.25 mcg/kg) each with a 20-minute lock-out. Study infusion up to 5 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patient controlled sedation</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Administered via a Lifecare PCA Infusion System (Hospira)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  adult intubated patients with respiratory failure expected to require mechanical
             ventilation for at least an additional 48 hours

          -  subjects have to have at least a 50% chance of being able to operate the PCS machine
             (i.e., adequate hand strength and cognition)

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  aggressive ventilatory support such as positive end expiratory pressure &gt; 15 cm of
             water, prone ventilation, use of high-frequency oscillator ventilator

          -  hypotension requiring vasopressors (systolic blood pressure &lt; 85 mmHg), second or
             third degree heart block or bradycardia (heart rate &lt; 50 beats/min.)

          -  permanent condition preventing the use of push button device (e.g., paralysis)

          -  pregnancy or lactation

          -  acute hepatitis or liver failure

          -  general anesthesia 24 hours prior

          -  acute stroke or uncontrolled seizures

          -  acute MI

          -  severe cognition or communication problems (e.g., coma as main reason for intubation,
             deafness without signing literacy, dementia or severe delirium)
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Minnesota Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55455</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 17, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 9, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>sedation</keyword>
  <keyword>mechanical ventilation</keyword>
  <keyword>anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>respiratory failure</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
