<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02957786</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the effectiveness, safety, and cost-effectiveness of cytisine plus behavioural support compared to varenicline plus behavioural support for smoking cessation, in indigenous Māori (or family of Māori) who smoke and are motivated to quit.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cytisine Versus Varenicline for Smoking Cessation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cytisine, a natural product, found in plants such as the Golden Rain and New Zealand Kowhai, partially blocks the effects of nicotine on the brain. Cytisine has been used as a smoking cessation treatment in several Central and Eastern European countries since the 1960s, is inexpensive compared to other cessation medications and has few known side effects. New Zealand research has shown cytisine to be more effective than nicotine replacement therapy at helping people quit smoking. Using a clinical trial design (N=2140) the investigators plan to investigate whether cytisine is at least as good as varenicline (the most effective, but most expensive, smoking cessation medication currently available in New Zealand) for helping Māori/family of Māori who smoke, to quit.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Varenicline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>daily tobacco smokers selfidentify as Māori (indigenous New Zealander) or whānau (family) of Māori want to stop smoking in the next two weeks are at least 18 years of age are able to provide verbal consent reside in the Lakes District Health Board region at the time of enrolment have daily access to a mobile phone with text capability and/or email and access to the internet via computer or smartphone are eligible for subsidised varenicline under special authority conditions are pregnant or breastfeeding are current users of other smoking cessation therapies (e.g. nicotine replacement therapy [NRT], buproprion [Zyban], clonidine, nortriptyline, ecigarettes) are enrolled in another smoking cessation programme or another smoking cessation study have a contraindication for cytisine or varenicline have used varenicline or cytisine in the past 12 months have another person in their household involved in the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>cytisine</keyword>
	<keyword>varenicline</keyword>
	<keyword>smoking cessation</keyword>
	<keyword>indigenous</keyword>
</DOC>