<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02957266</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to define an effectiveness of concurrent chemoradiotherapy of cervical cancer patients treated by VMAT (volumetric arc therapy) based external beam radiotherapy, polyradiosensitization by cisplatin and gemcitabine and interstitial brachytherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cervical Cancer Radiotherapy by Use of VMAT, Individualized Polyradiosensitization and Interstitial Brachytherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Now cisplatin based concurrent chemoradiotherapy for cervical cancer is a standard treatment modality. But we consider that the treatment results could be improved by several ways: 1. use of VMAT (volumetric arc therapy) based external beam radiotherapy could decrease toxicity by reducing of unnecessarily irradiated tissue volumes; 2. in addition to cisplatin gemcitabine could enhance tumor cell damaging effect of radiation; 3. interstitial brachytherapy could provide higher radiation dose boost to high risk tumor volume while sparing surrounding organs at risk.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed primary invasive carcinoma of the uterine cervix Previously untreated disease Any cell type Stage IB2, IIA, IIB, IIIA, IIIB, or IVA Paraaortic lymph nodes negative by radiologic evaluation or by biopsy if CT scan is suspicious for adenopathy No known metastases to scalene nodes or other organs outside the radiotherapy field Study enrollment within 8 weeks of diagnosis Performance status GOG 02 Absolute neutrophil count at least 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm^3 Bilirubin no greater than 1.5 times normal SGOT no greater than 3 times normal Creatinine less than 2.0 mg/dL No renal abnormalities (e.g., pelvic kidney, horseshoe kidney, or renal transplantation) that would require modification of radiotherapy fields No bilateral ureteral obstruction allowed unless treated with stent or nephrostomy tube Not pregnant Fertile patients must use effective contraception No septicemia or severe infection No circumstance that would preclude study completion or followup No other malignancy within the past 5 years except nonmelanoma skin cancer No prior cytotoxic chemotherapy No prior pelvic or abdominal radiotherapy No prior therapy for this malignancy Pregnancy or BreastFeeding: Pregnant or breastfeeding women will not be entered on this study due to risks of fetal and teratogenic adverse events.(Note: Serum Pregnancy tests must be obtained in women of child bearing potential). Sexually active females may not participate unless they have agreed to use an effective contraceptive method (such as abstinence, diaphragm, condom, or intrauterine device) to prevent pregnancy for the duration of the study. Growth factor(s): Growth factors that support platelet or white cell number or function must not have been administered within the past 28 days. Erythropoietic drug(s): Erythropoietin or related hormones must not have been administered within the past 28 days. Infection: Patients who have an uncontrolled infection. Evidence of distant metastases Prior invasive malignancy (except nonmelanomatous skin cancer), unless disease free for a minimum of 3 years. Prior systemic chemotherapy within the last three years. Prior radiotherapy to the pelvis</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>interstitial brachytherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>gemcitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>volumetric arc therapy</keyword>
</DOC>