<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02957136</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized clinical trial to assess the effect of rapid, near point-of-care testing for multiple common respiratory viruses and bacteria on antibiotic and anti-influenza medication use in emergency department (ED) patients with symptoms of influenza-like illness (ILI) and/or upper respiratory infection (URI). The intervention is a rapid, multi-respiratory pathogen nucleic acid amplification panel test (FilmArray Respiratory Panel; BioFire Diagnostics, LLC) with clinical result reporting within two hours of sample collection. Randomization is at the individual patient level. Intervention patients will receive usual care plus the rapid multi-respiratory pathogen test. Control patients will receive physician-directed usual care without the rapid, multi-respiratory pathogen test, which may include but is not limited to no testing, point-of-care influenza testing, or delayed testing for multiple respiratory pathogens at an off-site laboratory. The primary outcome is antibiotic administration or prescription during the initial ED episode of care. The investigators primary hypothesis is that rapid multi-respiratory pathogen testing will be associated with a ≥15% reduction in antibiotic use in intervention patients, relative to control patients (usual care). The investigators secondary outcome is administration or prescription of antivirals during the initial ED episode of care. The investigators secondary hypothesis is that rapid multi-respiratory pathogen testing will improve anti-influenza medication use in intervention patients (composite rate of anti-influenza treatment in positive patients and non-use of anti-influenza treatment in negative patients), relative to control patients receiving usual care alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rapid Diagnostics for Upper Respiratory Infections in the Emergency Department</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Common Cold</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<criteria>University of California, Davis (UC Davis) Emergency Department patients evaluated for influenza like illness and/or upper respiratory infection by an ED physician who consent and agree to have a nasopharyngeal swab collected for the study English speaking or Spanish speaking patients Neonates Prisoners Employees of UC Davis/Students of the Principal Investigator or CoPrincipal Investigator NonEnglish, nonSpanish speaking patients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>101 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Respiratory Tract Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza, Human</keyword>
	<keyword>Common Cold</keyword>
	<keyword>Viral Infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Pathology, Molecular</keyword>
	<keyword>Molecular Diagnostics</keyword>
	<keyword>Diagnostic Testing</keyword>
	<keyword>Clinical Microbiology</keyword>
	<keyword>Polymerase Chain Reaction</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibiotic Stewardship</keyword>
	<keyword>Antimicrobial Use</keyword>
	<keyword>Emergency Department</keyword>
	<keyword>Emergency Room</keyword>
</DOC>