<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01412723</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Iron deficiency and depleted levels of iron are the most prevalent nutritional deficiency and the leading cause of anemia in the world; this can occur at any age, but preschool children are at particular risk of developing it. This condition may cause serious repercussions for life, being a public health threat of considerable importance worldwide. Food fortification is considered the most effective solution to counter this situation, because it can help more people than other solutions. It is going to carry out a community trial to compare the efficacy of ferrous sulfate with respect to iron amino acid chelate as a dietary supplement in preschool children of Medellin with depleted levels of iron; in terms of increasing ferritin levels in blood and maintain hemoglobin levels. It is hypothesized that at the end of the study the effect of milk fortified with iron amino acid chelate won't be less than the effect of fortified with ferrous sulfate. It is hoped that the results may contribute, albeit indirectly, to improve the health status of children with depleted levels of iron whom consume iron-fortified products.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ferrous Sulfate Versus Iron Amino Acid Chelate</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Iron-Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chelating Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children who Belong to institute FAN in Medellín Attend full time to institute FAN (eight hours) Have 2 to 5 years inclusive Submit depleted levels of iron (ferritin level equal to or less than 24 mg/L) Children who Submit anemia (hemoglobin level equal to or less than 11 g/dL) Have not stool analysis before intervention</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Iron Deficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Child, Preschool</keyword>
	<keyword>Dietary Iron</keyword>
	<keyword>Ferrous sulfate</keyword>
	<keyword>Bis-glycino iron II</keyword>
</DOC>