<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01192022</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The efficacy and safety of TachoSil速 as secondary hemostatic treatment in hepatic resection surgery will be compared to the standard USA licensed hemostatic agent, Surgicel速 Original. Hemostatic efficacy will be evaluated intraoperatively after application of randomized treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TachoSil速 Versus Surgicel速 Original for the Secondary Treatment of Local Bleeding in Adult and Pediatric Patients Undergoing Hepatic Resection Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Resection of at least the equivalent tissue volume of 1 anatomical segment of the liver Minor to moderate (oozing/diffuse) bleeding from the resection area persisting after conventional resection procedure and primary control of arterial pulsating bleeding or major venous hemorrhage by sutures, ligations, clips, vascular stapler, point electrocautery or focal radiofrequency ablation Need for additional supportive hemostatic treatment Expected ability to lightly press the trial treatment to the liver resection wound for 3 minutes Indication for emergency surgery Known coagulopathy (as judged relevant by the investigator) Known or suspected hypersensitivity to any ingredient of the investigational medicinal products (e.g. human fibrinogen, human thrombin and/or collagen of any origin) Patient unwilling to receive blood products Known current alcohol or drug abuse Pregnancy, breastfeeding, no use of acceptable contraceptive method in females of childbearing potential Dry surgical field of the targeted application area Occurrence of any serious surgical complication Disseminated intravascular coagulopathy (DIC), i.e. microvascular bleeding Application of topical hemostatic material on the liver resection wound Radiofrequency precoagulation of the liver resection wound except focal radiofrequency ablation of vessels as primary hemostatic treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Liver resection</keyword>
	<keyword>Liver transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Liver surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Secondary hemostasis</keyword>
</DOC>