<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01638234</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sleep disturbance is a common complaint among patients with atopic dermatitis(AD). Melatonin may aid sleep and also has anti-inflammatory properties, and has been suggested in managing sleep disturbance in AD patients. However, there has been no large randomized controlled trials. Hence the objective of this double-blind randomized controlled study is to determine whether supplementing melatonin is effective in improving sleep problems in children with AD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Melatonin for Sleep Disturbances in Children With Atopic Dermatitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis, Atopic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eczema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyssomnias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Melatonin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children between 1 and 18 years of age with mild to moderate AD, affecting at least 5% of total body surface area, and with sleep problems in the previous 3 months 1. Those who had failed other systemic and/or topical immunosuppressive agents such as tacrolimus, methotrexate, or cyclosporine 2. Those who had received therapy for insomnia within 4 weeks before the baseline visit 3. Those who were, in the opinion of the investigator, known to be unreliable or noncompliant with medical treatment or appointments 4. Those who had drug abuse problems, mental health dysfunction, or other factors limiting their ability to cooperate fully 5. Those who were taking antihistamines, oral immunosuppressant medication, or antidepressant medication 6. Pregnant and lactating women and those who are presently planning to get pregnant 7. Those who had any other condition or earlier/current treatment which, in the opinion of the investigator, would render the participant ineligible for the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>atopic dermatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>eczema</keyword>
</DOC>