<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01638494</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Calcium (Ca2+) and vitamin D (VitD) play an important role in child health. Aims. The investigators evaluated the daily intake of Ca2+ and VitD in healthy children; and the efficacy of Ca2+ and VitD supplementation. Daily Ca2 + and VitD intake was evaluated in consecutive healthy children through a validated questionnaire. Subjects with a daily Ca2 + and VitD intake &lt; 70% of dietary reference intakes (DRIs) were invited to participate in prospective randomized trial with 2 groups of nutritional intervention: group 1, dietary counseling aiming to optimize daily Ca2+ and VitD intake plus administration of a commercially available Ca2 + and VitD supplementation product (Colecalcium®, Humana, Milan, Italy); group 2, dietary counseling alone. At the enrollment (T0) and after 4 months (T1) serum VitD levels were assessed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Calcium and Vitamin D Intakes in Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypocalcemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Avitaminosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rickets</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ambulatory healthy subjects (male and female, age range 317 years) consecutively observed at our Department for routine clinical examination because vaccination program were considered eligible for the study. Exclusion criteria malnutrition (defined as a weight/height ratio &lt;5° centile); presence of chronic systemic diseases (celiac disease, inflammatory bowel disease, food allergy, cystic fibrosis, malignancy, immunodeficiency, tuberculosis, geneticmetabolic disease, primitive bone disease, diabetes and endocrine disorder); and use of systemic steroids in the previous 3 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>25-Hydroxyvitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>dietary counseling</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatrics</keyword>
	<keyword>allergy</keyword>
	<keyword>bone metabolism</keyword>
</DOC>