<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00975078</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Suppression of the adrenal function is a common, potentially dangerous and unpredictable consequence of short term high dose glucocorticoid treatment. Identification of patients at risk would be of high clinical importance. The investigators hypothesized that the dexamethasone-suppression-test predicts the subsequent development of corticosteroid induced adrenal insufficiency.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Test Predicting Adrenal Insufficiency in Volunteers Under Prednisone Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of this study is to evaluate if adrenal axis integrity investigated by the dexamethasone-suppression-test will predict the development of adrenal insufficiency after 14 days treatment with 0.5mg/kg of body weight prednisone in healthy volunteers. The investigators hypothesize that subjects with a more suppressed cortisol level after dexamethasone will be more likely to develop adrenal insufficiency after 14 days intake of prednisone o.5mg/kg/body weight than subjects with less suppression of their cortisol levels after dexamethasone.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adrenal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Addison Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epinephrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Racepinephrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epinephryl borate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy male volunteers over 18 years No informed consent Intake of any kind of medication BMI over 30kg/m2 Acute or chronic illnesses</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>dexamethasone-suppression-test</keyword>
	<keyword>high dose glucocorticoid treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Population at Risk</keyword>
</DOC>