<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00082316</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a randomized, open-label multi-center evaluation of the tolerability of treatment with NGX-4010 in conjunction with pre-patch topical application of one of three 4% lidocaine-based local anesthetic products. Eligible subjects will have moderate to severe neuropathic pain secondary to painful diabetic neuropathy (PDN), postherpetic neuralgia (PHN) or HIV-associated neuropathy (HIV-AN), with average numeric pain rating scale (NPRS) scores during screening of 3 to 8 (inclusive).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tolerability of Three Local Anesthetic Formulations in Conjunction With NGX-4010 for the Treatment of Neuropathic Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polyneuropathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Neuropathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Herpes Zoster</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capsaicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics, Local</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Eligibility Criteria: Must have had for at least 3 months painful diabetic neuropathy, or postherpetic neuralgia, or painful HIVassociated neuropathy, with moderate to severe pain on average. Must not have significant pain due to other causes (for example, arthritis). Must have intact skin at the treatment area. Must be prepared to remain on the same pain medications at the same doses as before the study for the entire duration of the study (12 weeks). Must not use topical pain medications on painful areas. Must be able to comply with study requirements such as completing daily pain diary and attending study visits and refrain from extensive travel during study participation. Must be at least 18 years old, not pregnant, and able to take care of self independently, with only occasional assistance if needed. No significant medical problems of the heart, kidneys, liver or lungs, or cancer. No history or current problem with substance abuse.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dermal assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>Diary</keyword>
	<keyword>Analgesics</keyword>
	<keyword>Capsaicin</keyword>
	<keyword>Herpes zoster</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuralgia</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Peripheral Nervous System Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetic Neuropathies</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Polyneuropathies</keyword>
	<keyword>Complementary Therapies</keyword>
</DOC>