<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00828009</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Vaccines may help the body build an effective immune response to kill tumor cells. Monoclonal antibodies, such as bevacizumab, can block tumor growth in different ways. Some block the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Others find tumor cells and help kill them or carry tumor-killing substances to them. Drugs used in chemotherapy work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Radiation therapy uses high-energy x-rays to kill tumor cells. Giving vaccine therapy together with bevacizumab after chemotherapy and radiation therapy may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying the side effects of giving BLP25 liposome vaccine together with bevacizumab after chemotherapy and radiation therapy in treating patients with newly diagnosed stage IIIA or stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer that cannot be removed by surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>BLP25 Liposome Vaccine and Bevacizumab After Chemotherapy and Radiation Therapy in Treating Patients With Newly Diagnosed Stage IIIA or Stage IIIB Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer That Cannot Be Removed by Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - To determine the safety of BLP25 liposome vaccine and bevacizumab after definitive chemoradiotherapy and consolidation chemotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed, unresectable stage IIIA or IIIB nonsquamous cell non-small cell lung cancer. Secondary - To evaluate the overall survival and progression-free in patients treated with this regimen. - To evaluate the toxicity of this regimen in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. - Chemoradiotherapy: Patients receive paclitaxel IV over 1 hour and carboplatin IV over 15-30 minutes once a week for 6 weeks. Patients also undergo concurrent definitive radiotherapy 5 days a week for 6½ weeks. Patients with complete response (CR), partial response (PR), or stable disease (SD) proceed to consolidation chemotherapy. - Consolidation chemotherapy: Patients receive paclitaxel IV over 3 hours and carboplatin IV over 15-30 minutes on day 1. Treatment repeats every 21 days for 2 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients with CR, PR, or SD proceed to maintenance therapy. - Maintenance therapy: Patients receive a single dose of cyclophosphamide IV over 15-30 minutes 3 days before the first dose of bevacizumab and BLP25 liposome vaccine. Patients then receive bevacizumab IV over 30-90 minutes on day 1 and BLP25 liposome vaccine subcutaneously on days 1, 8, and 15 of courses 1 and 2 and on day 1 of every other course beginning in course 4. Treatment repeats every 21 days for up to 34 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed periodically for up to 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed newly diagnosed nonsquamous cell nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC), including the following subtypes: Adenocarcinoma Large cell undifferentiated Bronchoalveolar cell NSCLC, not otherwise specified Unresectable stage IIIA or stage IIIB disease Patients with stage IIIA disease with mediastinal lymph node enlargement between 1 cm and 2.0 cm on CT scan must have these nodes biopsied (pathologic confirmation) to rule out resectability Metastases to contralateral mediastinal or supraclavicular nodes allowed Measurable or nonmeasurable disease, as defined by RECIST criteria No significant pleural effusion as defined by either of the following: Pleural effusion is seen on CT scan only (not seen on chest xray) Pleural effusion does not reaccumulate within 1 week after thoracentesis AND is cytologically negative No CNS metastases by head CT scan or MRI within the past 4 weeks PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: ECOG performance status 01 WBC ≥ 4,000/mm³ OR ANC ≥ 2,000/mm³ Platelet count ≥ 140,000/mm³ Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 mg/dL AST/ALT ≤ 2.5 times upper limit of normal Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/mL OR creatinine clearance ≥ 45 mL/min Urine protein:creatinine ratio &lt; 1.0 by urine dipstick OR &lt; 1 g of protein by 24hour urine collection INR ≤ 1.5 OR ≤ 3.0 if patient is on therapeutic anticoagulation PTT normal Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception before, during, and for ≥ 6 months after completion of bevacizumab No other active malignancies No known hepatitis B or C No ongoing (lasting &gt; 14 days) or active infection or ongoing (lasting &gt; 14 days) fever within the past 6 months No gross hemoptysis ≥ grade 2 (defined as ≥ ½ teaspoon of bright red blood per episode) within the past 3 months No pulmonary hemoptysis Confirmed extrapulmonary hemoptysis allowed No bleeding ≥ grade 2 or any bleeding requiring intervention No history of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy No cardiac dysfunction, including any of the following: Clinically significant cardiovascular disease Myocardial infarction within the past 6 months New York Heart Association class IIIIV congestive heart failure Unstable angina pectoris Serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication within the past 4 weeks History of hypertensive crisis or hypertensive encephalopathy Stroke or transient ischemic attack within the past 6 months Peripheral vascular disease ≥ grade 2 within the past 6 months No abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation, or intraabdominal abscess within the past 6 months No psychiatric illness or social situation that would limit compliance with study requirements No history of uncontrolled hypertension (i.e., blood pressure ≥ 150/100 mm Hg) while on stable regimen of antihypertensive therapy No significant traumatic injury or serious nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture within the past 4 weeks No recognized immunodeficiency disease, including cellular immunodeficiencies, hypogammaglobulinemia or dysgammaglobulinemia, or hereditary or congenital immunodeficiencies No preexisting medical condition requiring chronic steroids or immunosuppressive therapy No autoimmune disease No known hypersensitivity to any component of bevacizumab PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics More than 4 weeks since prior open biopsy or major surgical procedure More than 28 days since prior immunotherapy (e.g., interferon, interleukin, sargramostim [GMCSF], or filgrastim [GCSF]) Patients must not have had prior chemotherapy or monoclonal antibodies for other cancers within 5 years prior to registration More than 7 says since prior core biopsy or any other minor surgical procedure, excluding the placement of a vascular access device No prior chemotherapy for lung cancer No prior chest radiotherapy No prior splenectomy Concurrent stable regimen of therapeutic anticoagulation or prophylactic anticoagulation for venous access devices allowed provided coagulation studies met entry criteria No concurrent daily aspirin (&gt; 325 mg/day) or nonsteroidal antiinflammatory agents (NSAIDs) known to inhibit platelet function No concurrent dipyridamole (Persantine), ticlopidine (Ticlid), clopidogrel bisulfate (Plavix), and/or cilostazol (Pletal) No concurrent major surgical procedure</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma of the lung</keyword>
	<keyword>bronchoalveolar cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>large cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>