<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00828529</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this Phase I, open-label, randomized crossover trial is to investigate the pharmacokinetic interaction between steady-state lopinavir/ritonavir and single-dose TMC207 in healthy volunteers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TMC207-TiDP13-C110: Interaction Study With Lopinavir/Ritonavir in Healthy Volunteer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>TMC207 is being investigated for the treatment of MDR-TB infection. This is a Phase I, open-label, randomized crossover trial in healthy volunteers to investigate the potential interaction between steady-state lopinavir/ritonavir (LPV/rtv) 400/100 mg twice daily and a single dose of 400 mg TMC207. The trial population will consist of 16 healthy volunteers. During 2 sessions, each participant will receive 2 treatments (Treatments A and B) in a randomized order. This means it will be decided by chance if subjects will receive first treatment A, then B or first treatment B, then A. In Treatment A, participants will receive a single dose of TMC207 400 mg on Day 1. In Treatment B, participants will receive LPV/rtv 400/100 mg twice daily on Days 1 to 24, while on Day 11 a single dose of TMC207 400 mg will be co-administered. The two single doses of TMC207 will be administered 4 weeks apart. Consequently, Treatment B should start 4 days after completion of Treatment A, and Treatment A should start 14 days after completion of Treatment B (counting from the day the last PK sample has been collected). Pharmacokinetic profiles over 336 hours will be determined for TMC207 and its N-monodesmethyl metabolite (M2) after administration of TMC207 400 mg alone (Day 1 of Treatment A), and in combination with steady-state LPV/rtv (Day 11 of Treatment B). Morning predose concentrations of lopinavir and ritonavir will be determined at several time points. Safety and tolerability will be evaluated throughout the trial. Day 1 of Treatment A and on Day 11 of Treatment B, 400 mg TMC207 (1 tablet) will be taken orally in the morning within 10 mins. after completion of a meal. Days 1 to 24 of Treatment B, 2 tablets of Lopinavir/Ritonavir (LPV/rtv = 400 mg lopinavir and 100 mg ritonavir) will be taken in the morning and evening. When LPV/rtv is administered alone, it can be taken with or without food. When co-administered simultaneously with TMC207, LPV/rtv intake will be within 10 mins. after completion of a meal.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lopinavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bedaquiline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diarylquinolines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Nonsmoking or smoking no more than 10 cigarettes, or 2 cigars, or 2 pipes per day for at least 3 months prior to selection Body Mass Index of 18.0 to 32.0 kg/m2, extremes included Able to comply with protocol requirements Healthy on the basis of a physical examination, medical history, ECG, vital signs and the results of blood biochemistry and hematology test and a urinalysis carried out at screening Informed Consent Form signed voluntarily before the first trialrelated activity. A positive HIV1 or HIV2 test Female, except if postmenopausal since more than 2 years, or posthysterectomy, or postsurgical sterilization Hepatitis A, B, or C infection Evidence of current use of illicit drugs or opioids or abuse of alcohol Currently active or underlying disorders including gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, neurologic, psychiatric, metabolic, renal, hepatic, respiratory, inflammatory, or infectious disease Any history of significant skin disease or allergy including allergy or hypersensitivity to any of the excipients of the investigational medication administered in this trial Use of concomitant medication, including overthecounter products and dietary supplements, except for ibuprofen and paracetamol up to 3 days before the first dose of trial medication Recent donation of blood or plasma or participation in a clinical trial Subjects with QTc prolongation or any other clinically significant ECG abnormality or a family history of Long QT Syndrome.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>TMC207-TiDP13-C110</keyword>
	<keyword>TMC207-C110</keyword>
	<keyword>TMC207</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug-drug interaction</keyword>
	<keyword>Tuberculosis</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>Kaletra</keyword>
	<keyword>Lopinavir</keyword>
	<keyword>Ritonavir</keyword>
	<keyword>Open-label</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Infections</keyword>
</DOC>