<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00562289</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A patent foramen ovale (PFO) is found more frequently in patients with an ischemic stroke than in control subjects. Therapeutic options to prevent stroke recurrence include antiplatelet drugs, oral anticoagulants, and transcatheter closure of the foramen. However, there are no published studies showing convincingly the superiority of any one of these strategies in preventing stroke recurrence. The aim of this randomized clinical trial is to assess whether chronic anticoagulation on the one hand and transcatheter on the other hand are superior to chronic antiplatelet therapy in preventing stroke recurrence.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Patent Foramen Ovale Closure or Anticoagulants Versus Antiplatelet Therapy to Prevent Stroke Recurrence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Secondary prevention for stroke patients with PFO is a subject of considerable debate. Therapeutic options include antiplatelet drugs, oral anticoagulants, and transcatheter closure of the foramen. There are no published studies showing convincingly the superiority of any one of these strategies in preventing stroke recurrence. All the therapeutic options have some risks and unless randomised trials can define who should be treated with what (if anything), and for how long, we could end up exposing patients to unnecessary complications of treatment. The primary objective of this study is to assess whether chronic anticoagulation (INR 2 to 3) on the one hand and endovascular treatment on the other hand are superior to chronic antiplatelet therapy in preventing stroke recurrence in young (16 to 60 years) patients with a PFO (&gt; 30 microbubbles or associated with an atrial septal aneurysm) and an otherwise unexplained ischaemic stroke. Secondary objectives of the study are: - to evaluate the safety of the three therapeutic options, in terms of major drug-, device- or procedure-related complications, in order to allow a benefit/risk assessment of each therapeutic option in this population. - to assess the rate of technical success and effectiveness of endovascular procedure to treat PFO and ASA.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Migraine Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Foramen Ovale, Patent</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Apixaban</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dabigatran</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antivitamins K</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anticoagulants</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female, 16 &lt;= age &lt;= 60 ans. Recent (&lt;= 6 months) ischemic stroke documented by CTsan or MRI (whatever the duration of symptoms: shorter or longer than 24 hours). Modified Rankin score &lt;=3. Absence of any other identifiable cause of stroke Presence of a PFO with at least one of the following characteristics: righttoleft shunt &gt; 30 microbubbles, at rest or during provocative manoeuvres, by TTE ou TOE associated ASA (base ≥ à 15 mm, total excursion &gt; à 10 mm) by TOE Informed consent. Any identifiable cause of ischemic stroke other than PFO. Isolated atrial septal defect or atrial septal defect associated with PFO with significant lefttoright shunt requiring closure. Previous surgical or endovascular treatments of PFO or ASA. Known or suspected pregnancy (beta hCG test must be performed before inclusion). Women who are breastfeeding. Inability to comply with the treatments or followup requirements of the study. No affiliation to the national health service. Presence of other medical problems that would either lead to inability to complete the trial or interfere with the assessment of outcomes. Participation in another study. Unable to understand the full meaning of the informed consent. Related medical treatments of the trial: Longterm oral anticoagulation or antiplatelet therapy is indicated for another disease. Contraindication to antiplatelet therapy or oral anticoagulants : 3arm trial : contraindication to aspirin or clopidogrel or antivitamins K 2arm trial (closure vs antiplatelet therapy) : contraindication to aspirin or clopidogrel 2arm trial (antivitamins K vs antiplatelet therapy : contraindication to antivitamins K or to any antiplatelet drug Increased risk of bleeding, such as severe hepatic insufficiency, current peptic ulceration, proliferative diabetic retinopathy, history of severe systemic bleeding (e.g. gastrointestinal bleeding, gross hematuria, intraocular bleeding, hemorrhagic stroke, or intracranial hemorrhage), or other history of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy. Related to endovascular treatments : Infection requiring antibiotics (inclusion is possible after healing, 4 weeks after withdrawal of antibiotics). Very large or multiperforated ASA for which endovascular treatments is deemed too risky. Presence of thrombus or occlusion between the venous access and the right atrium. Presence of an inferior vena cava filter. Severe pulmonary hypertension.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Patent Foramen Ovale</keyword>
	<keyword>Atrial septal aneurysm</keyword>
	<keyword>Antiplatelet therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Oral anticoagulants</keyword>
	<keyword>Transcatheter closure</keyword>
	<keyword>Migraine</keyword>
</DOC>