<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00562471</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to determine whether the adhesion prevention gel was safe to use, and was effective for the prevention/reduction of adhesion formation that typically occurs following gynecological surgery to remove myomas</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of a Hydrogel, Applied Following Removal of Myomas During Gynecologic Surgery, Administered for the Prevention/Reduction of Postoperative Adhesion Formation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Postoperative adhesions are a common medical complication of gynecologic and pelvic surgeries, and are frequently associated with chronic or recurrent pelvic pain, intestinal obstruction and infertility. This randomized, controlled, multicenter, clinical study was designed to evaluate the safety and performance of Adhibit™ Adhesion Prevention Gel versus the standard of care for the reduction of postoperative adhesions in subjects undergoing myomectomy via laparotomy or laparoscopy. Subjects were scheduled to return within 6-8 weeks after the initial surgical procedure. At that time, a second-look laparoscopy was performed for postoperative adhesion assessment. Adhesions were graded using a modified American Fertility Society (mAFS) scoring method.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tissue Adhesions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polystyrene sulfonic acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Preoperatively, subjects must have had: Been scheduled for myomectomy via laparotomy or laparoscopy. Agreed to a secondlook laparoscopic procedure to assess and lyse any adhesions formed at 6 to 8 weeks following myomectomy. Been &gt;=18 years of age. Provided voluntary written informed consent. Been willing to comply with all aspects of the treatment and evaluation schedule. Intraoperatively, subjects must have had: Had at least one 2 cm incision length on posterior uterine surface, which may include the fundal surface. Preoperatively, subjects must not have had: Been pregnant. Had a pelvic malignancy. Had acute pelvic inflammatory disease. Had an immune compromised condition. Been a participant in another clinical research study which the investigator believed could interfere with the purpose of this study. Been given corticosteroids intraoperatively or during the course of the postoperative study follow up. Intraoperatively, subjects must not have had: Had a pelvic malignancy. Had a pelvic or abdominal infection. Had acute pelvic inflammatory disease. Received any adhesion prevention adjuvants or barriers, or peritoneal instillates containing corticosteroids, NSAIDs, or Dextran.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>adhesions</keyword>
	<keyword>gynecologic surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>laparoscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>laparotomy</keyword>
	<keyword>polyethylene glycol</keyword>
	<keyword>hydrogel</keyword>
	<keyword>Adhesions following gynecologic surgery to remove myomas</keyword>
</DOC>