<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02358603</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is to collect human activity and ECG data from heart failure (HF) patients to aid in the development of a novel chronotropic incompetence (CI) algorithm designed to diagnose CI in patients with HF.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chronotropic Incompetence Diagnostic Algorithm in Heart Failure Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Investigation of the Chronotropic Incompetence Diagnostic Algorithm in Heart Failure Patients (CI Algorithm Study) is an acute data collection study using market released actigraphy devices (wGT3X-BT) and holter devices (DR 180) to measure study subjects' daily activities and surface ECG data simultaneously. The data will be analyzed to develop an algorithm to diagnose CI in patients with HF.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient is greater than 18 years of age and less than 70 years of old. Patient is willing and able to give informed consent. Patient has been diagnosed with stable chronic HF according to European Society of Cardiology 2012 HF guidance. New York Heart Association class I III, including with HF with preserved ejection fraction and HF with reduced ejection fraction patients. Patients can perform moderate exercise. Left ventricular ejection fraction less than 55% but greater than 35%. Patient is unable or unwilling to sign the patient informed consent. Patient has implantable pacemaker, Implantable cardiovert defibrillator (ICD) or cardiac resynchronize therapy (CRT) device. Patient has at least one pacemaker, ICD or CRT indications. Patients has persistent atrial fibrillation (AF). Patient whose hear rate baseline at the rest is greater than 95 beats per minutes (BPM). Patient has contraindications for cardiopulmonary exercise testing, including but not limited to, unstable angina, decompensated heart failure, active pericarditis or myocarditis and ECG STsegment shift &gt; 2mm at the resting. New York Heart Association Class IV. Less than 45 days after myocardial infarction. Less than 3 months after acute heart failure. Patient has uncontrolled hypertension. Patient is pregnant. Patient has a medical condition that would limit study participation. Patient is enrolled in a concurrent study that may affect the outcome of this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronotropic Incompetence</keyword>
	<keyword>Heart Failure</keyword>
</DOC>