<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02358993</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators will determine the efficacy of an innovative short regimen of methenamine hippurate on prevention of post-operative UTI in patients requiring short-term catheterization after pelvic reconstructive surgery through a single-blind, randomized controlled trial. Primary outcome will be the rate of symptomatic UTI within 3 weeks of catheter removal. The investigators will study cost-effectiveness, antibiotic resistance profiles, and adverse drug effects. Findings may reduce antibiotic use and nosocomial UTIs.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Short-course Methenamine Hippurate for Prevention of Post-operative UTI</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Prevention of post-operative urinary tract infections (UTI) is becoming important for both the individual patient and the health system. Complications of UTI include pyelonephritis and bacteremia, requiring hospitalization and parenteral antibiotics. Additionally, recurrent exposure to antibiotics commonly given for UTIs increases the risk of antibiotic resistance to uropathogens. UTIs also increase economic burdens on the health care system, with each episode costing nearly 600 dollars. UTIs associated with catheterization are particularly costly for hospitals, resulting in decreased hospital quality measures and lack of compensation. This is particularly important after pelvic reconstructive surgery, as reported rates of UTI reach up to 20-25%. Urinary retention requiring short-term indwelling catheterization, common in these women, contributes to the risk of UTIs by increasing the risk of bacteriuria by 5-10% per day and through the dislodging of bacterial colonies during catheter removal. Balancing prevention and resistance and cost is key. A meta-analysis by Marschall et al indicated the benefit of a short dose of antibiotic prophylaxis at catheter removal in general post-surgical patients. However, data is lacking on the effects of daily antibiotic prophylaxis on resistance and cost. A possible alternative to antibiotics presents itself in methenamine hippurate, a urinary antiseptic which forms formaldehyde in the presence of acidic urine. It is relatively inexpensive, and does not induce resistance in vivo. Prior studies have shown that daily use of methenamine can decrease the risk of post-operative UTI. The purpose of our study was to investigate the efficacy of a short course of methenamine hippurate at catheter removal to that of a short course of ciprofloxacin in prevention of UTIs after short-term indwelling catheterization. Additionally, we investigated factors that influence post-operative UTIs, the rate of culture-proven UTIs after prophylaxis, the antibiotic resistance profile of those undergoing prophylaxis, and the cost effectiveness of prophylaxis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Tract Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Catheter-Related Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ciprofloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methenamine hippurate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methenamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>female; patients who are able to read and write English; 18 years of age or older; underwent surgery for pelvic organ prolapse, urinary incontinence, or both; require postoperative shortterm transurethral catheterization for greater than 24 hours. patients undergoing surgical intervention for sacral neuromodulation, or mesh excision; patients requiring longterm catheterization secondary to injury to the urinary tract; patients who pass their postoperative trial void and thus, do not require additional catheterization; patients requiring catheterization for less than 24 hours; pregnant patients; patients who are breastfeeding; allergy to methenamine hippurate or fluroquinolones (either ciprofloxacin or levofloxacin); impaired renal or hepatic function; preoperative urinary retention; patients who are currently using sulfonamides; patients who have severe dehydration; patients using tizanidine; patients sensitive to quinolones class; patients using theophylline; patients with myasthenia gravis; patients with prolongation of QT interval.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Urinary Tract Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Catheter-Related Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Pelvic Reconstructive Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Urogynecology</keyword>
	<keyword>Urinary catheterization</keyword>
	<keyword>Post-operative Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Methenamine hippurate</keyword>
</DOC>