<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02358395</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label, multicenter, phase 1 study of BBI608 in combination with Sorafenib. This study population is adult Japanese patients with advanced hepatocellular carcinoma in Sorafenib combination therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of BBI608 Administrated With Sorafenib in Adult Patients With Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Niacinamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or diagnosed imaging with hepatocellular carcinoma, and not indicated with a)d) . 1. Radiofrequency ablation therapy (RFA) 2. Local therapy [such as percutaneous transhepatic ethanol injection therapy (PEIT), Microwave coagulation therapy (MCT)] 3. Transcatheter arterial embolization (TAE) 4. Transcatheter arterial chemoembolization (TACE) ≥ 20 years of age. Not treatment with systemic chemotherapy. Signed written informed consent must be obtained and documented. Life expectancy ≥ 3 months. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1. Must be Child Pugh Class A. Hemoglobin ≥ 8.5 mg/dl. Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1.5 x 10^9 /L. Platelets ≥ 75 x 10^9/L. Creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN. Total Bilirubin ≤ 3.0 mg/dl. Aspartate Aminotransferase (AST) and Alanine transaminase (ALT) ≤ 5.0 x the upper limit of normal (ULN). Females of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test. Male or female patients of childproducing potential must agree to use contraception or avoidance of pregnancy measures during the study and for 30 days after the last BBI608 dose. Have had any t a)i) treatment less than 28 days prior to beginning the enrolment. 1. Radiation therapy 2. Hormone therapy 3. Immune therapy 4. Hyperthermia 5. Surgical procedure 6. Local therapy (such as RFA, PEIT, MCT) 7. TAE 8. TACE 9. other anti tumour treatment Have had a brain metastases with a symptom or requiring treatment. Have had coinstantaneous active multiple cancers. Have had a carcinomatous pleural effusion, ascites, or cardiac effusion requiring treatment. Esophageal varix requiring treatment. Patient of pregnancy or possibility of pregnancy, and planning breastfeeding by the end of BBI608 administration after 30days. Crohns disease, ulcerative colitis, or historical surgery of extensively small intestine resection. Unable or unwilling to swallow BBI608 capsules or Sorafenib tablets. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness (such as Grade 3active infection, or serious respiratory disease). HIV infection. Abnormal ECGs which are clinically significant within 28 days before enrolment. Patients who are New York Heart Association (NYHA) functional classes III, or IV, or unstable angina. Patients newly expressing angina within three months before the enrolment. Have had myocardial infarction within six months before the enrolment. Administrating with antiarrhythmic drug. Have received other investigational products or postmarketing investigational products within 4 weeks of the first dose of BBI608. Prior treatment with BBI608. Hypersensitivity to Sorafenib or any other component of Sorafenib. Ineligible for participation in the study in the opinion of the Investigators.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>