<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02819895</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if in a rural setting of Ondo State, Nigeria, a customized automated telephone and email immunization reminder system will be feasible, acceptable, and significantly improve immunization utilization rates.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PRIMM Trial (Phone Reminder for IMMunization)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: Worldwide, vaccine preventable diseases account for 29% of all deaths between 1 month and 5 years, underscoring the importance of immunizations. In Nigeria, routine childhood immunization rates are unacceptably inconsistent and low, ranging from 35-85% at 14 weeks and 10-37% for all routine immunizations at 12-24 months. GAP: The feasibility, acceptability and utility of an automated phone immunization reminder system have never been explored in this rural setting of Nigeria. HYPOTHESIS: Given ~90% of the adult population in Nigeria uses a mobile phone, a customized mHealth immunization reminder system will be feasible and acceptable; and will significantly improve immunization rates in this rural setting of Ondo State, Nigeria. METHODS: A prospective randomized controlled trial study design will be utilized. This study will recruit parents of healthy newborn infants delivered at Mother and Child Hospital Ondo, who live in Akure or Ondo Town and plan to receive their immunizations at Mother and Child Hospital Ondo. DATA ANALYSIS: The proportion of immunization visits between intervention and control groups will be compared using a two-sided, two sample test of proportions with p &lt;0.05 being significant. Secondary analysis will focus on the predictive value of social demographic variables on immunization rates.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Parents of healthy infants who have a cellular phone 2. Born at Mother and Child Hospital Ondo (Akure or Ondo Town) 3. Plans to receive immunizations at Mother and Child Hospital Ondo 1. Parents of infants requiring hospital admission due to illness or prematurity. 2. Parents without a cellular phone</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>1 Week</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Phone Appointment Reminder</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunization Rates</keyword>
	<keyword>mHealth</keyword>
</DOC>