<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00593528</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Transjugular intrahepatic portosystemic shunts (TIPS) have been increasingly used for the treatment of complications of portal hypertension in patients with cirrhosis. The initial experiment of the TIPS was reported during the 1990s with stents of various brands, manufacture and sizes, but all "non covered", thus owing the pseudointimal hyperplasia growing inside the stent, which progressively decreases the diameter of the shunt and thus its efficacy. Since the beginning of the 2000s, appeared stents known as "covered" by polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) designed to reduce the obstruction rate and thus the frequency shunt revisions. However, these stents are, on average, 2.5 times more expensive than the non covered stents and the cost-effectiveness ratio of the TIPS according to the type of stents used has not been assessed. The aim of this multicentric and randomized study is to assess the cost-effectiveness ratio of these 2 principles of TIPS, the one using stents covered by PTFE, relatively expensive but seldom becoming obstructed, and the other using non covered stents, less expensive than PTFE but requiring regular gestures of redilatation. Population concerned: Patients with a cirrhotic portal hypertension responsible for: - recurrent variceal bleeding - refractory ascite (or hydrothorax)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PTFE Covered Stents Versus Naked Stents in the TIPS (Transjugular Intra-hepatic Porto-systemic Shunt)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension, Portal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Presence of a cirrhosis as documented by previous liverbiopsy or typical clinical signs Indication validated of the TIPS (Bavéno IV), except notcontrolled acute hemorrhagic : Recurrent variceal bleeding after failure of the usual pharmacological and endoscopic methods Refractory or recurrent ascites or difficult to treat Refractory Hydrothorax Non cirrhotic HTP CHILD C ≥12 Complete portal vein thrombosis Usual contraindication for TIPS : Known or suspected Hepatocarcinoma by increase of the alphafoetoprotein &gt;100 UI/mL associated with the presence of at least one hepatic nodule Cardiac insufficiency defined by a ventricular fraction of ejection &lt; 40% with the echocardiography preliminary to the procedure Pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAP &gt; 40 mmHg) Hepatic polycystosis Intrahepatic bile ducts dilatation, Spontaneous clinical recurrent hepatic encephalopathy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cirrhosis, STIC TIPS, Portal Hypertension, Transjugular Intrahepatic Portosystemic Shunt , Stents, PTFE</keyword>
	<keyword>cirrhotic HTP</keyword>
</DOC>