<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00593788</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study was to establish parameters for the Gaps-in-Noise test in normal-hearing young adults. One hundred subjects (50 males and 50 females) received an audiological evaluation to rule out hearing loss and auditory processing disorder. The Gaps-in-Noise test was then conducted on all subjects. The mean gap detection threshold was 4.19 msec. A psychometric function by gap duration was constructed, revealing that the percentage of correct responses was less than or equal to 5% for a gap duration of 2 msec, 10-30% for a gap duration of 3 msec, 60-70% for a gap duration of 4 msec, and over 96% for gap durations of 5 msec or longer. The results suggest that the data obtained can be applied as reference values for future testing. In the subjects evaluated, the Gaps-in-Noise test proved to be consistent with low variability.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Gaps-in-Noise Test: Gap Detection Thresholds in Normal-Hearing Young Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Subject inclusion criteria were: all of the subjects have to have auditory thresholds lower than 20 dB HL at all of the frequencies evaluated (octave frequencies between 0.25 to 8 kHz), bilaterally; type A tympanometric curves with presented ipsilateral and contralateral acoustic reflexes; 95% or higher correct responses for each ear in the dichotic digit test. Subject inclusion criteria also included negative histories for audiologic, otologic, head trauma, and neurologic involvement. Hearing loss; Auditory processing disorder; Histories of audiologic, otologic, head trauma, and neurologic involvement.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>31 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>GIN test</keyword>
	<keyword>gap detection</keyword>
	<keyword>temporal resolution</keyword>
	<keyword>auditory perception</keyword>
	<keyword>psychoacoustics</keyword>
</DOC>