<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00593801</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objective: To investigate whether recombinant EPO reduces the need for transfusion in extremely low birth weight (ELBW) infants and to determine the optimal time for treatment. The concentrations of trace elements and of antioxidant enzymes were investigated in all patients, too. Study population: 219 patient randomized into 3 groups</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Erythropoietin Treatment in Extremely Low Birth Weight Infants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Methods: Blinded , multicenter trial, ELBW infants were randomized on day 3 to one of 3 groups: early EPO group (rhEPO from the first week for 9 weeks , n= 74), late rhEPO group (rhWEPO from the fourth week for 6 weeks, n=74), or control group (no rhEPO, n= 71). All infants received enteral iron (3-9 mg/kg/day) from the first week. The rhEPO ß dose was 750 IU/kg/week. Success was defined as no transfusion and hematocrit levels never below 30%. The concentrations of trace elements and of antioxidant enzymes were investigated in all patients, too. Clinical and nutritional data were recorded prospectively.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Birth Weight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trace Elements</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antioxidants</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Extremely low birth weight infants Cyanotic heart disease Major congenital malformation requiring surgery Gestational age &gt; 30 weeks Administration of an investigational drug during pregnancy Lack of parental consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>3 Days</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>extremely low birth weight infants</keyword>
	<keyword>transfusion need</keyword>
	<keyword>erythropoietin</keyword>
	<keyword>trace elements</keyword>
	<keyword>antioxidant enzymes</keyword>
	<keyword>reduction of the transfusion need by EPO treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>trace elements and antioxidant enzymes in blood</keyword>
</DOC>