<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01789892</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether giving an anti-inflammatory medication (corticosteroid) prior to a positron emission tomography scan (PET) scan may reduce or eliminate false findings related to inflammation</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Methylprednisolone Before Fludeoxyglucose-Labeled Positron Emission Tomography in Patients With Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess whether premedication with a corticosteroid may reduce false positive findings on fluorodeoxyglucose (fludeoxyglucose F 18 [FDG[) PET/computed tomography (CT) scans in lung cancer patients, by reducing radiotracer uptake in thoracic lymph nodes related to inflammation. OUTLINE: Within 1-14 days of undergoing standard FDG PET/CT scan, patients receive methylprednisolone intravenously (IV) and then undergo a second FDG PET/CT scan. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorodeoxyglucose F18</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient undergoing initial staging of biopsy proven lung cancer (all cancer stages included) Undergone clinical FDG PET/CT scan within 14 days of enrollment Prisoners Diabetic patients (on insulin, on oral hypoglycemic, or fasting glucose &gt; 180 mg/dl) Serious infection within 14 days of enrollment Known hypersensitivity to methylprednisolone Viral skin lesions Immunocompromised ANC(absolute neutrophil count &lt; 1000/microliter) Pregnant/nursing History of tuberculosis or systemic fungal disease History of steroid psychosis Current peptic ulcer disease or diverticulitis Corticosteroid use within 14 days of enrollment (including inhaled steroids)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>