<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01789294</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Aim of this prospective, parallel multi-arm, randomized, clinical trial, was to compare the clinical outcome of patients Methods.We recruited children who undergone diagnostic colonoscopy in Umberto I Pediatric Department (Rome, Italy) from 2008 to 2010. Eligibility criteria were: 1) only demonstration of LNH; 2) no concomitant disease; 3) no treatment assumed since the clinical onset. Patients were allocated 1:1:1 to dietetic (Group A) vs mesalamine (Group B) vs no treatment (Group C) for a 8-weeks period. Skin prick tests and patch test for common foods, and symptoms scoring at baseline and follow up have been performed by blinded clinicians. Chi-square test for trend was used to compare the frequency of symptoms score improvement (&gt;1 point) among groups. The association of baseline features of patients with the clinical response was estimated by frequency analysis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Management of Childhood Intestinal Lymphoid Nodular Hyperplasia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Lymphoid nodular hyperplasia (LNH) of the lower gastrointestinal tract is a common finding in pediatric colonoscopies, whose clinical significance is not yet been clearly established. Although initially considered to be a normal, age-related variant, some authors recently suggested to regard LNH as a marker of food allergy (FA).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mesalamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. isolated finding of LNH[18], defined as the demonstration of a significant cluster of lymphoid nodules (&gt;10/visible field) by endoscopy and lymphoid follicle hyperplasia by hystology; 2. negative results of preliminary evaluation 1. diagnosis of concomitant inflammatory, rheumatic or infectious disease, and 2. the assumption of any dietetic or therapy since the clinical onset.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>lymphoid nodular hyperplasia</keyword>
	<keyword>food allergy</keyword>
</DOC>