<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01789775</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Phase 3 efficacy and safety study of CD07805/47 topical gel in subjects with facial erythema associated with rosacea. The study hypothesis is that CD07805/47 gel, applied topically once daily is more efficacious than vehicle and provides an acceptable safety profile in the treatment of facial erythema associated with rosacea</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 3 Efficacy and Safety Study of CD07805/47 Topical Gel in Subjects With Facial Erythema of Rosacea</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rosacea</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key 1. Male or female who is at least 18 years of age or older. 2. A clinical diagnosis of facial rosacea. 3. A Clinician Erythema Assessment (CEA) score of greater than or equal to 3 at Screening and at Baseline/Day 1 (prior to the study drug application). 4. A Patient Self Assessment (PSA) score of greater than or equal to 3 at Screening and at Baseline/Day 1 (prior to the study drug application). Key 1. More than 20 facial inflammatory lesions of rosacea 2. Particular forms of rosacea (rosacea conglobata, rosacea fulminans, isolated rhinophyma, isolated pustulosis of the chin) or other concomitant facial dermatoses that are similar to rosacea such as perioral dermatitis, demodicidosis, facial keratosis pilaris, seborrheic dermatitis, acute lupus erythematosus, or actinic telangiectasia. 3. Current treatment with monoamine oxidase (MAO) inhibitors, barbiturates, opiates, sedatives, systemic anesthetics, or alpha agonists. 4. Less than 3 months stable dose treatment with tricyclic anti depressants, cardiac glycosides, beta blockers or other antihypertensive agents. 5. Current diagnosis of Raynaud's syndrome, thromboangiitis obliterans, orthostatic hypotension, severe cardiovascular disease, cerebral or coronary insufficiency, renal or hepatic impairment, scleroderma, Sjögren's syndrome, or depression.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>