<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01789866</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Studies suggest that lutein and n-3 fatty acids may influence the development of a child's brain and may be related to how well children learn. Both lutein and the n-3 fats (also known as omega-3 fats) are not made by the body and must be obtained in the diet. The investigators are interested to understand the importance of n-3 fats and lutein to child brain development. Functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) will make it possible to look into the brain from the outside and see which parts of the brain are being used as children complete working memory tasks. The investigators will study brain function using fMRI among children with different intakes of n-3 fats and lutein. Hypothesis: 1. Children 6 years of age consuming &lt; 25 mg/day DHA and &lt; 400 μg lutein/day will show poorer activation of brain areas on fMRI than children consuming &gt; 150 mg/day DHA and &gt; 1,200 μg/day lutein. 2. Children consuming &lt; 400 μg lutein/day and &gt; 150 mg/day DHA will also show differences in fMRI results when compared to children consuming &gt; 150 mg/day DHA and &gt; 1,200 μg/day lutein.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>DHA &amp; Lutein and fMRI Brain Mapping in Healthy Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>fullterm single birth (no multiple births) no major illness or surgery requiring hospitalization likely to impact the outcomes no metabolic, congenital or allergic disease that impact food intakes parents have sufficient command of English language to complete the informed consent and study documents The specific inclusion enrollment criteria for: Group 1: children consuming &lt;25 mg/day DHA and &lt; 400 μg/day lutein, n=24; Group 2: children consuming &gt;150 mg/day DHA and &gt;1,200 μg/day lutein, n=24; Group 3: children consuming &gt;150 mg/day DHA and &lt;400 μg/day lutein, n=10; children of mothers enrolled in studies by our group that involved randomization to supplemental DHA during pregnancy children for whom blood, diet records or developmental tests at 5 years and 9 months of age are incomplete children consuming 25150 mg/day DHA or 4001200 μg/day lutein children of mothers who do not sign the informed consent any children having a cardiac pacemaker, aneurysm clip, cochlear implant of possible metallic foreign bodies in the eyes or other contraindication as detailed in the C&amp;W MRI Patient Screening Form will be excluded from this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>69 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>78 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>DHA</keyword>
	<keyword>lutein</keyword>
	<keyword>cognitive development</keyword>
	<keyword>fMRI</keyword>
</DOC>