<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00229528</DOC>
	<brief_summary>COAT-platelets stands for collagen and thrombin stimulated platelets, which are two things in the body that make platelets stick together. These platelets may be important in the initiation of a heart attack (myocardial infarction). A chemical in the body called serotonin maybe responsible for COAT-platelet production. Paroxetine causes a significant reduction in platelet serotonin and therefore may have value in preventing heart attacks. Therefore, the current study is designed to determine whether paroxetine will decrease COAT-platelet production in normal volunteers and patients with cardiovascular disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Paroxetine on COAT-Platelet Production in Normal Volunteers and Patients With Cardiovascular Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paroxetine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>normal volunteers (without heart disease) patients with heart disease between ages 18 &amp; 65 children less than 18 years adults greater than 65 years those who can not keep appointments patients within 2 weeks of a coronary catheterization patients within 6 months of unstable angina or myocardial infarction individuals with allergies to paroxetine or similar medications individuals having adverse events to paroxetine or similar medications individuals with diagnosis of mania individuals with a diagnosis of hypomania individuals with a diagnosis of bipolar disorders individuals with a diagnosis of depression individuals with a diagnosis of panic disorders individuals with a diagnosis of seizure disorders individuals with a history of suicide attempts individuals with a diagnosis of hyponatremia individuals with active bleeding disorders individuals with a diagnosis of narrow angle glaucoma individuals with an estimated creatinine clearance of less that 30 ml/min individuals taking potentially interacting medications</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2008</verification_date>
</DOC>