<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00634283</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study examines the effects of an antidepressant medication and placebo on the brain functioning of normal subjects. In this study, recordings of brain electrical activity are being used to detect and monitor the response to treatment with venlafaxine IR (Effexor), a drug used for the treatment of depression. The intent of this study is to test specific hypotheses regarding: 1. long-term brain effects of a single course of antidepressant treatment 2. pharmaco-conditioning effects underlying antidepressant tolerance/sensitization 3. brain functional response to initial versus subsequent antidepressant trials in normal healthy subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Effects of an Antidepressant Medication and Placebo on the Brain Functioning of Normal Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Venlafaxine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antidepressive Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject age is 1875 years Subject must be in overall good health (i.e., free of any medical condition known to affect brain function). Subject must have participated in former study, Physiologic Monitoring of Antidepressant Medication Effects in Normal Controls Subjects (IRB#: 001103813) Subject has had a normal physical exam within one year prior to entry of the study Capacity to give Informed Consent Subject has serious medical illness, such as high blood pressure, heart disease, renal impairment, or cirrhosis of the liver. Subject meets DSMIV Axis I criteria for a mood, anxiety, cognitive, or psychiatric disorder; or meets criteria for cluster A or B axis II diagnoses. These disorders will be determined on the basis of a structured assessment with the MINI (Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview for DSMIV Axis I Disorders) Subject has a history of current or past active suicidal ideation or suicide attempts. Subject has received treatment with an antidepressant medication or any medications that could influence brain function since his/her participation in the initial study Subject is using any of the following medications which interfere with EEG measures of brain function: Anticholinergics, Barbiturates, Benzodiazepines, Sedating Antihistamines (e.g. diphenhydramine (Benadryl) would be exclusionary, but not loratadine (Claritin)) Subject has a history of seizures, brain surgery, skull fracture, significant head trauma, or previous abnormal EEG Subject is pregnant or planning on becoming pregnancy during course of the study Subject is a UCLA student or staff member directly under instruction or employment of any of the investigators</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2009</verification_date>
</DOC>