<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00634439</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Using a proprietary insurance health claims database, Eli Lilly and Company has contracted with an external party to conduct a retrospective cohort study of health claims for the time period from 1 January 2003 through 31 December 2006 (with follow-up of patients through 30 June 2007). This study will evaluate the potential association between atomoxetine and cerebrovascular events. In this study, the incidence of selected cerebrovascular outcomes as represented in health claims data among adult patients who initiate therapy with atomoxetine will be estimated. In particular the study will focus on cerebrovascular accident (CVA) and transient ischemic attack (TIA) as the outcomes of interest. The incidence for each outcome among atomoxetine initiators will then be compared to the incidence in a cohort of similar patients who initiate stimulant treatment and an age and gender-matched general population cohort. The atomoxetine and stimulant-initiating cohorts will be matched on a broad variety of variables, including age, gender, diagnoses, medication use, and healthcare utilization through the use of propensity score matching in order to minimize the influence of confounding by indication. The analysis will include the cohorts (atomoxetine and stimulant initiators) from a previous completed study with increased follow-up time (1 January 2003 through 30 June 2007) and accrue new atomoxetine and stimulant ADHD medication initiators over a 2 year period, so that the study will represent initiators between January 1, 2003 and December 31, 2006 with follow-up through June 30, 2007.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of Atomoxetine and Cerebrovascular Outcomes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemic Attack, Transient</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atomoxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylphenidate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Stimulants</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients 18 years or older received dispensing of one of the study medications during the time period of the study (January 1, 2003 December 31, 2006) 6 months of continuous enrollment prior to first dispensing presence of preexisting arrhythmia and heart failure during the baseline period</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>cerebrovascular accident</keyword>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>transient ischemic attack</keyword>
	<keyword>TIA</keyword>
	<keyword>CVA</keyword>
	<keyword>attention deficit hyperactivity disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>ADHD</keyword>
</DOC>