<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02134080</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this trial is to examine the safety, tolerability and feasibility in the use of a FAAH inhibitor for the treatment of adults with Tourette syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>FAAH Inhibitor Trial for Adults With Tourette Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tourette Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult between 1860 years of age Meet DSM IV criteria for the diagnosis of Tourette's syndrome Significant current tic symptoms: YGTSS total tic score greater than or equal to 22 at baseline On stable psychiatric medication regimen for a minimum of 4 weeks prior to beginning the trial. Accepted method of birth control Comorbid bipolar disorder, psychotic disorder, substance use disorder, developmental disorder or intellectual disability (IQ&lt;70). Current use of medications that have significant effects on the cannabinoid or dopamine systems. Subjects will be specifically excluded for recent use (within last 8 weeks) of antipsychotic medications, dopamine agonists or psychostimulants. Recent change (less than 4 weeks) in other medications that have potential effects on tic severity (such as alpha2 agonists (guanfacine, clonidine or prazosin), SSRIs, clomipramine, naltrexone, lithium, anxiolytics, topiramate, baclofen etc.). Medication change is defined to include dose changes or medication discontinuation. Recent change in behavioral treatment for Tourette syndrome or comorbid conditions (i.e. OCD) within the last 4 weeks or initiation of behavioral therapy for tics within the last 12 weeks. Positive pregnancy test or drug screening test History of cannabis dependence Significant Medical Comorbidity</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tourette Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>FAAH-Inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Tics</keyword>
	<keyword>Tic Disorders</keyword>
</DOC>