<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01018537</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This project is based on the idea that we can learn about the complexities of MS by following disease and treatment patterns in a large group of people over several years. The information gathered is used for research only. Results are presented in summary form only. All details submitted by registry participants is strictly confidential. To participate in NARCOMS complete the baseline enrollment survey online at www.narcoms.org or you can request a mail-in survey be sent to you using the contact information provided. You will be asked to update the survey, online or by mail, twice a year. Each survey typically takes less than 20 minutes to complete. Surveys are available in English and Spanish. There is no cost to participate, for your participation you are offered a free subscription to the NARCOMS Quarterly Magazine. A quarterly magazine delivered to all NARCOMS participants provides a reliable source of information about the latest in MS research and disease management. You can quit participating at any time. You may also receive additional surveys or information on clinical trials. You are not obligated to participate and these additional studies will always come directly from NARCOMS. Your contact information will not be shared or sold to other parties.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Global Demyelinating Disease Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The data coordinating center, located at University of Alabama at Birmingham (UAB), maintains NARCOMS, the worlds largest voluntary, patient driven MS registry. The registry involves personnel from at least three other sites in the US and Canada (Rocky Mountain Multiple Sclerosis Center Anschutz Medical Campus in Aurora Colorado, Barrows Neurological Institute in Phoenix Arizona, and the University of Manitoba in Canada). Over the past 10 years more than 35,000 people with MS across the U.S., Canada and over 50 other countries, including over 4,000 Veterans, have participated in the registry by submitting their health-related data by mail or online. Registry data have been featured in 34 peer-reviewed journal articles and more than 80 scientific posters and presentations. These reports have provided information to guide new research. They also provide evidence supporting the approval of new drugs in the fight against MS. The North American Research Committee on Multiple Sclerosis (NARCOMS) is supported in part by the Consortium of Multiple Sclerosis Centers (CMSC), a not-for-profit professional organization for multiple sclerosis (MS) healthcare providers and researchers involving 198 participating centers of the MS treatment and research community.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Demyelinating Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Any individual who has been diagnosed with multiple sclerosis or clinically isolated syndrome Must be at least 18 years of age</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>NARCOMS</keyword>
	<keyword>Global Patient Registry</keyword>
</DOC>