<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="130617">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01401595</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>806753</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01401595</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Brain Imaging and Treatment Studies of the Night Eating Syndrome</brief_title>
  <acronym>NES</acronym>
  <official_title>Brain Imaging and Treatment Studies of the Night Eating Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Forest Laboratories</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the effectiveness of the anti-depressant Lexapro
      in the treatment of the Night Eating Syndrome.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This proposal explores the implications of our two recent major discoveries: the striking
      efficacy of the Selective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitor (SSRI) sertraline in the control of
      the Night Eating Syndrome (NES) and the unprecedented elevation in the level of serotonin
      transporter (SERT) binding in the midbrain of persons with NES. Our overall theory is that
      NES is associated with a syndrome-specific increase in SERT derived from a genetic
      vulnerability which is affected by life stress. This increased SERT activity produces a fall
      in post-synaptic serotonin levels. The investigators hypothesize that these decreased
      serotonin levels result in a significant phase delay in circadian food intake manifested by
      evening hyperphagia, nighttime ingestions and morning anorexia. SSRIs that block this
      increased SERT activity increase synaptic serotonin levels and restore the circadian rhythm
      of food intake.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brain Imaging and SERT binding</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The brain imaging performed before treatment (SPECT scan) is designed to determine if a measure, the serotonin transporter (SERT), is increased in the brain of persons with Night Eating Syndrome as compared to controls, and if this increase predicts the outcome of treatment for Night Eating Syndrome with Lexapro.
Outcome of treatment will be measured by self report questionnaires (The Night Eating Questionnaire, The Night Eating Symptom Scale, and The Eating Disorder Examination). A higher score on these measures is an indicator of disordered eating patterns.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SERT Binding and Night Eating Symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The second outcome will be the determination of the correlation between SERT binding and responses on the Night Eating Questionnaire (NEQ).
Subjects will complete the NEQ at their baseline visit, and at every treatment visit thereafter. The NEQ is a self report measure of night eating episodes. The NEQ will indicate whether or not Lexapro is having an effect on our patients' night eating symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">87</enrollment>
  <condition>Night Eating Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Night Eaters</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be given a medical history, height and weight will be measured, and BMI calculated. Initial outpatient assessment will include diary measurement of food intake and nighttime awakenings (and associated food intake) together with psychological testing. For women, a pregnancy test will also be administered no more than 48 hours before SPECT-CT imaging and the beginning of Lexapro treatment. Lexapro treatment will last 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Subjects</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>At the beginning of the study, control subjects will be given a medical history, height and weight will be measured, and BMI calculated. Initial outpatient assessment will include diary measurement of food intake and nighttime awakenings (and associated food intake) together with psychological testing.
An ADAM SPECT or SPECT-CT study of SERT binding will be conducted which will compare SERT binding of the 10 control subjects with that of the 30 night eating subjects. The first procedure will be to assess SPECT or SPECT-CT images of night eaters and controls following up our pilot SPECT study of night eaters and controls.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>escitalopram oxalate</intervention_name>
    <description>The purpose of this study is to determine the effectiveness of the anti-depressant Lexapro in the treatment of the Night Eating Syndrome. An ADAM SPECT-CT study of SERT binding will be conducted which will compare SERT binding in 30 night eaters with that of 10 control subjects. The first procedure will be to assess SPECT-CT images of night eaters and controls following up our pilot SPECT study of night eaters and controls. Medication will be administered starting at 10 mg daily, with increase up to 20 mg, as indicated and tolerated, for up to three months. Visits will occur at baseline and weeks 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, and 12.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Night Eaters</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lexapro</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  men and women suffering from NES

          -  ages 18 to 70 years

          -  BMI greater than 18.5 kg/m2

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Children or adolescents &lt;18 years

          -  persons older than 70

          -  patients with diabetes mellitus

          -  thyroid disease and other endocrine and metabolic disorders

          -  use within the past month of any psychotropic medication, oral steroids, diuretics or
             hypnotics

          -  current anorexia nervosa or bulimia nervosa

          -  participation in an organized weight reduction program

          -  use of antiobesity medication

          -  an occupation that involves night shifts or other unusual time requirements -Major
             Depressive Disorder (judged severe)

          -  Bipolar Disorder

          -  suicidal risk

          -  current or past psychosis

          -  substance use or abuse disorder within the past 6 months
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kelly C Allison, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pennsylvania</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Center for Weight and Eating Disorders</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.med.upenn.edu/weight/research.shtml</url>
    <description>The Center for Weight and Eating Disorders</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 27, 2012</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 23, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Pennsylvania</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kelly Allison</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Dexetimide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Citalopram</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
