<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03021486</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this clinical research study is to learn if chlorpromazine, high-dose haloperidol, or a combination of the 2 drugs can help to control the symptoms of delirium (loss of contact with reality) in patients with advanced cancer who did not respond to low-dose haloperidol. High-dose haloperidol doses are usually about 2-4 times the size of low-dose haloperidol. In addition, researchers want to learn if treating patients with these drugs can help to lessen any distress that their caregivers may be having. The safety of these drugs will also be studied.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Haloperidol and/or Chlorpromazine for Refractory Agitated Delirium</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Groups: If you are found to be eligible and agree to take part, you will be randomly assigned (as in a roll of the dice) to 1 of 3 study groups. This is done because no one knows if one study group is better, the same, or worse than the other group. You will have an equal chance of being in each group. - If you are in Group 1, you will receive haloperidol. - If you are in Group 2, you will receive chlorpromazine. - If you are in Group 3, you will receive haloperidol and chlorpromazine. Neither you nor the study staff will know which study drug you are receiving. However, if needed for your safety, the study staff will be able to find out what you are receiving. Study Drug Administration You will receive the study drug(s) by vein over about 3-15 minutes every 4 hours until you are discharged from the palliative care unit or you withdraw from the study. You may receive additional doses every 1 hour, if needed. The dose level and length of administration may be raised or lowered to meet your needs. Length of Treatment You may continue receiving the study drug(s) for as long as you are in the palliative care unit. You may stop receiving the study drug(s) at any time that you and/or your caregiver decides it is in your best interest. Baseline Procedures Before your first dose of the study drug(s): - Your demographic information (such as age, sex, date of birth, race, marital status, and education), medical information, and cancer history will be recorded. - You will complete a test to measure your level of delirium. To complete this test, the study doctor will ask you to complete several thinking tasks, such as recalling a set of numbers or words, remembering different objects, and stating what day it is. This test should take less than 10 minutes to complete. - You will complete 1 questionnaire about any symptoms you may be having. This should take about 5 minutes to complete. Study Procedures: Every 8 hours during the first 24 hours that you are in the palliative care unit, you will repeat the symptoms questionnaire. After the first 24 hours, you will complete the questionnaire 1 time each day until you are discharged. If and when you recover from the delirium, you will be asked to complete a questionnaire about your experience with delirium. This should take about 5 minutes to complete. Your active participation on this study will be over at that point. This is an investigational study. Both chlorpromazine and haloperidol are FDA approved and commercially available for the treatment of bipolar disorder and psychotic disorders. Their use to help control delirium is investigational. The study doctor can explain how the study drugs are designed to work. Up to 54 patients will take part in this study. All will be enrolled at MD Anderson.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Delirium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Haloperidol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorpromazine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Haloperidol decanoate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. [Patients] Diagnosis of advanced cancer (defined as locally advanced, metastatic recurrent, or incurable disease) 2. [Patients] Admitted to the acute palliative care unit 3. [Patients] Delirium as per DSMV criteria 4. [Patients] Hyperactive or mixed delirium with RASS &gt;/=2 in the past 24 h 5. [Patients] On scheduled haloperidol for delirium (&lt;/=8 mg in the past 24 h) 6. [Patients] Age 18 years or older 7. [Family Caregivers] Patient's spouse, adult child, sibling, parent, other relative, or significant other (defined by the patient as a partner) 8. [Family Caregivers] Age 18 years or older 9. [Family Caregivers] At the patient's bedside at least 4 h/day 1. [Patients] History of myasthenia gravis or acute narrow angle glaucoma 2. [Patients] History of neuroleptic malignant syndrome or active seizure disorder (with seizure episode within the past week) 3. [Patients] History of Parkinson's disease or Alzheimer's dementia 4. [Patients] History of prolonged QTc interval (&gt;500 ms) 5. [Patients] History of hypersensitivity to haloperidol or chlorpromazine 6. [Patients] On scheduled chlorpromazine within the past 48 h</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Malignant neoplasms of independent (primary) multiple sites</keyword>
	<keyword>Haloperidol</keyword>
	<keyword>Chlorpromazine</keyword>
	<keyword>Chlorpromazine hydrochloride</keyword>
	<keyword>Thorazine</keyword>
	<keyword>Symptom questionnaire</keyword>
	<keyword>Survey</keyword>
	<keyword>Delirium</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute palliative care unit</keyword>
	<keyword>APCU</keyword>
</DOC>