<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03021395</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this open-label, prospective clinical trial, the investigators enrolled acute myeloid leukemia (AML) patients after consolidation therapy. Patients with minimal residual disease (MRD) receive decitabine treatment if patients do not receive stem cell transplantation. The MRD clearance rate is the primary outcome to measure the efficacy of decitabine regimen.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Decitabine in Clearance of MRD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this open-label, prospective clinical trial, acute myeloid leukemia (AML) patients after consolidation therapy are enrolled. Patients with minimal residual disease (MRD) after consolidation therapy receive decitabine treatment if patients do not receive stem cell transplantation. The treatment regimen includes three course of decitabine regimen at a dose of 20mg/m² on day1-5. The MRD clearance rate is the primary outcome to measure the efficacy of decitabine regimen.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Decitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Azacitidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age of 14 to 55 years old; 2. Patients that meet the diagnostic criteria(WHO 2008 criteria) of AML after consolidation regimen. 3. Patients who had received induction and consolation therapy and reached CR. 4. ECOG score of ≤ 2; 5. Patients with eligible laboratory examination including liver,renal and heart function. 6. Adult patients are willing to participate in the study and sign the informed consent by themselves or by their immediate family. Patients under 18 years old willing to participate should have their legal guardians sign the informed consent. 1. Secondary leukemia. 2. Patients had other tumor at active stage or had received radiotherapy or chemotherapy in the last 6 months due to other tumor. 3. Patients with other blood diseases(for example, haemophiliacs) are excluded.However, undiagnosed MDS or MPD patients are included. 4. Acute panmyelosis with myelofibrosis and myeloid sarcoma patients; 5. With BCRABL fusion gene; 6. Pregnant or lactating women; 7. With ineligible renal or liver function; 8. With active cardiovascular disease; 9. Severe infection disease including uncured tuberculosis pulmonary aspergillosis; 10. AIDS; 11. Patients had central nervous system involvement when they were diagnosed as AML. 12. Patients with epilepsy or dementia or other mental disease who couldn't understand or follow the research. 13. Drugs, medical, mental or social situation may distract patients from following the research or being evaluated the results. 14. Patients with other factors which were considered unsuitable to participate in the study by the investigators.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>