<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02245594</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study we would like to clarify the effect of long lasting Crohn's Disease on motility of the gastrointestinal system in patient and the effect regarding sleep disturbances. This will be done with a newly developed 3D-Motility-and-Transit-detector (Motilis Medica, Schweiz) and the well known polysomnographic equipment. Our hypothesises are: Patients with ileocoecal and/or colonic CD in remission and gastrointestinal symptoms have abnormal colonic transit (primary endpoint). 1. Patients with ileocoecal and/or colonic CD in remission and gastrointestinal symptoms have abnormal gastric emptying and small intestinal transit (secondary endpoints). 2. Total and segmental transit times found in patients with CD will be compared with corresponding transit times in healthy volunteers found in a previous study. 3. Patients with ileocoecal and/or colonic CD in remission have abnormal sleep patterns. 4. Nocturnal basic colonic activity, have changed in patients with ileocoecal and/or colonic CD in remission and sleep disturbances.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>GI Symptoms and Sleep Disturbances in Patients With Quiescent Crohns Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyssomnias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with CD based on accepted endoscopic and histological criteria (according to ECCO guidelines (17) ) Age ≥18 years A minimum disease duration of five years Remission defined by Faecal calprotectin &lt; 100 and CRP level within normal values for a minimum of 1 month Baseline values: CRP normal Faecal calprotectin &lt; 100 Ileocoecal and/or colic localization of disease (Montreal phenotype classification) One or more IBSlikesymptoms (abdominal pain and discomfort, diarrhea, constipation) Stricturizing CD Obvious stenotic symptoms Previous major gastrointestinal surgery Diagnosis of other gastrointestinal diseases affecting motility (ex. Coeliac disease) Medication altering gastrointestinal motility Hepatobiliary disease (PSC) Diabetes Mellitus Metabolic disorder Bacterial overgrowth (hydrogen breath test) Planned MR scan in the four weeks following capsule intake (safety precaution) Abdominal diameter &gt; 140 cm Implanted electronic devices (pacemaker, ICD, etc.) Diagnosed sleep disorder Pregnancy and breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gastrointestinal motility</keyword>
	<keyword>Motility Tracking System (MTS)</keyword>
	<keyword>Transit time</keyword>
	<keyword>Sleep pattern</keyword>
</DOC>