<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02245217</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study of multi-tracer PET scans to assess response to gemcitabine in pancreatic cancer</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multi-Tracer PET Prediction and Assessment of Response to Gemcitabine in Pancreatic Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have either 1. histologically/cytologicallyconfirmed borderline resectable pancreatic cancer and be prescribed neoadjuvant gemcitabineplusAbraxane as part of their standard of care 2. histologically/cytologicallyconfirmed locally advanced unresectable pancreatic cancer and be prescribed neoadjuvant gemcitabineplusAbraxane as part of their standard of care. Diagnostic quality abdominal imaging (CT or MRI) within the past 45 days. Patients must be 18 years or older for inclusion in this research study. There is little experience with the safety of [18F]FLT in children and therefore this radiopharmaceutical should not be used in patients under the age of 18. Patients must be willing to lie flat on their back in the PET/CT scanner for up to 2 hours to allow the imaging data to be obtained. Patients must document their willingness to be followed for up to 24 months following enrollment in this imaging trial. By signing informed consent, the patients will document their agreement to have clinical and radiographic endpoints and the results of histopathologic tissue analysis and other laboratory information entered into a research database. All patients must sign a written informed consent and HIPAA authorization in accordance with institutional guidelines. Determination of pregnancy status: Female patients who are not postmenopausal or surgically sterile will undergo a serum pregnancy test prior to baseline and the subsequent set of multitracer PET scans. The serum pregnancy test must be performed within 48 hours prior to research PET imaging. A negative test will be necessary for such patients to undergo research PET imaging. ECOG Performance Status 02. Adequate organ function and laboratory parameters as defined laboratory testing. Any prior systemic or investigational therapy for pancreatic cancer. Patients with known allergic or hypersensitivity reactions to previously administered radiopharmaceuticals (patients with significant drug or other allergies or autoimmune diseases may be enrolled at the Investigator's discretion). Patients who are pregnant or lactating or who suspect they might be pregnant. Serum pregnancy tests will be obtained prior to the baseline and subsequent multitracer PET scans in female patients that are not postmenopausal or surgically sterile. Adult patients who require monitored anesthesia for PET scanning. Patients known to be HIV positive. This is due to the potential toxicities of [18F]FLT in HIV positive patients. Preexisting sensory neuropathy greater than grade 1. Prior malignancy except for adequately treated basal cell skin cancer, in situ cervical cancer or any other form of cancer from which the patient has been diseasefree for 5 years. Uncontrolled diabetes or blood glucose greater than180 mg/dl on the day of the [18F]FDGPET scan. Major surgery within 4 weeks of the start of study treatment, without complete recovery. Any other condition that would, in the Investigator's judgment, contraindicate patient's participation in the clinical study due to safety concerns or compliance with clinical study procedures, e.g. infection/inflammation, intestinal obstruction, social complications.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>