<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01051505</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to explore the safety and tolerability of AZD5069 at steady-state, following twice a day oral dosing in healthy subjects. AZD5069 is being developed by AstraZeneca and this study is being carried out on behalf of the sponsor by Quintiles Drug Research Unit at Guy's Hospital, London. This is the second time that AZD5069 will be administered to humans in clinical trials. We are conducting this study to determine whether AZD5069 is safe and well tolerated by healthy males and females at different dose levels over an 8-day dosing period. We will also be studying how quickly AZD5069 is absorbed into and cleared by the body. It is planned that there will be up to 3 dose groups in the study and each group will consist of up to 12 volunteers, with 9 receiving the active drug and 3 receiving placebo. The study involves 3 visits over approximately 8 weeks, and will include 1 residential visit lasting 10 nights and a follow up.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics (PK) and Pharmacodynamics (PD) of Multiple Ascending Doses of AZD5069 in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Provision of signed and dated, written informed consent Have a body mass index (BMI) between 18 and 30 kg/m2 inclusive and weigh at least 50 kg and no more than 100 kg Healthy male or female (of non child bearing potential)volunteers with suitable veins for cannulation or repeated venepuncture Subjects must not have any clinically significant disease or disorder, which, in the opinion of the Investigator, may either put the subject at risk because of participation in the study, or influence the results, or the subjects ability to participate Subjects must not have any history of gastrointestinal, liver or kidney disease, or any other condition known to interfere with how drugs are absorbed, used or eliminated by the body Subjects must not have had any significant illness or medical/surgical procedures or injuries with 4 weeks of administration of the investigational product</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Phase I</keyword>
	<keyword>multiple ascending dose</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Tolerability</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy Volunteer</keyword>
</DOC>