<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00716274</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the effects of atomoxetine on brain activation during attention and reading tasks via functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI) in patients ages 10 to 16 years old with ADHD and comorbid dyslexia</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Atomoxetine on Brain Activation During Attention and Reading Tasks in Patients With ADHD &amp; Comorbid Dyslexia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, single site study that uses an fMRI measurement to assess brain activation during attention and reading tasks and the effects of atomoxetine in reducing symptoms of ADHD in patients with ADHD and comorbid dyslexia. Similar assessments are performed in two additional groups of patients with ADHD only and dyslexia only to determine to what extent symptomatic change in the comorbid ADHD &amp; dyslexia is achieved independently by atomoxetine effects on either condition. A healthy control group of non-ADHD, non-dyslexia subjects (20) will be included to monitor practice effects &amp; effects of treatment that may be interpreted as normal maturation. The healthy control group will not be treated with any study medications.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyslexia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atomoxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must meet DSMIVTR criteria for ADHD Patient must meet DSMIVTR criteria for dyslexia Patients must achieve a score of 80 or more on the Full Scale Intelligence Quotient Child or adolescent patients must be 10 to 16 years old Must be able to communicate in English Must be able to swallow capsules Be reliable to keep appointments for clinic visits &amp; all related tests Subjects for healthy control group do not meet DSMIVTR criteria for AHHD and/or dyslexia Subjects for healthy control group must achieve a score of at least 80 but not &gt;120 on the Full Scale Intelligence Quotient Patients who weigh less than 25 kg or greater than 70 kg Patients with severe allergies to more than 1 class of medications or who have had multiple adverse drug reactions Patients with prior diagnosis of bipolar I or bipolar II disorder or psychosis Patients with documented history of autism, Asperger's syndrome, or pervasive developmental disorder Females who are pregnant or breastfeeding Patients treated with atomoxetine at a therapeutic dose (1.2 mg/kg/day) for at least 4 to 6 weeks</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>