<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02729025</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A study to assess the effects of proprotein convertase subtilisin/ kexin type 9 (PCSK9) inhibition on the arterial wall inflammation in patients with elevated lipoprotein(a).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Proprotein Convertase Subtilisin/Kexin Type 9 (PCSK9) Inhibition on Arterial Wall Inflamation Study in Patients With Elevated Lipoprotein(a) (Lp(a)).</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dyslipidemias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperlipidemias</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Fasting lipoprotein(a) (Lp(a)) 50mg/dL or more at screening 1 Fasting Lowdensity lipoproteincholesterol (LDLC) 100mg/dL or more at screening 1 Lipid lowering therapy including statin dose unchanged for at least 8 weeks prior to screening Targettobackground ratio (TBR) max higher than 1.6 (either right, left carotid or thoracic aorta) on fluorodeoxyglucosepositron emission tomography/computed tomography (FDGPET/CT). Currently receiving, or less than 4 weeks since receiving, treatment in another investigational device or drug study(ies), or participating in other investigational procedures Known diagnosis of diabetes mellitus or screening fasting serum glucose ≥ 126 mg/dL or hemoglobin A1C (HbA1C) ≥ 6.5% Subject with a history of homozygous familial hypercholesterolemia History of a Cardiovascular event Subject currently undergoing lipid apheresis Known contraindications or limitations to FDGPET/ CT (scanner weight limit, devices that can cause image artifacts, or carotid/aortic stents/grafts Subject has had exposure to investigational drugs targeting Lp(a) within the last 12 months, prior to Screening Other Exclusion Criteria May Apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hyperlipidemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Dyslipidemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Proprotein convertase subtilisin/kexin type 9 (PCSK9) Inhibition</keyword>
	<keyword>Arterial Wall Inflamation</keyword>
	<keyword>Elevated lipoprotein a</keyword>
</DOC>