<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02729259</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to find additional methods to reduce pain during wound care. In this study the investigators use virtual reality (a form of distraction) in addition to pain medication during a burn wound care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>H2O VR for Burns 2015</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will employ a randomized within-subjects design. There are three different conditions in this study. By randomization, the participants will experience at least two of the conditions and likely all three, depending on the number of their wound care sessions. All subjects will always receive all their usual pain medications for all treatment conditions. The three conditions are: High Tech Virtual Reality (VRD), Low Tech Virtual Reality (Nature Slides), and standard wound care (no VR). The subjects will be randomly assigned to receive some portions of their wound care sessions during High Tech Virtual Reality (VRD), some portions during Low Tech Virtual Reality (Nature Slides), and some portions with standard wound care, no virtual reality. The treatment orders will be randomized. After each treatment condition the investigators will ask subjects one pain question about their pain intensity during the most recent treatment condition.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Burns</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age greater than or equal to 18 years Compliant and able to complete questionnaires No history of psychiatric disorder Not demonstrating delirium, psychosis or any form of Organic Brain Disorder Able to communicate verbally Englishspeaking Age less than 18 years Not capable of indicating pain intensity Not capable of filling out study measures Evidence of traumatic brain injury History of psychiatric disorder Demonstrating delirium, psychosis or any form of Organic Brain Disorder and associated memory problems Unable to communicate orally Receiving prophylaxis for alcohol or drug withdrawal Developmental disability Any face/head/neck injuries that interfere with the use of Virtual Reality equipment NonEnglish Speaking Extreme susceptibility to motion sickness Seizure history</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>VRD</keyword>
</DOC>