<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01273259</DOC>
	<brief_summary>DHEA prevents and reverses chronic hypoxic pulmonary hypertension in a chronic hypoxic-pulmonary hypertension model in the rat. However, no study has been performed in human. The purpose of this study is to determine if DHEA is effective in the treatment of respiratory pulmonary hypertension in adults with Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) on exercise capacity and haemodynamic variables. Patients will receive after randomisation either 25 mg/day or 200mg/day oral DHEA over a one-year period. Evaluation concerns clinical parameters, echocardiography and right catheterization after and before treatment. Primary end-point is the six-minute walk test. This is a prospective double blind, randomised, placebo controlled study which will be realized in four university hospitals in France : Bordeaux, Strasbourg, Toulouse and Limoges.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA) in Respiratory Pulmonary Hypertension in Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dehydroepiandrosterone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years old and ≤ 75 years old Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease with FEVs/VC &lt; 70% (*) Respiratory pulmonary hypertension with mean pulmonary arterial pressure ≥ 20 mmHg (*) related to normal pulmonary capillar pressure assessed by catheterization of the right side of the heart (pulmonary capillary wedge pressure ≤12mmHg) PO2 ≤ 70 mmHg assessed by arterial gasometry at ease If oxygenotherapy then oxygenotherapy more than 6 months before prescreening Written informed consent (*) Criteria assessed from last health check or the last exams for COPD diagnosis clinical instability and/or respiratory exacerbation dangerous for catheterization Pregnancy (ßHCG &gt; 20 UI /l) or breastfeeding on going General corticotherapy &gt; 0,5 mg/kg/day prednisolon equivalent Hepatic insufficiency (TP &lt; 50%) or renal insufficiency (creatininemia &gt; 130 µmol/l) or diabetes mellitus type I or II (treated by oral antidiabetic or insulin) Leftheart failure (coronary heart disease and/or left valvulopathy) High level of prostatic specific antigen (PSA) (&gt; 7ng/ml) Cancer antecedent or treatment on going</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hypertension, pulmonary</keyword>
	<keyword>DHEA</keyword>
	<keyword>six-minute walk test</keyword>
	<keyword>pulmonary arterial pressure</keyword>
</DOC>