<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00830804</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the effectiveness and safety of an antiretroviral therapy (ART) regimen consisting of raltegravir (RAL) and darunavir (DRV)/ritonavir (RTV) as first-line therapy in treatment-naïve participants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Effectiveness of Raltegravir Plus Darunavir/Ritonavir in Treatment-Naive HIV-Infected Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Despite the remarkable strides made in the treatment of HIV-1-infected persons over the last decade, current first-line ART regimens are imperfect. The ideal combination, unlike some current first-line options, would have uncompromised efficacy in the presence of transmitted drug-resistant variants. The primary purpose of this study is to estimate the cumulative proportion of ART-naive participants experiencing virologic failure at or prior to week 24 after initiating raltegravir (RAL) plus darunavir/ritonavir (DRV/RTV). The study will last 52 weeks. All participants will follow the same treatment schedule and take RAL plus DRV/RTV orally daily for the duration of the trial. After entry, all participants will have scheduled visits at weeks 1, 4, 12, 24, 36, 48, and 52. Medical/medication history, blood and urine collection, and liver function tests will occur at screening. A targeted physical exam and concomitant medications history will occur at all study visits. Blood and urine collection and liver function tests will occur at most study visits. For females, a pregnancy test will occur at screening and study entry. RAL and DRV were provided by the study. RTV was not provided by the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Darunavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Raltegravir Potassium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HIV1infected Plasma HIV1 RNA of at least 5,000 copies/mL within 90 days prior to study entry HIV genotype (for reverse transcriptase and protease) performed at any time prior to study entry. More information on this criterion can be found in the protocol. ARV drugnaive. More information on this criterion can be found in the protocol. Negative result from a hepatitis B surface antigen test performed within 90 days prior to study entry Agree to use one form of medicallyaccepted contraceptive throughout the study and for 60 days after stopping study treatment. More information on this criterion can be found in the protocol. Serious illness requiring systemic treatment and/or hospitalization for at least 7 days prior to study. More information on this criterion can be found in the protocol. Screening HIV genotype obtained any time prior to study entry with more than one DRV resistanceassociated mutation [RAM] (V11I, V32I, L33F, I47V, I50V, I54L, I54M, T74P, I84V, and L89V) or L76V alone Known major integrase inhibitor RAM(s), including N155H, Q148H/R/K, Y143C/R, and G140S Severe renal insufficiency requiring hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis Treatment with immunomodulators within 30 days prior to study entry. More information on this criterion can be found in the protocol. Current medications that are prohibited with any study medications. More information on this criterion can be found in the protocol. Known allergy/sensitivity to study drugs or their formulations. A history of sulfa allergy is not an exclusion. Active drug or alcohol use or dependence that, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with the study. Certain abnormal laboratory results. More information on this criterion can be found in the protocol. Pregnant or breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Treatment Naive</keyword>
</DOC>