<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01873768</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Tranexamic acid (TXA) and ε-aminocaproic acid (EACA) are two drugs shown to limit blood loss following major surgery, from cardiac to orthopedic procedures. Yet compared to tranexamic acid (TXA), research on the clinical impact of ε-aminocaproic acid (EACA) in total knee arthroplasty (TKA) is limited. The primary aim of this study is to determine whether TXA and EACA provide similar blood decreasing effects following TKA or whether one drug provides a superior effect over the other in reducing patients' blood loss.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Efficacy of Tranexamic Acid and ε-Aminocaproic Acid in Reducing Blood Loss Following Total Knee Replacement</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aminocaproic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tranexamic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Persons aged 18 90 years who are scheduled to undergo a unilateral total knee replacement surgery NonEnglish speaking individuals Individuals with a history of deep vein thrombosis or pulmonary embolism within one year Individuals with a history of coagulopathy Heart stent within one year Preoperative autologous blood donation Unwilling or unable to take Coumadin for deep vein thrombosis (DVT) prophylaxis Received nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug (NSAID) or platelet antiaggregant treatment within five days prior to surgery Preoperative creatinine greater than 1.5mg/dL</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tranexamic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>6-Aminocaproic Acid</keyword>
	<keyword>Arthroplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Osteoarthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>Arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>Joint Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Musculoskeletal Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Rheumatic Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Antifibrinolytic Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Fibrin Modulating Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacologic Actions</keyword>
	<keyword>Coagulants</keyword>
	<keyword>Therapeutic Uses</keyword>
</DOC>