<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01873274</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to investigate the absorption of menaquinone-7 from a nutrient-enriched dairy product compared to a general dairy product enriched with menaquinone-7 and a menaquinone-7-containing supplement.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparative Study Menaquinone-7</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In an earlier study, beneficial effects of a nutrient-enriched dairy product on vitamin K-status were observed. The study product contained menaquinone-7 (MK-7) and omega-3 fatty acids for vascular health and extra minerals and antioxidants to support general health. It was the first time that such low dose of MK-7 (50 µg) could significantly improve vascular and general vitamin K-status already after short-term treatment. From the results of this study, it was assumed that the matrix of the dairy product and/or other components in the product, in which the vitamin was offered, contributed to optimal absorption and availability of vitamin K2. In this new study, the uptake and efficacy of MK-7 from the nutrient enriched product is investigated and compared to the uptake and efficacy from a MK-7-containing supplement and a basic dairy product enriched with MK-7.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin K 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin K</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin MK 7</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Apparently healthy men and postmenopausal women between 45 and 65 years old Subjects with body weight and height according to BMI between 20 and 30 kg/m2 Subjects of Caucasian race Subject has given written consent to take part in the study Subjects with hypertension Subjects with hypercholesterolemia Subjects with (a history of) metabolic or gastrointestinal disease Subjects presenting chronic degenerative and/or inflammatory disease Subjects with (a history) of diabetes mellitus Abuse of drugs and/or alcohol Subjects receiving corticosteroid treatment Subjects using oral anticoagulants and subjects with clotting disorders Subjects using blood pressurelowering medication Subjects using cholesterollowering medication Subjects using multivitamins or vitamin K supplements Subjects consuming high amounts of vitamin Kcontaining food products Subjects with cow's milk allergy and lactose intolerance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>