<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02092766</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Delayed anaemia has been reported in European travellers with malaria cured by artesunate. Although no deaths related to this delayed anaemia have been reported so far, blood transfusion has been necessary in some affected patients. Recent observations suggest that this episodes of anaemia also occurs in endemic countries. The aim of this trial is to assess the incidence of late onset anaemia after treatment with intravenous artesunate compared to intravenous quinine, to identify patients at risk and to clarify the causes of this delayed anaemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Parenteral Artesunate Compared to Quinine as a Cause of Late Anaemia in African Children With Malaria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artesunate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artemisinins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Quinine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt; 6 months and ≤ 14 years Acute uncomplicated P. falciparum malaria, confirmed by positive blood smear with asexual forms of P. falciparum or mixed with nonfalciparum species Asexual P. falciparum parasitaemia ≥ 100,000/uL and ≤500,000/uL Haemoglobin ≥5.0 g/dL Parents/guardians agree to hospitalize the child for the length of treatment (3 days) and bring the patient for planned followup visits at day 7, 14, 21, 28, 35, 42 Signed consent from the guardian/parents Body weight ≤ 5 kg Severe malaria or signs of severe malaria as defined by WHO Guidelines 2013 History of hypersensitivity or contraindication to quinine or artesunate A clear history of adequate antimalarial treatment in the preceding 24 hours with drugs expected to be effective Presence of intercurrent illness or any condition which in the judgement of the investigator would place the subject at undue risk or interfere with the patient treatment or results of the study Participation in another clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>14 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>malaria</keyword>
	<keyword>anaemia</keyword>
	<keyword>artesunate</keyword>
</DOC>