<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02092558</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: Squamous metaplasia refers to the pathological transformation of the urothelium leading to non-keratinised stratified squamous metaplasia (N-KSM). Objective: To present the investigators experiences in the diagnosis and treatment of N-KSM of the urinary bladder in children.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Immunological Disorders of T Lymphocytes and Endocrinological Disorders as Pathogen Factors in Patients With Metaplasia of Urinary Bladder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Design, setting, and participants: In this study, the investigators present their experiences in the diagnosis and treatment of N-KSM of the urinary bladder in children aged from 5 to 17 years. From 2005 to 2013, metaplasia was diagnosed in 119 patients - 116 girls and 3 boys. The reasons behind visiting the hospital were non-specific intense pain in the abdomen, recurrent urinary tract infections, and urination disorders. The most common symptoms of urinary bladder dysfunction were pollakiuria and difficulties in initiating micturition and retention of urine (reduced detrusor muscle activity). Outcome measurements and statistical analysis: In 20 patients (16.8%), metaplasia was incidentally diagnosed during cystoscopy performed for other causes. Only the children whose bladders showed metaplastic changes on cystoscopy were subjected to a bladder biopsy for collecting specimens for further histopathological examination.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Tract Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urolithiasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metaplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hematuria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Menstruation Disturbances</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nitrofurantoin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cephalosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antineoplastic Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The followup duration was 18 years. The main reasons behind visiting the hospital were: 1. recurrent urinary tract infection, 2. urinary urgencies, 3. pollakiuria, 4. difficulty in initiating micturition, 5. pain in hypogastrium, 6. night wetting and day wetting, 7. menstruation's disorders, 8. urolithiasis, 9. defects of urinary system and hematuria. No confirmation of squamous metaplasia of the urinary bladder in diagnostic cystoscopy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>metaplasia, dysfunction, urinary bladder, children</keyword>
</DOC>