<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00880750</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being conducted to assess any potential differences in the absorption and excretion between two lanthanum carbonate formulations. This study is also being done to assess the safety and tolerability of the two lanthanum carbonate formulations.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacodynamic Study of Two Lanthanum Carbonate Formulations in Healthy Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Ability to provide informed consent to participate in the study. Healthy volunteers, age 1855 inclusive. Subject must be willing to comply with applicable contraceptive requirements of the protocol Female subjects must have a negative pregnancy test Ability to chew and or swallow doses of the investigational products as prescribed in the protocol. Ability to fully comply with all study procedures and restrictions, including consumption of all food provided while a resident in the CRC. Exclusion Criteria Current or relevant previous history of physical or psychiatric illness, any medical disorder that may require treatment or make the subject unlikely to fully complete the study, or any condition that presents undue risk from the investigational product or study procedures. Clinically significant abnormal serum phosphate levels, outside of normal limits. Current use of any medication with the exception of hormonal replacement therapy or hormonal contraceptives within 7 days of first dose of investigational product. A known history of lactose intolerance or allergy to milk or other foods. Clinically significant or multiple allergies as determined by an Investigator. History of alcohol or other substance abuse within the last 6 months. A positive screen for alcohol or drugs of abuse. Male subjects who consume more than 21 units of alcohol per week or three units per day. Female subjects who consume more than 14 units of alcohol per week or two units per day. A positive human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antibody screen, Hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) or Hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody screen. Female subjects who are pregnant (positive pregnancy test), lactating, or less than 90 days postpartum. Subjects that have previously been randomized in this study. Use of tobacco in any form or other nicotinecontaining products in any form. Exusers must report that they have stopped using tobacco for at least 60 days prior to receiving the first dose of investigational product. Routine consumption of more than two units of caffeine per day or subjects who experience caffeine withdrawal headaches. Donation of blood or blood products within 60 days prior to receiving the first dose of investigational product. Plasma donation within 28 days prior to the first dose of the investigational product. Use of another investigational product within 30 days prior to receiving the first dose of investigational product or active enrolment in another drug or vaccine clinical study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>End stage Renal disease</keyword>
</DOC>