<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00880854</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out the highest safe dose of the investigational drug CP-675,206 when given in combination with BCG therapy to patients who have experienced recurrent superficial bladder cancer after standard BCG treatment. In addition, the study will look to see if taking CP 675,206 generates an immune response and evaluate how the drug affects superficial bladder cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of CP-675,206 in Bacillus Calmette-Guerin (BCG)-Resistant Bladder Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tremelimumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologic diagnosis of transitional cell cancer of the bladder must have completed a transurethral resection of all visible bladder tumors, and have completed two previous 6week courses with intravesical BCG. Evidence of disease recurrence within 1 year of previous BCG treatment Tumor tissue must be available from biopsy for study related immunohistochemical analysis If sexually active must use reliable form of contraception while on study and for 4 weeks after last treatment ECOG performance status of &lt;2 Life expectancy of at least 6 months Adequate hematologic, renal and liver function Informed consent No evidence of immunosuppression or treated with immunosuppressive therapy within 6 months No prior radiation to the pelvis No gross hematuria within 1 week prior to planned week 1 treatment Cannot have previous intolerance to BCG Cannot be seropositive for HIV, hepatitis B(HBV) or hepatitis C(HCV) per patient history No evidence of metastatic disease No prior treatment with antiCTLA4 monoclonal antibody Can not be pregnant or lactating No history of autoimmune disorder No history of thyroid or adrenal insufficiency No history of inflammatory bowel conditions, including diverticulitis, ulcerative colitis, Crohn's or celiac disease, intractable urinary tract infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>BCG-resistant localized transitional cell of the bladder</keyword>
</DOC>