<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00880893</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objectives: - To evaluate safety after each CYD Dengue vaccination. - To evaluate the immune response to each CYD Dengue serotype after each vaccination in a subset of subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Sanofi Pasteur's CYD Dengue Vaccine in Healthy Subjects in Singapore</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multicenter trial involving three vaccinations over a period of 1 year, and a 4-year follow-up following the last vaccination.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dengue</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhagic Fevers, Viral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Severe Dengue</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria : Aged from 2 to 45 years on the day of inclusion. Subject in good health, based on medical history and physical examination. Provision of informed consent form (and assent form for subjects aged 6 to 12 years) signed by the subject and by the parent(s) or another legally acceptable representative for subjects aged less than 21 years. Subject and parent(s)/legally acceptable representative able to attend all scheduled visits and comply with all trial procedures. For a woman of childbearing potential, avoid becoming pregnant (use of an effective method of contraception or abstinence) for at least 4 weeks before the first vaccination until 4 weeks after the last vaccination. Exclusion Criteria : Febrile illness (temperature ≥ 37.5°C) or moderate or severe acute illness/infection on the day of the first vaccination, according to Investigator judgment. For a woman of childbearing potential, known pregnancy or positive urine pregnancy test on the day of inclusion. Breastfeeding woman. Known systemic hypersensitivity to any of the components of the trial vaccines (especially egg proteins or neomycin) or history of a lifethreatening reaction to the trial vaccines or to a vaccine containing any of the same substances. Personal or family history of thymic pathology or myasthenia. Previous hepatitis A vaccination (for children only). Known or suspected congenital or acquired immunodeficiency, immunosuppressive therapy such as anticancer chemotherapy or radiation therapy within the past 6 months, or longterm systemic corticosteroid therapy. Chronic illness at a stage that could interfere with trial conduct or completion, in the opinion of the Investigator. Receipt of blood or bloodderived products in the past 3 months that might interfere with the assessment of immune response. Participation in another clinical trial investigating a vaccine, drug, medical device, or a medical procedure in the 4 weeks preceding the first trial vaccination. Planned participation in another clinical trial during the 18 coming months. Receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks preceding the first trial vaccination. Planned receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks following the first trial vaccination. Subject deprived of freedom by an administrative or court order, or in an emergency setting, or hospitalized without his/her consent. Current or past alcohol abuse or drug addiction that may interfere with the subject's ability to comply with trial procedures. Subject who plans to move to another country within the 18 coming months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dengue virus</keyword>
	<keyword>Dengue fever</keyword>
	<keyword>Dengue hemorrhagic fever</keyword>
	<keyword>Dengue diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Sanofi Pasteur's CYD Dengue Vaccine</keyword>
</DOC>