<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00240591</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a study for the long-term follow-up of patients who completed at least two years of follow-up after treatment with Tositumomab and/or Iodine I 131 Tositumomab (BEXXAR)on Study RIT-I-000, RIT-II-001, RIT-II-002, RIT-II-004 or CP-97-012. All patients will be assessed for survival and disease status, including subsequent therapy for NHL, and for long term safety. Laboratory evaluations consisting of a TSH level (for all patients) and a complete blood cell (CBC) count with a differential and platelet count (for patients in continuing response only) will be obtained annually through Year 10 post treatment with Tositumomab and/or Iodine I 131 Tositumomab. Patients that remain in response to their previous treatment with BEXXAR, will additionally be followed radiographically for response and progression.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Patients With Low-Grade Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma Previously Treated With Tositumomab and/or Iodine I 131 Tositumomab</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iodine-131 anti-B1 antibody</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iodine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have enrolled in one of the following Corixa sponsored clinical trials: RITI000, RITII001, RITII002, RIT II004 or CP97012 and are &gt;2 years post Tositumomab and/or Iodine I 131 Tositumomab administration. Patients must give written informed consent by signing an IRB/ethics committee approved consent form prior to entry on this followup study. Inability to meet the above referenced inclusion criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>BEXXAR</keyword>
	<keyword>Tositumomab</keyword>
	<keyword>Iodine I 131 Tositumomab</keyword>
	<keyword>low-grade follicular lymphomas</keyword>
</DOC>