<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01342926</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the safety and efficacy of GSK933776 in the treatment of geographic atrophy secondary to age-related macular degeneration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Study to Investigate Safety and Efficacy of GSK933776 in Adult Patients With Geographic Atrophy Secondary to Age-related Macular Degeneration</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 2a proof of concept study designed to evaluate the safety and efficacy of GSK933776 for the treatment of geographic atrophy secondary to age-related macular degeneration. This is a placebo-controlled parallel-group study that is double masked.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Geographic Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients ≥55 years of age inclusive Evidence of AMD confirmed by the presence of at least 1 druse ≥125 μm diameter Welldemarcated GA due to AMD of total area 1.917 mm2 measured in the study eye Bestcorrected visual acuity score of ≥ 35 letters (approximately 20/200 Snellen VA equivalent or better) in the study eye Additional eye disease in the study eye that could compromise assessment of bestcorrected visual acuity or imaging of the posterior pole History of CNV secondary to AMD in the study eye Any previous treatment for AMD in the study eye, approved or investigational, with the exception of dietary supplements Risk of cerebrovascular disease, cerebral hemorrhage or stroke History of systemic autoimmune disease Use of platelet antiaggregants or anticoagulants (aspirin up to 325 mg/day is allowable, or in subjects allergic or intolerable to aspirin, clopidogrel up to 75 mg/day is allowable) Use of chronic corticosteroids Uncontrolled hypertension in spite of antihypertensive medications Renal or hepatic insufficiency or clinically significant anemia More than moderate MRI white matter changes</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>age-related macular degeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>geographic atrophy</keyword>
	<keyword>dry AMD</keyword>
</DOC>