<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01342185</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to verify the effectiveness and safety of medical ozone therapy system in treatment of chronic hepatitis B.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Medical Ozone Therapy in Patients With Chronic Hepatitis B</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Total of 189 patients with compensated chronic hepatitis B will be divided equally and randomly into three arms. Patients in arm I and II treated with medical ozone therapy with different medical ozone generators, one was made in Tianyi medical instruments limited company and the other in Germany. Sixty-three patients of arm III treated with Diammonium glycyrrhizinate Capsules, common used liver protective herb drug. The term of therapy is 12 weeks. Virology response, biochemistry response and hepatitis B viral serological response will be studied at the end of 12 weeks treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glycyrrhizic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female, not less than 16 years old； 2. HBsAg positive for over 6 months； 3. ALT over 2×ULN, TBIL less than 80µmol/L and serum HBV DNA over 10000copies/ml。 1. Patient has a history of hemorrhagic or hemolysis disease; 2. Patient has any history of clinical signs/symptoms of hepatic decompensation or serious metabolic hepatic disease; 3. Patient is coinfected with HIV or HCV; 4. Patient is treated with antivirus drug like interferon or nucleoside analogue in recent 6 months; 5. Patient is treated with immunosuppressive agent for long time, including patient has a history of organ transplantation; 6. Pregnancy; 7. Current alcohol or drug abuse; 8. Difficulty to draw blood through veins; 9. Patient has a history of carcinoma, or finding suggestive of possible hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), or AFP over than 100ng/ml; 10. Patient has a history of any severe physical disease such as cardiovascular, kidney events, hyperthyroidism or serious electrolyte disturbance; 11. Patient is enrolled in any other clinical trials.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Medical ozone therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic hepatitis B</keyword>
</DOC>