<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02755610</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Peritoneal Dialysis (PD) has been the main method of treatment for Thai End-Stage Renal Disease (ESRD) patients under the "PD First" policy of the Universal Coverage (UC) scheme. The increased demand has resulted in not only supply chain logistical problems, but also product quality concerns. Peritonitis, the main complication and main cause of failure in Continuous Ambulatory Peritoneal Dialysis (CAPD) patients, could be caused by product defect. This cluster randomized trial will be conducted in participating Peritoneal Dialysis Outcomes and Practice Patterns Study (PDOPPS) centers in Thailand to assess if a check list intervention could reduce peritonitis rate and increase the number of product defect report.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Check List to Improve Patient Self-care and Product Defect Report in Continuous Ambulatory Peritoneal Dialysis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Peritoneal Dialysis (PD) has been the main method of treatment for Thai End-Stage Renal Disease (ESRD) patients under the "PD First" policy of the Universal Coverage (UC) scheme. The increased demand has resulted in not only supply chain logistical problems, but also product quality concerns. Peritonitis, the main complication and main cause of failure in CAPD patients, could be caused by product defect. PD Product Check List was developed based on the 28 routine steps of standard orientation manual for new Thai PD patients. Of these, step 2 (weighting the PD solution bag), step 3 (checking expiration date, volume, glucose concentration, clarity, and color, step 27 (weighting the PD solution bag), and step 28 (recording time, volume, and any abnormality encountered) are relevant to product defect report. This cluster randomized trial will be conducted in 22 Thai participating PDOPPS centers (20-25 prevalent and 10-15 incidence PD cases per center) to answer the primary research question: is the check list intervention effective in reducing peritonitis rate? The secondary research questions will also be considered: does the check list help increase the number of product defect report? Peritonitis incidence rate is the primary outcome, defined based on International Society for Peritoneal Dialysis (ISPD) 2010 recommendation. Product defect incidence is the secondary outcome, measured by number of incidence of product defect reported by the patients. Given no standard definition, a PD solution product will be considered defective if it is expired on the day of use, incorrect glucose concentration, abnormal clarity or color, physical abnormality of the box and/or the bag, or loosen connector. Because of the nature of the intervention, blinding is not possible. The randomization list will be generated separately for each participating PD center by using the random permuted block method with block size of two. Patients will be randomly allocated to either the study or control groups in a 1:1 ratio. While all subjects will receive standard PD care, the study subjects will also receive the check list plus a 30-minute orientation of how to use the check list.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peritonitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ESRD patients who start peritoneal dialysis not longer than one month and participate in PDOPPS study ESRD patients who receive only hemodialysis ESRD patients who receive emergency peritoneal dialysis Illiterate ESRD patients or their caregivers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Peritoneal Dialysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Checklist</keyword>
</DOC>