<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02755376</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose:Development of novel strategy for treatment of anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury using stem cell.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Development of Novel Strategy for Treatment of Anterior Cruciate Ligament (ACL) Injury Using Stem Cell</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>1. Purpose: Development of novel strategy for treatment of anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury using stem cell. 2. Subject: Anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury 30 patients - ACL reconstruction: 10 - ACL reconstruction + Human cord blood derived mesenchymal stem cells and hyaluronic acid (Cartistem (TM)): 10 - ACL reconstruction + hyaluronic acid: 10 3. Hypothesis: Human Cord blood derived mesenchymal stem cells can enhance healing between bone tunnel and graft in ACL reconstruction.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hyaluronic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 20~50 2. Lachman test grade II,III or Pivot shift test grade I,II,III or ACL rupture in MRI 3. prothrombin time (PT) (INR) &lt;1.5, activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) &lt;1.5 x control 4. Creatinine ≤2.0 ㎎/㎗, protein uria(dipstick) ≤ trace 5. Bilirubin ≤2.0 ㎎/㎗, aspartate aminotransferase (AST) /Alanine Aminotransferase (ALT) ≤100 IU/L 6. No surgery and radiation therapy in recent 6 weeks 7. No pregnancy 8. No combine ligament instability ≥ grade II in physical examination (grade 0: none, grade I: 0~5mm, grade II: 5~10mm, grade III: &gt;10mm) 9. voluntary singed a consent form 1. Degenerative osteoarthritis in knee 2. Revision or other surgery history (stem cell treatment) 3. Chronic inflammatory joint disease like rheumatoid arthritis 4. Infectious disease need to administration of parenteral antibiotics 5. Autoimmune disease 6. Myocardial infarction, congestive heart failure, other serious heart disease 7. Uncontrolled hypertension 8. Serious medical disease 9. Pregnancy and breastfeeding 10. psychiatric disorder and epilepsy 11. Alcohol overuse 12. Smoking overuse 13. Administration of immunosuppressive agents like Cyclosporin A or Azathioprine in recent 6 weeks prior screening test 14. Patient participating in other clinical trials in recent 4 weeks 15. Combined ligament instability ≥ grade II in physical test. 16. No allergy history to gentamicin antibiotics 17. Hypersensitivity patient to bovine protein, hyaluronic acid, and anesthetic agent 18. Inappropriate patient judged by researcher.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>