<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00766831</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this is study to evaluate improvement of sleep disorder caused by cancer pain after the administration of Hydromorphone Oral Osmotic System (OROS) in Korean participants with cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Efficacy and Safety Study of Hydromorphone Oral Osmotic System (OROS) in Korean Participants With Cancer Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label (all people know the identity of the intervention), multi-center (conducted in more than 1 center), prospective (study following participants forward in time) dose-ascending study to evaluate the clinical usefulness of hydromorphone OROS in improvement of sleep disturbance caused by cancer pain.Total duration of study will be 3 weeks. The study consists of 3 phases: Screening phase (up to 1 week), Treatment phase (2 weeks), and Extension phase (12 weeks). The study will include 6 visits: Day -7, Day 1, Day 15, Day 43, Day 71, and Day 99. During screening phase, potential participants will receive strong oral (long acting) opioid analgesic (for 7 days) until Day 1 and the participants will be evaluated for participation in clinical study on Day 1. During treatment phase, participants will receive hydromorphone OROS (8 milligram [mg] to greater than or equal to 32 mg), once daily for 2 weeks, and the dose will be adjusted every 2 days from Day 3 at the Investigator's discretion and according to the strong oral (long acting) opioid analgesic administered from screening phase to Day 1 (the initial dose of the study drug will be determined by converting the dose of the previously administered analgesic to that of the daily dose of oral morphine with the equivalent analgesic effect to the study drug [dose with equivalent analgesic effect; Hydromorphone OROS dose: oral morphine dose =1:5]). Participants who completed treatment phase and suffer from continuing cancer pain will be enrolled to extension phase and study drug will be administered as per Investigator discretion for 99 days. Participants primarily will be evaluated for improvement in sleep disturbance measured by Korean Brief Pain Inventory (KBPI). Participants' safety will be monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hydromorphone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants who are currently receiving strong opioid analgesic (drug used to control pain) for their cancer pain management Participants whose arithmetical mean of sleep disturbance caused by pain measured with Numeric Rating Scale for 3 days before Visit 2 (Day 1) is equal to or greater than 4 points Participants who are able, in the opinion of Investigator, to comply fully with the trial requirements including completion of the KoreanBrief Pain Inventory Participants who have signed an informed consent form Participants with pain who are not likely to response to opioid analgesics Participants who are intolerant or hypersensitive to hydromorphone Participants with the following digestive tract diseases which is serious enough to interfere action of an oral analgesic; diseases which can affect absorption and transit of oral drugs such as dysphagia (trouble swallowing), vomiting, no bowel movement, intestinal obstruction, serious intestinal stenosis (narrowing of a duct, tube, or 1 of the valves in the heart), etc Female participants of childbearing potential who are pregnant or lactating, seeking pregnancy, or failing to take adequate contraceptive precautions Participants in whom the risks of treatment with morphine/hydromorphone outweigh the potential benefits, including such risk categories as raised intracranial pressure, hypotension, hypothyroidism, asthma, compromised respiratory function compromised liver function, convulsive (an involuntary contraction or series of contractions of the voluntary muscles) disorder and Addison disease (disorder that occurs when the adrenal glands do not produce enough of their hormones)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cancer pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Hydromorphone OROS</keyword>
	<keyword>Jurnista</keyword>
</DOC>