<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00987415</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether allopurinol is effective in relieving symptoms of patients with heart failure and high blood uric acid levels.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Using Allopurinol to Relieve Symptoms in Patients With Heart Failure and High Uric Acid Levels</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Allopurinol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>NYHA class IIIV heart failure due to ischemic or nonischemic cardiomyopathy. Left ventricular ejection fraction ≤ 40% by echocardiography Heart failure symptoms for 3 months despite standard treatment. Serum uric acid level ≥ 9.5 mg/dl. At least one of the following additional markers of increased risk: Hospitalization, ER visit or urgent clinic visit for heart failure requiring IV diuretics within the previous 12 months; Left ventricular ejection fraction ≤ 25; Btype natriuretic peptide level &gt; 250 pg/ml Hypertrophic or restrictive cardiomyopathy, constrictive pericarditis, biopsyproven myocarditis, severe stenotic valvular disease, or complex congenital heart disease. Acute coronary syndrome, PCI or CABG within 3 months. Current ventricular assist device or ventricular assist device or heart transplant likely within the next 6 months. Uncontrolled hypertension (i.e., SBP &gt; 170 mm Hg or DBP &gt; 110 mm Hg) Serum creatinine &gt; 3 mg/dL or estimated GFR &lt; 20 ml/min. Evidence of active hepatitis with ALT and AST greater than 3x normal. Any condition other than HF which could limit the ability to perform a 6minute walk test Any diseases other than HF which are likely to alter the patient's global perception of status or quality of life over a period of 6 months. Receiving treatment with allopurinol currently or within 30 days, or having symptomatic hyperuricemia which requires treatment with allopurinol.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>