<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00485797</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Experimental design overview The proposed project is a prospective experimental study design. Children (age &lt;15) suffer from attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) that their Parents willing to participate in the study will be tested with well-established measuring techniques of Balance control before and 1 hour after taking of Methylphenidate (Ritalin) in the movement and Rehabilitation Laboratory at BGU. An automated algorithm will be used to extract standardized stabilogram-diffusion parameters from each of the COP data sets collected during quiet standing. These parameters include diffusion coefficients, critical displacement, critical time and scaling exponents for both lateral and anterior-posterior sway directions (Collins &amp; De Luca, 1993). For each of the conditions (before and 1 hour after the use of Ritalin) in three task conditions single task; dual task (concentrating and identifying specific music); and just Listening to a relaxing music. Participants will be required to stand on the platform 10 times for 30 s. For each trial, they will be instructed to sway as little as possible.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Ritalin on Postural Stability of Hyper Active Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylphenidate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 612 years old Diagnosed as ADHD childrens by a neurologist Taking methylphenidate (Ritalin) Children who suffer from CP, or other neurological disease Children who suffer from psychiatric state Children who suffer from orthopedic condition (1/2 a year after a fracture in the lower limb)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Dual tasking</keyword>
	<keyword>Postural Control</keyword>
	<keyword>Methylphenidate (Ritalin)</keyword>
	<keyword>The focus of the study is To explore the effects of Ritalin on postural control in ADHD Children, during single and dual task conditions.</keyword>
</DOC>