<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00669578</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Biological therapies, such as CC-4047, may stimulate the immune system in different ways and stop cancer cells from growing. CC-4047 may also stop the growth of cancer cells by blocking blood flow to the cancer. PURPOSE: This trial is studying the side effects and best dose of CC-4047 and to see how well it works in treating patients with myelofibrosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CC-4047 in Treating Patients With Myelofibrosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Phase I: Primary - To determine the Maximum Tolerated Dose of CC-4047 in the treatment of Primary, Post Polycythemia Vera, or Post Essential Thrombocythemia Myelofibrosis (PMF, post-PV MF, or post-ET MF). Phase II: Primary - Best overall response as determined by International Working Group Criteria over the first 6 cycles (168 days) of study treatment. Secondary - Safety (type, frequency, severity [National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 3.0] of adverse events (AEs), and relationship of AEs to CC-4047. - Duration of response. - Time to response. - Best overall response as determined by International Working Group Criteria over the first 12 cycles (336 days) of study treatment. OUTLINE: Patients receive oral CC-4047. Treatment repeats every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed at 28 days and then every 6 months for up to 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Primary Myelofibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polycythemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polycythemia Vera</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thrombocythemia, Essential</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myeloproliferative Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pomalidomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thalidomide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of primary and post essential thrombocythemia (ET) or post polycythemia vera (PV) myelofibrosis requiring therapy De novo presentation (i.e., agnogenic myeloid metaplasia AND post ET or post PV myelofibrosis) Developed after an antecedent history of PV (i.e., post polycythemic myeloid metaplasia) or essential polycythemia (i.e., post thrombocythemic myeloid metaplasia) Total hemoglobin &lt; 10 g/dL OR transfusion dependent anemia (defined by a history of ≥ 2 units of red blood cell (RBC) transfusions within the past 28 days for hemoglobin &lt; 8.5 g/dL that was not associated with overt bleeding) OR marked splenomegaly (e.g., ≥ 10 cm below costal margin) PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 02 Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 500/μL Platelet count ≥ 20,000/μL Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤ 3 times upper limit of normal (ULN) (≤ 5 times ULN if attributed to hepatic extramedullary hematopoiesis) Total bilirubin ≤ 3 times ULN OR direct bilirubin ≤ 2 times ULN Serum creatinine ≤ 2.0 mg/dL Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective doublemethod contraception for ≥ 28 days before, during, and for ≥ 28 days after completion of study treatment Agrees to abstain from donating blood, semen, or sperm during and for ≥ 28 days after completion of study treatment Willing to undergo transfusion of blood products (if applicable) Able to complete questionnaire(s) alone or with assistance No known HIV positivity, hepatitis B carrier, or active hepatitis C infection No serious medical condition, psychiatric illness, or any other condition, including the presence of laboratory abnormalities, that (as judged by the treating physician) would preclude giving informed consent or participating in the study or confound the ability to interpret data from the study No other active malignancies, except basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix or breast No active deep vein thrombosis or pulmonary embolism that has not been therapeutically anticoagulated PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Recovered from all prior therapy No prior CC4047 More than 28 days since prior growth factors, cytotoxic chemotherapeutic agents (e.g., hydroxyurea or anagrelide), corticosteroids, or experimental drugs or therapies No other concurrent experimental drugs or therapies or cytotoxic chemotherapeutic agents (e.g., hydroxyurea or anagrelide) for myelofibrosis No concurrent growth factors (including erythropoietin) for myelofibrosis, except GCSF or pegfilgrastim No concurrent chronic use (i.e., &gt; 2 weeks) of more than physiologic doses of corticosteroids (dose equivalent to &gt; 10 mg/day of prednisone)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>secondary myelofibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>polycythemia vera</keyword>
	<keyword>essential thrombocythemia</keyword>
	<keyword>primary myelofibrosis</keyword>
</DOC>