<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01681992</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate end of shelf-life potency in terms of the immunogenicity and safety of GSK Biologicals' trivalent MMR vaccine, by comparing it to Merck &amp; Co., Inc.'s MMR vaccine, which is approved for use in the United States (US).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunogenicity and Safety Study of GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) Biologicals' Combined Measles-mumps-rubella (MMR) Vaccine in Children in Their Second Year of Life</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This trial is a Phase IIIA, randomized, observer-blind, controlled, multi-center, multi-country study with four parallel groups. This study will evaluate the immunogenicity and safety of GSK Biologicals' trivalent investigational MMR vaccine (referred to as Inv_MMR vaccine, throughout this document) in contrast to the US standard of care comparator vaccine (M M R®II, Merck and Co., Inc., referred to as Com_MMR throughout this document) in children during their second year of life. The first dose of this two-dose study is designed to establish the end of shelf-life potency of Inv_MMR vaccine. The Inv_MMR vaccine will be given as one of two lots; one of a minimum potency, designated Inv_MMR_Min; and the other at a mid-range or medium potency designated Inv_MMR_Med to two groups. The second dose for both of these Inv_MMR groups will have a potency within the release range of the marketed vaccine. The Com_MMR vaccine will consist of two lots designated Com_MMR_L1 and Com_MMR_L2 and will be analyzed as pooled lots within the study. The first MMR vaccine dose will be co-administered with Varivax, Havrix and (in the US sub-cohort only) Prevnar 13 which are routinely administered to children of this age in the US.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Measles</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rubella</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mumps</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heptavalent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female child between 12 and 15 months of age at the time of vaccination. The investigator believes that the parent(s) or Legally Acceptable Representative(s) (LAR(s)) of the child, can, and will comply with the requirements of the protocol. Written informed consent obtained from the parent(s)/LAR(s) of the child. Child is in stable health as determined by investigator's clinical examination and assessment of child's medical history. For US children only: • Child that previously received a 3dose series of Prevnar 13 with last dose at least 60 days prior to study entry. Child in care. Use of any investigational or nonregistered product other than the study vaccine(s) during the period starting 30 days before the day of study vaccination or planned use during the entire study period. Concurrently participating in another clinical study, in which the child has been or will be exposed to an investigational or a noninvestigational product. Chronic administration of immunosuppressants, or other immunemodifying drugs during the period starting 180 days prior to the first vaccine dose or any planned administration of immunosuppressive and immunemodifying drugs during the entire study. Inhaled and topical steroids are allowed. Planned administration / administration of a vaccine not foreseen by the study protocol during the period starting 30 days prior to study vaccination at Visit 1 and ending at Visit 2 (or ending at Visit 3 for the US postdose 2 subcohort). Please Note: Inactivated influenza (Flu) vaccine and Haemophilus influenzae type b conjugate vaccine (Hib) vaccines may be given at any time during the study, including the day of study vaccination (Flu and Hib vaccines must be administered at a different location than the study vaccine/s). Any age appropriate vaccine may be given starting at Visit 2 (or starting at Visit 3 for the US postdose 2 subcohort), and anytime thereafter. Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products during the period starting 180 days prior to study vaccination at Visit 1 or planned administration from the date of vaccination through the immunogenicity evaluation at Visit 2, or at Visit 3 for the US postdose 2 subcohort. History of measles, mumps, rubella, varicella/zoster and/or hepatitis A diseases. Known exposure to measles, mumps, rubella and/or varicella/zoster during the period starting 30 days prior to the first study vaccination. Previous vaccination against measles, mumps, rubella, hepatitis A and/or varicella virus. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, based on medical history and physical examination. A family history of congenital or hereditary immunodeficiency. History of allergic disease or reactions likely to be exacerbated by any component of the vaccines, including hypersensitivity to neomycin, latex or gelatin. Blood dyscrasias, leukemia, lymphomas of any type, or other malignant neoplasms affecting the bone marrow or lymphatic systems. Acute disease at the time of enrollment. Acute disease is defined as the presence of a moderate or severe illness with or without fever. Fever is defined as temperature ≥38°C/100.4°F by any age appropriate route. All vaccines can be administered to persons with a minor illness such as diarrhea, mild upper respiratory infection without fever. Active untreated tuberculosis based on medical history. Any other condition which, in the opinion of the Investigator, prevents the child from participating in the study. For US children only: • A child that previously received a fourth dose of any pneumococcal conjugate vaccine.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Measles, mumps and rubella diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunogenicity</keyword>
</DOC>