<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01681914</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Utilizing funding through the President´s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) this project seeks to assess the effectiveness of a subset of the new Mozambican clinical guidelines for the diagnosis, initial management, and follow-up ( &gt;1 follow-up visit to determine response to initial and/or second-line therapy) of common signs and symptoms in HIV-infected adult patients as used under field conditions by Mozambique-based clinicians in MOH health facilities in Zambézia province, Mozambique. The operational feasibility of the new guidelines will be described; they will be compared to the previous standard of care for the problem(s) of interest, and the clinical importance of differences between guidelines designed for Mozambican non-physician clinicians and new guidelines (also issued in late 2009) for Mozambican physicians will be described. The subset of guidelines to be addressed in the current phase of this 2-year project includes algorithms for diagnosis and management of acute fever, persistent fever, and anemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of the Effectiveness of New Clinical Guidelines for Differential Diagnosis and Management of Common HIV/AIDS-related Conditions in Mozambique</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Seropositivity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>&gt; 18 years old HIVinfected Fever &gt; 37.5° C or history of fever Anemia with recorded hemoglobin level &lt;10 mg/dL Primary language/dialect is not spoken or understood by any member of the study team. Participants who meet algorithmdriven definitions of "danger signs" related to the condition of interest at the time of screening Pregnant women will be excluded only if they meet the following criteria (in labor, or in need of emergency Caesarean section or dilatation and curettage)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult HIV positive patients</keyword>
</DOC>