<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01681446</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine whether interferon-alpha is effective in the treatment of low miR-26 expression patients with HCC after curative resection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Postoperative Interferon- Alpha Treatment in Low miR-26 Expression Patients With HCC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>BACKGROUND: Postoperative interferon-alpha (IFN-alpha) therapy improved survival in patients with hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). MiR-26 is a predictive marker for the efficiency of postoperative interferon-alpha treatment in patients with HCC. Our study is to identify the Efficiency of Postoperative IFN-Alpha Treatment in low miR-26 expression Patients With HCC. METHODS: A quantitative reverse-transcriptase-polymerase-chain-reaction assays of miR-26 are performed on specimens which are collected from patients who underwent a curative resection of HCC. These patients with low miR-26 expression will return to the hospital 25±5 days after the resection following the baseline examination. If all requirements are satisfied, these patients will be randomly divided into the treatment group who received postoperative IFN-alpha therapy or the comparison group who not received any treatment. Besides the disease-free survival rate, the overall survival rate, time to recurrence and the side effect will be observed. Anticipated RESULTS: IFN alpha treatment improved the disease-free survival and the overall survival in low miR-26 expression patients with HCC after curative resection, probably by postponing recurrence.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Perioperative Period 1. Signed informed consent; 2. Aged ≥ 18 years and ≤ 75 years old, male or female； 3. Patients with low miR26 expression(confirmed by RTPCR) underwent a curative resection of HCC; 4. The tumor characteristics must meet the following: 1. tumor diameter is between 3 to 8 centimeters,and the number of tumor is less tnan 3 2. no thrombosis is detected in the main branches of the portal vein, hepatic vein and bile duct 3. no extrahepatic and lymphnode metastasis Perioperative Period 1. Concomitant malignant primary tumor(s) in other systems is/are present; 2. The subject receives any previous systemic antiHCC therapy prior to the resection surgery (except the resection surgery), such as liver transplantation, intervention, ablation, radiotherapy, chemotherapy, molecular targeted therapy or other antiHCC therapy; 3. The subject takes other study/investigational drugs during this study; 4. The subject has cerebrovascular accident, renal insufficiency, depression, hyperthyreosis, hypothyroidism or other severe uncontrolled diseases; 5. The subject has a history of study drug or similar drug allergy. Baseline (PostSurgeryDay 25 ± 5) 1. Baseline (postresection) blood routine examination shows that the number of leukocyte&gt;2.5*10^9/L and platelet count&gt;40*10^9/L; 2. ChildPugh score of class A at baseline. Baseline (PostSurgeryDay 25 ± 5) 1. Concomitant malignant primary tumor(s) in other systems is/are present; 2. The subject takes other study/investigational drugs within 4 weeks prior to randomization; 3. The baseline examination indicates that infection, bleeding, bile leakage, or other postoperative complications are present; 4. The baseline examination suggests the presence of tumor metastasis; 5. The subject has cerebrovascular accident, renal insufficiency, depression, hyperthyreosis, hypothyroidism or other severe uncontrolled diseases; 6. The subject has a history of investigational drug or similar drug allergy; 7. The subject is pregnant, lactating, or urine pregnancy test result is positive.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>hepatocellular carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>interferon-alpha</keyword>
	<keyword>miR-26</keyword>
</DOC>