<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01681264</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Dual medication (guanfacine and morphine) as a standard treatment for chronic pain.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Guanfacine on Opioid-induced Hyperalgesia (OIH) and Tolerance</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This aim proposes that guanfacine would be a useful drug to deter Opioid-Induced Hyperalgesia (OIH) when combined with an opioid (morphine) in chronic pain management.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperalgesia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polystyrene sulfonic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Guanfacine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 1865 years old Chronic neck or back pain condition for at least 3 months VAS score of 48 Has not taken an opioid for the last 3 months Has not taken guanfacine (or other alpha2AR agonists) for the last 6 months Exclusion Criteria Sensory deficits at site of QST, such as peripheral neuropathy Allergic to or has had a severe adverse reaction to study medication (i.e. opioids, guanfacine, lactose, vitamin B2 a.k.a. riboflavin) Cannot tolerate study drugs' maximum doses Takes vitamin B2 &gt; 1.6mg/day during the study Pregnant or breastfeeding Pending litigation Diagnosed with Raynaud's syndrome Has other chronic pain conditions such as fibromyalgia or joint osteoarthritis that are predominant over back and neck pain with regard to its intensity (VAS) Has known preexisting cardiovascular disease (i.e. arrhythmia prolonged QT interval &gt; 440ms), cerebrovascular disease, hepatic or renal impairment, CNS condition, metabolic condition, or history of syncope Hypotension (SBP &lt; 90 mmHg and DBP &lt; 60 mmHg for female or SBP &lt; 100 mmHg and DBP &lt; 60 mmHg for male; measured while in a sitting position) or bradycardia (resting heart rate &lt; 60 bpm) Subjects are on antihypertensive drugs (e.g., a betablocker) that result in hypotension and/or bradycardia as defined above Tests positive for nonstudy opioids, illicit drugs, marijuana, or nonprescribed drugs Major psychiatric disorders that required hospitalization in the past 6 months such as: major depression, bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, anxiety disorder, or psychotic disorders Currently in a treatment program for alcohol or drug abuse, or currently on methadone or buprenorphine (i.e. suboxone, subutex) for treatment of addiction, or stimulants for treatment of ADHD History of substance or alcohol abuse (meets DSM IV criteria) per medical record or subject admission Subjects are on medications that serve as CYP3A4/5 inhibitors or CYP3A4 inducers including, but are not limited to, valproic acid, macrolide antibiotics, antifungal drugs, St. John wort, ACE inhibitors, nefazodone (antidepressant), calcium channel blockers, H2receptor antagonists, antiHIV or AIDS drugs, and antiepileptic drugs Subjects are on medications that are ligands for alpha2adrenergic receptors including antipsychotic drugs (e.g. clozapine) and tricyclic or tetracyclic antidepressants (e.g. imipramine, mirtazapine, mianserin). Any medications taken by a subject at the enrollment will be reviewed regarding their compatibility with guanfacine and morphine as well as possible confounding side effects. In addition, subjects will be warned of side effects of morphine such as sedation, respiratory depression at the enrollment. Subjects will be allowed to take nonopioid pain medications except for gabapentinoids and amitriptyline/nortriptyline as far as such medications do not have incompatibility with morphine and guanfacine.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Back pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Neck pain</keyword>
</DOC>