<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01681888</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Movement disorders such as dystonia, hypertonia, and spasticity interfere with or prevent voluntary movement. Studies have suggested that using biofeedback to increase awareness of muscle activation can improve motor function in patients with motor deficits. The investigators hypothesize that the daily use of a surface electromyographic (SEMG) biofeedback device for one month will improve motor function in children and young adults with dystonia, hypertonia, and/or spasticity. The SEMG biofeedback device is worn over the muscle(s) the subject has difficulty in controlling and provides vibratory feedback about muscle activation. Groups of children and young adults (ages 3-21), with dystonia, hypertonia, and/or spasticity will be asked to wear a small (approx 1 square inch) sensory feedback device on their affected muscle(s) for 5 hours a day for one month. The device will vibrate and emit a blue light when the muscle is activated. At the start of the experiment, subjects will be tested on the Goal Attainment Scale (GAS), the Pediatric/Adolescent Outcomes Data Collections Instruments (PODCI), and the Barry Albright Dystonia Scale (BAD). For one month, subjects will practice goals without device. After a month, subject will be assessed again and be given device to practice goals for a month. After one month, the subjects will be tested on the outcome measures again and return device.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Surface EMG Biofeedback for Children With Cerebral Palsy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Paralysis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Palsy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dystonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Movement Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Cerebral palsy, or associated movement disorders such as dystonia, spasticity, and/or hypertonia Able to wear device for given amount of time Unable to wear device for at least 5 hours day for a month.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>