<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01396551</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Clinical study investigating the feasibility and safety of using an anchored Calypso transponder in the airways of the lung for real-time monitoring of tumor location during radiotherapy</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluating an Anchored Transponder in Lung Cancer Patients Receiving Radiation Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Calypso anchored lung transponders are a modified version of the previously FDA-cleared Calypso soft tissue transponders. This modification includes an anchoring mechanism to hold the transponder positionally stable within small airways of the lung. Transponders are placed locally to the tumor within the lung and during subsequent radiotherapy the Calypso system may be used to monitor the location of the transponders and, by extension, the tumor, in real-time. This allows for improved tumor-targeting as well as gating of the radiation beam when the tumor moves outside the target field during respiratory motion. The goals of this investigation are to show that patients with implanted anchored transponders can be localized with the Calypso System, that anchored transponder implantation and use are feasible and safe, and that anchored transponders are positionally stable in the small airways of patients with cancer of the lung.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years at time of consent (19 years if required by local or state laws) Patients planning to undergo radiation therapy for primary or recurrent carcinomas of the lung or cancer that is metastatic to the lung. Patients who are to receive 30 Gy or more of external beam radiation therapy. Patients who are able to tolerate flexible bronchoscopy. Patients with life expectancy of at least 12 months and who are expected to be able to complete the full followup assessment in the protocol. Patients for whom the physician is able to identify suitable implantation sites for the anchored transponders on a recent (within the past 8 weeks) CT scan. This will require acquisition of a CT scan if a suitable one is not already available. Patients who are able to comply with the protocol. Patients with implants in the chest region that contain metal or conductive materials (e.g., metal implants, rods, or plates) which the Sponsor considers will interfere with the Calypso System's electromagnetic localization (note that the Sponsor will review a patient's implanted metal on a case by case basis). Patients with active implanted devices, such as pacemakers, defibrillators, and drug infusion pumps since the effect of the Calypso System operation on these devices is unknown. Patients with active infections. Patients with bronchiectasis in the lobe of the intended implantation sites. Patients with a history of hypersensitivity to nickel. Patients whose lung tumors are being monitored with MR imaging (MR imaging of the anchored transponders is safe but yields an image artifact around the anchored transponders). Patients with any other medical condition or laboratory value that would, at the discretion of the investigator, preclude the patient from participation in this clinical study. Patients enrolled in any other clinical studies the investigator believes to be in conflict with this investigation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anchored Beacon Transponder</keyword>
	<keyword>Anchored Transponder</keyword>
	<keyword>Lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Calypso system</keyword>
	<keyword>Realtime tracking</keyword>
</DOC>