<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01396525</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To determine the safety and efficacy of the Omnilink Elite™ Peripheral Balloon-Expandable Stent System in subjects with atherosclerotic de novo or restenotic lesions in the native common iliac artery and/or native external iliac artery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial to Evaluate the Safety &amp; Efficacy of the Omnilink Elite™ Peripheral Balloon-Expandable Stent System in Subjects With Atherosclerotic de Novo or Restenotic Lesions in the Native Common Iliac Artery and/or Native External Iliac Artery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The MOBILITY study was a prospective, non-randomized, two-arm, multi-center study. The 2 arms (Omnilink Elite arm and Absolute Pro arm) were designed to independently assess the safety and effectiveness of the 2 devices used in this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical 1. Subject must be at least 18 and &lt; 90 years of age. 2. Subject has been informed of the nature of the trial, agrees to its provisions, and has signed the informed consent form. 3. Subject must agree to undergo all protocolrequired followup examinations and requirements at the investigational site. 4. History of symptomatic claudication (Rutherford Becker Clinical Category 23) or ischemic rest pain (Rutherford Becker Clinical Category 4). 5. Female subjects of childbearing potential must have had a negative pregnancy test before treatment, and must not be nursing at the time of treatment, and agree at time of consent to use birth control during participation in this trial up to and including the followup at 9 months. Angiographic Inclusion Criteria 1. Up to two bilateral de novo or restenotic lesions of the native common iliac artery and/or native external iliac artery may be treated(one per side). 2. Common iliac artery lesion visually estimated to be ≥50% stenosis and ≤100% stenosis (total occlusion) 3. External iliac artery lesion visually estimated to be ≥50% stenosis and ≤99% stenosis 4. Lesion length for stenosis of the common or external iliac artery visually estimated to be ≥ 10 mm and ≤ 110 mm (Absolute Pro) 5. Lesion length for total occlusion of the common iliac artery visually estimated to be ≤40 mm 6. Target vessel reference diameter visually estimated to be ≥3.6 mm and ≤9.1 mm (Absolute Pro) 7. On the treatment side(s), patent superficial femoral and popliteal arteries and at least one patent distal outflow artery with inline distal vessel flow to the foot as confirmed by arteriography. Patent is defined as &lt; 50% stenosis. 8. Lesion length for stenosis of the common or external iliac artery visually estimated to be ≥ 10 mm and ≤ 50 mm (Omnilink Elite). 9. Target vessel reference diameter visually estimated to be ≥ 5.0 mm and ≤ 11.0 mm (Omnilink Elite). Clinical Exclusion Criteria 1. Subject is unable to walk. 2. Subject has had recent major surgery (last 3 months) e.g., abdominal surgery, coronary artery bypass graft surgery, thoracic surgery. 3. Subject has received, or is on the waiting list for a major organ transplant (heart, lung, kidney, liver). 4. Subject is diagnosed as Rutherford Becker Clinical Category 0, 1, 5, or 6. 5. Subject has ulcers or lesions on the lower extremity(ies) of the target lesion side(s). 6. Subject has elevated serum creatinine &gt; 2.0 mg/dl. 7. Subject has uncontrolled diabetes mellitus (DM) (serum glucose &gt; 400 mg/dl). 8. Subject has had a myocardial infarction(MI)(Qwave or NQWMI) within the previous 30 days. 9. Subject has had a stroke within the previous 30 days and/or has deficits from a prior stroke that limits the subjects ability to walk. 10. Subject has unstable angina defined as rest angina with ECG changes. 11. Subject has a groin infection, or an acute systemic infection that is currently under treatment. 12. Subject has acute thrombophlebitis or deep vein thrombosis in either extremity. 13. Subject requires any planned procedure within 30 days after the index procedure that would necessitate the discontinuation of aspirin, clopidogrel or ticlopidine following the procedure. 14. Subject has other medical illnesses (e.g., cancer or congestive heart failure) that may cause the subject to be noncompliant with protocol requirements, confound the data interpretation, or is associated with limited lifeexpectancy (i.e., less than 2 years). 15. Subject is currently participating in an investigational drug or device trial that has not completed the primary endpoint followup or that clinically interferes with the current trial endpoints. 16. Subject is unable to understand or unwilling to cooperate with trial procedures or is unwilling or unable to return to the treatment center for followup visits. 17. If intended stent is Absolute Pro, subject has known hypersensitivity or contraindication to nickel, titanium or platinum; subject has known hypersensitivity or contraindication to standard intraprocedure anticoagulant(s); subject has sensitivity to contrast which cannot be adequately pretreated with medication. 18. Subject has known allergy or contraindication to aspirin or clopidogrel (Plavix®); if allergy or contraindication is to clopidogrel, subject is unable to tolerate ticlopidine (Ticlid®). 19. Subject has known bleeding disorder or hypercoagulable disorder, or will refuse blood transfusions. 20. Subject has suffered a gastrointestinal (GI) bleed within 30 days before the index procedure that would interfere with antiplatelet therapy. 21. If intended stent is Omnilink Elite, subject has known hypersensitivity or contraindication to cobalt chromium; subject has known hypersensitivity or contraindication to standard intraprocedure anticoagulant(s); subject has sensitivity to contrast which cannot be adequately pretreated with medication. 22. Requirement of general anesthesia or spinal block for the procedure. 23. Presence of contralateral limb amputation that was performed to treat any nontraumatic disease in that limb, e.g. atherosclerotic, vascular, neuropathic. 24. Presence of bypass conduit in any outflow vessel, i.e. SFA, popliteal, anterior tibial, posterior tibial, peroneal, ipsilateral to the target lesion. 25. Subject requires a concomitant percutaneous endovascular procedure in another vessel, e.g. coronary. 26. Target lesion is in an iliac artery that has been previously stented. Angiographic Exclusion Criteria 1. Subject has a totally occluded (100% stenosis) external iliac artery ipsilateral to the target lesion. 2. Subject has a totally occluded (100% stenosis) outflow artery (SFA) ipsilateral to the target lesion 3. Target lesion is within or adjacent to an aneurysm. 4. Lesion is located within or beyond a vessel that contains a bypass graft. 5. Lesion(s) requires atherectomy (or ablative devices) to facilitate stent delivery. 6. Subject has a history of aortic revascularization or has an abdominal aortic aneurysm &gt; 3cm. 7. Lesion extends beyond the inguinal ligament. 8. Subject has angiographic evidence of thrombus in the target disease segment or vessel that is unresponsive to antithrombotic therapies. 9. Subject has multilevel disease in the target extremity that requires other staged procedures within 30 days before or after the procedure. 10. On the treatment side(s), subject is without patent superficial femoral and popliteal arteries and at least one patent distal outflow artery with inline distal vessel flow to the foot as confirmed by arteriography. Patent is defined as &lt; 50% stenosis. 11. Requirement for &gt; 1 stent to treat full length of lesion.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Atherosclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Peripheral artery disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Peripheral vascular disease</keyword>
	<keyword>PAD</keyword>
	<keyword>Claudication</keyword>
	<keyword>Peripheral Arterial Occlusive Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Stent</keyword>
	<keyword>PAOD</keyword>
	<keyword>PVD</keyword>
</DOC>