<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02748694</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics (PK) of TAK-041 following oral single and multiple doses in healthy participants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 1 TAK-041 First-in-Human Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The drug being tested in this study is called TAK-041. TAK-041 is being tested to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics (PK) of single and multiple doses of TAK-041 in healthy participants. The study will enroll approximately 40 participants. The study is composed of 2 parts. Part 1 (single-rising dose [SRD], alternating panel design) and Part 2 (multiple-rising dose [MRD], sequential panel design). Part 1 consists of 2 cohorts, participants will be randomly assigned to one of the two treatment sequences of 4 and 3 periods in cohorts 1 and 2 respectively: - TAK-041 5-400 mg - Placebo (inactive)- this is a similar formulation that looks like the study drug but has no active ingredient. Part 2 consists of 3 cohorts, participants will be randomly assigned to one of the two treatments. Dose levels and duration for Part 2 will be based on emerging safety/tolerability and PK data from Part 1. - TAK-041 - Placebo This single center trial will be conducted in the United States. Participants will remain confined to the study site from check-in (Day -1) through Days 5 of each period in part 1 and through Day 18 in Part 2. Participants will be contacted by telephone 14±2 days after the last dose of study drug for follow-up assessment.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. In the opinion of the investigator, the participant is capable of understanding and complying with protocol requirements 2. The participant signs and dates a written, informed consent form and any required privacy authorization prior to the initiation of any participant procedures including requesting that a participant fast for any laboratory evaluations 3. The participant is willing to comply with study restrictions described in the protocol 4. Healthy adult men and women (of nonchildbearing potential) 5. The participant is aged 18 to 55 years, inclusive, at the time of informed consent 6. Weighs at least 45 kg (99 lb) with a body mass index from 18 to 32 kg/m^2 7. A male participant who is nonsterilized and sexually active with a female partner of childbearing potential agrees to use adequate contraception form signing of informed consent throughout the duration of the study and for 184 days (i.e. 90 days after 5 halflives) have elapsed since the last dose of study drug 1. The participant has received any investigational compound within 30 days prior to the first dose of study drug 2. The participant is an immediate family member, study site employee, or is in a dependent relationship with a study site employee who is involved in the conduct of this study (e.g. spouse, parent, child, sibling) or may consent under duress 3. Has hypersensitivity to TAK041 4. Has a positive urine/blood drug result for drugs of abuse (defined as any illicit drug use) at Screening or Checkin (Day 1) 5. Has a history of drug abuse (defined as any illicit drug use) or a history of alcohol abuse (defined as 4 or more alcoholic beverages per day) within 1 year prior to the Screening Visit or is unwilling to agree to abstain from alcohol and drugs throughout the study 6. Has taken any excluded medication, supplements, or food products during the time periods listed in the protocol 7. If female, the participant is of childbearing potential (eg, premenopausal, not sterilized) 8. If male, the participant intends to donate sperm during the course of this study or within 90 days after 5 halflives have elapsed since the last dose of study drug 9. Evidence of current cardiovascular, central nervous system, hepatobiliary disease including history of biliary tree disorders and/or cholecystectomy, hematopoietic disease, renal dysfunction, metabolic or endocrine dysfunction, serious allergy, asthma, hypoxemia, hypertension, seizures, or allergic skin rash. There is any finding in the participant's medical history, physical examination, or safety laboratory test results (including elevated alkaline phosphatase [ALP], elevated bilirubin, elevated gammaglutamyl transferase [GGT], elevated 5'nucleotidase, elevated sorbitol dehydrogenase, or abnormal urine osmolality) that in the judgment of the principal investigator represents a reasonable suspicion of a disease that would contraindicate taking TAK041, or that might interfere with the conduct of the study. This includes, but is not limited to, peptic ulcer disease, seizure disorders, and cardiac arrhythmias 10. Has current or recent (within 6 months) gastrointestinal disease that would be expected to influence the absorption of drugs (i.e. a history of malabsorption, esophageal reflux, peptic ulcer disease, erosive esophagitis, frequent [more than once per week] occurrence of heartburn, or any surgical intervention) 11. Has a history of cancer, except basal cell carcinoma that has been in remission for at least 5 years prior to Day 1 12. Has a positive test result for hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody at Screening or a known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection 13. Has used nicotinecontaining products (including but not limited to cigarettes, pipes, cigars, chewing tobacco, nicotine patch or nicotine gum) within 21 days prior to Checkin on Day 1. Cotinine test is positive at Screening or Checkin (Day 1) 14. Has poor peripheral venous access 15. Has donated or lost 450 mL or more of his or her blood volume (including plasmapheresis), or had a transfusion of any blood product within 30 days prior to Day 1 16. Has a Screening or Checkin (Day 1) abnormal (clinically significant) ECG. Entry of any participant with an abnormal (not clinically significant) ECG must be approved, and documented by signature of the principal investigator or a medically qualified subinvestigator 17. Has a sustained resting heart rate outside the range of 50 to 100 beats per minute (bpm), confirmed on repeat testing within a maximum of 30 minutes at Screening or Checkin 18. Has a QT interval with Fridericia correction method (QTcF) &gt;450 ms or PR outside the range 120 to 220 ms, confirmed on repeat testing within a maximum of 30 minutes, at the Screening Visit or Checkin (Day 1) 19. Has abnormal Screening or Day 1 laboratory values that suggest a clinically significant underlying disease or participant with the following lab abnormalities: alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and/or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt;1.5 × the upper limits of normal. (ULN); alkaline phosphatase (ALP) &gt;1.5 x ULN in conjunction with elevated total bilirubin, GGT, 5'nucleotidase, AST, or ALT; ALP &gt; 2 x ULN persisting longer than 3 days; ALP &gt;3 x ULN, elevated sorbitol dehydrogenase, or abnormal urine osmolality 20. Has a clinically significant history of head injury or trauma 21. Has a risk of suicide according to the investigator's or subinvsetigator's clinical judgment or has made a suicide attempt in the previous 6 months Additional exclusion criteria for Part 2 Cohort 2 only: 1. Has had cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) collection performed within 30 days prior to Checkin 2. Has a known hypersensitivity to the anesthetic or its derivatives used during the CSF collection or any medication used to prepare the area of lumbar puncture 3. Has significant vertebral deformities (scoliosis or kyphosis) that, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with the lumbar puncture procedure 4. Has a history of clinically significant back pain and/or injury or in the opinion of the investigator 5. Has local infection at the puncture site 6. Has thrombocytopenia or other suspected bleeding tendencies noted before the procedure 7. Has developed signs and symptoms of spinal radiculopathy, including lower extremity pain and paresthesias 8. Has any focal neurological deficit that might suggest an increase in intracranial pressure 9. Has any abnormal findings on ophthalmological assessment/funduscopy indicative of raised intracranial pressure (i.e. optic disc swelling, or [uncontrolled] hypertensive retinopathy) 10. The participant suffers regularly from moderatetosevere headaches requiring analgesics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>