<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02748915</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this research is to evaluate the relationships between multiple data from cochlear implant (CI) adult users to and to estimate predictive models of their fitting parameters. In a group of patients, the Electrically-evoked Compound Action Potentials (ECAP) will be collected intra-operatively and the correlation with demographic data (deafness duration, age deafness onset, etiology, duration of cochlear implant use of CI), auditory performances and subjective measures used for implant fitting (hearing threshold and most comfortable level) will be calculated. In a second group of experienced users (more than 9months of use of their CI), ECAP and Electrically-evoked Auditory Brainstem Response (EABR) will be collected after 9 months of CI experience and after 12 months or more of use. Correlation analyzes with demographic data, performance and fitting parameters will be performed as well. Statistical predictive models for both fitting at the activation or in experienced users should be developed according to the correlation analysis. The secondary objective is to evaluate the effects of simultaneous stimulation on hearing performances. Simultaneous stimulations will be delivered in one ear (bimodal condition) in patients using an Electro-Acoustic Stimulation device (EAS) or in the two ears (binaural condition) for bilateral CI users. ECAP, EABR and speech perception will be measured and compared in the different conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Electrophysiological-based Estimation of Cochlear Implant Fitting</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Good general health status including no neuropsychological diseases affecting intellectual capacities Users of cochlear implant or electroacoustic stimulation devices Normal otoscopy No excessive sound exposure within 48h before the measure For women, possibility of pregnancy (absence of effective contraception or confirmed menopause); Concomitant use of ototoxic or psychotropic treatment with anxiolytic and / or antipsychotic</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cochlear Implant</keyword>
	<keyword>ECAP</keyword>
	<keyword>EABR</keyword>
	<keyword>perceptual levels</keyword>
	<keyword>hearing performances</keyword>
</DOC>