<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00890305</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial will be performed in previously untreated patients with metastatic colorectal cancer. The study will evaluate the safety, tolerability and efficacy of the study drug, CT-011, in combination with FOLFOX chemotherapy (FOLFOX4 or mFOLFOX6) compared with treatment by FOLFOX alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability and Efficacy of FOLFOX + CT-011 Versus FOLFOX Alone</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The proposed clinical trial will be a multi-center, randomized, open label, active control study in previously untreated patients with metastatic colorectal cancer aimed to evaluate the safety, tolerability and efficacy of the monoclonal antibody, CT-011, administered at 3mg/kg in combination with FOLFOX chemotherapy (FOLFOX4 or mFOLFOX6) compared with treatment by FOLFOX alone. Approximately 168 patients are planned to be enrolled to this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leucovorin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patient's age is 18 years or older, both genders. 2. Patients with metastatic disease who are eligible for first line FOLFOX chemotherapy. Adjuvant or neoadjuvant given at least 12 months prior for nonmetastatic disease is permitted. 3. ECOG performance status ≤ 1 4. At least 4 weeks from prior major surgery or radiotherapy. 5. Life expectancy &gt;3 months 6. Hematology: ANC ≥ 1.5X109/L; Platelets &gt;100x109/L. 7. Adequate Renal function 8. Adequate Hepatic functions 9. Normal Cardiac function 1. Patients who had adjuvant or neoadjuvant therapy for nonmetastatic disease given within the last 12 months. 2. Patients who had received Oxaliplatin within 12 months prior to diagnosis of metastatic disease. 3. Patients on concurrent anti cancer therapy other than that allowed in the study. 4. Patients on concurrent steroids, other than those allowed for routine antiemetics, or inhaled steroids 5. Presence of clinically apparent or suspected brain metastasis. 6. Patients who have had myocardial infarction, severe congestive heart failure, or significant arrhythmia within the past 6 months. 7. Serious active infection at the time of prestudy screening. 8. Active or history of autoimmune disorders/conditions. 9. Women who are pregnant or lactating 10. Concurrent active malignancy. 11. Ascites, pleural effusions, or osteoblastic bone metastases as the only site of disease. 12. Other prior malignancies, except for cured or adequately treated malignancies for which there has been no evidence of activity for more than 5 years. 13. Subjects with a condition which may interfere with the subjects' ability to understand the requirements of the study. 14. Patients with history of life threatening allergic reactions to food or drugs 15. Patients with symptomatic peripheral neuropathy&gt; Grade 1. 16. Known positive HIV, Hepatitis B surface antigen or Hepatitis C antibody.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic colorectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>FOLFOX chemotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>