<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00014781</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the amount of hepatic glucose production derived from gluconeogenesis and glycogenolysis in the post-absorptive state in patients with cystic fibrosis. II. Determine de novo lipogenesis in relationship to resting energy expenditure in this patient population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Hepatic Glucose Production and De Novo Lipogenesis in Patients With Cystic Fibrosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: Patients undergo an oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT) in which blood is drawn from an IV in the arm 6 times over 3 hours. After the first blood draw, patients receive a beverage containing sugar and write down everything they ate and drank during the 24 hours before study entry. Patients also undergo a dual energy x-ray absorptiometry (DEXA) scan over 15 minutes. Within 2 weeks after the OGTT, patients keep a journal of everything they ate and drank over 3 days. Patients are fed a selected meal the following evening and receive saline fluids IV overnight. During the night, patients receive 2 doses of oral doubly labeled water. The next morning, patients receive [1,2-13C]acetate IV. A liquid mixed meal (Ensure Plus) is ingested hourly throughout the day. Patients also undergo hood indirect calorimetry over 30 minutes twice to measure resting energy expenditure. All urine is collected.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Diagnosis of cystic fibrosis OR Normal healthy volunteer; not an endurancetrained athlete No colonization with Burkholderia cepacia Prior/Concurrent Therapy Endocrine therapy: At least 2 months since prior oral or IV corticosteroids; lowdose inhaled corticosteroids allowed Other: Shortacting insulin therapy allowed; at least 24 hours since prior longacting insulin (i.e., neutral protamine Hagedorn, or ultalente); at least 4 weeks since prior oral or IV antibiotics; no hospital admissions within the past 6 weeks Patient Characteristics Hepatic: No elevation of SGOT or SGPT within the past 3 months Other: Must be medically stable; diabetes mellitus allowed; weight stable within the past 3 months; not pregnant; no prisoners</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>cardiovascular and respiratory diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>cystic fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>genetic diseases and dysmorphic syndromes</keyword>
	<keyword>rare disease</keyword>
</DOC>