<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01231230</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The addition of an inhaled long-acting beta-adrenergic agonist to an inhaled glucocorticosteroid improves disease control in persistent asthma. This observation has supported the use of long-acting beta-adrenergic agonist/glucocorticosteroid combination preparations for the management of asthma. Currently, salmeterol/fluticasone and formoterol/budesonide are available for clinical use. The long-term beneficial clinical effects of the two drug classes seem to be synergistic, and several mechanisms of glucocorticoid-beta-adrenergic agonist interactions involving gene transcription have been invoked to explain this phenomenon.This study, wish to address the question whether glucocorticoids can acutely potentiate the bronchodilator response to a long-acting beta-adrenergic agonist.We expect that in patients with asthma, the short-term bronchodilator effect of salmeterol is enhanced by the addition of fluticasone, which by itself has no short-term bronchodilator effect. To test this premise, we will assess the respective short-term effects of salmeterol (50 µg), fluticasone (250 µg), salmeterol/fluticasone (50/250 µg), and placebo/placebo on spirometric parameters. Airway Blood flow will also be measured to ensure that vasoconstriction does not occur.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Interactive Acute Smooth Muscle Effects of Salmeterol and Fluticasone in the Airway</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Fourteen lifetime nonsmokers with a physician diagnosis of asthma will be recruited for the study. All subjects will be allowed to use short-acting beta-adrenergic agonists as rescue medication. Inclusion criteria: 1. Males and females, 18 to 65 years of age. 2. FEV1 60-85% of predicted on the screening day. Exclusion criteria: 1. Women of childbearing potential who do not use accepted birth control measures; pregnant and breast feeding women. 2. Cardiovascular disease and/or use of cardiovascular medications 2. Subjects with known beta-adrenergic agonist or glucocorticosteroid intolerance 4. Acute respiratory infection within four weeks prior to the study 5. Use, within two weeks prior to the study, of any anti-asthma medication not mentioned above</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Salmeterol Xinafoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone Propionate, Salmeterol Xinafoate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Males and females, 18 to 65 years of age. 2. FEV1 6085% of predicted on the screening day. 1. Women of childbearing potential who do not use accepted birth control measures; pregnant and breast feeding women. 2. Cardiovascular disease and/or use of cardiovascular medications 3. Subjects with known betaadrenergic agonist or glucocorticosteroid intolerance 4. Acute respiratory infection within four weeks prior to the study 5. Use, within two weeks prior to the study, of any antiasthma medication not mentioned above</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>asthma, corticosteroids, bronchodilator, airway blood flow</keyword>
</DOC>