<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01231178</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The project aims to examine the efficacy of a 12-week intake of alginate based ready to drink supplement on development in body weight and body composition, and risk markers for type-2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease in obese subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of an Alginate Based Beverage on Weight Loss</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study consists of a parallel RCT with 96 overweight/obese subjects enrolled into two treatment arms: placebo or active for 12 weeks. They will undergo examination at time points 0 and 12 weeks where a DXA scan will be performed to assess body composition and a fasting blood sample will be taken. At time points 0, 2, 4, 6, 8, 10 and 12 weeks their weight and waist circumference and number of test products not consumed will be recorded. In addition all subjects receive dietary counselling during the 12 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alginic acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy men and women Overweight to obese (BMI 2845 kg/m2) Chronic diseases including:liver and kidney disease, including PAlanine aminotransferase (ALT), Paspartate aminotransferase (AST), gammaglutamyltransferase (GGT), creatinine kinase and Plactate dehydrogenase (LD)&gt; 2.0 times the upper limit of normal (ULN) (measured at the screening at the Department of Human Nutrition) systemic infections and metabolic diseases that can interfere with energy balance, diabetes or fasting blood glucose concentration&gt; 7.0 mM, cardiovascular disease, systolic blood pressure ≥ 160 and / or a diastolic blood pressure ≥ 100 mmHg, hyperlipidemia (total cholesterol&gt; 6.5 mM and triglycerides&gt; 5.0 mM) (measured by the screening at the Department of Human Nutrition) Food allergies Psychiatric disorders and any clinical condition that makes the person unfit to participate in the experiment Use of dietary supplements (during the experimental period and 3 months before study start) Provision of blood for example. of donation or other scientific studies (during the trial and 3 months before study start) and hemoglobin &lt;7.5 mmol / l (measured at the screening at the Department of Human Nutrition) Smoking (throughout the trial and 6 months before study start) Elite Athletes (&gt; 10 hours strenuous exercise per week, selfreported) Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding, and postmenustruelle (self reported)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>