<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01231672</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A prognostic score was proposed by the investigative team to predict death at 1 month. This score is based on certain biological markers, scored under emergency conditions in the first 24 hours of routine clinical practice management for septic shock. The main objective of this multicenter study is to validate the performance of the score in terms of area under the ROC curve and negative predictive value.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Validation of Clini-biological Parameters Including Initial Hemostasis, Which Improve the Prediction of Death at 1 Month Among Patients With Septic Shock</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There are two secondary objectives: - Validate a prognostic score for death at the end of the first week from initial data. - Validate a predictive score of disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC) in patients with septic shock by comparing with the Gold Standard of the International Society on Thrombosis and Haemostasis (overt-DIC in the first 5 days after inclusion). As for the main objective, these scores are based on biological markers scored under emergency situations within the first 24 hours of routine clinical practice management for septic shock. The objectives and endpoints stated correspond to the protocol directly submitted to ethics authorities prior to the first inclusion and can be verified by contacting the Committee for the Protection of Persons Sud Mediterranée III (mail: CPP SUD-MEDITERRANEE III, UFR MEDECINE 186, chemin du Carreau de Lanes CS 83021, 30908 NIMES Cedex 2 FRANCE. Study reference: 2008.11.04 bis) For more information: carey.suehs@chu-nimes.fr</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Shock</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Shock, Septic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemostatics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patient (or representative) received the information notice patient has hemodynamic insufficiency of nontraumatic or cardiogenic origin associated with severe sepsis (treated with Noradrenalin) and organ dysfunction, hypoperfusion or hypotension body temperature &gt; 38.3°C or &lt; 36°C heart rate &gt; 90 bpm Tachypnea &gt; 20 C/min or PaCO2 &lt; 32 mmHg or mechanical ventilation leukocytes &gt; 12000 µL1 ou &lt; 4000 µL1 ou &gt; 10% immature forms oliguria &lt; 0.5 ml/kg/h for at least 2 hours abrupt alteration (24 h) of conscienceness thrombocytopenia &lt; 100 000 G/L or disseminated intravascular coagulation mottled skin and / or capillary refill time&gt; 3 sec PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 300 mmHg ou &lt; 40KPas Lactatemia &gt; 2mMol/l septic shock: Systolic Blood Pressure (SBP) &gt; 90 mmHg or need for vasopressors to maintain SBP&gt; 90 mmHg despite a prior filling (2030 ml / kg of macromolecules or 40 to 60 ml / kg of normal saline (or decrease in SBP&gt; 40% in the hypertensive) patient is dying or limitation or cessation of active treatment patient is already included in another trial patient or family refusal patient not affiliated with a social security system</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>