<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01001520</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will test the hypothesis that a medication called tolcapone (Brand Name: Tasmar) will help reduce cognitive problems that smokers experience when they quit. This study will also determine whether the benefits of this medication differ depending on a smokers' genetic background.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neural Substrates in Nicotine Withdrawal</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Tolcapone, an FDA-approved treatment for Parkinson's disease, improves cognitive performance in healthy controls with COMT val/val genotypes, putatively by increasing prefrontal dopamine levels. We propose a within-subject double-blind cross-over neuroimaging study of short-term (11 days) treatment with tolcapone (vs. placebo). Thirty chronic smokers (15 with val/val genotypes and 15 with val/met or met/met genotypes) will undergo blood oxygenation level dependent (BOLD) fMRI during the two medication periods: 1. after 24 hours of monitored abstinence while on tolcapone, and 2. after 24 hours of monitored abstinence while on placebo (medication order counterbalanced with at least a 10-day washout). The BOLD fMRI data will be acquired while subjects perform a working memory task (Fractal N-back), a sustained attention task (Continuous Performance Task; CPT), and a response inhibition task (Go/No-Go). The primary outcome is medication effects (within subject) on task-related BOLD activation after 24 hours of abstinence. Changes in behavioral performance and subjective symptoms will be examined in relation to brain activity changes. The proposed study will provide a critical mechanistic understanding of the role of COMT in abstinence-induced cognitive symptoms that promote smoking relapse. Information obtained in this study may further establish cognitive performance measures as endophenotypes for nicotine dependence.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tobacco Use Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nicotine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tolcapone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Smokers who are between 18 and 65 years of age who selfreport smoking at least 10 cigarettes (menthol and nonmenthol) per day for at least the last 6 months. Healthy as determined by the Study Physician, based on a medical evaluation including medical history and physical examination, psychiatric evaluation, and liver function tests (LFTs and GGT enzyme levels). Capable of giving written informed consent, which includes compliance with the requirements and restrictions listed in the combined consent and HIPAA form. Women of childbearing potential must consent to use a medically accepted method of birth control while participating in the study (e.g., condoms and spermicide, oral contraceptive, Depoprovera injection, contraceptive patch, tubal ligation) and have 3 months of regular menstrual cycles. Capable of providing a Carbon Monoxide (CO) breath test reading greater than 10 parts per million (ppm) at the medical screening visit. Smoking behavior Current enrollment or plans to enroll in another research or smoking cessation program in the next 3 months. Provide a CO reading less than or equal to 10ppm at the medical screening visit. Plans to use nicotine substitutes (gum, patch, lozenge, ecigarette) while enrolled in the study. Alcohol/Drug Exclusion: History (past 2 years) or current diagnosis of substance abuse and/or currently receiving treatment for substance abuse (alcohol, THC, cocaine, PCP, amphetamines, methamphetamines, MDMA/ecstasy, opiates, methadone, benzodiazepines, tricyclic antidepressants, and barbiturates). Current alcohol consumption that exceeds 21 standard drinks/week over the last 6 months. Positive urine drug screen (for substances listed previously) at the medical screening visit or either testing day. Breath Alcohol Concentration (BrAC) assessment greater than or equal to 0.01 at medical screening visit or either testing day. Medication Current use or recent discontinuation (within last 28 days) of any medication including the following: Any form of psychotropic medications including: Antipsychotics; Moodstabilizers (e.g., lithium, valproic acid, carbamazepine/tegretol); Antidepressants (tricyclics, SSRI's, MAOI's, nonselective MAOIs, Wellbutrin, St. John's Wort); Antianxiety/Antipanic agents; Antiobsessive agents; Prescription stimulants (e.g., Provigil, Ritalin); Diet Pills/Anorectics; Systemic Steroids; Daily medication for chronic pain (e.g., opiates) or muscle spasms; Daily use of over the counter stimulants in pill form (e.g., ephedrine) Anticoagulants (e.g., Warfarin) Any heart medications (e.g., dobutamine, isoproterenol) Daily medication for asthma Parkinson's disease medications (e.g., levodopa, methyldopa, apomorphine) Sympathomimetic (e.g., albuterol, pseudoephedrine) Other smoking cessation medications (Wellbutrin/Zyban, Chantix/varenicline) Medical Women who are pregnant, planning a pregnancy within the next 3 months, or lactating. History or current diagnosis of any Axis 1 disorder as identified by the MINI (Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview) or selfreport. For major depression, only a current diagnosis will be exclusionary. History or current diagnosis of AttentionDeficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD). Serious or unstable disease (e.g., cancer within the past 6 months [except squamous cell carcinoma], HIV, Parkinson's disease). History of epilepsy or a seizure disorder. History or current diagnosis (last 6months) of abnormal rhythms and/or tachycardia (&gt;100 beats/minute); history or current diagnosis of COPD, cardiovascular disease (stroke, angina, coronary heart disease); heart attack in the last 6 months; uncontrolled hypertension (SBP&gt;150 or DBP&gt;90). History or current kidney and/or liver failure (including transplant), disease, or impairment (e.g., cirrhosis); history or current diagnosis of hepatitis (excluding hepatitis A); liver function tests more than 20% outside of the normal range; Gammaglutamyl Transpepsidase (GGT) values greater than 20% outside the normal range. Allergy to the study medication, tolcapone (Tasmar). History of severe, uncontrolled muscle movements (e.g., uncontrolled jerking, twitching) or a certain severe muscle problem (rhabdomyolysis). Low or borderline intellectual functioning determined by receiving a score of less than 90 on the Shipley Institute of Living Scale (SILS) which correlates with the Wechsler Adult Intelligence ScaleRevised (WAISR) Estimated IQ Test (administered at the medical screening visit). Experience of dizziness or lightheadedness upon standing on a daily basis. Lifetime history of stroke. fMRI Selfreported history of claustrophobia. Lefthandedness. Color blindness. Any impairment preventing subjects from using response pad necessary for cognitive testing. Circumstances or conditions that may interfere with magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). Having a cochlear implant or wearing bilateral hearing aids. Selfreported history of head trauma (including being knocked unconscious for 3 minutes or greater and diagnosis of a concussion) or CNS tumor. Selfreported use of pacemakers, certain metallic implants, or presence of metal in the eye as contraindicated for MRI. History of gunshot wound. Weight greater than 300lbs. at medical screening or either testing day. Completion of cognitive testing in study #810493 or #811325 within the last 6 months. Genetic Profile In order to balance the distribution of males and females, some participants who meet genotype and other eligibility criteria may not be enrolled in the study. General Any medical condition or concomitant medication that could compromise subject safety or treatment, as determined by the Principal Investigator and/or Study Physician. Inability to provide informed consent or complete any of the study tasks as determined by the Principal Investigator and/or Study Physician.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Genetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Nicotine</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognition</keyword>
	<keyword>fMRI</keyword>
</DOC>