<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01900444</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to document the immunogenicity and safety of a booster dose of IMOJEV® administered 12 months after the primary dose. Primary objective: - To describe the immune response to Japanese Encephalitis (JE) before (Day 0) and 28 days (Day 28) after a booster dose of IMOJEV® administered at least 1 year after primary vaccination with IMOJEV®. Exploratory objectives: - To test the non-inferiority of IMOJEV® versus previous data obtained in the JEC15 study (NCT01190228) with the same product in terms of seroprotection rate 28 days after booster vaccination. - To describe the safety profile of a booster dose of IMOJEV® .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of a Booster Dose of IMOJEV® Vaccine One Year After Primary Immunization in Healthy Children in South Korea</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All participants who previously participated in Study JEC12 (NCT 01396512) and were primed with IMOJEV® vaccine will receive a single booster dose of IMOJEV® vaccine 12 months after the primary dose. They will be assessed for immune response before and on Day 28 after the booster dose and will be monitored for safety through Day 28. The duration of each participant's participation in the study will be approximately 6 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Encephalitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Encephalitis, Japanese</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must have participated in study JEC12 and received 1 dose of IMOJEV® at least 12 months before booster vaccination Age 2 to 4 years on the day of inclusion In good general health at the time of inclusion Informed Concent Form signed and dated by parent(s) or another legally acceptable representative(s) Subject and parent(s)/legally acceptable representative(s) able to attend all scheduled visits and comply with all study procedures. Participation at the time of study enrollment (or in the 4 weeks preceding the trial vaccination) or planned participation during the present trial period in another clinical study investigating a vaccine, drug, medical device, or a medical procedure in the 4 weeks preceding the study vaccination Known or suspected congenital or acquired immunodeficiency, or receipt of immunosuppressive therapy such as anticancer chemotherapy or radiation therapy within the preceding 6 months, or longterm systemic corticosteroids therapy Known systemic hypersensitivity to any of the vaccine components, or history of a lifethreatening reaction to the vaccine used in the trial or to a vaccine containing any of the same substances Chronic illness that, in the opinion of the investigator, is at a stage where it might interfere with trial conduct or completion Receipt of immune globulins, blood or bloodderived products in the past 3 months, that might interfere with the assessment of the immune response Previous vaccination against flavivirus disease, including JE, with another vaccine, except with IMOJEV® while participating in JEC12 Administration of any antiviral within 2 months preceding Visit 1 and up to the 4 weeks following the study vaccination Receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks preceding the trial vaccination or planned receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks following the trial vaccination, except for inactivated influenza vaccination, which may be received at least 2 weeks before the study vaccine History of central nervous system disorder or disease, including seizures Planned receipt of any JE vaccine during the course of the study History of flavivirus infection (confirmed either clinically, serologically or virologically) Administration of systemic corticosteroids for more than 2 consecutive weeks within the 4 weeks preceding vaccination Thrombocytopenia, contraindicating vaccination Bleeding disorder, or receipt of anticoagulants in the 3 weeks preceding inclusion, contraindicating vaccination Febrile illness (temperature ≥38.0°C) or moderate or severe acute illness/infection 3 days before vaccination as well as the day of vaccination, according to Investigator judgment. A prospective subject should not be included in the study until the condition has resolved or the febrile event has subsided In an emergency setting or hospitalized involuntarily Identified as a natural or adopted child of the Investigator or employee with direct involvement in the proposed study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>4 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Japanese encephalitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Japanese encephalitis chimeric virus vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>IMOJEV®</keyword>
</DOC>