<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01900288</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test Mobile Technologies in Assisting Patients &amp; Family Caregivers in Healthy Living and complex home care by connecting to information and professionals from a distance.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Home Parenteral Nutrition (HPN) Families' Mobile Distance Connections to Care Research</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>HPN (Home Parenteral Nutrition) families with TPN (Total Parenteral Nutrition) users are typically geographically distant from one another (peers) as well as professional providers. Real-time mobile access to health related information, peer and professional support will be tested in this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Short Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malabsorption Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>13 years or older total parenteral nutrition (TPN) patients/users and family members/caregivers (defined as those individuals involved in daily home HPN care) TPN users (also called HPN users) must be receiving intravenous nutrition for a nonmalignant short bowel disorder Read, write, speak English and provide informed consent Be able to participate in group clinic visits enteral nutrition dependency only less than 13 years of age 13 through 17 years of age without parental consent currently enrolled in an intervention study or HPN management program severe cognitive impairment disability disorders (e.g. blindness which cannot be accommodated for active participation in the group clinics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>short bowel disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>short bowel syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>home parenteral nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>HPN</keyword>
	<keyword>total parenteral nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>TPN</keyword>
	<keyword>telehealth</keyword>
	<keyword>telemedicine</keyword>
</DOC>