<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01900431</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: To evaluate the efficacy of sarilumab at week 16 in patients with non-infectious uveitis (NIU). Secondary Objectives: To evaluate the change in best corrected visual acuity (BCVA). To evaluate the safety of subcutaneous sarilumab in patients with NIU. To evaluate the change in macular edema. To evaluate the change in other signs of ocular inflammation. To evaluate the effect on retinal vessel leakage. To evaluate the effect of sarilumab on reducing concomitant immunosuppressant therapy. To evaluate the change in ocular inflammation in the anterior chamber. To evaluate the pharmacokinetics of sarilumab in NIU patients. To evaluate the immunogenicity with anti-drug antibodies (ADA).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II Study to Analyze Sarilumab in Non-Infectious Uveitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The total duration per patient is up to 58 weeks, which includes a 2 week screening period, 16 weeks principal treatment period, 34 weeks extension treatment period (or open label treatment period), and 6 weeks after last treatment administration. Non-responder patients, observed within the first 16 weeks, will be offered to be treated by open-label sarilumab. Patients will be treated for 34 extra weeks (up to 18 extra injections).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Uveitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leucovorin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levoleucovorin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: ≥18 years of age. Noninfectious intermediate, posterior, or panuveitis in the study eye. Active disease at screening or evidence of activity within the 3 months prior to screening visit. Following the approval of Amendment 2, only patients with "active disease" as defined above will be enrolled in the study. Starting oral prednisone dose must be greater than or equal to 15 mg/day and less than 80 mg/day. At screening, patients must be receiving oral prednisone (≥15 mg and &lt; 80 mg/day [or equivalent oral corticosteroid]) as single immunosuppressive therapy or in combination with Methotrexate (MTX) (≤ 25 mg/week) orally or intravenously or intra muscular or subcutaneous). Patients can be receiving one or several of the following therapies: Azathioprine (≤2.5 mg/kg/day), Mycophenolate mofetil (≤2g daily, orally), Cyclosporine (≤4 mg/kg daily, orally), Tacrolimus (≤4 mg daily, orally). The doses may not have been increased for at least 4 weeks prior to the randomization visit. At randomization, patients have been receiving oral prednisone (≥15 mg and &lt; 80 mg/day [or equivalent oral corticosteroid]) as single immunosuppressive therapy or in combination with methotrexate (MTX) (≤ 25 mg/week) orally or intravenously or intra muscular or subcutaneous). Azathioprine, mycophenolate mofetil, cyclosporine and tacrolimus have to be permanently discontinued at least 48 hours prior to the first study treatment injection, or longer as per Investigator's judgment. These immunomodulatory therapy (IMTs) are not permitted anytime during the treatment period. Signed written informed consent. Exclusion criteria: Patient with bestcorrected visual acuity worse than 20 ETDRS letters in at least one eye. Patient with confirmed or suspected uveitis of infectious etiology or uveitis of traumatic etiology. Patient with primary diagnosis of anterior uveitis. Prior treatment with antiIL6 or IL6R antagonist therapies, including tocilizumab and sarilumab. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>