<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00250705</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The proposed study will be a 6-week open label study evaluating aripiprazole in the treatment of 12 male post-pubertal adolescents (13-17 years, Tanner Stage 4) diagnosed with conduct disorder. The initial dose depending on the weight of the patient will be as follows: &lt; 25 kg = 1 mg/d; 25-50 kg = 2 mg/d; 50-70 kg = 5 mg/d; &gt; 70 kg = 10 mg/d (Data on File, 2003, Bristol-Myers Squibb). For the first two weeks of the study, the dose will be flexible based on response and tolerance and thereafter will remain fixed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial of Aripiprazole in the Treatment of CD in Adolescents</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The use of atypical antipsychotics in children began in 1992 with several small case series with clozapine. Since that time, five other atypical agents, risperidone, olanzapine, quetiapine, ziprasidone and aripiprazole have been introduced into the US market. The newer atypical agents are not associated with agranulocytosis that has limited the usefulness of clozapine. Among the atypical antipsychotics, risperidone has remained the most extensively studied in children and adolescents, for a variety of problems, including Tourette's disorder, conduct disorder, schizophrenia, aggression, and pervasive development disorder. Risperidone has been shown to be an effective treatment in many of these disorders. However, weight gain, hyperprolactinemia, and extrapyramidal symptoms (EPS) are troublesome adverse effects more commonly associated with risperidone such that the drug's utility in this aged patient population is limited. We expect that the utility of aripiprazole in treating the pediatric population will not be limited by adverse effects like the other atypical antipsychotics.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Conduct Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aripiprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male postpubertal adolescents (1317 years, Tanner Stage 4) diagnosed with conduct disorder. Clinically significant laboratory and/or ECG abnormalities Preexisting health conditions that would compromise patient safety Mental retardation Previous use of aripiprazole Active psychosis</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Aripiprazole</keyword>
</DOC>