<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02400762</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to collect on-label safety and efficacy data where InQu Bone Graft Extender is applied to transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion (TLIF) and posterior lumbar interbody fusion (PLIF). It is expected that this study will contribute to the compilation of clinical data required to demonstrate the ability of InQu to promote safe, effective and timely spine fusion in patients who undergo PLIF or TLIF surgery. The results of this study will lead to further analysis (i.e. comparison to historical data of other marketed bone graft products, as well as, to local bone alone).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Study of Safety and Efficacy of InQu® Bone Graft Extender in Lumbar Interbody Fusion Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to collect on-label safety and efficacy data where InQu Bone Graft Extender is applied to transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion (TLIF) and posterior lumbar interbody fusion (PLIF) at multiple clinical sites. Adverse events, time to fusion and Patient Reported Outcomes(PROs) will be recorded through 12 months follow-up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Intervertebral Disc Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A subject may be included if s/he meets the following criteria: 1. ≥18 years of age; 2. Able to give appropriate informed consent; 3. Willing and able to meet the proposed followup schedule; 4. Has documented diagnosis of up to, and including, Grade 1 spondylolisthesis and/or degenerative disc disease; 5. Has given appropriate consent for, and undergoes, standardofcare transforminal or posterior lumber interbody fusion; 6. Use of InQu Bone Graft Extender onlabel. 1. Any prior lumbar fusion surgery; 2. Requires fusion surgery of more than two adjacent levels; 3. Has fusion surgery requiring titanium cages; 4. Has a systemic infection or has infection at the site of surgery; 5. Has a medical condition or requires postoperative medication that, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with bony/soft tissue healing; 6. Has any physical, social, psychological or economic condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, may preclude accurate data collection or evaluation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>