<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01164618</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the effects of repeated RIPC and exercise, on exercise performance, skeletal muscle responses and circulating cellular and humoral biology in humans</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Biology of Chronic Preconditioning: Genomic and Physiologic Mechanisms of Response</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Remote ischemic preconditioning (RIPC) results in a powerful and widespread protective effect against subsequent prolonged ischemia-reperfusion (IR) injury of distant organs and systemic inflammatory responses, both of which are key elements in the evolution of local and multiorgan effects of many clinical IR syndromes. The signal transduction within the target organ to generate ischemia tolerance, and the effects of RIPC on systemic anti-inflammatory pathways, however, remain to be elucidated fully. Particularly, data regarding the mechanisms of 'second window' protection (a resurgence of protection 24-72 hrs after the initial RIPC stimulus) is scant; even less is known of the effects of repeated RIPC, and a potential 'third window' of protection. Our preliminary data and several recent publications have shown that the biology of RIPC and exercise show considerable overlap. This research has raised the possibility of a reciprocal effect between RIPC and exercise, with chronic exercise being a model of the potential effects of 'chronic preconditioning'. This is relevant, as repeated RIPC might be a strategy to improve exercise function in those with limited exercise tolerance e.g. heart failure.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Age ≥ 18 years, 2. Informed consent 1. Contraindication to exercise, 2. Vigorous aerobic/anaerobic exercise in duration of ≥15 minutes during the 21 days prior to commencement of the study, or either of the RIPC or exercise protocol arms, 3. Overt viral or bacterial infection in the 10 days prior to commencement of the study, or during either of the RIPC or exercise protocol arms, 4. Alcohol and/or caffeine consumption in the 10 days prior to, or at any time during the study period 5. Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>pediatrics</keyword>
	<keyword>Remote ischemic preconditioning</keyword>
</DOC>