<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01834833</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluate the benefit of systematic appointment with a cardiologist a week after hospitalisation for acute heart failure. Randomised, endpoint: number of day alive out of hospital during 6 months</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Consultation at 8 Days to Reduce Hospitalisations in Heart Failure Patient</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: the risk for rehospitalisation is very high after hospitalisation for acute heart failure. Aim: evaluate the benefit of a consultation with a cardiologist, including echocardiography and education of the patient, between 7 and 15 days after discharge, in high risk patients, identified with BNP or incomplete therapy. Parallel randomised study. The main endpoint is the number of day alive out of hospital during the 6 months post discharge; statistics intention to treat comparison of the number of days alive out of hospital in the group with consultation compared with the group without consultation. Recruitment 3 years and 4 months, follow-up 6 months. Patients included have been hospitalised in hospital BICHAT 75018 Paris, France. Financing is by the ministry of health (PHRQHOS)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Criteria of inclusion : Patient with decompensated heart failure hospitalized in the hospital BICHAT, For whom is planned a return at home, Valid (being able to return for a consultation to the hospital) Having NtProBNP of exit ≥ 3500 ng /l and/or a non optimized treatment of exit according to the doctor who has it the responsibility, Having signed the consent form by participation in the study. Criteria of not inclusion : Age &lt; 18 years, Not membership in a national insurance scheme or in the Universal Health Coverage (CMU)(FREE UNIVERSAL HEALTH CARE)(A patient benefiting from the Medical aid of the State (AME) cannot be included) Participation to another protocol of research, Not being reachable by telephone in 6 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute heart failure; rehospitalisation; education; follow-up</keyword>
</DOC>