<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01834053</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is Single arm, Single Centre trial to check the Safety and Efficacy of Bone Marrow Derived Autologous mononuclear cell {MNC} (100 Million per dose).trial to be conducted for 36 months in patients with diabetes Mellitus in India,Primary outcome measure are Improvement in cognitive and Psychiatric Symptoms and Improvement in Jerky,random, and Uncontrollable Movements called Chorea.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Bone Marrow Derived MNCs for Treatment of Cells for the Treatment of Hunting Tons Chorea.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is Single arm, Single Centre trial study the Safety and Efficacy of Bone Marrow Derived Autologous mononuclear cells (MNCs) ,to be conducted for 36 months in patients with diabetes Mellitus in India,Primary outcome measure are Improvement in cognitive and Psychiatric Symptoms and Improvement in Jerky,random, and Uncontrollable Movements called Chorea.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Huntington Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient should suffer from Hunting tons Chorea, Hunting tons chorea commonly become noticeable between the ages of 35 44 Willingness to undergo Bone Marrow derived Autologous cell Therapy. Ability to comprehend the explained protocol and thereafter give an informed consent as well as sign the required Informed Consent form(ICF) for the study. Ability and willingness to regular visit to hospital for protocol procedures and follow up Patient with History of Immunodeficiency HIV+,Hepatitis B virus ( HBV) and History of Life threatening allergic or immune Mediated Reaction. the site of bone marrow aspiration potentially limiting Procedure. alcohol and drug abuse / dependence. Severe skin infection. Haemodynamically unstable. =subject with primary and secondary diabetes , Insulin dependence. Neurological disease caused by autoimmune or genetic cause. patients suffering from peripheral muscular dystrophy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>44 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Huntington Disease,stem cell therapy</keyword>
</DOC>