<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01702909</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether Interleukin-2 at the dose and schedule used in this study will help increase tumor shrinkage.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Interleukin-2 in Metastatic Kidney Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this phase II study, the IL-2 schedule (daily IL-2 for 5 days (per week) every 3 weeks) will be tested in a cohort of kidney cancer patients to attempt to determine the response rate, median duration of response, and median survival. The dose intensity of this schedule would allow a patient treated on this regimen to achieve the target threshold (&gt; 1440 million IU/m2/year).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interleukin-2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients must have a histologic diagnosis of metastatic kidney cancer. Patients may have received prior systemic therapy or may be previously untreated 2. Patients must have bidimensional measurable disease on physical exam or radiologic studies. 3. ECOG performance status of 0 or 1 and estimated survival of at least 3 months. 4. White blood count of &gt; 3500/mm3, platelet count &gt; 100,000/mm3, hemoglobin &gt; 9.0 gm/dl; bilirubin, ALT, AST &lt; 3 x upper limit of normal; serum creatinine &lt; 2.0 mg/dl. 5. Patients must undergo a lowlevel cardiac stress test as a screen for possible atherosclerotic heart disease. Patients with a positive stress test would be excluded from this trial. 6. Patients with elevated temperatures &gt; 100.5 F must have sources of occult infection excluded. 7. Patients must be felt to have recovered from effects of prior therapy, such as &gt; 2 weeks after prior chemotherapy. 8. Patient consent must be obtained prior to entrance onto study. 9. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test and must take adequate precautions to prevent pregnancy during treatment 1. Medical illness requiring corticosteroids or other immunosuppressive agents (such as cyclosporin or methotrexate. 2. Autoimmune disease such as inflammatory arthritis which could be exacerbated by immunebased therapy. 3. Prior history of psychiatric disorder which could be exacerbated by interleukin2. 4. Lactation or pregnancy. 5. Evidence of significant cardiovascular disease including history of recent (&lt; 6 months prior) myocardial infarction, congestive heart failure, primary cardiac arrhythmias (not due to electrolyte disorder or drug toxicity, for example) beyond occasional PVC's, angina, positive lowlevel stress test, or cerebrovascular accident. 6. Current brain metastasis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic Renal Cell</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic Kidney Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>