<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01702363</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of GSK573719 Inhalation Powder 125 mcg once-daily over 52 weeks in Japanese subjects with COPD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-term Safety Study for GSK573719 in Japanese</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) treatment guidelines recommend an incremental approach to pharmacological treatment as the disease state worsens, involving the use of combinations of drug classes with different or complementary mechanisms of action [Celli, 2004, GOLD 2009]. As disease progresses from mild to moderate, regular treatment with one or more long-acting bronchodilators is recommended. Inhaled bronchodilators, including beta2 agonists and anticholinergics are included with inhaled corticosteroids (ICS) therapy and are mainstays of therapy in patients diagnosed with COPD. Since GSK573719 Inhalation Powder is expected to be used for chronic management of COPD as long-acting muscarinic antagonist (LAMA), this study is intended to evaluate the safety and tolerability of long-term administration of GSK573719 Inhalation Powder 125 mcg in Japanese patients with COPD at doses possibly used to be in Japan. In this study, patient safety will also be monitored by evaluating pulmonary function and clinical symptoms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Outpatient. A signed and dated written informed consent prior to study participation. Japanese subjects 40 years of age or older at Visit 1. Male or female subjects. A female is eligible if she is of: Nonchild bearing potential or Child bearing potential agrees to one of the contraceptive methods. Subjects with a clinical history of COPD in accordance with the definition by COPD domestic guideline. Current or former cigarette smokers with a history of cigarette smoking of &gt;=10 packyears at Visit 1. Subject with a measured postsalbutamol forced expiratory volume/forced vital capacity (FEV1/FVC) ratio of &lt;70% and Subjects with a measured postsalbutamol FEV1 &lt;80% of predicted normal values. Exclusion Criteria (Visit 1): Women who are pregnant or lactating or are planning on becoming pregnant during the study. A current diagnosis of asthma. Known respiratory disorders other than COPD. Subjects with historical or current evidence of clinically significant abnormalities that are uncontrolled. A chest Xray or computed tomography (CT) scan that reveals evidence of clinically significant abnormalities not believed to be due to the presence of COPD. Allergy or hypersensitivity to muscarinic, beta2agonist, lactose/milk protein or magnesium stearate or a condition that contraindicates participation. Hospitalization for COPD or pneumonia within 12 weeks prior to Visit 1. Subjects with lung volume reduction surgery within the 12 months prior to Screening (Visit 1). An abnormal and significant ECG finding from the 12lead ECG conducted at Visit 1. Significantly abnormal finding from clinical chemistry or hematology, tests at Visit 1. Use of longterm oxygen therapy (LTOT) described as oxygen therapy prescribed for greater than 12 hours a day. Regular use (prescribed every day, not for asneeded use) of shortacting bronchodilators (e.g., salbutamol) via nebulized therapy. Participation in the acute phase of a pulmonary rehabilitation program within 4 weeks prior to Visit 1. A known or suspected history of alcohol or drug abuse within 2 years prior to Visit 1. Affiliation with Investigator Site. Previous use of GSK573719, the GSK573719/GW642444 combination. Use of any other investigational medication within 30 days or 5 drug halflives (whichever is longer). Exclusion Criteria (Visit 2): COPD Exacerbation during runin period: Subject must not have experienced a COPD exacerbation or a lower respiratory tract infection during runin or at Visit 2.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD), GSK573719, Pharmacogenetics</keyword>
</DOC>