<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00961675</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of FST-201 compared to Ciprodex in the treatment of acute otitis externa. This study will be conducted at one site, the LBJ Tropical Medical Center, Department of Otolaryngology, in Pago Pago, American Samoa.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>FST-201 in the Treatment of Acute Otitis Externa</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The proposed clinical trial will evaluate the efficacy of FST-201 (dexamethasone 0.1% ) Otic Suspension vs. the FDA-approved drug Ciprodex (ciprofloxacin 0.3%, dexamethasone 0.1%) Otic Suspension (Alcon Laboratories, Inc.) in the treatment of acute otitis externa. Acute otitis externa is a common inflammatory condition of the external auditory canal often associated with infection, allergy and dermatitis. The active ingredient in our novel dexamethasone suspension is identical in concentration and route of administration to the steroid component of the approved drug Ciprodex, which is currently the most widely-prescribed dexamethasone-containing agent in the treatment of acute otitis externa. We will enroll 60 patients (30 each in two separate treatment groups) in this trial. All patients electing to participate in this study will receive either FST-201 or Ciprodex. FST-201 and Ciprodex will be masked and provided free of charge to all study participants. Patients will be followed for at least 15 days or until their ear inflammation is either resolved or determined to need additional interventions. The study will be conducted with attention to all relevant GCP, ICH, FDA, HIPPA and Declaration of Helsinki guidelines.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Otitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Otitis Externa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ciprofloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Povidone-Iodine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Povidone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Study participants must: Have a clinical diagnosis of AOE in one or both ears, defined as a clinical score of at least 1 for edema (03 scale), 2 for overall inflammation (03 scale) and 1 for tenderness (absent=0, present=1) Be at least 18 years of age at Visit 1 (Day 1, Screening/Baseline) of either sex and any race Study participants must NOT: Have known sensitivity to any component of the study medications Have a current infection requiring systemic antimicrobial treatment Have used topical or systemic pain meds on the same day as Screening/Baseline Visit 1 and for the duration of the study. Take any systemic (within 30 days) or otic corticosteroids (within 1 days) prior to Screening/Baseline Visit 1 Current use of topical or systemic nonsteroidal or other antiinflammatory drugs Use any topical otic treatment with alcohol, vinegar, hydrogen peroxide or other astringent medication during the course of the study or on the same day as Screening/Baseline Visit 1 Have taken any antibiotics within 3 days prior to Visit 1 Have signs and symptoms of AOE for &gt; 4 weeks at Screening/Baseline Visit 1 Have a clinical diagnosis of malignant otitis externa; Have overt fungal AOE Have a viral infection of the pinna or tympanic membrane (i.e herpes zoster) Have congenital abnormalities of the external auditory canal in the enrolled ear(s) Have obstructive bony exostoses in the enrolled ear(s); Have mastoid or other suppurative, noninfectious ear disorders (e.g, cholesteatoma) Have malignant tumors of the external auditory canal Have a history of otologic surgery. Surgery performed more than 1 year prior to Screening/Baseline Visit 1and limited to the tympanic membrane is allowed Have seborrheic dermatitis of the external auditory canal Have a current or prior history of immunosuppressive disorders Be pregnant, nursing or planning a pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>otitis</keyword>
	<keyword>acute</keyword>
	<keyword>externa</keyword>
	<keyword>ear</keyword>
</DOC>