<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00961857</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A two-part study to demonstrate the bioequivalence of a single dose of the Final Market Image (FMI) of sitagliptin /metformin (50/500 and 50/1000 mg) Fixed-Dose Combination (FDC) tablet and co-administration of a single dose of sitagliptin (50 mg) and metformin ( 500 or 1000 mg) as individual tablets. Subject will only participate in one part, receiving treatment A and B (Part I) or Treatment C and D (Part II).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Demonstrate the Bioequivalence of Sitagliptin/Metformin Combination Tablets and Concomitant Administration of Sitagliptin and Metformin as Individual Tablets (0431A-048)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sitagliptin Phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female subjects of reproductive potential test negative for pregnancy and agree to use appropriate contraception Subject is in good health and is a nonsmoker Subject is willing to avoid strenuous physical activity during the study Subject agrees to refrain from eating grapefruit or grapefruit products during the study Subject has a history of neoplastic disease (cancer), stroke, chronic seizures, or major neurological disorder. Subject has a history of clinically significant endocrine, gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, hematological, hepatic, immunological, renal, respiratory, or genitourinary abnormalities or diseases Subject consumes excessive amounts of alcohol or caffeinated beverages Subject has donated blood, had surgery or participated in another clinical study within the past 4 weeks Subject has a history of significant multiple and/or severe allergies to prescription or nonprescription drugs or food Subject has a history of hypersensitivity to metformin, sitagliptin, or sitagliptin/Metformin Subject is a regular user or past abuser of any illicit drugs Subject is unable to refrain from or anticipates the use of any medication, including prescription and nonprescription drugs or herbal remedies during the study. Subject is a nursing mother</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>