<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00837590</DOC>
	<brief_summary>We intend to pursue the following Aims: 1. Does inflammation contribute importantly to concurrent defects in vascular and metabolic dysfunction in human pre-diabetic obesity? 2. Are there benefits of anti-inflammatory treatment strategies in pre-diabetic obesity in the context of existing treatment with metformin? 3. Are there benefits of anti-inflammatory treatment strategies in pre-diabetic obesity in the context of existing treatment with lisinopril? The intent of the current project is to efficiently and at low cost generate preliminary data along each of these lines of questioning, studying the minimum number of subjects required to assess the viability of the question using the current measurement approaches.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vascular Function, Endothelin, and Inflammation in Pre-diabetic Obesity Versus Lean Healthy Controls</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prediabetic State</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucose Intolerance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lisinopril</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sodium Salicylate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Salicylsalicylic acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>healthy normotensive (BP&lt;140/95 mmHg) lean and obese 18 and 55 years women must be premenopausal use of pharmacologic agents or recreational drugs, with the exception of occasional use of nonnarcotic pain medications blood pressure (&gt;140/90 mmHg) elevated cholesterol (LDL &gt;130 mg/dL) diabetes mellitus (by ADA criteria) evidence of coronary and/or peripheral vascular disease by history and physical exam &gt;5 kg change in weight in the preceding 3 months chronic systemic illness with recognized metabolic effects hepatitis C and HIV recognized systemic inflammatory or autoimmune processes such as rheumatoid arthritis or systemic lupus erythematosis Raynaud's phenomenon or other abnormalities of hand or finger perfusion regular participation in endurance or highperformance athletic activity history of aspirin or salsalate sensitivity including aspirininduced asthma prior treatment with salsalate, pentoxyfilline, or monoclonal antiTNFalpha antibodies pregnancy liver transaminase levels &gt;3 times the upper limit of normal creatinine &gt;1.5 mg/dL history of a cellular immunodeficiencyrelated opportunistic infections, such as an endemic mycosis (eg. histoplasmosis) or mycobacterial infection (eg tuberculosis) reactive tuberculin skin test history of malignancy except for basal cell carcinoma of the skin</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vascular function</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucose tolerance</keyword>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Pre-diabetes</keyword>
</DOC>