<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00837551</DOC>
	<brief_summary>WBI-1001 is a synthetic,new, non-steroid, small molecule being developed as a candidate drug for the topical, cream treatment of inflammatory skin diseases. As such, it affects T-cells through inhibition of T-cell activities including their infiltration processes, and it shows direct anti-inflammatory manifestation in the mouse edema model. This was a 28 day study (plus one follow-up week) on patients with Atopic Dermatitis, and 36 patients were treated randomly, BID with either 0.5%, 1.0% or placebo. Blood samples were taken weekly for PK analysis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase IIa Study of WBI-1001 Cream for Atopic Dermatitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A double-blind, single-centered, vehicle-controlled, randomized Phase IIa study of WBI-1001 on patients with mild to moderate Atopic Dermatitis (AD). All body areas were treatable except face, scalp, groin and genital areas. Cream applied BID between 6.00 and 10.00am and 7.00 and 10.00pm daily for 4 weeks. Blood draws for PK analysis were taken weekly at the study centre prior to the morning cream application. Patients returned to the study centre approximately one week later for a follow-up visit.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis, Atopic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eczema</mesh_term>
	<criteria>AD diagnosis (based on Hanifin's criteria) presenting a minimum of 1% and a maximum of 10% body surface area (BSA) excluding face, groin, scalp and genital areas. Disease severity index (EASI) of less than 12, Investigator's Global Assessment (IGA) of 23 at Day 0. In good general health and free of any condition that might impair evaluation of AD. Women of child bearing potential (WOCBP) had to have a negative a negative serum humanbeta chorionic gonadotropin pregnancy test before randomization. WOCBP had to abstain from sex or they and their partners had to use adequate contraceptive precautions for the duration of the study. Willing and able to comply with the protocol and attend all study visits. Provide a written informed consent form prior to initiation of study procedures. Had spontaneously improving or rapidly deteriorating AD. Had AD lesions on only hands and/or feet. Had skin diseases other than AD. Had active allergic contact dermatitis or other nonatopic forms of dermatitis. Had other concomitant medical condition that could put the patient at risk during the study. Had a history of neurological/psychiatric disorders that could interfere with the patient's participation. Had systemic immunomodulatory therapies within 12 weeks prior to the baseline visit. Had prolonged exposure to natural or artificial ultraviolet radiation within 4 weeks of baseline visit. Had phototherapy (including laser), photochemotherapy or systemic AD therapy within 4 weeks prior to baseline visit. Had topical AD therapies in the areas to be treated within 2 weeks prior to the baseline visit. Had alcohol abuse in the last 2 years. Had allergic history to any nonmedical ingredients of the study cream. Were treated with an investigational drug within 1 month of Day 0 or were currently participating in another trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-steroid</keyword>
	<keyword>Small molecule</keyword>
	<keyword>Topical cream</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammatory disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin</keyword>
</DOC>