<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00281957</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized phase II trial is studying how well giving sorafenib together with either temsirolimus or tipifarnib works in treating patients with stage IV melanoma that cannot be removed by surgery. Sorafenib, temsirolimus, and tipifarnib may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth. Sorafenib and tipifarnib may also stop the growth of tumor by blocking blood flow to the tumor. It is not yet known whether sorafenib is more effective when given together with temsirolimus or tipifarnib in treating patients with malignant melanoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sorafenib With Either Temsirolimus or Tipifarnib in Treating Patients With Stage IV Malignant Melanoma That Cannot Be Removed By Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Compare the response rate (confirmed and unconfirmed and complete and partial) in patients with unresectable stage IV malignant melanoma treated with sorafenib in combination with either temsirolimus or tipifarnib. II. Compare the 4-month progression-free survival rate of patients treated with these regimens. III. Compare the safety and tolerability of these regimens, with an emphasis on long-term side effects and toxic effects, in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to metastatic (M) stage (M1a/b vs M1c). Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. ARM I (reopened to accrual as of 8/15/2009): Patients receive oral sorafenib twice daily on days 1-28 and temsirolimus IV over 30 minutes on days 1, 8, 15, and 22. ARM II (closed to accrual as of 8/15/2009): Patients receive oral sorafenib as in arm I and oral tipifarnib twice daily on days 1-21. In both arms, courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed periodically for up to 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tipifarnib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Niacinamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Criteria: Histologically confirmed malignant melanoma of cutaneous origin Patients with unknown primary allowed Stage IV disease Measurable disease by physical examination, CT scan, MRI or plain xray Unresectable disease Residual or recurrent disease after prior surgery for stage IV disease allowed Residual tumor at the site of incomplete resection may be included only as nonmeasurable disease Must have serum lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) levels measured Must have tissue specimens available Negative brain CT scan or MRI within the past 42 days Creatinine =&lt; 1.5 times ULN Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,000/mm^3 Platelet count &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin &gt;= 9.0 g/dL Fasting cholesterol =&lt; 350 mg/dL (lipidlowering agents allowed) Triglycerides =&lt; 300 mg/dL (lipidlowering agents allowed) No symptomatic sensory neuropathy &gt;= grade 2 No evidence of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy No congestive heart failure No myocardial infarction within the past 2 months No New York Heart Association class III or IV heart disease No condition that impairs the ability to swallow pills (e.g., gastrointestinal tract disease resulting in an inability to take oral medication, requirement for IV alimentation, prior surgical procedure affecting absorption, or active peptic ulcer disease) No known allergy to imidazoles (e.g. clotrimazole, ketoconazole, miconazole, or econazole) No history of allergic reaction to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition as tipifarnib No hypertension with systolic blood pressure (BP) &gt; 140 mm Hg or diastolic BP &gt; 90 mm Hg Patients with wellcontrolled hypertension allowed Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception No uncontrolled diabetes No uncontrolled diabetes No active uncontrolled infection No other severe or uncontrolled medical disease No psychologic or medical condition that would preclude study treatment or compliance No other malignancy within the past 5 years except adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, adequately treated stage I or II cancer that is in complete remission, or carcinoma in situ of the cervix At least 90 days since prior adjuvant therapy, including cytotoxic agents At least 28 days since prior radiotherapy At least 28 days since prior surgery to remove the tumor No prior systemic therapy for stage IV melanoma No prior therapy with agents targeting farnesyl transferase, the MAP kinase pathway, or vascular endothelial growth factors (VEGF) or receptors (VEFGR), including drugs such as sorafenib, temsirolimus, or tipifarnib Concurrent lipidlowering agents allowed Not requiring fulldose anticoagulation for recent thrombotic event No concurrent highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART) in HIVpositive patients No concurrent use of any of the following: dilantin; carbamazepine; Phenobarbital; rifampin; hypericum perforatum (St. John's wort); ketoconazole; itraconazole; ritonavir; cyclosporine; phenytoin; grapefruit juice Bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) SGOT or SGPT =&lt; 2.5 times ULN (5 times ULN if hepatic metastases) No history of brain metastases Zubrod performance status 01</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>