<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00281333</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Hemophilia patients tend to lower their physical activity level due to the fear of increasing bleeding episodes. Although recent literature has shown that with routine muscle strengthening and physical activity, the frequency and duration of bleeds was reduced. Our study has built a routine of strength training exercises and karate training. The study is built in two stages, each stage being three months. The participants fill out a bleeding diary that includes information from the previous six months. It includes place of bleed, duration, pain level, spontaneous or traumatic bleed, factor replacement and joint limitation. Before the exercise, the participants are tested for muscle strength and endurance. The bleeding diary will be filled out following the first three months and the second phase as will the muscle strength and endurance. We are hoping to see a drastic reduction of bleeding episodes occurring especially from spontaneous bleeds.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Influence of "Karate" on Bleeding in Hemophilic Patients.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>none - Hemophilia patients tend to lower their physical activity level due to the fear of increasing bleeding episodes. Although recent literature has shown that with routine muscle strengthening and physical activity, the frequency and duration of bleeds was reduced. Our study has built a routine of strength training exercises and karate training. The study is built in two stages, each stage being three months. The participants fill out a bleeding diary that includes information from the previous six months. It includes place of bleed, duration, pain level, spontaneous or traumatic bleed, factor replacement and joint limitation. Before the exercise, the participants are tested for muscle strength and endurance. The bleeding diary will be filled out following the first three months and the second phase as will the muscle strength and endurance. We are hoping to see a drastic reduction of bleeding episodes occurring especially from spontaneous bleeds.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Severe Hemophilia. No Inhibitors.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>11 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>