<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02704104</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to monitor patient safety after excision of skin lesions and subsequent application of AC5 topical hemostatic agent and to assess the performance of AC5 for controlling bleeding in skin wounds.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Performance Evaluation of the Topical Hemostatic Device (AC5™) Following Excision of Skin Lesions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Skin Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemostatics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and women between the ages of 18 and 85. Voluntary written informed consent, given before performance of any clinical investigationrelated procedure not part of standard medical care, and with the understanding that consent may be withdrawn at any time without prejudice to future medical care. Scheduled for excision of 2 (two) or more skin lesions from their trunk or upper limbs (defined as lying below the level of the inferior border of the patient's mandible). If subjects is currently prescribed an antiplatelet therapy, it must from one of the following therapies at levels as per hospital protocol: Antiplatelet monotherapy with one of the following agents: Aspirin Clopidogrel (thienopyridineclass antiplatelet agent) Ticagrelor Dipyridamole Female subjects must meet at least one of the following additional criteria: Surgically sterile with bilateral tubal ligation or hysterectomy. Postmenopausal for at least one year. If of childbearing potential, practicing an acceptable method of birth control for the duration of the clinical investigation as judged by the Investigator, such as condoms, foams, jellies, diaphragm, intrauterine device or abstinence. Subjects willing to undergo preand postclinical investigation blood and urine collection, physical exams and laboratory investigations. Active infection as demonstrated by temperature &gt; 37.5 C and clinical features of active infection. Wound expected to expose bone or tendon. Wound expected to require topical antibiotics. Know contraindication or reaction to Tegaderm use. Presence of malignancy or clinical expectation of malignancy based on examination. Known immunosuppression or taking immunosuppressive agents including systemic steroids. Plan for adjunctive flap or graft procedure to obtain closure of the wound(s) subject to this study. History of severe comorbidity with expected patient survival ≤ 6 months. Pregnancy or lactation Intake of investigational drugs within 28 days prior to enrollment. Currently taking oral anticoagulants History of concurrent condition that, in the Investigator's opinion, would jeopardize the safety of the subject or compliance with the protocol. History of clinically significant, active disease (within 12 months prior to enrollment) of the pulmonary, gastrointestinal, neurological, genitourinary, renal, or haematological system, that in the opinion of the Principal Investigator, may confound the results of the trial or pose additional risk to the subject following the administration of AC5. History of clinically significant cardiac disorder, defined as: acute coronary syndrome, congestive heart failure (NYHA class III/IV), diagnosis of unstable angina pectoris, cerebral stroke and or myocardial infarction within the last 12 months or planned coronary or carotid revascularisation procedures anytime through 30 Day followup. History of severe uncontrolled treated or untreated hypertension (systolic blood pressure ≥180 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure ≥100 mmHg). Likely inability to comply with the protocol or cooperate fully with the investigator and site personnel. Presence of significant cognitive impairment (Mini Mental Status Examination &lt;22) or mental incapacity. Unwillingness or language barrier precluding adequate understanding of the trial procedure or cooperation with trial site personnel. Known or suspected active abuse of alcohol, narcotics or nonprescription drugs. Other planned surgical procedures within 30 days prior to or 30 days postindex procedure. Prior enrollment in this AC5 clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>