<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02128204</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is a double-blind, randomized, within-subject controlled, 2-armed, single-centre study sponsored by SciVision Biotech Inc. and approved by Yuan's General Hospital Institutional Review Board. The aim of this post-marketing study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of HYADERMIS LA facial dermal implant for the improvement of nasolabial folds. The study was estimated to be held half to one year including a 0-2 weeks screening period, a day of treatment, and follow-up at week 1 and 2. Patient informed consent forms will be obtained before volunteers enter screening period. If the volunteers meet all the criteria, they will be given a number to replace their name in the study. The participants will be randomised assigned to receive experiment treatment, HYADERMIS LA, in one side of nasolabial folds and control treatment, Hya-Dermis, in the other side of the face. The safety assessment evaluated any recorded adverse events following the device treatments either by blinded evaluator or subjects. The effectiveness of the treatment devices will be assessed by using photographic assessment, nasoalabial folds severity scale, global aesthetic improvement scale, and pain visual analog scale.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Safety and Efficacy of Using HYADERMIS LA for Wrinkle Correction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Be 25 to 60 years of age and of any sex who is willing to receive nasolabial folds correction by intradermal injection procedures Have approximately symmetrical nasolabial folds with a nasolabial folds severity grade of 24 and the grade difference between two sides is less than 1 Agree to refrain from undergoing invasive aesthetic treatments in the injective areas 12 months after the injections Agree to refrain from undergoing other physical or chemical aesthetic treatments in the injective areas 3 months after the injections If female of childbearing potential, not be breastfeeding, have a negative urine pregnancy test on the treatment day and agree to use any approved contraceptives or medically acceptable method of birth control throughout the study Have ability to understand and comply with the study requirements, and provide the written informed consent prior to any procedures Have history or active dermal diseases, inflammation, or any related disease Had permanent or semipermanent implantation on nasolabial areas Had invasive aesthetic treatments or surgeries history 6 months before the treatments Had physical or chemical aesthetic treatments 1 months before the study starts Have history of coagulation defect diseases and still take aspirin, anticlotting, or blood activating medications 1 week before the treatments Have AdamsStokes syndromes, wolffprkinsonwhite syndromes, severe sinus node, the atrioventricular node dysfunction, or the blocked ventricular Have a known history of allergic reactions like hypersensitivity to hyaluronic acid Have a known history of allergic reactions like hypersensitivity to lidocaine or other anaesthetics Have poor compliance with the study or followup schedule</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>