<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02128607</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objectives: Determine the efficacy of the SNAG technique (Mulligan) applied to a subgroup of people with non-specific low back pain (LBP) on two new kinematic-algorythms, on pain, functional disability and kinesiophobia. Design: A randomized double blinded placebo controlled trial with double arms in accordance with the CONSORT statement. Subjects: Patients with non-specific low back pain will be recruting from Saint-Luc hospital, only a subgroup of them will be included according to specific inclusion criteria tailored for indication of application of SNAG's therapy (Mulligan technique applied on the lumbar spine). Method: Subjects will be randomized in 2 groups; real-SNAG and sham-SNAG groups. All patients will be treated during a single session, and real/sham SNAG will be applied from a sitting position with the belt, and in a flexion direction. Two kinematic-algorythms (ROM and Speed) from a validated kinematic spine model will be used and recorded with an opto-electronic device (BTS-Elite). Pain at rest and during flexion, as well as functional disability and kinesiophobia will be recorded by self-reported measures. These outcomes will be blindly evaluated before and after treatment to compare both groups with " Two-Way-ANOVA " statistic with for factors; time and groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomized Placebo Controlled Trial on the Efficacy of Sustained Natural Apophyseal Glide (SNAG) in Low Back Pain Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>nonspecific LBP, mechanical LBP with a pain in flexion direction, the pain in flexion is reduce with the application of SNAG therapy specific LBP, nonmechanical LBP, the pain is not release in a flexion direction when SNAG is appllied</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>low back pain</keyword>
	<keyword>manual therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Mulligan</keyword>
	<keyword>sustained natural apophyseal glide (SNAG)</keyword>
	<keyword>Kinematic spine model</keyword>
</DOC>