<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02128516</DOC>
	<brief_summary>this clinical trial would try to confirm whether NUTRALYS速, a fast pea protein with an intermediate profile, rich in leucines and other essential amino acids, can significantly enhance muscle mass gain during strength training. This study will compare the efficacy of NUTRALYS速 to a reference product. If the results of the study demonstrate a significant improvement in relation to the placebo, not inferior to that of whey, NUTRALYS速 could be considered as an alternative to sports nutrition products, to which many people are intolerant.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>NUTRALYS速 Pea Protein Oral Supplementation Effects on Muscle Mass</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Male subjects from 18 to 35 years of age: engaged in moderate or occasional sports activity; having given their written informed consent; in gainful employment or a student; in possession of a medical certificate of fitness for sports Subject already engaged in regular sports or training increasing muscle strength or volume in the upper limbs and particularly the biceps brachial; Subject engaged or having engaged in the last 6 months in weight training more than once a week; Subject having had a muscle injury in the 3 months prior to the study; Asthmatic subject liable to be administered corticosteroids; Subject taking part in another trial; Subject with a known hypersensitivity to whey or pea proteins; Subject deprived of their freedom for administrative, medical or legal reasons or not in possession of the legal or ethical capacity to enter into a contract due to cognitive function impairment; Subject liable not to comply with the constraints required by the protocol; Subject not covered by health insurance; Subject having taken in the previous month or currently taking: medication, a dietary supplement, sports drink, food for particular nutritional uses or functional foods, of any kind, liable or described as liable to increase physical performance and notably to increase muscle mass; Subject taking anabolic protein or corticosteroid treatment; Subject on a highprotein diet.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>