<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01023633</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Previous OPTIMOX1 study investigated the use of oxaliplatin discontinuation and reintroduction in a novel stop-and-go strategy. Previously untreated patients were randomly assigned to either FOLFOX4 administered every 2 weeks until progression (arm A) or FOLFOX7 for 6 cycles, maintenance without oxaliplatin for 12 cycles, and reintroduction of FOLFOX7 for another 6 cycles (arm B). Data showed that there was no significant difference in median progression-free survival (PFS) and overall survival (OS) between two arms. Furthermore, this study showed lower Grade 3 neurotoxicity rate in arm B (17.9% vs 13.3%, P = 0.12).In order to investigate the efficacy and feasibility of the novel "Stop and go" strategy in Chinese mCRC patients, Prof. Shu Yongqian in JiangShu Province Hospital plans to conduct a randomized controlled study to compare continuous FOLFOX4 vs. FOLFOX4 in a Stop-and-Go Fashion in 1st Line mCRC patients. To avoid the high oxaliplatin dosage related neurotoxicity, FOLFOX4 regimen is chosen in this study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>OPTIMOX1 in Chinese mCRC Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with histologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the colon or rectum Unresectable metastases At least one bidimensionally measurable lesion of ≥ 1 cm No previous chemotherapy for metastatic disease; Completed at least more than 1 year oxaliplatin therapy for adjuvant treatment 1875 years old ECOG 02 Life expectancy greater than 3 months Hemogram: WBC≥4.0 X109/L, ANC ≥2 X109/L, PLT ≥100 X109/L, Hb ≥90g/L, Adequate Renal Function Adequate Liver Function Signed informed consent before the treatment Patients with previous oxaliplatin based adjuvant chemotherapy within 1 Year Completely or partially bowel obstruction Presence of peripheral neuropathy (CTC＞grade I) Severe mental disorder CNS metastasis With other severe disease: uncontrolled active infectious disease, uncontrolled hypertension, heart infarction within 1 year, uncontrolled highrisk arrhythmia, unstable angina With other malignant disease previously or concurrently Receive other antitumor treatment Pregnant or lactating women, or women of child bearing potential without contraceptive method.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>to investigate the efficacy and feasibility of this novel treatment strategy in Chinese mCRC patients</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary Endpoint:DDC</keyword>
	<keyword>Secondary Endpoint:OS, RR,DCR, PFS,safety</keyword>
</DOC>