<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03059043</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates the safety and efficacy of a viscoelastic-free method for Implantable Collamer Lens(ICL) implantation to treat high myopia. Subjects were randomly assigned either to the new method group or to the control group which uses the standard method for implantation. The post-operative data are collected for analysis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of A Viscoelastic-free Method for Implantable Collamer Lens (ICL) Implantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Implantable Collamer Lens(ICL) implantation has been proved to be an effective refractive option for surgical correction of high myopia. Currently, standard method utilizing the viscoelastic agent to fill and maintain the anterior chamber during the implantation, this requires an additional step to remove the viscoelastic agent at the end of the surgery and may cause the intraocular pressure spike in the early post-operative phase due to the incomplete removal of the viscoelastics. The new method is viscoelastic-free, which can be achieved by using balanced salt solution irrigation during the implantation. This study is a prospective randomized controlled trial to compare the safety and efficacy of the viscoelastic-free method with the standard method. Subjects enrolled in the study will be randomized to receive either viscoelastic-free method or standard method, and the clinical outcomes of two groups will be assessed at several follow-ups: 2 hours, 1 day, 1 week, 1 month, 3 months and 6 months post-operatively.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Myopia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Documented stable refraction for at least 1 year(within 0.5D) Best spectaclecorrected visual acuity (BCVA) of 20/40 or better Clear central cornea 0.5D to 18.0D of myopic refractive error Normal anterior chamber depth at least 2.8 mm to endothelium Endothelial cell density (ECD) more than 2000 cell/mm2 Pupil diameter smaller than 7.0 mm under mesopic condition Discontinued 3 weeks for hard contact lens and 1 week for soft contact lens wear Preexisting ocular diseases or conditions other than myopia, evidence of progressive or acute ocular disease Evidence of connective tissue disease or other systemic diseases that may confound the results of the study; Narrow angle of anterior chamber Pregnant, lactating, or planning to become pregnant during the course of the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Phakic Intraocular Lenses</keyword>
	<keyword>viscoelastic</keyword>
</DOC>