<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03059459</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Several studies have demonstrated the association between atmospheric pollution and chronic respiratory diseases. The magnitude of this association and its dependence of local factors are still unknown in Argentina, particularly for obstructive lung diseases like asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). The objective of this study is to assess the effect of atmospheric pollution due to particulate matter (PM) on asthma and COPD exacerbations in adults. A prospective cohort study will be carried out in patients attending the pulmonary service of a public hospital located in San Nicolas, Buenos Aires province, Argentina. Patients will be followed for 12 months after recruitment. The outcome variables will be the frequency of hospitalizations or emergency department consults for asthma or COPD exacerbations and related conditions, and the impact of COPD on a person's life as measured by the COPD assessment test (CAT) questionnaire. The exposure will be the pollution level in the particular address, measuring PM10 concentrations with portable equipment. Other variables as air temperature, humidity, and individual patient risk factors will be considered as potential confounders or effect modifiers. The associations will be estimated through regression models, i.e. logistic and Poisson regressions and recurrent event survival analysis. The results of this study should provide elements to estimate the risk of chronic respiratory diseases associated with atmospheric pollution, and to evaluate strategies for risk assessment in the local community.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Atmospheric Pollution on Obstructive Lung Diseases</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with asthma or COPD attending the pulmonary service. Patients who refuse to participate in this study or to sign the informed consent document.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</keyword>
	<keyword>Air Pollution</keyword>
	<keyword>Particulate Matter</keyword>
</DOC>