<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03059472</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Strong Hearts for New York is a research study which aims to reduce cardiovascular disease (CVD), improve quality of life, and reduce CVD related health care costs in rural communities. Our aim is to better understand how changes in lifestyle can affect the health of rural women and others in their communities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Strong Hearts for New York: A Rural Heart Disease Prevention Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There are notable cardiovascular disease (CVD) disparities among people living in rural settings, particularly medically underserved rural areas. Complex factors such as socioeconomic disadvantage, social and cultural dynamics, geographic distances/barriers, and limited access to healthcare, healthy foods, and/or physical activity opportunities contribute to the issue. The objective of Strong Hearts, Healthy Communities (SHHC) is to reduce rural CVD disparities through civic engagement and implementation of a community-based intervention in 8 underserved New York communities. SHHC builds upon a long-standing collaboration with National Institute of Food and Agriculture cooperative extension educators, who will implement the project. There is limited knowledge about how programs and services can move beyond commonly used individual-level approaches—which have limitations in terms of cost, impact, reach, and sustainability—to effectively reduce rural CVD health disparities using an integrated, multi-level, community-engaged approach. The objective of Strong Hearts, Healthy Communities (SHHC) is to address this gap in knowledge and practice by working with residents, practitioners, health educators, local leadership, and other stakeholders in 8 medically underserved rural communities in New York to test a comprehensive program designed to: a) improve diet and physical activity behaviors, b) promote local built environment resources, and c) shift social norms about active living and healthy eating through civic engagement, capacity building, and community based programming. RANDOMIZED INTERVENTION AND DELAYED INTERVENTION: In the current phase of the project, the efficacy of the SHHC program curriculum will be evaluated in a 24-week delayed intervention trial. The investigators will compare changes in CVD-related anthropometric, physiologic, behavioral, and psychosocial parameters between subjects in 4 intervention and 4 delayed communities in New York State. In addition, changes in behavior, attitudes, and knowledge among SHHC intervention subjects' "social network" will be evaluated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Body Mass Index (BMI) greater than or equal to 25 If BMI is less than 30, not currently physically active Blood pressure is less than 160/100 mm Hg Heart rate is between 60100 bpm Englishspeaking Able and willing to obtain physician's approval to participate in intervention starting either in March 2017 or September 2017 Willing to participate in assessment activities Willing to make a firm commitment to participate in intervention starting either in Spring or Fall 2017 BMI less than 25 If BMI is less than 30, currently physically active Untreated hypertension Heart rate lower than 60 or higher than 100 bpm NonEnglish speaking Not able or willing to obtain physician's approval to participate Not interested or willing to participate in assessment activities Not able or willing to make a firm commitment to participate in intervention starting either in Spring or Fall 2017</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>social network</keyword>
	<keyword>civic engagement</keyword>
</DOC>