<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02733367</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 3, open-label, single-group, non-randomised, observational study of the safety and biochemical disease control of Infacort速 in neonates, infants and children with AI who have completed study Infacort 003. All subjects who have satisfactorily completed study Infacort 003 will be offered the opportunity to take part in Infacort 004.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Extension Study for Patients Entered Into Study Infacort 003</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 3, open-label, single-group, non-randomised, observational study of the safety and biochemical disease control of Infacort速 in neonates, infants and children with AI who have completed study Infacort 003 (EudraCT number 2014-002265-30). All subjects who have satisfactorily completed study Infacort 003 will be offered the opportunity to participate in study Infacort 004 at or after their final visit of study Infacort 003. Subjects will receive the usual clinically-appropriate dose (since bioequivalence has been demonstrated with conventional hydrocortisone), as determined by the Investigator, which will be administered according to usual clinical practice - generally 3 or 4 times a day. Subjects can continue to be treated in this study until they meet the study withdrawal criteria, Infacort速 is granted a marketing authorisation (and so is available commercially, which is expected within 2 years of initiation of this study), Infacort速 is refused a marketing authorisation, or the Sponsor decides to discontinue the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adrenal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects successfully completing study Infacort 003, whose inclusion criteria were: 1. Male and female children less than 6 years of age. 2. A diagnosis of adrenal insufficiency (AI) as confirmed by an inappropriately low cortisol usually with other supporting tests. 3. Receiving appropriate adrenocortical replacement therapy (hydrocortisone with/without fludrocortisone). 4. Adequately hydrated and nourished. In addition, the parents/carers must be able to understand and give written Informed Consent for this extension study. 1. Clinically evident acute AI (adrenal crisis) (Note: the subject can be reevaluated for eligibility once the episode is over) 2. Inability of the child to take oral therapy 3. Subjects with clinical signs of acute infection or fever on inclusion (Note: the subject can be reevaluated for eligibility once the episode is over) 4. Any surgical or medical condition that in the opinion of the Investigator may place the subject at higher risk from his/her participation in the study 5. Parents/carers of subjects unwilling to consent to saving and propagation of pseudonymised medical data for study reasons 6. Subjects who are in a dependent relationship with the Investigator or the Sponsor</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>