<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02733549</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Dizziness is one of the most common complaints among patients admitted to the emergency department (ED). In most cases, the etiology remains unclear. Dizziness has a broad differential diagnosis. The initial symptoms of ALD can include many general complaints. Aim of this study is to investigate whether SOD is a symptom of ALD, the necessity of liver function tests for patients with SOD in the ED, and a cost analysis of liver function tests.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Is The Sudden Onset of Dizziness A Symptom of Acute Liver Dysfunction?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Dizziness is one of the most common complaints among patients admitted to the emergency department (ED). In most cases, the etiology remains unclear. Dizziness has a broad differential diagnosis. The initial symptoms of ALD can include many general complaints. The diagnosis of acute liver dysfunction (ALD) can usually be made by initial symptoms, physical examination, and biochemical tests, including liver function tests (LFTs) with high sensitivity and specificity. LFTs include albumin, bilirubin, coagulation factors (Activated Partial Thromboplastin Time (aPTT) and International Normalized Ratio (INR)), and liver enzymes, such as alanine aminotransferase (ALT), aspartate aminotransferase (AST), alkaline phosphates (ALP), and y-glutamyl transpeptidase (GGT), which are marker of hepatic damage. Aim of this study is to investigate whether SOD is a symptom of ALD, the necessity of LFTs for patients with SOD in the ED, and a cost analysis of LFTs.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dizziness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vertigo</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adult patients who were experiencing sudden onset dizziness of unknown etiology for the first time were included in the study 1. Patients with a history of chronic diseases such as any liver disease,diabetes mellitus, hypertension,congestive heart failure, hepatitis B or C infection 2. Patients with any central dizziness attacks 3. Patients with hemodynamically unstable and emesis; 4. Patients receiving drugs that could affect liver function tests, such as, acetaminophen, antibiotics, oral contraceptives, antihypertensive drugs (e.g., angiotensinconverting enzyme inhibitors), or hormones (e.g.,estrogen) 5. Patients who was experienced dizziness with systemic diseases 6. Patients with any neurological disorders 7. Patient who do not want to participate in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>