<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03049878</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objectives: The aim of this study was to determine the effectiveness of preoperative administration of single-dose of paracetamol-codeine, in the relieving of acute post-operative pain after the surgical removal of an impacted mandibular third molar. Materials and Methods: The study cohort consisted of 32 Caucasian outpatients, giving a total of 64 bilateral symmetrical impacted mandibles. Patients were randomized in two experimental groups to receive a preoperative oral dose of paracetamol-codeine (analgesic group) or a placebo (placebo group) at the first and second surgeries. Study participants were asked to record pain intensity scores during the operation and the next 2 days, the time of the first request for rescue analgesic, and the total number of postoperative-supplement paracetamol-codeine tablets.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Preoperative Administration of Paracetamol-codeine on Pain Following Impacted Mandibular Third Molar Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Codeine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acetaminophen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>absence of systemic pathologies (ASA class I); nonsmoker; not pregnant or lactating; good oral hygiene; no drug consumption for 10 days before the operation; bilateral impacted mandibular third molars with comparable position, depth and inclination; presence of the first and second molars; absence of painful symptoms and associated inflammatory or osteolytic pathologies in a radiographic examination; extraction difficulty index of &gt;7 according to Pederson's scale and a degree of IV (complex procedures) on a modified version of Parant's scale.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>postoperative pain</keyword>
	<keyword>paracetamol</keyword>
	<keyword>codeine</keyword>
	<keyword>tooth extractions</keyword>
	<keyword>analgesia</keyword>
	<keyword>premedication</keyword>
</DOC>