<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00414635</DOC>
	<brief_summary>For people with HIV who are currently taking specific medications (including Sustiva (efavirenz)) and have no detectable viral load, this study tracks how patients do if they take their medications for five days of the week compared with seven days of the week.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>FOTO: Five Consecutive Days on Treatment With Efavirenz, Tenofovir, and Emtricitabine Followed by Two Days Off Treatment Versus Continuous Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to evaluate virologic control of a weekly schedule of 5 days of treatment followed by two days off treatment versus continuous treatment with the same regimen. This is a larger study based on the results of our successful pilot study using the same protocol. The 48 week, phase IV trial addresses the issues of the high cost of HIV treatment, adherence problems associated with daily treatment, and cumulative toxicities. Virologic and immunologic parameters, drug levels of efavirenz, adherence, and toxicity will be measured. Subjects will have to be seen at CRI for 6 visits after randomization. Subjects randomized to daily therapy will cross over to 5/2 therapy at 24 weeks if their viral load remains undetectable.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Efavirenz</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 years or older CD4 count &gt; or = 200 Viral load &lt; 50 Treatment with a regimen containing efavirenz and tenofovir and lamivudine or emtricitabine for at least 90 days prior to screening Detectable HIV RNA on an ultrasensitive assay within the 90 days preceding screening Prior evidence of intermediate or high level resistance to efavirenz, tenofovir or cytidine analogues Hepatitis B infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV/AIDS</keyword>
	<keyword>efavirenz</keyword>
	<keyword>tenofovir</keyword>
	<keyword>emtricitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>FOTO</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment interruption</keyword>
	<keyword>Atripla</keyword>
	<keyword>Truvada</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment Experienced</keyword>
</DOC>