<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02281123</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chikungunya is a viral disease transmitted by mosquitoes whose clinical feature is the early joint damage. Approximately 8% of patients have chronic arthropathy resembling to the rheumatoid polyarthritis. The EchoCHIK study we propose is in the context of the epidemic in Martinique which began in January 2014. It should give a better understanding of arthritis and juxtaarticular of CHIK and look for signs that may allow ultrasound predict the evolution of chronic arthropathy of CHIK.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Prognostic Value of Musculoskeletal Ultrasound in Adults With Chikungunya</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Chikungunya Fever</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age at onset of symptoms ≥ 45 years 2. Seen in consultation at the University Hospital of FortdeFrance 3. Suspected chikungunya infection (fever and sudden onset of joint pain affecting the wrists, hands, ankles or knees) 4. Duration of symptoms suggestive of infection chikungunya less than or equal to 10 days 5. Presence of joint pain on the day of inclusion 6. No history of inflammatory arthritis 7. Absence of steroidal or nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs taken within two weeks prior to inclusion 8. Ability to participate in the study throughout its duration (12 months) 9. Patient affiliated or beneficiary of a social health care. 10. Acceptance to participate in the study and monitoring proposed and signed informed consent 1. Age at onset of symptoms &lt;45 years 2. Duration of symptoms suggestive of chikungunya for more than 10 days 3. Lack of joint pain on the day of inclusion 4. History of inflammatory arthritis Nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs or 5. Taking in the two weeks preceding the inclusion 6. Inability to participate in the study throughout its duration (12 months) 7. Patient is not affiliated or beneficiary of a social health care. 8. Refusal to participate in the study or to sign a consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>