<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02281461</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The PrePex is a WHO prequalified medical device for adult male circumcision for HIV prevention. The Government of Rwanda was the first country to implement the PrePex and acts as the leading Center of Excellence providing training and formal guidelines. In support of efforts to scale up male circumcision, readily available data have been applied to estimate the potential cost and impact of scaling up medical MC services in Rwanda to reach 80 percent of adult, children and newborn males by 2015. Infant and children male circumcision ensures that the wound will be healed before sexual activity begins, and thus reduces the risk of HIV transmission during healing period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Feasibility Study of PrePex Device When Performed on Early Infants &amp; Children Male Population by Physicians</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) published in August 2012 a technical report and a policy statement, "Evaluation of current evidence indicates that the health benefits of new-born male circumcision outweigh the risks; furthermore, the benefits of newborn male circumcision justify access to this procedure for families who choose it. Specific benefits from male circumcision were identified for the prevention of urinary tract infections, acquisition of HIV, transmission of some sexually transmitted infections, and penile cancer. Male circumcision does not appear to adversely affect penile sexual function/sensitivity or sexual satisfaction. It is imperative that those providing circumcision are adequately trained and that both sterile techniques and effective pain management are used. Significant acute complications are rare." The primary objective of the study was to assess the safety and efficacy of the PrePex device among healthy early infant and children males scheduled for voluntary circumcision. The study consisted of 2 phases: Phase I included infants age 5-33 days Phase II included children age 4-10 years. The study examined the feasibility of performing PrePex circumcision on early infants and children male population.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Early infants and children males in ages 5 to 33 days or 410 years Weighs more than 2500gr (for early infants) The infant or child should be healthy and in fullterm Parent/legal guardian consent to the circumcision procedure Uncircumcised Parent/legal guardian able to understand the study procedures and requirements Parent/legal guardian agree to keep the infant for 48 hours or child for 24 hours hospitalization Parent/legal guardian agree to return to the health care facility for followup visits (or as instructed) after his circumcision until complete healing is achieved Parent/legal guardian able to comprehend and freely give informed consent for participation in this study and is considered by the investigator to have a good compliance for the study Parent/legal guardian agrees to anonymous video and photographs of the procedure and follow up visits. Parent/legal guardian withhold consent Active genital infection, anatomic abnormality or other condition, which in the opinion of the investigator prevents the participant from undergoing a circumcision Participant with the following diseases/conditions: Bilateral hydroceles, Curvature with penile torsion, Absence of ventral foreskin, Concealed penis (trapping urine beneath the foreskin), Megalourethra with deficiency of corpus spongiosum, Penoscrotal webbing, Epispadias, dorsal curvature, Hypospadias, Phimosis, paraphimosis, warts under the prepuce, torn or tight frenulum, narrow prepuce, hypospadias, epispadias, known haematological disorders and jaundice, yellow sclera or purpuric skin lesions, congenital abnormality Known bleeding / coagulation abnormality, uncontrolled diabetes Participant that to the opinion of the investigator is not a good candidate Parent/legal guardian does not agree to anonymous video and photographs of the procedure and follow up visits.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>PrePex</keyword>
	<keyword>Infants</keyword>
	<keyword>Early infants</keyword>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
	<keyword>Circumcision</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS</keyword>
	<keyword>Non surgical</keyword>
</DOC>