<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02281266</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Efficacy and safety of Thymalfasin adjuvant therapy in HBV-related HCC after curative resection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Thymalfasin Adjuvant Therapy in Hepatitis B Virus (HBV)-Related Hepatocellular Carcinoma (HCC) After Curative Resection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Multi-center, Randomized, Controlled Clinical Trial to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Adjuvant Thymalfasin Therapy in Hepatitis B Virus (HBV)-Related Hepatocellular Carcinoma After Curative Resection.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Entecavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thymalfasin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria during perioperative period Male or female patients with age between 1870 years. Life expectance ≥ 3 months. Diagnosis of Hepatocellular Carcinoma confirmed by Histological or Cytological examination. Hepatitis B history with current HBsAg positive and/or HBV DNA positive Will undergo hepatic curative resection. Tumor feature a. with cancer embolus b. a solitary nodule measuring between 38 cm or 2 nodule, a total combined measurement between 38 cm East Cooperative Oncology Group performance score of 02 Normal liver function or sufficient liver function, defined as Chlid'sPugh A Inclusion criteria at baseline postoperation (4weeks ± 7days postoperation) No documented evidence of disease recurrence with computed tomography (CT) scan and CT angiography. Grade A of Chlid'sPugh score hematological test white blood cell (WBC)&gt;3.5X109/L, red blood cell (RBC)&gt;30%, platelet count (PLT)&gt;50,000/Ul, neutrophil (NEU)&gt;1.0X109/L, Cr&lt;1.5 mg/dl signed informed consent Any anticancer therapy, including liver transplant, transarterial Chemoembolization (TACE), imageguided tumor ablation, radiotherapy, chemotherapy, molecular targeted therapy and immunotherapy, etc. prior to the liver surgery procedure. Taking the hepatotoxic drug or immunosuppressant drug. Invasion of portal vascular and its first branch, hepatic duct and its first branch, inferior vena cava and hepatic vein. Organ transplant recipient. Extrahepatic organs and lymph node metastasis. Uncontrolled Hypertension, unstable angina within 3 months, congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class II or greater), history of myocardial infarction within 6 months prior to randomization and severe arrhythmia need to be treated. History of malignancy other than a successfully treated nonmetastatic cutaneous squamous cell or basal cell carcinoma and/or localized carcinoma in situ of the cervix Known human immune deficiency virus (HIV) infection hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection History of stroke or transient ischemic attack within 6 months prior to randomization Active or untreated central nervous system (CNS) metastasis History of clinically significant drug or alcohol abuse Prior treatment with immunomodulator (e.g. interferon, Thymalfasin) or traditional Chinese medicine within 30 days prior to randomization Know postoperative complications (e.g. infection, bleeding, bile leak) at baseline Known allergic reaction to the investigational product and its excipient. Female subjects who are pregnant or breastfeeding or considering becoming pregnant during the study. The investigator considers the subject, for any reason, to be unacceptable for study participation. Participating in other clinical trials of the drug or medical device within 30 days prior to randomization.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>