<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02281357</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Multicentre, Randomized, Double-blind, Parallel Group, Placebo Controlled, Phase 3 Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Tralokinumab in Reducing Oral Corticosteroid dependent Asthma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 3 Study to Evaluate the Efficacy &amp; Safety of Tralokinumab in Adults &amp; Adolescents With OCS Dependent Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, double-blind, parallel group, placebo-controlled study designed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of a fixed 300 mg dose of tralokinumab administered subcutaneously every 2 weeks in adult and adolescent subjects with oral corticosteroid dependent asthma. Approximately120 subjects will be randomized globally. Subjects will receive tralokinumab or placebo, administered via subcutaneous injection at the study site, over a 40-week treatment period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1) Age 1275 2) Documented physiciandiagnosed asthma. 3) Documented treatment with ICS at a total daily dose corresponding to ≥500µg fluticasone propionate dry powder formulation and a LABA. 4) Subjects must have received OCS for the treatment of asthma for 6 months prior to Visit 1 and on a stable OCS dose between ≥7.5 to ≤30mg daily or daily equivalent for at least one month prior to enrolment (Visit 1) . 5) PreBD FEV1 value &lt;80% (&lt;90% for patients 1217 yrs of age) of their PNV. 6) PostBD reversibility of ≥12% in FEV1. 1) Clinically important pulmonary disease other than asthma. 2) History of anaphylaxis following any biologic therapy. 3) Hepatitis B, C or HIV. 4) Pregnant or breastfeeding. 5) History of cancer. 6) Current tobacco smoking or a history of tobacco smoking for ≥10 packyears. 7) Previous receipt of tralokinumab.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>Reactive Airways</keyword>
	<keyword>Repiratory Tract Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Obstructive Lung Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Lung Diseases</keyword>
</DOC>