<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02203903</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This Phase I dose-escalation trial is designed to evaluate the safety of administering rapidly-generated multi-antigen-specific T lymphocytes, to HSCT recipients (group A) or future HSCT recipients (group B) for the treatment or relapsed or refractory hematopoietic malignancies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multi-institutional Prospective Research of Expanded Multi-antigen Specifically Oriented Lymphocytes for the Treatment of VEry High Risk Hematopoietic Malignancies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with evidence of relapsed or persistent hematopoietic malignancies (e.g. acute leukemia, MDS, Hodgkins lymphoma, CML) will be eligible for this study. Patients will be enrolled at two time points (for differing indications) in two groups (Group A - post HSCT and Group B- pre HSCT). Because patients with persistent malignancy prior to transplantation have an extremely poor prognosis, these patients will be eligible to receive TAA-CTL before and/or after allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT). Group B patients may receive autologous TAA-CTL following a cycle of conventional chemotherapy in an effort to decrease the burden of disease prior to HSCT. Additionally, patients with persistent disease or high risk for relapse will be eligible to receive planned infusion of TAA-CTL after HSCT (given the very high likelihood of relapse and poor outcome) on group A. These high risk/refractory patients and their donors will be enrolled prior to HSCT and TAA-CTL will be given any time after day 30 post HSCT In either population, we will utilize a rapid generation protocol for multi-antigen specific T lymphocytes. Peripheral blood mononuclear cells will be exposed to antigen presenting cells pulsed with peptides to tumor antigens (Prame, WT1, Survivin, and MAGE-A3) in a cytokine milieu favorable to T cell expansion/activation, inducing selective expansion of T cells targeted to kill tumor cells. Patients would be monitored for the development of toxicity. In patients with disease at the time of TAA-CTL infusion, efficacy would be evaluated as a secondary endpoint using standard criteria. Exploratory investigational analyses would include monitoring of cytokine and cellular milieu pre- and post- TAA-CTL infusion and in vitro characterization of the host tumor, donor lymphocyte product, and TAA-CTL product. For Group A Patients (post HSCT): T cells will be infused any time after neutrophil engraftment post-HSCT or day 30, whichever comes first. For Group B Patients (pre HSCT): T cells will be infused any time &gt;1 week after previous therapy for relapsed disease. Four different dosing schedules will be evaluated. Two to four patients will be evaluated on each dosing schedule (see below). This protocol is designed as a phase I dose-escalation study. Each patient will receive 1 injection per dose level, at least 14 days apart, according to the following dosing schedules. The expected volume of infusion will be 1 to 10 cc. Dose Level One: 5 x 106 cells/m2 Dose Level Two: 1 x 107 cells/m2 Dose Level Three: 2 x 107 cells/m2 Dose Level Four: 4 x 107 cells/m2 Patients will receive cells either because: of prior refractory disease and/or high risk for relapse and/or detectable disease at the time of infusion. Group A and Group B patients will use the dose escalation strategy described above. Ideally, patients should not receive other systemic antineoplastic agents for at least 6 weeks after infusion of TAA- specific T-cells (for purposes of evaluation), although such treatment may be added at the discretion of their attending physician. If patients with active disease have stable disease or a partial response by the International Working Group (IWG) criteria at their 8 week or subsequent evaluations they are eligible to receive up to 6 additional doses of CTLs at monthly intervals-each of which will consist of the same cell number as their second injection. Patients will not be able to receive additional doses until the initial safety profile is completed at 6 weeks following the second infusion.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hematologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Recipient procurement Inclusion criteria Patients who have undergone alloHSCT with high risk for relapse or residual/recurrent disease (see below) OR patients with relapsed/refractory disease (&gt; 2 regimens with greater than M1 marrow or persistent HD) with anticipated alloHSCT pre and/or postHSCT: Acute lymphoblastic leukemia, Acute myeloid leukemia, Ambiguous lineage leukemia or lymphoma, Chronic Myelogenous leukemia, Myelodysplastic syndrome: Evidence of active leukemia or lymphoma disease by flow cytometry, morphology, or cytogenetic evaluation within the marrow or extramedullary sites Hodgkins disease: Evidence of HD by morphology, PET/CT uptake in a site of previous disease in the absence of other etiologies Age 6 months to 30 years Karnofsky/Lansky score of &gt; 50 (see appendix B). Absolute neutrophil count &gt; 500/ µL (may be supported with GCSF) Bilirubin &lt; 2.5 mg/dL, AST/ALT &lt;5x upper limit of normal, Serum creatinine &lt; 1.0 or 2x the upper limit of normal (whichever is higher) Pulse oximetry of &gt; 90% on room air Agree to use contraceptive measures during study protocol participation (when age appropriate) LVEF &gt; 50% or LVSF &gt; 27% if history of TBI (may be performed within the last 6 months) Patient or parent/guardian capable of providing informed consent Recipient Inclusion criteria for initial CTL administration and for subsequent infusions Steroids less than 0.5 mg/kg/day prednisone or equivalent Karnofsky/Lansky score of &gt; 50 Pulse oximetry of &gt; 90% on room air Recipient Procurement Exclusion Criteria Patients with uncontrolled infections Patients with HIV infection Current evidence of GVHD &gt; grade 2 or bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome, sclerotic GVHD, or serositis. Pregnancy or lactating (female of childbearing potential) Recipient Exclusion criteria for initial and subsequent CTL infusions Patients receiving ATG, or Campath or other immunosuppressive T cell monoclonal antibodies within 28 days of screening for enrollment. Uncontrolled infections Acute GVHD &gt; grade 2 or chronic GVHD manifestations: bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome, sclerotic GVHD, or serositis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>