<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01474265</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study has the following primary aim: - the main objective of this study is to investigate the effects of smoking cessation during quit attempts on sympathovagal balance. These effects will be observed in smokers quitting smoking with pharmacological support or without. Secondary aims of this study are also: - the definition of MSNA in smokers and non-smokers - the investigation of other parameters concerning the autonomic nervous system, like baroreflex-sensitivity, heart rate-variability before and during the quit attempt. - the definition of withdrawal symptoms and craving before, during and after the quit attempt. - the investigation of effects of smoking cues on craving and sympathovagal balance - the investigation of relapse rates after smoking cessation in correlation with the parameters mentioned above.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sympathovagal Balance in Smoking Cessation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Varenicline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nicotine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and Women at the age of 25 to 60 years. Group AD: Smokers willing to quit smoking and a FTNAresult &gt;5. Group E: Neversmokers. Signed consent after information. formerly known hypersensitivity against one of the used pharmacological interventions or structurally similar drugs or against one of the ingredients. participation in another study during this study or within 4 weeks prior to this study. Addiction or other circumstances that prevent the patient from estimating the study and the consequences. Pregnancy and breastfeeding women with childbearing potential, except women that fulfill the following criteria: post menopause postoperative (6 weeks after bothsides ovariectomy with or without hysterectomy) regular and correct use of prevention methods (errorrate &lt;1% a year), e.g. implants, depot injections, oral contraceptives, IUP) sexual abstinence signs that predict a possible noncompliance of the patient exclusion because of nicorette tx: psoriasis, dermatitis, urticaria exclusion because of varenicline creatinineclearance &lt; 30ml/min epilepsy psychiatric diseases (schizophrenia, bipolar disorders, depression). Exclusion because of methods Diseases that increase the sympathetic level (Heart insufficiency, high blood pressure (arteria /pulmonary), obstructive sleeping apnoea, COPD) cardiac rhythm disturbances myocardial infarction within the last 8 weeks polyneuropathy diseases that come along with damages of peripheral nerves severe or lifethreatening diseases (e.g. cancer with lifeexpectancy &lt; 5 years, terminal kidneyinsufficiency) treatment with antihypertensive drugs or sympathomimetic substances (e.g.theophyllin) or smoking cessation medication (NRT, Varenicline) Other reasons, that make a patient not suitable for the study (estimation of primary investigator)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>smoking cessation</keyword>
	<keyword>varenicline</keyword>
	<keyword>sympathovagal balance</keyword>
	<keyword>quit attempts</keyword>
	<keyword>MSNA</keyword>
</DOC>