<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01616654</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the efficacy and safety of different concentrations of CD5789 cream in subjects with acne vulgaris for the purpose of dose identification.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose Range Study of CD5789 in Acne Vulgaris</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Acne Vulgaris</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nicotinic Acids</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tazarotene</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subject, 12 to 35 years old with the following characteristics: Facial acne severity grade of the following: Stratum 1: IGA score of 3 or 4 Stratum 2: IGA score of 4 Stratum 3: IGA score of 3 or 4 A minimum of 30 noninflammatory lesions and fulfills the criteria of one of the following strata: Stratum 1: A minimum of 20 but not more than 40 inflammatory lesions, and a maximum of one nodule on the face. Stratum 2: More than 40 inflammatory lesions, and up to four nodules on the face. Stratum 3: Subjects of Japanese origin with at least 20 inflammatory lesions and up to four nodules on the face. Note: Subjects of Japanese origin will not be included in Stratum 1 or Stratum 2. Japanese origin is defined as all four grandparents were born in Japan. The presence of severe forms of acne (acne conglobata, acne fulminans) or secondary acne form (chloracne, druginduced acne, etc.) Any uncontrolled or serious disease, or any medical or surgical condition, that may either interfere with the interpretation of the clinical trial results and/or put the subject at significant risk (according to the Investigator's judgment) if the subject participates in the clinical trial. Known or suspected allergies or sensitivities to any components of any of the study drugs. Current participation in any other clinical trial of a drug or device OR past participation within the 30 days prior to the Baseline visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>