<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01616875</DOC>
	<brief_summary>26 patients with invasive primary transitional cell carcinoma of the bladder will receive 4 cycles of combination chemotherapy consisting of Cabazitaxel and Cisplatin both given intravenously on day 1 of each 3 weekly cycle prior to radical cystectomy, to evaluate the overall response rate and to determine whether this approach warrants further research of a phase II/III study.Participation in 2 sub studies will also be offered to the participants. 1. Contrast Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI ) scans will be taken at baseline and after cycle 1 and cycle 3. 2. A pilot sub study involving the circulating tumour cell concentration from blood samples taken at baseline, prior to each cycle of chemotherapy and prior to surgery</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bristol Bladder Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥18 years Histologically confirmed primary transitional cell carcinoma (TCC) of the urinary bladder T2 to T4 disease, N0 M0 determined by computerised tomography (CT) imaging and biopsy or transurethral resection Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance status 0 or 1 Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) ≥60ml/min. Written, informed consent Exclusion Criteria ECOG Performance Status ≥ 2 Lymph node involvement or metastatic disease Prior surgery (except transurethral resection of bladder tumour), radiation, chemotherapy, or other anticancer therapy within 4 weeks prior to enrolment Active Grade ≥2 peripheral neuropathy Active secondary cancers History of severe hypersensitivity reaction (≥Grade 3) to polysorbate 80 containing drugs Other concurrent serious illness or medical conditions Inadequate organ function as evidenced by peripheral blood counts at enrolment: Electrocardiogram (ECG) evidence of uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmias, angina pectoris, and/or hypertension, history of congestive heart failure, or myocardial infarction within last 6 months. Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus. Active uncontrolled gastrooesophageal reflux disease (GORD). Active infection requiring systemic antibiotic or antifungal medication Participation in another clinical trial with any investigational drug within 30 days prior to study enrolment. Concurrent or planned treatment with strong inhibitors of cytochrome P450 3A4/5. A 1week washout period is necessary for patients who are already on these treatments. Concurrent or planned treatment with strong inducers of cytochrome P450 3A4/5. A 1week washout period is necessary for patients who are already on these treatments. Contraindications to cisplatin. Patient with reproductive potential not implementing an accepted and effective method of contraception.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Transitional cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Urothelial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Cisplatin</keyword>
	<keyword>Cabazitaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Neo adjuvant chemotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>