<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01940848</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study shall prove whether treatment of irritable bowel syndrome with Iberogast is superior to placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy/Safety Study to Confirm Iberogast's Efficacy in Rome-III Patients in Irritable Bowel Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients of either sex aged &gt;18 years Patients meeting the Rome III irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) diagnostic criteria. IBS is defined as recurrent abdominal pain or discomfort at least 3 days/month in last 3 months (onset at least 6 months ago) associated with two or more of the following: Improvement with defecation Onset associated with a change in frequency of stool Onset associated with a change in form (appearance) of stool History of pain intensity with an average of worst abdominal pain in past 24 hours score of &gt; 30 on a daily measured VAS (visual analogue scale) during screening phase Intake of STW5 within the last 5 years Concomitant treatment during the study (including screening phase) with any medication that could influence the gastrointestinal function Regular intake of nonsteroidal antiphlogistic drugs incl. COX2inhibitors (exception: acetylsalicylic acid for cardiovascular prevention up to 100 mg daily) Patients with known hypersensitivity to any component of the trial drugs History of eating disorders Patients with a history of diseases with abdominal symptoms that can resemble IBS Presence of any other acute or chronic gastrointestinal disorder History of abdominal surgery (cholecystectomy and appendectomy can be tolerated when performed at least one year previously) Known intolerance to azo dyes E 110 and E 151</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Iberogast</keyword>
	<keyword>efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
</DOC>