<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01261312</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Phase 1-2 dose escalation randomized study in patients with intermediate or high risk myelodysplastic syndromes (MDS) or acute myelogenous leukemia (AML). The Dose Escalation Segment will evaluate the biological activity, preliminary safety and efficacy of SGI-110 with two dosing schedules in MDS and AML patients while the Dose Expansion Segment will further evaluate safety and efficacy at the biological effective dose (BED) or maximum tolerated dose (MTD)as defined in the Dose Escalation Segment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SGI-110 in Patients With Myelodysplastic Syndromes (MDS) or Acute Myelogenous Leukemia (AML)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Once the BED and MTD is determined in the Dose Escalation Segment, the Dose Expansion Segment will randomize patients with MDS, treatment naïve elderly AML, and relapsed/refractory AML patients to receive the BED or MTD dose. Relapsed/refractory AML patients may also receive SGI-110 on a daily x 10 schedule based on the total dose per cycle evaluated in the Dose Escalation Segment using the 5-daily regimen.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Azacitidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Men or women, 18 years of age or older, with a confirmed diagnosis of international prognostic scoring system (IPSS) intermediate1, intermediate2 or highrisk MDS including Chronic Myelomonocytic Leukemia (CMML) or AML. In the Dose Escalation Segment, patients who are refractory, relapsed, or unresponsive to standard treatment. In the Dose Expansion Segment, hypomethylating agent (HMA) treatmentnaïve MDS subjects (including CMML), and intermediate2 or highrisk MDS subjects (including CMML) relapsed or refractory to prior HMA treatment are allowed, and treatmentnaïve AML subjects who are at least 65 years of age will be allowed if they also have at least one of the following criteria AML secondary to MDS, chemotherapy, or radiation therapy poor cytogenetics preexisting clinically significant dysfunction of the heart or Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) poor performance status, Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG), of 2 2. Eastern ECOG performance status of 0 to 2. 3. Adequate organ function. 4. Prior allogeneic stem cell transplant, no evidence of active graftversus host disease (GVHD) and must be ≥ 2 weeks off immunosuppressive therapy. 5. No major surgery within 4 weeks of first dose of SGI110. 6. No chemotherapy within 2 weeks of first dose of SGI110 (minimum of 6 weeks for nitrosoureas and 8 weeks for bone marrow transplantation) with the exception of hydroxyurea which will be allowed during course 1 of treatment. 7. Sign an approved informed consent form for this study. 1. In the Dose Expansion Segment, which includes the 10day regimen, subjects who have received 2 complete full dose cycles or more of a hypomethylating agent (HMA) decitabine or azacitidine (except for intermediate2 or highrisk MDS subjects (including CMML) relapsed or refractory to prior HMA treatment). 2. Acute promyelocytic leukemia (M3 classification). 3. Prior malignancy, except for adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, in situ cervical cancer, or other cancer from which the patient has been disease free for at least 3 years. 4. Lifethreatening illnesses other than AML or MDS, uncontrolled medical conditions or organ system dysfunction which, in the investigator's opinion, could compromise the patient's safety, or put the study outcomes at risk. 5. Known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or active infection with hepatitis C virus (HCV) or hepatitis B virus (HBV). 6. Hypersensitivity to decitabine, SGI110, or SGI110 excipients. 7. With the exception of treatmentnaïve elderly AML patients, patients with uncontrolled congestive heart failure (CHF), coronary heart disease (CAD), chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), or left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) of ≤ 50% are excluded, symptomatic or uncontrolled arrhythmias or on continuous corticosteroids.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>SGI-110</keyword>
	<keyword>DNA Hypomethylating Agent</keyword>
	<keyword>Intermediate 1, Intermediate 2, CMML or High Risk MDS</keyword>
	<keyword>AML</keyword>
</DOC>