<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00106288</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the efficacy and safety of micafungin (FK463) versus liposomal amphotericin B (AmBisome) in treating neutropenic and non-neutropenic patients with confirmed invasive candidiasis or candidemia. Enrollment will include adult and pediatric patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Micafungin Versus AmBisome in Invasive Candidiasis and Candidemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A phase III, multicenter, double-blind, comparative, parallel, randomized study. Enrollment will include adult and pediatric patients. The adult population is sized to test for non-inferiority. For the pediatric population, descriptive analyses are planned.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Candidiasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Candidemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Candidiasis, Invasive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Micafungin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amphotericin B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal amphotericin B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Echinocandins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients either nonneutropenic with absolute neutrophil counts &gt;= 500 cells/mm3 or neutropenic with absolute neutrophil counts &lt; 500 cells/mm3 must have: Candidemia or invasive candidiasis, Confirmation and typical clinical signs and symptoms by fungal culture and/or histology, Positive culture obtained no more than four days prior to the first dose of study medication. Patient is pregnant or nursing Patients with evidence of liver disease as defined by: a) SGOT/AST or SGPT/ALT &gt; 10 times the upper limit of normal (ULN); or b) Total bilirubin &gt; 5 times ULN. Patients whose sole diagnosis is oropharyngeal and/or esophageal candidiasis and/or with positive cultures of urine specimens, sputum specimens, bronchoalveolarlavage specimens or samples from indwelling drains. Patients who have received prophylactic/empiric therapy with azoles or conventional amphotericin B for more than three days within one week prior to enrollment. Neutropenic patients, however, may have received prophylactic azoles without time restrictions.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Candidaemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Micafungin</keyword>
</DOC>