<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00106158</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety of repeated doses of cholesterol-bearing hydrophobized pullulan (CHP) and NY-ESO-1 protein (CHP-NY-ESO-1) and describe the NY-ESO-1 specific-humoral and cellular immune response to immunization with CHP-NY-ESO-1 in patients with cancer expressing NY-ESO-1.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of NY-ESO-1 Protein Vaccine to Treat Cancer Expressing NY-ESO-1</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>NY-ESO-1 was isolated by serological analysis of recombinant cDNA expression libraries (SEREX), using tumor mRNA and autologous serum from an esophageal cancer patient. Reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) analysis showed that NY-ESO-1 displayed the typical expression pattern of CT antigens. NY-ESO-1 mRNA was expressed only in testis of normal tissues tested and in various types of cancer, including lung cancer, breast cancer, malignant melanoma and bladder cancer. LAGE-1 was identified by the representational difference analysis and revealed to display 84% amino acid homology with NY-ESO-1. In most cases, expression of LAGE-1 parallels the expression of NY-ESO-1. Since testis is an immune privileged organ where HLA molecules are not expressed, these antigens can be considered tumor-specific. Because of frequent NY-ESO-1 mRNA expression and high immunogenicity in advanced cancer, NY-ESO-1 is an attractive target molecule for a cancer vaccine. Current therapies against advanced cancer have limited effectiveness. The idea of vaccination with NY-ESO-1 protein in cancer patients with tumors expressing NY-ESO-1 mRNA is based on two findings: 1) the number of CD8+ T cell epitopes identified in NY-ESO-1 molecule are limited to those binding to HLA-A0201, A31, Cw3 and Cw6. These HLA subtypes are carried by a minor Japanese population; 2) CD8+ T cell responses specific to NY-ESO-1 are polyclonal. Protein vaccination may induce immune response more effectively against tumors expressing NY-ESO-1 than peptide immunization.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Histologically proven cancer Confirmed NYESO1 expression No other effective therapy available 4 weeks since conventional therapy before start of the current protocol Performance status &lt; 2 (ECOG scale) Age &gt; 18 Able and willing to give written informed consent Serious illness Metastatic diseases to central nervous system Concomitant systemic treatment with corticosteroids, antihistaminic drugs or NSAIDs HIV positive Mental impairment that may compromise the ability to give written informed consent Pregnancy and breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>cancer/testis antigen</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>recombinant protein</keyword>
</DOC>