<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01871558</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To compare a therapeutic strategy combining vildagliptin+metformin + Basal Insulin versus SU+metformin + Basal Insulin on the incidence of hypoglycemic events over 24 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vildagliptin/Metformin in T2DM Patients Starting Basal Insulin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study, conducted in T2DM patients failing a dual therapy with metformin/SU in whom the decision to start basal insulin has been taken, will compare vildagliptin+metformin versus the previously used SU+met combination (regimen kept unchanged) in association with basal insulin, up-titrated as per usual algorithms primarily based on FPG to obtain a similar improvement in glycemic control in both arms, on the incidence of hypoglycemic episodes over 24 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vildagliptin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>T2DM patients inadequately controlled with metformin+ SU combination therapy at max tolerated doses and in whom the decision to start basal insulin has been taken with stable metformin+ SU combination therapy for at least 12 weeks prior to randomization with a glycemic target of HbA1c &lt;= 7% with HbA1c at inclusion &gt;7% and &lt;=9% Patients willing and able to start basal insulin and perform appropriate self monitoring of blood glucose (SMBG) contraindication for either SUs, metformin or insulin and history of hypersensitivity to vildagliptin acute or chronic diseases that interfere with efficacy/safety results of this trial or put patient at risk Other protocol defined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>type 2 diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>basal insulin</keyword>
	<keyword>vildagliptin</keyword>
</DOC>