<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01871454</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this prospective phase II protocol is to assess the toxicity and efficacy of pentoxifylline and SABR in the re-treatment of recurrent or new lung cancers</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety of Pentoxifylline and Vitamin E With Stereotactic Ablative Radiotherapy (SABR) in Non-small Cell Lung Cancers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin E</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tocopherols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tocotrienols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>alpha-Tocopherol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pentoxifylline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>3.1 Eligibility Criteria 3.1.1 Age &gt;/= 18 years 3.1.2 ECOG performance status 01 3.1.3 Histologically proven diagnosis of a prior thoracic malignancy treated with thoracic external beam radiotherapy with or without systemic chemotherapy 3.1.4 Pathologic or clinical diagnosis of a new or locoregional recurrent lung malignancy. A reasonable attempt should be made to make a pathologic diagnosis of malignancy (ie. bronchoscopy, CT guided lung biopsy) Locoregional is defined as recurrence within the region of the primary tumor or adjacent draining lymph node regions. The new lesion or locoregional recurrence must be within or adjacent to the previously irradiated treatment volume. 3.1.5 Imaging as follows: CT scan of the chest with IV contrast within 8 weeks of registration Whole body PET scan within 8 weeks of registration 3.1.6 Pulmonary function test (PFTs), including diffusion capacity within 8 weeks of registration 3.1.7 Negative serum pregnancy test within 2 weeks prior to registration for women of childbearing potential. 3.1.6 Women of childbearing potential and male participants who are sexually active must agree to use a medically effective means of birth control 3.1.7 Patients must provide study specific informed consent prior to study entry. 3.2 Exclusion Criteria 3.2.1. No previously reported thoracic radiotherapy 3.2.2. FEV1 &lt;20% predicted and/or DLCO &lt;20% predicted 3.2.2. Pregnant women or lactating women 3.2.3 Chemotherapy within 4 weeks of the initiation of SABR 3.2.4 Plans to administer systemic chemotherapy overlapping with radiotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>