<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01871584</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to demonstrate the efficacy of the hydrocolonic lavage method in order to prepare the colon prior to performing a colonoscopy, by comparison the hydrotherapy to standard preparation solution. Hypothesis: Colon cleansing by hydrotherapy is as good as colon cleansing by standard preparation solution.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Post Marketing Study of Angel of Water™ for Colon Cleansing as Preparation for Colonoscopy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Colonoscopy is the current standard method for evaluation of the colon. It has an indispensable place in the diagnosis and treatment of colon diseases. Diagnostic accuracy and therapeutic safety of colonoscopy depends on the quality of the colonic cleansing or preparation. Good preparation of the bowel is necessary prior to colonoscopy, to allow clear visualization of the bowel wall and any pathology within. The proposed study is a post-marketing study in which the study device, the Angel of Water system will be used for hydrotherapy of the colon in adult subjects scheduled for elective colonoscopy, instead of standard preparation solution. The effectiveness of the hydrotherapy in comparison to the standard preparation will be defined by evaluating colon cleanliness, subject's attitude and the duration of colonoscopy procedure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colonic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subject is &gt;= 18 and ≤ 80 years old, referred to colonoscopy 2. Subject is able and agrees to sign the informed consent and follow the study requirements 1. Myocardial infarction within the last 3 months 2. Symptomatic congestive heart failure 3. Established renal failure (serum creatinine &gt; 2.0 mg/dL) 4. Previous abdominal surgery, colectomy, or recent colon or rectal surgery 5. Abdominal hernia 6. Partial or complete intestinal obstruction 7. Acute exacerbation of inflammatory bowel disease 8. Intestinal perforation 9. Fissures or fistula 10. Grade III or IV hemorrhoids 11. Carcinoma of the rectum 12. Distal rectal anastomosis 13. Cirrhosis 14. Hypokalemia 15. Pregnancy 16. Subject's weight &gt; 400 lbs. /182 kg 17. Participation in another study that may affect the results of this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>A colon hydrotherapy system</keyword>
	<keyword>Hydrocolonic preparation</keyword>
	<keyword>Preparation for colonoscopy</keyword>
</DOC>