<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01871259</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To relate two different predictive values of sleep apnea: the STOP score (snoring while sleeping, daytime tiredness, observed breathing stoppages, and high blood pressure) and the estimated respiratory disturbance index (eRDI) with the occurrence of apnea-hypopnea during propofol sedation,thirty four middle-aged male patients who underwent urologic surgery under spinal anaesthesia will be enrolled. Before surgery, patients will be asked to complete a STOP-questionnaire. The eRDI will be calculated using the modified Mallampati's grade, tonsil grade, and the body mass index. After performing spinal anaesthesia, propofol will be infused and adjusted to BIS 70-75. An ApneaLinkTM, which measures airflow through a nasal cannula, will be then applied to estimate the level of apnea-hypopnea.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Predictors of Apnea-hypopnea During Propofol Sedation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators will evaluate correlation between STOP scor and AHI(apnea hypopnea index) or eRDI and AHI. After then the investigators will compare AHI severity between high risk group and low risk group subgrouped according to STOP score or eRDI.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Propofol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Thirty four males who underwent spinal anaesthesia for transurethral resection of the bladder (TURB) or prostate (TURP) were enrolled in this studyInclusion criteria were American Society of Anaesthesiologists (ASA) physical status of 12, and ages of more than 40 years. Patients with electrocardiographic or simple chest radiographic abnormalities or who had taken medication that could affect their sleep patterns were excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sedation, sleep apnea, propofol</keyword>
</DOC>