<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01871064</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess the residual neuromuscular blockade (NMB) Train-Of-Four (TOF) ratios at tracheal extubation when anesthesiologists have determined that full recovery of neuromuscular function has occurred using standard clinical criteria for participants whose non-depolarizing-induced NMB is either not reversed or reversed with an acetylcholinesterase inhibitor administered as per standard routine care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Residual Curarization and Its Incidence at Tracheal Extubation in China</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, multi-site, anesthesiologist and PACU nurse TOF-Watch SX® blinded observational study of surgical patients undergoing elective laparoscopic or open abdominal procedures requiring general anesthesia and non-depolarizing neuromuscular blockade. There are two temporal aspects to the data collection: a prospective data collection in the OR and PACU; and a retrospective chart review one week after hospital discharge.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Age≥18; American Society of Anesthesiologists(ASA) class 13; Scheduled for elective open or laparoscopic abdominal surgery that is anticipated to last less than 4 hours; Administration of general anesthesia and ≥ 1 dose of nondepolarizing neuromuscular blockers for endotracheal intubation or maintenance of neuromuscular blockade; Planned for extubation to occur in the OR; Signed informed consent. Redo surgery on the same hospital admission; Preestablished need or expected to require postoperative mechanical ventilation; Conditions, surgical procedures, or participant positioning that may interfere with TOFWatch SX® operation, calibration, or accuracy; Anesthesiologist use of objective neuromuscular monitoring during surgery (e.g. mechanomyography, electromyography or related method); Pregnancy; Participation in any other clinical trial; Member or a family member of the personnel of the investigational or Sponsor staff directly involved with this trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Laparotomy</keyword>
	<keyword>laparoscopic surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>general anesthesia</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuromuscular Block</keyword>
</DOC>