<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01871103</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Soft tissue reconstruction in the finger continues to evolve. The dorsum of the finger is a reliable flap donor site in reconstructive hand surgery because of its similar quality to the original. The dorsal homodigital island flap can be used as a reliable alternative for reconstructing small to moderate defects of the fingers. In this retrospective study, the investigators would evaluate the efficacy of the technique for tissue reconstruction in different regions of the finger, with an emphasis on sensibility, pain and donor site morbidity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Dorsal Homodigital Island Flap Based on the Dorsal Branch of the Digital Artery: A Review of 171 Cases</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>At final follow-up, sensory restoration of the flap is measured using the static 2-point discrimination test and Semmes-Weinstein monofilament test. We evaluate pain sensations of the reconstructed fingers and donor sites with a visual analog scale. The system consist of a 10 cm line that is grouped into mild (0-3 cm), moderate (4-6 cm) and severe (7-10 cm). Active motion of the joints is measured using a goniometer. The motion arcs of the reconstructed fingers are compared with the opposite side.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>the soft tissue defect in one finger or in multiple fingers a defect &gt; 1.5 cm and &lt; 3 cm in length necessity to preserve finger length a patient between 15 and 60 years of age injuries to the dorsum of the finger or to the course of the vascular pedicle that precluded its use as the donor a defect≤1.5 cm or ≥3 cm in length a soft tissue defect of the thumb</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Soft tissue defect</keyword>
	<keyword>dorsal branch of the digital artery</keyword>
	<keyword>dorsal branch of the digital nerve</keyword>
	<keyword>dorsal homodigital island flap</keyword>
</DOC>