<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00515476</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the present study is to characterize the quality of HDL-Cholesterol in patients with metabolic syndrome and reduced blood HDL-Cholesterol levels and to examine the effect of exercise training on the vasculoprotective effects of HDL-Cholesterol in these patients. Additionally the investigators aim to investigate the endothelial function, oxidative stress and the regenerative capacity of the endothelial progenitor cells in patients with metabolic syndrome and the changes dependent on physical activity of patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Exercise Training on the Function of the High Density Lipoprotein (HDL)-Cholesterol, Endothelial Function and Endothelial Progenitor Cells in Patients With Metabolic Syndrome(HERMET-Study)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Reduced HDLCholesterol levels in blood: &lt; 40 mg/dl (1.03 mmol/L) in male, &lt; 50 mg/dl (1.29 mmol/L) in female Plus two of the following criteria: Elevated waist circumference: ≥ 102 cm (≥ 40 inches) in men or ≥ 88 cm (≥ 35 inches) in women Elevated triglycerides: ≥ 150 mg/dL (1.7 mmol/L Elevated blood pressure: ≥ 130 mmHg systolic blood pressure or ≥ 80 mmHg diastolic blood pressure or antihypertensive treatment Elevated fasting glucose: ≥ 100 mg/dL or on drug treatment for elevated fasting glucose Acute coronary syndrome Unstable Angina pectoris Myocardial infarction during the last 8 weeks Therapy with Niacin Active infections Ventricular arrhythmias Systolic blood pressure &gt; 160 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &gt; 95 mmHg Cancer Pregnancy, lactation Alcoholism</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>metabolic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>HDL-Cholesterol</keyword>
	<keyword>EPC</keyword>
	<keyword>endothelial function</keyword>
	<keyword>reduced blood HDL-Cholesterol level</keyword>
</DOC>