<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00343486</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will test the effectiveness and safety of two doses of solabegron against placebo in reducing the symptoms of overactive bladder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose Ranging Study Of Solabegron Versus Placebo In Female Patients With Overactive Bladder Symptoms</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Overactive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Solabegron</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Overactive bladder with symptoms of urgency with urge incontinence and frequency which may be associated with nocturia but without bladder pain. Body mass index in the range of = 19 kg/m2 to &lt;35 kg/m2. Pregnant Of childbearing potential or willing to use specific barrier methods outlined in the protocol. Grade III/IV pelvic organ prolapse with or without cystocele. History of interstitial cystitis or bladder related pain. Stress incontinence or mixed incontinence where stress incontinence is the predominant component based on prior history. History of pelvic prolapse repair (cystocele or rectocele) or urethral diverticulectomy within six months of screening. Urinary incontinence due to causes other then detrusor over activity (e.g., overflow incontinence). Nocturnal enuresis only. Urinary retention, or other evidence of poor detrusor function. Current or history of Urinary Tract Infection. Diabetes insipidus. History of myocardial infarction, unstable angina, or Congestive heart failure. Chronic severe constipation. History of prior antiincontinence surgery. History of radiation cystitis or a history of pelvic irradiation. Electrostimulation, biofeedback, or bladder training therapy (behavioral therapy) during the previous month prior to screening, or the intention to initiate such therapies during the study. Pessaries and implants are also excluded. Received any investigational product within 30 days of enrollment into the study.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Overactive Bladder</keyword>
</DOC>