<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="34036">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02663505</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ICU-Risk-Score</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02663505</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Development Of An ICU Risk Score</brief_title>
  <official_title>I See You Risk Your ICU Capacity - Development Of An ICU Risk Score Discriminating Reasonable and Non-Reasonable ICU Admissions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Schleswig-Holstein</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Schleswig-Holstein</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Capacity on intensive care units is limited but inevitable for high risk surgery and/or high
      risk patients i.e. patients with severe preconditions.

      Contrary, if there is no capacity on an ICU elective surgery has to be postponed.

      The aim of this study is to evaluate the current allocation process of ICU capacities and
      analyze parameters important for ICU admission in an university hospital in Germany. In a
      second phase a risk score for ICU admission shall be invented from parameters obtained
      during phase one (ICU-Risk-Score). This new score will then be evaluated in a third phase of
      the project.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Capacity on intensive care units is limited but inevitable for high risk surgery and/or high
      risk patients.

      Contrary, if there is no capacity on an ICU elective surgery has to be postponed. It is one
      of the core duties of Anesthesiologists in our hospital to identify patients with high risk
      for a post-surgery ICU stay upon hospital admission. We do know that there is two factors
      influencing the possibility of an ICU admission: The patient centered risk i.e. severe
      preconditions and the surgery centered risk with high possibility for perioperative
      complications i.e. bleeding, hemodynamic instability, pulmonary complications etc.. However,
      we do not know what these factors look like exactly and more importantly, how they are
      evaluated and weighed against each other.

      The aim of this study is to evaluate the current allocation process of ICU capacities and
      analyze parameters important for ICU admission in an university hospital in Germany. This
      evaluation will be fulfilled by a data collection sheet completed by Anesthesiologists
      performing anesthesia in all elective and emergency surgery during a specific period of
      time. In a second phase a risk score for ICU admission shall be invented from parameters
      obtained during phase one (ICU-Risk-Score). This new score will then be evaluated in a third
      phase of the project.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ICU-Risk-Score</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Development of a risk score for ICU admission consisting of patient centered risk factors (i.e. comorbidities) and surgery centered risk factors (i.e. what type of surgery is associated with a high ICU admission rate).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Influence of different comorbidities on ICU admission</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of different comorbidities as risk factors for ICU admission gathered by a questionnaire filled in by the attending anesthesiologist. Statistical analysis is supposed to reveal what comorbidity (i.e. coronary artery disease) shows what impact on ICU admission.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Influence of different types of surgery on ICU admission</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of different types of surgery as risk factors for ICU admission gathered by a questionnaire filled in by the attending anesthesiologist. Statistical analysis is supposed to reveal what type of surgery (i.e. vessel surgery) shows what impact on ICU admission.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">8000</enrollment>
  <condition>Intensive Care Unit Admission</condition>
  <condition>Intensive Care Unit Admission Score</condition>
  <condition>Critical Care</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients receiving either elective or emergency surgery. Pre-conditions and type of surgery are documented. Planned and actual post-surgery observation i.e. ICU or intermediate care or post-anesthetic care unit are documented as well.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Patients receiving the surgery planned for them</intervention_name>
    <description>No intervention will be performed apart from the surgery planned for each patient. Different aspects of data i.e. patient-centered and surgery-centered will be collected.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients receiving elective or emergency surgery during phase 1 (2 months) and phase 3
        (2 months) of the study, approximately 8000 in total.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  All patients ≥ 18 years receiving surgery in the time frame of data collection

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients &lt; 18 years
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jan Höcker, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital Schleswig-Holstein, Campus Kiel, Germany</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Timo Iden, MD</last_name>
    <email>timo.iden@uksh.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Schleswig-Holstein, Campus Kiel</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kiel</city>
        <zip>24105</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Timo Iden, MD</last_name>
      <email>timo.iden@uksh.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Orsini J, Blaak C, Yeh A, Fonseca X, Helm T, Butala A, Morante J. Triage of Patients Consulted for ICU Admission During Times of ICU-Bed Shortage. J Clin Med Res. 2014 Dec;6(6):463-8. doi: 10.14740/jocmr1939w. Epub 2014 Sep 9.</citation>
    <PMID>25247021</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lupei MI, Chipman JG, Beilman GJ, Oancea SC, Konia MR. The association between ASA status and other risk stratification models on postoperative intensive care unit outcomes. Anesth Analg. 2014 May;118(5):989-94. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0000000000000187.</citation>
    <PMID>24781569</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wanderer JP, Anderson-Dam J, Levine W, Bittner EA. Development and validation of an intraoperative predictive model for unplanned postoperative intensive care. Anesthesiology. 2013 Sep;119(3):516-24. doi: 10.1097/ALN.0b013e31829ce8fd.</citation>
    <PMID>23756454</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 10, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 12, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Schleswig-Holstein</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Timo Iden</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
