<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00262860</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Bortezomib may stop the growth of cancer cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as gemcitabine hydrochloride, work in different ways to stop the growth of cancer cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Giving bortezomib together with gemcitabine hydrochloride may kill more cancer cells. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well giving bortezomib together with gemcitabine hydrochloride works in treating patients with relapsed or refractory Hodgkin's lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bortezomib and Gemcitabine Hydrochloride in Treating Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Hodgkin's Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the overall response rate (partial and complete response) in patients with relapsed or refractory Hodgkin's lymphoma treated with bortezomib and gemcitabine hydrochloride. Secondary - Determine the safety and toxic effects of this regimen in these patients. - Determine the time to progression in patients treated with this regimen. - Correlate NF-kB inhibition and proteasome activity with response in patients treated with this regimen. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter, pilot study. Patients receive bortezomib IV on days 1, 4, 8, and 11 and gemcitabine hydrochloride IV over 30 minutes on days 1 and 8. Treatment repeats every 21 days for up to 6 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed periodically for 2 years and then annually thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 24 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed Hodgkin's lymphoma Recurrent or refractory disease after prior standard combination chemotherapy Measurable disease, defined as ≥ 1 unidimensionally measurable lesion &gt; 1 cm by physical exam or imaging studies No history of nonHodgkin's lymphoma No history of other hematological malignancy PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Performance status ECOG 02 Life expectancy Not specified Hematopoietic Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,000/mm^3 Hepatic Bilirubin ≤ 2 times upper limit of normal (ULN) (unless due to Gilbert's disease or involvement by Hodgkin's lymphoma) AST ≤ 3 times ULN (unless due to involvement by Hodgkin's lymphoma) Renal Creatinine clearance ≥ 30 mL/min Cardiovascular Ejection fraction ≥ 40% by MUGA or echocardiogram (in patients with a history of cardiac disease) Pulmonary Must not require supplemental oxygen therapy Immunologic No known HIV infection No uncontrolled bacterial, viral, or fungal infection Other Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception No other malignancy requiring therapy No peripheral neuropathy ≥ grade 2 within the past 14 days No hypersensitivity to boron No hypersensitivity to mannitol PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy More than 30 days since prior monoclonal antibody therapy for Hodgkin's lymphoma More than 6 months since prior autologous stem cell transplantation No prior allogeneic stem cell transplantation No concurrent sargramostim (GMCSF) No concurrent pegfilgrastim or filgrastim (GCSF) No concurrent interleukin11(oprelvekin) Chemotherapy See Disease Characteristics More than 30 days since prior chemotherapy for Hodgkin's lymphoma No prior treatment with gemcitabine hydrochloride Endocrine therapy More than 30 days since prior corticosteroid therapy for Hodgkin's lymphoma No concurrent corticosteroid therapy Radiotherapy More than 30 days since prior radiotherapy for Hodgkin's lymphoma Other No prior treatment with bortezomib More than 14 days since prior investigational drugs No other concurrent investigational agents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent adult Hodgkin lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>