<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00262795</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as fludarabine and chlorambucil, work in different ways to stop the growth of cancer cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. It is not yet known whether fludarabine is more effective than chlorambucil in treating chronic lymphocytic leukemia. PURPOSE: This randomized phase III trial is studying fludarabine to see how well it works as first-line therapy compared to chlorambucil in treating older patients with previously untreated chronic lymphocytic leukemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fludarabine or Chlorambucil as First-Line Therapy in Treating Older Patients With Previously Untreated Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Compare the overall and progression-free survival of older patients with previously untreated chronic lymphocytic leukemia treated with fludarabine vs chlorambucil. - Compare the duration of remission in patients treated with these regimens. Secondary - Compare the incidence of toxicity, especially infections, in patients treated with these regimens. - Compare the quality of life in patients treated with these regimens. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, multicenter study. Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. - Arm I: Patients receive fludarabine IV on days 1-5. Treatment repeats every 28 days for up to 6 courses. - Arm II: Patients receive oral chlorambucil on day 1. Treatment repeats every 15 days for up to 12 months. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 205 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorambucil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vidarabine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Confirmed diagnosis of chronic lymphocytic leukemia, meeting any of the following staging criteria: Binet stage A with B symptoms Binet stage B or C, meeting 1 of the following criteria: Rapid disease progression Enlarged lymph nodes and organs Severe B symptoms Previously untreated disease PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Performance status ECOG 02 Life expectancy More than 6 months Hematopoietic No thrombocytopenia No autoimmune hemolytic anemia Hepatic Not specified Renal Not specified Other No severe organ dysfunction No other prior or concurrent neoplasm PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Chemotherapy No prior chemotherapy No other concurrent chemotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage 0 chronic lymphocytic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I chronic lymphocytic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II chronic lymphocytic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III chronic lymphocytic leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV chronic lymphocytic leukemia</keyword>
</DOC>