<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02675270</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to remediate word-finding problems in patients with Primary Progressive Aphasia (PPA) and to delay the further progression of word-finding impairment. The current approach is novel in that it contains a prophylaxis component in which the investigators attempt to strengthen neural connections that remain functional, making them more resistant to degradation as the disease progresses. While the study is specific in its targeting of word-finding problems, a successful outcome would bode well for other studies aimed at prevention or reversal of declining cognitive functions in dementia. Patients with PPA whose naming of pictures has just begun to show signs of decline will receive practice with picture naming in two conditions: viewing the picture and repeating the name; and viewing the picture with its written name, plus reading and writing the name. Naming of pictures trained in each of these conditions will be compared, at three time intervals post-training, with naming of pictures tested before the study but never trained. A scene-description task containing trained items will be used to assess generalization. It is predicted that the pairing of the picture with its written name, combined with the motor task of writing the name, will result in a greater ability to name the picture at a later date than simple practice viewing the picture and repeating the name. Generalization to other exemplars and to other task situations is also predicted.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rehabilitation and Prophylaxis of Anomia in Primary Progressive Aphasia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Aphasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anomia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aphasia, Primary Progressive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pick Disease of the Brain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Frontotemporal Dementia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of Primary Progressive Aphasia (PPA; including Frontotemporal Dementia, Semantic Dementia, or a similar condition) At least 10 years of education Ability to follow spoken instructions Medically stable First language is English, or fluent in English since childhood Willing to participate over a period of two years No history of additional neurological problems No history of substance abuse or psychiatric problems</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>