<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01271595</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There is inconclusive evidence whether acupuncture treatment is effective in the treatment of seasonal allergic rhinitis (SAR). Furthermore, the underlying mechanisms of acupuncture in SAR are only poorly understood. It was hypothesised that the therapeutic mechanism of acupuncture is related to changes in autonomic function. AUTO-ACUSAR is a sub-study of the DFG-funded three-arm randomized controlled trial ACUSAR trial investigating the efficacy of acupuncture vs. sham acupuncture vs. rescue medication in SAR. The aim of AUTO-ACUSAR was to investigate short and long-term effects of acupuncture vs. sham acupuncture on autonomic function in a sub-group of ACUSAR patients. Baseline values were compared to data from matched healthy controls.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>AUTO-ACUSAR - Effects of Acupuncture on the Autonomic Nervous System in Seasonal Allergic Rhinitis Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In AUTO-ACUSAR a subsample of ACUSAR patients from acupuncture or sham acupuncture groups were included. Tests of autonomic functions included measurement of heart rate variability during paced breathing, blood pressure, heart rate and salivary alpha amylase response to a cold pressure test (CPT) and cortisol awakening response before the first and the last of twelve treatment sessions. Healthy matched controls underwent the same measurement once only</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic, Seasonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female or male patients (aged 1645 years) with seasonal allergic rhinitis, clinically positive and test positive (skinprick test and/or RAST) to grass and birch pollen Patients with &gt;2 years of moderate to severe SAR Positive skinprick test and/or RAST (at least class 2) results Visual analogue scale &gt;40mm and &lt;80 mm for SAR symptoms during the past year Patients must be able to complete a diary for selfevaluation of symptoms and recording use of antisymptomatic medication Use of, or indication for, oral antihistamines as antiallergic medication Written informed consent Perennial SAR or other types of chronic rhinitis Allergic asthma and/or moderate to severe atopic dermatitis Active tuberculosis Autoimmune disorders Severe chronic inflammatory diseases History of anaphylactic reactions Hypersensitivity to Rescue medication or related drugs used in study related drugs Specific immunotherapy &gt;3 years Simultaneous participation in other clinical trials Serious acute or chronic organic disease or mental disorder Pregnancy or breast feeding Allergy desensitisation therapy (current, during the past two years, or planned in the next two years) Blood coagulation disorder and/or current use of anticoagulants Previous acupuncture treatment for SAR Any Complementary and alternative medicine treatment at the moment, in the last three months or planned in the next two years intake of BetaBlocker Medication use of pacemaker</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>acupuncture</keyword>
	<keyword>autonomic nervous system</keyword>
	<keyword>seasonal allergic rhinitis</keyword>
</DOC>