<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01271309</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present project aims to determine whether a deficit in migration of stem cells could be implicated in the failure to mount an adequate collateralization after Myocardial Infarction (MI) and thereby facilitate the development of post-ischemic heart failure (HF) and to dissect underlying molecular mechanisms. Furthermore, the investigators wish to determine the predictive value of stem cell migration assay in patients with MI.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Stem Cell Migratory Activity: Prognostic Marker in Myocardial Ischemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>MAIN OBJECTIVES OF THE STUDY: Characterization of circulating CD133+ stem cells in a group of 170 patients with MI (mean post-MI follow up, 6 months): - Counting total mononuclear cells and FACS analysis of CD133 stem cells. - Characterization of CD133+ stem cell biology: Migratory assay, imaging of cytoskeleton, angiogenesis tests in vitro. - Evaluation of migratory signalling, with specific focus on the PI3K/Akt/eNOS system. Assessment of the prognostic value of the stem cell migration assay. - Relationship between cell biology tests on CD133+ cells and changes in circulating cytokines and pro-angiogenic factors after MI. - Assessment of area at risk by ECG-synchronized Single Photon Emission Computed Tomography (gated-SPECT) in subgroups with different patterns of stem cell migratory tests. - Assessment of ventricular remodelling (echocardiography, NMR) in relation with patterns of stem cell migratory test. EXPECTED RESULTS: Clarification of the implication of stem cell migratory deficit in post-ischemic HF. - Identification of underlying mechanisms - Identification of a cellular marker for prediction of patients at risk of HF. RELEVANCE TO PUBLIC HEALTH: - Introduction of a biological test for the early diagnosis of post-MI HF - Recognition of therapeutic targets for the rescue of stem cell migratory liabilities</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt;= 18 years Thoracic pain lasting at least 20 min and ST changes or left B block, not present in previous ECG. MI confirmed by elevation of troponin I and CKMB. Patients with Killip II e III LV dysfunction will be included. Patients reporting thoracic pain 24 hours prior to hospitalization HF symptoms resistant to therapy Haemoglobin&lt; 10 gr/dl Haemodynamic instability (systolic pressure &lt;90 mmHg after treatment) Alterations in haematopoiesys Concurrent neoplastic disease No written informed consent or other conditions that affect patient's compliance to protocol.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>