<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="55015">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02389933</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CLCZ696B2318M</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02389933</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Multiple Patient Program to Ensure Access to LCZ696 Treatment to Patients Diagnosed With Heart Failure With Reduced Ejection Fraction (HF-rEF)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Multiple Patient Program to Ensure Access to LCZ696 Treatment to Patients Diagnosed With Heart Failure With Reduced Ejection Fraction (HF-rEF)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Novartis</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Novartis has set up this global Multiple Patient Program (MPP) treatment plan to provide
      access to life-saving treatment with LCZ696 for patients that were not previously exposed to
      LCZ696 but have no other option to receive LCZ696 in their country prior to market
      authorization OR commercial availability, based on local regulatory and legal requirements.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Available</overall_status>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Expanded Access</study_type>
  <condition>Heart Failure With Reduced Ejection Fraction (HF-rEF)</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LCZ696</intervention_name>
    <description>immediate release film coated tablet in 50 mg, 100 mg, 200 mg, and 400 mg strengths for oral administration.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria

        The patient(s) for whom the MPP is sought meets all of the following:

          -  Is suffering from a serious or life-threatening disease or condition

          -  Does not have access to a comparable or satisfactory alternative treatment (i.e.,
             comparable or satisfactory treatment is not available or does not exist)

          -  Patient should be on optimized standard of care treatment, including treatment with
             ARBs or ACEI, beta-blockers and MRA;

          -  Intolerance to evidence-based target doses should be documented by the treating
             physician

          -  Meets any other relevant medical criteria for compassionate use of the
             investigational product

        Patients eligible for inclusion in this program have to fulfill all of the following
        criteria:

          1. Adult patients (but not younger than 18 year old) will be included, upon completion
             of written informed consent before any assessment is performed.

          2. Patients with a diagnosis of CHF NYHA class II-IV and reduced ejection fraction:

             • LVEF ≤ 35% at the time of screening for participation in the program (any local
             measurement, made within the past 6 months using echocardiography, MUGA, CT scanning,
             MRI or ventricular angiography is acceptable, provided there are no subsequent
             measurement above 35%)

          3. Patient had a hospitalization for HF within the last 12 months

          4. Patients must be on an ACEI or an ARB at a stable dose for at least 4 weeks prior to
             starting treatment with LCZ696

          5. Patients must be treated with a β-blocker, unless contraindicated or not tolerated,
             at a stable dose for at least 4 weeks prior to starting treatment with LCZ696 (reason
             should be documented for patients not on CHF target doses per local guidelines, or in
             absence of that medication).

          6. An aldosterone antagonist should also be considered in all patients, taking account
             of renal function, serum potassium and tolerability. If given, the dose of
             aldosterone antagonist should be optimized according to guideline recommendations and
             patient tolerability, and should be stable for at least 4 weeks prior to starting
             treatment with LCZ696

        Exclusion criteria

        Patients fulfilling any of the following criteria are not eligible for inclusion in this
        program:

          1. The patient is eligible for participation in any of the IMP's ongoing clinical trials

          2. The patient has recently completed a clinical trial that has been terminated and
             other options (e.g., trial extensions, amendments, etc.) are available to continue a
             similar treatment.

          3. The patient is being transferred from an ongoing clinical trial for which the patient
             is still eligible for participation

          4. History of hypersensitivity or allergy to LCZ696 or to any of its metabolites; to
             drugs of similar chemical classes, ARBs, or NEP inhibitors; as well as known or
             suspected contraindications to LCZ696

          5. Use of other investigational drugs at the time of enrollment, or within 30 days or 5
             half-lives of enrollment, whichever is longer

          6. Previous history of intolerance to recommended target doses of ARBs

          7. Known history of angioedema

          8. Requirement of concomitant treatment with both ACEIs and ARBs

          9. Current acute decompensated HF (exacerbation of chronic HF manifested by signs and
             symptoms that may require intravenous therapy)

         10. Symptomatic hypotension and/or a SBP less than 100 mm Hg over the last 4 weeks prior
             to starting treatment with LCZ696

         11. Estimated GFR below 30 mL/min/1.73m2 as measured by the simplified MDRD formula

         12. Presence of bilateral renal artery stenosis

         13. Serum potassium above 5.2 mmol/L during the week prior to starting treatment with
             LCZ696

         14. Acute coronary syndrome, stroke, transient ischemic attack, cardiac, carotid or other
             major CV surgery, percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) or carotid angioplasty
             within the 3 months prior to starting treatment with LCZ696

         15. Coronary or carotid artery disease likely to require surgical or percutaneous
             intervention within the 6 months after the schedule date to start treatment with
             LCZ696

         16. Implantation of a cardiac resynchronization therapy pacemaker (CRT-P) or a cardiac
             resynchronization therapy defibrillator (CRT-D) or upgrading of an existing
             conventional pacemaker or an implantable cardioverter defibrillator (ICD) to CRT
             device within 3 months prior to starting treatment with LCZ696, or intent to implant
             such a device.

             Also, patients who had implantation of a conventional pacemaker or an ICD or had a
             revision of a pacemaker or other device leads within 1 month before starting
             treatment with LCZ696 are excluded.

         17. Heart transplant or ventricular assistance device (VAD) or intent to transplant (on
             transplant list) or implant a VAD

         18. History of severe pulmonary disease

         19. Diagnosis of peripartum or chemotherapy induced cardiomyopathy within the 12 months
             prior to starting treatment with LCZ696

         20. Documented untreated ventricular arrhythmia with syncopal episodes within the 3
             months prior to starting treatment with LCZ696

         21. Symptomatic bradycardia or second or third degree heart block without a pacemaker

         22. Presence of hemodynamically significant mitral and/or aortic valve disease, except
             mitral regurgitation secondary to left ventricular dilatation

         23. Presence of other hemodynamically significant obstructive lesions of left ventricular
             outflow tract, including aortic and sub-aortic stenosis

         24. Any surgical or medical condition which might significantly alter the absorption,
             distribution, metabolism, or excretion of study drugs, including but not limited to
             any of the following:

               -  History of active inflammatory bowel disease during the 12 months before
                  starting treatment with LCZ696.

               -  Current duodenal or gastric ulcers during the 3 months prior to starting
                  treatment with LCZ696

               -  Evidence of hepatic disease as determined by any one of the following: AST or
                  ALT values exceeding 2 x ULN prior to starting treatment with LCZ696, history of
                  hepatic encephalopathy, history of esophageal varices, or history of portacaval
                  shunt

               -  Active treatment with cholestyramine or colestipol resins

         25. Evidence of hepatic disease as determined by any one of the following: AST or ALT
             values exceeding 3 x ULN prior to starting treatment with LCZ696, history of hepatic
             encephalopathy, history of esophageal varices, or history of portacaval shunt

         26. Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women, where pregnancy is defined as the state of a
             female after conception and until the termination of gestation, confirmed by a
             positive hCG laboratory test (above 5 mIU/mL)

         27. Women of child-bearing potential, defined as all women physiologically capable of
             becoming pregnant, including women whose career, lifestyle, or sexual orientation
             precludes intercourse with a male partner and women whose partners have been
             sterilized by vasectomy or other means, UNLESS they are using two birth control
             methods. The two methods can be a double barrier method (if accepted by the local
             regulatory authority and ethics committee) or a barrier method plus a hormonal method

               -  Adequate barrier methods of contraception include: diaphragm, condom (by the
                  partner), intrauterine device (copper or hormonal), sponge or spermicide.
                  Hormonal contraceptives include any marketed contraceptive agent that includes
                  an estrogen and/or a progesterone agent.

               -  Reliable contraception should be maintained throughout the treatment and for 7
                  days after LCZ696 treatment discontinuation

               -  Women are considered post-menopausal and not of child bearing potential if they
                  have had 12 months of natural (spontaneous) amenorrhea with an appropriate
                  clinical profile (e.g. age appropriate, history of vasomotor symptoms) or six
                  months of spontaneous amenorrhea, or have had surgical bilateral oophorectomy
                  (with or without hysterectomy) at least six weeks ago. In the case of
                  oophorectomy alone, only when the reproductive status of the woman has been
                  confirmed by follow up hormone level assessment.

         28. Presence of any other disease with a life expectancy of &lt; 3 years

         29. Any condition, not identified in the protocol that in the opinion of the treating
             physician is likely to prevent the patient from safely tolerating LCZ696 or complying
             with the requirements of the therapy.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <phone>1-888-669-6682</phone>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <phone_ext>+41613241111</phone_ext>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vero Beach</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32960</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Poelten</city>
        <zip>3100</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vienna</city>
        <zip>1130</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wien</city>
        <zip>A-1090</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ahlen</city>
        <zip>59227</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Augsburg</city>
        <zip>86199</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bad Kreuznach</city>
        <zip>55543</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bad Krozingen</city>
        <zip>79189</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bad Oeynhausen</city>
        <zip>32545</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>13353</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bonn</city>
        <zip>53115</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chemnitz</city>
        <zip>09126</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chemnitz</city>
        <zip>09130</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dinslaken</city>
        <zip>46535</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dresden</city>
        <zip>01277</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Eilenburg</city>
        <zip>04838</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Essen</city>
        <zip>45355</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Friedrichroda</city>
        <zip>99894</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hannover</city>
        <zip>30159</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hassfurt</city>
        <zip>97437</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Köln</city>
        <zip>50937</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Magdeburg</city>
        <zip>39114</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oldenburg</city>
        <zip>26133</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rostock</city>
        <zip>18107</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wildeshausen</city>
        <zip>27793</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wuerzburg</city>
        <zip>97080</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Co Dublin</city>
        <country>Ireland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dublin</city>
        <zip>9</zip>
        <country>Ireland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beirut</city>
        <zip>11-2555</zip>
        <country>Lebanon</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beirut</city>
        <zip>1107 2020</zip>
        <country>Lebanon</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beirut</city>
        <zip>166378</zip>
        <country>Lebanon</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beirut</city>
        <zip>166830</zip>
        <country>Lebanon</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beirut</city>
        <country>Lebanon</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saida</city>
        <zip>652</zip>
        <country>Lebanon</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <state>Andalucia</state>
        <zip>41014</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hospitalet de Llobregat</city>
        <state>Barcelona</state>
        <zip>08907</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Villamartin</city>
        <state>Cadiz</state>
        <zip>11650</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Palmas de Gran Canaria</city>
        <state>Las Palmas de G.C</state>
        <zip>35010</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Palmas de Gran Canaria</city>
        <zip>35016</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Luzern</city>
        <state>LU</state>
        <zip>6004</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Abu Dhabi</city>
        <zip>51900</zip>
        <country>United Arab Emirates</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ras Al Khaimah</city>
        <zip>4727</zip>
        <country>United Arab Emirates</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Ireland</country>
    <country>Lebanon</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
    <country>United Arab Emirates</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 7, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 10, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Multiple Patient Program, LCZ696, heart failure, heart failure with reduced ejection fraction, HF-rEF</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>LCZ 696</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
