<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02149043</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Ulcerative colitis represents a chronic condition occurring in relapsing and remitting fashion with uncertain outcome and requires lifelong treatment with considerable side effects. Diagnostic methods currently in use, clinical (endoscopy), imaging (CT, MR) or laboratory (C - reactive protein, calprotectin) give an insight into disease activity, but are possibly associated with significant discomfort for the patient and / or increased risk of irradiation and potential allergic reactions on contrast agents. For that reason there is a need for a noninvasive, biologically inert method for evaluation of disease activity in inflammatory bowel disease (IBD). Thermography possesses most of these characteristics. The aim of this study is to find potential link between pathological thermographic signs and endoscopic findings, serum C reactive protein (CRP) and calprotectin in the stool of patients with active and extensive ulcerative colitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Thermography in Surveillance of Ulcerative Colitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Hypothesis: Documenting pathological thermographic signs in patients with extensive ulcerative colitis investigators will demonstrate pathological thermography criteria that correlate with standard inflammatory markers such as Mayo endoscopic subscore (ESS), CRP and calprotectin in patients with ulcerative colitis. Aims: The aim of this study is to record abdominal thermographic images of patients with active ulcerative colitis (UC), to create interpretational thermographic criteria for these images and to compare them to abdominal infrared (IR) images of healthy volunteers. Furthermore investigators intend to correlate these criteria with standard markers of inflammation such as CRP and calprotectin in patients with UC at the beginning of treatment and at the end. Materials and methods: For the purpose of this work, 30 patients with extensive UC and 30 healthy individuals will be put throe thermographic imagining, have their stool tested for calprotectin and their blood for CRP. In addition, patients with UC will receive colonoscopy evaluations. Expected scientific contribution: The results of this paper would give additional contribution to existing tools for pursuing ulcerative colitis activity thus demonstrating the potential of thermography as a complementary method to standard methods in assessing disease activity. Establishing diagnostic criteria for this method would be a good addition to present clinical practice.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Endoscopic diagnosis of active extensive ulcerative colitis Stool Calprotectin &gt; 150 mcg/g CRP &gt; 5 mg/L Signed informed consent form Inability to preform total colonoscopy Marked abdominal comorbidities Prior abdominal surgery</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>inflammatory bowel disease</keyword>
	<keyword>ulcerative colitis</keyword>
	<keyword>thermography</keyword>
	<keyword>endoscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>CRP</keyword>
</DOC>