<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02028819</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Ibalizumab is a humanized immunoglobulin G monoclonal antibody directed against a human T-cell receptor (CD4) and thus suppresses HIV replication by blocking entry of HIV into CD4+ lymphocytes. Ibalizumab has completed phase I and II clinical studies in HIV-negative and HIV-infected individuals showing safety and efficacy for suppressing HIV replication.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Compassionate Use of Ibalizumab for the Treatment of HIV Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>1. Ibalizumab is a humanized immunoglobulin G monoclonal antibody directed against a human T-cell receptor (CD4) and thus suppresses HIV replication by blocking entry of HIV into CD4+ lymphocytes. Ibalizumab is in the pipeline for FDA approval to treat HIV infection. Phase I and II clinical studies have been completed in HIV-negative and HIV-infected individuals showing safety and efficacy for suppressing HIV replication. 2. Use of this medication requires that a single patient IND be obtained from the FDA for each patient requiring ibalizumab. An individual use IND has been approved by the FDA for one patient on treatment through this protocol; The IND number is 114515. The manufacturer of ibalizumab (TaiMed Biologics, Inc) will ship the drug directly to the Denver Health pharmacy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dolutegravir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients with a diagnosis of HIVinfection with resistance or intolerance to currently available antiretroviral medications available in the United States or in whom additional drugs need to be added to their regimen because of inadequate response to existing therapy Patients with HIV infection that is expected to be sensitive to dolutegravir and ibalizumab Patients who do not qualify for or who are otherwise ineligible for clinical trials of medications not currently approved for treatment of HIV infection in the U.S. Patients who are allergic to or have had a severe adverse reaction to dolutegravir or ibalizumab in the past. Age &lt;18 years or &gt;89 years Women may not be pregnant Prisoners and decisionally challenged patients will be excluded</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>