<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02752139</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the relationship between sleep disorders and cerebral hemodynamics.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cerebral Hemodynamics in Sleep Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Sleep disorders continue to be the most unrecognized modifiable risk factor for stroke. The relationship between sleep disorders and vascular risk factors and stroke has been well-documented but not fully understood. The investigators hypothesize hemodynamics impairment to be its potential mechanism. It has been reported that sleep-related breathing disorder, a type of sleep disorders, contributed as a risk factor for stroke through hemodynamic and hematologic changes. The purpose of this study is to determine the relationship between sleep disorders and cerebral hemodynamics. The dynamic cerebral auto-regulation (dCA) and Transcranial Doppler (TCD) will be used to evaluate cerebral hemodynamics.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Disorders, Intrinsic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients with sleep disorders meet the Diagnostic Criteria for Sleep Dyssomnias sufficient bilateral temporal bone windows for insonation of the MCA middle cerebral artery (MCA) and/or other intracranial and/or extracranial major vascular 4 stenosis/occlusion, as diagnosed by a transcranial Doppler having a prior symptomatic cerebral vascular disease current arrhythmia, hyperthyroidism, anemia and unstable blood pressure, which may undermine hemodynamic stability inability to cooperate sufficiently to complete the dCA examination</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sleep Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Cerebral Hemodynamics</keyword>
	<keyword>Dynamic Cerebral Auto-Regulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
</DOC>