<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02752802</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the amount of contrast media (CM) saved using the DyeVert system in diagnostic angiographic procedures compared to a control group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>DyeVert System RCT</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, randomized, parallel group, single center clinical evaluation of the DyeVert System. Subjects undergoing a diagnostic coronary angiogram procedure with a 5 French catheter are eligible to participate in this study. The treatment group will use the DyeVert System. The trial will be conducted at one center, located in Germany. A sample size of 96 evaluable subjects will provide a sufficient number of samples to evaluate the primary objectives. Randomization will occur following confirmation that the subject meets the inclusion/exclusion criteria and has signed an informed consent. Subjects that are anticipated to be a diagnostic only procedure, but end up being an ad-hoc PCI, can still remain enrolled in the trial. If a subject proceeds to a PCI, data will only be collected through the diagnostic portion of the case.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. The subject is indicated for a diagnostic coronary angiogram procedure with a 5 French catheter only. 2. The subject is ≥ 18 years of age 3. The subject is willing and able to provide appropriate informed consent. 1. Subject is undergoing a STEMI procedure 2. Subject has previously been diagnosed with anomalous coronary anatomy 3. Subject has previously underwent coronary artery bypass grafting 4. Subject has severe peripheral artery disease at access site 5. Subject is having a staged PCI 6. The subject is female and currently pregnant 7. In the investigator's opinion, the subject is not considered to be a suitable candidate</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Contrast Media</keyword>
	<keyword>Angiography</keyword>
</DOC>