<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02752815</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a clinical trial to compare the efficacy and safety of four cycles of R-CHOP followed by four cycles of Rituximab with six cycles of R-CHOP followed by two cycles of Rituximab in the treatment of de novo, low-risk, non-bulky diffuse large B-cell lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Reduced Chemotherapy in Low Risk DLBCL</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epirubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vincristine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed de novo diffuse large Bcell lymphoma, complete response after 4 cycles of standard RCHOP21 Age&gt;=14 y.o.,&lt;=75 y.o. IPI=01 nonbulky (largest diameter &lt;7.5cm) ECOG =01 Life expectancy&gt;6 months Informed consented Chemotherapy before Stem cell transplantation before History of malignancy, except for basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix Uncontrollable cardiocerebral vascular, coagulative, autoimmune, serious infectious disease Primary cutaneous, CNS DLBCL LVEF≤50% Other uncontrollable medical condition that may that may interfere the participation of the study Lab at enrollment(unless caused by lymphoma) Neutrophile&lt;1.5*10^9/L Platelet&lt;80*10^9/L Hemoglobulin&lt;100g/L ALT or AST &gt;2*ULN,AKP or bilirubin &gt;1.5*ULN Creatinine&gt;1.5*ULN Not able to comply to the protocol for mental or other unknown reasons Pregnant or lactation If HbsAg positive, should check HBV DNA, DNA positive patients cannot be enrolled. If HBsAg negative but HBcAb positive (whatever HBsAb status), should check HBV DNA,DNA positive patients cannot be enrolled. HIV infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>