<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00901095</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of the study is to investigate the efficacy of an evidence-based weight loss intervention, on a background of quality health care, on asthma control among obese adults. The intervention will employ a combination of recommended dietary and physical activity changes, and behavioral modification techniques.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Can Diet- and Exercise-Induced Weight Loss Improve Asthma Control in Adults?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants will meet all of the following: Age: 1870 years of age; Obesity: BMI &gt;30.0 kg/m2; Physiciandiagnosed asthma that is poorly controlled: Documented diagnosis of asthma on the current medical problem list Currently prescribed an antiasthma medication Overall score &lt;20 on the Asthma Control Test (ACT)64 or a score&lt;3 on any of the first four ACT questions regarding symptoms, nighttime awakening, interference with normal activity, and SABA use for symptom relief Demonstrable airway reversibility Seen in primary care at Kaiser at least once in the preceding 24 months; KPNC member for &gt;1 year. Any of the following will exclude participants from the study: Inability to speak, read or understand English; Intermittent asthma, defined as either seasonal asthma or (daytime asthma symptoms &lt; 2x/week and nocturnal symptoms &lt; 2x/month and no use of longterm control medications); Diagnosis of COPD (emphysema or chronic bronchitis) on the current medical problem list or suggested by spirometry at baseline; Unwilling to attempt weight loss, including unwillingness to perform selfmonitoring; Body weight change (+/) &gt; 10 pounds or use of weightloss medications in the preceding 3 months; Inability to perform pulmonary function tests by spirometry in a consistent manner; Significant medical comorbidities, including uncontrolled metabolic disorders (e.g., thyroid, diabetes, renal, liver), unstable heart disease, heart failure, and ongoing substance abuse; Diagnosis of psychiatric disorders that would limit adequate informed consent or ability to comply with study protocol; Regular use of medications that can cause weight gain (e.g., oral corticosteroids, insulin, certain oral hypoglycemics, certain antidepressants, etc.); Under treatment for cancer or another condition that may prevent completion of followup; Diagnosis of a terminal illness and/or in hospice care; Use of a pacemaker or other implanted medical devices; Pregnant, planning to become pregnant, or lactating; Actively enrolled in a care management program focused on weight loss at Kaiser or elsewhere; Already enrolled or planning to enroll in a research study that would limit full participation in the study or confound the observation and interpretation of the study's findings; Family household member already enrolled in the study; No longer receiving primary care from Kaiser, or planning not to do so within the study period; PCP determination that the study is inappropriate or unsafe for the patient; Investigator discretion for clinical safety or protocol adherence reasons.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>