<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02118571</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this protocol is to develop items for a patient-reported outcome (PRO) measure to assess the patient's perspective and subjective experience of cognitive impairment associated with schizophrenia (CIAS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Schizophrenia Cognition Scale Development</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cognitive impairment associated with schizophrenia (CIAS) has been shown to be the strongest predictor of functional impairment among people with schizophrenia because it is associated with poor response to psychosocial interventions, employment status, and social functioning. Because the subjective experience of CIAS is likely to be associated with patient burden, distress, and motivation for treatment, it is important that this experience be assessed in a reliable and valid manner and from the perspective of the patient's self report. No existing instrument to assess CIAS has been developed with patient input directly about their qualitative experience of impaired cognition during the item generation stage, in accordance with FDA guidance for patient-reported outcome (PRO) measures.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients with established diagnoses of schizophrenia (confirmed by the Structured Clinical Interview for DSMIV [full version or Clinical Trial version] either performed as part of the study screening process or as documented in the medical record within 2 years prior to the study) with the following clinical features: a)Clinically stable and in the residual (nonacute) phase of their illness for at least 8 weeks b)Maintained on current antipsychotic and concomitant psychotropic medications for at least 6 weeks and on current dose for at least 2 weeks c)Have no more than a ''moderate'' severity rating on hallucinations and delusions (e.g. Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale [PANSS] item scores &lt; 5 d)Have no more than a ''moderate'' severity rating on positive formal thought disorder (e.g. Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale [PANSS] conceptual disorganization item score &lt; 5) e)Have no more than a ''moderate'' severity rating on negative symptoms (e.g., Positive and Negative Syndrome Scalenegative syndrome total score &lt; 21) f) Have no more than a minimal level of depressive symptoms (e.g. Calgary Depression Scale total score &lt; 10); or, for eligibility for a waiting list, have a moderate level of depressive symptoms (e.g., Calgary Depression Scale total score between 10 and 15) 2. Male or female patients age 18 to 55 years 3. Exhibits reliability, physiologic capability, and an educational level sufficient to comply with all protocol procedures. 4. Able to provide informed consent 1. Patient currently treated with more than two antipsychotic medications 2. Patient's cognitive impairment severity compromises the ability of the participant to participate meaningfully in a semistructured interview, in the clinical judgment of the investigator 3. Any suicidal ideation of type 4 or 5 in the CSSRS in the past 3 months (i.e. active suicidal thought with intent but without specific plan, or active suicidal thought with plan and intent) 4. Nonpsychiatric disorders of the central nervous system (including but not limited to any kind of seizures, stroke, or traumatic brain injury) 5. Any other clinical condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would jeopardize a patient's safety while participating in this study 6. In the 6 months prior, having met the criteria for dependence or abuse according to the DSM V in the opinion of the investigator. 7. Participation in another trial with an investigational drug or procedure within 30 days prior to screening or previous participation in any BI 409306 study 8. Unable to speak or read in English</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>