<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01131156</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators hypothesized that an enriched focus on mother-infant bonding during a newborn's hospitalization in the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit would reduced the rate maternal postpartum smoking relapse and would prolong the duration of breastfeeding in mothers who had quit smoking during or just prior to pregnancy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prevention of Postpartum Smoking Relapse in Mothers of Infants in the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Mothers of newborns admitted to the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU), who had quit smoking during or just prior to pregnancy where randomized to either the Standard of Care or Smoking Relapse Prevention group. Mothers in both groups were encouraged to remain smoke free following the birth of their babies and were given routine lactation support for breastfeeding during their babies' hospitalization in the NICU. Mothers in the Smoking Relapse Prevention group were also given the study intervention, which was enhanced support for maternal-infant bonding by providing information about their newborn's behaviors using books, DVDs, and handouts that were appropriate for their baby's gestational age and by encouraging frequent skin-to-skin holding. Primary outcomes included duration of smoke-free status and duration of breastfeeding.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Mothers: Who had quit smoking during pregnancy or within one year prior to pregnancy Who had newborns &lt; 1 week old at the time of admission to our NICU. Mothers: Who were smokers at the time of delivery Whose infant's length of stay &lt; one week Who were not available (jail, adoption) Who had a history of drug use Who did not speak English</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>1 Week</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>postpartum</keyword>
	<keyword>smoking</keyword>
	<keyword>relapse</keyword>
	<keyword>breastfeeding</keyword>
</DOC>