<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02824146</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Anesthesia-induced atelectasis is a well-known entity observed in approximately 68-100% of pediatric patients undergoing general anesthesia. The collapse of dependent lung zones starts with anesthesia induction but can persist for hours or even days after surgery. Such anesthesia-related atelectasis has a number of negative clinical consequences such as the impairment of arterial blood oxygenation and lung mechanics as well as the predisposition for ventilator-associated lung injury. The adjustment of ventilator settings for preventing the occurrence of atelectasis and for reducing pulmonary complications remains controversial. Lung sonography (LUS) plays an important role in diagnosing pulmonary diseases in children, including atelectasis of different origins. LUS has demonstrated its high sensitivity and specificity for diagnosing anesthesia-induced atelectasis in children.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lung Recruitment Assessment With Lung Ultrasound In Pediatric Patient Scheduled For Laparoscopic Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Compare lung aeration between two different mechanical ventilation strategies (protective mechanical ventilation and recruitment maneuvers) in pediatric patients scheduled for abdominal laparoscopic surgery using ultrasound imaging and a four-point-aeration score to assess the lung aeration.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Atelectasis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent by parents. Patients aged 6 months to 7 years old Scheduled for abdominal laparoscopic surgery American Society of Anesthesiologists classification: physical status III Acute airway infection Cardiovascular and or pulmonary disease Previous thoracic procedure</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>7 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>atelectasis</keyword>
	<keyword>children</keyword>
	<keyword>lung ultrasound</keyword>
	<keyword>lung recruitment</keyword>
</DOC>