<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02824198</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to assess and describe the booster effect of a CYD dengue vaccine dose administered 5 years after the completion of a 3-dose vaccination schedule. Primary Objective: - To demonstrate the non-inferiority in terms of geometric mean of titer ratios (GTMR) of a CYD dengue vaccine booster compared to the third CYD dengue vaccine injection in subjects from CYD 28 trial (subjects from Group 1 only). Secondary Objectives: - If the primary objective of non-inferiority is achieved: To demonstrate the superiority, in terms of GMTRs, of a CYD dengue vaccine booster compared to the third CYD dengue vaccine injection in subjects from CYD28 trial (subjects from Group 1 only). - To describe the immune responses elicited by the CYD dengue vaccine booster or placebo injection in subjects who received three doses of the CYD dengue vaccine in the CYD28 trial in all subjects. - To describe the neutralizing Abs levels of each dengue serotype post-dose 3 (CYD28 subjects) and immediately prior to booster or placebo injection in all subjects. - To describe the neutralizing Ab persistence 6 months, 1 year and 2 years post booster or placebo injection in all study subjects. - To evaluate the safety of booster vaccination with CYD dengue vaccine in all study subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunogenicity and Safety of a Tetravalent Dengue Vaccine Booster Injection in Subjects Who Previously Completed a 3-dose Schedule</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Healthy adolescents and adults who received 3 doses of the tetravalent dengue vaccine 5 years earlier in a previous CYD dengue vaccine trial (CYD28 - NCT00880893) will receive a booster injection of either a CYD dengue vaccine or a placebo on Day 0. They will be evaluated for safety and antibody persistence of the booster injection up to 2 years post-vaccination.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dengue</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhagic Fevers, Viral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Severe Dengue</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Has been identified as a potential subject by the Sponsor, and is included in the list provided to the investigator (i.e., aged 9 to 45 years on the day of first injection of CYD dengue vaccine in CYD28, has received 3 doses of CYD dengue vaccine in the CYD28 trial, and has a postDose 3 serum sample available). Presently in good health, based on medical history and physical examination. Informed consent form (ICF) has been signed and dated by the subject (based on local regulations), and ICF has been signed and dated by the parent(s) or another legally acceptable representative (and by an independent witness if required by local regulations) Subject and parent(s)/legally acceptable representative(s) able to attend all scheduled visits and to comply with all trial procedures. Subject who received any other dengue vaccination that was not part of CYD28 Subject is pregnant, or lactating, or of childbearing potential (to be considered of non childbearing potential, a female must be premenarche or postmenopausal for at least 1 year, surgically sterile, or using an effective method of contraception or abstinence from at least 4 weeks prior to vaccination until at least 4 weeks after vaccination) Participation at the time of study enrollment (or in the 4 weeks preceding the trial vaccination) or planned participation during the present trial period in another clinical trial investigating a vaccine, drug, medical device, or medical procedure Receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks preceding the trial vaccination or planned receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks following the trial vaccination Receipt of immune globulins, blood or bloodderived products in the past 3 months Known or suspected congenital or acquired immunodeficiency; or receipt of immunosuppressive therapy, such as anticancer chemotherapy or radiation therapy, within the preceding 6 months; or longterm systemic corticosteroid therapy (prednisone or equivalent for more than 2 consecutive weeks within the past 3 months) Known systemic hypersensitivity to any of the vaccine components, or history of a lifethreatening reaction to the vaccines used in the trial or to a vaccine containing any of the same substances Chronic illness that, in the opinion of the Investigator, is at a stage where it might interfere with trial conduct or completion Receipt of blood or bloodderived products in the past 3 months, which might interfere with assessment of the immune response Deprived of freedom by an administrative or court order, or in an emergency setting, or hospitalized involuntarily Current alcohol abuse or drug addiction Moderate or severe acute illness/infection (according to investigator judgment) on the day of vaccination or febrile illness (temperature ≥ 38.0°C). A prospective subject should not be included in the study until the condition has resolved or the febrile event has subsided Identified as an Investigator or employee of the Investigator or study center with direct involvement in the proposed study, or identified as an immediate family member (i.e., parent, spouse, natural or adopted child) of the Investigator or employee with direct involvement in the proposed study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dengue Hemorrhagic Fever</keyword>
	<keyword>Dengue Virus</keyword>
	<keyword>CYD Dengue Vaccine</keyword>
</DOC>