<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01008904</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Magnesium oxide may help relieve hot flashes in women with cancer. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well magnesium oxide works in treating hot flashes in menopausal women with cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Magnesium Oxide in Treating Hot Flashes in Menopausal Women With Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - To determine if magnesium oxide supplement will decrease the frequency and severity of hot flashes by 50% in menopausal women with cancer. Secondary - To evaluate the effect of magnesium oxide on overall quality of life. - To evaluate the toxicities of magnesium oxide when administered at commonly used supplement doses. OUTLINE: Patients receive oral magnesium oxide once daily in weeks 2-5. Patients whose hot flashes are not satisfactorily controlled after 2 weeks of treatment may receive magnesium oxide twice daily in weeks 4 and 5. Patients complete a daily hot flash diary for 5 weeks beginning 1 week before treatment. Patients also complete quality-of-life, symptom, and self-assessment questionnaires at baseline, once weekly during treatment, and at the completion of treatment. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for at least 30 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hot Flashes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Magnesium Oxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Meets 1 of the following criteria: History of breast cancer (currently without malignant disease) No history of breast cancer but wishes to avoid estrogen due to a perceived increased risk of breast cancer Must have bothersome hot flashes (defined by their occurrence of ≥ 14 times per week and of sufficient severity to make the patient desire therapeutic intervention) for ≥ 1 month before study entry Has undergone treatment for cancer (patients other than breast cancer survivors are eligible) PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 02 Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception Creatinine clearance ≥ 30 mL/min No hypersensitivity to magnesium oxide No medical or other condition(s) that, in the opinion of the investigator/subinvestigator, may compromise the objectives of the study PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics More than 4 weeks since prior and no concurrent antineoplastic chemotherapy, androgens, estrogens, progestational agents, or gabapentin More than 28 days since prior and no other concurrent investigational drugs Concurrent tamoxifen, raloxifene, or aromatase inhibitors allowed provided patient has been on a constant dose for &gt; 4 weeks AND is not expected to stop the medication during the study period</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cancer survivor</keyword>
	<keyword>hot flashes</keyword>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>unspecified adult solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
</DOC>