<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03020927</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to examine whether adding a parent education component to an existing intervention (Reciprocal Imitation Training) results in improved outcomes for children with Autism Spectrum Disorder. Reciprocal Imitation Training (RIT) is a behavioral intervention designed to improve spontaneous imitation skills in young children with Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD). Previous research suggests that it can be effective when used by trained therapists, teachers, siblings, and parents of children with ASD. However, it is unclear to what extent training parents to use RIT strategies in the home environment may enhance outcomes, compared to having therapists implement RIT individually with the child. The study will compare two different versions of RIT for young children with ASD: (1) two 60-minute weekly sessions of therapist-implemented RIT and (2) one weekly 60-minute session of therapist-implemented RIT and one weekly 60-minute session of parent education about using RIT in the home environment. The investigators will examine child and family outcomes between these two intervention types. Outcomes examined will include: (1) spontaneous and prompted imitation skills in the child with ASD, (2) social communication skills in the child with ASD, (3) parent stress, and (4) parent and child behaviors during parent-child play interactions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Therapist and Parent Delivered Reciprocal Imitation Training for Young Children With Autism Spectrum Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Child Development Disorders, Pervasive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>have a community diagnosis of Autism Spectrum Disorder (as reported by parent) meet cutoff for "Autism" or "Autism Spectrum" on the Autism Diagnostic Observation Schedule, 2nd Edition be between 24 and 60 months of age at the time of study enrollment demonstrate difficulties with imitation skills on the Motor Imitation Scales and/or the Unstructured Imitation Assessment during pretreatment assessments Participants must not be the sibling of another study participant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>24 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>