<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03020264</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Diabetes is a chronic and progressive disease that affects nearly 3.5 million people in France. Currently the investigators are seeing an aging of the population explained by the increase in life expectancy and thus an increasing incidence of diabetes in the elderly. However, the frequency of hypoglycemia in older vulnerable patients remains poorly characterized</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Frequency of Hypoglycemia in Patients With Type 2 Diabetes Under Insulin Therapy Older Than 75 Years in Real Life</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypoglycemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female ≥ 75 years of age; Type 2 diabetes for at least 1 year and treated with insulin for at least 6 months; Treated with basal insulin (ie glargine U100: Lantus®, Abasaglar®, glargine U300: Toujeo®, detemir: levemir®, NPH), premix (ie Novomix® and Humalog Mix®), and / Insulin associated or not with one or more oral and / or injectable antidiabetic agents (analog of GLP1...); Benefiting from at least 1 capillary glucose per day (carried out by the patient himself or a caregiver); Benefiting from a standardized geriatric assessment; Signature of informed consent. Male or female aged &lt;75 years; Person without diabetes or type 1 diabetes; Patient treated only lifestyle modifications and / or oral antidiabetic drugs and / or GLP1 receptor agonists alone; Subjects with secondary or corticosteroidinduced diabetes; Refusal to participate in the study or inability to collect consent; Patient for whom followup of the study procedures is impossible (glycemic record impossible or insufficient); Patient not eligible for geriatric assessment; Patient already participating in another study; Patient with a severe pathology limiting his life expectancy (palliative care ...) compromising his participation in the study at the discretion of the investigator; Patient benefiting from a safeguard of justice.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>75 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypoglycemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulinotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>