<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01563939</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Epidural analgesia for pain relief in labor may not be suitable for all patients, and intravenous patient controlled analgesia (IV PCA) with opioids offers the best alternative. The purpose of this study is to assess the effectiveness of two methods remifentanil administration in the form of either an infusion or PCA demand bolus (intravenous injection of a single dose over a short period of time). Currently, our hospital gives remifentanil by demand bolus, however it may be equally effective, with less side effects, to give the drug as an infusion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Patient-controlled Intravenous Analgesia With Remifentanil Infusion for Labour</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will be conducted as a randomized trial with two arms: Group I- continuous infusion of remifentanil with stepwise increase in infusion rates and Group II- demand bolus only with stepwise increase in bolus dose, as per the patient's analgesic requirement. Visual analog scores will be the primary outcome. Maternal and fetal side effects will be recorded. The results of this study will determine the regimen that suits the patients needs for painless labor with high efficacy, less adverse effects and a higher patient satisfaction.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Remifentanil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent Term pregnancy in labour with singleton fetus in cephalic presentation Patients requesting systemic analgesia Patients with contraindication for regional anesthesia without fetal compromise (coagulopathy, thrombocytopenia, refusal, etc.) Refusal to sign written informed consent Inability to communicate in English Opioid dependence or addiction Patients on Methadone Allergy or hypersensitivity to remifentanil Fetal heart rate abnormalities Fetal congenital anomalies</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Labour analgesia</keyword>
	<keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>IVPCA</keyword>
</DOC>