<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="142457">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01246401</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1007007169</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01246401</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Naltrexone for Opioid Dependent Released Human Immunodeficiency Virus Positive (HIV+) Criminal Justice Populations</brief_title>
  <acronym>NewHope</acronym>
  <official_title>Naltrexone for Opioid Dependent Released Human Immunodeficiency Virus Positive (HIV+) Criminal Justice Populations</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Baystate Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Specific Aim: To conduct a randomized, placebo-controlled trial of extended
      release-naltrexone (XR-NTX) among Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) infected prisoners
      meeting Diagnostic Statistical Manual IV (DSM-IV) criteria for opioid dependence who are
      transitioning from the structure of a correctional setting to the community.

      Hypotheses:

      i. XR-NTX will result in improved HIV clinical outcomes, including lower changes in HIV-1
      RNA levels, higher CD4 counts and higher rates of retention in care.

      ii. XR-NTX will result in improved opioid treatment outcomes, including longer time to
      opioid relapse, lower addiction severity and lower craving for opioid.

      iii. XR-NTX will result in reduced drug- and sex-related HIV risk behaviors compared to the
      control group.

      iv. XR-NTX will result in decreased rates of reincarceration after 12 months of release to
      the community.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The specific aim for this study is to conduct a placebo-controlled trail (RCT) of XR-NTX
      among HIV+ persons in jails and prisons meeting DSM-IV criteria for opioid dependence who
      are transitioning to the community. HIV treatment outcomes (HIV-1 RNA levels, CD4 count,
      Highly Active Antiretroviral Therapy (HAART) adherence, retention in care), substance abuse
      (time to relapse to opioid use, % opioid negative urines, opioid craving), adverse side
      effects and HIV risk behavior (sexual and drug-related risks) outcomes will be compared in
      150 recruited prisoners and jail detainees in Connecticut (CT) and Massachusetts (MA) who
      will be randomized 2:1 to either XR-NTX or placebo. The primary outcome of interest will be
      the proportion with a HIV-RNA &lt;400 copies/mL at 6 months. Secondary outcomes include mean
      CD4 count, antiretroviral adherence, retention on HAART and in HIV care, HIV risk behaviors,
      time-to-relapse to opioid use, percent opioid negative urines, retention on d-NTX and HIV
      quality of life. Primary and secondary outcomes will be assessed for an additional 6 months
      after completion of the intervention. If this placebo-controlled trial of XR-NTX among
      released HIV+ criminal justice system (CJS) persons with opioid dependence demonstrates
      efficacy and safety, it is likely to become an evidence-based intervention to intervene with
      this extremely marginalized population in a way that will meet Healthy People 2010's goals
      to increase the quality and years of life, decrease health disparities particularly among
      minorities, break the cycle of addiction, reduce the numbers of people within the CJS and
      launch a number of new and innovative trials and second generation questions for future
      research. As such, the individual, our health care system and society have a high likelihood
      to benefit. This will not only be true for strategies here in the U.S., but may have even
      greater application for geographic areas where the interface between opioid disorders and
      HIV is even greater.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HIV-1 RNA levels (copies/mL)</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline and every 3 months for 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline labs will be drawn while subject is in prison, one to three months prior to release. Additionally, labs will be drawn every 3 months for 1 year to monitor changes in HIV-1 RNA levels.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CD4 cell count (cells/mL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and every 3 months for 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline labs will be drawn while subject is in prison, one to three months prior to release. Additional labs will be drawn every 3 months for 1 year to monitor changes in CD4 levels.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>time to opioid relapse</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, months 3, 6, 9, and 12</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>addiction severity</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, months 3, 6, 9 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Addiction Severity Index questionnaire will be used to assess addiction severity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Craving for opioids</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline then every month until 12 months after release</time_frame>
    <description>Done using Visual Analog Scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">102</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV</condition>
  <condition>AIDS</condition>
  <condition>Opioid Dependence</condition>
  <condition>Drug Dependence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Extended-Release Naltrexone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive intramuscular (IM) injections of Naltrexone once monthly for 6 months, the first injection being prior release</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive IM injections of Placebo once monthly for 6 months, the first injection being prior release</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Extended-Release Naltrexone</intervention_name>
    <description>Extended-Release Naltrexone (Vivitrol), once a month by IM injection, for a total of 6 months. Dosage is 380mg</description>
    <arm_group_label>Extended-Release Naltrexone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Naltrexone, depot</other_name>
    <other_name>Vivitrol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Meets DSM-IV criteria for opioid dependence

          2. Age &gt; 18 years

          3. Confirmed HIV infection, either through positive HIV antibody or detectable HIV-1 RNA
             level.

          4. Within the Connecticut Department of Corrections (CTDOC) or Hampden County
             Correctional Center (HCCC) and within 30 days of being released to the greater New
             Haven, Hartford or Springfield areas or within 30 days after release from CTDOC or
             HCCC.

          5. No participation in pharmacotherapy trial in the previous 30 days

          6. Not pregnant

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Unable to provide informed consent

          2. Verbally or physically threatening to research staff

          3. Unable to communicate in either English or Spanish

          4. Pending trials for a felony

          5. Liver failure (Childs-Pugh Class B or C Cirrhosis)

          6. Grade IV Hepatitis (liver function tests &gt; 10X normal)

          7. Receiving opioid prescription narcotics or has pain syndrome necessitating future use
             of opioid prescription narcotics.

          8. Receiving active methadone or buprenorphine/naloxone for the treatment of opioid
             dependency

          9. Active opioid withdrawal (within 3-5 days since last opioid ingestion)

         10. Pregnancy or unwilling to take contraceptives measures

         11. Breast-feeding
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sandra A Springer, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Frederick L Altice</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hartford</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale University</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06519</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baystate Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Springfield</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>01103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Di Paola A, Lincoln T, Skiest DJ, Desabrais M, Altice FL, Springer SA. Design and methods of a double blind randomized placebo-controlled trial of extended-release naltrexone for HIV-infected, opioid dependent prisoners and jail detainees who are transitioning to the community. Contemp Clin Trials. 2014 Nov;39(2):256-68. doi: 10.1016/j.cct.2014.09.002. Epub 2014 Sep 18.</citation>
    <PMID>25240704</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vagenas P, Di Paola A, Herme M, Lincoln T, Skiest DJ, Altice FL, Springer SA. An evaluation of hepatic enzyme elevations among HIV-infected released prisoners enrolled in two randomized placebo-controlled trials of extended release naltrexone. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2014 Jul;47(1):35-40. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2014.02.008. Epub 2014 Mar 12.</citation>
    <PMID>24674234</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Springer SA, Brown SE, Di Paola A, Altice FL. Correlates of retention on extended-release naltrexone among persons living with HIV infection transitioning to the community from the criminal justice system. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2015 Dec 1;157:158-65. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2015.10.023. Epub 2015 Oct 28. Erratum in: Drug Alcohol Depend. 2016 Apr 1;161:372. Altice, Frederick L [added].</citation>
    <PMID>26560326</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>October 4, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>November 22, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>HIV Seropositivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Naltrexone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data has been shared with the National Institute on Drug Abuse as a site in the data harmonization project associated with Seek, Test, Treat and Retain for Criminal Justice Populations.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
