<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02169089</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Atherosclerotic disease, or hardening of the arteries, is characterized by the thickening of the arterial walls due to fatty deposits in wall and inflammation in the wall of arteries. High cholesterol, high blood pressure, diabetes, obesity and genetics play an important role in developing clinical symptoms of atherosclerosis disease. The complications of advanced atherosclerosis are chronic, slowly progressive and cumulative, resulting in heart attack, stroke and/or death and blockage of arteries. This study is being done to assess the effectiveness of Spironolactone therapy to slow down the worsening of atherosclerotic disease (hardening of the arteries) in aorta (this is a large vessel coming out of your heart) compared to placebo (look alike sugar pill). This will be checked by comparing before and after therapy magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) pictures of your aortic wall. Spironolactone is an FDA approved drug used to treat heart failure and in the management of hypertension (high blood pressure), but in this study it is used for another unapproved reason. In this study, we would like to evaluate the effects of Spironolactone in people with diabetes and atherosclerotic disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mineralocorticoid Receptor Antagonism Clinical Evaluation in Atherosclerosis Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spironolactone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mineralocorticoids</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female patients &gt; 45 years and able to provide informed consent (females must be either postmenopausal for one year, surgically sterile, or using effective contraception. Oral contraceptives are disallowed. 2. Patients with Type II Diabetes with HbA1c ≤ 8.0 on stable antiglycemic regimen that may include oral and/or injectable therapy (GLP1/Insulin etc.). No new drugs are allowed. Changes in dose of glycemic regimen is allowed during the course of the trial if felt to be clinically appropriate. 3. In addition to Type II diabetes, 2 of the following additional high risk features: 1. Established cardiovascular disease [previous MI, CVA or PAD OR prior intervention/surgery for these conditions 2. Age &gt;45 years 3. Evidence of proteinuria (Urine Albumin/Creatinine Ratio of &gt;30) in a urine specimen within 12 months 4. Evidence of documented retinopathy 5. LVH on Echocardiogram or 12lead EKG 6. Family history of premature CAD 4. LDL cholesterol &lt;130 mg/dL and Plasma triglycerides &lt;300 mg/dl 5. Blood pressure ≤145/90 mm Hg at visit 2 (see TABLE 2) 6. Patients must be on ACE and/or ARB therapy and statin therapy with no planned dose adjustments. 7. Willing to sign an informed consent form to participate in the research trial 1. Uncontrolled hypertension (SBP&gt;160 and/or DBP&gt;95 mmHg at visit 0 (screening) and SBP &gt;145 mm Hg at visit 2). 2. GFR (MDRD) of &lt;40 at Visit 1. 3. Hyperkalemia defined as serum K+≥ 5.0 meq/L at visit 0 (screening). If K+ is &gt;5.5 meq/L at any time point during dose escalation the patient will be terminated. If K between 5.05.4 meq/L, Epl dose will be decreased and K+ rechecked. If K+ continues to be ≥5.5 the patient will be discontinued from the trial. There is a specific K+ management protocol in the Human Subjects section. K+ values and management will be blinded from the study investigator. 4. Contraindications to MRI (metallic implants, severe claustrophobia). 5. Acute coronary syndrome, Transient ischemic attack, CVA or critical limb ischemia during the last 6 months or coronary/peripheral revascularization within the last 3 months. 6. Evidence of a secondary form of hypertension. 7. Initiation of new therapy with statins, ACEI/ARB, antioxidants, CCBs, diuretics, β blockers. 8. Initiation of new therapy with GLP1 agonists such as Liraglutide, Exenatide etc. 9. Type I diabetes mellitus 10. Known contraindication, including history of allergy to Epl 11. Any surgical or medical condition which might alter pharmacokinetics of drug. 12. Concurrent potentially life threatening arrhythmia or symptomatic arrhythmia. 13. Significant hyponatremia defined as Na &lt;130 meq/L. 14. History of prior malignancy including leukemia and lymphoma (but not basal cell skin cancer, cured squamous cell cancer and localized Prostate cancer). 15. History of any severe, lifethreatening disease. 16. Any surgical or medical conditions which places the patient at higher risk derived from his/her participation into the study, or likely to prevent patient from complying with requirements. 17. History of drug abuse within the last 2 years, noncompliance and unwillingness/inability to consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>46 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>