<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02169284</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized phase II trial studies how well erlotinib hydrochloride works in treating patients with bladder cancer undergoing surgery. Erlotinib hydrochloride may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Erlotinib Hydrochloride in Treating Patients With Bladder Cancer Undergoing Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine if there is a difference in epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) phosphorylation in normal appearing bladder epithelium adjacent to tumor approximately 9-18 hours post-study dose, between patients randomized to erlotinib (erlotinib hydrochloride) weekly as compared to placebo. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. Assess the tolerance of high dose weekly erlotinib compared to placebo. II. Assess the expression of phosphorylated epidermal growth factor (EGF) receptor in tumor tissue when available. III. Assess the expression of cadherin 1, type 1 (e-cadherin) and marker of proliferation Ki-67 (Ki67) in normal and abnormal urothelium. IV. Assess the expression of phosphorylated extracellular regulated kinase (ERK) in normal and abnormal urothelium. V. Assess limited pharmacokinetics of weekly erlotinib. VI. Assess the expression of tumor protein 53 (p53) in normal and abnormal urothelium. VII. Assess the expression of lethal-7 (let-7) in normal and abnormal urothelium. VIII. Exploratory assessment of urination symptoms in men. OUTLINE: Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment groups. GROUP I: Patients receive erlotinib hydrochloride orally (PO) once daily (QD) on days 1, 8, and 15. Patients then undergo transurethral resection of bladder tumor (TURBT) or cystectomy on day 16. GROUP II: Patients receive placebo PO QD on days 1, 8, and 15. Patients then undergo TURBT or cystectomy on day 16. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 7-14 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants must have a confirmed or suspected invasive or noninvasive bladder tumor (initial or recurrent) discovered on cystoscopy or radiologic imaging performed within 120 days of randomization Patients with muscle invasive bladder cancer (MIBC) must have never received and currently be ineligible for cisplatinbased neoadjuvant chemotherapy due to any of the following: Calculated creatinine clearance of &lt; 60 ml/min Karnofsky performance status (KPS) &lt; 80 Solitary kidney or Patient refusal to undergo neoadjuvant chemotherapy The participant may have prior treatment for bladder tumor (excluding radiation therapy) provided that treatment: Was completed greater than 30 days prior first dose of study agent Participants must be a candidate for a transurethral resection of the bladder tumor (TURBT), cystectomy (partial or radical) or cystoscopy with biopsy at a participating organization Karnofsky &gt;= 60% White blood cells (WBC) &gt;= 3000/mm^3 Platelets &gt;= 100,000mm^3 Hemoglobin &gt; 10 g/dL International normalized ratio (INR) =&lt; 1.2 Alkaline phosphatase =&lt; upper limit of normal Bilirubin =&lt; upper limit of normal Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal A calculated creatinine clearance (Cockcroft Gault) of &gt;= 30 ml/min Sodium &gt;= 130 mg/dl and =&lt; upper limit of normal Potassium &gt;= 3.0 mg/dl and =&lt; upper limit of normal Calcium =&lt; 11.2 mg/dl Women of childbearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry and for the duration of study participation; should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while participating in this study, she should inform her study physician immediately Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document Any treatment for the bladder tumor other than intravesical therapy between the prestudy cystoscopy or radiologic imaging which identified the suspected bladder tumor and the scheduled surgical removal or cystoscopyguided biopsy of that tumor Any evidence of other cancers (excluding nonmelanoma skin cancer) or metastatic disease; suspected local lymph node involvement will be allowed Any prior pelvic radiation A concurrent skin rash or skin condition requiring treatment with a prescription medication Concurrent systemic chemotherapy for any other cancer The following medications may not be taken within 24 hours of the first dose of study agent or at any time while a participant is taking study agent Strong cytochrome P450, family 3, subfamily A, polypeptide 4 (CYP3A4) inhibitors including ketoconazole, atazanavir, boceprevir, ceritinib, clarithromycin, cobicistat, darunavir, dasabuvir, idelalisib, indinavir, itraconazole, lopinavir, nefazodone, nelfinavir, ombitasvir, paritaprevir, posaconazole, ritonavir, saquinavir, telithromycin, troleandomycin, voriconazole, and grapefruit or grapefruit juice CYP3A4 inducers including rifampicin, rifabutin, rifapentine, phenytoin, carbamazepine, phenobarbital, primidone, enzalutamide, fosphenytoin, lumacaftor, mitotane, and St. John's wort Agents which decrease gastric acid are allowed but should be avoided if possible Participants may resume inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4 &gt; 14 days after their last dose of study agent Participants requiring daily use of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), with the exception of =&lt; 81 mg aspirin per day; during study participation, acetaminophen is preferred for treatment of pain; the use of NSAIDs, as needed for pain, is discouraged Participants may not be receiving any other investigational agents History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition to erlotinib or clindamycin (topical agent for potential skin toxicity) An underlying predisposition to rectal or gastrointestinal bleeding or uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements Females who are pregnant or lactating may not participate in this study; females of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test before starting study agent; patients who have had a bilateral oophorectomy, hysterectomy, or are greater than 1 year since their last menses are not considered to be of childbearing potential</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>