<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02169752</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research study is looking at the use of the drug ambrisentan and if it can improve right ventricle function in people with systemic sclerosis-associated pre-pulmonary arterial hypertension. It is also looking at using right ventricle function changes as a marker of disease severity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ambrisentan for the Improvement in Right Ventricular Strain in Scleroderma Associated Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This research study is looking at the use of the drug ambrisentan and if it can improve right ventricle function in people with systemic sclerosis-associated pre-pulmonary arterial hypertension. It is also looking at using right ventricle function changes as a marker of disease severity. Pre-pulmonary arterial hypertension is a borderline elevation in blood pressure in the lungs. Pre-pulmonary arterial hypertension is not currently treated with the drug therapies that are used for pulmonary arterial hypertension. It represents a group of patients that are at risk for developing pulmonary arterial hypertension. The administration of ambrisentan is the experimental part of this study. Ambrisentan has not been approved by the FDA for use of improving right ventricle function in people with pre-pulmonary arterial hypertension. You will still receive your normal clinical care. The purpose of this study is to learn more about ambrisentan and its role in treating systemic sclerosis-associated pre-pulmonary arterial hypertension. Ambrisentan is already approved for use in people with systemic sclerosis-associated pulmonary arterial hypertension, but this study wants to research its role in people with pre-pulmonary arterial hypertension.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Familial Primary Pulmonary Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Scleroderma, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Scleroderma, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt;18 years, &lt; 80 years Systemic sclerosis with any of the following features: 1. Duration of Raynaud's phenomena &gt;8 years 2. Anticentromere antibody positivity 3. isolated nucleolarpattern ANA positivity 4. Extensive telangiectasias 5. DLCO &lt; 60% in the absence of extensive ILD 6. FVC%/DLCO% &gt;1.6 7. Unexplained dyspnea Right heart catheterizationproven pre PAH (mean PAP 2025 mmHg and pulmonary capillary wedge pressure &lt;15 mmHg) Systolic blood pressure &gt;100 mmHg Reliable contraception for women of childbearing age Informed consent &lt; 18 years or &gt; 80 years Left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 55% Systolic or diastolic left ventricular congestive heart failure Liver disease (abnormal AST/ALT, chronic hepatitis, or cirrhosis) Extensive ILD or FVC&lt; 60% Pregnant Breastfeeding women Cyclosporine use</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pre-Pulmonary Atrial Hypertension</keyword>
</DOC>