<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01399151</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Hypothesis: Volunteers with vitamin D insufficiency (serum 25(OH)D 25-50 nmol/L) given intermediate or high dose vitamin D supplements (2,000 or 5,000 IU per day) will have increased production of anti-bacterial peptides and interleukin-1, decreased production of other pro-inflammatory cytokines, increased production of regulatory cytokines and an enhanced T- and B-cell response to a tetanus vaccine compared to vitamin D insufficient subjects given low dose vitamin D supplements (400 IU per day).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of Vitamin D Supplementation and Immune Function</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Specific Aim 1: Determine if high dose vitamin D supplements decrease the production of proinflammatory and increase the production of regulatory cytokines and chemokines by innate immune cells stimulated ex vivo. Specific Aim 2: Determine if high dose vitamin D supplements decrease serum markers of inflammation and increase serum and cellular levels of defensive molecules (e.g., cathelicidin). Specific Aim 3: Determine if high dose vitamin D supplements decrease blood levels of proinflammatory T-helper type 1 (Th1) and Th17 cells and increase levels of anti-inflammatory T-regulatory (Treg) and Th2 cells. Specific Aim 4: Determine if high dose vitamin D supplements increase antigen specific T cell and B cell responses after tetanus vaccination.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 2049 (men) and 2045 (women) BMI 18.530 Serum 25OH Vitamin D 2550 nmol/L Pregnant or nursing women Daily smoker Anemia (Hgb&lt;12 mg/dL for women and &lt;13 mg/dL for men) determined at initial visit Any report or diagnosis of disease or chronic condition that may affect vitamin D absorption such as cystic fibrosis, celiac disease, surgical removal of part of the stomach or intestines, and some forms of liver disease Diagnosis of hyper parathyroidism and chronic granulomatous disease, which increases risk of hypercalcemia. Planned to travel to a location at which either altitude or latitude would result in significant vitamin D synthesis during the study period. Not previously vaccinated with TT, or vaccinated within five years Use of steroids or antibiotics within the past 4 weeks Current use of nutritional supplements that may alter immune function such as omega 3 fatty acid supplements Current use of antiinflammatory or anticonvulsion medications Self reported history of significant adverse response to previous vaccinations</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>Immune function</keyword>
</DOC>