<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00764530</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluate the safety and efficacy of the CeramTec Acetabular Alumina Insert and CeramTec Alumina head when used with the Foundation Porous Coated Acetabular Shell and an Encore hip stem.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cementless Alumina-Alumina Total Hip and Hybrid</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Necrosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with inflammatory tissue disorders (e.g. rheumatoid arthritis, lupus, etc), osteoarthritis, posttraumatic arthritis or secondary arthritis, or avascular necrosis. Less than 70 on preoperative HHS score Primary total hip replacement Patient is likely to be available for evaluation for the duration of the study. Patients with physical conditions that would eliminate adequate implant support or prevent the use of an appropriately sized implant (e.g., tumor) Previous surgery that has adversely affected bone stock (such as some hip pinning or some osteotomies) or prior total hip replacement. Insufficient quality or quantity of bone resulting from conditions such as: Cancer, where radiation has destroyed the available bonestock Congenital dislocation Metabolic bone disease of the upper femur or pelvis Femoral osteotomy revision Girdlestone revision Active infection of the hip joint Old or remote infection Other conditions that lead to inadequate skeletal fixation Neurological conditions that might hinder patient's ability to follow study procedures, e.g., to restrict physical activities (e.g., Severe Parkinson's, CVA on affected side) Patient's mental condition that may interfere with his ability to give an informed consent or willingness to fulfill the required followup of the study Mental illness Senility Drug Abuse Alcoholism Conditions that place excessive demands on the implant Charcot's joints Muscle deficiencies Multiple joint disabilities Refusal to modify postoperative physical activities Skeletal immaturity Obesity (50% over recorded body weight mass index) Greater than or equal to 70 on preoperative HHS score</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>