<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00764478</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial will study the efficacy and safety of a fixed dose of asenapine in participants diagnosed with Bipolar 1 Disorder. Participants who qualify for the study will be randomly assigned to receive a fixed dose of asenapine (either 5 mg or 10 mg twice daily [BID]) or placebo (BID) for 3 weeks. Throughout the trial, observations will be made on each participant at various times to assess the safety and effectiveness of the study treatment. The primary hypothesis is that there is at least one dose of asenapine that is superior to placebo in the change from baseline in manic symptoms (as measured by Young Mania Rating Scale [YMRS]) at Day 21 of the trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fixed-dose Safety and Efficacy Study of Asenapine for the Treatment of Acute Manic or Mixed Episode in Bipolar 1 Disorder (P05691)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Asenapine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Each participant must be at least 18 years of age Male, or a female who is not of childbearing potential or who is nonpregnant, nonlactating, and is using a medically accepted method of contraception Each participant must have a current diagnosis of Bipolar I Disorder, current episode manic or mixed Each participant must be confirmed to be experiencing an acute manic or mixed bipolar 1 episode Each participant must have discontinued the use of all prohibited psychotropic medications A participant must not have a primary Axis I disorder other than Bipolar 1 Disorder (i.e., an Axis 1 disorder other than Bipolar 1 Disorder that is primarily responsible for current symptoms and functional impairment) A participant must not currently (within the past 6 months) meet the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders Fourth Edition, Text Revision (DSMIVTR™) criteria for substance abuse or dependence (excluding nicotine) A participant must not be at imminent risk of selfharm or harm to others, in the investigator's opinion based on clinical interview and responses provided on the Columbia Suicide Severity Rating Scale (CSSRS).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>