<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00764647</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this evaluation is to determine the effectiveness of an educational program designed to assist family caregivers to learn the knowledge and skills to take better care of their frail elder relatives and themselves.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Education Program for Family Caregivers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Spouses, children, and other family members typically care for frail elderly persons. These family caregivers attempt to provide care for their relative in the home, despite the potential for excessive stress to themselves. This care may extend over many years, involving unrelenting management of their relative, which puts the caregiver at risk for the development of physical and mental health consequences. The stress of caring for a frail elder may result in the institutionalization of the care receiver due to declining health or abilities in the caregiver as caregivers frequently continue to provide care at the expense of their own health. The goal of the education program is to fill an important need, that is, assist caregivers to become empowered, hardier, and have the ability to cope with the stress associated with caregiving. The aim is to investigate whether this educational intervention improves selected outcomes for family caregivers of frail elders. The selected outcomes are knowledge of caregiving, hardiness, quality of life, physical health, depressive symptoms, burden, and coping.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>18 years of age and older family member participating in care of a frail elder (60 years and older) unable to speak or read English (materials are written in English)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>family caregivers</keyword>
	<keyword>caregiver education</keyword>
	<keyword>caregiver burden</keyword>
	<keyword>caregiver hardiness</keyword>
	<keyword>caregiver depressive symptoms</keyword>
</DOC>