<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01410890</DOC>
	<brief_summary>- The primary objective of this study is to characterize the pharmacokinetics of alglucosidase alfa manufactured at the 4000 L scale in patients who have a confirmed diagnosis of Pompe disease. - A secondary objective of this study is to evaluate and explore the relationship between anti-rhGAA antibody titers and the pharmacokinetics of alglucosidase alfa.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetics of Alglucosidase Alfa in Patients With Pompe Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The total study duration per patient will be 4 to 9 weeks that consist of a screening period (from 2 days to 4 weeks), treatment visit (1 day), and a follow up call (≥30 days).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glycogen Storage Disease Type II</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glycogen Storage Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A patient must meet all of the following criteria to be eligible for this study: The patient and/or the patient's parent/legal guardian is willing and able to provide signed informed consent. The patient has a confirmed GAA enzyme deficiency from skin, blood, or muscle tissue and/or 2 confirmed GAA gene mutations. Infant and toddler Pompe disease patients can be included in the study only under condition (minimal body weight) that the trialrelated blood loss (including any losses in the maneuver) will not exceed 3 percent of the total blood volume during a period of 4 weeks and will not exceed 1 percent at any single time. The patient, if female and of childbearing potential, must have a negative pregnancy test (urine betahuman chorionic gonadotropin) at screening. Note: All female patients of childbearing potential and sexually mature males must agree to use a medically accepted method of contraception throughout the study. For patients previously treated with alglucosidase alfa the patient has received alglucosidase alfa for at least 6 months. A patient who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from this study: The patient is participating in another clinical study using an investigational product. The patient, in the opinion of the Investigator, is unable to adhere to the requirements of the study. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>