<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00265863</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Hyperthermia therapy kills tumor cells by heating them to several degrees above normal body temperature. Peritoneal infusion of heated chemotherapy drugs, such as mitomycin, may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well mitomycin works when given as a hyperthermic peritoneal perfusion in treating patients with malignant ascites.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mitomycin as a Hyperthermic Peritoneal Perfusion in Treating Patients With Malignant Ascites</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the effectiveness of laparoscopic hyperthermic perfusion of mitomycin C in preventing relapse at 4 weeks post-treatment in patients with malignant ascites. Secondary - Determine any improvement in the quality of life of patients treated with this procedure. OUTLINE: This is a nonrandomized study. Patients undergo laparoscopic surgery to remove ascitic fluid and any intraabdominal adhesions and to place 2 inflow and 2 outflow catheters. Mitomycin C is infused into the abdominal cavity by hyperthermic perfusion over 60 minutes. Quality of life is assessed at study entry and at 4 weeks. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed periodically for 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ascites</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitomycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitomycins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of peritoneal metastases and malignant ascites by physical examination, ultrasound, or CT scan Not eligible for cytoreductive surgery based on any of the following criteria: Metastases outside peritoneal cavity Poor performance status Unresectable peritoneal disease Must have undergone at least 1 prior paracentesis procedure No ascites caused by any of the following conditions: Cardiac failure Nephrotic syndrome Pancreatic ascites Chylous ascites Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 03 WBC ≥ 3,000/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 70,000/mm^3 Bilirubin ≤ 2.0 mg/dL Creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Prior peritoneal chemotherapy Dense intraabdominal adhesions limiting laparoscopy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>malignant ascites</keyword>
</DOC>