<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00767832</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to assess the coagulation changes that occur in patients undergoing elective Cesarean delivery using thromboelastography (TEG). We will compare coagulation data to assess potential coagulation changes associated with hemoglobin changes before and after surgery, and related to estimated blood loss.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Thromboelastography to Assess Hemostatic Changes in Patients Undergoing Elective Cesarean Delivery.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of the study is to assess the coagulation changes that occur in patients undergoing elective Cesarean delivery using thromboelastography (TEG). TEG is a point-of-care device which measures the viscoelastic properties of clot formation. This device can provide rapid and detailed information about coagulation changes in the perioperative period. We will compare coagulation data collected from the study to assess potential coagulation changes associated with Hemoglobin changes before and after surgery, and related to estimated blood loss.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemostatics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All obstetric patients with singleton pregnancies admitted to the labor and delivery unit at Lucile Packard Hospital who undergo elective Cesarean delivery. We will select 100 healthy ASA 1 patients with singleton pregnancies who are scheduled for uncomplicated elective Cesarean delivery, with no anticipated risk of obstetric hemorrhage. Patients with underlying coagulation disorders. Patients with thrombocytopenia. Patients with pregnancyinduced hypertension, preeclampsia. Patients requiring the following medications prior to surgery: NSAIDS, aspirin, anticoagulants. Patients requiring nonelective Cesarean delivery. Patients with significant obstetric or medical disease. No patients &lt;18 years of age will be recruited.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2009</verification_date>
</DOC>