<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00767182</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Pregnancy complications called PVP are mainly responsible for perinatal mortality. In these cases, the placenta is smaller and often the centre of thrombotic lesions. The estimation of the placenta volume by 3D ultrasound coupled with growth factors and D-Dimers measures could improve the understanding of these pathologies to optimize their detection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Estimation of the Placental Volume by 3D Ultrasound at 12, 16 and 22 Weeks : Relation With Growth Factors and D-Dimers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Pregnancy complications called Placental Vascular Pathologies (PVP) are mainly responsible for perinatal mortality. In these cases, the placenta is smaller and often the centre of thrombotic lesions. The estimation of the placenta volume by 3D ultrasound coupled with growth factors and D-Dimers measures could improve the understanding of these pathologies to optimize their detection. Thus, the identification of predictive factors of the risk of occurrence or recurrence of PVP could allow us to propose a monitoring of patients at risk, to anticipate corticoids administration for the foetuses pulmonary maturation and perhaps later to adapt anti hypertensive and antithrombotic therapeutics.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Congenital Abnormalities</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Malformations</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibrin fragment D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitogens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>previous history of one or more PVC episodes : preeclampsia, HELLPs, retroplacental hematoma, vascular IUGR&lt;10th percentile, recurrence miscarriage &gt;2, unexplained IUFD or IUFD after abruption placentae, eclampsia. coming for a 12 weeks ultrasound Multiple pregnancy past history of in utero fetal death due to congenital malformations, rhesus incompatibility or an infection previous history of IUGR which etiology was a chromosomal, genic or infectious anomaly</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>preeclampsia</keyword>
	<keyword>eclampsia</keyword>
	<keyword>retroplacental hematoma</keyword>
	<keyword>vascular IUGR</keyword>
	<keyword>IUFD</keyword>
	<keyword>placental volume</keyword>
</DOC>