<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00720382</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if one allergy treatment (0.15% azelastine hydrochloride) is as safe as mometasone furoate (nasonex) alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety and Tolerability of a Nasal Spray to Treat Perennial Allergic Rhinitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic, Perennial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mometasone Furoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Azelastine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female patients 12 years and older with a compatible history greater than or equal to 1 year of rhinitis due to perennial allergies. Must be willing and able to provide informed consent and to participate in all study procedures Must be in generally good health Positive skin test to a prevalent perennial allergen On nasal examination, the presence of nasal mucosal erosion, nasal ulceration or nasal septal perforation Use of any investigational drug within 30 days of the first visit Any nasal surgery or sinus surgery within the previous year Presence of any hypersensitivity to drugs similar to azelastine or mometasone furoate and to either sorbital or sucralose Women who are pregnant or nursing Women who are not using an acceptable method of birth control Nasal Diseases likely to affect deposition of intranasal medication, such as sinusitis, rhinitis medicamentosa or clinically significant nasal polyposis or nasal structural abnormalities. Asthma or other lung diseases such as COPD. Mild asthma symptoms may be considered after consultation with investigator. Patients with Arrythmia Patients with know history of alcohol and drug abuse Existence of any surgical or medical condition, which in the opinion of the investigator or sponsor, might significantly alter the evaluation of the study. Use of medications that could affect the study results</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>