<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00720330</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators are conducting this study to find out if intravenous (injected through the vein) infusion of lidocaine and ketamine administered with general anesthesia is as effective as a paravertebral block in lessening pain after surgery and that both of these techniques are superior to general anesthesia alone in reducing pain immediately after surgery and in the long-term.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lidocaine and Ketamine Versus Standard Care on Acute and Chronic Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants will be randomized into one of three study groups; Group 1 - Paravertebral Group - ropivacaine is injected near the spine before surgery. Midazolam and fentanyl are administered intravenously for sedation. Group 2 - Lidocaine/Ketamine - General anesthesia with lidocaine and ketamine administered intravenously throughout your surgery and for 60 minutes after surgery. Group 3 - General Anesthesia Alone. General anesthesia with placebo administered intravenously throughout surgery and for 60 minutes after surgery. All participants will rate their pain on a scale from 0 to 10 after surgery and on days 1 and 2 after surgery. Participants are called 3 and 6 months after surgery for pain and quality of life assessments</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Midazolam</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age greater than 18 and less than 75 years Unilateral inguinal hernia scheduled for elective open repair Incarcerated hernia or urgent procedure Reoperation (recurrent hernia) Contraindication to regional anesthesia such as: Coagulopathy Infection at the site of needle insertion Preexisting chronic pain (at any site) requiring treatment Contraindication to any study medication (local anesthetic or ketamine) History of significant Axis I psychiatric disease (major depressive disorder,bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, etc.) Significant hepatic (ALT or AST &gt; 2 times normal) or renal (serum creatinine &gt; 2 mg/dl) impairment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Inguinal Herniorrhaphy</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>Outcomes</keyword>
</DOC>