<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02769949</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: Some patients with unusual genetic conditions are referred to the National Institutes of Health (NIH). They may not be eligible to join current research studies. Testing such patients is a good way to improve the skills of research staff. The findings could lead to new processes and research. Objectives: To recruit a diverse group of pediatric subjects with genetic disorders. To give clinic staff hands-on experience working with these patients. Eligibility: Children any age with a known or suspected genetic disorder. Design: Participants will be screened with medical history and physical exam. They may have lab and other tests. Family members may give DNA samples. Participants will have: Medical history Physical exam Height, weight, and other measurements taken. A clinical evaluation of their disorder. They may have: Blood, urine, and saliva samples taken Imaging tests. These may include x-rays, scans, ultrasound, or skeletal survey. A sleep study A visit with other specialists at NIH A genetic test from a commercial lab Medical photographs taken Other tests Participants may have follow-up visits. They may get medical or surgical treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pediatric Patients With Metabolic or Other Genetic Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of this protocol is to allow genetic-related evaluations for patients with a variety of known or suspected genetic disorders, supplement and offer an additional opportunity for training in clinical genetics, dysmorphology and metabolic genetics in the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD) and other Institutes of the National Institutes of Health (NIH). If not eligible for a specific NICHD research protocol, patients with genetic-related conditions may be evaluated under the auspices of this protocol to advance the clinical skills of physicians participating in NICHD clinical research and training programs, and to provide stimuli for new clinical research initiatives. Standard medically-indicated laboratory or radiological studies may be performed to confirm a diagnosis or to aid in the management of the patient. In some cases, the child participant may receive medical or surgical treatment for their disorder at the NIH CC according to current clinical practice. The overall purpose of genetic evaluations under this protocol is to support our clinical training and research missions. Family members of children evaluated on this protocol (who have informative meiotic inheritance relationships to the proband or index case) may be enrolled in the genetic/DNA testing part of the protocol.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fragile X Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Genetic Diseases, Inborn</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Asperger Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Participants with known or suspected genetic disorder ages 0 to any years are eligible for this protocol. Protocol investigators will make the actual selection of patients most appropriate for clinical training. Existence of a referring community health care provider who would be able to manage medical care outside of NIH. Relatives may be enrolled if clinically indicated for the diagnosis of a proband. EXCLUSION CRITERIA: There are no formal exclusion criteria. Any medical, psychiatric, or social conditions, which, in the opinion of the investigators, would make participation in this protocol not in the best interest of the patient. Patients who are critically ill, unstable, or with severe organ failure that may effect/limit the evaluation and place unsustainable demands on Clinical Center or NICHD resources will be excluded. Subjects with disabilities are not formally excluded from the study unless the disability would specifically prevent their participation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 23, 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Genetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic</keyword>
	<keyword>Dysmorphic Syndromes</keyword>
	<keyword>Developmental Delay</keyword>
	<keyword>Genetic Counseling</keyword>
</DOC>