<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00806286</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study has a safety and a Phase 2 portion. In the safety portion of the study, subjects with metastatic non-small cell lung cancer will be treated with study drug (CS-7017) in combination with carboplatin and paclitaxel to evaluate safety. In the Phase 2 portion of the study, subjects will receive study drug (CS-7017) or placebo in combination with carboplatin and paclitaxel to evaluate effectiveness and safety. The study will find out if adding CS-7017 to carboplatin and paclitaxel will be safe and improve progression free survival in subjects with metastatic non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Carboplatin/Paclitaxel With or Without Investigational Drug (CS-7017) in Subjects With Metastatic Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Efatutazone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed metastatic (stage IV) NSCLC with no significant pleural effusion or pleural involvement from the tumor Age greater than or equal to 18 years Adequate organ and bone marrow function Any prior systemic therapy for NSCLC Major surgical procedure or other investigational agents within 4 weeks before study enrollment Need for concomitant use of other thiazolidinediones during the study History of any of the following conditions within 6 months prior to initiating study treatment: Diabetes mellitus requiring treatment with insulin or sulfonylureas or TZDs agents; Myocardia infarction with significant impairment of cardia function; Malabsorption syndrome, chronic diarrhea, inflammatory bowel disease or partial bowel obstruction; Clinically active brain metastases, uncontrolled seizure disorder; spinal cord compression or carcinomatous meningitis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>