<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00806260</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine how VI-0521 affect speed and reaction time on specific tasks that require eye and hand coordination, compared to placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate How VI-0521 Affect Psychomotor Performance in Healthy Overweight and Obese Subjects.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written consents; Adequate contraception from screening through 28 days after the last dose of study drug for female subjects; Healthy obese or overweight subjects with BMI between 27 and 35. History of glaucoma or any past or present use of medications to treat increased intraocular pressure; Current use of any tobacco products, including cigarettes, cigars, pipes, or chewing tobacco, or use within the three months prior to screening; History of drug abuse during the three years prior to screening; History of alcohol abuse, or excessive alcohol consumption, or describes themselves as nonusers of alcohol; Current depression of moderate or greater severity, or any presence or history of suicidal behavior or active suicidal ideation More than one lifetime episode of major depression; Currently working night shifts at a job; On average consumes greater than two cups of coffee or xanthinecontaining beverages per day (&gt;200 mg/day) within the two weeks prior to screening; Any use of dietary, herbal, and/or fitness/bodybuilding supplements (with the exception of vitamins) within one month prior to screening; Aspartate aminotransferase or alanine aminotransferase &gt;2.5 x ULN; Serum creatinine ≥1.5 mg/dL for men or ≥1.4 mg/dL for women.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Overweight</keyword>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>coordination</keyword>
	<keyword>psychomotor</keyword>
</DOC>