<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03098303</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to determine the variables associated with patient acceptation or refusal to participate in a clinical research protocol when seen in during a pneumology consultation (excluding oncology and tobaccology).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Criteria Associated With Patient Willingness to Participate in Biomedical Research</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The secondary objectives of this study are: - To compare patient acceptance rates for participation in a clinical research protocol before and after January 15, 2016. - To determine the variables associated with accepting or refusing to participate in a clinical research protocol for patients seen during a pneumology consultation (excluding oncology and tobaccology) before January 15, 2016. - To determine the variables associated with accepting or refusing to participate in a clinical research protocol for patients seen during a pneumology consultation (excluding oncology and tobaccology) after January 15, 2016. - To describe the patient population seen during pneumology consultations. - To determine the variables associated with accepting or refusing to participate in a clinical research protocol sponsored by a pharmaceutical laboratory. - To determine the variables associated with accepting or refusing to participate in a clinical research protocol sponsored by an academic institution. - Construct clusters (homogeneous groups) of patients seen during the pneumology consultations.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>The patient was informed about the study. The patient is scheduled for a consult in the pneumology department The patient is under judicial protection or is an adult under any kind of guardianship The patient expresses opposition to the study It is impossible to correctly inform the patient about the study The patient cannot fluently read French The patient is pregnant The patient is breastfeeding The patient has cancer The patient is consulting in tabaccology</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>