<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01202565</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There is clearly a need for further data on the efficacy of biologic agents in the treatment of nail and scalp psoriasis, especially in the routine clinical setting. A few case reports can be found, but no published data exists from non-interventional studies, such as post-marketing observational studies (PMOS) that reflect routine clinical practice. The aim of this PMOS is to evaluate the long-term (12-month) efficacy of adalimumab in the treatment of nail and scalp psoriatic lesions in routine dermatologic practice.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Adalimumab (HUMIRA®) in the Treatment of Scalp and Nail Affection in Patients With Moderate to Severe Plaque Psoriasis in Routine Clinical Practice</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is post-marketing observational study (PMOS) in which HUMIRA® is prescribed in the usual manner in accordance with the terms of the local marketing authorization with regards to dose, population and indication, and following the local prescription and/or reimbursement guidance. Follow-up visits are not strictly scheduled, but rather left to the judgment of each investigator within the 12-month study period for each participant. Five visits are indicated within the 12-month observational period: Baseline and follow-up at 3 months, 6 months, 9 months and at 12 months (Study End). As nails are not included in the general measures of disease severity (such as Psoriasis Area and Severity Index [PASI]), the Nail Psoriasis Severity Index (NAPSI) will be used to assign a score of nail psoriasis. The scalp, though being involved in the general measures of disease severity (e.g. PASI), represents only 4-5% of the body surface and is therefore poorly represented. Psoriasis Scalp Severity Index (PSSI) will be used to quantify the intensity of scalp psoriasis and its changes during the study. The association between general skin and localized nail and scalp, and changes in quality of life in response to adalimumab therapy will also be examined.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients will be enrolled in this PMOS if they fulfill all of the below criteria: 1. Patients with moderate to severe plaque psoriasis eligible for Humira therapy according to the local product label and prescription/reimbursement guidelines 2. Have significant psoriatic nail affection (total Nail Psoriasis Severity Index NAPSI score of hands and feet ≥ 10) and/or significant psoriatic scalp affection (Psoriasis Scalp Severity Index PSSI score ≥ 10) 3. Adult (≥18 years of age) 4. Have negative result of tuberculosis (TB) screening test or TB prophylaxis as per local guidelines 5. Willing to provide informed consent if requested by the local law regulations Patients fulfilling any of the below exclusion criteria will not be eligible for this PMOS: 1. Meet contraindications as outlined in the latest version of the local Summary of Product Characteristics (SmPC) 2. Participate in another clinical/observational study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Post-marketing observational study (PMOS) Protocol</keyword>
	<keyword>Moderate to Severe Plaque Psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment of Scalp and Nail Affection</keyword>
	<keyword>Effectiveness of Adalimumab (HUMIRA®)</keyword>
</DOC>