<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01202591</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety and effectiveness of AZD4547 in combination with fulvestrant vs. fulvestrant alone in ER+ breast cancer patients with FGFR1 polysomy (FISH4/5) or gene amplification (FISH 6)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of AZD4547 in Combination With Fulvestrant vs. Fulvestrant Alone in ER+ Breast Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fulvestrant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Exemestane</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Postmenopausal women (either through bilateral oophorectomy or amenorrhoeic for 24 months) Histological confirmation of Breast Cancer with documented ER+ receptor status Safety runin: Relapsing during/within 12 months of completion of a single regimen of adjuvant endocrine therapy with nonsteroidal AI and/ tamoxifen or progression following 1st line endocrine therapy with nonsteroidal AL Rand phase IIa: Received at least 1 prior endocrine therapy in the metastatic setting or have relapsed during/ within 6 months of completion of adjuvant endocrine therapy (either nonsteroidal AI or tamoxifen or a combination of both). Chemotherapy administered in the adjuvant setting is permitted. Rand phase IIa: Mandatory provision of tumour sample to confirm FGFR1 polysomy or gene amplification. At least one measurable lesion that can be accurately assessed by CT/MRI/xray at baseline and follow up visits Prior exposure to exemestane (safety runin) / fulvestrant (randomized phase IIa), or any agent known to inhibit FGFRs. More than 1 prior regimen of chemotherapy for breast cancer ECG recordings that demonstrate significant abnormalities in cardiac rate, rhythm or conduction History of hypersensitivity to active or inactive excipients of AZD4547 or exemestane (safety runin ) or fulvestrant (Randomized phase), including castor oil, or drugs with a similar chemical structure or class to AZD4547 or exemestane or fulvestrant. Randomized phase IIa: bleeding/blood clotting conditions that would prevent the administration of the fulvestrant injection into the buttocks</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>ER+</keyword>
	<keyword>FGFR1</keyword>
	<keyword>Exemestane</keyword>
	<keyword>AZD4547</keyword>
	<keyword>Fulvestrant</keyword>
</DOC>