<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01202552</DOC>
	<brief_summary>One-site dose sparing intradermal influenza vaccination in elderly had been studied but resulted in unsatisfactory outcomes. The investigators evaluate the safety and immunogenicity of the two-site intradermal injection of influenza vaccine containing all 6 and 12 micrograms of hemagglutinin antigen per strain (with 4/10th and 8/10th of a regular 15 microgram HA/strain intramuscular vaccine respectively) in elderly over 60 years of age. An influenza vaccine administered intramuscularly at the standard dose is used as the reference vaccine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Two-site Intradermal Influenza Vaccination in Elderly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The subjects would be randomly divided into three groups of 60 subjects each. Group1 receives a single intramuscular dose of 0.5 ml of trivalent influenza vaccine, containing at least 15 microgram of hemagglutinin antigen per strain, Group II receives two-site intradermal dose of 0.1 ml each, containing at least 3 microgram of hemagglutinin antigen per strain per site and group III receives two-site intradermal dose of 0.2 ml each, containing at least 6 microgram of hemagglutinin antigen per strain per site. Check for HA Antibody</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemagglutinins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>healthy male or female volunteer aged at least 60 years old willing to participate in this study previous influenza vaccination within 6 months systemic ypersensitivity to egg or chicken proteins or any of the vaccine components history of a lifethreatening reaction to the study vaccine or a vaccine containing the same constituents. ongoing acute febrile illness (oral temperature, ≥37.5 c ) congenital or acquired immunodeficiency treatment with immunosuppressive or other immune modifying drugs or cancer therapy within previous 6 months longterm treatment with systemic corticosteroids receipt of blood or bloodderived products in the previous 3 months history of thrombocytopenia or a bleeding disorder contraindicating for intramuscular vaccination.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>influenza</keyword>
	<keyword>aged</keyword>
	<keyword>intradermal injection</keyword>
</DOC>