<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01202786</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is in cancer of unknown primary (CUP) patients, to compare the cost-effectiveness of miRview™ mets test with conventional work-up in identifying the primary tumor site.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cost-effectiveness Study of miRview™ Mets in Patients With Cancer of Unknown Primary (CUP)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Thousands of patients are diagnosed each year with metastatic cancer; however, about 3-5% of them are diagnosed with Cancer of Unknown Primary (CUP). In order to identify the optimal treatment plan for individual patients with CUP, the primary tumor site must be identified. Patients undergo a wide range of costly, time-consuming, and inefficient tests to identify the primary site of origin, often to no avail. In this era of targeted therapies, the accurate diagnosis of the primary tumor can be crucial. miRview™ mets is a new molecular diagnostic tool that identifies the tissue-of-origin of metastatic tumors, with 90% sensitivity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Unknown Primary</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients who present with histologicallyconfirmed metastatic cancer in whom an initial workup which consists of detailed medical history, physical examination, basic laboratory studies, histopathological review of biopsy material, and CT scan of the chest abdomen and pelvis fail to identify the primary site. 2. Older than 18 years 3. Performance status &lt;2 4. life expectancy &gt;3 months 5. ANC &gt;1500 6. Platelets &gt;100,000 if bone marrow is not involved 7. Hb &gt; 9 8. Creatinine &lt;2 9. LFTS &lt; x5 normal 10. Histology proven of malignancy 11. Enough material for miRview test (10 slices of 10 micrometer sections) 12. Member of Clalit HMO 1. Patients unable or unwilling to sign the informed consent form 2. Under 18 years old 3. Performance status &gt;2 4. life expectancy&lt;3 months 5. ANC &lt;1500 6. Platelets &lt;100,000 if marrow not involved 7. Hb &lt; 9 8. Creatinine &gt;2 9. LFTS &gt; x5 normal 10. Not member of Clalit HMO</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cancer of Unknown Primary Site (CUP)</keyword>
</DOC>