<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01733134</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients being hospitalized for acute heart failure and already receiving standard therapy will be randomized to receive either tolvaptan or placebo, based on the level of copeptin measured in their bloodstream. Patients with high copeptin levels will be able to participate in the trial, patients with low levels will be excluded. Patients being admitted to the observation unit for acute heart failure and already receiving standard therapy will be randomized to receive either tolvaptan or placebo without consideration of the copeptin level. The hypothesis is that patients receiving tolvaptan will have better improvement of shortness of breath than those receiving placebo, within 9 hours of drug administration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acute Heart Failure Patients With High Copeptin Treated With Tolvaptan Targets Increased AVP Activation for Treatment (ACTIVATE)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tolvaptan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Older than or equal to 18 years of age, with diagnosis and planned treatment for Acute Heart Failure 2. Dyspnea at rest or minimal exertion per the patient 3. Evidence of extracellular volume expansion by at least one of the following: JVD, Rales, Ascites, Edema or positive Chest Xray defined as cardiomegaly, pulmonary vascular congestion, Kerley Blines, pulmonary edema and/or pleural effusion. 4. Elevated BNP level &gt;200 pg/ml, or NTproBNP &gt; 1000pg/mL 5. Able to administer study drug within 8 hours from triage time Inpatient Hospitalized Inclusion Only: Copeptin level &gt; 27 pmol/L 1. Unable to provide informed consent 2. Unable to have 30 day telephone follow up 3. Not expected to survive past 6 months 4. On Renal replacement therapy or creatinine &gt;3.5 5. History of allergy or intolerance to Tolvaptan 6. Suspected Pregnancy 7. Cardiogenic Shock 8. Participation in any interventional trial in prior 30 days. 9. Receiving or planned to receive IV Inotropic therapy 10. ACS now or in the past 30 days 11. Treatment with IV infusion vasoactive drugs in the hour prior to enrollment 12. Temperature &gt; 100.5 13. Heart Failure due to atrial fibrillation with Rapid Ventricular Response 14. SBP &lt; 90 mmHg</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>acute heart failure</keyword>
	<keyword>emergency department</keyword>
	<keyword>copeptin</keyword>
	<keyword>adh antagonists</keyword>
</DOC>