<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01733303</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Osteoporosis is a prevalent health concern among older adults and is associated with an increased risk of falls that can cause fracture, injury or mortality. Identifying the factors related to falls occurring within this population is essential for the development of effective regimes for fall prevention. Studies have shown that muscle quality and good posture alignments are critical for balance control in older adults. People are diagnosed with osteoporosis often combining with muscles weakness, and increased spine kyphosis leading vertebral, fractures and poor balance control, even falls. Therefore, improving muscle quality, strengthening weak muscles and correcting postural alignment are essential elements for fracture and fall prevention in older adults with osteoporosis. The long-term objectives of this work are to prevent fracture and fall in older adults with osteoporosis by improving the function of degenerative muscles using exercise training.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fracture and Fall Prevention in Elderly With Osteoporosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The inclusion criteria for osteopenia or osteoporosis group: 1. able to stand and walk for 5 minutes independently; 2. having normal or corrected to normal vision; 3. having age between &gt; 50 years 4. with osteopenia (2.5 &lt; tscore &lt; 1.0) or osteoporosis (tscore &lt;2.5). The exclusion criteria for osteopenia or osteoporosis group: 1. being pregnant; 2. sensorymotor deficits; 3. inability of communication 4. lack of access to a telephone. The inclusion criteria for control agematched group: 1. able to stand and walk for 5 minutes independently; 2. having normal or corrected to normal vision; 3. having age between &gt; 50 years 4. without osteopenia or osteoporosis (tscore &gt; 1.0). The exclusion criteria for control agematched group: 1. being pregnant; 2. sensorymotor deficits; 3. inability of communication 4. lack of access to a telephone.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>