<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01733121</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of NBI-98854 (titrated to a subject's optimal dose in the range of 25 to 75 mg) administered once daily for the treatment of Tardive Dyskinesia (TD) symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>NBI-98854 Dose Titration Study for the Treatment of Tardive Dyskinesia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 2, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-titration study to evaluate the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of NBI-98854 (titrated to subject's optimal dose in the range of 25 to 75 mg) compared to placebo, administered once daily (q.d.) for a total of 6 weeks of treatment. Approximately 90 medically stable male and female subjects with one of the following clinical diagnoses will be enrolled: schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder with neuroleptic-induced TD; mood disorder with neuroleptic-induced TD; or gastrointestinal disorder with metoclopramide-induced TD. For subjects randomized to active treatment, the starting dose will be 25 mg NBI 98854, which may be escalated in increments of 25 mg every 2 weeks to a maximum of 75 mg to achieve an optimal dose of NBI-98854 for each subject</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dyskinesias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Movement Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have one of the following clinical diagnoses for at least 3 months prior to screening a) schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder; b) mood disorder; or c) gastrointestinal disorder (e.g., gastroparesis, gastroesophageal reflux disease) Have a clinical diagnosis of neurolepticinduced tardive dyskinesia for at least 3 months prior to screening. Be receiving a stable dose of antipsychotic medication for a minimum of 30 days before study start. Subjects who are not using antipsychotic medication must have stable psychiatric status. Have the doses of concurrent medications and the conditions being treated be stable for a minimum of 30 days before study start and be expected to remain stable during the study. Subjects of childbearing potential must agree to use hormonal or two forms of nonhormonal birth control during the study. Female subjects must not be pregnant. Be in good general health and expected to complete the clinical study as designed. Have a body mass index (BMI) of 18 to 38 kg/m2 (both inclusive). Have a negative urine drug screen (negative for amphetamines, barbiturates, benzodiazepine, phencyclidine, cocaine, opiates, or cannabinoids) at screening and study start, except for any subject receiving a stable dose of benzodiazepine. Have a negative alcohol breath test at screening and study start. Have an active clinically significant unstable medical condition within 1 month (30 days) prior to screening. Have a history of substance dependence or substance (drug) or alcohol abuse within the 3 months before study start(nicotine and caffeine dependence are not exclusionary). Have a known history of neuroleptic malignant syndrome. Have a significant risk of suicidal or violent behavior. Receiving any excluded concomitant medication such as reserpine, metoclopramide, stimulants, or tetrabenazine. Receiving medication for the treatment of tardive dyskinesia. Have a positive human immunodeficiency virus antibody, (HIVAb), hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), or hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody result at screening or have a history of positive result. Have received an investigational drug within 30 days before screening or plan to use an investigational drug (other than NBI98854) during the study. Have an allergy, hypersensitivity, or intolerance to tetrabenazine. Have had previous exposure with NBI98854.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>