<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03010839</DOC>
	<brief_summary>During cardiac surgery with cardiopulmonary bypass , injury occurs to the heart muscle.The myocardial injury is a serious complication ,which increases both mortality and morbidity of cardiac surgery .Remote ischemic preconditioning(RIPC) with transient upper limb ischemia/reperfusion is a novel, simple, cost-free,non-pharmacological and non-invasive strategy.Recent some trials suggested that RIPC could provide myocardial protection by reducing serum cardiac biomarkers,however,whether the RIPC can improve the clinical outcomes in patients undergoing on-pump cardiac surgery,is still uncertain. The study hypothesis is: remote ischemic preconditioning will provide myocardial protection and improve clinical outcomes in patients undergoing cardic surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Remote Ischemic Preconditioning for Cardic Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Remote ischemic preconditioning (RIPC) protocol will be induced twice daily for one day before cardiac surgery and once before induction of anesthesia by 3 cycles of 5-min upper limb ischemia and 5-min reperfusion using a blood-pressure cuff inflated to a pressure 200mmHg</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients undergoing heart surgery on cardiopulmonary bypass 2. Patients aged 18 years to 80 years 1. Inability to give informed consent 2. Cardiogenic shock 3. Cardiac arrest on current admission 4. Left ventricular ejection fraction less than 30% 5. Current atrial fibrillation 6. Preoperative use of inotropics or mechanical assist device 7. Patients with significant hepatic dysfunction (Prothrombin&gt;2.0 ratio) 8. Patients with known renal failure with a GFR&lt;30 mL/min/1.73 m2 9. Patients with significant pulmonary disease (FEV1&lt;40% predicted) 10. Recent myocardial infarction (within 7 days) 11. Recent systemic infection or sepsis (within 7 days) 12. Severe stroke (within 2 months) 13. Significant peripheral arterial disease affecting the upper limbs 14. Previous serious psychiatric disorders (e.g. schizophrenia, dementia) 15. Surgeries: cardiac transplantation, concomitant carotid endarterectomy , previous heart surgery,offpump surgery, emergency surgery</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>