<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01311674</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to vaccinate plasmapheresis donors for collection of high titer plasma to be used in the manufacture of Hepatitis B Immune Globulin (HBIG).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hepatitis B Virus (HBV) Antibody (Anti-HBs) Booster Program for the Production of Hepatitis B Immune Globulin (HBIG)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>gamma-Globulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rho(D) Immune Globulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 2055 years Naive or previously hepatitis Bvaccinated males or females Normal and healthy as determined by medical history, physical exam, vital signs and clinical laboratory tests Subject must meet all required/recommended subject suitability criteria that pertain to normal source plasma donors with the following exceptions. Subjects who previously tested positive for HBsAg may be accepted into the antiHBs program provided they now test negative and meet all other normal donor suitability criteria. Written informed consent. Subjects who have received a hepatitis vaccination in the previous six months. History of hypersensitivity to yeast or any component of the EngerixB® vaccine. History of hypersensitivity to any hepatitis Bcontaining vaccine. Use of any investigational product within the past 30 days or during the course of the study. Use of steroids or immunosuppressives during the study period. Subjects who have received immunosuppressive therapy (including systemic steroids) within 30 days before study entry Subjects who have received cytotoxic therapy (in the previous 5 years prior to study entry) Received parenteral immune globulin products or blood products within 3 months before study entry with the following exceptions (as specified by plasma center procedures): Rho (D) immune globulin (e.g. RhoGAM or WinRho) within 6 weeks before study entry; Pertussis immune globulin: no exclusion Past, present, or suspected IV drug use Positive HIV, HBV* or HCV test result (*except as described above in the Inclusion Criteria section) Subjects with autoimmune disease (such as, but not limited to demyelinating disease) Subjects with cancer, heart disease (including hospitalization for myocardial infarction, arrhythmia, syncope, congestive heart failure), uncontrolled hypertension, uncontrolled insulindependent diabetes mellitus, seizures, kidney disease Severely or morbidly obese, or higher obesity classification, which corresponds to BMI of 35 or higher Pregnancy or lactation (females must have a negative pregnancy test prior to each vaccination).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>