<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01311206</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of the proposed research is to assess the efficacy of an eight-week, efficient and tolerable, low-intensity resistance-training program with concurrent application of partial blood flow restriction (PBFR) for improving quadriceps strength and volume in women with risk factors for incident symptomatic or progressive knee OA. This specific aim will be achieved through a randomized, controlled trial, comparing low intensity training with and without PBFR. There have been numerous reports of exercise interventions in people with knee osteoarthritis. However, this research is novel in that it will be the first to use a low intensity regimen that will minimize forces on the knee while still having the potential to lead to clinically meaningful strength gains in older adults with risk factors for incident symptomatic or progressive knee OA.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Low Intensity Resistance Training With Partial Blood Flow Restriction for Quadriceps Strengthening</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female Age 4560 BMI less than 37 and greater than or equal to 25 kg/m2, or a history of a knee joint injury or surgery, or knee symptoms (pain, aching, or stiffness) on most of the last 30 days, or knee osteoarthritis Resistance training at any time in the last 3 months prior to study 5° malalignment of a knee Bilateral knee replacement Lower limb amputation Lower limb surgery in the last 6 months that affects walking ability or ability to exercise Back, hip or knee problems that affect walking ability or ability to exercise Unable to walk without a cane or walker Unable to ascend at least 2 stairs (to enter our building) Inflammatory joint or muscle disease such as rheumatoid or psoriatic arthritis or polymyalgia rheumatica Multiple sclerosis Known neuropathy Selfreport of Diabetes Currently being treated for cancer or having untreated cancer Terminal illness (cannot be cured or adequately treated and there is a reasonable expectation of death in the near future) Peripheral Vascular Disease History of myocardial infarction or stroke in the last year Deep Venous Thrombosis Chest pain during exercise or at rest Use of supplemental oxygen Inability to follow protocol (e.g. lack of ability to attend visits or understand instructions) Staff concern for subject health (such as history of dizziness/faintness or current restrictions on activity) Concurrent study participation (such as the MOST study) Planning to be away for more than one week during the study</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>knee osteoarthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>isokinetic knee extensor strength</keyword>
	<keyword>quadriceps volume</keyword>
	<keyword>symptomatic knee osteoarthritis</keyword>
</DOC>