<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01073982</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the effects of tart cherry juice to reduce pain and inflammation among individuals with arthritis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Tart Cherry Juice to Reduce Pain and Inflammation Among Patients With Inflammatory Osteoarthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Numerous antioxidant and anti-inflammatory agents have been identified in tart cherries, and a study among healthy, non-exercising individuals demonstrated that cherry consumption decreased serum inflammatory biomarkers after 14 days. Osteoarthritis (OA) is a common syndrome affecting 65 million Americans characterized by pain, inflammation, and disability. Such natural anti-inflammatory effects of cherry consumption may be beneficial for the management and treatment of osteoarthritis and inflammatory diseases. The purpose of this randomized, double-blind, placebo controlled study is to examine individuals with inflammatory OA and assess the analgesic and anti-inflammatory effects of tart cherry juice as compared to a placebo drink among twenty 30-70 y/o OA subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosed with inflammatory osteoarthritis In good general health Stable pattern of antiinflammatory or pain relieving drug use for 3 months prior to study Ability and willingness to maintain consistent pattern of antiinflammatory or pain relieving drug use during the course of the study, and to not seek any other treatment during the study Ability and willingness to consume juice or placebo drink for 21 consecutive days, and to participate in screening measures, including a blood draw, before and after the intervention period Pregnancy Serious medical conditions such as recent heart attack or stroke, cancer, diabetes (type 1 and type 2), or gastrointestinal ulcers Individuals who have not been on a stable dose of pain medications or pain modalities for at least 3 months, including muscle relaxants, tender point anesthetic injections, systemic or intrabursal or intraarticular steroids, or any investigational drug/device in the prior 90 days Individuals who have used nonpharmacologic pain therapies including acupuncture, ultrasound, or transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation within the past 30 days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>osteoarthritis</keyword>
</DOC>