<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03096587</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Recruited patients with symptomatic irreversible pulpitis are assigned to interventional (XP Endo Finisher file) and control group(ultrasonic activated irrigation) to undergo single visit endodontic treatment and record postoperative pain afterwards.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect Of XP Endo Finisher Versus Ultrasonic Activated Irrigation On Post-operative Pain In Endodontic Treatment of Symptomatic Irreversible Pulpitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigator will recruit patients from the clinic of endodontics in faculty of oral and dental medicine, Cairo university. The patients who are found eligible to the criteria, will be randomly assigned to either the control group (ultrasonic activated irrigation )or to the intervention group( XP Endo-Finisher file). Endodontic treatment will be done in single visit. After the visit, patients will be asked to record post operative pain by NRS (Numerical Rate Scale)in a given sheet.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulpitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Medically free of any systemic disease 2. Male or female 3. Patients with age range 2545 4. Symptomatic irreversible pulpitis in single rooted single canal teeth without apical periodontitis. 5. Teeth with mature root 6. Restorable teeth 7. Teeth without calcified root canals 8. Teeth without root caries 9. Teeth without internal or external root resorption 10. Teeth with no sign of crack formation 11. Teeth without anatomic abnormalities 1. Pregnant females. 2. If analgesics have been administrated during the past two weeks preoperatively. 3. Patients having bruxism or clenching. 4. Multi rooted or multi canaled teeth. 5. Patients with swelling or acute periapical abscess. 6. Previously endodontically treated teeth 7. periodontally affected teeth .</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>XP Endo Finisher</keyword>
	<keyword>ultrasonic activated irrigation</keyword>
	<keyword>postoperative pain</keyword>
</DOC>