<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03096145</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot study is being done to adapt an effective 1 session phone coaching intervention for nonsmoking support persons to a low income population. This study will also pilot new intervention components including text messaging and health incentives. The goal of the intervention is for support persons to prompt their smoker to use quitline services. To see if these methods are effective, smokers in this study will be asked to complete assessments about their quit attempts and smoking status. The study will also evaluate if the smokers use quitline services or not. The preliminary findings will be used to provide data for an R01 NIH grant submission.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Support Person Intervention to Promote a Smoking Helpline Among Under Resourced Smokers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a proposal to conduct a pilot study to adapt an effective 1 session phone coaching intervention for nonsmoking support persons to a low income population. The study will also pilot new intervention components including text messaging and health incentives. The goal of the intervention is for support persons to prompt their smoker to use quitline services. The study will also build on prior work by enrolling smokers for assessments of quit attempts and smoking abstinence. The study uses a non-randomized, single group design. Thirty nonsmoker-smoker dyads will be enrolled in three waves of 10 each. The nonsmokers will receive different intervention components depending on the time of their enrollment. Nonsmokers will complete assessments at baseline and at 1 month follow-up. Smokers will be enrolled for assessments only at baseline and 3 month follow-up. The vendor for the Minnesota state quitline, Alere Wellbeing Inc. (a sole subsidiary of Optum) will track if smokers use quitline services over 3 months of follow-up. The aims of this pilot study are to: (1) Assess the feasibility of enrolling low income, racially diverse nonsmoker-smoker dyads; (2) Adapt and refine the support person intervention components to a low income population with feedback from the nonsmoker participants; and (3) Assess the feasibility of obtaining assessments from the smokers on quit attempts and smoking abstinence outcomes. The preliminary findings will be used to provide data for an R01 NIH grant submission.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Nonsmoker Minnesota resident 18 years of age or older Is a never smoker or former smoker (no cigarette smoking in past 6 months) Has a low income defined as receiving state funded health insurance including medical assistance (e.g., Medicaid) or MinnesotaCare Has access to a working cellular telephone with text messaging capabilities Has a mailing address/P.O. box Have regular contact with a current smoker is at least 18 years of age, resides in MN Provided verbal consent Nonsmoker Their smoker does not provide written informed consent Smoker Study Minnesota resident 18 years of age or older Has a low income defined as receiving state funded health insurance including medical assistance (e.g., Medicaid) or MinnesotaCare Has access to a working phone Has a mailing address/P.O. box Has smoked at least 1 cigarette in the past 30 days (to include both light/intermittent as well as daily/frequent smokers thus enhancing generalizability) Has not participated in a stop smoking program in the past 3 months including receiving pharmacotherapy for smoking cessation Provided written informed consent Smoker Their nonsmoker does not provide verbal consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>tobacco</keyword>
	<keyword>quitlines</keyword>
	<keyword>social support</keyword>
	<keyword>mobile support</keyword>
</DOC>