<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02779517</DOC>
	<brief_summary>By developing an affordable mobile service robot for therapeutic activities in a health center environment, this project addresses the issue of both the high cost and man-power required to provide rehabilitation for stroke survivors and other patients. Our goal is to measure users - clinician and patient - responses to a telepresence robot, VGo, that has been modified with a humanoid torso robot, NAO, to facilitate remote communication between the patient and clinician, and to complete supervisory exercise coaching.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mobile Service Robot for Task-Oriented Stroke Therapy: User Evaluations</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a short demonstration and survey study. Clinical staff and patients will be gathered together and our idea for the mobile service robot will discussed. A demonstration of the telepresence feature of the robots and the NAO robot greeting and helping them with simple exercises will follow (e.g., pick up and object that is handy and lift their hands over their heads). The approximately 30-minute demonstration part of the study will start with an introduction and explanation about the project and a short speech about the Rehabilitation and Robotics Lab. After the demonstration the oral consent will be read and surveys will be handed out to those study participants who agree to complete them; if necessary, the research team will assist the study participant with the survey. Surveys will then be collected, and the group will be thanked by the research team.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Certified rehabilitation healthcare professionals Participants with upper extremity disabilities Participant must be older than 18 years Less than 18 years of age</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>upper extremity</keyword>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>robotics</keyword>
	<keyword>telepresence</keyword>
	<keyword>elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>aged</keyword>
	<keyword>Housing for the elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>retirement</keyword>
	<keyword>homes for the aged</keyword>
</DOC>