<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02067780</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is one of the most common diseases in the world. In a recent study, we showed that administration of levofloxacin is superior to placebo in the treatment of decompensation of COPD; it is accompanied by a substantial reduction in mortality and a significant reduction in the residence time in hospital. In Tunisia, few data are available on the epidemiology of COPD decompensation. The choice of antibiotic to be used in this situation is challenging to the clinician who must choose between traditional antibiotics (cyclins, aminopenicillins, cotrimoxazole...) and new antimicrobial agents. Recently, it has been emphasized the selection of patients for treatment according to the degree of systemic inflammation (C-Reactive Protein). Indeed, there would have a correlation between the tracheobronchial infection and elevated inflammatory markers. As the elevation of these markers is proportional to the intensity of the inflammatory reaction of the body, is based on the kinetics of these biomarkers in antibiotic treatment seems logical. Thus, C-Reactive Protein allowed not only knowing when to start antibiotics, but also through their kinetic, these markers can guide the duration of therapy and shorten the duration of antibiotic therapy: a rate cut would ensure that the antibiotic treatment was adopted. The objectives of this randomized prospective and double blind study are to evaluate the efficacy and safety of a short treatment of 48 with levofloxacin compared with treatment with the same molecule during a time guided by monitoring markers of inflammation in patients admitted to the emergency for exacerbation of COPD and to study the epidemiology of viral and bacterial COPD decompensation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Short Antibiotic Treatment Versus Duration Guided by Markers of Inflammation in the Treatment of AECOPD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a randomized prospective double-blind, accomplished with sealed envelopes ,with three parallel groups : - Group A: Short treatment: 1 tablet Levofloxacin 500mg / day hang two days completed by 1 tablet Placebo Levofloxacin 500mg / day for 5 days. - Group B: Short Treatment control : 1 tablet Levofloxacin 500mg / day for 7 days. - Group C: Titled treatment by inflammation markers (CRP): 1 tablet Levofloxacin 500mg / day for 7 days. - Group D: Titled treatment by inflammation markers (CRP) Control : 1 tablet Levofloxacin 500mg / day hang two days completed by 1 tablet Placebo Levofloxacin 500mg / day for 5 days. We started our study by recruitment COPD patients to collect their blood samples and sputum samples and we made them up for control. These samples will be used for the inflammatory analyses and the study of bacterial and viral serology. The results were seized by the SPSS.18.0 software.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levofloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ofloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibiotics, Antitubercular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients having COPD (according to the definition of the American Thoracic Society) in acute exacerbation Pneumonia Antibiotic treatment in the previous days Pregnancy Immunodeficiency Concomitant infection intubation immediately</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>