<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02302911</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims to investigate the effectiveness of early (before the age of 5 years) and intensive intervention for children with Autism Spectrum Disorders.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Swiss Early Intervention Project in Autism: An Evaluation of Early Intervention Outcome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study aims to investigate the effectiveness of early (before the age of 5 years) and intensive intervention for children with Autism Spectrum Disorders. The type of intervention proposed in Switzerland differs greatly depending on where people live. Several international studies show positive outcomes in children with Autism after receiving early behavioural intervention. However, Disability Insurance (DI) in Switzerland does not fully cover these scientifically proven interventions. Since January 2014 they cover 45 000 CHF per child for only two years of early treatment across five centres chosen by the Federal Social Insurance Office. The remaining costs are covered by the parents, foundations or by the cantons. In addition, families benefit from this early intervention only if their child is enrolled in one of the five selected centres. There are currently various types of support for children with Autism in Switzerland before age five, early intensive behavioural interventions, eclectic early intervention and less intensive interventions with a treatment that is not specific to Autism (about 3 hrs./week), which includes occupational therapy, speech therapy and early curative education. Some children do not receive any treatment. This research aims to evaluate the efficacy of these interventions (early intensive behavioural/ eclectic/treatment as usual) as has been done previously in international studies. The study also aims to include centres other than those selected by the Swiss Federal Social Insurance Office.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: For all groups: parents speak English, German or French diagnosis of Autism or Pervasive Developmental Disorder not otherwise specified 5 years or younger at the start of Intervention parents consent Experimental Group: family was accepted by one of the participating Service Providers Experimental Group: receipt of a second intervention that either interferes with the intensive Intervention or is also intensive (more than 10 hours a week) Comparison Group: receipt of any Intervention that is more than 10 hours a week</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Early intervention</keyword>
</DOC>