<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01831089</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Clinical trial of PM01183 in combination with paclitaxel, with or without bevacizumab, in patients with solid tumors</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase I Study of Lurbinectedin (PM01183) in Combination With Paclitaxel, With or Without Bevacizumab, in Selected Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Clinical trial to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and the recommended dose (RD) of PM01183 in combination with weekly paclitaxel, with or without bevacizumab. Once a recommended dose is defined for the PM01183 and weekly paclitaxel combination, the feasibility of adding bevacizumab to this combination will be explored in a selected cohort of patients to characterize the safety profile and feasibility of this combination, to obtain preliminary information on antitumor activity, to obtain preliminary information on quality of life (QoL), to characterize the pharmacokinetics (PK) of this combination and to detect major drug-drug PK interactions and PK/PD (pharmacokinetic/pharmacodynamic) correlation and to conduct an exploratory pharmacogenomic(PGx) analysis in patients with selected advanced solid tumors.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Voluntarily signed and dated written informed consent Age between 18 and 75 years old (both inclusive) Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) of ≤ 1 Life expectancy ≥ 3 months. Patients with a histologically/cytologically confirmed diagnosis of advanced and/or unresectable disease of any of the following tumors: 1. Breast cancer 2. Epithelial ovarian cancer or gynecological cancer 3. Head and neck squamous cell carcinoma 4. Nonsmall cell lung cancer 5. Small cell lung cancer 6. Platinumrefractory germcell tumors. 7. Adenocarcinoma or carcinoma of unknown primary site Adequate bone marrow, renal, hepatic, and metabolic function Recovery to grade ≤ 1 or to baseline from any AE derived from previous treatment (excluding alopecia of any grade). Premenopausal women must have a negative pregnancy test before study entry and agree to use a medically acceptable method of contraception throughout the treatment period and for at least six weeks after treatment discontinuation Prior treatment with PM01183 or weekly paclitaxel or nanoalbuminpaclitaxel Patients who have previously discontinued paclitaxelbased regimes due to drug related toxicity. Known hypersensitivity to bevacizumab or any component of its formulation Patients who have previously discontinued bevacizumabcontaining regimes due to drugrelated toxicity. More than three prior lines of chemotherapy Less than three months since last taxanecontaining therapy. Washout period: 1. Less than three weeks since the last chemotherapycontaining regimen 2. Less than three weeks since the last radiotherapy dose 3. Less than four weeks since last monoclonal antibodycontaining therapy Concomitant diseases/conditions: Unstable angina, myocardial infarction, valvular heart disease, encephalopathy, ischemic attacks, hemorrhagic or ischemic cerebrovascular accident (CVA) or ongoing pulmonary embolism within last year, arrhythmia, hepatopathy, uncontrolled infection, hemoptysis or oxygen requiring dyspnea, known HIV infection, bleeding risk, muscular problems, peripheral neuropathy, Symptomatic or progressive brain metastases or leptomeningeal disease. Men or premenopausal women who are not using an effective method of contraception as previously described; actively breast feeding women. Patients who have pelvic irradiation with doses ≥ 45 Grays (Gy). History of previous bone marrow and/or stem cell transplantation. Confirmed bone marrow involvement</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>