<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01831882</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to investigate the biological components of major depression. The investigators are particularity interested in genetic variation and how it contributes to cortisol (because cortisol is higher in severe depression than mild depression or healthy controls) and how it contributes to clinical symptoms, especially suicidal ideation/behavior and psychosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Identifying Biological Markers for Severe Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for depressed patients: 1. Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders 4th Edition (DSMIV) diagnosis of Unipolar Major Depressive Disorder with or without psychotic features. 2. 21item Hamilton Depression Rating Scale (HDRS) score greater than or equal to 21. 3. Thase Core Endogenomorphic Scale score greater than or equal to 8 on the items included in the 21item HDRS. 4. Between 18 70 years of age. 5. If currently taking antipsychotic, antidepressant, anticonvulsant, and/or moodstabilizing medications, must be stable on the medication for at least oneweek prior to entering the study. 6. Preexisting (current) primary treating psychiatrist for subjects with psychotic features. 7. Any secondary diagnoses from the anxiety disorder spectrum is acceptable. Primary preexisting chronic ObsessiveCompulsive Disorder (OCD) will be an exclusion criteria. Inclusion criteria for healthy controls: 1. Between 18 70 years of age. 2. Have a HAMD score of less than or equal to 5. Exclusion Criteria for depressed patients: 1. Electroconvulsive Therapy (ECT) in the 6 months prior to the study. 2. Abuse of drugs or alcohol in the 6 months prior to study. 3. Unstable or untreated hypertension or cardiovascular disease. 4. Use of additional prescription medications, street drugs, or alcohol during the week before the study. 5. Any Axis II diagnosis or traits which would make participation in the study difficult. 6. Current pregnancy or lactation. 7. Postpartum depression 8. Diagnosis of obsessivecompulsive disorder 9. History of significant cognitive decline Exclusion criteria for healthy controls: 1. Personal history of Axis I or Axis II disorders. 2. Active unstable medical problems. 3. Abuse of drugs or alcohol in the 6 months prior to study. 4. Use of additional prescription medications, street drugs, or alcohol during the week before the study. 5. Currently pregnant or lactating. 6. History of significant cognitive decline</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>