<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01831947</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial investigates the impact of intravitreal injection of Ranibizumab antibody on the acuteness of vision. Patients included are suffering from choroidal neo-vascularization (CNV) as a consequence of age-related macular degeneration (AMD). Initially, all patients get injections of 0.5 mg Ranibizumab in monthly intervals for 3 months. Subsequently, one group gets Ranibizumab in intervals of 2 months, whereas a second group is treated on demand. The primary end point of the study is the change of best-corrected visual acuity after 12 month. Secondary end points include the impact of Ranibizumab on morphological changes of the retina, the number of patients with gain or loss of 15 or more letters visual acuity after 12 months, changes in quality of life and the number of injections required during the first 12 months of treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Study of Ranibizumab on Patients With Age-related Macular Degeneration.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Choroidal Neovascularization</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients with choroidal neovascularization (CNV) as a consequence of agerelated macular degeneration (AMD) age 50 and older, male and female membrane &lt;= 12 papillary diameter visual acuity between 20/320 and 20/40 (ETDRS) written informed consent known hypersensitivity to the medicinal product under investigation, ingredients or medicinal products with a similar chemical structure participation in another clinical trial within the last 4 weeks unability to understand trial information pregnant or lactating women women with an amenorrhea &lt; 12 months suspected unability to cooperate detachment of pigment epithelium without membrane detection &gt;= 50%,retinal angiomatotic proliferation (RAP), presumed ocular histoplasmosis syndrome (POHS), chorioretinal anastomosis (CRA), myopic CNV, CNV following trauma, uveitis, RCS or reasons except AMD rupture of pigment epithelium subretinal bleeding &gt;= 50% of membrane or &gt;= 1 PD subretinal fibrosis or chorioatrophy pretreatment with Verteporfin (photodynamic therapy), radiotherapy, transpupillary thermotherapy of the eye under investigation as a consequence of maculadegeneration treatment with Verteporfin of the eye not under investigation within 7 days prior inclusion former participation in clinical trials with antiangiogenic substances: Pegaptanib, Ranibizumab, Bevacizumab, Anecortave Acetat, Proteinkinase C Inhibitors former injection of antiangiogenic substances in the eye under investigation former focal subfoveal lasercoagulation of the eye under investigation juxta or extrafoveal lasercoagulation of the eye under investigation within 1 month prior inclusion former vitrectomy former surgery as a consequence of maculadegeneration glaucoma patients which have been treated with prostaglandin containing eye drops other ocular diseases which may lead to surgery within the clinical study or may lead to a loss of vision of two lines acute intraocular inflammation of the eye under investigation vitreous hemorrhage of the eye under investigation maculaforamen of the eye under investigation diabetic retinopathy former retina detachment of the eye under investigation uveitis acute conjunctivitis, keratitis, scleritis, or endophthalmitis aphakia or pseudoaphakia with damaged backcapsule(exception: YAGcapsulotomy) myopia larger than 8 diopter former intraocular surgery of the eye under investigation within 2 months prior inclusion decompensated glaucoma with &gt;= 30 mm Hg despite therapy former filtrating glaucoma surgery of the eye under investigation former corneal grafting of the eye under investigation former stroke or heart attack ongoing therapy because of systemic infection known allergic reaction to fluorescein bad quality of fundus documentation because of bad range of vision</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>age-related macular degeneration</keyword>
	<keyword>Ranibizumab</keyword>
</DOC>