<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02772367</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate whether cells from a biopsy taken from the patient skin can be transformed into cardiomyocytes the changes in cardiomyocyte (heart muscle cells) when grown in a special culture medium outside of the body. The structure and function of these cells will then be studied to determine why some patients with breast cancer who are treated with chemotherapy including anthracycline (e.g. Doxorubicin) and anti-HER2 therapy (e.g. Herceptin) develop decreased heart function.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Generation of Heart Muscle Cells From Skin Cells of Breast Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female Age greater than 18 years Willing to participate in protocol procedures with signed informed consent History of nonmetastatic HER2 positive breast cancer Prior/current treatment with anthracycline based chemotherapy followed by antiHER2 directed therapy Subjects in the cardiotoxicity group (TOX) must meet the following criteria: Prior confirmed diagnosis of symptomatic cardiotoxicity associated with anthracycline and antiHER2 based therapy, defined as a decrease in LVEF &gt; 10% from baseline to &lt; 55% with symptoms of heart failure (NYHA class IIIV). Subjects in the no cardiotoxicity group (NOTOX) must meet the following criteria: Completion of planned anthracycline and antiHER2 therapy No symptoms of heart failure (NYHA class IIIV) during and at the end of anthracycline and antiHER2 therapy Normal LVEF &gt;55% at each assessment during and at the end of trastuzumab therapy. Maximum absolute decrease in LVEF &lt;5% from baseline during and at the end of trastuzumab therapy. LVEF assessment performed at baseline and at least two time points during trastuzumab therapy. Unwilling or unable to give skin biopsies Contraindications to punch biopsy including but not limited to bleeding diathesis, as determined by the investigator. Known pre‐existing CV disease prior to initiation of breast cancer therapy as determined by the investigator, including Obstructive coronary artery disease (stenosis &gt;70%) Arrhythmia paroxysmal or persistent atrial arrhythmias, sustained ventricular tachycardia (&gt;30 seconds), ventricular fibrillation, or cardiac arrest Cardiomyopathy (EF &lt;55%) Heart failure (NYHA class IIIV) Valvular heart disease with equal to or greater than moderate stenosis or regurgitation</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cardiotoxicity</keyword>
	<keyword>16-025</keyword>
</DOC>