<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02772146</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A single-center, prospective, non-randomized, clinical and first-in-human study. Each patient will be studied during a single treatment session of ten hours. The device will be connected to an existing, standard PD catheter that the patient will be using routinely prior to the study (i.e. a peritoneal dialysis catheter will not be specifically inserted for the study). The patient will be hospitalized for observation during the test day and during the night following the study session. Ultrafiltration volume, dialysate glucose concentrations, blood glucose concentrations as well the patient's acceptability and tolerance of the wearable device will be evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Study of the Safety and Efficacy of a Wearable Device (CLS UF) That Delivers Continuous Administration of Glucose to Recirculated Peritoneal Dialysis Fluid for the Purpose of Ultrafiltration in Patients With Congestive Heart Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardio-Renal Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dialysis Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patient, 1880 years of age. Prevalent PD patients with CHF with cardiorenal syndrome type II, on stable ultrafiltration, for more than two months, treated with PD based UF according to German national guidelines. Therapy resistance of pharmacologic therapy: resistant hypervolemia with ascites, pleural fluid and pulmonary edema Recurrent hospitalization with cardiac decompensation, ≥ 2 occasions during the last six months Isolated failure of the right heart chamber Treatment based on night time APD therapy combined with a day time long dwell. Obtained written consent to participate in the study. End stage renal disease requiring dialysis. Malignant disease. Ongoing infection. Diabetes mellitus. HIV and/or hepatitis positive. Pregnancy. Breastfeeding women. Participation in other clinical trials within one month before inclusion. Abdominal hernia. Cardiac diseases other than left ventricular heart failure, biventricular heart failure or isolated right heart chamber failure, with volume overload. Any immune deficiency.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>