<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01661309</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Vegetarians are known to be deficient in vitamin B12, due to a lack or absence of dietary animal produce, which can elevate homocysteine. There is strong evidence indicating that elevated plasma total homocysteine (tHcy) is a contributor to chronic conditions, such as primary cardiovascular disease (CVD). The study hypothesis is: There will be a significant decrease in plasma tHcy of vegetarians following the intervention by supplementary vitamin B12 (of the methylcobalamin type) and this will lead to a reduction of the risk of CVD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Supplementary Vitamin B12 Effects on Elevated Homocysteine Levels of Vegetarians - Clinical Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vitamin B 12 Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperhomocysteinemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin B 12</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxocobalamin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin B Complex</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Having a plasma tHcy &gt;10 micromol/L Not suffering from conditions as described in exclusion criteria. Vegetarian for at least one year. Not participating in a weight reducing diet. Not consuming regularly vitamin B12 supplements. Give written consent to participate in clinical trial and be fluent in English language. Having a plasma tHcy less or equal to 10 micromol/L. Suffering from pernicious anemia or other vitamin B12 deficiency disease. Undergone bowel surgery or suffer from gastrointestinal disease. Pregnant, lactating or trying to conceive. Smoker. Alcohol intake regularly greater than official recommended daily units (i.e. 2 units female, 3 units male). Consume large amounts of caffeine (regular consumption of &gt;4 cups of strong tea or coffee per day). Use of medications known to influence nutritional status. Have genetic metabolic disease. Suffer from renal failure, diabetes, thyroid disease, cardiovascular disease, dementia or cancer. Have a known bloodborne infection (e.g. Hepatitis or HIV).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hyperhomocysteinemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Methylcobalamin</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Plasma total homocysteine</keyword>
	<keyword>Vegetarians</keyword>
</DOC>