<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01661439</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Preconceptional use of low molecular weight heparin (enoxaparin) and aspirin in patient with recurrent miscarriages with positive anti phospholipid antibodies increase the implantation rate and the duration of pregnancy with low complications to the mother and the baby.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Preconceptional Thromboprophylaxis in Recurrent PREGNANCY LOSSES Caused by Antiphospholipid Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Preconceptional heparin during follicular or luteal phase,improves the implantation rate by increasing the blood flow and increasing the implantation factors,also decreasing the pregnancy complication resulting from Antiphospholipid Syndrome (APS).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abortion, Spontaneous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fetal Death</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antiphospholipid Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium heparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heparin, Low-Molecular-Weight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dalteparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heparin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. All women with recurrent firsttrimester miscarriage and all women with one or more secondtrimester miscarriage who screened before pregnancy for antiphospholipid antibodies. 2. To diagnose antiphospholipid syndrome it is mandatory that the woman has two positive tests at least 12 weeks apart for either lupus anticoagulant or anticardiolipin antibodies of immunoglobulin G and/or immunoglobulin M class present in a medium or high titre over 40 g/l or ml/l,or above the 99th percentile). In the detection of lupus anticoagulant, the dilute Russell's viper venom time test together with a platelet neutralisation procedure is more sensitive and specific than either the activated partial thromboplastin time test or the kaolin clotting time test. Anticardiolipin antibodies are detected using a standardised enzyme linked immunosorbent assay. 1. Age above forty years old . 2. Intrauterine abnormalities (as assessed by ultrasound, hysterosonography, hysterosalpingogram, or hysteroscopy). 3. Fibroids distorting uterine cavity . 4. Abnormal parental karyotype . 5. Other identifiable causes of recurrent miscarriages (tests initiated only if clinically indicated) e.g., diabetes, thyroid disease and systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE).</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Recurrent miscarriages</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent pregnancy loss</keyword>
	<keyword>aps</keyword>
	<keyword>anti coagulants in pregnancy</keyword>
</DOC>