<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02608671</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will be undertaken to question the superiority of use skin adhesive tape (® Steri-Strip) closure system in wound healing over the traditional running absorbable subcuticular suture technique in perineal repair after episiotomy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adhesive Tape in Episiotomy Repair</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Episiotomy is the most common operating procedure that most obstetricians will perform in their lifetime. Because it is so common and considered minor surgery, teaching students or interns the principles and techniques usually is left to the most junior of residents The optimal method for episiotomy and perineal trauma repair following childbirth remains open to debate and a great cause of concern to doctors, midwives, and the public Apparently, the ideal method for perineal repair should be quick, painless, easy to perform and preferably, without increase in pain and dyspareunia during the puerperium This study will be undertaken to question the superiority of use skin adhesive tape (® Steri-Strip) closure system in wound healing over the traditional running absorbable subcuticular suture technique in perineal repair after episiotomy.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Primiparous. First and second degree perineal tear. Normal not instrumental vaginal delivery; spontaneous not induced. Patient willingness to randomize to episiotomy repair technique. Previously existing local infections or lesions. Third and forth degrees perineal tear. Maternal diseases interfere with wound healing or causing excessive bleeding (coagulopathy, collagen disease, diabetes mellitus, known immunodeficiency, immunosuppressive treatment). Known hypersensitivity to adhesive materials Maternal unwillingness to undergo randomization. Participation in another interventiontrial with interference of intervention and/or outcome of this study.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Episiotomy</keyword>
	<keyword>continuous suture</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin adhesive tape</keyword>
</DOC>