<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02608099</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the prospective, randomized cohort in this study is to assess the safety and efficacy of 2 apixaban treatment strategies (uninterrupted versus interrupted) in subjects planned to undergo catheter ablation for the treatment of non-valvular atrial fibrillation (NVAF). Simultaneously, a retrospective cohort of 300 warfarin-treated individuals, identified by chart review, who are matched to the prospective randomized subjects, will be identified. The purpose of the retrospective warfarin cohort is to compare the efficacy and safety of warfarin(the current clinical practice) to that of apixaban (uninterrupted, interrupted, combined uninterrupted and interrupted).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Apixaban Evaluation of Interrupted Or Uninterrupted Anticoagulation for Ablation of Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Prospective, Randomized Cohort Subjects undergoing ablation for NVAF who meet all eligibility criteria and sign informed consent will be enrolled into the study. Subjects will be treated with apixaban for ≥21 days prior to the ablation procedure (for subjects already on apixaban for ≥21 days, it is not necessary to wait 21 days before the ablation procedure. Apixaban dose will be 5 mg b.i.d. per product label, or 2.5 mg b.i.d. in subjects with 2 or more of the following: age ≥80 years, body weight ≤60 kg, or serum creatinine ≥1.5 mg/dL. Eligible subjects will then be randomized in a 1:1 ratio to 2 peri-procedural treatment strategies: - Uninterrupted treatment: administer the evening apixaban dose on the day prior to the procedure; administer the morning apixaban dose on the day of the procedure; administer heparin bolus before transseptal puncture to maintain a target activated clotting time [ACT] &gt; 300 seconds; administer the evening apixaban dose after the procedure if there were no peri-procedural complications that necessitate withholding anticoagulation for longer duration. - Interrupted treatment: administer the evening apixaban dose on the day prior to the procedure; do not administer the morning apixaban dose on the day of the procedure; administer heparin bolus before transseptal puncture to maintain a target ACT &gt; 300 seconds; administer the evening apixaban dose after the procedure if there were no peri-procedural complications that necessitate withholding anticoagulation for longer duration. Randomization will take place prior to the procedure (on the day of the procedure or up to 3 days prior to the procedure) and will be stratified by site. It is anticipated that up to 360 subjects may be enrolled in order to evaluate a total of 300 randomized subjects (150 subjects per treatment arm): Randomized subjects will continue treatment with apixaban for 1 month post procedure. Retrospective, Warfarin Cohort In addition, a chart review of 300 warfarin-treated patients who underwent catheter ablation for NVAF on or after September 1, 2013 in the enrolling centers and who have documented follow-up in the medical record for ≥ 30 days post-ablation procedure will be performed. Patient records for warfarin-treated individuals who meet the applicable inclusion/exclusion criteria and who are matched 1:1 to a subject in the prospective, randomized cohort for age (+/- 5 years), gender and atrial fibrillation (AF) type (paroxysmal vs. persistent), will be identified. Sites will document key demographic and outcome variables. This review will be performed in a blinded manner such that site personnel are blinded to the outcome of each retrospective subject during the subject selection process. Only pre-existing data will be collected for the analysis of this cohort.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Apixaban</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Signed informed consent. 2. &gt;18 years of age. 3. NVAF with planned catheter ablation treatment. 4. Planned anticoagulant treatment for at least 1 month after the index procedure. 5. Subject agrees to all required followup procedures and visits. 6. For women of childbearing potential (WOCBP): Must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 24 hours prior to the start of study drug. Must not be breastfeeding Must agree to follow instructions for method(s) of contraception for a total of 33 days posttreatment completion. 7. Males who are sexually active with WOCBP must agree to follow instructions for method(s) of contraception for a total of 93 days posttreatment completion. 8. Azoospermic males and WOCBP who are continuously not heterosexually active are exempt from contraceptive requirements. However, WOCBP must still undergo pregnancy testing as described in this section. 1. History of significant bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy or inability to accept blood transfusions. 2. Known hypersensitivity or contraindication to heparin or apixaban. 3. Subjects with mechanical prosthetic heart valves. 4. History of cerebrovascular accident or transient ischemic attach (TIA) within the last 6 months. 5. Prior intracranial hemorrhage. 6. Endstage renal failure (creatinine clearance rate &lt;15 mL/minute or on dialysis treatment). 7. Hepatic disease associated with coagulopathy. 8. Current or expected systemic treatment with strong dual inducers of CYP3A4 and Pglycoprotein (e.g., rifampin, carbamazepine, phenytoin, St. John's Wort). 9. Current or expected systemic treatment with dual antiplatelet therapy, other anticoagulants, or fibrinolytics. 10. Planned or expected surgery, or other invasive procedure that would require interruption of anticoagulation within 1 month of the catheter ablation procedure. 11. Currently enrolled in another investigational device or drug trial that has not completed the primary endpoint or that clinically interferes with the current study endpoints. 12. Comorbid condition(s) that could limit the subject's ability to participate in the trial or to comply with followup requirements, or that could impact the scientific integrity of the trial. 13. Platelet count ≤100,000/mm3. 14. Hemoglobin level &lt;9 g/dL. 15. Any active bleeding. 16. Prisoners or subjects who are involuntarily incarcerated. 17. Subjects who are compulsorily detained for treatment of either a psychiatric or physical (e.g., infectious disease) illness.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Atrial fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-valvular atrial fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>Catheter ablation</keyword>
	<keyword>Apixaban</keyword>
	<keyword>Warfarin</keyword>
	<keyword>Harvard Clinical Research Institute</keyword>
</DOC>