<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02319837</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess enzalutamide plus leuprolide in patients with high-risk nonmetastatic prostate cancer progressing after radical prostatectomy or radiotherapy or both.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of Enzalutamide Plus Leuprolide in Patients With Nonmetastatic Prostate Cancer (EMBARK)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leuprolide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the prostate at initial biopsy, without neuroendocrine differentiation, signet cell, or small cell features; Prostate cancer initially treated by radical prostatectomy or radiotherapy (including brachytherapy) or both, with curative intent; PSA doubling time ≤ 9 months; Screening PSA by the central laboratory ≥ 1 ng/mL for patients who had radical prostatectomy (with or without radiotherapy) as primary treatment for prostate cancer and at least 2 ng/mL above the nadir for patients who had radiotherapy only as primary treatment for prostate cancer; Serum testosterone ≥ 150 ng/dL (5.2 nmol/L). Prior or present evidence of distant metastatic disease as assessed by radiographic imaging; Prior hormonal therapy. Neoadjuvant/adjuvant therapy to treat prostate cancer ≤ 36 months in duration and ≥ 9 months before randomization, or a single dose or a short course (≤ 6 months) of hormonal therapy given for rising PSA ≥ 9 months before randomization is allowed.; Prior cytotoxic chemotherapy, aminoglutethimide, ketoconazole, abiraterone acetate, or enzalutamide for prostate cancer; Prior systemic biologic therapy, including immunotherapy, for prostate cancer; Major surgery within 4 weeks before randomization; Treatment with 5α reductase inhibitors (finasteride, dutasteride) within 4 weeks of randomization; Known or suspected brain metastasis or active leptomeningeal disease; History of another invasive cancer within 3 years before screening, with the exception of fully treated cancers with a remote probability of recurrence</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>