<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01919814</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine whether Appethyl™, made from spinach, will reduce appetite and hunger given on the same day of testing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Short-Term Appetite Suppression Trial Using Appethyl™: The Pizza</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Four hours after breakfast a small amount of liquid to drink will be given to a participant that will contain either the Appethyl™ or placebo. You will be given a lunch of about 750 calories and 40% fat prepared by the Metabolic Kitchen and be asked to eat all of it. You will have food choice testing performed 4 hours after starting your lunch meal. This will be done in two ways. You will be given a list of two foods that are made of carbohydrate like bread and pretzels and be asked which you prefer most. You will also be given a list of foods that differ in the amounts of fat, carbohydrate and protein that they contain and you will be asked to mark the ones that appeal to you. You will be presented with a pizza in a quantity more than you could reasonably be expected to eat 5 hours after the start of your lunch meal and be asked to eat to your satisfaction over 30 minutes. You are not expected to eat all of the pizza.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>You are a male or female aged 18 to 65 years. You have a BMI (a number calculated from your height and weight) between 2535 kg/m2, inclusive. Your waist circumference is over 35 inches. You have been on a diet for weight loss in the last 2 months. You are being treated for blood pressure, diabetes, heart disease, rheumatoid arthritis, or blood vessel disease. You have a psychotic illness. You have other chronic diseases like an inflammatory bowel disease such as Crohn's disease or ulcerative colitis. You have a dysfunction of your gastrointestinal tract. You have food allergies. You have rheumatoid arthritis with inflammation. You have chronic constipation. You are taking any products to lose weight such as medication for obesity or nonprescription medications for weight loss.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>