<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01919697</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multi-center, open-label, 52-week safety and tolerability study of plecanatide in patients with Chronic Idiopathic Constipation (CIC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-label Extension (OLE) Study of Plecanatide for Chronic Idiopathic Constipation (CIC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label extension study of plecanatide in the treatment of patients with CIC who previously completed Synergy Protocols SP304-20210 and SP304203-00 (The CIC3 Study). The planned duration of each patient's study participation is up to 411 days, including up to 33 days of screening, 8 study visits over 52 weeks of treatment and a follow-up visit 2 weeks after the last dose of study drug.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Constipation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient completed a previous doubleblind plecanatide study and was compliant with the study requirements. Patient is in good health without unstable acute illness or exacerbation of an unstable chronic illness or chronic disease that may affect study assessments, particularly if there has been a significant change to health status since the previous plecanatide study. Patient has had major surgery including laparoscopic procedures requiring general anesthesia within 60 days of Day 1. Patient has a medical history of hepatitis B, hepatitis C or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. Patient has taken a protocolprohibited drug without the appropriate washout period.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>81 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Plecantaide</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Idiopathic Constipation</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic</keyword>
	<keyword>Idiopathic</keyword>
	<keyword>Constipation</keyword>
	<keyword>Synergy</keyword>
	<keyword>CIC</keyword>
	<keyword>CIC study</keyword>
	<keyword>CIC OLE</keyword>
	<keyword>CIC OLE study</keyword>
	<keyword>OLE</keyword>
	<keyword>OLE CIC</keyword>
	<keyword>OLE CIC3</keyword>
	<keyword>Open label</keyword>
	<keyword>Open label study</keyword>
	<keyword>Long term</keyword>
	<keyword>Long term study</keyword>
	<keyword>Extension</keyword>
	<keyword>Extension study</keyword>
</DOC>