<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02328105</DOC>
	<brief_summary>ABRAXANE, based on results from prior studies, is a promising drug in squamous cell carcinoma of the lung. This study will help to explore the combination of ABRAXANE and carboplatin more thoroughly in the subgroup of patients who had the best response in prior studies as well as determine whether there are any biomarkers which can predict for response.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>LCI-LUN-ABR-001: Carbo With Nab-Paclitaxel in Patients With Advanced NSCL Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single arm phase II study for subjects receiving first line therapy for metastatic squamous cell lung cancer. Following informed consent and eligibility check, all subjects will receive therapy with carboplatin and ABRAXANE on an outpatient basis. A total of 50 subjects will be enrolled over an enrollment period of about 24 months. Interim analyses will be conducted after the enrollment of subject 15, subject 30, and subject 45. Tissue biomarkers will be analyzed at baseline; and blood biomarkers will be analyzed at baseline, pre-dose on cycles 3 and 5, and then within 30 days of last dose of study treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed stage IV nonsmall cell lung cancer with predominantly squamous histology No prior systemic treatment for metastatic disease. Patients who have received prior adjuvant chemotherapy for earlystage lung cancer are eligible if at least 12 months have elapsed between the date of final chemotherapy administration and the date of consent Patients must have measurable disease, defined as at least one lesion that can be accurately measured in at least one dimension (longest diameter to be recorded for nonnodal lesions and short axis for nodal lesions) as &gt;20 mm with conventional techniques or as &gt;10 mm with CT scan, MRI, or calipers by clinical exam Biopsy accessible disease Patients with previous radiotherapy as definitive therapy for locally advanced nonsmall cell lung cancer are eligible, as long as the recurrence is outside the original radiation therapy port. Definitive radiation therapy must have been completed &gt;4 weeks prior to the date the informed consent is signed Age &gt;18 years ECOG performance status less than or equal to 1 If patient has brain metastasis, the disease must be stable (treated and/or asymptomatic) for at least 4 weeks prior to first dose of study treatment Bilirubin &lt; 1.5 mg/dL Adequate liver function: AST and ALT &lt;= 2.5x upper limit of normal, alkaline phosphatase &lt;= 2.5x upper limit of normal, unless bone metastasis is present (&lt; 5x upper limit of normal) in the absence of liver metastasis Adequate bone marrow function: Platelets &gt;100,000 cells/mm3, Hemoglobin &gt; 9.0g/dL and ANC &gt; 1,500 cells/mm3 Adequate renal function with creatinine &lt;1.5 mg/dL is recommended Females of childbearing potential and sexually active males must use an effective contraception method during treatment and for six months after completing treatment Negative serum or urine BhCG pregnancy test at screening for patients of childbearing potential Patients must have &lt; Grade 2 preexisting peripheral neuropathy (per CTCAE version 4.0) Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document Exclusion Criteria Received prior systemic therapy for metastatic disease Received limited field radiation for palliation &lt;= 2 weeks prior to starting study treatment and/or from whom &gt;= 30% bone marrow was irradiated Receiving any other investigational agents Known hypersensitivity to either carboplatin or ABRAXANE Uncontrolled and current illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements Pregnant or breast feeding Other active malignancies Neuropathy greater than or equal to grade 2</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>