<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02328898</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study objective is to assess the safety and efficacy of the Permanent Polymer Zotarolimus-Eluting Stent Resolute Integrity™ to the Polymer Free Amphilimus-Eluting Stent Cre8™ compared in an all-comer patient population. 1 month of dual antiplatelet duration will be applied in stable angina pectoris patients. Myocardial infarction patient population will be treated with 12 months of dual antiplatelet therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized "All-comer" Evaluation of a Permanent Polymer Resolute Integrity Stent Versus a Polymer Free Cre8 Stent</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Prospective, Single-Center, Open Label, Randomized Controlled, two-arm Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of the Permanent Polymer Zotarolimus Eluting Stent 'Resolute Integrity™' Compared to Polymer Free Amphilimus Eluting Stent 'Cre8'. Dual Antiplatelet Therapy duration of 1 Month will be applied in stable angina pectoris patient population. Myocardial infarction patient population will be treated with 12 months of dual antiplatelet therapy (DAPT). One thousand five hundred thirty-two (1532) patients (1:1 randomization Cre8 stent: Resolute Integrity™ stent) will be enrolled in the study, with clinical follow-up at 12 months to assess the primary end point. After a period of 12 months, a clinical registry will be implemented Information will be collected at 3-years post procedure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angina Pectoris</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angina, Stable</mesh_term>
	<criteria>General 1. Allcomer patients aged 18 years and older 2. Patient has been informed of the nature of the trial and agrees to its provisions and has provided either oral during emergency procedure, followed by written informed consent, or written informed consent in case of an elective procedure as approved by the Medical Research Ethics Committee (MREC) of the respective investigational site 3. Patient is eligible, according to heart team decision if applicable, for PCI with implantation of a drugeluting stent (DES) 4. Patient has clinical evidence of ischemic heart disease, angina pectoris, myocardial infarction, or silent ischemia Angiographic 1. All denovo lesions and all restenotic lesions (whether native coronary or bypass graft), not amenable for treatment with drug eluting balloons 2. All lesions types are allowed: calcified lesions (lesion preparation with scoring/cutting and rotational atherectomy are allowed), thrombus, chronic total occlusion (CTO; randomized after successful wire crossing and predilatation), bifurcation lesions, ostial lesions, bypass graft (venous and arterial) lesions and left main. 3. There is no limit for lesion length; overlapping stents are allowed, or number of lesions or diseased vessels. 4. Target vessel size reference (visual estimation) between 2.5 mm and 4.5 mm. 1. Inability to provide informed consent 2. Participation in another study for intracoronary stents that had not reached its primary endpoint 3. Planned surgery within the next 3 months 4. Known intolerance to P2Y12 receptor antagonist that would prevent adherence to DAPT, or intolerance to aspirin, clopidogrel, Ticagrelor, Prasugrel, heparin/bivalirudin, contrast agent (that cannot be adequately premedicated) or component of DES 5. Female of childbearing potential, who are pregnant or are planning to become pregnant 6. Life expectancy of less than 12 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Polymer free stent</keyword>
	<keyword>percutaneous coronary intervention</keyword>
</DOC>