<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01855126</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In conjunction with investigators at the Cecil G. Sheps Center for Health Services Research, University of North Carolina (UNC) at Chapel Hill, we propose to develop and evaluate a low-cost, minimally obtrusive device that delivers individualized light therapy to adults with early-awakening insomnia - the most common sleep disturbance in older adults, and a significant problem because of its relationship to daytime sleepiness, use of potentially hazardous sleep medication, and reduced quality of life. The proposed device will measure light/dark exposure data over 24 hours, estimate optimum timing for light delivery, and deliver an individualized light dosage while subjects are asleep. Light applied through closed eyelids in the early part of the night will delay the dim light melatonin onset, a marker of the circadian clock, and help those with early sleep onset to fall asleep later</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Individually Tailored Lighting System to Improve Sleep in Older Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We will recruit 28 subjects who report going to bed early and desiring later bedtimes and will ask them to wear an active and an inactive light mask for 8 consecutive weeks each. A 4-week washout period between active and inactive conditions will be applied. Outcome measures will be collected periodically throughout the 8 weeks. Baseline (no intervention) will be collected prior to the active and inactive lighting interventions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dyssomnias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Melatonin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age 65 or older cognitively capable able to respond to study staff verbally and in English score greater than 6 using the Pittsburgh Sleepiness Quality Index suffer from insomnia suffer from excessive daytime sleepiness Severe sleep apnea Severe restless leg syndrome (RLS) Significant cognitive impairment History of severe photosensitivity dermatitis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>light</keyword>
	<keyword>circadian rhythms</keyword>
	<keyword>dim light melatonin onset</keyword>
	<keyword>sleep</keyword>
</DOC>