<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01429337</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this international study is to assess the effect of varying degrees of impaired hepatic function compared to a normal hepatic function (Child-Pugh classification) on the pharmacokinetics and safety of midostaurin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetics and Safety of Midostaurin in Subjects With Impaired Hepatic Function and Subjects With Normal Hepatic Function</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>4'-N-benzoylstaurosporine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Staurosporine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>• Subjects must be able to communicate well with the Investigator and comply with the requirements of the study. Significant neurologic or psychiatric disorder which could compromise participation in the study. Subjects with known ongoing alcohol and/or drug abuse within 1 month prior to dosing or evidence of such abuse. Subjects with cotinine levels greater than 500ng/mL are considered as smokers and will not be enrolled. Consumption of alcohol within 3 days prior to dosing or during the study. Women of childbearing potential unless they are using a highly effective contraception method the length of the study and for at least for at least 3 months after the last exposure to midostaurin. Highly effective methods include: Total abstinence, female sterilization or male partner sterilization. Or use a combination of (a+b): a) Placement of an intrauterine device or intrauterine system , b)barrier method of contraception Sexually active males unless they use condom during intercourse while taking midostaurin and for at least 3 months after the last exposure to drug. A condom is required to be used also by vasectomized men. Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatic impaired patients</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy volunteers</keyword>
	<keyword>Varying degrees of hepatic impairment</keyword>
</DOC>