<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00099970</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial is being conducted to determine tumor response and preliminary safety of a monoclonal antibody that specifically binds to a cell surface receptor (α5β1 integrin) that is required for the establishment of new blood vessels during tumor growth, a process known as angiogenesis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Volociximab in Combination With DTIC in Patients With Metastatic Melanoma Not Previously Treated With Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and females of at least 18 years of age with stage IV or unresectable stage III nonocular melanoma who may have received 0 to 2 prior regimens for metastatic disease with a biological therapy or immunotherapy (e.g., IL2 or interferonalfa). Measurable disease according to Response Criteria for Solid Tumors (RECIST). Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status less than or equal to 1. Estimated survival is greater or equal to 4 months. Negative pregnancy test (women of childbearing potential only). Pretreatment laboratory levels that meet specific criteria. Signed informed consent, including permission to use protected health information. Prior treatment with M200 or a5b1 inhibitors and murine or chimeric monoclonal antibodies. Prior treatment with DTIC, temozolomide, or other chemotherapeutic regimens. Known sensitivity to murine proteins or chimeric antibodies or other components of the product. Use of any investigational drug within 4 weeks prior to screening or 5 halflives of the prior investigational drug (whichever is longer). Systemic biologic, immunotherapy, and/or radiation therapy within 4 weeks of the first dose of M200. Documented central nervous system (CNS) tumor or CNS metastasis. History of thromboembolic events and bleeding disorders within the past year. Medical conditions that may be exacerbated by bleeding.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Solid tumors</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic melanoma</keyword>
</DOC>