<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT01896089</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>This prospective , multi-center , observational study determine combination desensitization enrollment regional kidney pair donor ( KPD ) exchange program improve overall rate kidney transplantation sensitize patient .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Regional Kidney Paired Donor Exchange Sensitized Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>A . Potential Recipients must meet follow inclusion criterion : 1 . Willing able sign inform consent form 2 . Must least 18 year old 3 . Meet recipient selection criterion transplant center 4 . Listed deceased donor kidney wait list renal transplant participate center 5 . Potential recipient must : Group 1 : one medically suitable donor ABO incompatible HLA incompatible ( define positive serologic crossmatch ) ; Group 2 : medically suitable donor otherwise deem incompatible due age , size , mismatch respective transplant center ; Group 3 : list decease donor wait list ≥ one year without identifiable living donor PRA % ≥ 60 % B . Potential Living Donors must meet follow inclusion criterion : 1 . Must provide informed consent accordance process outline Informed Consent Requirements Section KPD Program Manual Operations 2 . Must least 18 year old 3 . Meet living donor selection criterion transplant center 4 . Meet evaluation requirement set forth Living Donor Evaluation Section KPD Program Operational Guidelines C. Recipients 1 . Do meet selection criterion transplant center 2 . Eligible compatible donor time enrollment 3 . Inactive ( eligible receive kidney ) decease donor waitlist 4 . Pregnant breast feeding D. Donors 1 . Unwilling unable provide inform consent 2 . Have identify barrier donation set forth Living Donor Evaluation Section KPD Program Manual Operations ( Appendix A ) 3 . Must currently list potential living donor recipient register KPD system 4 . Pregnant breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>