<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01505959</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Targeted population: Sleep apnea patients at high cardiovascular risk newly treated by CPAP Hypothesis: Improvement in blood pressure after 6 months of CPAP treatment might be greater in the telemonitoring arm compared to usual CPAP care. Main goal: To compare 6-months blood pressure reduction when Sleep Apnea patients at high cardiovascular risk are randomly allocated to usual CPAP care or a multidisciplinary and coordinated follow-up based on a telemonitoring web platform.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Blood Pressure Reduction Induced by CPAP in Sleep Apnea Patients at High Cardiovascular Risk : OPTISAS 2 Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study procedures: The telemonitoring system will involve respiratory physicians, home care providers and include regular assessments of home self-measured blood pressure, oximetry, physical activity recorded by actigraphy, CPAP compliance, side effects and residual events. Secured data transmission to medical staff computers and secured websites will allow easy telemonitoring. Automatic algorithms have been built-up for early adjustment of CPAP treatment in case of side effects, leaks and persistent residual events. An interim analysis will be performed when 300 patients will be included.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age between 18 to 78 years Men and women AHI &gt; 30 / hour Patient with high cardiovascular score (&gt;5% defined by European SCORE) or known cardiovascular disease (i.e. transient ischemic attack, stroke, coronary artery disease) Patient affiliated to the National health insurance Willingness to use a telemonitoring system Central sleep apnea syndrome Previous CPAP treatment with respiratory support for sleep respiratory trouble Cardiac failure with left ventricular ejection fraction lesser than 40% Hypercapnic chronic respiratory failure (daytime PaCO2 &gt; 50 mmHg) Terminal disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>78 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obstructive Sleep Apnea Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Apnea</keyword>
	<keyword>Sleep Apnea</keyword>
	<keyword>Telemedicine</keyword>
	<keyword>CPAP compliance</keyword>
</DOC>