<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00256087</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the effect of addition of probiotic Lactobacilli to standard enteral feeding on infection rates and feeding efficacy in critically ill patients. The study hypothesis is that critically ill patients who receive the addition of probiotic lactobacilli to the enteral feed will lead to a reduced rate of hospital acquired infections. The null hypothesis is that there will be no significant difference in the rate of hospital acquired infection in critically ill patients who receive enteral feeding with or without the addition of probiotic Lactobacilli.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Prophylactic Probiotic Lactobacilli in Enteral Feeding on Nosocomial Pneumonia Rates in Critically Ill Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The patients are randomised to one of three treatment groups. Each comprising of 100 patients. 1. Standard therapy group. Patients will receive enteral feeding (with fibre) aiming at the target feeding rate that is determined by the treating physician and the ICU dietician, as is standard current practice. Two capsule containing placebo will be given 12 hourly via the feeding tube. 2. The first active treatment group, will receive enteral feeding (with fibre) plus probiotic Lactobacillus fermentum included in the feeding regime. Two capsules containing Lactobacillus fermentum (10 11 organisms per capsule) will be delivered via the feeding tube 12 hourly. 3. The second active treatment group will receive enteral feeding (with fibre) plus the probiotic Lactobacillus acidophilus included in the feeding regime. Two capsules containing Lactobacillus acidophilus (2x10 9 organisms per capsule) will be delivered via the feeding tube 12 hourly.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adult patients (18 years or over)admitted to ICU with an expected stay of more than 48 hours. 2. Patients who are commenced on enteral feeding via gastric or post pyloric routes. 3. Patients who consent or if the patients is incompetent, their next of kin who consent, to inclusion in the study 1. Patients less than 18 years old. 2. Patients who are already receiving probiotic treatment. 3. The lactobacillus acidophilus preparation to be used in the study, contains a very small amount of MSG (total dose of 20mg/day, equivalent to 10% of the initial dose used to test MSG sensitivity) and as a precaution, patients with asthma or recurrent urticaria will be excluded. 4. Patients with HIV infection, preexisting immunosuppression, or who are pregnant. As the Lactobacillus is a live microorganism, immunosuppressed and pregnant pateints will be excluded. 5. Patients with a contraindication to enteral feeding. 6. Patients with contraindication to placement of enteral feeding tube. 7. Patients or nextofkin who do not consent to inclusion in the study. 8. Patients who are already enrolled in another study that may influence the outcome of the probiotic study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Nosocomial rates in critically ill patients</keyword>
</DOC>