<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00256529</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective descriptive cross sectional study to determine the percentage of patients presenting with dysphagia who are found to have eosinophilic esophagitis (EoE) and to establish which presenting factors warrant esophageal biopsies. We hypothesize that a greater than expected percentage of patients who are biopsies will have histologic changes consistent with EE.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Analysis of Eosinophilic Esophagitis in Patients Presenting With Dysphagia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All patients presenting with dysphagia who do not already carry a previous diagnosis for their dysphagia will be asked to enroll. If patients have undergone previous work up for dysphagia such as manometry, 24-hour probe, or barium swallow they can still participate in this study. Informed consent will take place prior to enrollment. After patients present with dysphagia they will fill-out a questionnaire regarding their dysphagia symptoms. An EGD with biopsies will then be performed. Biopsies will be taken from 4 quadrants in the proximal and distal esophagus. The distal esophagus biopsies will be taken 5 cm proximal to the Z-line. Proximal biopsies will be taken anywhere proximal to 30 cm from the incisors.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Esophagitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deglutition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eosinophilic Esophagitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients aged 1890 presenting with dysphagia or food impaction Ability to undergo esophagogastroduodenoscopy and biopsies No significant cardiopulmonary disease, or other contraindication to EGD Contradiction to EGD and/or biopsies such as Boerhaave's syndrome, or history or bleeding disorder or elevated INR Inability to provide informed consent Esophageal varices</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>dysphagia</keyword>
	<keyword>eosinophilic esophagitis</keyword>
</DOC>