<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00256620</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The principal objective to this randomized trial is to compare the efficacy of two strategies of intra-operative hemodynamic management during cardiopulmonary bypass among patients undergoing primary elective coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) surgery in preventing peri-operative cardiac, cognitive and neurologic morbidity and mortality and post-operative deterioration in the patient's quality of life as measured by the seven domains of SF-36 Health Survey (bodily pain, health perceptions, energy, and mental, physical, social and role function).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Outcomes and Quality of Life After CABG</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In one group, mean arterial pressure (MAP) was 65 mmHg. In the other, the MAP target was determined by the patients usual preoperative MAP. Thus, the trial will evaluate whether tailoring the MAP target for the period of cardiopulmonary bypass to within 10 mmHg of the patients usual MAP, but &lt; 90 mmHg (and thus achieving pressures during bypass within the patients usual autoregulatory range) reduces major neurologic and cardiac morbidity and mortality, as well as cognitive complications, thereby improving post-operative quality of life.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>All patients undergoing primary elective/urgent coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) surgery. Patients who elect not to participate in the study Patients undergoing valve replacement or other cardiovascular surgical procedures Patients who are not fluent in English Patient who cannot provide informed written consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cardiopulmonary bypass</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary artery disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac morbidity</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurologic morbidity</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurocognitive function</keyword>
	<keyword>Autoregulation</keyword>
</DOC>