<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00246701</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of OM6 is to evaluate efficacy and safety of Lovaza (omega-3-acid ethyl esters) [formerly known as Omacor] combined with simvastatin for lowering non-high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (non-HDL-C) in subjects with persistent high triglycerides despite statin therapy. Additionally, a two-year extension trial (LOV111818/OM6X) is posted on NCT00903409.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Efficacy and Safety of Combined Omacor (Omega-3-acid Ethyl Esters) and Simvastatin Therapy in Hypertriglyceridemic Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Two studies comprise this OM6 Program. Study OM6 / LOV111858 (double-blind study) and is not required to post results based on FDAAA. Study OM6X / LOV111818 (open-label extension) is posted on NCT00903409.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertriglyceridemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Simvastatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and women ages 1879 years, inclusive Current therapy with a statin drug Triglyceride levels between 200 and 499 mg/dL Normally active and in good health on the basis of medical history, brief physical examination, electrocardiogram, and routine laboratory tests Provide written informed consent and authorization for protected health information disclosure Sensitivity to statin drugs or omega3 fatty acids Lipoprotein lipase impairment or apo C2 deficiency or type III hyperlipidemia Unexplained muscle pain or weakness History of pancreatitis Recent history of certain heart, kidney, liver, lung, or gastrointestinal diseases, or cancer (except nonmelanoma skin cancer) Poorly controlled diabetes, or receiving insulin therapy Pregnant or lactating females. Women of childbearing potential who are not using a medically approved method of contraception. Use of certain types of hormones, anticonvulsant drugs, immunologic drugs, antibiotic, antifungal and antiviral drugs, and cardiac drugs Use of warfarin (Coumadin)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>omega-3-acid ethyl esters</keyword>
	<keyword>simvastatin</keyword>
	<keyword>Lovaza</keyword>
	<keyword>High triglycerides</keyword>
</DOC>