<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00891293</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This was a 24-month, open-label extension study that followed an 8-week double-blind study (Study LOV111859/OM5) and an 8-week, open-label extension study (LOV111860/OM5X). Study LOV111859/OM5 was conducted to evaluate whether combination therapy with Lovaza (omega-3-acid ethyl esters) and Antara (fenofibrate) would result in a greater reduction in serum triglyceride levels in hypertriglyceridemic subjects than treatment with fenofibrate alone. This second extension of 24 months was to assess the continued efficacy of adjunctive Lovaza (omega-3-acid ethyl esters) [formerly known as Omacor] therapy in hypertriglyceridemic subjects treated with Antara (fenofibrate) in lowering serum triglyceride (TG) levels.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Second Open-Label Extension of a Double-Blind, Parallel, Phase IV Study to Assess the Efficacy and Safety of Adjunctive Lovaza® (Formerly Known as Omacor®) Therapy in Hypertriglyceridemic Subjects Treated With Antara™</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Three studies comprise this program. Study LOV111859/OM5 (double-blind study) was followed by two open label extensions - LOV111860/OM5X (1st open label extension - 8 weeks) and LOV111821/OM5XX (2nd open label extension - 24 months). Studies LOV111859/OM5 and LOV111860/OM5X are outlined in NCT00246636.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertriglyceridemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fenofibrate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects were men and women who had successfully completed the previous openlabel extension study (LOV111860/OM5X) and had met all inclusion and exclusion criteria for the original doubleblind study (LOV111859/OM5) and throughout LOV111860/OM5X, or who had a renewed waiver of a previously approved protocol deviation. Eligibility for entry into this study was based on the inclusion/exclusion criteria described of the doubleblind LOV111859/OM5 protocol. Subjects were men and women who had successfully completed the previous openlabel extension study (LOV111860/OM5X) and had met all inclusion and exclusion criteria for the original doubleblind study (LOV111859/OM5) and throughout LOV111860/OM5X, or who had a renewed waiver of a previously approved protocol deviation. The main eligibility criteria for LOV111859/OM5 were, 18 to79 years of age (inclusive) at screening fasting serum TG levels ≥500 mg/dL and &lt;1300 mg/dL BMI ≥ 25 kg/m2 and ≤43 kg/m2. Subjects enrolled directly from the end of LOV111860/OM5X into LOV111821/OM5XX.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>omega-3-acid ethyl esters</keyword>
	<keyword>Very high triglycerides</keyword>
	<keyword>Lovaza</keyword>
	<keyword>fenofibrate</keyword>
</DOC>