<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02268968</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this study is to evaluate the relative efficacy of topical lidocaine on reducing pain associated with the application of nasal CPAP in preterm infants</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of Topical Lidocaine to Reduce Pain in Preterm Infants Receiving Nasal CPAP Continuous Positive Airway Pressure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Preterm infants admitted to NICUs are exposed to a range of painful procedures. The exposure to pain during this critical of brain development may have adverse consequences. Application of nasal CPAP is one of the painful procedures. A consensus statement on neonatal pain made recommendations for analgesia for neonatal procedures. Topical lidocaine is frequently used as a topical anesthetic during venipuncture, heel lancing, circumcision, endotracheal intubations, nasogastric tube insertion, endoscopy and bronchoscopy. However, the use of topical lidocaine for its analgesic effect on application of nasal CPAP has not been evaluated. This study proposes a randomized controlled trial to evaluate the relative efficacy of topical lidocaine on reducing pain associated with the application of nasal CPAP in preterm infants.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Preterm infants &lt; 37 weeks gestation Admitted to NICU, Mansoura University Children's Hospital Respiratory distress requiring use of nasal CPAP Informed consent obtained Serious, lifethreatening malformations Use of sedation, analgesia in the preceding 72 hours Those who undergo any surgical intervention Those who undergo any painful procedures as venipuncture, intubation, suctioning, blood sampling, heelprick, catheterization 30 minutes before assessment Those with signs of nasal injuries at the time of application of nCPAP Necrotizing enterocolitis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>28 Days</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Topical Lidocaine</keyword>
	<keyword>Nasal CPAP</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Preterm Infants</keyword>
	<keyword>Salivary cortisol</keyword>
</DOC>