<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01864525</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Essential voice tremor is a neurological condition that produces a regular, shaking quality in the voice. One form of drug treatment that produces some improvement in tremor of the hands is octanoic acid, which is a food additive that is similar to alcohol. Research suggests that octanoic acid may reduce tremor in the hands/arms with few side effects and no intoxication effects. This study will determine whether octanoic acid may be useful for reducing tremor when it affects the voice. Researchers are hypothesizing that octanoic acid will reduce the effects of tremor on the voice.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Octanoic Acid for Treatment of Essential Voice Tremor</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: - Essential tremor of the voice produces regular shaking and hoarseness in the voice, making it difficult speech difficult to understand - Several previous studies have found that octanoic acid and octanol, which are related to alcohol, can improve tremor in some people without producing many side effects and without producing intoxication - Researchers are interested in determining whether octanoic acid can improve tremor that affects the voice Objectives: - To determine the effects of octanoic voice using voice recordings and listener ratings of voice - To determine the effects of octanoic acid on level of voice disability experienced by people with essential voice tremor</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tremor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Essential Tremor</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants have a diagnosis of essential voice tremor and show signs of tremor during the endoscopy examination (when pictures of the voice box are obtained)during screening appointment Participants show measurable voice tremor from recordings of the voice during screening appointment Participants have a diagnosis or show signs of Parkinson's Disease or another nonessential tremor movement disorder Participants have a diagnosis or show signs of spasmodic dysphonia (a different neurological voice disorder) Participants have a diagnosis of a severe, nonstable medical condition, such as kidney or liver failure, severe heart disease, severe lung disease, severe metabolic disease, uncontrolled hyperthyroidism, or other lifethreatening disease such as active cancer Participants have a diagnosis of diabetes mellitus Participants are unable to suspend/stop a medication that they are currently taking for tremor or voice disorder for 12 weeks to complete this study Participants have a dependence on alcohol or allergy to alcohol Participants are pregnant or lactating Participants have an allergy to soy Participants have Irritable Bowel Syndrome</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>voice</keyword>
	<keyword>tremor</keyword>
	<keyword>essential tremor</keyword>
	<keyword>essential voice tremor</keyword>
	<keyword>voice treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>octanoic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>octanol</keyword>
	<keyword>voice disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>dysphonia</keyword>
</DOC>