<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01401452</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this post-marketing observational study (PMOS) is the assessment of effectiveness of Adalimumab in moderate to severe Plaque Psoriasis patients with distinct co-morbidities and impact of Adalimumab on the quality of life in routine clinical praxis over the period of 9 month. Psoriasis is associated with several co-morbidities such as depression, obesity and metabolic syndrome. Until now it is unclear if these co-morbidities are due to the pathophysiology of psoriasis or psoriasis-associated behaviors (e.g. smoking and alcohol abuse). Disease severity is correlated with smoking and alcohol abuse. The severity of psoriasis shall be established before and under treatment of Adalimumab by calculation of the Psoriasis Area Severity Index (PASI) and the analysis of Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI) in Patients with at last one co-morbid disease and/or symptom. Also the prevalence of co-morbidities in consideration of gender and other parameters of Life Quality (SF-36) and Life-Quality for specific co-morbidities should be evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Adalimumab in Moderate to Severe Plaque Psoriasis Patients With Distinct Co-morbidities</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients for whom Adalimumab therapy is indicated and has been prescribed according to the product label and who meet the following criteria: Patients age &gt;= 18 years Moderate to severe Plaque Psoriasis patients with at last one comorbid disease and/or symptom such as hypertension, Psoriasis Arthritis confirmed by a rheumatologist, obesity, diabetes, metabolic syndrome or depression. Adalimumab naïve patients with moderate to severe Plaque Psoriasis after unsatisfactory response or non tolerability or contraindication of systemic therapies such as ciclosporin, methotrexate or PUVA ( psoralen + UVA) or after biological disease modifying antirheumatic drugs (BDMARDs) failure (e.g.: infliximab, etanercept or ustekinumab) Patients must fulfill Austrian Treatment Recommendations for use of BDMARD in Psoriasis (Chest Xray and IGRA* interferon gamma release assay or PPDskin test negative for tuberculosis) Patient is willing to consent to data anonymous being collected and provided to Abbott. Patient must be able and willing to selfadminister Adalimumab injections or have a qualified person available to administer Humira® syringe or Humira® Pen injections. The following patients will not be included in this observational study: Patients who meet contraindications as outlined in the latest version of the Humira syringe® Summary of Product Characteristics (SPC) and Humira Pen® SPC. Patients participating in another study program or clinical trial. Patients who have been treated with Humira® before.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Monoclonals</keyword>
	<keyword>Moderate to severe plaque psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Psoriasis Area &amp; Severity Index (PASI)</keyword>
	<keyword>Adalimumab</keyword>
	<keyword>Biological disease modifying anti-rheumatic drugs (BDMARD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Co-morbidities</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibodies</keyword>
	<keyword>Disease Life Quality Index (DLQI)</keyword>
</DOC>