<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02587728</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Carpal tunnel is an early manifestation of amyloidosis in a significant minority of patients. This specimen collection protocol will allow the investigators to screen patients with carpal tunnel syndrome for amyloidosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Carpal Tunnel/Amyloidosis Blood Sample Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators propose to assess a high risk population of patients, those with carpal tunnel syndrome, and systematically assess them for Amyloid Light-chain (AL) amyloidosis and Transthyretin-Related Amyloidosis (ATTR) with simple laboratory blood tests. The combination of serum immunofixation electrophoresis together with serum free light chain (FLC) assay approaches 100% sensitivity for identifying the monoclonal protein underlying the illness in patients with AL amyloidosis. In addition to this, testing for transthyretin gene mutations will allow the investigators to identify patients with ATTR. The investigators believe this simple screening panel (serum immunofixation and serum FLC assay and transthyretin mutation analysis) may allow the investigators to identify patients early in the course of their disease, at which point the investigators can intervene with effective treatment and spare patients a significant amount of morbidity and mortality.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carpal Tunnel Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amyloidosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients with symptoms and signs "highly suggestive of" or consistent with "possible" carpal tunnel syndrome. 2. Patients with electrographic confirmation of median neuropathy at the wrist 3. Age ≥18 years 4. Ability to understand and willingness to sign a written informed consent document. 1. Pregnant women 2. Patients receiving hemodialysis 3. Known amyloidosis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Carpal Tunnel Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Amyloidosis</keyword>
</DOC>