<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00204256</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is the evaluation of the efficacy and safety of intravenous iron sucrose in anemic patients with chronic kidney disease not on renal replacement therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intravenous Iron in Patients With Anemia of Chronic Kidney Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, open label, phase IV study in anemic predialysis patients (Hb between 8 and 11.5 g/dl) who require iron supplementation. The duration of the study for each patient will be approximately 6 months. Patients will be randomized to one of two treatment arms and admitted to the anemia correction phase (days 1-43). Treatment will be intravenous iron sucrose alone versus iron sucrose plus rhEPO. The main treatment evaluation will at the end of the correction phase: The primary end-point will be the change of hemoglobin during correction phase. Secondary end-points will be the change of ferritin and transferrin saturation from baseline to day 43. Safety assessments will include recording of adverse events, vital signs, physical examinations and clinical laboratory tests. Incidence and severity of adverse events will be compared between the two different treatment arms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ferric oxide, saccharated</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronic kidney disease Anemia (Hb 8 11.5 g/dl) Age above 18 years Signed informed consent Rapid progression of kidney disease Need for dialysis Uncontrolled hypertension</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2005</verification_date>
	<keyword>chronic kidney disease</keyword>
	<keyword>anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>intravenous iron</keyword>
	<keyword>recombinant human erythropoetin</keyword>
</DOC>