<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01964885</DOC>
	<brief_summary>IQP-AS-105, is a food supplement derived from garlic (Allium sativum). The objective of this study is to evaluate the possibilities of clinical use of IQP-AS-105 as a preventive medicine, based on its ability to enhance the immune system responses</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Benefit and Tolerability of IQP-AS-105 in Reducing Susceptibility to Upper Respiratory Tract Infections</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Disease Susceptibility</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Common Cold</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age 1870 years increased risk for infections at least 4 cold episodes within 12 months commitment to adhere to their accustomed diet and physical activity women of childbearing potential have to agree to use appropriate birth control methods written consent of the subject to participate is a prerequisite for study participation acute / chronic upper airways disease chronic cough of any origin acute / chronic lower airways disease any allergic reaction that may influence the study outcome (e.g. acute/chronic rhinitis) history of nasal reconstructive surgery presence of nasal ulcers or nasal polyps severe nasal septum deviation or other condition that could cause nasal obstruction congenital or acquired immunodeficiency disease (e.g. HIV infection) severe organ or systemic diseases body temperature above 37.5°C suspected swine flu or influenza vaccination against influenza or swine flu within 3 months prior to study start stomach/gastrointestinal diseases sleep disorder psychiatric disorders known sensitivity to the ingredients of the investigational product intake of products that may influence the study outcome within the last 14 days prior to study start and during the study analgesics , antibiotics or decongestant nose drops/spray, unless they are used as rescue medications pregnancy or nursing alcohol / drug abuse simultaneous participation in another clinical trial or participation in a clinical trial within the last 30 days insufficient compliance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>