<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01964170</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To compare the efficacy and safety of ASP3550 to goserelin acetate in patients with prostate cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Compare the Effect of ASP3550 With Goserelin in Patients With Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study consists of two parts. The purpose of PART 1 is to test non-inferiority of ASP3550 to goserelin acetate with respect to the cumulative castration rate in terms of serum testosterone when ASP3550 or goserelin acetate is administered for one-year in patients with prostate cancer. The patients assigned to receive ASP3550 and completed the treatment in PART 1 are eligible for the treatment in PART 2, and will receive ASP3550 maintenance dose subcutaneously for additional term. The long-term safety, efficacy and PK of the continued ASP3550 treatment will be assessed in PART 2.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Goserelin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male patient with histologically confirmed prostate cancer (adenocarcinoma). Patient in whom endocrine treatment is indicated. Patient having undergoing prostatectomy or radiotherapy with curative intention and has a rising serum PSA (PSA ≥ 2 ng/mL at screening) may be included. Has a serum testosterone level above 2.2 ng/mL at screening. Has an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status (PS) score of 0 to 2 at screening. Has a serum PSA ≥ 2 ng/mL at screening. Has a life expectancy of at least 12 months. Previous or present endocrine treatment for prostate cancer. Example: surgical castration, GnRH agonists, GnRH antagonists, antiandrogens or oestrogens, and 5αreductase inhibitors. Received a 5αreductase inhibitor within 25 weeks preceding screening. Is a candidate for curative therapy, i.e., radical prostatectomy or radiotherapy within 12 months. Has concurrent or a history of poorly controlled severe asthma, anaphylactic reactions, severe urticaria or angioedema. Has hypersensitivity towards mannitol. Has a marked prolongation of QT/QTc interval (two consecutive increases to &gt;450 ms in QTc interval at retest) at screening. Has concurrent or a history of a disease (heart failure, hypokalemia, a family history of QT prolongation syndrome, etc.) that may induce Torsade de Pointes.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ASP3550</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostate cancer</keyword>
</DOC>