<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02926144</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to compare the proportion of tracheal intubations for which more than one person is necessary when using the McGRATH® MAC videolaryngoscope.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Does McGRATH® MAC Videolaryngoscope Decrease the Number of People Required to Perform Intubation During Anesthesia ?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Videolaryngoscopes, such as McGRATH® MAC videolaryngoscope, are used to facilitate tracheal intubations. This study is designed to evaluate the proportion of cases requiring more than one member of the anesthesiology team when the video feature of McGRATH® MAC is available during laryngoscopy in a population of patients without a predicted difficult intubation (Arne's score &lt;11). General anesthesia from induction until tracheal intubation is recorded on a video for further analysis. Analysis includes characteristics of intubation, patient's monitoring and cooperation between anesthesiologists in two groups. In the control group, the screen of the McGRATH® MAC videolaryngoscope is hidden. In the experimental group, the McGRATH® MAC videolaryngoscope is used with its video feature.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Aged 18 years old minimum Requiring general anesthesia and orotracheal intubation with a single lumen tube Having signed an inform consent form Having a telephone and agreeing to communicate their phone number Benefiting from a social insurance scheme or beneficiary Pregnant or breastfeeding women Patients taken care in ambulatory surgery who could not be contacted within 24 hours following surgery Patients having a predicted difficult intubation (Arné's score ≥ 11) or predicted difficult mask ventilation patients requiring a rapidsequence intubation patients for whom general anesthesia using sufentanil, propofol, atracurium or rocuronium is not suitable.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Intratracheal intubation</keyword>
	<keyword>videolaryngoscope</keyword>
	<keyword>McGrath MAC</keyword>
</DOC>