<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01365767</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine how relevant dynamic ultrasound scans using contrast agents (SonoVue) is in the diagnosis of Crohns disease in the small bowel, compared to dynamic Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) of the small bowel.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Contrast Ultrasound of the Small Intestine in Patients With Crohns Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Crohns disease (CD) is a lifelong chronic Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IBD) normally with an early debut. It requires continuous evaluation with either endoscopy, Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI), Computed Tomography (CT) or Wireless Capsule Endoscopy (WCE). These methods are either expensive, invasive or with uses radiation. Therefore UltraSound (US), as a cheap, fast and well tolerated examination of the small bowel are tested against the the validated MRI examination of the small bowel. Both examinations are using intra venous (i.v.) contrast agents. Obtained results are compared to disease activity. Hypothesis is, that dynamic US is comparable to dynamic MRI and therefore should be the first examination of choice in evaluating patients with CD. This study is a pilot study only.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with known Crohns Disease 18 years old or older. Referred to a Magnetic Resonance Imaging scan of the small bowel Contraindications to or not suitable of a Magnetic Resonance Imaging Liver transplant nursing og pregnancy Known Allergy of SonoVue Acute Myocardial infarction &lt; 4 weeks Coronary angiography &lt; 4 weeks Electrocardiogram changes &lt; 4 weeks frequent and repetitive angina pectoris symptoms within the last week. Heartfailure serious arrhythmia right to left heart shunt Very high pulmonary artery pressure uncontrolled hypertension Adult respiratory distress syndrome</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Crohn disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Ultrasonography, contrast enhanced</keyword>
	<keyword>Elasticity Imaging Techniques</keyword>
	<keyword>Small intestine</keyword>
	<keyword>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>CDAI</keyword>
	<keyword>Calprotectin</keyword>
	<keyword>IBD</keyword>
	<keyword>Sonography</keyword>
</DOC>