<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01693367</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the performance of Dynamic Locking Screws (DLS) used to stabilize the shaft component of distal femur fractures in comparison to standard locking screws (SLS). The hypothesis is that DLS will lead to better functional outcomes (WOMAC score) due to increased and more symmetrical callus formation and fewer non-unions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dynamic Locking Screws 5.0 vs. Standard Locking Screws in Fracture of Distal Femur Treated With Locked Plate Fixation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Femoral Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>21 years and older Closed or open distal femur fracture (AO 33 A13, 33 C13) including distal femur fractures above a total knee arthroplasty Ability to walk independently prior to injury Eligible for treatment with ORIF of the distal femur with a large fragment locking plate (LISS, LCP) Willing and able to comply with postoperative protocol and return for followup. Ability to understand the content of the patient information / informed consent form and participate in the clinical investigation Signed informed consent Additional ipsi or contralateral lower extremity fracture Any kind of implant at the ipsilateral proximal femur Preexisting malunion or nonunion of the ipsilateral lower extremity Segmental bone defect requiring bone grafting More than 4 weeks between injury and surgery Pathologic fracture due to a disease other than osteoporosis (eg, tumor, metastasis) Polytrauma Active malignancy Any not medically managed severe systemic disease Recent history of substance abuse (ie, recreational drugs, alcohol) that would preclude reliable assessment Pregnancy or women planning to conceive within the study period Prisoner Participation in any other medical device or medicinal product study within the previous month that could influence the results of the present study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Femoral fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>Periprosthetic fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>Fracture fixation, internal</keyword>
	<keyword>Distal femur fractures</keyword>
	<keyword>Dynamic Locking Screw</keyword>
	<keyword>WOMAC</keyword>
</DOC>