<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03093844</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a study to evaluate the safety and efficacy of Miltenyi CliniMACS® CD34 Reagent System to promote engraftment of haploidentical CD34+ selected cells combined with single unit umbilical cord blood transplant for treatment of high-risk hematologic disorders.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Haploidentical CD34+ Selected Cells Combined With Single Unit Umbilical Cord Blood Transplant for Treatment of High-risk Hematologic Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this clinical protocol, the CliniMACS® CD34 Reagent System will be used for processing hematopoietic progenitor cells collected by apheresis (HPC, Apheresis) from an allogeneic, HLA-haploidentical, related donor to obtain a CD34+ cell-enriched population for hematopoietic reconstitution. The haploidentical donor will be mobilized by G-CSF and undergo one apheresis to collect CD34+ stem cells. The products will be cryopreserved until the time of transplantation. Recipients with hematologic disorders who require transplant will receive a standard conditioning regimen and will receive an allograft on day 0 containing donor CD34+ cells that have been positively selected and T-cell depleted following G-CSF mobilization combined with a single UCB unit.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hematologic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Recipient Eligibility Ages 1880 years inclusive Diagnosed with high risk hematologic disorders warranting stem cell transplant pert institutional standard of care Lack HLAidentical related donor Availability of at least one HLA haploidentical (i.e. greater than or equal to 5/10 and less than or equal to 8/10 HLA match) related donor (HLAA, B, C, DR, and DQ loci) who is available to donate CD34+ cells. Availability of at least one 4/6 HLAmatched (HLAA, B, and DR loci) cord blood unit from the National Marrow Donor Program (NMDP). The cord blood unit must contain a minimum TNC (prior to thawing) of at least 2x107 cells per kilogram of recipient body weight Ability to comprehend the nature of the treatment HLA identical (6/6) related donor available and readily accessible at time of transplantation evaluation Any patient not meeting institutional standard guidelines for transplant eligibility</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Stem Cell Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Umbilical Cord Blood Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Haploidentical CD34+ Selected Cells</keyword>
</DOC>