<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00427622</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Measuring how often hot flashes occur in postmenopausal women may be done by using a skin conduction device or by using a diary. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is comparing a skin conduction device with a hot flash diary as a way of measuring hot flashes in postmenopausal women with hot flashes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Skin Conduction Device for Measuring Hot Flashes in Postmenopausal Women With Hot Flashes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Correlate hot flash frequency, as measured by an ambulatory sternal skin conductance measuring and recording tool, with patient-recorded hot flash frequency using a hot flash diary in postmenopausal women with hot flashes. - Determine the comfort, obtrusiveness, and feasibility of using the skin conductance recording tool for measuring hot flashes when worn daily for five weeks in these patients. OUTLINE: Patients wear an ambulatory sternal skin conductance hot flash device continuously for 5 weeks. Patients complete hot flash diaries once daily for 5 weeks. Patients also complete the Comfort, Bother, and Weight Questionnaire at the end of week 5. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 25 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hot Flashes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of bothersome hot flashes, defined by their occurrence of ≥ 4 times/day Daily hot flashes have been present for ≥ 1 month PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Female Postmenopausal ECOG performance status 01 No history of allergic or other adverse reactions to adhesives No other medical condition known to cause sweating and/or flushing Willing to record hot flashes in a hot flash diary daily for 5 weeks Willing to wear a skin conductance device 24 hours a day for 5 weeks No implanted pacemakers or metal implants No reliance on other electronic devices for regular monitoring (i.e., insulin pumps or blood pressure monitors) PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>hot flashes</keyword>
</DOC>