<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00427934</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate whether maraviroc, an investigational drug given with methotrexate (MTX) is safe and effective in the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis in adult patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Maraviroc in Rheumatoid Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Following a planned interim analysis in the POC component on 21 August 2008 by the internal DMC (Data Monitoring Committee) of study A4001056, the trial was discontinued due to lack of efficacy. All participating investigators/country offices and monitors were notified on 22 August 2008 to cease patient enrollment. The DMC indicated that maraviroc was well tolerated in the Rheumatoid Arthritis patients and there were no safety concerns in the study. The termination date of this trial was 07 October 2008 when the last patient last visit occurred.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Maraviroc</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must be legal age of consent Must have active rheumatoid arthritis based upon the American College of Rheumatology (ACR) 1987 (Revised Criteria); minimum disease criteria required for entry into the efficacy component of the study Must meet ACR 1991 Revised Criteria for Global Functional Status in RA, Class I, II, or III Must be receiving methotrexate for at least 12 weeks duration and on a stable dose for 4 weeks. Diagnosed with any other inflammatory arthritis or a secondary noninflammatory arthritis that would interfere with disease activity assessments. Subject receiving prior treatment with certain medications for rheumatoid arthritis Tuberculosis and/or a positive tuberculin reaction Significant trauma or major surgery within 2 months History of alcohol and/or drug abuse outside of a defined period of abstinence History of or a finding at screening of postural hypotension Any condition that would affect the oral absorption of the drug History of cancer and in remission less than 3 years or Grade IIIIV congestive heart failure Having an infection of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), Hepatitis B or C or evidence of any active infection Abnormalities of clinical or laboratory assessments completed at the screening visit such as elevated liver enzymes, decreased hemoglobin or an abnormal ECG Having a positive chemokine receptor 5 (CCR5) delta 32 mutation Requiring the use of certain medications Lactating or pregnant women or subjects have reproductive potential unwilling to use an adequate method of birth control Chronic or recent serious or lifethreatening infection; severe , progressive and/or uncontrollable renal, hepatic, hematological, gastrointestinal, endocrine, pulmonary, cardiac, neurological disease within 12 weeks of the first dose.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>