<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01939353</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 2 exploratory study being conducted to evaluate the efficacy and safety of EB-1020 SR in treating adult male patients who meet DSM-IV-TR diagnostic criteria for ADHD on the M.I.N.I.-Plus. Evaluations include determining an effectiveness signal for ADHD and related symptoms and exploring dosing, tolerability, onset of action, and duration of effect. Dose-response/tolerability relationships with EB-1020 SR will also be explored. The 1-week placebo lead-in also will be used for informal safety comparison purposes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Exploratory, Single-Blind Pilot Study Of Flexible Doses of the Triple Reuptake Inhibitor EB-1020 SR in the Treatment of Adult Males With Attention-Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This Phase 2, flexible-dosage, single-blind study consists of a Screening Phase (up to 28 days [Visit 1]), a 5-week Treatment Phase (1 week of treatment with placebo [Baseline-1/Visit 2 to Baseline-2/Visit 3] followed by 4 weeks of treatment with EB-1020 SR [Weeks 1 through 4/Visits 4 through 7]), and a 2-week Discontinuation Phase, which starts at the time of Week 4/Visit 7 and includes a Follow-up Visit (Week 6/Visit 7). Approximately 40 patients are planned to enter the treatment period. At Baseline-1, patients must have a score of greater than or equal to 28 on the ADHD-RS-IV to be eligible to continue participation in the study. At the end of single-blind placebo treatment (i.e., Baseline-2), the ADHD-RS-IV with adult prompts is re-administered. Patients who show an improvement greater than or equal to 30% over baseline values or who have a score of less than 28 on the ADHD-RS-IV are withdrawn from the study prior to receiving any active drug. Those who show less than 30% improvement from Baseline-1 to Baseline-2 scores will continue in the study. The consent form will be phrased such that patients are not informed of the exact timing of EB-1020 SR vs. placebo treatment in order to maintain the blinded nature of the placebo treatment and reduce potential placebo effects. Dosing will be flexible, with a target maximum dosage of 500 mg daily in divided doses (morning and afternoon, approximately 5 hours later) to be achieved if possible during Week 2 of EB-1020 SR treatment. The patient will take a starting dose of 100 mg of EB-1020 SR daily; the dose will be titrated in 100 mg increments up to the maximum dosage of 500 mg daily. The treating physician will escalate the dose to the maximum dose if patients have not achieved remission of ADHD in his/her judgment, and EB-1020 SR is still well tolerated. If in the physician's judgment the patient could not tolerate further dose escalation, or is not tolerating the current dose well, the dose may be maintained or reduced, with the goal of re-assessing dose and response at the subsequent visit for a possible increase in dose, until study completion.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed Written Informed Consent 1. Patients must be able to give informed consent, as required by the Institutional Review Board (IRB), prior to the initiation of any procedures required per protocol. Target Population 1. Patients must be able to understand the nature of the study, agree to comply with the prescribed dosage regimens, report for regularly scheduled office visits, and communicate to study personnel about adverse events and concomitant medication use. 2. Patients must meet Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, Fourth Edition, Text Revision (DSMIVTR) diagnostic criteria for ADHD (Combined, Predominantly Inattentive or Predominantly HyperactiveImpulsive Types) on the Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview Plus, Version 6.0 (M.I.N.I.Plus) 3. Patients must have an ADHDRSIV score of greater than or equal to 28 at Baseline1 and Baseline2. 4. Patients must have a CGIS (ADHD version) score of greater than or equal to 4. 5. Patients must be male. 6. Patients must be 18 to 55 years old, inclusive. 7. Patients must be able to read well enough to understand the informed consent form and other patient materials. 8. Patients must be able to be reliably rated on the psychiatric scales required by the protocol based on investigator's judgment. 9. Patients must be able to read and understand English. 10. Patients must have a body mass index (BMI) of approximately 18 to 35 kg/m2. The BMI is to be calculated using the following formula: mass (lb) x 703/(height (in))2. Guidelines for this calculation will be provided to the investigational centers. Sex and Contraceptive Criteria 1. Sexually active, fertile males must use effective birth control if their partners are women of childbearing potential. Adequate birth control methods for both males and females (as appropriate) are defined as those which result in a low failure rate (i.e., less than 1% per year) when used consistently and correctly such as implants, injectable or patch hormonal contraception, oral contraceptives, an IUD, doublebarrier contraception, or true sexual abstinence. The form of birth control for the male and/or partner, where relevant, must be documented at screening and baseline. 2. Women of childbearing potential (if a partner of a male participant) include any female who has experienced menarche and who has not undergone successful surgical sterilization (hysterectomy, bilateral tubal ligation, or bilateral oophorectomy) or is not postmenopausal (defined as amenorrhea greater than or equal to 12 consecutive months); or women on hormone replacement therapy [HRT] with documented serum follicle stimulating hormone [FSH] level greater than 35 mIU/mL. Even women who are using oral contraceptives, other hormonal contraceptives (vaginal products, skin patches, or implanted or injectable products), or mechanical products such as an intrauterine device or barrier methods (diaphragm, condoms, spermicides) to prevent pregnancy, or are practicing abstinence or where the partner is sterile (e.g., vasectomy), should be considered to be of childbearing potential. 1. Patient has a DSMIVTR diagnosis of ADHD not otherwise specified (NOS). 2. Patients rated as having a greater than or equal to 30% improvement in ADHD symptoms or a score of less than 28 on the ADHDRSIV after Week 1 (placebo leadin). Such patients will be withdrawn from the study prior to receiving any active drug. 3. Patient has a current or lifetime history of bipolar disorder or any psychotic disorder as established by M.I.N.I.Plus. 4. Patient has a current history (past 90 days) of major depression, generalized anxiety disorder, obsessivecompulsive disorder, panic disorder or posttraumatic stress disorder as established by the M.I.N.I.Plus. 5. History in the past 20 years of electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) or lifetime history of vagal nerve stimulation or deep brain stimulation for the treatment of depression. 6. Patients with a history of drug or alcohol use disorders (abuse or dependence) must have been free of the diagnosis and of substance use for at least 6 months prior to the Screening visit. 7. Patient has a history of epilepsy, seizures, syncope, unexplained blackout spell(s), head trauma with clinically significant loss of consciousness or noninfantile febrile seizures. 8. Patient has a currently active medical condition (other than ADHD) that, in the opinion of the investigator, could interfere with the ability of the patient to participate in the study safely. 9. Patient has a history of clinically significant, diagnosed cardiovascular disease of any kind, including uncontrolled hypertension. Patient has newly diagnosed cardiovascular disease of any kind in the investigator's judgment. 10. The patient has an IQ less than 80. 11. In the opinion of the investigator, the patient has not derived significant therapeutic benefit from 2 or more ADHD therapies given with an adequate dose and duration in adulthood (age 18 or older); i.e., 1 failed course of treatment is acceptable, but 2 failed courses of treatment are not acceptable. 12. Patient taking medication specifically for treatment of ADHD symptoms (e.g., stimulants, atomoxetine, tricyclic antidepressants, bupropion, modafinil, etc) must be off stimulants for 2 weeks and off nonstimulant ADHD therapies for 3 weeks prior to the Baseline1 Visit and must have returned to the baseline level of ADHD symptoms in the opinion of the investigator. Patients must not have evidence of a discontinuation or withdrawal reaction. 13. Patient is currently taking any antidepressant medication for any condition. 14. Patient is currently taking antipsychotic medication, or an anticonvulsant medication (e.g., phenytoin, carbamazepine, lamotrigine, or valproic acid) at anticonvulsant doses. 15. Patient has a known history of allergy to EB1020. 16. Patient is unwilling to refrain from taking medications that may interfere with the assessment of cognitive function and the assessment of sleep. Examples include benzodiazepines, sedating antihistamines, zolpidem, eszopiclone, and zaleplon. Herbal preparations with effects on the central nervous system also are prohibited throughout the study, (e.g., St. John's Wort or melatonin). 17. Patient has a history of sleep problems in the last 3 months. 18. Patient is unwilling to refrain from taking more than one unit of alcohol within 24 hours of the investigational center visits. 19. Patient is unwilling to restrict caffeine to no more than 500 mg/day (5 cups of coffee). 20. Patient is actively using any drugs with potential for abuse (e.g., marijuana, cocaine, amphetamines) 21. Patient reports passive or active suicidal ideation or intent. 22. Patient is concurrently participating in another clinical research study or investigational drug study or has participated in such a study within the past 1 month. 23. Patient is at high risk of nonadherence to investigational product and the protocol regimen in the investigator's opinion. 24. Patient may not begin psychotherapy during the study, but may continue therapy at the same intensity and frequency, if begun at least 3 months prior to Baseline1 Visit. 2. Exclusion Criteria, Physical and Laboratory Test Findings 1. Patients who have a positive urine drug screen, which cannot be explained by prescribed medications. The urine drug screen may be repeated based on investigator judgment. 2. Patients with clinically significantly abnormal thyroidstimulating hormone (TSH) or a positive result on a standard hepatitis screening panel or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) screen. NOTE: Adequate thyroid replacement for a previously diagnosed thyroid deficiency, which has been stable for 3 months or more, is acceptable. 3. Patients with clinically significant laboratory abnormalities or with clinical laboratory values of potential clinical concern. 4. Diastolic blood pressure greater than 85 mm Hg at Baseline1. 5. Systolic blood pressure greater than 135 mg Hg at Baseline1. 6. Patient has a QT interval of greater than 450 ms on 2 or more ECG tracings taken within 15 minutes, assessed with the patient in a supine position for 3 minutes. Other Exclusion Criteria 1. Prisoners or patients who are involuntarily incarcerated. 2. Patients who have a compulsory detainment for treatment of either a psychiatric or physical illness. 3. Patients who plan to have elective surgeries during the course of the study. 4. Patients with a history of antidepressantinduced hypomania or dysphoria.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Adult ADHD</keyword>
</DOC>