<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01939197</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety and efficacy of ombitasvir/paritaprevir/ritonavir with and without dasabuvir coadministered with and without ribavirin for 12 and 24 weeks in adults with genotype 1 or 4 Chronic Hepatitis C Virus Infection with Human Immunodeficiency Virus, Type 1 coinfection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Two Part, Open-label Study to Evaluate the Safety and Effectiveness of ABT-450/r/ABT-267 or ABT-450/r/ABT-267 and ABT-333 Given With or Without a Drug Called Ribavirin in People With Both Hepatitis C Virus Genotype 1 or 4 Infection and Human Immunodeficiency Virus, Type 1 Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronic HCV infection at Screening defined as: Positive antiHCV Ab at Screening and HCV RNA &gt; 1,000 IU/mL at Screening. Plasma HIV1 RNA &lt;40 copies/mL during Screening using Abbott RealTime HIV1 assay. On a stable qualifying human immunodeficiency virus, type 1 (HIV1) antiretroviral therapy regimen. Positive test result at screening for Hepatitis B surface antigen. Evidence of HCV genotype other than genotype 1 or genotype 4 during screening. Receipt of any other investigational or commercially available antiHCV agents (for example, telaprevir, boceprevir, simeprevir, daclatasvir and ledipasvir) with the exception of interferon (including pegylatedinterferon alfa2a or alfa2b), sofosbuvir and ribavirin. Consideration by the investigator, for any reason, that the subject is an unsuitable candidate to receive ABT450, ABT267, ABT333, ritonavir or ribavirin. Chronic human immunodeficiency virus, type 2 (HIV2) infection.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cirrhotic</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Genotype 4</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C Genotype 1</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Genotype 1</keyword>
	<keyword>Compensated Cirrhosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C Genotype 4</keyword>
	<keyword>Interferon-Free</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV-1</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV / HIV coinfection</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C</keyword>
</DOC>