<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02475577</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will test a hypothesis that the remote monitoring with text and email alerts sent to study subject and optional family/other caregiver (Intervention 1) will have a higher return on investment compared to remote monitoring with nurse researcher follow-up telephone communication to study subject (on Blue alerts) or study subject's healthcare professional (on Red alerts) (Intervention 2) and self-monitoring without intervention (Control).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Determine Return on Investment in Heart Failure Remote Monitoring Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of this remote monitoring study is to evaluate return on investment and end-user clinical outcomes associated with the use of self-monitoring peripherals and tablet/smartphone-based Welch Allyn HealthInterlink technology without intervention (Control), HealthInterlink remote monitoring with text and email alerts sent to study subject and optional family/other caregiver (Intervention 1), and HealthInterlink remote monitoring with nurse research assistant follow-up telephone communication to study subject (on Blue alerts) or study subject's healthcare professional (on Red alerts) (Intervention 2 added to Intervention 1).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Absence of significant vision, hearing, or other communication deficits English speaking; Capable and willing to give informed consent; Participated in the inpatient heart failure class within the last three months. Acceptable candidate for elective, nonemergent, remote monitoring as determined by ordering physician; Living in a private home; Hospital admission for Heart Failure or decompensation in the previous 12 months New York Heart Association (NYHA) classes IIIV, as assigned by the nurse researcher, trained by a cardiologist Cardiac aetiology: ischaemic, idiopathic, hypertensive, or valvular Left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;40% s an index of systolic dysfunction, combined or not with a left ventricular filling pattern supporting the presence of diastolic dysfunction, according to the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Guidelines for chronic heart failure. or NYHA class IIIII who had an ejection fraction &gt;40% and evidence of diastolic left ventricular dysfunction. Optional subject with a diagnosis of diabetes (indicated by HbA1c &gt;7). Currently involved in other investigational clinical trials (unless permission is granted by other study PI); Females who are pregnant, planning to become pregnant within 3 months, or lactating; Requirement for emergent placement other than private home (subject's condition would be compromised if there is a delay in placement). Myocardial infarction, revascularization or Implantable Cardioverter Defibrillator (ICD) implantation in the previous 6 months angina or objective myocardial ischaemia requiring future revascularization implanted ventricular or atrial pacemaker (except dual chamber ICD pacemakers with good sinus activity); Endstage heart failure requiring regular inotropic drug infusions; Chronic renal failure requiring dialysis treatment and Unstable angina.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>telemedicine</keyword>
	<keyword>heart failure</keyword>
	<keyword>home blood pressure monitoring</keyword>
</DOC>