<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00959166</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Subtle changes to the brain, which doctors find difficult to detect through conversation or examination, may occur in patients with HIV and/or hepatitis C infection. It is not currently known whether the brain is affected in early (or acute) hepatitis C. This study plans to evaluate what happens to the brain in patients with HIV and early hepatitis C. The investigators will be comparing 3 groups of individuals: - Group 1: Individuals with HIV infection and acute (early) hepatitis C infection - Group 2: Individuals with HIV infection - Group 3: Healthy volunteers Individuals wishing to take part will complete a series of tests assessing different aspects of their brain including: - 2 brain scans using different technology: - Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) brain scan with spectroscopy - CT PET brain scan - A computer game test which measures brain function - 2 short questionnaires Results of these tests will be analyzed and compared between 3 groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Assess Neuroinflammation and Neurocognitive Function in Patients With Acute Hepatitis C and Chronic HIV Co-Infection - A Positron Emission Tomography (PET) Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coinfection</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. HIV1 antibody positive for at least 12 months 2. Acute HCV (Blood HCV PCR positive with negative PCR within past 8 months) 3. HCV genotype 1 4. Ability to give informed consent 5. Aged &gt; 25 years 6. Male 7. Abbreviated Mental Test Score of at least 8/10 1. Evidence of established cirrhosis or encephalopathy 2. Commencing or any change to HIV medications within 12 weeks 3. Active opportunistic infection 4. Taking antidepressants or any psychoactive medications within past 4 weeks 5. Use of benzodiazepines within past 4 weeks 6. Recent significant head injury 7. Established dementia 8. Alcohol dependence or recreational drug misuse 9. Untreated early syphilis 10. Hepatitis B infection (HBsAg positive) 11. Pregnancy 12. Unable to give informed consent 13. Any contraindication to MR scanning</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute hepatitis C</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurocognitive function</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuroinflammation</keyword>
</DOC>