<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01162122</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present phase III study aims to evaluate the safety and immunogenicity of MF59-adjuvanted subunit seasonal influenza vaccine and to evaluate the consistency in the manufacturing process of three consecutive lots of MF59-adjuvanted subunit seasonal influenza vaccine with respect to immunogenicity in subjects aged 65 years and older. The active comparator non-adjuvanted seasonal influenza vaccine is approved for use in this age group in the United States and will be used to provide a comparative assessment for immunogenicity and safety.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Immunogenicity of MF59C.1 Adjuvanted Trivalent Subunit Influenza Vaccine in Elderly Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>MF59 oil emulsion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and females subjects aged ≥65 years at day of vaccination who are willing and able to comply to study procedures. 1. Individuals with behavioral or cognitive impairment or a psychiatric condition or with a history of any illness that,in the opinion of the investigator, would have interfered with the subject's ability to participate in the study. 2. Individuals who were not able to comprehend and/or follow all required study procedures for the whole period of the study. 3. Known or suspected impairment/alteration of immune function. 4. Individuals with a known bleeding diathesis. 5. History of GuillainBarré syndrome. 6. Individuals with history of allergy to vaccine components and/or a history of any anaphylaxis, serious vaccine reactions or hypersensitivity to influenza viral proteins, egg proteins (including ovalbumin), polymyxin, neomycin, betapropiolactone, thimerosal/ sodium ethylmercurothiosalicylate/ mercury and nonylphenolethoxylate/ nonoxynol9 (spermicide). 7. Receipt of another investigational agent within 30 days prior to enrollment in the study or before completion of the safety followup period in another study. 8. Individuals who had received any other vaccines within 2 weeks for inactivated vaccines or 4 weeks for live vaccines prior to enrollment in this study or who had planned to receive any vaccine within 3 weeks from the study vaccine. 9. Individuals who had received vaccination against seasonal influenza in the previous 6 months. 10. Individuals with oral temperature ≥38.0°C (≥100.4°F) on day of study vaccination. 11. Individuals with history of substance or alcohol abuse within the past 2 years. 12. Individuals providing consent who did not consent to the retention of their serum samples after study completion. 13. Elective surgery or hospitalization planned to occur during the treatment phase or during the followup phase that, according to the opinion of the investigator, might have poses additional risk to the subject. 14. Subjects from whom blood could not be drawn at visit 1.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunogenicity</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Adjuvant</keyword>
	<keyword>Adjuvanted</keyword>
	<keyword>Adjuvants</keyword>
	<keyword>Vaccines</keyword>
</DOC>