<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="7432">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03010176</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1454-001</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2016-003160-40</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03010176</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of MK-1454 Alone or in Combination With Pembrolizumab in Participants With Advanced/Metastatic Solid Tumors or Lymphomas (MK-1454-001)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 1 Open Label, Multicenter Study of MK-1454 Administered by Intratumoral Injection as Monotherapy and in Combination With Pembrolizumab for Patients With Advanced/Metastatic Solid Tumors or Lymphomas</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to identify a maximum tolerated dose (MTD) or maximum
      administered dose (MAD) of MK-1454 alone or MK-1454 in combination with pembrolizumab
      (MK-3475) in participants with advanced/metastatic solid tumors or lymphomas. MK-1454 will
      be administered intratumorally (IT); pembrolizumab will be administered intravenously (IV).
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Participants will receive either MK-1454 monotherapy or MK-1454 in combination with
      pembrolizumab for up to 35 cycles (approximately 2 years). Participants will undergo a
      24-hour observation period following the first dose administration on Cycle 1, Day 1.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 3, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 22, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 22, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>No masking</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Experience a Dose-limiting Toxicity (DLT) Per Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events, Version 4.0 (CTCAE 4.0)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 weeks at each dose level</time_frame>
    <description>DLTs will be assessed during the first cycle of treatment (21 days) and are defined as: Grade 4 non-hematologic toxicity; Grade 4 hematologic toxicity lasting ≥7 days, except thrombocytopenia, Grade 4 thrombocytopenia of any duration, Grade 3 thrombocytopenia (if associated with bleeding); any non-hematologic adverse event (AE) ≥ Grade 3 (with exceptions); any Grade 3 or Grade 4 non-hematologic laboratory abnormality (if medical intervention is required, or the abnormality leads to hospitalization, or the abnormality persists for &gt;1 week); Grade 3 or Grade 4 febrile neutropenia; any toxicity which causes treatment discontinuation or dose delay &gt;7 days between consecutive doses during Cycle 1; any toxicity which causes a &gt;2 week delay in initiation of Cycle 2; Grade 5 toxicity. The percentage of participants who experience a DLT during Cycle 1 will be presented.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Discontinue Study Drug Due to an Adverse Event (AE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>AEs are defined as any unfavourable and unintended sign (including an abnormal laboratory finding, for example), symptom, or disease temporally associated with the use of study treatment or protocol-specified procedure, whether or not considered related to the study treatment or protocol-specified procedure. Any worsening (i.e., any clinically significant adverse change in frequency and/or intensity) of a pre-existing condition that is temporally associated with the use of the study treatment, is also an AE. The percentage of participants who discontinue study treatment due to an AE will be presented.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Plasma Drug Concentration-Time Curve from 0 to 24 hours (AUC0-24h) of MK-1454 When Administered as Monotherapy and as Combination Therapy With Pembrolizumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose and 0.5, 1, 1.5, 3-4, 6-8 and 24 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <description>AUC0-24h is the area under the plasma drug concentration curve during the first 24 hours after study treatment administration. The AUC0-24h of MK-1454 when administered as monotherapy and as combination therapy with pembrolizumab will be presented.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC0-24h of Pembrolizumab When Administered as Combination Therapy With MK-1454</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose and 0.5, 1, 1.5, 3-4, 6-8 and 24 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <description>AUC0-24h is the area under the plasma drug concentration curve during the first 24 hours after study treatment administration. The AUC0-24h of pembrolizumab when administered as combination therapy with MK-1454 will be presented.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MK-1454</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive escalating doses of MK-1454 via IT injection on Days 1, 8 and 15 of each 21-day cycle for Cycles 1, 2 and 3 and then receive MK-1454 via IT injection on Day 1 of each 21-day cycle for Cycle 4 and beyond for up to 35 cycles (approximately 2 years).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MK-1454+Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive escalating doses of MK-1454 via IT injection on Days 1, 8 and 15 of each 21-day cycle for Cycles 1, 2 and 3 PLUS pembrolizumab 200 mg via IV infusion on Day 1 of each 21-day cycle and then receive MK-1454 via IT injection on Day 1 of each 21-day cycle for Cycle 4 and beyond PLUS pembrolizumab 200 mg via IV infusion on Day 1 of each 21-day cycle or up to 35 cycles (approximately 2 years).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MK-1454</intervention_name>
    <description>IT injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>MK-1454</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MK-1454+Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>IV infusion</description>
    <arm_group_label>MK-1454+Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MK-3475</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Has a histologically- or cytologically-confirmed advanced/metastatic solid tumor or
             lymphoma by pathology report and who has received, or been intolerant to, all
             treatment known to confer clinical benefit. Solid tumors and lymphomas of any type
             are eligible for enrollment.

          -  Has stage III or stage IV disease that is not surgically resectable.

          -  Has ≥1 injectable lesion which is amenable to injection and biopsy and is measurable.

          -  Has ≥1 distant, discrete non-injected lesion which is amenable to biopsy.

          -  Has an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status score of 0 or 1.

          -  Has a life expectancy &gt;3 months.

          -  Demonstrates adequate organ function.

          -  Female participants of childbearing potential must be willing to use a highly
             effective method of birth control or be surgically sterile, or abstain from
             heterosexual activity for the course of the study drug through 130 days after last
             dose of study drug. Male participants of reproductive potential must agree to use a
             highly effective method of contraception during sexual contact with females of
             childbearing potential starting with the first dose of study drug through 130 days
             after the last dose of study drug.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Has had chemotherapy, definitive radiation, or biological cancer therapy within 4
             weeks prior to the first dose of study drug, or has not recovered to Baseline or
             CTCAE grade 1 from the adverse events due to cancer therapeutics administered &gt;4
             weeks earlier.

          -  Has participated in a study of an investigational agent and has received study
             therapy or has used an investigational device within 28 days of administration of
             MK-1454.

          -  Is expected to require any other form of antineoplastic therapy while on study.

          -  Is on chronic systemic steroid therapy in excess of replacement doses (prednisone ≤
             10 mg/day is acceptable), or on any other form of immunosuppressive medication.

          -  Has a history of a second malignancy, unless potentially curative treatment has been
             completed, with no evidence of malignancy for 5 years.

          -  Has clinically active central nervous system (CNS) metastases and/or carcinomatous
             meningitis.

          -  Has had a severe hypersensitivity reaction to treatment with a monoclonal antibody
             (mAb).

          -  Has an active autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment in the past 2
             years.

          -  Has a history of vasculitis.

          -  Has a history of (non-infectious) pneumonitis that required steroids or current
             pneumonitis

          -  Has undergone prior allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation within the
             last 5 years.

          -  Has known HIV and/or Hepatitis B or C infection(s).

          -  Is pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father children within the
             projected duration of the study.

          -  Has received a live vaccine within 30 days prior to first dose of study drug.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Toll Free Number</last_name>
    <phone>1-888-577-8839</phone>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount Sinai Hospital ( Site 0002)</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10029</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>646-537-9639</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University ( Site 0003)</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>212-305-3997</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mary Crowley Cancer Research Center. ( Site 0001)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75230</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>214-658-1965</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Gustave Roussy ( Site 0049)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Villejuif</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+33142115592</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chain Sheba Medical Center ( Site 0040)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ramat Gan</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+97235302542</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Royal Marsden Foundation Trust ( Site 0031)</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+442078118311</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Israel</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 3, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 3, 2017</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
