<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01354574</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if consumption of meals containing carbohydrates with different glycemic index (a high glycemic index meal and a low glycemic index meal)have different effects on energy expenditure, type of metabolic fuels used for energy, blood lipids and lipoproteins, and sensations of hunger, fullness, and the hormones related to satiety.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Thermic &amp; Lipemic Properties of Dietary Carbohydrates</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Little is known about the metabolic effects of chronic dieting and weight cycling in humans, but limited evidence suggests that fatty acid oxidation may be depressed leading to periodic elevation of circulating lipids associated with meal ingestion and preferential storage of fat in adipose tissue. With the traditional approach of restrictive dieting failing to result in permanent weight loss and, possibly producing abnormalities in lipid metabolism, it is important to evaluate alternative approaches to achieve a healthy body weight through improved metabolism. In this study the investigators will test the postprandial metabolic effects of standard mixed meals containing carbohydrates with high glycemic index and compare these effects to responses obtained with standard mixed meals, matched for protein and fat content but containing carbohydrates with low glycemic index.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Body mass index between 25 and 30 kg/m2 Having regular menses Willing to refrain from restrictive dieting during the course of the study Pregnant or currently planning a pregnancy Cigarette smoking Taking medications to induce weight loss or change appetite History of cardiovascular disease History of metabolic disorders, including diabetes</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>48 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>energy metabolism</keyword>
	<keyword>lipids</keyword>
	<keyword>lipoproteins</keyword>
	<keyword>satiety</keyword>
	<keyword>glycemic load</keyword>
	<keyword>insulin</keyword>
</DOC>