<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02858986</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Introduction: Three-dimensional key-hole surgery ('laparoscopic') systems are proven to reduce the time required to complete tasks in laboratory settings. This benefit derives from the addition of binocular depth perception cues when compared to two-dimensional (2D) systems. This year a '4K' laparoscopic system has become commercially available, so-named as it provides a high resolution 2D image with four times the number of pixels of 2D full high definition. The improved visualisation is likely to provide additional non-binocular depth cues. It is currently unclear to what degree improving the resolution of 2D systems can compensate for binocular depth cues. Aim: To determine whether the binocular vision provided by 3D laparoscopic systems provides benefits in simulated tasks when compared to the monocular vision provided by high-resolution 4K systems. Methods: Two experiments will be performed: 1) A laboratory assessment of 3D versus 4K laparoscopic systems against industry optical standards, 2) A study to assess the benefits to novices and expert surgeons of using 3D and 4K laparoscopic systems during laparoscopic simulator tasks. The primary outcome measure is number of errors during laparoscopic simulator tasks. The secondary outcome measures include: objective and subjective measures of picture quality, task completion time, side effects (such as eye discomfort) and cognitive workload during laparoscopic simulator tasks Impact: This study is a unique, first-of-its-kind investigation into two new surgical technologies, and is the first study to involve a 4K system. The uptake of three-dimensional systems has been curbed by financial cost and the limitations of early 3D technologies. This study aims to determine which system may be the safest, quickest and most cost- effective, in order to guide future investment and technological development towards either 3D or 2D systems. In addition, these systems may also aid in the learning curve of trainee surgeons.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>3D Versus 4K Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Gallstones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecystitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acalculous Cholecystitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Informed, written consent obtained after provision of information leaflets and facetoface answering of any questions participants may have 2. Elective laparoscopic cholecystectomy 3. Medically fit for discharge as day case 4. Age 18 to 85 years 1. Unable to obtain informed, written consent 2. Emergency cholecystectomy 3. Not medically fit for discharge as day case 4. Age &lt;18 or &gt;85 years 5. Conversion to open cholecystectomy 6. History of upper abdominal surgery 7. Recent/current involvement in another clinical trial 8. Common bile duct exploration at time of operation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>