<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02041663</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Use of brain natriuretic peptide to evaluate the cardiac function in the course of meningococcal septic shock or severe sepsis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Septic cArdiac Deficiency and MenIngococcal seveRe Sepsis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: determining sensibility and specificity of BNP blood level to detect myocardial dysfunction in septic shock or severe sepsis due to Neisseria meningitidis in children. METHODS: Prospective multicentric clinical trial including 7 French pediatric intensive care units. Serial cardiac ultra sounds and blood sampling will be done for patients hospitalized for purpura fulminans beginning at the time of admission in pediatric intensive care. Any child from 6 months to 18 years without preexisting cardiac disease and presenting with purpura fulminans will be enrolled after obtaining consent of both parents. From adult's studies on septic shock and BNP, a total number of 30 patients was calculated to be necessary to prove the interest of BNP in this indication.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sepsis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Toxemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Shock, Septic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Meningococcal Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Natriuretic Peptide, Brain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children 6 months to 18 years aged without previous cardiac pathology hospitalized in the participating pediatric intensive care units for serious sepsis with extensive purpura Heart malformative disorder with rightleft shunt Preexistent known cardiac insufficiency whatever is the origin Concomitant participation in another trial Patient in period of exclusion from another trial Not membership in a national insurance scheme</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>brain natriuretic peptide</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiac function</keyword>
	<keyword>meningococcal infections</keyword>
	<keyword>septic shock</keyword>
	<keyword>severe sepsis</keyword>
</DOC>