<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01663155</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators would like to see if lung cancer screening with chest x-rays,computer aided detection (CAD)and a lose dose CT scan can detect lung cancer in early stages when it is more responsive to treatment. The investigators would also like to see if early detection will reduce the incidence of symptomatic advanced lung cancer compared to no screening in former and current smokers with or without a family history of lung cancer who are 40-75 years old.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chest Imaging, Breath, and Biomarkers in a Screening Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The fight against lung cancer is waged on three major fronts: prevention, detection and treatment. Our goal is to determine if chest x-rays,computer aided detection (CAD)and a CT scan can detect disease earlier when treatment is more effective. If we improve the detection of disease, we will see if screening reduces the incidence of symptomatic advanced lung cancer relative to no screening in people at high risk to develop lung cancer.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>ages 4075 years If ages 4059, then one of the following criteria needs to be met: Current or exsmoker with &gt;25 pack years and a family history of lung cancer(parent or sibling) OR current or exsmoker with &gt; 25 pack years and COPD OR current or exsmoker with a &gt; 35 pack year history If ages 6075, then one of the following additional criteria needs to be met: Current or exsmoker with &gt;25 pack years and a family history of lung cancer (parent or sibling) OR Current or exsmoker with &gt;25 pack years and COPD OR Current or exsmoker with a &gt;30 pack year history Subject is able to return to Cleveland Clinic for annual followup screening Subject is willing to sign a medical release form Current health requires oxygen Have had a chest xray or CT of the chest within the last 6 months Previous pneumonectomy Lobectomy of the lung within the last 5 years Diagnosed malignancy within the last 5 years, excluding nonmelanoma skin cancer, carcinoma in situ of the cervix and localized prostate cancer A medical condition that would prevent treatment for lung cancer Within the last 6 weeks, one of the following has occured: A new cough or chronic cough that has gotten worse Either new shortness of breath, or any worsening of shortness of breath A cough producing blood Constant chest pain Respiratory infection, pneumonia, or cold Unintentional and unexplained weight loss greater than 5% of total body weight</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>chest x-ray</keyword>
	<keyword>CT scan</keyword>
	<keyword>computer aided detection (CAD)</keyword>
	<keyword>screening</keyword>
	<keyword>smokers</keyword>
</DOC>