<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02174549</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase 1 study is to determine the optimal dose and tolerability of a hypoxia-activating agent, tirapazamine, when it is combined with embolization in liver cancer. Liver cancer patients who are Child-Pugh score A, suitable for embolization with tumor no more than 4 nodules are eligible. Tirapazamine will be given by intravenous infusion in the first two cohorts and then switched to intra-arterial injection before embolization in subsequent cohorts. Treatment effect is evaluated by MRI based on modified RECIST criteria. Repeat treatment is necessary only if disease progression. Each patient is allowed to have up to 6 treatments in a 18-month period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose-defining Study of Tirapazamine Combined With Embolization in Liver Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is a 3+3 design for dose escalation. Each cohort will have 3-6 patients based on tolerability. Patients will receive escalated doses of tirapazamine until maximally tolerated dose. Embolization is performed per standard practice using Lipiodol and Gelfoam under X-ray guidance. Once a suitable dose is determined, an expansion cohort of 15 patients will be treated with the recommended phase 2 dose to determine preliminary efficacy. Depending on the dose escalation, there will be 23-63 patients enrolled in the study. All patients will be admitted into hospital on the day before embolization, and post-treatment observation will be done in hospital until their liver function tests show improvement before they are discharged from hospital. Adverse events are evaluated by CTCAE vs. 4.0 and efficacy is evaluated by MRI using modified RECIST criteria.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tirapazamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed diagnosis of HCC &gt; 10 mm with a characteristic 4phase CT or dynamic contrast enhanced MRI finding showing intense arterial uptake followed by "washout" of contrast in the venousdelayed phases per American Association for the Study of Liver Disease (AASLD) criteria. Patients between ages 20 and 75 Patients with single or multiple (24 nodules) HCC who are unsuitable or unwilling for surgical resection or RFA. The largest tumor nodule should be less than 10 cm in the largest diameter. The total volume of tumor cannot exceed 50% of liver Patients are candidates for TAE or Transarterial ChemoEmbolization (TACE). No tumor invasion to portal vein or thrombosis in portal vein. Patients have no lymph node involvement or distant metastasis. ECOG score 01 with no known cardiac, pulmonary or renal dysfunction ChildPugh score group A liver functional score Patients should have measurable disease by contrast MRI. Prior local therapies such as surgical resection, radiofrequency ablation, or alcohol injection are allowed as long as tumor progresses from the prior treatment and the patients are still candidates for TAE. All prior therapy must be at least 4 weeks prior to enrollment and free from treatmentrelated toxicity. Patients have normal organ function: ANC ≥ 1500 /µL, Hemoglobin ≥ 9 gm/dL, Platelets ≥ 75,000 /µL, Creatinine ≤ 2 mg/dL, AST and ALT &lt; 5 X upper normal limit of the current institution; bilirubin &lt; 2.0 mg/dL, PT prolongation no more than 4 sec above upper limit of normal Patients are able to understand and willing to sign the informed consent. Men and women of childbearing age need to commit to using two methods of contraception simultaneously to avoid pregnancy. Patients who have had a liver transplantation Patients with HCC lesions whose feeding artery cannot be identified in arteriogram before injection of study medication will be excluded during the embolization procedure. Patients who have major medical problems such as cardiac, pulmonary (COPD requiring constant oxygen), renal (creatinine over 2.0) diseases, active infectious diseases (except chronic Hepatitis B or C), or nonhealing ulceration Patients who have uncontrolled hepatitis B or C with a high viral DAN or RNA titer over 3 X ULN should be treated before enrolled into the study. Patients who are on HBV or HCV medications before enrollment into the study should hold medication on Day 1 and resume prior medications after day 2. Patients who have any clinical evidence of hypoxia with O2 saturation less than 92% without oxygen. Patients with evidence of arterial insufficiency or microangiopathy in any organ due to any reason, such as diabetes, which could lead to distal extremity hypoxia, as evidenced by any gangrenous change in distal limbs or requiring resection for this reason. Patients on interferon treatment, but eligible after a washout period of 4 weeks. Patients with known HIV infection Patients with major gastrointestinal bleeding in the prior 2 months of enrollment. Patient on chronic anticoagulation therapy that is considered a risk for any invasive procedure such as TAE. Patients with known diagnosis of cancer other than HCC, unless the cancer is considered cured by the treating physician due to no evidence of recurrence for more than 5 years, or localized and resected earlystage cancer such as basal cell carcinoma, resected early stage prostate cancer, superficial melanoma, breast ductal carcinoma in situ, without evidence for recurrence for more than a year. The impact of tirapazamine on pregnant or lactating women has not been investigated. Patients who are pregnant or lactating are not allowed in this study Patients with QTc interval &gt; 470 msec or those known to have congenital long QTc syndrome. Patients who take any medication that is known to prolong the QT interval and/or are associated with a risk of Torsades de Pointes within 7 days prior to the first dose. Patients on antiplatelet agents such as aspirin, nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) or other platelet inhibitors such as clopidogrel, vorapaxar, and dipyridamole will need to have a washout period of 7 days before embolization.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hypoxia</keyword>
	<keyword>Embolization</keyword>
	<keyword>Tirapazamine</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatocellular carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>