<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01749176</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Randomized controlled trial testing the efficacy of a text messaging intervention in a low income, low health literacy group of Latino patients. Project Dulce 2.0 (PD 2.0) will address barriers to participation in health education classes, increasing adherence to treatment and medications and improving diabetes self management behaviors and skills. Two community clinic organizations that provide services to a large proportion of Latino patients with type 2 diabetes will participate to randomize 200 patients into one of 2 arms: standard diabetes management care (control) only or text messaging and standard care. Comparisons between groups will evaluate clinical, behavioral and psychosocial outcomes. Intervention: Standard Care and Text Messaging. All participants will receive standard diabetes care provided by primary care providers at the clinic. Of the 100 that are randomized to the intervention arm will be given instructions on how the text messaging component will be addressed throughout the duration of the study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dulce Digital-Project Dulce 2.0 Texting Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Ages 1875, Type 2 DM, Enrolled at community health center, Latino ethnicity, non Project Dulce participant, HbA1c&gt;/= 8%, must be able to read Have a severe illness precluding frequent visits to the clinic, have a severe medical condition, poor mental function or any other reason to expect patient difficulty in complying with the requirements of the study, any history of malignancy, except subjects who have been diseasefree for &gt;10 years, or whose only malignancy has been basal or squamous cell skin carcinoma, patients who have a creatinine level greater than 3.5, any history of drug or alcohol abuse within 12 months prior to the study, those who are not a permanent resident in the area. Patients who are not willing to use a cell phone with texting capability.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>High risk Latino patients with diabetes</keyword>
</DOC>