<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02989948</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A prospective, single-arm, traditional feasibility study of a physician-modified fenestrated Cook Zenith TX2 aortic endograft base device in adult patients meeting traditional size criteria for open surgical treatment of thoracoabdominal aortic aneurysms. Patients meriting surgical treatment of their aneurysm that also meet inclusion and exclusion criteria will be eligible for enrollment. Patients will be followed for 5 years post procedure. Major adverse events will also be recorded by the Sponsor-Investigator and will be monitored by a locally appointed Data Monitoring Committee, the Colorado Multiple Institutional Review Board, and the FDA.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physician-Modified Fenestrated and Branched Aortic Endografting for TAAA</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aortic Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aortic Aneurysm, Thoracic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Must be a man or woman 50 years of age or older by the date of informed consent. 2. Must have a thoracoabdominal aortic aneurysm of any Crawford classification (extent IV) that extends no more proximal than the left subclavian artery. 3. Must have an aneurysm size that meets standard indications for surgical repair (6.0 cm in maximum diameter in the descending thoracic aorta, or 5.5 cm in maximum diameter in the abdominal aorta). 4. Must be considered, in the judgment of the SI, to be a high risk candidate for open surgical repair. 5. Must not be a candidate for repair under the Instructions for Use of a commercially available, FDAapproved endovascular graft. 6. Patient or their LAR must be able to provide informed consent. 7. Must be able to comply with the five year study assessment schedule of events. 8. Must have a nonaneurysmrelated life expectancy, in the judgment of the SI, of greater than 2 years. 1. Aneurysm due to acute or chronic dissection, intramural hematoma, penetrating aortic ulceration, pseudoaneurysm, mycotic aneurysm, or traumatic transection. 2. Ruptured or acutely symptomatic aortic aneurysm. 3. Known connective tissue disorder. 4. Imaging demonstrating any of the following: Lack of 20 mm nonaneurysmal proximal seal zone (zone 3, or zone 2 with a carotidsubclavian bypass or transposition). Lack of 15 mm nonaneurysmal distal seal zone(s) (aortic, common iliac, or external iliac). Branch vessel target (renal, superior mesenteric, or celiac) &lt; 5 mm or &gt; 10 mm in average diameter. Untreated left subclavian artery stenosis or occlusion. Untreated unilateral or bilateral hypogastric artery occlusion. Signs that the inferior mesenteric artery is indispensable. Have branching, duplication, aneurysm, or untreatable stenosis of the celiac, superior mesenteric artery, or renal arteries that would preclude implantation of the investigational devices. 5. Known allergy to stainless steel or polyester. 6. History of anaphylaxis to contrast, with inability to prophylax appropriately. 7. Have uncorrectable coagulopathy. 8. Have unstable angina. 9. Have a body habitus that would inhibit Xray visualization of the aorta. 10. Have a major surgical or interventional procedure unrelated to the treatment of the aneurysm planned ≤30 days of the endovascular repair. 11. Known to be participating in any other clinical study which may affect performance of this device. 12. Known or visible pregnancy. 13. Contraindication to oral antiplatelet therapy. 14. Prisoners or those on alternative sentencing. 15. Known systemic infection with potential for endovascular graft infection. 16. Anticipated need for MRI scanning within 3 months of insertion of investigational product. 17. Other conditions or comorbidities that, in the opinion of the SponsorInvestigator, would exclude the patient.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>95 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Endovascular</keyword>
</DOC>