<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02989844</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multi-center, phase II clinical trial to prevent relapse using interleukin-15 (IL-15) super-agonist complex (ALT-803) maintenance after allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation (alloHCT) in acute myelogenous leukemia (AML) and myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>QUILT-3.035: Relapse Prophylaxis With ALT-803 for AML and MDS Pts Following Allo HSCT</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosis of acute myelogenous leukemia (AML) or myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS) for whom an allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplant using a reduced intensity conditioning is planned or has been performed and patient is prior to day 100 posttransplant. 2. Able to begin study treatment between day +60 and day +100 after the transplant and meets the following transplant related requirements: Sustained neutrophil (ANC &gt; 1000/mcL) and platelet (&gt; 30,000/mcL) engraftment &gt;50% donor chimerism in blood or bone marrow No evidence of recurrent disease on most recent bone marrow evaluation (day 21 or 28 posttransplant is acceptable) No morphologic evidence of relapse (&lt; 5% bone marrow blasts) Ability to be treated in the outpatient setting (not an inpatient) 3. No signs or symptoms of acute graft versus host disease; however prior acute GVHD which is resolved and controlled with low dose steroids (&lt; 0.3 mg/kg/day for at least 1 week) may be eligible. 4. One of following donor graft sources: Group 1: sibling donor Group 2: haploidentical donor [with posttransplant cyclophosphamide] Group 3: unrelated donor Group 4: unrelated umbilical cord blood 5. Karnofsky performance status ≥ 70% 6. Adequate organ function within 14 days of study enrollment defined as: Renal: serum creatinine: ≤ 2.0 mg/dL Hepatic: SGOT or SGPT &lt; 3 x upper limit of institutional normal (ULN) 7. Sexually active females of child bearing potential and males with partners of child bearing potential must agree to use effective contraception during therapy and for 4 months after completion of therapy. 8. Voluntary written consent prior to the performance of any research related procedures 1. Pregnant or breastfeeding ALT803 is an investigational agent. Women of child bearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test at screening. 2. Class II or greater New York Heart Association Functional Classification criteria or serious cardiac arrhythmias likely to increase the risk of cardiac complications of cytokine therapy (e.g. ventricular tachycardia, frequent ventricular ectopy, or supraventricular tachyarrhythmia requiring chronic therapy) 3. Marked baseline prolongation of QT/QTc interval (e.g. demonstration of a QTc interval greater than 500 milliseconds) 4. Active uncontrolled bacterial, fungal, or viral infections all prior infections must have resolved following optimal therapy. 5. Active autoimmune disease requiring immunosuppressive therapy 6. History of severe asthma and currently on chronic medications (mild asthma requiring inhaled steroids only is eligible) 7. Received any investigational agent within the 14 days before the start of study treatment (1st dose of ALT803)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>