<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01507493</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study was conducted to explore whether the non-synonymous single-nucleotide polymorphisms in SCN9A gene can predict individual basal pain perception and postoperative pain intensity in the general population undergoing upper abdominal surgery. Methods: Patients receiving elective upper abdominal surgery under general anesthesia were recruited into this study. Genotyping of SCN9A was carried out by direct sequencing. The investigators measured their preoperative pressure pain threshold (PPT) and pressure pain tolerance (PTO). The visual analog scale (VAS) was used for pain evaluation at rest during patient-controlled analgesia (PCA) treatment 0 h, 12 h ,24 h and 48h after operation. And the PCA press frequency and drug consumption were recorded.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Impact of SCN9A Gene Polymorphism on Individual Pain Perception in the General Population</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with the following diseases were excluded: known history of chronic pain, psychiatric diseases or communication disorders, diabetes mellitus, severe cardiovascular diseases, kidney or liver diseases with poor hepatic function, alcohol or drug abuse, heavy smoker, pregnancy or at the lactation period.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Aged 2070 years Receiving elective upper abdominal surgery Anesthesiologists (ASA) physical status I or II Received PCA administration Agreed to participate the research History of chronic pain Psychiatric diseases Diabetes mellitus Severe cardiovascular diseases Kidney or liver diseases Alcohol or drug abuse Heavy smoker Pregnancy or at lactation period Refused PCA administration Disagree to participate to the research</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>gene polymorphism</keyword>
	<keyword>SCN9A</keyword>
	<keyword>pain perception</keyword>
	<keyword>postoperative pain</keyword>
</DOC>