<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01507597</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Diabetes(both types) are recognized by high levels of glucagon in the circulation. Glucagon is known to increase blood glucose, and might therefore contribute to the respective diseases. Under some circumstances the gut hormone GLP-1 inhibits the glucagon secretion. The investigators aim to identify the impact of GLP-1 on the glucagon secretion, at increasing blood glucose levels in healthy subjects, in patients with type 2 diabetes, and in patients with type 1 diabetes. The investigators think that the effect of GLP-1 on the glucagon secretion might be dependent of blood glucose levels.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of GLP-1 on the Inhibition of Glucagon Secretion</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon-Like Peptide 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with T2DM Above the age of 35 years, treatment with diet or oral antidiabetic medication. Diagnosed with T2DM in at leat three months in advance(WHO criterion) Normal hemoglobin Informed content Patients with T1DM T1DM (WHO criterion) PlasmaCpeptid negative due to arginintest Normal hemoglobin age&gt; 18 years Informed content Healthy subjects Normal fasting plasma glucose and normal glucose tolerance (WHO criterion) Normal hemoglobin Age &gt;18 years Informed content Patients with T2DM Treatment with glitazones and/or gliptins Inflammatory bowels disease previous bowel resection with or without stomy Nephropathy (serum creatinin &gt;150 µM and/or albuminuria) Liver disease (serum alanineaminotransferase (ALAT) and/or serum aspartateaminotransferase (ASAT) &gt;2×normal values) Medical treatment impossible to break for 12h. Age &gt;80 years Patients with T1DM Overweight (BMI &gt;30 kg/m2) Inflammatory bowels disease previous bowel resection with or without stomy Nephropathy (serum creatinin &gt;150 µM and/or albuminuria) Liver disease (serum alanineaminotransferase (ALAT) and/or serum aspartateaminotransferase (ASAT) &gt;2×normal values) Medical treatment impossible to break for 12h (except treatment with insulin). Age &gt;80 years Healthy subjects Diabetes Prediabetes (impaired glucose tolerance and/or impaired fasting plasma glucose) First order relatives with diabetes Overweight (BMI &gt;30 kg/m2) Inflammatory bowels disease previous bowel resection with or without stomy Nephropathy (serum creatinin &gt;150 µM and/or albuminuria) Liver disease (serum alanineaminotransferase (ALAT) and/or serum aspartateaminotransferase (ASAT) &gt;2×normal values) Medical treatment impossible to break for 12h. Age &gt;80 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Glucagon-like peptide-1</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucagon</keyword>
	<keyword>Normal physiology</keyword>
	<keyword>T2DM</keyword>
	<keyword>T1DM</keyword>
</DOC>