<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="18160">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02870478</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IND 128961</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02870478</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effects of Low Concentration Atropine on Pupil Size and Accommodation</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Study of Time and Dose-dependent Effect of Low Concentration Atropine on Accommodation and Pupil Size</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, Berkeley</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Berkeley</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether less frequent dosing of atropine drops may
      be as effective as daily dosing for the treatment of progressive myopia.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Myopia has become an epidemic in developed countries, particularly in Asian countries and in
      the United States. Myopia, or near-sightedness, is a result of uncontrolled axial elongation
      of the eye. Besides needing optical correction in order to see clearly, myopia can result in
      many sight-threatening complications, such as retinal thinning, retinal holes and tears,
      retinal detachment, and vascular proliferation. Atropine drops have been used in clinical
      practice for over 100 years at varying concentrations and different dosing regimens. The
      proposed small study seeks to establish evidence-based treatment (dosing) guidelines for the
      use of low dose atropine for myopia control.

      The specific objectives of this study are:

        1. To assess the effects of 0.01% atropine and 0.05% atropine on pupil dilation and
           accommodation as a measure of active drug levels in the eye when dosed twice per week
           compared to daily

        2. To assess the subjective effects of 0.01% atropine and 0.05% atropine on the subjects'
           vision

      Participants will be asked to attend one screening session and a total of 8 test sessions.
      Following the screening exam (information will be collected on the screening form), the
      subject will be randomly assigned to one of four atropine treatment groups, where they will
      treat their non-dominant eye with:

        1. 0.01% daily dosing for one week

        2. 0.01% twice per week dosing for one week

        3. 0.05% daily dosing for one week

        4. 0.05% twice per week dosing for one week

      Once assigned to a treatment group, each subject will have two medication bottles to use,
      labeled A and B. The subjects will use bottle A to administer a drop on Monday and Thursday.
      Bottle B will be used to administer a drop every other day of the week to their non-dominant
      eye only. For subjects in treatment groups 1 and 3, the medication in each bottle will be
      identical. For subjects in treatment groups 2 and 4, the medication will be in bottle A and
      bottle B will be sterile saline. The investigator will review with each subject how to
      instill the medication properly when they are at home by themselves.

      Test sessions (expected to be no more than 30 mins in length) will be held twice per week
      during the testing period and scheduled at the subject's convenience. Session measurements
      will include best-corrected visual acuity, subjective amplitude of accommodation, objective
      amplitude of accommodation, and pupil size, as described previously (see screening section
      7b). An anterior segment slit lamp biomicroscopy exam will also be performed to ensure good
      ocular health. The subject will also be asked to fill out a brief symptom questionnaire
      (attached) while they are present for the test session. Information will be recorded on the
      data collection sheet for this portion of the testing.

      Once the subject has completed the two week period (total of four sessions) for that
      treatment group, the subject will be released from testing for a &quot;wash out period&quot; of 1-2
      weeks. At the first day of the wash out period, measurements of pupil size and accommodation
      will be taken prior to the instillation of a single dose of 0.01% or 0.05% atropine, and
      then at 1min, 5 min, 30 min, 1hr, 2hr, 4hr, and 8hr post-instillation. The subject will
      undergo a total of 2 full-day test sessions either after the two 0.01% testing periods or
      the 0.05% testing periods, but not both.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>Single Blind (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in pupil size at 1 week</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at baseline and again 1 week after first using drop</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Myopia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>0.01% atropine daily</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nightly dosing of 0.01% atropine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>0.01% atropine twice per week</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Atropine dosed twice per week</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>0.05% atropine daily</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Atropine dosed daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>0.05% atropine twice per week</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Atropine dosed twice per week</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Atropine</intervention_name>
    <description>Dosing frequency comparison, using atropine sulfate 1% solution diluted to 0.01% and 0.05% by Leiter's Compounding Pharmacy</description>
    <arm_group_label>0.01% atropine daily</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>0.01% atropine twice per week</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>0.05% atropine daily</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>0.05% atropine twice per week</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>atropine sulfate ophthalmic solution</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Participants must have vision that is correctable to 20/20 in each eye

          -  Participants must also have normal binocular vision (no history of manifest eye turns
             or eye surgeries to correct an eye turn)

          -  Participants must have normal accommodation (amplitude and facility within a normal
             range based on the subject's age)

          -  Participants must have normal ocular health

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Previous chronic use of atropine

          -  Participants who are pregnant, plan to become pregnant, or are breastfeeding

          -  Sensitivity or allergy to atropine
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Maria Liu, OD, MPH, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UC Berkeley</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Maria Liu, OD, MPH, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(510)642-1457</phone>
    <email>marialiu75@berkeley.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UC Berkeley, Department of Vision Science</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berkeley</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94720-2020</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maria Liu, OD, MPH, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>510-642-1457</phone>
      <email>marialiu75@berkeley.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>August 16, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 27, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Atropine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
