<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00350896</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The prevalence of digital osteoarthritis varies according to whether a radiological or clinical definition is adopted. Interventions: Thumb orthoses to be worn at night and usual care vs usual care. Outcome measures: Pain at 1 month assessed on visual analog scale is the main outcome measure. Disability at 6 months (Cochin Hand Function Scale) and deformation at 1 year are the main secondary outcome measures.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of Thumb Orthoses in Osteoarthritis in the Base of the Thumb (BTOA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The prevalence of digital osteoarthritis varies according to whether a radiological or clinical definition is adopted. Radiologically defined osteoarthritis of the hand has been estimated to represent 38% of women and 24.5% of men over 66 years of age but higher prevalence of 60-70% has also been reported. Of patients with radiological signs, 20 to 40% become symptomatic. For patients over 55 years of age, the distal interphalangeal joints are the most prevalent site of osteoarthritis (20%) determined radiologically and clinically, followed by the base of the thumb (8%) and proximal interphalangeal joints (5%). This prevalence increases with age, and the incidence peaks in perimenopausal women. Osteoarthritis in the base of the thumb (BTOA) concerns the trapeziometacarpal joint, with a possible secondary location at the trapezotrapezoidial and scaphotrapezial joints. BTOA induces a closure of the first web, which in turn causes an alteration of the thumb-index pinch and therefore a limitation in hand function. Pain induced by the compression of the thumb column during pinching could also lead to functional disability. Effect of a simple intervention such as wearing rest thumb orthoses on pain and disability is unknown.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pain at the base of the thumb 30 mm on VAS Patient aged 45 and &lt; 75 years old At least 2 of the 5 items on the trapeziometacarpal joint radiograph osteophytes joint space narrowing subchondral bone sclerosis subchondral cysts At least 1 of the 2 clinical items trapeziometacarpal joint enlargement closure of the first web Post traumatic osteoarthritis Cristal arthropathy Inflammatory arthritis Neurologic disorder involving upper limb Psychiatric disorder needing treatment adaptation in the last 3 months Hand or wrist trauma within the last 2 months Previous hand surgery Unable to speak or write French Pregnancy Collagen diseases (Dupuytren, Marfan, Ehlers Danlos syndromes) Hand or wrist infiltration within 2 months Skin disease interfering with the wearing of the orthoses Having already worn a BTOA orthoses Having bilateral BTOA without predominant symptomatic side</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>trapezotrapezoidial</keyword>
	<keyword>scaphotrapezial</keyword>
	<keyword>thumb</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>orthoses</keyword>
	<keyword>Osteoarthritis in the BTOA concerns the trapezometacarpal joint</keyword>
</DOC>