<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00533624</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The comparison the incidence of G.I. toxicity between Myfortic® vs. Cellcept® in 150 sequential patients, in which 75 will be randomized to Cellcept® and 75 to Myfortic® in first and second living or deceased donor renal transplant recipients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Myfortic vs. Cellcept in Kidney Transplant Recipients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Purpose and Description: The purpose of the study is to determine if gastrointestinal toxicity of an anti-rejection medication Myfortic® (mycophenolic acid delayed release) is less than equivalent doses of a similar anti-rejection medication Cellcept® (mycophenolate mofetil, MMF) in patients receiving their first or second kidney transplant from cadaver or living donors. This study consist of two randomized groups, 75 patients given 3 doses of Thymoglobullin (Group I) vs. 75 patients given 3 doses of Thymoglobulin and 2 doses of Basiliximab (Group II). Our standard maintenance protocol dosing of tacrolimus, IMPDH inhibitor (vide infra) and one week course of corticosteroids. Patients will be randomized to receive Myfortic® 1,440 mg/day vs. Cellcept® 2,000 mg/day, each in two divided doses (induced with either the IL-2 receptor inhibitors or thymoglobulin). Tacrolimus will be dosed to 12-hour trough levels of 8-10 ng/ml. Methylprednisolone is to be given as per our center protocols, weaning to dose levels of &lt;0.1 mg/kg by 3-6 months post-operatively.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patient has been fully informed and has signed a dated IRB approval informed consent form and is willing to follow study procedures for the extent of the study (12 months). Parent or legal guardian must provide written consent for patients &lt;18 years of age. 2. Age 1875 years. 3. Weight &gt; 40 kg. 4. Primary or secondary renal allograft: living or deceased donor. 5. Negative standard crossmatch for T cells. 6. Women of childbearing potential will be required to have a negative qualitative serum pregnancy test and agree to use an adequate method of contraception for the study duration. 7. Males and females are to be studied equivalently as they become available for transplantation using these criteria. 1. Patient has previously received or is receiving an organ transplant other than a kidney. 2. Patient is receiving an ABO incompatible donor kidney. 3. Recipient or donor is seropositive for human immunodeficiency (HIV), Hepatitis C viruses, or Hepatitis B virus antigenemia. 4. Patient has a current malignancy or a history of malignancy (within the past 5 years), except nonmetastatic basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin that has been treated successfully, or carcinoma in situ of the cervix that has been treated successfully. 5. Patients with significant liver disease, defined as having during the past 28 days continuously elevated AST (SGOT) and/or ALT (SGPT) levels greater than 3 times the upper value of the normal range of this center. 6. Patient has uncontrolled concomitant infections and/or severe diarrhea, vomiting, active upper gastrointestinal tract malabsorption or an active peptic ulcer or any other unstable medical condition that could interfere with study objectives. 7. Patient is currently participating in another clinical trial of an investigational drug in the 30 days prior to transplant. 8. Patient will be receiving any immunosuppressive agent other than those prescribed in the study. 9. Patient is unable to take medications orally or via nasogastric tube by the morning of the second day following completion of the transplant procedure (i.e., skin closure) (Group I only). 10. Patient is receiving or may require warfarin, fluvastatin, or herbal supplements during the study. 11. Concurrent use of astemizole, pimozide, cisapride, terfenadine, or ketoconazole. 12. Patient has a known hypersensitivity to tacrolimus, thymoglobulin, IL2 receptor inhibitor monoclonal antibodies, sirolimus, MMF, Myfortic®, or corticosteroids. 13. Patient is pregnant or lactating. 14. Patients with a screening/baseline (or within 96 hours of transplant) total white blood cell count &lt;4000/mm3; platelet count &lt;100,000/mm3; fasting triglycerides &gt;400 mg/dl (&gt;4.6 mmol/L); fasting total cholesterol &gt;300 mg/dl (&gt;7.8 mmol/L); fasting HDLcholesterol &lt;30 mg/dl; fasting LDLcholesterol &gt;200 mg/dl. 15. Patient is unlikely to comply with the visits scheduled in the protocol. 16. Patient has any form of substance abuse, psychiatric disorder or a condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, may invalidate communication with the investigator. If tacrolimus cannot be instituted for longer than 5 days postoperatively.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gastrointestinal toxicity</keyword>
</DOC>