<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00582296</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to examine how people with a family history of colon cancer and other related cancers respond to recommendations for cancer screening after genetic counseling. The purpose of your participation would be to help us learn more about whether people with a personal and/or family history of colorectal cancer and other cancers follow cancer screening recommendations.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multi-Organ Screening Recommendations in Patients With Lynch Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms, Hereditary Nonpolyposis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A patient will be eligible for enrollment if he/she is selfreferred or physicianreferred for genetic counseling at Memorial SloanKettering Cancer Center's (MSKCC) Clinical Genetics Service due to a concern about increased risk for colon cancer or; An individual who presents for genetic counseling at MSKCC's Clinical Genetics Service after undergoing genetic testing at an outside institution with a documented mutation in any gene associated with Lynch Syndrome or; An individual who in the context of genetic counseling has received stricter colorectal and/or gynecologic screening recommendations than that of the general population regardless of genetic test results. DNA of patients who have been consented to protocol 93102 ("Ascertainment of Peripheral Blood or Saliva Samples for Genetic Epidemiology Studies of Familial Cancers"), who meet the eligibility criteria listed above, will also be eligible for inclusion in this study. Patients will be excluded from this study if: he/she has physical, cognitive or psychiatric conditions that interfere with ability to give meaningful informed consent; he/she cannot read, write or communicate in English; he/she is less than 18 years of age; he/she has received a diagnosis of FAP.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lynch syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>04-144</keyword>
</DOC>