<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00582088</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is designed to assess the safety and immunogenicity of Venezuelan Equine Encephalomyelitis Vaccine, Inactivated, Dried, C-84, TSI GSD 205, as a booster vaccination.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Immunogenicity of Venezuelan Equine Encephalomyelitis Vaccine (VEE C-84) as a Booster to VEE TC-83</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Objectives: Primary: To assess safety of Venezuelan Equine Encephalomyelitis Vaccine, Inactivated, Dried, C-84, TSI GSD 205, as a booster vaccination as a single dose or a three-dose series, and To assess immunogenicity of Venezuelan Equine Encephalomyelitis Vaccine, Inactivated, Dried, C-84, TSI GSD 205, as a booster vaccination as a single dose or a three-dose series Secondary: To assess incidence of VEE infection in C-84 boosted personnel.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Encephalomyelitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Encephalomyelitis, Venezuelan Equine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Encephalomyelitis, Equine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 18 years old. VEE PRNT80 &lt; 1:20 before immunization. (females) Negative urine pregnancy test on the same day before vaccination. Not planning pregnancy for 3 months. Actively enrolled in the SIP. At risk for exposure to virulent VEE virus (with uptodate risk assessment). Previous TC83 vaccination Uptodate (within 1 year) physical examination/tests. Sign and date the approved informed consent. Willing to return for all followup visits. Agree to report adverse event (AE) up to 28 days after vaccination. Over age of 65 years Clinically significant abnormal lab results including evidence of Hepatitis C, Hepatitis B carrier state, or elevated liver function tests. History of immunodeficiency or current treatment with immunosuppressive medication. (females) Currently breastfeeding. Confirmed human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) titer. Any known allergies to components of the vaccine. A medical condition that in the judgment of the Principal Investigator (PI) would impact subject safety (i.evaccination and or exposure to another alphavirus). Administration of any vaccine within 28 days of C84. Any unresolved AEs resulting from a previous immunization.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Encephalitis, Viral Infections, Neurologic diseases, Alphavirus Infections, VEE</keyword>
</DOC>