<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03095092</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study was to investigate the effect of food on the pharmacokinetics of a single 400 mg dose of BIA 6-512 (trans-resveratrol) in healthy volunteers</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Food on BIA 6-512 (Trans-resveratrol)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Single-centre, open-label, randomised, two-way crossover study in 24 healthy male and female subjects. The study consisted of 2 single-dose periods separated by a washout of 7 days or more. Eligible subjects were admitted to the UFH on the day (Day 0) prior to receiving the dose of study medication (Day 1). On the morning of the next day (Day 1), a BIA 6-512 400 mg dose was administered following either a standard breakfast (Test) or at least 8 hours of fasting (Reference). Subjects remained confined in the UFH from admission (Day 0) until at least 24 h post dose (Day 2); then, they were discharged and returned for the second treatment period or a follow-up visit.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Resveratrol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subjects aged between 18 and 45 years, inclusive. Subjects of body mass index (BMI) between 19 and 30 kg/m2, inclusive. Subjects who were healthy as determined by prestudy medical history, physical examination, vital signs, and 12lead ECG. Subjects who had clinical laboratory test results clinically acceptable at screening and admission to first treatment period. Subjects who had negative tests for HBsAg, antiHCVAb and HIV1 and HIV2 Ab at screening. Subjects who had a negative screen for alcohol and drugs of abuse at screening and admission to each treatment period. Subjects who were nonsmokers or who smoke ≤ 10 cigarettes or equivalent per day. Subjects who were able and willing to give written informed consent. (If female) She was not of childbearing potential by reason of surgery or, if of childbearing potential, she used one of the following methods of contraception: double barrier, intrauterine device or abstinence. (If female) She had a negative urine pregnancy test at screening and admission to each treatment period. Subjects who did not conform to the above inclusion criteria, OR Subjects who had a clinically relevant history or presence of respiratory, gastrointestinal, renal, hepatic, haematological, lymphatic, neurological, cardiovascular, psychiatric, musculoskeletal, genitourinary, immunological, dermatological, endocrine, connective tissue diseases or disorders. Subjects who had a clinically relevant surgical history. Subjects who had a clinically relevant family history. Subjects who had a history of relevant drug or food hypersensitivity. Subjects who had a history of alcoholism or drug abuse. Subjects who consumed more than 21 units of alcohol a week. Subjects who had a significant infection or known inflammatory process on screening or first admission. Subjects who had acute gastrointestinal symptoms at the time of screening or first admission (e.g., nausea, vomiting, diarrhoea, heartburn). Subjects who had used medicines within 2 weeks of first admission that, in the opinion of the investigator, may affect the safety or other study assessments. Subjects who had used any investigational drug or participated in any clinical trial within 2 months of their first admission. Subjects who had donated or received any blood or blood products within the previous 2 months prior to screening. Subjects who were vegetarians, vegans or have medical dietary restrictions. Subjects who cannot communicate reliably with the investigator. Subjects who were unlikely to cooperate with the requirements of the study. Subjects who were unwilling or unable to give written informed consent. (If female) She was pregnant or breastfeeding. (If female) She was of childbearing potential and she did not use and approved effective contraceptive method (doublebarrier, intrauterine device or abstinence) or she used oral contraceptives.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>