<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01803373</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test the relative bioavailability (extent and rate to which a drug is taken up by the body) of TMC207 following the administration of two pediatric formulations of TMC207 taken with and without food in healthy adult participants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess the Relative Bioavailability of TMC207 Following Single-Dose Administrations of Two Pediatric Formulations in Healthy Adult Participants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label (all study staff and participants know the identity of treatments assigned), 3-way cross-over (method used to switch participants from one treatment to another treatment) study. Three panels of 12 healthy adult participants each will be enrolled. Within each panel, participants will be randomly (by chance) assigned to 1 of 6 treatment sequences to receive each of the 3 formulations of TMC207 in a randomized order. The 3 formulations of TMC207 will be referred to as Treatments A, B, and C. In Treatment A, participants will receive a single 100-mg dose of TMC207 formulated as a 100-mg tablet (reference formulation). In Treatment B, participants will receive a single 100-mg dose of TMC207 formulated as 20-mg water dispersible (dissolvable) tablets (i.e. 5 tablets) (pediatric formulation 1). In Treatment C, participants will receive a single 100-mg dose of TMC207 formulated as granules 5 grams (20 mg/g) (pediatric formulation 2). Each treatment will be separated by 4 weeks. Participants in Panel 1 will receive each treatment with a standardized breakfast, Panel 2 will receive each treatment with yogurt, and Panel 3 will receive each treatment after a 10-hour overnight fast (without food). The duration of the treatment period in this study will be 8.5 weeks (includes 4 weeks between treatments).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Bedaquiline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy participant on the basis of physical examination, medical history, vital signs, and electrocardiogram (ECG), and the results of blood biochemistry and hematology tests and a urinalysis performed at screening Must have a Body Mass Index (BMI, weight in kg divided by the square of height in meters) of 18.5 to 30.0 kg/m2, extremes included Women must be postmenopausal for at least 2 years and have a negative serum pregnancy test at screening and a negative urine pregnancy test at Day 1 Men must agree to use a highly effective method of birth control (eg., male condom with either female intrauterine device, diaphragm, cervical cap or hormone based contraceptives by their female partner) when having sexual intercourse with a female partner of childbearing potential, and to not donate sperm during the study and for 6 months after receiving the last dose of study drug. Men who have had a vasectomy and have a female partner of childbearing potential must agree to use a male condom during the study and for 6 months after receiving the last dose of study drug Participants must be nonsmokers for at least 3 months prior to screening Human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV1) or type 2 (HIV2) infection confirmed at screening Hepatitis A, B or C infection confirmed at screening A positive urine drug test or alcohol breath test at screening. Urine will be tested for the presence of amphetamines, barbiturates, benzodiazepines, cocaine, methadone, and opioids History or any currently active disease or condition that the Investigator considers to be clinically significant for which, in the opinion of the Investigator, participation would not be in the best interest of the participant (eg, compromise the wellbeing) or that could prevent, limit, or confound the protocolspecified assessments</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Healthy</keyword>
	<keyword>Biological Availability</keyword>
	<keyword>Bioavailability</keyword>
	<keyword>TMC207</keyword>
	<keyword>Bedaquiline</keyword>
	<keyword>R207910</keyword>
</DOC>