<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01803256</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The full body marker sets that are typically used in opto-electronic 3D gait analyses either disregard the spine entirely or regard it as a rigid structure. Therefore, the purpose of this study is to identify the possibilities and limitations of an enhanced trunk marker set for the measurement of spine dynamics during gait in adolescents with and without structural spine deformities. It has been hypothesized that the enhance trunk marker set: 1. is a valid method for the measurement of spine deformations in the sagittal, frontal and indirectly transverse planes. 2. is an applicable and reliable method for the measurement of spine dynamics during gait in healthy adolescents and in patients with structural deformities such as seen in scoliosis. 3. is sensitive enough to distinguish the spinal movement pattern during gait measured in scoliosis patients from the one measured in healthy adolescents. To verify the hypotheses, the following measurements will be carried out: - Biplanar radiographs (a-p and lateral) with radio-opaque markers in scoliosis patients. - Instrumented gait analysis with a standard full body marker set and the enhanced trunk marker set in scoliosis patients and healthy controls.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Possibilities and Limitations of a New Method for the Measurement of Spine Dynamics During Gait</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Scoliosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Scoliosis patients: Adolescent idiopathic scoliosis Able to walk a distance of minimum 50 meters barefoot and without any assistive device Other types of scoliosis (e.g. of neurological origin) Previous treatment of scoliosis (conservative or surgery) Injuries of the locomotor system which led to persistent deformities Healthy controls: Any pathologies or diseases affecting the locomotor system Injuries to the locomotor system which led to persistent deformities Obesity (&gt; 95th BMIperage percentile) Leg length discrepancy (more than 1% of body height)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>