<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00367497</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Aggressive non-Hodgkin's lymphoma is difficult to handle once it relapses or becomes refractory to chemotherapy. Various second or third line chemotherapies, which are called salvage chemotherapy, were developed without promising results. Improvement in efficacy by adding relatively new agent, rituximab, to chemotherapy is now widely accepted in non-Hodgkin's lymphoma. This study will test the safety and efficacy of adding rituximab to existing salvage chemotherapy, ESHAP (R-ESHAP). Our aim is also to proceed to high-dose chemotherapy with autologous hematopoietic stem cell transplantation after successful R-ESHAP therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of Salvage Chemotherapy (R-ESHAP) to Treat Relapsed and Refractory Aggressive Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aggression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cytarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of aggressive nonHodgkin's lymphoma Refractory to the first line chemotherapy or relapsed Expression of CD20 on lymphoma cells Measurable lesions on imaging studies Blood cell counts not reaching to 3,000/microliter for white blood cells, 7 g/dl for hemoglobin, and 50,000/microliter for platelets without transfusion at the time of registration Circulating lymphoma cells equal to or more than 25,000/microliter Hepatic dysfunction Renal insufficiency Cardiac dysfunction or arrhythmia Sever infection (bacterial, viral) CNS involvement Other malignancies Pregnancy or breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>69 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>aggressive non-Hodgkin's lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>salvage chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>rituximab</keyword>
</DOC>