<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01499433</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators propose to study the efficacy and safety of three-week antifungal therapy with caspofungin in hospitalized patients with proven or probable IPA underlying chronic obstructive pulmonary disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Caspofungin for Invasive Pulmonary Aspergillosis Underlying Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Recently, there has been increasing appreciation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) as an important risk factor of invasive pulmoanry aspergillosis (IPA). However, clinical data on the morbidity and mortality of IPA underlying COPD as well as the efficacy and safety of antifungal treatment in such subset of patient population is very limited. In clinical pratice, capofungin is often used as primary antifungal therapy for IPA, especially in patients with impaired renal function. Based on this data, the investigators propose to study the efficacy and safety of three-week antifungal therapy with caspofungin in hospitalized patients with proven or probable IPA underlying COPD.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspergillosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Invasive Pulmonary Aspergillosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Aspergillosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Caspofungin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Echinocandins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Proven invasive pulmonary aspergillosis Probable invasive pulmonary aspergillosis Hospitalized in respiratory wards Not having received an empirical antifungal therapy for 72h before inclusion A history of allergy to echinocandins Severe renal failure, severe hepatic insufficiency Inadequately treated bacterial infection Documented HIV infection Status of pregnancy or lactation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>