<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00597428</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of lubiprostone administration in patients with opioid-induced bowel dysfunction (OBD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Opioid-induced Bowel Dysfunction Pivotal Assessment of Lubiprostone</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Intestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lubiprostone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Consistent treatment for chronic, noncancerrelated pain with any full agonist opioid for at least 30 days prior to screening. Diagnosis of opioidinduced bowel dysfunction as confirmed during the screening period. If patient has a history of chronic constipation, condition must have been exacerbated by initiation of opioid treatment. Use of prescribed or overthecounter (OTC) medication that affects gastrointestinal motility (other than opioid therapy) must be discontinued during the study. If treated for clinical depression with selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs), serotoninnorepinephrine reuptake inhibitors (SNRIs), or monoamine oxidase (MAO) inhibitors, treatment must have been at a stable dose for at least 30 days prior to screening. Use of laxative and stool softeners (with the exception of approved rescue medications) must be discontinued while on study. Opioid dose adjustment (+/ 30%), and/or change in opioid agent or route of administration within 30 days of screening. Nonambulatory patients, or those who are unable to eat/drink, take oral medications, or to hold down oral medications due to vomiting. Treatment with opioid therapy for cancerrelated pain, abdominal pain, scleroderma, and/or for the management of drug addiction. Patient has been treated for cancer in the past 5 years (with the exception of localized basal cell, squamous cell skin cancer, or in situ cancer that has been resected). Gastrointestinal or abdominal surgical procedures within 90 days prior to screening. Female patients of childbearing potential who are unable/unwilling to use protocolspecified method(s) of birth control and/or are pregnant, nursing, or plan to become pregnant or nurse during the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>