<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00116142</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized study is looking at the benefits of using docetaxel (chemotherapy) added to one of the standard treatments (radiation and hormones) for men with high-risk prostate cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hormone Suppression and Radiation Therapy for 6 Months With/Without Docetaxel for High Risk Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Radiation therapy plus six months of hormone therapy is one standard way of treating men with high-risk prostate cancer. In this study, we want to see whether or not adding the chemotherapy drug docetaxel (Taxotere)will make this treatment more effective. Docetaxel has shown a benefit in median survival when given to men who have become resistant to hormonal therapy and in men who have metastatic prostate cancer (spread to other areas of the body).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methyltestosterone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ascorbic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estrogens, Conjugated (USP)</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Biopsy proven prostate cancer Clinical Tumor Category T1b, T1c, T2a and PSA greater than (&gt;) 10 or Gleason score equal or greater than 4+3=7 or PSA velocity &gt; 2.0 ng/ml per year and also eligible patients with tumor category T2c, T3a, T3b, or T4 as per 2002 AJCC guidelines. Any minor tertiary grade of Gleason 5; Biopsy Proven or Radiographic (erMRI Seminal Vesicle Invasion); Gleason = or &gt; 3+4=7 with 50% or more cores positive Negative bone scan Lymph node assessment by CT or MR Adequate hematologic function (Blood Counts) Adequate liver functions (blood tests) ECOG performance Status 0 or 1 Peripheral neuropathy must be =&lt; grade 1 PSA obtained within 3 months of entry Prior history of malignancy that are &lt; 5 years except for cancers found to be "insitu" and would not likely impact a patient's life expectancy with appropriate medical management. Prior pelvic radiation therapy Prior hormonal therapy (up to 4 weeks prior to enrollment allowed) Individuals unable to tolerate lying still 5 10 minutes Patients with a history of severe hypersensitivity reaction to docetaxel or other drugs formulated with polysorbate 90.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prostate Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Hormone Refractory</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic</keyword>
	<keyword>Localized</keyword>
	<keyword>Locally Advanced</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostate Cancer - High Risk Localized or Locally Advanced</keyword>
</DOC>