<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00868751</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see if tocilizumab is safe and effective for treating systemic onset Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis (soJIA). Another purpose is to see if tocilizumab helps reduce the amount of steroids (prednisone) needed to control symptoms of soJIA.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Single Patient Use of Tocilizumab in Systemic Onset Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Systemic onset Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis (soJIA) is a type of arthritis (inflammation of the joints) that occurs with other symptoms including fever, swollen lymph nodes (glands), rash, and body aches. Because soJIA can be difficult to treat, children with soJIA can have severe problems from long-term use of steroids (prednisone). These problems include low bone density (weak bones), fractures, failure to grow properly, and large weight gain. The arthritis that occurs in soJIA often causes damage to many joints. This can make it hard to move around or do basic tasks like dressing. Also, a life-threatening illness called Macrophage Activation Syndrome (MAS) can occur when starting, stopping, or changing drugs that are used to treat soJIA. SoJIA can be hard to treat and many children with soJIA do not respond to drugs that work for other kinds of arthritis. Research doctors have studied a chemical signal called IL-6 that the body uses to manage inflammation. This signal has been found to be very high in patients with active soJIA. A drug called tocilizumab (TCZ) has been designed to block IL-6. For about 6 years, TCZ has been tested in Japan for treating soJIA. It is now being tested in studies in the United States. These studies can have very strict rules for enrolling patients. This trial is a single-patient research study for a subject who otherwise does not meet the rules for enrollment in ongoing trials.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Systemic Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis according to ILAR criteria (2001) Duration of disease ≥ 6 months since onset Presence of active disease as determined by the presence of at least 5 active joints, OR at least 2 active joints if receiving prednisone at a dose &gt; 0.2 mg/kg/day or &gt; 10 mg/day (whichever is less) Incomplete prior response to methotrexate treatment for at least 3 months at a minimum dose of 15 mg/M2/week, or intolerance to methotrexate Discontinued treatment with other biologics prior to first tocilizumab infusion, for approximately two pharmacokinetic halflives as per specific biologic (e.g. 48 hours for anakinra, 7 days for etanercept) Not receiving corticosteroids, OR taking oral corticosteroids and the dose has remained stable for 1 week prior to the first tocilizumab infusion at ≤ 2 mg/kg/day prednisone or prednisolone and no more than 80 mg/day Concomitant administration of biologic therapies Serum creatinine &gt;1.5 ULN (upper limits normal) AST or ALT &gt; 1.5 ULN Total bilirubin &gt; 1.3 mg/dL Platelet count &lt; LLN (lower limits normal) Hemoglobin &lt; 6.0 g/dL WBC count &lt; 5,000/mm3 Neutrophil count &lt; 2,000/ mm3 Fibrinogen &lt; LLN</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Antibodies, Monoclonal</keyword>
	<keyword>Interleukin 6</keyword>
</DOC>