<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02017509</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an observational study of tumor samples and MRI imaging in patients with colorectal, melanoma, breast, renal cell, lung, bladder, head and neck, ovarian and thyroid cancers. A tumor sample, MRI scans, and treatment outcome data will be used for research purposes to see if it is possible to predict patients' response to treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunoscore in Rectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The quality of the immune environment in colorectal cancer biopsy samples correlates with disease-free survival and overall survival more so than current staging conventions. This study will use a scoring system called 'immunoscore' to characterize the immune enviroment. Researchers hypothesize that the immunoscore will correlate with outcomes of colorectal patients treated with neoadjuvant chemoradiation. Researchers will also collect samples from melanoma, breast, renal cell, lung, bladder, head and neck, ovarian and thyroid cancers for exploratory research.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thyroid Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with a diagnosis of a rectal mass suspicious for or known to be an adenocarcinoma of the rectum. Age &gt; 18 Ability to give informed consent and comply with the protocol. Patients with a history of psychiatric illness must be judged able to understand fully the investigational nature of the study and the risks associated with the therapy. History of other malignancy in the past 2 years except carcinoma in situ of the cervix or bladder, or nonmelanomatous skin cancer Other medical or psychiatric conditions that in the opinion of the Principal Investigator would preclude safe participation in protocol.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Immunophenotype</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunoscore</keyword>
	<keyword>MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>RNA Later</keyword>
</DOC>