<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01533883</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cardioband is an adjustable annuloplasty band designed for mitral valve repair by a transfemoral delivery system. The aim of this study is to evaluate the performance and safety of the Cardioband for repair of mitral regurgitation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cardioband Adjustable Annuloplasty System for Minimally Invasive Mitral Valve Repair</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The current state of the art management of severe mitral regurgitation is surgical mitral valve repair, either with open chest surgery or mini-thoracotomy. However, standard surgical approaches requiring cardiopulmonary bypass are reserved to fit patients with low or moderate surgical risk, and thus several patients are refused surgery because of unfavorable risk-benefit balance. Cardioband is an adjustable annuloplasty band designed for mitral valve repair by a transfemoral delivery system. Cardioband is intended to remodel the annulus by deployment and fixation along (and direct) the posterior annulus of the mitral valve, in order to correct mitral regurgitation. Adjustment can be performed on a beating heart, to optimize correction of mitral regurgitation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Mitral Valve Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt; 18 years Moderate to severe functional MR Symptomatic Patients (NYHA ClassIIIV) despite optimal medical therapy , including CRT if indicated LVEF ≥ 25%, LVEDD ≤ 70mm Subject is high risk to undergo MV surgery (as assessed by a cardiac surgeon and a cardiologist at the site, and according to ESC/EACTS guidelines on the management of valvular heart disease) Transseptal catheterization and femoral vein access is determined to be feasible Subject is able and willing to give informed consent and follow protocol procedures Active bacterial endocarditis Severe organic lesions with retracted chordae or congenital malformations with lack of valvular tissue Heavily calcified annulus or leaflets Subjects in whom transesophageal echocardiography is contraindicated Untreated clinically significant CAD requiband revascularization Any percutaneous coronary, carotid, endovascular intervention or carotid surgery within 30 days or any coronary or endovascular surgery within 3 months CVA or TIA within 6 months or severe carotid stenosis (&gt;70% by Ultra sound) Renal insufficiency requiband dialysis Life expectancy of less than twelve months Patient is pregnant (urine HCG test result positive) or lactating Known sensitivity to Nickel or Chromium Known hypersensitivity or contraindication to procedural medications which cannot be adequately managed medically Bleeding or clotting disorders Subject is participating in concomitant research studies of investigational products Pulmonary hypertension &gt;70mmHg at rest Mitral valve anatomy which may preclude proper device treatment Rightsided congestive heart failure with echocardiographic evidence of severe right ventricular dysfunction and severe tricuspid regurgitation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mitral</keyword>
	<keyword>Valve</keyword>
	<keyword>Annuloplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Transatrial</keyword>
	<keyword>Transapical</keyword>
	<keyword>Transfemoral</keyword>
	<keyword>Mitral valve insufficiency</keyword>
</DOC>