<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01533753</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the change in quality of life over a 6 month period between gabapentin and venlafaxine in men with prostate cancer treated for hot flashes related to androgen deprivation therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Quality of Life Study Using Gabapentin Versus Venlafaxine in Treating Hot Flashes in Patients With Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>60 evaluable patients with prostate cancer currently receiving androgen ablation therapy or who have had an orchiectomy will be enrolled in this study. All patients will be randomized 1:1 (30 patients per treatment arm) to either receive gabapentin or venlafaxine. Treatment duration will be a total of 6 months. During those 6 months, study staff will evaluate frequency and intensity of hot flashes using hot flash score from hot flash diary every 28 days. Patients will also record side effects associated with either gabapentin or venlafaxine on their medication diaries. Study staff will record the severity of all adverse events reported. Patients will also complete the quality of life Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Prostate (FACT-P) form at baseline, cycle 3, and cycle 6/off study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hot Flashes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venlafaxine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gabapentin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>gamma-Aminobutyric Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men 18 years or older with histologically proven adenocarcinoma of the prostate Prior or current androgen deprivation for at least 6 months prior to study entry with either bilateral orchiectomy or being maintained on a stable dose of LHRH (luteinizing hormonereleasing hormone) agonist or antagonist Hot flash frequency of an average of 2 or more per day (average of 14 hot flash episodes per week) cannot currently be taking serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs), serotoninnorepinephrine reuptake inhibitors (SNRIs) or monoamine oxidase inhibitors (MAOIs) cannot have uncontrolled hypertension cannot have history of past or current of epilepsy, epilepsy syndrome or other seizure disorder cannot have psychiatric history of mania, hypomania, bipolar disorder or anorexia nervosa cannot be receiving concurrent treatment with amy medications or herbal products being used with the express purpose of treating hot flashes.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>hot flashes</keyword>
	<keyword>prostate cancer</keyword>
</DOC>