<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01726582</DOC>
	<brief_summary>See treatment pathways at http://www.mcw.edu/surgery/patientinfo/Pancreatic-Cancer-Trial.htm : In this clinical trial, if the doctor knows or suspects that a growth in the pancreas is cancer (adenocarcinoma), then a sample of the growth is tested (the test is called molecular profiling). The results of the test are used by the doctor to recommend therapy (chemotherapy and radiation therapy) that the patient will receive before having surgery to remove the adenocarcinoma. When the patient goes to surgery, the adenocarcinoma that is removed is tested again. The results of that test are used to guide the choice of therapy after surgery. The chemotherapy drugs and the radiation therapy used in this clinical trial are already approved for treatment of pancreas cancer. This trial is intended to establish which treatment is best for a specific patient, based on test results from that patient's actual adenocarcinoma. In the past, the decision as to which treatment the patient will receive was not based on testing of the actual adenocarcinoma. Hypothesis: Resectability rate, overall survival rate and progression-free survival will be superior in patients with adenocarcinoma of the pancreas who receive targeted "personalized" therapy, as compared to historical data of patients who received standard therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pancreas Cancer: Molecular Profiling as a Guide to Therapy Before and After Surgery ("Personalized Medicine")</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancrelipase</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Enrollment/ eligibility criteria: 18 years of age or older Able to understand and provide written informed consent Diagnosis of adenocarcinoma of the pancreas or high suspicion of adenocarcinoma of the pancreas based on CT and MRI findings as detailed below by "Definition of...." Treatment Eligibility Criteria: Have an ECOG performance status less than or equal to 2 Have biopsyproven resectable or borderline resectable adenocarcinoma of the pancreas Have adequate organ and bone marrow function as defined by: total leukocytes greater than or equal to 3 x1000/μL absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt; or equal to 1.5x 1000/μL hemoglobin &gt; or equal to 9 g/dL platelets &gt; or equal to 100 x 1000/μL creatinine clearance &gt;60 mL/min or creatinine &lt; or equal to 1.5 mg/dL bilirubin &lt; or equal to 2 mg/dL or &gt;2 and declining as described in the protocol aspartate transaminases (AST/SGOT) &lt; or equal to3 x ULN alanine transaminases (ALT/SGPT) &lt; or equal to 3 x ULN Female patients must be post menopausal for &gt; 1 year, surgically sterile, or have a negative pregnancy test and used at least one form of contraception for 4 weeks prior to Day 1 of the study, during study treatment and during the first 4 months after study treatment is discontinued. Male patients must be surgically sterile or use barrier contraception during the study and for 4 months after the last dose of any study drug. Definition of Resectable Pancreatic Cancer includes: No evidence of extrapancreatic disease No evidence of tumorarterial abutment (celiac, SMA or HA) If tumor induced narrowing of the SMV, PV or SMPV confluence is present it must be &lt;50% of the diameter of the vessel Ca 199 &lt;5000, when bilirubin is &lt;2 (or &gt;2 and declining as described in the protocol) Definition of Borderline Resectable Pancreatic Cancer to include at least one of the following: Tumor abutment &lt; or equal to 180 degrees of the SMA or celiac axis Tumor abutment or encasement (&gt;180 degrees) of a short segment of the HA Tumor induced narrowing of SMV, PV or SMPV of &gt;50% of the diameter of the vessel. Short segment occlusion of the SMV, PV or SMVPV with a suitable PV above and SMV below, for reconstruction CT or MRI findings suspicious for, but not diagnostic of, metastatic disease (based on multidisciplinary assessment at the MCW weekly pancreatic cancer conference) Biopsy proven N1 disease (regional lymph nodes involved) from prereferral biopsy or EUSguided FNA Resectable tumor and CA 199 &gt;5000 Any patient with one or more of the following will be excluded: Have received chemotherapy or chemoradiation within 5 years prior of study enrollment Have any previous history of another malignancy (other than cured basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or cured insitu carcinoma of the cervix) within 5 years of study enrollment Uncontrolled comorbidities including, but not limited to, ongoing or active serious infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina, unstable cardiac arrhythmias, psychiatric illness, excessive obesity, or situations that would limit compliance with the study requirements or the ability to willingly give written informed consent Known HIV, HBV, or HCV infection Pregnant or breastfeeding patients or any patient with childbearing potential not using contraception 4 weeks prior to, during and 4 months after study treatment is discontinued</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>pancreas</keyword>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>molecular profile</keyword>
	<keyword>molecular profiling</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreatic cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreas cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>molecular target</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreas head</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreas neck</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreas uncinate</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreas body</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreas tail</keyword>
</DOC>