<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00816270</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this randomized and masked prospective trial is to compare the effectiveness of Liquid Bandage (Octyl-2-Cyanoacrylate) and 6/0 nylon suture as a wound closure device in upper lid blepharoplasty surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Liquid Bandage (2-Octyl-Cyanoacrylate) in Upper Lid Blepharoplasty</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Tissue adhesives have been safely used in a variety of surgical procedures for several years. Butyl-2-cyanoacrylate (Histoacryl) and Octyl-2-cyanoacrylate (Dermabond) was also studied for cosmetic blepharoplasty with satisfactory results. Liquid Bandage (Johnson &amp; Johnson, Skillman, NJ, USA) is a more flexible formulation of octyl-2-cyanoacrylate available in many american drugstores for home use. Animal models shown that this product could accelerate the healing of lamellar wounds and studies in humans have demonstrated its safety and effectiveness as an occlusive protective film over cuts, abrasion and wound surgery. Liquid Bandage was also used as a temporary wound barrier in clear corneal cataract surgery with satisfactory applicability. There is no study in the literature using this device in blepharoplasty yet.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Blepharoptosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients older than 25 years with diagnosis of dermatochalasis who presented surgical indication of primary blepharoplasty. Prior eyelid surgery Concomitant ocular or systemic disease or current use of medications that could interfere in coagulation or wound healing (eg, diabetes mellitus, oral acetyl salicylic acid or corticosteroids) Pregnant female Known allergy to cyanoacrylate Inability to return for followup consultations</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Blepharoptosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Dermatochalasis</keyword>
	<keyword>octyl 2-cyanoacrylate</keyword>
	<keyword>Suture Techniques</keyword>
	<keyword>Tissue Adhesive</keyword>
</DOC>