<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01098565</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to provide proof-of-concept that the test product can perform as intended in an intra-operative setting and the responses to the test product are perceivable in a person. The study will also compare results of the test product to the commercially-available product. Hypothesis: the test product will elicit successful test results in over 90% of test product.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Deep Brain Stimulation Effects Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is indicated for Activa® DBS implant for the treatment of Parkinson's disease and scheduled for surgery at the study site. Subject is willing to sign the informed consent to participate in the study. Subject is 18 years of age or older. Subject is a male or nonpregnant female. Subject has no factors that would put the subject at an additional risk for intraoperative or postoperative bleeding. This includes underlying disorders of the coagulation cascade (eg, hemophilia), disorders that affect platelet count or function (eg, Von Willebrand's disease), as well as administration of any antiplatelet or anticoagulant medication in the 7 days prior to surgery, or any history of anticoagulant or aspirin use, that in the view of the neurosurgeon or neurologist would place the subject at an increased risk for intraoperative or postoperative bleeding. Subject is indicated for DBS for treating a disorder other than Parkinson's disease. Subject has any medical contraindications to undergoing DBS surgery, (eg, infection, coagulopathy, or significant cardiac or other medical risk factors for surgery). Subject has a history of hemorrhagic stroke. Subject has a history of a neurosurgical ablation procedure. Subject is currently enrolled in or plans to enroll in any concurrent study that may confound the results of this study, as determined by the investigator or Medtronic. Subject has a diagnosis of acute myocardial infarction or cardiac arrest less than or equal to 6 months prior to the screening testing. Subject has a history of a seizure disorder Subject requires short surgery time due to general health issues, as determined by the investigator. Subject is a woman who is pregnant or planning to become pregnant, or a woman of childbearing potential, who is not using a medicallyacceptable method of birth control. Women of childbearing potential must undergo a pregnancy test, with a clear negative result, no more than 7 days prior to the investigational procedure visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>