<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00431587</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The metabolic risks associated with obesity are closely correlated with central (abdominal), rather than a peripheral (gluteofemoral) fat pattern It has been shown that weight loss after bariatric surgery is followed by metabolic improvements. The amount of fat lost from each site may be independently regulated. Very scant information is found in the literature regarding the relative changes in different fat body compartments, and their effect on the improvement of the metabolic profile. In this study we define the absolute and relative changes in the different adipose tissue compartment after weight loss surgery</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Changes in Different Fat Compartments and Their Effect on Particular Manifestations of Metabolic Syndrome After Bariatric Procedures.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The metabolic risks associated with obesity are closely correlated with central (abdominal), rather than a peripheral (gluteofemoral) fat pattern. The amount of fat lost from each site may be independently regulated. Very scant information is found in the literature regarding the relative changes in different fat body compartments. Rapid and preferential reduction of visceral fat mass could occur in morbid obese with visceral obesity. It has been previously shown, and it was also partially confirmed in this study, that a reduction in visceral fat was associated with metabolic improvements that included improved glucose tolerance and reduced plasma insulin and lipid levels. This again suggests a threshold of proportional visceral fat loss, above which there is an improvement in insulin sensitivity and other component of metabolic syndrom. We will quantify the different fat compartments changes after bariatric surgery by means of CT scan.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obesity, Morbid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obesity, Abdominal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Morbid obesity, Metabolic syndrome Previous abdominoplasty surgery, Previous major abdominal surgey</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>morbid obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>visceral fat</keyword>
	<keyword>peripheral fat</keyword>
</DOC>