<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00869973</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to compare efficacy and tolerability of aprepitant versus dexamethasone in the prevention of delayed emesis induced by moderately emetogenic chemotherapy (cyclophosphamide plus anthracyclines) in breast cancer patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aprepitant in the Prevention of Delayed Emesis Induced by Cyclophosphamide Plus Anthracyclines in Breast Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase III, double-blind, randomized trial, to evaluated the efficacy and safety of aprepitant for the prevention of delayed emesis in patients with breast cancer submitted for the first time to chemotherapy with cyclophosphamide plus anthracyclines. The study will be carried out during the first cycle of chemotherapy. For the prevention of acute emesis, all patients will receive, before chemotherapy: - dexamethasone 8 mg iv in 15 minutes, 30 minutes before chemotherapy; - palonosetron 0.25 mg iv bolus, 30 minutes before chemotherapy - aprepitant 125 mg orally, 60 minutes before chemotherapy After 24 hours from chemotherapy administration, patients will be randomized to receive: A) dexamethasone 4 mg orally: 24 hours after chemotherapy and at 8 pm on day 2, then at 8 am and 8 pm on day 3. B) Aprepitant 80 mg orally: 24 hours after chemotherapy on day 2 and then at 8 am on day 3. The patients will receive prochlorperazine suppositories as rescue medication, for important nausea and vomiting (&gt; 2 episodes) during days 1-5 after chemotherapy. The patients will receive a diary, which includes a Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) for nausea and vomiting evaluation. All patients will fill out the diary in which, for 6 consecutive days (days 1-6), patients will report for each day the number of vomiting episodes, the intensity and duration of nausea, any antiemetic rescue medication and any adverse event and its treatment. In addition, on day 1 before chemotherapy and then on day 6, patients will fill out the FLIE (Functional Living Index-Emesis), a questionnaire concerning the impact of nausea and vomiting on their quality of life. Primary end point is the percentage of complete responses (no vomiting and no rescue treatment) on days 2-5 after chemotherapy administration</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aprepitant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fosaprepitant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients with breast cancer, receiving for the first time chemotherapy with cyclophosphamide + anthracyclines (FAC, FEC, AC, EC). patients over 18 years old and those who signed informed consent adequate contraception if premenopausal women Every other anticancer drug in the first 24 hours will be administered after the end of cyclophosphamide plus anthracycline. patients already submitted to chemotherapy patients receiving any chemotherapy on days 24 after treatment patients with concomitant severe diseases or with predisposition to emesis such as intestinal obstruction, active peptic ulcer, hypercalcemia and brain metastases contraindications to corticosteroids (i.e., active peptic ulcer or previous bleeding from peptic ulcer patients submitted to concomitant radiotherapy or submitted to radiotherapy in the 15 days before chemotherapy or planned to receive radiotherapy during the 8 days after chemotherapy patients receiving other concomitant antiemetic treatments or submitted to antiemetic treatments in the 24 hours before chemotherapy patients with nausea or vomiting in the 24 hours before chemotherapy patients receiving concomitant steroids, except when administered at physiologic doses patients receiving concomitant benzodiazepines, except when used for nocturnal sedation patients with WBC count &lt;3000/mm3 or platelet count &lt;70000/mm3 patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>aprepitant</keyword>
	<keyword>delayed emesis</keyword>
	<keyword>cyclophosphamide plus anthracyclines</keyword>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>antiemetic</keyword>
</DOC>