<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00869115</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study explores a potential drug-drug interaction between istaroxime and digoxin in patients with stable CHF on chronic oral digoxin treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase I Interaction Study of Istaroxime and Digoxin in Subjects With Stable Heart Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single center, randomized, double blind, placebo controlled, escalating dose phase I interaction study. The three dose levels of istaroxime or placebo will be randomized sequentially to three cohorts (I to III) of 16 patients each (12 patients on istaroxime and 4 patients on placebo). Digoxin will be administered non blinded in all patients, once daily in the morning after a standardized breakfast, continuing with previously personalized dosage schedule during the screening period, treatment period, post treatment period and follow up period. Prior to accrual of cohorts II and III, a Data Monitoring Committee (DMC) will advise on the continuation to the next istaroxime dose, based on a predetermined safety review. This 37 day study includes a screening period (Days -21 to -1), a treatment period (Day 1), a post treatment period (Days 2-4), and a follow up period (which includes one patient visit on Day 14). Patients will be confined in the phase I research center from Day -2 to Day 4.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Digoxin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Main screening inclusion criteria : Signed informed consent; Male or female patients ≥18 years; Female patients of childbearing potential must not be pregnant; Chronic stable cardiac function impairment (no change in heart failure medication over the last 3 months and without any dosage adjustment in the last 4 weeks); Systolic blood pressure (SBP) of ≥ 90 mmHg and ≤ 140 mmHg; LVEF ≤ 35% by any method (to be performed at screening if not measured within the last 12 months); Chronic treatment (i.e. once daily dosing without interruption) with oral digoxin started at least 3 months prior to study entry and without any concomitant administration of other positive inotropic drugs; Main screening exclusion criteria : Need for current or intermittent intravenous positive inotrope administration within the preceding 6 months, or hemodynamic support devices; Acute coronary syndrome within the past 3 months; Coronary artery bypass graft or percutaneous coronary intervention within the past 3 months; Stroke within the past 6 months; Atrial fibrillation or uncontrolled heart rate (HR) (&gt; 100 beats per minute [bpm]); Significant arrhythmia or second or third degree atrioventricular block; Valvular disease as the primary cause of HF; Significant ECG abnormalities as assessed by appropriately qualified physician or investigator including QTcF &gt;450; Positive testing for Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV), Hepatitis B and/or Hepatitis C; Main randomization exclusion criteria: HR &gt; 100 bpm or &lt; 50 bpm; Serum potassium &gt; 5.3 mmol/L or &lt; 3.8 mmol/L and magnesium &gt; 1.1 mmol/L or &lt; 0.6 mmol/L, TN I &gt; ULN.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Digoxin</keyword>
	<keyword>Inotropes</keyword>
	<keyword>Lusitropic agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Istaroxime</keyword>
	<keyword>Debio 0614</keyword>
</DOC>