<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00889629</DOC>
	<brief_summary>People with kidney transplants often develop bone disease. One reason for bone disease may be overactivity of a gland in the neck called the parathyroid gland. Overactivity of the parathyroid gland may be caused by lack of Vitamin D in the body. It has recently been discovered that many patients with kidney transplants have low Vitamin D levels. The investigators are examining the effects of doxercalciferol on parathyroid hormone levels, proteinuria and bone turnover markers in people who have had a kidney transplant.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Study Evaluating Doxercalciferol Replacement Therapy in Kidney Transplant Recipients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>People with kidney transplants often develop bone disease. One reason for bone disease may be overactivity of a gland in the neck called the parathyroid gland. Overactivity of the parathyroid gland may be caused by lack of Vitamin D in the body. It has recently been discovered that many patients with kidney transplants have low Vitamin D levels. 25-OH Vitamin D3 is now recommended to treat kidney transplant patients with low vitamin D levels but it may not be enough to treat the parathyroid problems and bone disease. Doxercalciferol is a form of Vitamin D that has been used to treat bone disease and parathyroid problems in dialysis patients but has not yet been studied in patients with kidney transplants. We are interested in seeing whether doxercalciferol given together with 25-OH Vitamin D3 will be a better treatment for the overactive parathyroid gland and bone disease than 25-OH Vitamin D3 alone in patients with kidney transplants.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>1 alpha-hydroxyergocalciferol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults of both genders between the ages of 18 and 65. Kidney transplant at least 1 year prior to enrollment Creatinine value of &lt;2.5 mg/dl with no excursion &gt;0.5 within the past 3 months Proteinuria of 500 mg/24 hours or a protein/creatinine ratio of 0.5 or greater Hypovitaminosis D, as defined by a 25OH Vitamin D value of &lt;25 ng/ml Intact PTH value between 150 and 600 pg/ml History of parathyroidectomy History of prior intolerance to vitamin D therapy (not including hypercalcemia) History of biopsy proven acute rejection over the 3 months preceding enrollment Recent (over the past month) addition of an ACE inhibitor or Angiotensin Receptor Blocking agent patients who have been on a stable dose are acceptable Current use of active Vitamin D supplement (patients in whom therapy has been discontinued more than 1 month prior to enrollment are acceptable) Postmenopausal woman or women receiving hormone replacement therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>kidney transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>kidney transplant recipients</keyword>
</DOC>