<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00889798</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this registry is to record information on therapy reality of malignant lymphatic systemic diseases by office-based haematologists in Germany.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tumor Registry of Lymphatic Neoplasia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The TLN is a prospective, longitudinal, nation wide cohort study with the purpose to record information on the antineoplastic treatment of lymphatic neoplasms in Germany. The registry will follow patients for up to five years. It will identify common therapeutic sequences and changes in the treatment of the disease. At inclusion, data in patient characteristics, comorbidities, tumor characteristics and previous treatments are collected. During the course of observation data on all systemic treatments, radiotherapies, surgeries, and outcome are documented. The impact of nutrition (LyNut) and physical activity (LyNut) on the course of the adjuvant disease will be examined in patients with indolent and aggressive Non-Hodgin Lymphoma, as well as long-term effects of systemic treatment (LyTox) and quality of life (LyLife) in patients with multiple myeloma.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed diagnosis of NonHodgkin`s lymphoma, chronic lymphocytic leukaemia or multiple myeloma Must receive a first or secondline therapy 18 years or older Signed, written informed consent no systemic therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Malignant lymphatic disease</keyword>
	<keyword>therapy-reality</keyword>
	<keyword>observation</keyword>
	<keyword>registry</keyword>
	<keyword>therapy sequences</keyword>
	<keyword>NHL</keyword>
	<keyword>CLL</keyword>
	<keyword>Germany</keyword>
	<keyword>lenalidomide</keyword>
	<keyword>alemtuzumab</keyword>
	<keyword>rituximab</keyword>
	<keyword>bendamustin</keyword>
	<keyword>thalidomide</keyword>
	<keyword>bortezomib</keyword>
	<keyword>ibritumomab-tiuxetan</keyword>
	<keyword>G-CSF</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic lymphocytic leukaemia</keyword>
	<keyword>follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>gastric MALT lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>nongastric MALT lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>nodal marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>splenic marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>mantle cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>diffuse large b-cell lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>