<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01052077</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Double-blind study wherein patients with Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) will receive either from 1 to 3 mg a day of study medication (OPC-34712)or placebo (an inactive substance) in addition to an FDA approved antidepressant in order to determine if the study medication is effective as an add on treatment of MDD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Safety and Efficacy of OPC-34712 as Adjunctive Therapy in the Treatment of Adults With Major Depressive Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subjects between 18 and 65 years of age, with diagnosis of major depressive disorder, as defined by DSMIVTR criteria The current depressive episode must be equal to or greater than 8 weeks in duration Subjects must report a history for the current depressive episode of an inadequate response to at least one and no more than three adequate antidepressant treatments. Females who are breastfeeding and/or who have a positive pregnancy test result prior to receiving study drug. Subjects who report an inadequate response to more than three adequate trials of antidepressant treatments during current depressive episode at a therapeutic dose for an adequate duration. Subjects with a current Axis I (DSMIVTR) diagnosis of: Delirium, dementia,amnestic or other cognitive disorder Schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder, or other psychotic disorder Bipolar I or II disorder Subjects with a clinically significant current Axis II (DSMIVTR) diagnosis of borderline, antisocial, paranoid, schizoid, schizotypal or histrionic personality disorder.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>OPC-34712</keyword>
	<keyword>Major Depressive Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Adjunctive Treatment</keyword>
</DOC>