<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01052571</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate differences in outcomes in patients receiving steroids compared to those patients randomized to the local anesthetic group who did not receive steroids. To evaluate and compare the adverse event profile in all patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Transforaminal Epidural Injections in Lumbar Disc Herniation or Radiculitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Recruitment is indicated in patients with chronic low back and lower extremity pain secondary to lumbar disc herniation and/or lumbar radiculitis of at least 6-months duration, non-responsive to conservative management with NSAIDs, physical therapy, chiropractic treatment, and exercises. This is a single center study performed in an interventional pain management referral center in the United States. The study involves 120 patients studied in 2 groups with 60 patients in each group. Randomization includes sequence generation, allocation concealment, implementation, and blinding. Data management analysis includes sample size justification of 40 patients in each group with a power of 80% and a 0.05% 2-sided significance level. Statistical methodology includes chi-squared statistics, Fisher's exact test, t-test, and paired t-test with significance evaluated at P value &lt; 0.05.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intervertebral Disc Displacement</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hernia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Radiculopathy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics, Local</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Patients with disc herniation or radiculitis Patients who are 18 years of age Patients with a history of chronic functionlimiting low back and lower extremity pain of at least 6 months duration Patients who are competent to understand the study protocol and provide voluntary, written informed consent and participate in outcome measurements Exclusion criteria: Previous lumbar surgery, radiculitis secondary to spinal stenosis without disc herniation Uncontrollable or unstable opioid use Uncontrolled psychiatric disorders Uncontrolled medical illness either acute or chronic Any conditions that could interfere with the interpretation of the outcome assessments Pregnant or lactating women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic low back pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Lumbar disc herniation</keyword>
	<keyword>Lower extremity pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Lumbar radiculitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Local anesthetic</keyword>
	<keyword>Steroid</keyword>
	<keyword>Lumbar transforaminal epidural injection</keyword>
</DOC>