<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00958217</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will compare two different types of psychotherapy for Veterans with depression, addiction, and a past traumatic experience. Everyone in the study will receive 12 weeks of group cognitive behavioral therapy focused on depression and addiction, followed by 12 weeks of individual psychotherapy sessions. For the second 12 weeks, half of the people will receive a review of the initial therapy, and half will receive a cognitive behavioral therapy focused on trauma. Everyone will complete research interviews every 3 months for a total of 18 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intervention for Veterans With Depression, Substance Disorder, and Trauma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The goal of this study is to evaluate whether a second disorder-specific intervention improves longer term (up to 18 months) treatment outcomes for male and female Veterans with co-occurring depression and alcohol/substance disorders and trauma history (with or without PTSD diagnosis). This 4 years randomized two-group design uses repeated assessments at baseline and every 3 months for a total of 12 months. The investigators are providing their recently developed integrated intervention for comorbid depression and substance disorders for the initial 12 weeks in group format (Integrated Cognitive Behavioral Therapy; Phase I). After the 12 week group intervention, participants will be randomized to receive either a review of the initial intervention in individual sessions, or a trauma-specific intervention, Cognitive Processing Therapy, with integrated addiction treatment components. Length, duration, and setting of both interventions will be the same, and all participants will meet with the program psychiatrist for medication appointments. No medications are under study and no placebo is used; medications will be prescribed using standard VA protocol. Research assessments will document diagnosis, recent substance use, depression and PTSD symptoms, medication adherence, and life stress.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Veterans 18 years of age and older living in the San Diego, California area Who are able to attend inperson therapy sessions Have depression, alcohol or substance addiction, and a past traumatic experience Nonveterans Individuals with schizophrenia or severe memory impairment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Depressive symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>Substance-related disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Posttraumatic stress disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>