<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02914340</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicenter, prospective study designed to evaluate performance of the SVS in the REACH SVS control patients. The study is expected to enroll up to 20 patients at up to 12 sites with up to 6 patients per site.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>REACH SVS Control Patient Cross-Over Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Emphysema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Emphysema</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient was enrolled in the REACH SVS Study control group and has completed their participation in the Study including the 12 month followup visit. Patient has received standardofcare medical management and it has been stable for 6 weeks. Patient is willing to participate in a study, complete the required followup visits, and maintain consistent nutrition and exercise habits during the study period. Patient is classified as ASA Class greater than P4 including presence of comorbidity that could significantly increase the risk of a bronchoscopy procedure. Patient participated in a study of an investigational drug or device within the past 30 days prior to participation in this study. Patient has demonstrated unwillingness or inability to complete baseline data collection procedures. Patient has coexisting major medical disease that will limit evaluation, participation, or followup in the study. Patient is unable to provide informed consent. Patient is not an appropriate candidate for or is unable to tolerate, flexible bronchoscopy procedures. Patient has history of 4 or more hospitalizations for COPD exacerbation or respiratory infections in the past year and none have occurred in the prior 3 months. Patient has evidence of systemic disease or neoplasia expected to compromise survival during the 3month study period Patient has demonstrated unwillingness or inability to complete screening or baseline data collection procedures.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>