<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02914587</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate and compare the safety and effectiveness of the ARTAS™ System to manual hair follicle implantation method following a nine month period of post-procedure evaluation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Computer-Assisted Hair Implantation Using ARTAS System VS Manual Implantation Technique Hair Restoration Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This comparative study is a multi-center, prospective, blinded, randomized controlled clinical study where subjects act as their own control. The purpose of this study is to demonstrate that the ARTAS System is safe and effective for implanting follicular hair units. Patients will be followed for a nine months period of time.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alopecia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is male with clinical diagnosis of androgenetic alopecia with NorwoodHamilton grade of IVVI; Subject is 29 to 70 years old; Subject has black or brown hair color; Subject has straight hair; Subject agrees to cut hair short (about 11.4 mm) on the scalp in the designated study areas for harvesting and implantation; Subject agrees to have 6 dot tattoos placed on scalp; Subject is able to understand and provide written consent; and Subject consents to postoperative followup per protocol. Subject has prior history of scalp reduction surgery(s); Subject has prior history of hair restoration procedure(s) using the strip excision technique; Subject has bleeding diathesis; Subject has active use of anticoagulation medication; Subject has used finasteride in the previous 6 months, or plans to use finasteride during the study; Subject has used minoxidil in the previous 2 weeks, or plans to use minoxidil during the study; or Subject has any other condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, makes the subject inappropriate to take part in this study.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>29 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>