<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02914314</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the pharmacokinetics (PK) of an oral suspension of perampanel given as an adjunctive therapy and to generate preliminary safety and efficacy data in pediatric participants, ranging from 1 month to less than 24 months of age, with epilepsy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetic Study With an Oral Suspension of Perampanel as Adjunctive Therapy in Pediatric Subjects With Epilepsy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multicenter, open-label study comprised of pretreatment, treatment (core study), and extension phases that is designed to evaluate the PK of an oral suspension of perampanel (target dose of 12 milligrams per day [mg /day] for non-enzyme-inducing antiepileptic drug [non-EIAED] or 16 mg/day for EIAED) when given as an adjunctive therapy in participants ranging from 1 month to less than 24 months (&lt;2 years) of age with epilepsy. The Pretreatment Phase will last up to 2 weeks, during which participants will be assessed for their eligibility to participate in the study. The Treatment Phase will consist of 3 periods: Titration (12 to 16 weeks), Maintenance (4 weeks), and Follow-Up (4 weeks; only for those participants who complete the Maintenance Period but do not continue into the Extension Phase and those participants who discontinue study participation). The Extension Phase will consist of 2 periods: Maintenance (32 to 36 weeks) and Follow-Up (4 weeks). The maximum total duration of treatment for each participant will be 52 weeks, and the maximum total duration of the study for each participant will be 58 weeks (52 weeks of treatment + 2 weeks of pretreatment + 4 weeks of follow-up).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have a minimum weight of 4 kilograms (kg) (8.8 pounds [lb]) Have a diagnosis of epilepsy with any type of seizure according to the International League Against Epilepsy's (ILAE) Classification of Epileptic Seizures (1981). Diagnosis should have been established at least 2 weeks (≤6 months of age) or 4 weeks (&gt;6 months of age) before Visit 1, by clinical history and an electroencephalogram (EEG) that is consistent with epilepsy; normal interictal EEGs will be allowed provided that the participant meets the other diagnosis criterion (i.e., clinical history) Have had brain imaging (computed tomography [CT] or magnetic resonance imaging [MRI]) before Visit 1 that ruled out a progressive cause of epilepsy Have had 1 or more seizure(s) during the 4 weeks before Visit 1 Currently being treated with a stable dose (i.e., unchanged for at least 5 halflives) of 1 to a maximum of 3 antiepileptic drugs (AEDs) (at least 6, but not more than 8, participants will be taking 1 enzymeinducing AED [EIAEDs] out of the maximum of 3 AEDs allowed. The remaining participants cannot be taking any EIAEDs). Have been on their current concomitant AED regime with a stable dose for at least 2 weeks (≤6 months of age) or 4 weeks (&gt;6 months of age) before Visit 1 Must have discontinued all restricted medications at least 2 weeks or 5 halflives (whichever is longer) before Visit 1 If entering the Extension Phase, must have completed the last visit of the Maintenance Period of the Core Study Have a history of status epilepticus that required hospitalization during the 3 months before Visit 1 Have seizures due to treatable medical conditions, such as those arising due to metabolic disturbances, toxic exposure, or an active infection Have epilepsy secondary to progressive central nervous system (CNS) disease or any other progressive neurodegenerative disease, including tumors Have had epilepsy surgery before Visit 1 Are scheduled and/or confirmed to have epilepsy surgery within 6 months after Visit 1 Used intermittent rescue benzodiazepines (i.e., 1 to 2 doses over a 24hour period considered onetime rescue) 2 or more times in the 2 weeks before Visit 1 Prior use of felbamate Prior use of vigabatrin Are on ketogenic diet regimen that has not been stable for at least 4 weeks before Visit 1 Have used other drugs known to influence the CNS, where the dose has not been stabilized for at least 2 weeks (≤6 months of age) or 4 weeks (&gt;6 months of age) before Visit 1 Have any concomitant illnesses/comorbidities that could severely affect the participant's safety or study conduct Have evidence of clinically significant disease (e.g., cardiac, respiratory, gastrointestinal, renal disease) that in the opinion of the investigator(s) could affect the participant's safety or study conduct Have clinically significant laboratory abnormalities or any clinically acute or chronic disease Have evidence of significant active hepatic disease. Stable elevation of liver enzymes, alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) due to concomitant medication(s), will be allowed if they are less than 3 times the upper limit of normal (ULN) Have clinical evidence of significant active hematological disease; white blood cell (WBC) count ≤2500/ microliter (μL) (2.50 x 10^9/Liter [L]) or an absolute neutrophil count ≤1000/μL (1.00 x 10^9/L) Have conditions that may interfere with their participation in the study and/or with the PK of study drug Have participated in a study involving administration of an investigational drug or device within 4 weeks before Visit 1, or within approximately 5 halflives of the previous investigational compound, whichever is longer Have previously participated in a clinical trial involving perampanel Have a clinically significant ECG abnormality, including prolonged corrected QT interval (QTc) defined as &gt;450 milliseconds (msec) Have had multiple drug allergies or a severe drug reaction to an AED(s), including dermatological (e.g., StevensJohnson syndrome), hematological, or organ toxicity reactions</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>epilepsy</keyword>
	<keyword>refractory partial seizures</keyword>
</DOC>