<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02185872</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to examine the differences in glucose control, fitness, and body composition between a standard aerobic and resistance exercise training program and a shorter-duration, high-intensity CrossFit training program in overweight and obese physically inactive adults. Hypotheses: 1. Both groups would improve glucose control, with the CrossFit group improving significantly more than the aerobic and resistance training group. 2. Both groups would improve fitness, with the CrossFit group improving significantly more than the aerobic and resistance training group. 3. Both groups would demonstrate decreases in body fat percentage and fat mass and increases in lean body mass, with the CrossFit group improving significantly more than the aerobic and resistance training group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CrossFit Exercise to Improve Glucose Control for Overweight and Obese Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Overweight or obese participants will take part in an 8-week exercise intervention after clearance from a doctor, that is expected to improve glucose control, fitness (Eurofit and peak aerobic capacity), and body composition (body fat percentage, fat mass, and lean body mass). After stratification by age and body mass index, participants will be randomized to either a standard aerobic and resistance training exercise program or a relatively higher intensity, shorter duration CrossFit exercise program.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperglycemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>body mass index (BMI) of 25 &lt; 40, physically inactive (i.e., not participating in any structured exercise programs for the past 2 months and not exceeding 30 total minutes of physical activity per week) current smoker, pregnant, taking blood glucose altering medications, heart disease, type 1 or 2 diabetes mellitus, total cholesterol 200 mg/dL or higher</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical Fitness</keyword>
	<keyword>Body Composition, Beneficial</keyword>
</DOC>