<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01016054</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a parallel arm study to evaluate AGS-8M4 administered in combination with chemotherapy in subjects with ovarian cancer. AGS-8M4 will be administered as an IV infusion until disease worsens.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of the Safety and Pharmacokinetics of AGS-8M4 Given in Combination With Chemotherapy in Women With Ovarian Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All Subjects will receive AGS-8M4 treatment. Subjects will be enrolled into 1 of 2 treatment arms according to their disease status. A disease assessment will be performed every 8 or 9 weeks (± 3 days) depending on the treatment arm assignment. The assessment will be based both on changes in clinical symptoms, and radiographic images. Subjects without evidence of disease progression may continue to receive treatment based on their original treatment assignment until disease progression or intolerability. A safety follow-up visit will occur 4 weeks after the last dose infusion of AGS-8M4.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects with recurrent disease Stage III/IV diagnosis of epithelial ovarian cancer, fallopian tube cancer, or primary peritoneal carcinoma Subjects with either platinum resistant or platinum sensitive ovarian cancer At least 14 days of previous cytotoxic chemotherapy and have recovered from all toxicities Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) equal to or greater than the institutional lower limit of normal as measured by echocardiogram or MUGA (ONLY required for platinum resistant patients) Active infection requiring treatment with systemic (intravenous or oral) antiinfectives (antibiotic, antifungal, or antiviral agent) within 72 hours of screening Use of any investigational drug within 30 days prior to screening Prior monoclonal antibody therapy other than Avastin Avastin administration within 90 days of screening History of thromboembolic events and bleeding disorders ≤ 3 months (e.g.,DVT or PE)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Clinical Trial, Phase1</keyword>
	<keyword>Combination Drug Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Ovarian</keyword>
</DOC>