<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03063034</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate exposure to "tar" and nicotine from two menthol cigarette products and provide a basis for comparing mouth-level exposure when smokers smoke the two cigarette products. Mouth-level exposure is the measurement of substance trapped in the cigarette butt after smoking the cigarette. Other purposes of this study are to: - Compare the plasma cotinine, a byproduct of your body's processing of nicotine, levels found in users after smoking each of two different cigarettes. - Find out the daily mouth-level exposure to cigarette "tar" and nicotine from smoking each of two different cigarettes in adult smokers. - Determine if certain measures of nicotine dependence change based on the type of cigarette smoked - To compare product liking and intent to use it again.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CSD1602: A Crossover Study to Evaluate the Exposure to "Tar" and Nicotine From Two King Size Menthol Cigarette Products</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will consist of one group of approximately 40 adult subjects randomly assigned to the order in which they will smoke two study menthol cigarette products (including one comparator product and one test product). Subjects will smoke each study product exclusively for approximately one week prior to a test visit, with a different product smoked each week over a two-week period. Cigarette butts will be collected the day prior to each test visit for determination of MLE "tar" and nicotine levels. Blood samples will be collected at each test visit for determination of plasma cotinine levels. Subjects will provide responses to questions during each test visit to assess their cigarette smoking and cigarette butt collection behavior during the preceding day.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Nicotine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Menthol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Able to read, understand, and willing to sign an Informed Consent Form (ICF). Generally healthy males and females, 21 years of age or older, at ScreeningEnrollment Visit. Selfreports smoking at least seven cigarettes per day and inhaling the smoke. Usual brand of cigarette is one of the brand styles specified. Smoked usual brand for ≥ 3 months. Agrees to exclusively smoke the study cigarettes and not smoke or use any other tobacco or nicotinecontaining products during the course of the study. Able to read and comprehend English. Able to safely perform the required study procedures, as determined by the Investigator. Selfreported history of heart disease, kidney disease, asthma or any other lung disease, diabetes, liver disease, hypertension, or hypercholesterolemia. At risk for heart disease, i.e., obesity (body mass index [BMI] ≥ 40 kg/m2), as determined by the Investigator. Females ≥ 35 years of age currently using systemic, estrogencontaining contraception, or hormone replacement therapy. Postponing a decision to quit smoking (defined as planning a quit attempt within 30 days of the ScreeningEnrollment Visit) to participate in this study. Use of any medication or substance that aids in smoking cessation, including but not limited to any nicotine replacement therapy (NRT) (e.g., nicotine gum, lozenge, patch), varenicline (Chantix®), bupropion (Wellbutrin®, Zyban®), or lobelia extract within 30 days prior to the ScreeningEnrollment Visit. Females who test positive for pregnancy, are pregnant or breastfeeding, or plan to become pregnant during the course of the study. Determined by the Investigator to be inappropriate for the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>