<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03063359</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Acute tramatic pain is one of main reasons for consultation in pediatric emergency departments. To manage pain quickly and effectively must be a primary outcome of the emergency department. However, pediatric emergency department are sometimes criticized for inadequate and delayed initiation analgesia . Indeed, several studies have shown the inadequacy between the intensity of the pain evaluated by the care team and the therapeutic management of it. The ideal analgesic must have a rapid onset of action, have a powerful analgesic effect, have few side effects and can be administered quickly and painlessly. That's why, the main outcome of this study is to assess the non inferiority of a treatment by intranasal Fentanyl vs morphine sulfate (oral use) in children with traumatic pain on arrival to pediatric emergency department.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intranasal Fentanyl Versus Oral Morphine Sulfate in the Treatment of Pain in Pediatric Trauma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Acute Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient aged between 4 years old and 15,3 years old Acute pain in traumatic context with a suspicion of fracture for patient &lt;7years old : feeling Pain&gt;6/10 defined with a face analogue scale and a visual analogic scale (the difference between the scales is not &lt;10 oints) For patients &gt;7 years old : feeling pain &gt;6 points and defined thanks to a visual analogic scale Informed consent form signed by parents Beneficiary of an european health protection Antalgic ( II or III) within 4 hours before the inclusion Allergic or nonindication of fentanyl Allergic or contraindication of morphine sulfate Pre existing peripheral intravenous catheter Traumatic brain injury Nasal traumatic</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>traumatic pain</keyword>
	<keyword>children</keyword>
	<keyword>fentanyl</keyword>
	<keyword>intranasal use</keyword>
</DOC>