<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03063918</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot clinical trial studies how well personalized dietary intervention works in managing bowel dysfunction and improving quality of life in stage I-III rectosigmoid cancer survivors. Personalized dietary intervention may help people understand bowel symptoms, identify helpful and troublesome foods for bowel symptoms, adjust diets and food preparation based on food triggers, and coach on healthy diet recommendations after cancer treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Personalized Dietary Intervention in Managing Bowel Dysfunction and Improving Quality of Life in Stage I-III Rectosigmoid Cancer Survivors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Administer and determine the feasibility of the personalized dietary intervention. II. Using qualitative methods, evaluate the acceptability of the intervention as reported by survivors. III. Explore decisional conflict associated with treatment decision-making in rectal cancer surgery. OUTLINE: At 6 months after standard of care treatment, patients receive 10 sessions of personalized dietary intervention over 30 minutes each over 4 months via the telephone. Patients also receive a workbook including reference materials and intervention content. After completion of study, patients are followed up for 6 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Intestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of stage IIII cancers of the rectosigmoid colon or rectum 6 months posttreatment completion Have a permanent ostomy or anastomosis Englishspeaking All subjects must have the ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent Patients with stage IV disease will be excluded from the study Subjects, who in the opinion of the investigator, may not be able to comply with the safety monitoring requirements of the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>