<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03063112</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study compares between the efficacy, safety and impact on the quality of life of radiofrequency thermocoagulation and chemical neurolysis of bilateral thoracic splanchnic nerves in the management of refractory pain which developed in patients suffering from upper abdominal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Radiofrequency and Chemical Neurolysis of Thoracic Splanchnic Nerve for Abdominal Cancer Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Radiofrequency thermocoagulation of splanchnic nerves was done bilaterally at level of thoracic vertebra T10 and T11 ( there were no enough studies done to test the efficacy, safety and impact on the quality of life of radiofrequency thermocoagulation of splanchnic nerves at level of T10 ). Aim of the Study is to compare between the efficacy, safety and impact on the quality of life of radiofrequency thermocoagulation of bilateral thoracic splanchnic nerves at level T10 and T11 vertebra and chemical neurolytic block of them at level of T11 vertebra only in the management of upper abdominal cancer pain.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Abdominal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients suffering from upper abdominal cancer pain. 2. Visceral pain with visual analogue pain score ≥ 4. 3. Normal coagulation profile. 4. Positive diagnostic test. 5. Written informed consent from the patients . 1. Patients with organ failure. 2. Coagulation disorders. 3. Local infection at the puncture site or sepsis. 4. Allergy to the contrast dye or alcohol. 5. Severe displacement of intraabdominal structures. 6. Pregnant women. 7. Documented metastatic lesions. 8. Psychiatric illness affecting cooperation. 9. Decompensated cardiac disorders. 10. Liver and renal dysfunction.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>