<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00619489</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This was an open-label study to provide an opportunity for participants with Ulcerative Colitis (UC) who previously completed Study C13002 (NCT01177228), and for treatment-naïve participants with UC or Crohn's Disease (CD) to receive treatment with vedolizumab, and to determine the long term safety of vedolizumab in patients afflicted with these diseases.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long Term Safety of Vedolizumab (MLN0002) in Patients With Ulcerative Colitis and Crohn's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This was a phase 2, multiple-dose, open-label study of vedolizumab administered intravenously (IV) every 8 weeks. The study population included treatment-naïve ulcerative colitis (UC) or Crohn's Disease (CD) participants, as well as 38 UC participants who had tolerated vedolizumab well during Study C13002 (NCT01177228). In the original study protocol, all participants were randomized to receive vedolizumab at doses of either 6 mg/kg or 10 mg/kg. With the implementation of Amendment 1, the assigned doses of vedolizumab were decreased to 2.0 mg/kg and 6.0 mg/kg. To implement the dose changes, instead of randomizing all participants across both doses, those who rolled over from Study C13002 were reassigned to receive the 2.0 mg/kg dose and all participants who entered C13004 naïve to treatment were to receive the 6.0 mg/kg dose, starting on the next scheduled dosing day. Also, if participants assigned to the 2 mg/kg dose experienced flare, they were to receive the higher 6 mg/kg dose. In the results analyses for this study, participants are grouped according to the lowest dose received, i.e., 2.0 mg/kg or 6.0 mg/kg vedolizumab.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vedolizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed and active ulcerative colitis (UC) or Crohn's Disease (CD) Crohn's Disease Activity Index (CDAI) Score of 220 450 for participants with CD Partial Mayo score of 2 7 for participants with UC Patient should be appropriate candidate for biologic therapy per guidelines Uptodate on cancer screening No severe systemic disease Patients with evidence of abscess Agree to comply with study procedures including contraception Low lymphocyte counts History of imaging abnormalities, multiple sclerosis (MS), brain tumor or other neurological illness Active or recent serious infections Recent treatment with biologic (i.e., Remicade) or investigational drug Impending surgery Any participants with vedolizumab human antihuman antibody (HAHA) titers ≥1:125 or with a previous immediate hypersensitivity reaction during or shortly after vedolizumab infusion</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>