<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00619827</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to assess the effect of grass pollen extract SLIT tablets on the Rhinoconjunctivitis Total Symptom Score (RTSS) of the six rhinoconjunctivitis symptoms in response to grass pollen challenge after one week, one, two and four months of treatment in patients suffering from Seasonal Allergic Rhinoconjunctivitis (SAR) due to grass pollen.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Sublingual Tablets of Grass Pollen Allergen Extract</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to determine whether SLIT tablets are effective on symptoms of allergic rhinitis compared to placebo in patients suffering from allergic rhinitis to grass pollen when exposed in an allergen chamber and also to determine the onset of action of SLIT tablets on allergic rhinitis symptoms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic, Seasonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female outpatients 1850 years old grass pollen rhinoconjunctivitis of at least 2 years. positive specific skin prick test and a specific IgE dosage level of at least 0.70 kU/L at screening. written consent a positive response to the baseline challenge test (RTSS reaches 7 at one timepoint at least during baseline challenge) Allergic rhinoconjunctivitis due to a cosensitisation, likely to significantly change the symptoms of the subject throughout the study Asthma requiring treatment other than shortacting beta2 inhaled agonists. Desensitisation treatment for grass pollen in the previous five years and current immunotherapy with another allergen.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sublingual immunotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Rhinitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Conjunctivitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Allergen challenge</keyword>
	<keyword>Allergen exposition chamber</keyword>
	<keyword>Grass pollen tablet</keyword>
	<keyword>Allergic rhinoconjunctivitis</keyword>
</DOC>