<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00619866</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to see how a research compound (NBI- 56418) works compared to placebo (also known as a sugar pill) in women with endometriosis and to see the effect, if any, on bone mineral density.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Efficacy and Safety Study of NBI-56418 in Endometriosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase II, multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled parallel-group study to assess the efficacy and safety of NBI-56418 at two dose levels administered once daily for up to 6 months. Approximately 150 subjects will be randomized (1:1:1) to one of the following treatment groups for the first 12 weeks of dosing: 150 mg NBI-56418 q.d.; 250 mg NBI-56418 q.d; or placebo q.d. Following 12 weeks of dosing, subjects will continue in the study for an additional 12 weeks; subjects randomized to NBI-56418 will continue to receive their assigned dose and subjects randomized to placebo will be re-randomized to receive one of the two doses of NBI-56418 for 12 weeks in a double-blind fashion. The effect of NBI-56418 treatment on bone mineral density (BMD) following 6 months of treatment with NBI-56418.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Endometriosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Be female, aged 18 to 49 years, inclusive Have moderate to severe pelvic pain due to endometriosis Have been surgically (laparoscopy) diagnosed with endometriosis within the last 8 years and have recurrent or persistent endometriosis symptoms Have regular menstrual cycle Have a Body Mass Index (BMI) of 18 to 36 kg/m2, inclusive Agree to use two forms of nonhormonal contraception during the study Exclusion Criteria Are currently receiving GnRH agonist or GnRH antagonist or have received any of these agents within 6 months of the start of screening Are currently receiving DMPASC or DMPAIM or have received any of these agents within 3 months of the start of screening Are currently using hormonal contraception or other forms of hormonal therapy or received such treatment within the last month Have had surgery for endometriosis within the last month Have had a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy Are using systemic steroids on a chronic or regular basis within 3 months Have uterine fibroids ≥3 cm in diameter Have pelvic pain that is not caused by endometriosis Have unstable medical condition or chronic disease Have been pregnant within the last six months Currently breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>bone mineral density</keyword>
	<keyword>NBI-56418</keyword>
	<keyword>estradiol</keyword>
	<keyword>Endometriosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Pelvic Pain</keyword>
</DOC>