<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01441583</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the IVORY Study is to gather data to support global submissions/approvals for some models of the Ingenio device family.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ingenio Device Algorithm Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>IVORY is a prospective, multi-center, randomized within-patient, single-blinded study to gather data to support Right Atrial Auto Threshold and RYTHMIQ</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sick Sinus Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who are willing and capable of providing informed consent to undergo a device implant and to participate in all testing associated with this clinical study; Subjects whose age is 18 or above, or of legal age to give informed consent specific to national law; Subjects indicated for a dual chamber pacemaker or a CRTP device according to class I or class II indications of the standard ESC or ACC / AHA implant guidelines; Subjects who are planned to be implanted with all leads intended for a specific device type (dual chamber pacemaker: atrial and right ventricular lead, CRTP: atrial, right and left ventricular lead) or are already implanted with such leads; Subjects who receive or are implanted with a bipolar atrial lead. Women of childbearing potential who are or might be pregnant at the time of the study (method of assessment upon physician's discretion); Enrolled in any other concurrent study, with the exception of local mandatory governmental registries and observational studies/registries that are not in conflict or affect Schedule of procedures for IVORY (i.e. should not cause additional or missed visits); Programming of devices for IVORY per CIP; IVORY outcome (i.e. involve medications that could affect the heart rate of the subject); Conduct of IVORY per GCP / ISO 14 155:2011 / local regulations. Subjects who live at such a distance from the clinic that travels for FU visits at a study center would be unusually difficult or burdensome for the subject; Inability or refusal to comply with the FU schedule; A life expectancy of less than 12 months, per physician discretion; Subjects who are planned to be programmed to a pacing mode other than DDD / DDDR during the study period.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>pacemaker, CRT-P, auto threshold</keyword>
</DOC>