<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01293435</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will collect real-life data from patients with community acquired pneumonia (CAP) OR complicated skin and skin structure infections (cSSSI) to assess the burden of the disease, review the treatment pathways, evaluate how health resources are used and identify any areas of unmet medical needs. The aim of the study is to compare how patients who are admitted to hospital with CAP or cSSSI are managed across Europe. This will be done by collecting data to understand the patient and disease characteristics, current practice of treatment, and outcomes for the patient. Overall 4000 patients will be recruited from 10 European countries.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Evaluating Management of Patients With Community-Acquired Pneumonia (CAP) or Complicated Skin Infections</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients hospitalised with CAP or cSSSI 1. CAP: Radiographicallyconfirmed bacterial pneumonia AND Requiring treatment with IV antimicrobials as startup therapy 2. cSSSI: Affecting deeper soft tissue and/or requiring significant surgical intervention or developing an abcess/ulcer/cellulitis in a lower limb AND Having at least two local signs and one systemic sign of cSSS AND Treatment with antimicrobials Patients already participating in clinical trials or any other interventional study. 1. CAP: CAP suitable for outpatient therapy with an oral antimicrobial agent. 2. cSSSI: Uncomplicated SSSI. Skin and skinstructure infections with a high cure rate after surgical incision alone or after aggressive local skin care.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Community Acquired Pneumonia (CAP)</keyword>
	<keyword>Complicated Skin and Skin Structures Infections (cSSSI)</keyword>
	<keyword>Complicated Skin and Soft Tissues Infections (cSSTI)</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibiotics</keyword>
	<keyword>Infection management</keyword>
	<keyword>Use of Resources</keyword>
	<keyword>MRSA</keyword>
	<keyword>PRSP</keyword>
</DOC>