<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01293669</DOC>
	<brief_summary>TC-6987 is a selective nicotinic α-7 receptor ligand (open channel stabilizer) that has demonstrated potent anti-inflammatory/antioxidant properties in animal models. Following the oral administration of a 1mg/kg dose of TC-6987 to diabetic mice (db/db mouse) for 7 weeks, numerous metabolic improvements were observed. Specifically, plasma glucose and triglyceride concentrations declined by approximately 30%; Hb1Ac was reduced by nearly 50%; and TNF-α declined more than 60% relative to control db/db mice Therefore, it appears that TC-6987 could prove beneficial in reducing elevated glucose concentrations in diabetic patients as well as in ameliorating organ damage associated with inflammation, oxidative stress and hyperglycemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Glycemic Control, Safety and Tolerability of TC-6987 Monotherapy in Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase II, multicenter, randomized, double-blind, parallel group, placebo-controlled study to assess the efficacy, safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetic parameters of TC-6987 in subjects with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). The study is organized into three phases: (a) Screening phase consisting of a 1-week Screening (Week -5)and a 4-week Washout (Week -4 to Day 1); (b) 4-week, Double-Blind Treatment (Day 1 to Week 4) during which subjects are randomized to either TC-6987 (20 mg on Day 1 and 10 mg from Day 2 to Week 4) or placebo; and (c) 2-week Follow-Up (Week 6). Unscheduled visits will be allowed between visits from Washout through Follow-up to evaluate a subject's glycemic status or other safety issues, as required. Subjects will fast overnight for a minimum of 10 hrs and refrain from drinking alcohol 24 hrs prior to each visit.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males or postmenopausal/surgically sterile females Being treated for T2DM with oral antidiabetic agents (excluding glitazones) BMI limit ≤ 38 Subjects at least 80% compliant on reporting daily SMBG values during washout At the end of washout the subject's fasting SMBG is higher than it was at the start of washout and the fasting SMBG ≤ 280.g treated for T2DM with oral antidiabetic agents (excluding glitazones) Type 1 diabetes mellitus Severe complications of T2DM (especially diabetic retinopathy imminently requiring treatment for preserving or restoring vision, diabetic neuropathy with symptomatic orthostatic hypotension, urinary retention, gastric stasis, or pedal ulcers) Current treatment with insulin or a glitazone Use of moderate to strong cytochrome P450 3A4 (CYP3A4) inhibitors FSH level of &lt; 35 IU/L and a LH level &lt; 25 IU/L except for confirmed surgically sterile women with functioning ovaries Significant cardiovascular diseases (including arrhythmia) or congestive heart failure, or severe ischemic disease within the last 3 months prior to Screening, or evidence of stroke, myocardial infarction, unstable angina, coronary bypass and/or percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty History of significant other major or unstable neurological, metabolic, hepatic, renal, hematological, pulmonary, CV, GI, or urological disorder; or diagnosis of major depressive disorder; if stable medical disorder, any medical treatment must be stable for last 2 months prior to Screening History of diabetic ketoacidosis Patients who have an increased red blood cell (RBC) turnover or thalassemia or anemia Known HIV or history of viral hepatitis type B or C Systemic infection with TB Current or previous use of oral or injectable corticosteroids 3 months prior to screening. Subject has persistent, uncontrolled severe hypertension as indicated by a systolic blood pressure &gt; 180 mmHg or a diastolic blood pressure of &gt; 110 mmHg, with or without treatment Subject has had a malignancy in the last 5 years, except for successfully treated basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or of the cervix Subject is receiving chemotherapy Tobacco user within 4 months prior to Screening Smoking cessation therapy within 4 months prior to Screening and/or planned during the study Use of prohibited concomitant medications including psychoactive agents History within 6 months prior to Screening of alcohol abuse or illicit drug abuse Was administered study medication in another clinical trial in the past 3 months prior to Screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
</DOC>