<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02894983</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There is no consensus about the best conservative treatment for patients with dorsally displaced distal radius fractures. The previous studies that have examined the most valid method for cast immobilization have lacked uniform and patient-rated outcome measures, proper randomization and sufficient study population. The aim of this study is to compare functional position cast to flexion-ulnar -deviation with dorsally displaced distal radius fractures in patients aged 65 years or older. The conservative treatment is performed in clinical practice by various health care professionals with different techniques of reduction which are not limited to any specific technique in this pragmatic, randomized controlled trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Conservative Treatment of Distal Radius Fracture in Elderly in Randomized Controlled Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Radius Fractures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colles' Fracture</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calpastatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Low energy intra or extraarticular dorsally displaced distal radius fracture within 3 cm of the radiocarpal joint diagnosed with lateral and posterioranterior radiographs in ER Physician oncall (general practitioner, acute physician, orthopedic resident, orthopedic consult) thinks patient could be appropriate for nonoperative treatment Operative treatment Refuse to participate the study Open fracture more than Gustilo 1 gradus Age under 65 years Chauffeure's or Barton´s fracture Smith´s fracture (volar angulation of the fracture) Does not understand written and spoken guidance in local languages Pathological fracture or previous fracture in the same wrist, forearm or elbow</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>wrist fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>colles fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>non-operative</keyword>
	<keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
</DOC>