<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02894658</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The LipiFlow System (TearScience, Morrisville, NC) is an in-office FDA approved treatment for meibomian gland dysfunction. It relieves meibomian gland obstruction through the use of heat and pulsatile pressure. A recent study has observed that a single treatment with the LipiFlow system can decrease dry eye symptoms and objective findings of meibomian gland dysfunction for 1 year. We aim to see if the Lipiflow System will be beneficial in patients with Parkinsons disease who may have difficulty performing normal meibomian gland dysfunction treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lipiflow Versus Warm Compresses in Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objectives To determine whether a single treatment with thermal pulsation relieves dry eye symptoms (primary objective) and improves objective findings of meibomian gland dysfunction in patients with Parkinsons disease. Methods and Measures Design - Randomized, controlled trial - Patient eyes will be randomized to either receive a single thermal pulsation treatment the FDA-approved Lipiflow thermal pulsation system or to use traditional eyelid hygiene or to use traditional eyelid hygiene</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with Parkinsons disease and dry eye attributed to meibomian gland dysfunction Medical diagnosis of Parkinsons disease &gt; 18 yearsold Reported dry eye symptoms within 3 months of baseline examination with a Standard Patient Evaluation for Eye Dryness (SPEED) score ≥ 6 at baseline visit Evidence of meibomian gland obstruction (based on a total meibomian gland secretion score of ≤ 12 for 15 glands of the lower lid) Willingness to stop dry eye medications including antibiotics, nonsteroidal and antiinflammatory drugs, and corticosteroids for 2 weeks prior to treatment and during the duration of the study Active intraocular inflammation Ocular surface abnormality that could potentially compromise corneal integrity in either eye</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>