<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02894437</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the Protocol is the prevention of pelvic pressure ulcers within a care network of SCI patients whose general organization refers to the medical literature and the recommendations of the ministerial circular of 18 June 2004. A conceptual framework for work (CFW) will be set up and semi-structured interviews will be conducted with patients and professionals. They will confirm or dismiss the CFW gradually with a refined coding As of domains and sub-domains of the skin preventing spinal cord injury related to the perceptions and behaviors of those involved in the sector. Quality control will be provided by experts in qualitative research and interviews will be stopped when the analyzes will further refine the domains and subdomains. A final framework will be validated to modulate our organization.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Qualitative Study of Preventive Organization of the Pelvic Bedsores Injured Spinal Cord</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pressure Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Paying patients: Spinal cord injured person from any level of injury and any posttraumatic period Age 18 to 65 years inclusive Person affiliated to the social security or receiving such a plan Main ambulation mode: Wheelchair Agreeing to participate in interviews Professional side: Medical and paramedical health professionals involved in the care sector or studied various professionals (administrators, insurers, ...) involved in the studied care sector Agreeing to participate in interviews Minors or patients older than 65 years Person unable to consent Who do not speak the French language Person refusing to attend meetings Hospitalized person without consent Cognitive pathologies incompatible with interviews Main wandering mode of patients: walking Protected adults</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>organization</keyword>
	<keyword>pressure ulcers</keyword>
</DOC>