<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03040544</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: Laparoscopic surgical procedures have become increasingly established in operative medicine. They require special motor, haptic, and spatial-visual skills to perform the interventions safely and effectively. The basic skills are often learned in the operating room on the patient. This is economically inefficient and can be improved with regard to patient safety. Against the background of this problem, various simulators were developed in order to train laparoscopic basic skills outside the surgery. The Lübecker Toolbox (LTB) curriculum is a video-based trainer, which - unlike the other trainees on the market - has standardized and validated exercises with concrete targets, based on the skills of experts in minimally invasive surgery (MIC). Against the background of different, non-validated training programs and simulators with ambiguous objectives, it is not known how training programs and simulators improve the skills of the advanced physicians in performing laparoscopic-assisted operations. An evidence of effectiveness in the practice transfer could have a considerable relevance with regard to the integration of the training programs into the specialist doctoral training. Aim of the study: The aim of the study is to investigate whether physicians in the first years of further education are able to improve laparoscopic skills required to perform laparoscopic operations, if they have successfully completed the LTB curriculum. In the prospective study, the subjects are randomized into two groups, one group completing the LTB curriculum after the first own laparoscopic cholecystectomy and the other not. After 2 months, both groups will perform their first laparoscopic cholecystectomy again. The laparoscopic video recordings will be analysed and compared using the Global Operational Assessment of Laparoscopic Skill (GOALS) score.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized Study to Investigate Laparoscopic Skills by Physicians in the First Year of Further Education After Completing the "Lübeck Toolbox Curriculum" (NOVICE Study)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Possession of an approbation to the medical doctor in Germany. Physician in first year of further education as specialist for general or visceral surgery. Conducting further training as a specialist for general or visceral surgery in a clinic / department with a corresponding qualification as a specialist for visceral or general surgery The examiner has declared his / her consent to participate in the study and to go through the LTB curriculum. The participant has not yet completed any other simulation or training programs for the training of laparoscopic surgical techniques. Before the start of the study, the examiner did not perform a laparoscopic procedure as the first operator, but merely assisted an operative during laparoscopic procedures. there should be no motor or sensory impairments which limit the manual skills</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>minimally invasive surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>video-based trainer</keyword>
</DOC>