<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03040973</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The rollover study will provide continued treatment and assessment of long-term safety follow-up in patients receiving capmatinib (INC280) in a Novartis sponsored study and in the opinion of the Investigator would benefit from continued treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Roll-over Study for Patients With cMET-dependent Malignancies Who Previously Completed a Novartis Capmatinib Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Patient is currently receiving treatment with INC280 monotherapy within a Novartissponsored study which has fulfilled the requirements for the primary objective and, in the opinion of the Investigator, would benefit from continued treatment. Willingness and ability to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plans and any other study procedures. Written informed consent obtained prior to enrolling in the rollover study and receiving study medication. If consent cannot be expressed in writing, it must be formally documented and witnessed, ideally via an independent trusted witness. Patient has been previously permanently discontinued from INC280 study treatment in the parent study due to any reason. Patient currently has unresolved toxicities for which INC280 dosing has been interrupted in the parent study (Patients meeting all other eligibility criteria may be enrolled once toxicities have resolved to allow INC280 dosing to resume). Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women. Women of childbearing potential, defined as all women physiologically capable of becoming pregnant, unless they are using highly effective methods of contraception during dosing and for 7 days after stopping treatment. Sexually active males unless they use a condom during intercourse while taking drug and for 7 days after stopping treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>capmatinib</keyword>
	<keyword>cMET</keyword>
	<keyword>advanced solid tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
</DOC>