<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03040128</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To date, no neuroprotective drugs have demonstrated clinical efficacy in intracerebral hemorrhage (ICH). This study will use intravenous (IV) minocycline in ICH to evaluate for (1) safety/ tolerability and (2) evaluate for clinical efficacy</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of Minocycline in Intracerebral Hemorrhage</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Intracerebral hemorrhage (ICH) remains a devastating neurological disorder with high mortality and poor prognosis with unchanged mortality rates (53-59%). Acute treatment options for ICH remain supportive with no available effective drug or surgical therapy. All trials so far have failed to improve clinical outcome in randomized, double-blinded trials. However, one area of interest has been maintaining the integrity of the blood-brain-barrier (BBB) and preventing the growth of vasogenic edema. Matrix metalloproteinases (MMP) are a family of ubiquitous zinc-dependent endopeptidase enzymes whose primary function is the digestion of collagen type IV, laminin, and fibronectin for the purpose of remodeling extracellular basal lamina. Elevated MMP-9 as a pathological process associated with larger hematoma volume, larger perihematomal edema, and poorer clinical outcome in intracerebral hemorrhage is well documented in animal models and patients. One particular MMP-9 inhibitor gaining usage in cerebrovascular disease is minocycline. Normally FDA-approved for bacterial infection and acne vulgaris, minocycline has also been found to be both a safe and effective treatment in ischemic stroke; its potential role as a neuroprotectant in ischemic stroke is currently being tested in a large, randomized, double-blinded trial. Minocycline's beneficial role as a neuroprotectant may also extend to ICH. By inhibiting MMP-9, minocycline may decrease BBB permeability, resulting in less perihematomal edema and decreased mass effect. Although numerous animal ICH models support minocycline's role as an inhibitor of MMP-9 and neuroprotectant, its use has never been studied in humans with ICH.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Minocycline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 1. Age 1880 yo 2. Acute neurological deficit with corresponding ICH noted on head CT 3. Glasgow Coma Scale (GCS) &gt; 8 4. Onset of symptoms within 12 hrs 5. &lt; 30 ml of blood noted on initial CTH (30 ml hematoma volume is a noted independent marker between good and poor clinical outcome) 6. ICH score &lt; 3 7. English/ Spanish speaking 1. Allergy to tetracycline and tetracycline analogues 2. Pregnancy or suspected pregnancy 3. Hepatic and/or renal insufficiency (LFTs 3x greater than upper limit of normal; creatinine &gt; 2 mg/dL) 4. Thrombocytopenia (plt count &lt; 75,000) 5. History of intolerance to minocycline 6. Baseline modified Rankin score &gt; 1 7. Stuporous or comatose (GCS &lt; 8) 8. Presence of concomitant serious illness that would confound study, including serious psychiatric disease or prior suicide attempts.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>