<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02652442</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Recent studies suggest that otolith dysfunction is a common finding in individuals with a history of head trauma/blast exposure and/or noise-induced hearing loss. Therefore, otolith dysfunction may be a significant health concern for the Veteran population, and determining optimal intervention strategies for otolith dysfunction is important for VA healthcare. The purpose of this project is to compare the effectiveness of standard vestibular rehabilitation compared to a novel treatment approach, centrifugation, in the treatment of individuals with otolith dysfunction.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vestibular Rehabilitation and Otolith Dysfunction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary function of the vestibular (inner ear balance) system is to maintain gaze and postural stability. The vestibular system is comprised of two types of sensory organs (semicircular canals and otolith organs) each with unique contributions to balance. Vestibular Rehabilitation (VR) is the treatment of choice for patients experiencing dizziness, imbalance, and mobility impairments related to vestibular dysfunction. VR typically includes gaze stability exercises, gait and balance training, and general conditioning. Gaze stability exercises were developed based on the concepts of adaptation and substitution with the goal of improving gaze stability by facilitating vestibular compensation of the semicircular canal-mediated vestibulo-ocular reflex (VOR). Many factors that might influence recovery, such as the involvement of different vestibular sensory organs (semicircular canals versus otolith organs) have not been examined to determine their impact on recovery. Most studies examining the effectiveness of VR have used only tests of VOR function (caloric and rotational tests) that measure hSCC to determine vestibular loss. Thus, little is known about interventions to facilitate vestibular compensation of the otolith organs. Recent studies have demonstrated adaptation following otolith organ stimulation using centrifugation (or linear acceleration). The concept of using centrifugation for otolith adaptation may be similar to using gaze stability exercises for VOR adaptation. Participants with dizziness/imbalance related to otolith dysfunction will be randomized to receive a staged intervention of either gaze stability exercises (n=14) or centrifugation (n=14) followed by balance rehabilitation. Providing the intervention in stages allows isolation of key components of vestibular rehabilitation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dizziness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vertigo</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 18 years of age Documented balance or mobility problems Isolated otolith dysfunction Progressive neurological disorders and central vestibular abnormalities Benign paroxysmal positional vertigo Superior semicircular canal dehiscence Middleear pathology with conductive hearing loss Lower extremity joint replacement Cognitive impairment (Mini Mental Status Exam &lt; 24/30) Severe depression (geriatric depression scale 10) Severe anxiety (geriatric anxiety inventory 11/30) Bestcorrected visual acuity worse than 20/40 in the better eye</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>69 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>dizziness</keyword>
	<keyword>postural balance</keyword>
	<keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
</DOC>