<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02843399</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary objective of this study is to compare diabetes-related healthcare utilization and costs in patients initiating exenatide once weekly vs insulin glargine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Economic Outcomes of EQW (Exenatide Once Weekly) vs. IG (Insulin Glargine) in T2D Patients Who Are New to Injectable Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This retrospective, observational cohort analysis will assess medical and pharmacy claims for adult patients with type 2 diabetes from the Truven Health MarketScan® Commercial and Medicare Supplemental claims databases between 2011 and 2015. Diabetes-related healthcare utilization and costs will be measured as a primary outcome. Secondary outcomes include all-cause healthcare utilization and costs, major adverse cardiovascular event (MACE)-related utilization and costs, and medically attended hypoglycemia events.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Exenatide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Glargine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. One or more outpatient prescription claim for EQW (Exenatide Once Weekly) vs. IG (Insulin Glargine) between February 1, 2012, and June 30, 2014 (date of first claim = index date; medication to which first claim corresponds = index therapy). 2. Aged 18 or older as of the index date. 3. Continuous enrollment in medical and pharmacy benefits for 12 months before (baseline period) and 12 months after (followup period) the index date. (6 months followup will be provided to determine the effect on sample size.) 4. One or more medical claims with a diagnosis code for T2DM (ICD9CM 250.x0 or 250.x2) in the baseline period or on the index date. 1. No outpatient prescription claims for any injectable glucoselowering medication during the baseline period (GLP1RA or insulins). 2. No medical claims with a diagnosis (or procedure, where appropriate) code indicative for type 1 diabetes mellitus (ICD9CM 250.x1 or 250.x3), gestational diabetes (ICD9CM 648.8x), or pregnancy or childbirth in the baseline or followup periods.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus Type 2</keyword>
</DOC>