<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01168271</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Malaria caused by Plasmodium falciparum continues to be a global problem with devastating consequences. A greater understanding of the immunologic and parasitologic factors associated with infection and disease is badly needed, and will accelerate the development of highly protective vaccines for both mothers and children. Pregnancy malaria is associated with low birth weight, maternal anemia, and gestational hypertension, and both inflammation and the fetal response to infection may contribute to these poor outcomes. Childhood malaria is a major cause of mortality, and we have found that risk of childhood malaria is related to in utero exposure to pregnancy malaria, as well as other host factors like iron status and constitutive cytokine levels. Pregnancy malaria is caused by a distinct parasite binding phenotype, and as our primary hypothesis in this study we speculate that severe childhood malaria parasites may also have distinct features. A longitudinal cohort study will be conducted in Ouelessebougou, Mali an area of intense seasonal transmission. Up to 2000 pregnant women and their infants and 2000 children ages 0 - 3 will be enrolled and followed to age 5 years, with clinical evaluation and periodic venous and peripheral blood samples obtained. In addition, 2000 febrile children up to age 10 years will be enrolled at the Ouelessebougou district health centers or the Gabriel Tour(SqrRoot)(Copyright) Pediatric Hospital in Bamako, Mali, with acute and convalescent samples being obtained and 500 pregnant women enrolled at the health centers and hospital in Ouelessebougou district or the Gabriel Tour(SqrRoot)(Copyright) Hospital in Bamako for a case-control study on pregnancy malaria and preeclampsia. Clinical, parasitologic and host response (including immunologic) endpoints will be analyzed using appropriate statistical methods, including possible confounders, to determine factors associated with infection and disease in pregnant woman and young children.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Host and Parasite Factors That Influence Susceptibility to Malaria Infection and Disease During Pregnancy and Early Childhood in Ouelessebougou and Bamako, Mali</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Malaria caused by Plasmodium falciparum continues to be a global problem with devastating consequences. A greater understanding of the immunologic and parasitologic factors associated with infection and disease is badly needed, and will accelerate the development of highly protective vaccines for both mothers and children. Pregnancy malaria is associated with low birth weight, maternal anemia, and gestational hypertension, and both inflammation and the fetal response to infection may contribute to these poor outcomes. Childhood malaria is a major cause of mortality, and we have found that risk of childhood malaria is related to in utero exposure to pregnancy malaria, as well as other host factors like iron status and constitutive cytokine levels. Pregnancy malaria is caused by a distinct parasite binding phenotype, and as our primary hypothesis in this study we speculate that severe childhood malaria parasites may also have distinct features. A longitudinal cohort study will be conducted in Ouelessebougou, Mali an area of intense seasonal transmission. Up to 2000 pregnant women and their infants and 2000 children ages 0 - 3 will be enrolled and followed to age 5 years, with clinical evaluation and periodic venous and peripheral blood samples obtained. In addition, 2000 febrile children up to age 10 years will be enrolled at the Ouelessebougou district health centers or the Gabriel Tour(SqrRoot)(Copyright) Pediatric Hospital in Bamako, Mali, with acute and convalescent samples being obtained and 500 pregnant women enrolled at the health centers and hospital in Ouelessebougou district or the Gabriel Tour(SqrRoot)(Copyright) Hospital in Bamako for a case-control study on pregnancy malaria and preeclampsia. Clinical, parasitologic and host response (including immunologic) endpoints will be analyzed using appropriate statistical methods, including possible confounders, to determine factors associated with infection and disease in pregnant woman and young children.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Disease Susceptibility</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: A study participant must satisfy the following criteria to be enrolled in this study: 1. Pregnant women aged 1545 years and their newborn infants who are residents of the district of Ouelessebougou for at least one year at the time of enrollment; OR 2. Children aged 3 years or less, who are residents of the district of Ouelessebougou for at least one year at the time of enrollment; OR 3. Febrile hospitalized children (aged 0 10 years), including those with positive and negative blood smears for P. falciparum in Ouelessebougou or the pediatric service of Gabriel Toure Hospital in Bamako and pregnant women aged 1525 in Ouelessebougou district health centers or maternity unit of Gabriel Toure Hospital iin Bamako for a casecontrol study of pregnancy malaria and preeclampsia. Cases include women with signs/symptoms of preeclampsia. Control pregnant women without signs/symptoms of preeclampsia will be recruited sequentially after identification of individual cases, matched for parity, age (+/2 years) and pregnancy trimester. 4. The study participant or parent/guardian understands the study and gives informed consent for participation of themselves and/or their child and agrees to have samples stored. EXCLUSION CRITERIA: A participant will be excluded from the study if any one or more of the following criteria are met: 1. Chronic, debilitating illness, other than malaria, determined by history and physical examination fo mother or study participant. 2. Conditions that in the judgment of the investigator could increase the risk to the volunteer. 3. History of previous participation in a malaria vaccine trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 15, 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Observational</keyword>
	<keyword>Newborns</keyword>
	<keyword>Hospitalized</keyword>
	<keyword>Febrile</keyword>
	<keyword>Resistance</keyword>
</DOC>