<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00142376</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is a chart review of all children admitted over a two year period with the diagnosis of acute respiratory distress syndrome. Short term outcomes, such as mortality, length of ventilation and length of stay, will be reviewed. Factors that impact these outcomes will also be reviewed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Short Term Outcomes of Children With Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We would like to conduct a chart review of all patients with pediatric ARDS hospitalized in the PICU at Columbus Children’s Hospital in the last two years. Patients would be included for review if they met the clinical criteria for ARDS. These criteria are: rapidly progressive respiratory failure, severe hypoxemia (PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 200), and evidence of bilateral pulmonary infiltrate on chest radiography. We estimate 40-50 patients will meet criteria. Once criteria are met, patient charts will be pulled or reviewed electronically. We will then compose a database that includes no patient identifiers but contains information regarding the cause, length, and outcome of the ARDS admission and PICU stay. Factors such as nutritional status, antibiotic and muscle relaxant use, and type of ventilation used will be examined. Other care-related variables will be included if they are felt to impact outcome during the review process. The database will then be analyzed and information regarding pediatric ARDS outcomes in our institution will be published. We anticipate that examining the factors that impact short term outcomes in pediatric ARDS will lead to research possibilities regarding ways to improve both short and long term outcomes in children with this illness. We propose that reviewing the disease entity as a whole will lead to improvements in caring for children with the disease, and eventually bring about a decline in mortality rates.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Rapidly progressive respiratory failure, Severe hypoxemia (PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 200), Evidence of bilateral pulmonary infiltrate on chest radiography 018 years of age Heart failure Cardiac shunt present</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2004</verification_date>
</DOC>