<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02767661</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is designed to compare the clinical benefit following treatment with aromatase inhibitor in combination with metronomic capecitabine versus aromatase inhibitor alone in women with hormone receptor-positive, Her2-negative advanced breast cancer who have not received prior systemic anti-cancer therapies for their advanced/metastatic disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Metronomic Capecitabine Plus Aromatase Inhibitor for First Line Treatment in HR(+), Her2(-) Metastatic Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Initial endocrine therapy (ET) is a common choice for hormone receptor positive (HR+), HER2 negative (HER2-) metastatic breast cancer (MBC) patients for its good tolerability, low toxicity and durable response. The median time to progression (TTP) of initial ET in HR+, HER2- metastatic patients is about 9 months with aromatase inhibitors (AIs). However, all metastatic patients receiving ET will develop resistance to the conventional endocrine treatments ultimately. So some novel agents, like palbociclib and everolimus, are approved to be effective in improving the efficacy of standard ET. But the fact we have to face is either palbociclib or everolimus is focusing on a single checkpoint of pathway that responsible for resistance of ET. In clinical, there are some patients without an activation of resistance-related pathways have poor response to endocrine therapy. And the mechanisms of resistance to endocrine therapy is complicated and not fully understood. So far, these novel agents have not completely solved the clinical problems of secondary drug-resistance. Maybe a broad spectrum anti-cancer therapy with low toxicity and good tolerability is more practical and promising in the near future. Metronomic chemotherapy is administration of low-dose chemotherapy to induce disease control in metastatic cancer patients, which has low-incidence of adverse effects. More and more evidences showed activity of metronomic therapy in breast cancer. Metronomic therapy with or without endocrine therapy in both metastatic and neoadjuvant setting showed considerable efficacy. Although the concept of combination of chemotherapy and endocrine therapy simultaneously was large abandoned because of previous using tamoxifen and intravenous chemotherapy showing no additional benefit, with better understanding of the biology of endocrine therapy and metronomic chemotherapy, it's worth to evaluate whether endocrine therapy plus low-dose metronomic chemotherapy brings a better clinical benefit rate without sacrificing the quality of patients' life. In this phase III study, we investigate the efficacy and safety of low-dose capecitabine plus AI to treat metastatic HR+, HER2- postmenopausal breast cancer patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Exemestane</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anastrozole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Letrozole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aromatase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult women with locoregionally recurrent or metastatic disease not amenable to curative therapy Confirmed diagnosis of ER positive/Her2negative breast cancer No prior systemic anticancer therapy for advanced ER+ disease Any menopausal status On a luteinizing hormone releasing hormone (LHRH) agonist for at least 28 days, if pre/perimenopausal, and willing to switch to goserelin (Zoladex ®) at time of randomization Measurable disease defined by RECIST version 1.1, or boneonly disease Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) 01 Adequate organ and marrow function Resolution of all toxic effects of prior therapy or surgical procedures Patient must agree to provide tumor tissue from metastatic tissue at baseline Patients with advanced, symptomatic, visceral spread that are at risk of life threatening complication in the short term Known uncontrolled or symptomatic central nervous system metastases Second primary malignancy(except in situ carcinoma of the cervix or adequately treated nonmelanomatous carcinoma of the skin) Serious uncontrolled intercurrent infections or intercurrent medical or psychiatric illness</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>metronomic capecitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>aromatase inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>first line treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>