<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02767310</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the bioequivalence of Rosuvastatin/ Verisfield 20 mg film-coated tablets and Crestor™/ AstraZeneca 20 mg film-coated tablets.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Determine the Bioequivalence of Two Products Containing Rosuvastatin (20 mg/Tablet)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study aims to compare the absorption and disposition kinetics of two products containing rosuvastatin under fasting conditions. These products are: Rosuvastatin/ Verisfield 20 mg film-coated tablets, a Test product manufactured by HELP S.A., Greece and Crestor™/ AstraZeneca 20 mg film-coated tablets, a Reference product manufactured by AstraZeneca, UK. The bioequivalence of a single 20 mg dose of both products will be assessed by comparing the pharmacokinetic parameters derived from the plasma concentration-time profiles for rosuvastatin.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rosuvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Willingness to provide informed consent to participate in the study. Comprehension of the nature and purpose of the study and willingness to comply with the requirements of the entire procedure. Healthy adult, human Indian volunteers within the age range of 18 to 45 years (both inclusive). Body Mass Index (BMI) ≥ 18.50 kg/m2 to ≤ 30.00 kg/m2. Hemoglobin: ≥12.0 gm% for male and ≥11.5 gm% for female. Absence of disease markers of HIV I &amp; II, HBsAg, HCVAb and P24 antigen test. Females of childbearing age must be practicing an acceptable form of birth control for at least six months before screening, unless they have had bilateral oophorectomy or tubal ligation or their male partner has had vasectomy. Females of childbearing age agree to use acceptable form of birth control during the study and until the drug is washed out from the body, i.e. at least 14 days after last dosing, unless they have had bilateral oophorectomy or tubal ligation or their male partner has had vasectomy. Absence of significant disease or clinically significant abnormal laboratory values during the laboratory evaluations. Absence of any diseases in medical history or physical examination during the screening. Have a normal 12lead ECG or one with abnormality considered clinically insignificant. Have a normal chest Xray (P. A. view). Non smokers (since last six months) Negative serum βHCG at the time of screening (for females only) History / evidence of allergy or hypersensitivity to rosuvastatin or to any of the excipients or to any other drug. Any major illness within the last three months or any significant ongoing chronic medical illness. History of or active liver or kidney disease. History of or active deep vein thrombosis and thromboembolic disorders. History of breast cancer, endometrial cancer or other estrogendependent neoplasia, endometriosis and undiagnosed vaginal bleeding (for females only). History of drug abuse (including barbiturates, benzodiazepines, opioids, cocaine, cannabinoids and amphetamine etc.) within the last three months. History of neuropsychiatric diseases. History of hypothyroidism. Personal or family history of hereditary muscular disorders. History of myopathy. History of myalgia. History of rhabdomyolysis. History of alcohol abuse. History of proteinuria. Asian population (except Indian). History of interstitial lung disease. History of or current gastrointestinal diseases influencing drug absorption. History of alcoholism (more than two years), moderate drinkers (more than three drinks per day). Participation in any clinical trial within last three months. History of difficulty with donating blood or difficulty in accessibility of veins in left or right arm. Donation of blood (one unit or 350 mL or more) within last three months. Use of any prescription drug therapy within last two weeks and over the counter (OTC) drugs or herbal products within last one week. Pregnant women. Breast feeding women.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bioequivalence</keyword>
	<keyword>two rosuvastatin-containing products</keyword>
</DOC>