<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02767570</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Nearly one out of every two Americans will develop knee osteoarthritis by age 85. Over 20 million Americans, including nearly three million Veterans, currently have painful knee arthritis that limits their daily activity or recreation. The vast majority of those individuals will be prescribed anti-inflammatory drugs that provide some pain relief but do not slow the progression of the disease. Often people with knee arthritis are told they must live with the pain until they become appropriate candidates for knee replacement surgery, but that can require tolerating the pain and limiting function for many years. Because of other health issues, some individuals are never acceptable surgery candidates. What is desperately needed are better conservative approaches for treating these patients. Two such approaches will be tested and compared in this study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-Term Effectiveness of Walking Training in Patients With Knee Osteoarthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a randomized controlled trial to investigate conservative treatments for individuals with painful knee osteoarthritis (OA). The study will recruit participants who have isolated, medial compartment knee OA. Subjects will be assigned to one of two gait training groups. Both groups will undergo gait analysis to determine their foot progression angle at their comfortable walking speed. Both groups will receive personalized gait retraining to either alter their foot progression angle or to achieve consistency of their natural foot progression angle. Gait retraining will consist of once a week sessions for six weeks. The gait training will use a fading feedback approach, where the percentage of each weekly session during which feedback is used is decreased from week to week until no feedback is used by the last training session. Throughout the six-week training period subjects will be encouraged to practice their gait for at least ten minutes per day. Subjects will continue to practice their gait throughout the remainder of the 52-week intervention. Subjects will have their walking activity recorded using a 3-axis pedometer, and smart shoes that will log their foot progression angle under free-living conditions. Compared to their baseline walking activity, participants will be instructed to increase their daily walking by ten minutes per day throughout the 52-week intervention. All subjects will receive monthly phone calls to encourage maintaining a regular walking regimen. Walking activity will be monitored periodically using a pedometer. Subjects will receive knee MRIs and weight-bearing knee radiographs at the start and end of the study. All participants will complete visual analog pain evaluations and clinical knee score questionnaires during the study. The investigators expect that subjects in both groups will have a reduction in knee pain over the course of the 52-week intervention. The primary objective of the study it to determine if there is change in pain between baseline and week 52 is different between the two groups.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosed with isolated, medial compartment knee OA of at least six months duration KellgrenLawrence grade of I, II, or III Age greater than 18 years at the time of enrollment Ability to give informed consent Knee pain three days per week on average Average knee pain of 27.5 mm or greater on a 100 mm visual analog scale and less than 90 Ambulatory without aids Able to walk for at least 25 consecutive minutes Able to walk on treadmill safely Able to reduce the prominent peak of the knee adduction moment by changing foot progression angle Body mass index equal to or greater than 35 Pregnancy Plans for knee replacement within the next 12 months Contraindications to MRI Nerve or muscle disease associated with walking difficulty Narcotic pain medication usage History of rheumatoid arthritis, gout or pseudogout, or autoimmune disease History of neuropathic arthropathy, infectious disease, or other major systemic diseases History of symptomatic arthritis in lower limb joints other than the knees History of lower limb fracture or surgery requiring hospitalization Lateral tibiofemoral joint space width less than medial Mechanical knee symptoms (e.g., catching or locking) indicative of clinically significant meniscal pathology Significant meniscal or ligament pathology based on magnetic resonance imaging Physical examination findings of a positive McMurray or Apley test Recurrent giving way of the knee Finding of a positive Lachman test Positive anterior or posterior drawer test Symptoms originating from the patellofemoral joint Avascular necrosis History of knee buckling or recent (within two months) knee injury Replacement of any lower extremity joint Use of a hinged knee brace within the past six months Current or recent past use (within two months) of oral corticosteroids Severe knee malalignment of more than 5 degrees from neutral Intraarticular injection within the past 2 months or planned for the next 12 months Cognitive impairments that would limit a subject's understanding Expecting a significant change in activity level or weight within the next 12 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Osteoarthritis, Knee</keyword>
	<keyword>Arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>Joint Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Musculoskeletal Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Rheumatic Diseases</keyword>
</DOC>