<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="27063">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02754414</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2016 - 01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02754414</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cold Apheresis Platelets in Isoplate</brief_title>
  <acronym>CAPI</acronym>
  <official_title>Cold Apheresis Platelets in Isoplate</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bloodworks (Puget Sound Blood Center)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bloodworks (Puget Sound Blood Center)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a platelet transfusion study. The purpose of this study is to measure the life span
      and quality of platelets preserved in an additive solution and stored in a refrigerator.
      Participants will give platelets by apheresis. Platelets will be stored for 3 -20 days. A
      small portion of the subject's own stored platelets will be tagged with a radioactive
      isotope and infused back into the participant. This will enable us to track how many
      transfused platelets survive after storage in the refrigerator.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A double hyperconcentrated apheresis platelet unit will be collected from a healthy adult
      volunteer subject using the Trima Accel® Automated Blood Collection System. Concurrent
      plasma will be collected. After collection the unit will be split into two equal portions
      and will be re-suspended in 65% Isoplate (a platelet additive solution) and 35% plasma while
      the other half will be suspended in plasma. Both units will achieve a final platelet
      concentration of ~1500 x 103 platelets/μL. Both units will be stored, without agitation, at
      4°C. The plasma suspended unit (control) will be stored for 3 days, the maximum platelet
      storage time allowed for refrigerated platelets by the FDA. The Isoplate/plasma unit (test)
      will be stored for up to 20 days.

      On Day 3 the subject will receive an Indium 111 (In-111) radiolabeled aliquot of their
      control plasma 4°C stored platelets. Follow-up samples from the subject will be collected
      approximately 2 hours post-infusion and on Days 1 (2X), 2, 3, 4, and 5 to calculate recovery
      and survival of the subject's 3 day stored platelets. On Day 1 the sample draws will be 2 -
      10 hours apart.

      The Isoplate 4°C stored platelets will initially be stored for 10 days. The subject will
      receive an infusion of In-111 aliquot of their 4°C Isoplate stored platelets. Follow-up
      samples, as above, will be collected to calculate platelet recovery and survival of the test
      unit.

      These studies will allow comparison of the 3 and 10 day stored platelets. Indium will be
      used to label both control and test platelets because the other available isotope, chromium,
      is not taken up by refrigerated platelets. The In-111 administered on Day 3 will be largely
      undetectable by Day 10 and therefore re-use of the same isotope to measure both control and
      test cold stored platelets is valid. Additionally, the investigator will collect a
      pre-infusion radioactivity sample to account for any residual In-111, and adjust the
      calculations accordingly.

      Each subject's Isoplate platelet recovery and survival will be considered acceptable if they
      are ≤20% less than the subject's corresponding 3-day stored sample measurements. Acceptance
      criteria are met for a given storage time if samples from all subjects in that group meet
      acceptability threshold.

      So long as acceptance criteria are met with 5 split paired units stored for 10 days the
      investigator will progressively increase the storage period in two day increments until
      acceptance criteria are no longer met (i.e., when at least one subject has &gt;20% reduction in
      either recovery or survival compared to the same subject's 3-day 4°C plasma stored
      platelets). The investigator will evaluate 12, 14, 16, 18 and 20 day storage so long as test
      platelets for all 5 subjects in the group demonstrate ≤20% reduction in recovery and
      survival as compared to their own 3-day plasma 4°C stored platelets. Once the first storage
      period that fails to meet acceptance criteria is identified, the investigator will fall back
      by one day to evaluate the mid storage period between that which met and that which failed
      criteria. If that mid-storage period fails, then the investigator will evaluate the prior
      storage period again with 5 additional samples, continuing to step back down until a group
      meets acceptance criteria for all 10 subjects. Thus, once the maximum acceptable storage
      time has been determined, a total of 10 subjects satisfying acceptance criteria will have
      platelet viability data collected at that storage time.

      In addition to radiolabeled platelet recovery and survival measurements, various in vitro
      assays will be performed at the end of each storage condition (3 day and extended stored;
      i.e. 10 to 20 day).
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2016</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximal storage time with acceptable recovery and survival (as defined below)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 20 days storage at 4°C</time_frame>
    <description>Each subject's Isoplate platelet recovery and survival will be considered acceptable if they are ≤20% less than the subject's corresponding 3-day stored sample measurements. Acceptance criteria are met for a given storage time if samples from all subjects in that group meet this acceptability threshold.
So long as these acceptance criteria are met for 5 split paired units stored for 10 days, the storage period will be progressively increased in two day increments until acceptance criteria are no longer met (i.e., when at least one subject has &gt;20% reduction in either recovery or survival compared to the same subject's 3-day 4°C plasma stored platelets). Stored samples will be evaluated at up to 20 days storage if test platelets for all 5 subjects in the prior storage period demonstrate ≤20% reduction in recovery and survival as compared to their own 3-day plasma 4°C stored platelets.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Platelet Transfusion</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Autologous, cold stored, isoplate suspended platelets stored at 3 days (control) and 10 days (test). Storage to be extended out to 20 days until acceptance criteria are not met.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Apheresis platelet collection</intervention_name>
    <description>A double hyperconcentrated apheresis platelet unit will be collected from a healthy adult volunteer subject using the Trima Accel® Automated Blood Collection System. Concurrent plasma will be collected.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Refrigerated storage of apheresis platelets in platelet additive solution (Isoplate)</intervention_name>
    <description>After collection the unit will be split into two equal portions and will be re-suspended in 65% Isoplate (a platelet additive solution) and 35% plasma while the other half will be suspended in plasma. Both units will achieve a final platelet concentration of ~1500 x 103 platelets/µL. Both units will be stored, without agitation, at 4°C. The plasma suspended unit (control) will be stored for 3 days, the maximum platelet storage time allowed for refrigerated platelets by the FDA. The Isoplate/plasma unit (test) will be stored for up to 20 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Autologous infusion of aliquot of radiolabeled platelets</intervention_name>
    <description>At 3 days post collection the subject will receive an Indium 111 (In-111) radiolabeled aliquot of their control plasma 4°C stored platelets. The amount of the isotope that will be infused is ≤30 μCi of indium in two separate infusions.
Follow-up samples from the subject will be collected approximately 2 hours post-infusion and on Days 1 (2X), 2, 3, 4, and 5 to calculate recovery and survival of the subject's 3 day stored platelets. On Day 1 the sample draws will be 2 - 10 hours apart.
The Isoplate 4°C stored platelets will initially be stored for 10 days. The subject will receive an infusion of In-111 aliquot of their 4°C Isoplate stored platelets. Follow-up samples, as above, will be collected to calculate platelet recovery and survival of the test unit.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>In Vitro Tests Performed on Control and Test Units</intervention_name>
    <description>Tests to evaluate platelet function will be performed on plasma and Isoplate resuspended units. Samples for these tests will be collected from the platelet unit at the end of storage for both control and test units.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Weight: ≥ 125 pounds

          -  Hematocrit: ≥ 38%

          -  Platelet count: ≥ 225 X 10 to the 3rd per microliter

          -  Temperature: ≤ 99.5 F

          -  Resting blood pressure: systolic ≤180 mmHg; diastolic ≤ 100 mmHg

          -  Resting heart rate: 40 to 100 beats per minute

          -  Subjects must be: at least 18 years old, of either sex

          -  Subjects must be able to read, understand and sign the informed consent document and
             commit to the study follow-up schedule. The ability to read and speak English is
             required for participation.

          -  Subjects must have good veins for apheresis platelet collection and drawing blood
             samples.

          -  Subjects of child-bearing potential (either male or female) must agree to use an
             effective method of contraception during the course of the study. The following
             methods of contraception are be considered effective; abstinence, intrauterine
             contraception devices, hormonal methods, barrier methods or history of sterilization.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Ever received radiation therapy.

          -  Already participated in 4 research studies involving radioisotopes within the
             contemporaneous calendar-year.

          -  Taken aspirin, non-steroidal anti-inflammatory, or other platelet affecting drugs
             within 72 hours of collection or infusion.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lynda Fitzpatrick, RN</last_name>
    <phone>206-689-6285</phone>
    <email>lyndaf@BloodWorksNW.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bloodworks Northwest (formerly Puget Sound Blood Center)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lynda B Fitzpatrick, RN</last_name>
      <phone>206-292-2347</phone>
      <email>lyndaf@BloodWorksNW.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 27, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 7, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Bloodworks (Puget Sound Blood Center)</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sherrill J. Slichter, M.D.</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director, Platelet Transfusion Research</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Platelets</keyword>
  <keyword>transfusion</keyword>
  <keyword>cold storage</keyword>
  <keyword>apheresis</keyword>
  <keyword>Isoplate</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
