<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00536536</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Obesity affects one in five children in the UK and undoubtedly causes increased ill health with rising levels of childhood and adolescent diabetes, obesity induced liver disease and increased risk of early heart disease. There are few clinics offering effective treatment for childhood obesity. However, the clinic for childhood obesity at Bristol Royal Hospital for Children (BCH) has been successful in around 83% of cases. This pilot study aims to examine the feasibility of transferring the success of the hospital clinic to primary care in preparation for a full RCT. The study will entail training a practice nurse, community dietician and exercise specialist to deliver the same clinical service in primary care as that offered in BCH. Initial work will gather the views of staff delivering the hospital service and those of patients and parents to identify the crucial components of the intervention that are likely to be needed in primary care and to then to refine the intervention.A pilot trial will examine how feasible it is to recruit patients into the service and get some initial idea as to whether weight management is equally good, patient satisfaction and retention improves and what data needs to be collected for a full economic assessment. If found to be effective, the next step will be to use knowledge gained in this study to design and undertake a more extensive, formal study across Bristol in various primary care settings.This larger study will address how such a service can be delivered across a complete spectrum of primary care populations, so that similar services could be developed across the country.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluating the Transferability of a Successful, Hospital-based, Childhood Obesity Clinic to Primary Care: a Pilot Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>5 to &lt;18 yrs old on day of recruitment Children consulting their general practitioner or other primary care professional with a weight &gt; 95th percentile Suspected underlying pathology or syndrome on primary consultation Severe learning difficulties</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Childhood</keyword>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary Care</keyword>
</DOC>