<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01556815</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Transarterial chemoembolization (TACE) is widely used for unresectable hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). However, the hypoxia caused by TACE in surviving tumor cell leads to release of angiogenic and growth factors contributing to poor outcome. Sorafenib can block tumor cell proliferation and angiogenesis. The hypothesis is that patients with unresectable HCC may benefit from sorafenib in combination with TACE.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sorafenib Combined With Transarterial Chemoembolization in Treating HBV-infected Patients With Intermediate Hepatocellular Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms by Site</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Digestive System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms by Histologic Type</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Glandular and Epithelial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorotrianisene</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Niacinamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients newly diagnosed as HCC according to European Association for Study of the Liver criteria. BCLC stage B ChildPugh class A ECOG performance status of 0 Etiology: Hepatitis B virus(HBV) infection Written informed consent (approved by the Institutional Review Board [IRB]obtained prior to any study specific screening procedures Patient must be able to comply with the protocol Age 1880 years Haematology:Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt; 1 x 109/L, Platelet count &gt; 40 x 109/L, Haemoglobin &gt; 9 g/dL (may be transfused to maintain or exceed this level) Prothrombin time international normalized ratio &lt; 1.5 Biochemistry:Total bilirubin &lt; 2 mg/dL Serum creatinine &lt; 1.5 x the upper limit of normal Life expectancy of &gt; 3 months Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &lt; 5 x the upper limit of normal Other severe concomitant disease that may reduce life expectancy uncontrolled hypertension Pregnancy (positive serum pregnancy test) or lactation Uncontrolled hypertension Serious, nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture Currently or recent (within the 30 days prior to starting study treatment) treatment of another investigational drug or participation in another investigational study Clinically significant (i.e. active) cardiovascular disease for example cerebrovascular accidents ( ≤ 6 months prior to study entry), myocardial infarction ( ≤ 6 months prior to study entry), unstable angina, New York Heart Association (NYHA) grade II or greater congestive heart failure, serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication Evidence of other disease, metabolic dysfunction, physical examination finding, or clinical laboratory finding giving reasonable suspicion of a disease or condition that contraindicates use of Sorafenib/TACE or patient at high risk from treatment complications</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Sorafenib</keyword>
	<keyword>Transarterial Chemoembolization</keyword>
	<keyword>HBV</keyword>
</DOC>