<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01861743</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Most patients undergoing surgery experience significant post-operative pain. Inadequate peri-operative pain management may decrease post-operative mobilization and increase length of hospitalization. Additionally, poorly managed acute post-operative pain analgesia is associated with an increased risk of developing chronic pain and delayed wound healing. Lumbar spine surgery is particularly painful, often requiring a multi-day hospitalization. The most common post-operative analgesia used in spine surgery is narcotic medication delivered via an intravenous patient controlled analgesia (IV PCA). A multimodal peri-operative pain management protocol for spine surgery has the potential to not only decrease pain but also to improve recovery, decrease narcotic consumption, decrease length of stay in the hospital and reduce both direct and indirect hospital costs. The purpose of this study is to determine if post-operative pain and rate of recovery are improved in patients undergoing spine surgery using MMA compared to usual analgesic care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multimodal Analgesia Versus Routine Care Pain Management</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We hypothesize patients undergoing spinal fusion who receive peri-operative MMA will have: 1. decreased post-operative pain compared to patients receiving usual care for pain management. 2. shorter hospital LOS compared to patients receiving usual care pain management. 3. fewer analgesic-related post-operative complications (urinary retention, ileus, etc) compared to patients receiving usual care pain management. 4. improved physical functioning at the time of hospital discharge compared to patients receiving usual care pain management. 5. better short and long term outcomes. Subjects will be randomized to MMA (Group 1) or usual care (Group 2). The unit of randomization will be a week (Monday through Sunday). Each week will randomly be assigned to MMA or usual care. Subjects who are hospitalized into a consecutive week will continue with the pain regimen they were assigned upon hospitalization.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Spondylolisthesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Stenosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intervertebral Disc Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients undergoing single level MISTLIF Patients able to provide informed consent Allergies or other contraindications to medicines in the protocol Current liver disease with documented liver function test abnormality Current renal disese with documented glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt; 60 mL/min/1.73m2 Baseline (preoperative) opioid use greater than 30 mg of morphine equivalents/day Active alcohol dependence Active illicit drug dependence</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multi-modal Pain Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Lumbar fusion</keyword>
	<keyword>misTLIF</keyword>
</DOC>