<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01228188</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of surgical treatment of FTMH using an inverted ILM repositioning to improve anatomical and functional outcomes in patients with a macular hole.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Inverted ILM Repositioning as Treatment for Full Thickness Macular Holes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>At present, the anatomical closure rate of macular hole is around 90% using pars plana vitrectomy with ILM peeling. Improvement of visual acuity is around 80% including stage II to IV. With macular hole greater than 400 μm there is higher risk of surgical failure and visual acuity is usually less than 0.2. Large macular holes are more likely to have flat-open type closure, which is anatomical success but has limited improvement in visual acuity. Inverted ILM repositioning will form a scaffold for glial cells, which allows their migration and proliferation. This process will close the macular hole and secure it from re-opening, and will reduce the risk of flat-open type of closure. The aim of this study is to estimate the efficiency and safety of inverted ILM repositioning in the treatment of macular hole with a minimum diameter exceeding 400 μm and compare results with the currently used methods of surgical large macular holes treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Perforations</mesh_term>
	<criteria>fullthickness macular hole with a minimum diameter exceeding 400 μm BCVA of 0,3 or worse in log MAR units (&lt;=70 ETDRS letter) and 1,6 or better in log MAR units (&gt;=5 ETRDS letter) 18 years of age Informed consent eyes with previous vitreous surgery cystoid macular edema from any cause post traumatic macular hole macular hole associated with retinal detachment any other ocular reason which causes the lack of improvement after macular hole surgery (e.g pigmentary abnormalities, agerelated macular degeneration, corneal scarring)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>FTMH</keyword>
	<keyword>PPV</keyword>
	<keyword>inverted ILM repositioning</keyword>
</DOC>