<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02466256</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized clinical trial compares subjective performance during Intraocular lens (IOL) implantation, as well as incision enlargement and anterior segment morphology on OCT when IOL implantation was performed during microcoaxial phacoemulsification through a 2.2mm incision using one of three injectors : Manual screw type (Monarch III), Manual plunger type (Royale) and motorised injector (Autosert). Further, the investigators also looked at incision integrity by comparing ingress of trypan blue from the ocular surface into the anterior chamber.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intra and Postoperative Outcomes With 3 Injectors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this randomized, clinical trial, three types of injectors were compared : 1. Manual, screw type injector (Monarch III) 2. Manual, plunger type injector (Royale, ASICO) 3. Motorized injector (Autosert, Alcon) Having performed a phacoemulsification through 2.2mm incision, IOL implantation was performed using a D cartridge and one of three injectors which was decided in a randomized fashion. The investigators evaluated incision enlargement at following points : at the end of phacoemulsification, and then, at the end of IOL implantation The investigators also looked at trypan blue ingress into the anterior chamber from the ocular surface. At 1 day, 1 week, and 1 month after surgery anterior segment OCT morphology was also studied. further, the surgeon was asked to subjectively grade the ease of implantation with each injector</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cataract</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients undergoing phacoemulsification for agerelated uncomplicated cataracts through a 2.2mm incision. Nuclear or corticonuclear of grade 2 to 4 according to the Lens Opacities Classification System (LOCS III) Glaucoma, uveitis, shallow anterior chamber (depth &lt;2.1mm), prior ocular trauma or surgery, maximal pupillary dilatation &lt;6mm, high myopia (axial length &gt;25mm), posterior polar cataracts, dense cataracts, and an IOL power &lt;19.0 D or &gt;25.0 D</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Intraocular lens implantation</keyword>
</DOC>