<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02362958</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluating the Efficacy of Lapatinib in Combination With Chemotherapy in Patients With Trastuzumab-refractory Metastatic HER2-positive Breast Cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Multi-Center Study of Lapatinib in Patients With Trastuzumab-refractory Metastatic Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Some studies has demonstrated that even in trastuzumab pretreated patients with HER-2 positive breast cancer, might benefit from the treatment of trastuzumab. However, there is small benefit for some patients having short disease-free survival after adjuvant trastuzumab or short progression-free survival after first-line trastuzumab-based therapy. In clinical practice, the investigators also found it is fact. And the investigators have a scientific rationale for clinical testing of lapatinib plus chemotherapy in patients with trastuzumab-refractory, metastatic HER2-positive breast cancer.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vinorelbine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lapatinib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vinblastine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Metastatic breast cancer Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) 0 or 1 HER2expressing primary or metastatic tumor Recurrence within 1 year completing adjuvant trastuzumab OR rapid progress following firstline trastuzumabbased care. Measurable disease with Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1 Normal organ function, including bone marrow function, renal function, liver function, and cardiac function Signed and dated an informed consent form Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks Pregnant or breast feeding left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt; 45% by echocardiogram Diseasefree interval (DFI) less than 12 months Uncontrolled medical problems Any previous malignancy exceptions for carcinoma of the cervix, squamous carcinoma of the skin, or basal cell carcinoma of the skin Patients were unable or unwilling to comply with program requirements</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>