<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02362906</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of traditional Chinese medicine for treatment of pediatric pneumonia. It is a multicenter randomized controlled trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness Study of Integrative Treatment for Pediatric Community Acquired Pneumonia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The block randomization is used in this trial. Random numbers are generated by statistical analysis system(SAS) software. Statistical analysis staff and those who perform the follow-up are blinded. Sample size calculation was performed, which was 1164 , and considering drop-out or withdrawal, investigators plan to enroll 1500 patients (500 in experimental group 1, 500 in experimental group 2, 500 in experimental group 3).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin Estolate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin Ethylsuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythromycin stearate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cephalosporins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>children,aged 1 to 14 years old; diagnosed as pneumonia according to western medicine diagnostic criteria; diagnosed as TCM pneumonia with pneumonia with dyspnea and cough, meeting windheat blocking lungs pattern (feng re bi fei zheng), and phlegmheat blocking lungs pattern(tan re bi fei zheng); disease progression within 72 hours; those whose guardians understood and assigned the informed consent; severe pneumonia; complicated with other Pulmonary Disorders attack other than pneumonia; complicated with primary disease of heart(congenital heart disease, myocarditis, et al),liver(alanine aminotransferase(ALT),and aspartate transaminase(AST) ≥1.5 times of normal value ceiling),kidney (blood urea nitrogen(BUN) ＞8.2mmol/l, or serum C reactive protein ＞104umol/l,et al) and blood system (anemia) ,and those with psychopathy; allergic to interventional medications; those who are participating or have participated in other clinical trials in 3 months; those who intend to lost followup by practitioners' judgment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>14 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>pneumonia</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatrics</keyword>
</DOC>