<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02360956</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether olmesartan medoxomil is effective in the treatment of coronary atherosclerosis progression and epicardial adipose tissue(EAT) volume reduction in patients with coronary atherosclerosis detected by coronary CT angiography(CCTA).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Study of Olmesartan Medoxomil on Coronary Atherosclerosis and Epicardial Adipose Tissue(EAT)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Epicardial adipose tissue(EAT) is directly deposited around the pericardium and coronary artery. By means of paracrine action, it can generate various kinds of cytokines, inflammatory factor and free fatty acids, that can affect the state of coronary endothelial function, inflammation and oxidative stress, which finally aggravate the progression of coronary atherosclerosis. In recent years, clinical studies have shown that EAT is a newly discovered independent risk factor of coronary atherosclerosis.Studies confirm that olmesartan medoxomil can improve endothelial function, resisting thrombosis, improve tissue reconstruction, resisting oxidative stress so as to achieve atherosclerosis resistant. Latest researches show that olmesartan medoxomil can better inhibit rat epididymal adipose cell hypertrophy and inflammatory reaction. Coronary CT angiography(CCTA) has emerged as a noninvasive imaging method for analysis coronary atherosclerosis. The purpose of this study is to determine whether olmesartan medoxomil is effective in the treatment of coronary atherosclerosis progression and EAT volume reduction in patients with coronary atherosclerosis detected by CCTA.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Olmesartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Olmesartan Medoxomil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antihypertensive Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium Channel Blockers</mesh_term>
	<criteria>coronary artery stenosis between 30% and 70% determined by CCTA in essential hypertension patients resting diastolic blood pressure (DBP) between 90 and 110 mmHg type A and B for coronary artery vascular lesions secondary hypertension coronary artery stenosis less than 30% or greater than 70% determined by CCTA contraindications to treatment with olmesartan medoxomil (allergy, glaucoma, digestive ulcer, is currently taking phosphodiesterase5 inhibitor) resting systolic blood pressure (SBP) ＞ 200 mmHg or resting diastolic blood pressure (DBP) ＞ 110 mmHg Severe calcification, distortion or type C for coronary artery vascular lesions pregnancy unwillingness or inability to provide informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Olmesartan medoxomil</keyword>
	<keyword>Epicardial adipose tissue</keyword>
	<keyword>Multidetector Computed Tomography</keyword>
</DOC>