<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02360176</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Demonstrate non-inferiority of the single port for sleeve gastrectomy compared to the reference method in terms of complications using a score of morbidity and mortality at 6 and 24 months: Rate of fistula, intra and extra abdominal abcess, hemorrhage, gastric stenosis, splenic lesions, hernia, residual gastric pouch and mortality</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Benefit of Single Port-surgery in Sleeve Gastrectomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The single port surgery is the natural evolution of laparoscopy. To date only few studies have evaluated the feasibility of this technique in sleeve gastrectomy. The investigators want to demonstrate the non-inferiority in terms of morbidity-mortality of use single trocar in sleeve gastrectomy compared the multiport technique. Moreover it should highlight the non-inferiority in terms of anatomical quality, reduction of excess weight lost, reduction of comorbidities, decrease post operative pain, improved quality of life and evaluate medico-economic impact of these technique to validating this new surgical approach for bariatric surgery. The study will be multicentric with 6 university center (Montpellier, Amiens, Lille, Creteil, Poissy and Montsouris Institut). 388 patients will be included in the tow group of the prospective randomise study.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>BMI&gt; 35 kg/m2 with comorbidity (s) or&gt; 40 kg/m2 Failure of a previous medical treatment Supports more than six months in preoperative time into a multidisciplinary team Patients aged 18 to 65 years Discussion and decision sleeve gastrectomy multidisciplinary meeting Free, informed and written consent Karnofsky Index&gt; 70% Affiliation to a social security or other assurance Exclusion Criteria Anesthetics Uncontrolled severe infection Liver disease other than obesity pathology Pregnancy (positive hCG) Large hiatal hernia Esophagitis uncontrolled History of gastric bypass and gastric surgery other than gastric banding Life expectancy less than 10 years Lack of prior identified medical care Saving Justice guardianship Participation in another ongoing study Cognitive or severe mental illness Severe and nonstabilized eating disorders Addiction to alcohol and psychoactive substances"</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>single port surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>bariatric surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>sleeve gastrectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>randomise prospective study</keyword>
	<keyword>complication rate</keyword>
</DOC>