<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01169922</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research is examining how genetic and brain factors play a role in adolescents' health risk behavior as well as studying behaviors that young people engage in that may place them at risk for contracting a sexually transmitted disease like HIV/AIDS, and what kind of educational program works best to reduce these risky behaviors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>HIV Prevention With Adolescents: Neurocognitive Deficits and Treatment Response</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A baseline assessment is conducted, including a computer questionnaire assessing personality characteristics, attitudes toward and experiences with sex, alcohol, drugs, and cigarettes, among other things. The participant also meets with a therapist to conduct a brief motivational interview at this time. A "Time-Line Follow-Back" is conducted; this notes incidences of sexual intercourse, alcohol use, marijuana use, and cigarette use in a 30-day period. An fMRI is conducted, and a saliva sample is gathered. During the second session of the study, participants are randomly assigned to either a sex and alcohol risk reduction intervention, or a sex risk reduction intervention. After the intervention, participants are contacted at 3 month intervals (3 months later, 6 months later, 9 months later, and 12 months later) to meet. At these "follow-up" meetings, another Time-Line Follow-Back is conducted, along with another computer questionnaire (again assessing attitudes toward and experiences with sex, alcohol, drugs, and cigarettes).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Drinking Behavior</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adolescents age 1418 Involved in Juvenile Justice System OR enrolled in a private school Currently taking antipsychotics Involved in similar interventionbased study (2 similar studies being conducted simultaneously by this lab)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>