<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02171052</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate the bioavailability of dabigatran with and without concomitant administration of digoxin and the bioavailability of digoxin with and without concomitant administration of dabigatran etexilate</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Relative Bioavailability of Dabigatran and Digoxin in Healthy Male and Female Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Digoxin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dabigatran</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Healthy males and females according to the following criteria: Based upon a complete medical history, including the physical examination, vital signs (BP, PR), 12lead ECG, clinical laboratory tests 2. Age ≥18 and ≤65 years 3. BMI ≥18.5 and BMI ≤29.9 kg/m2 (Body Mass Index) 4. Signed and dated written informed consent prior to admission to the study in accordance with GCP and the local legislation. 1. Gastrointestinal, hepatic, renal, respiratory, cardiovascular, metabolic, immunological or hormonal disorders 2. Relevant surgery of gastrointestinal tract 3. History of any bleeding disorder or acute blood coagulation defect 4. Puls below 50 bpm at screening 5. Diseases of the central nervous system (such as epilepsy) or psychiatric disorders or neurological disorders 6. History of relevant orthostatic hypotension, fainting spells or blackouts 7. Chronic or relevant acute infections 8. History of allergy/hypersensitivity (including drug allergy) which is deemed relevant to the trial as judged by the investigator 9. Intake of any medication within four weeks of first dosing. 10. Use of drugs which might reasonably influence the results of the trial based on the knowledge at the time of protocol preparation within four weeks prior to administration or during the trial 11. Participation in another trial with an investigational drug within two months prior to administration or during the trial 12. Alcohol abuse (more than 60 g/day) 13. Drug abuse 14. Within 5 days of study medication no intake of grapefruit, grapefruit juice, or products containing grapefruit juice, Seville oranges, garlic supplements, or St. John's Worth 15. Blood donation (more than 100 mL within four weeks prior to administration or during the trial) 16. Excessive physical activities (within one week prior to administration or during the trial) 17. Any laboratory value outside the reference range that is of clinical relevance 18. Inability to comply with dietary regimen of study centre 19. Females of child bearing potential who are pregnant, breast feeding or who are either not surgically sterile or are sexually active and not using an acceptable form of contraception as either the oral contraceptives since at least two months and the double barrier method, i.e. intrauterine device with spermicide and condom for the male partner 20. Male subjects must agree to minimise the risk of female partners becoming pregnant from the first dosing day until 3 months after the completion of the post study medical. Acceptable methods of contraception comprises barrier contraception and a medically accepted contraceptive method for the female partner (intrauterine device with spermicide, hormonal contraceptive since at least two month) 21. Planned surgeries within four weeks following the endof study examination 22. Intake of medication, which influences the blood clotting, i.e., acetylsalicylic acid, cumarin etc. 23. The subject is able to understand and comply with protocol requirements, instructions and protocolstated restrictions 24. Vulnerable subjects (e.g. persons kept in detention).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>