<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02171312</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The iDETECT (Integrated Display Enhanced Testing for Concussion and mild traumatic brain injury) system is a novel portable, open access platform that enables immediate and rapid assessment of multimodal neurologic function. This study seeks to evaluate the iDETECT function testing battery with currently used balance and inner ear assessment methods during initial concussion clinic referral. Two groups of participants will be enrolled; a concussion related dizziness cohort and control subjects. The investigators will enroll the concussion cohort from patients presenting to the Sports Concussion Institute (SCI) with persistent dizziness and imbalance symptoms following possible concussion. Healthy control participants will be recruited from the local community. iDETECT's ability to identify post concussion balance/vestibular disturbances will be compared to an expert concussion assessment. Both cohorts will participate in the iDETECT assessment and the clinical assessment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Evaluation of a Novel Balance, Vestibular and Oculomotor Assessment Tool</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The iDETECT (Integrated Display Enhanced Testing for Concussion and mild traumatic brain injury) system is a novel portable, open access platform that enables immediate and rapid assessment of multimodal neurologic function. This study seeks to evaluate and validate the iDETECT balance, vestibular, and oculomotor testing battery with clinician performed balance and vestibular assessment methods. Two groups of participants will be enrolled; concussion related dizziness cohort and control subjects (no concussion or dizzy symptoms). The investigators will enroll the concussion cohort from patients presenting to the Sports Concussion Institute (SCI) with persistent dizziness and imbalance symptoms following possible concussion. Healthy control participants with normal vestibular function and no history of concussion will be recruited from the local community. All participants will be tested with both the iDETECT balance and vestibular assessment battery and the current clinical reference standards for imbalance and vestibular dysfunction performed by a clinician. Performance on the iDETECT balance and vestibular assessment battery will be compared between normal controls and the concussion cohort.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neuritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Post-Concussion Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vestibular Neuronitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Concussion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Concussion Cohort Age ≥ 12 History of concussion within prior 6 months Complaint or symptoms of dizziness / balance problems History of any of the following:Depression, sleep apnea, seizure disorder, migraine headaches, prior brain or spine surgery, peripheral neuropathy, lower extremity orthopedic problems Chronic drug or alcohol use; or drug or alcohol use within the previous 24 hours. Control Cohort Age ≥ 12 Physically active (at least 60 min of exercise, teambased or recreational, 3 times of week) Concussion or concussivelike symptoms within prior 6 months Current complaint or symptoms of dizziness/balance problems History of any of the following: Depression, sleep apnea, seizure disorder, claustrophobia, prior central nervous system (CNS) surgery, peripheral neuropathy, developmental delay, learning disabilities lower extremity orthopedic problems that prevent standing or walking Participants also cannot currently be the under care of a doctor these or any related conditions that may cause cognitive impairment. Chronic drug or alcohol use; or drug or alcohol use within the previous 24 hours</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dizziness</keyword>
	<keyword>Imbalance</keyword>
</DOC>