<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02631525</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Bispectral monitoring anesthesia with remifentanil-desflurane has a better post-operative recovery than remifentanil-propofol.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Recovery Profile Comparison Between Remifentanil-propofol or Desflurane Anesthesia Monitored With Bispectral Index.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>It is a randomized, double blind study, involving 40 adult female patients submitted to general anesthesia. The patients were distributed into 2 groups: remifentanil-propofol-based anesthesia and remifentanil-desflurane-based anesthesia groups. Bispectral index (BIS) monitoring guided the anesthesia by setting target BIS range value between 40 and 60. Anesthetics were adjusted to reached that. Primary outcome was: extubation time (time from anesthetic discontinuation to endotracheal tube cuff). Secondary measured outcomes: intra-operative cardiovascular drug use; time to follow command before extubation; protective airway reflex recovery time after extubation. Protective airway reflex test recovery was performed at predetermined time intervals (2, 6, 14, 22 and 30 minutes) from the time to follow a standard command until the first demonstrated ability to swallow 20 ml of water in an upright position.Post-anesthesia care unit recovery data were also recorded: Ramsay sedation scale; vital signs, post-operative pain; morphine consumption.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Delayed Emergence from Anesthesia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Propofol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Desflurane</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isoflurane</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Remifentanil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female patients over 18 years old classified by the American Society of Anesthesiologists as physical status I or II, undergoing elective breast surgery with general anesthesia. History of: illegal drug and alcohol abuse Pregnancy on course or suspicion of Neuromuscular disorders Cerebral vascular disease Dysphagia Dysphonia Gastroesophageal reflux disease Previous larynx and/or upper gastrointestinal tract surgery Allergy to any drug to be used and malignant hyperthermia. Patients who develop hemodynamic instability in the surgery and need blood transfusion were excluded from the study. Patients unable to swallow 20 ml of water in an upright position were also excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Airway extubation</keyword>
	<keyword>Anesthesia Recovery Period</keyword>
	<keyword>Desflurane</keyword>
	<keyword>Propofol</keyword>
	<keyword>Intravenous anesthesia</keyword>
	<keyword>Balanced Anesthesia</keyword>
</DOC>