<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01171859</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being conducted to explore the potential benefits of a twelve-month doxycycline (at the best tolerated dose of 200 mg/day) and tauroursodeoxycholic acid (750 mg/day) treatment on disease progression in patients affected by transthyretin amyloidosis, including: 1) patients not eligible for liver transplantation; 2) patients eligible for liver transplantation, as a "bridge" therapy between the time of diagnosis and surgery, with the aim of stabilizing the disease; 3) patients showing disease progression after liver transplantation performed since at least 1 year. It is a phase II, therapeutic exploratory, two-part, 18-month, single centre, prospective study. Part I is a 12-month, open label treatment period in which doxycycline (200 mg/day, continuously) and tauroursodeoxycholic acid (750 mg/day continuously) are administered to 40 consenting subjects with transthyretin amyloidosis. Part II is a withdrawal period in which subjects will be monitored for disease progression. During part I, subjects will be evaluated at baseline (study Day 0), and then after 3, 6, 9 and 12 months of doxycycline plus tauroursodeoxycholic acid treatment or at premature treatment discontinuation; during part II, they will be assessed at months 15 and 18. Monthly phone contacts and blood tests will be performed to monitor potential adverse events.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Efficacy and Pharmacokinetics of Doxycycline Plus Tauroursodeoxycholic Acid in Transthyretin Amyloidosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Amyloidosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amyloid Neuropathies, Familial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tauroursodeoxycholic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Taurochenodeoxycholic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxycycline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histochemical diagnosis of amyloidosis as based on detection by polarizing microscopy of green birefringent material in Congo redstained tissue specimens; Molecular definition of the transthyretin (TTR) mutation or immunohistochemical staining of amyloid fibrils with antiTTR antibody; ECOG performance status (PS) 0, 1, 2; New York Heart Association (NYHA) class ≤III Systolic blood pressure ≥100 mmHg (standing) Must have symptomatic organ involvement with amyloid to justify therapy; must have evidence of neuropathy and/or cardiomyopathy progression after liver transplantation performed since at least one year. Contraception for women of childbearing potential. Medically approved contraception could include abstinence. A negative serum pregnancy test is required prior to initiation of treatment with study medication. Liver transplantation in the previous 12 months or liver transplantation anticipated in less than 6 months; ALT and/or AST ≥ 2 x Upper Normal Limit (UNL); Alkaline phosphatase ≥ 2 x UNL; Creatinine clearance &lt; 30 ml/min; Any other lab values that in the opinion of the investigator might place the subject at unacceptable risk for participation in the study; Echocardiographic ejection fraction &lt; 50%; Other neuropathies, due to vitamin B12 deficiency, alcoholism, hypothyroidism, uremia, diabetes mellitus, vasculitides; History of poor compliance; History of hypersensitivity to any of the ingredients of the study therapies; Use of any investigational drug, device (or biologic) within 4 weeks prior to study entry or during the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>amyloidosis</keyword>
	<keyword>transthyretin</keyword>
	<keyword>doxycycline</keyword>
	<keyword>Tauroursodeoxycholic acid</keyword>
</DOC>