<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02678286</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the analgesic efficacy of N1539 in subjects with acute moderate to severe pain following abdominoplasty surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of N1539 Following Abdominoplasty Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Meloxicam</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Voluntarily provide written informed consent. Male or female between 18 and 75 years of age, inclusive. Be scheduled to undergo elective abdominoplasty surgery without collateral procedures. Be American Society of Anesthesiology (ASA) physical class 1 or 2. Female subject are eligible only if all the following apply: Not pregnant; Not lactating; Not planning to become pregnant during the study; Commit to the use of an acceptable form of birth control for the duration of the study. Have a body mass index ≤35 kg/m2 Be able to understand the study procedures, comply with all study procedures, and agree to participate in the study program. Have a known allergy to meloxicam or any excipient of N1539, D5W, aspirin, other nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) or to any peri or postoperative medications used in this study. Have a clinically significant abnormal clinical laboratory test value. Have history of or positive test results for HIV, or hepatitis B or C. Have a history or clinical manifestations of significant renal, hepatic, cardiovascular, metabolic, neurologic, psychiatric, or other condition that would preclude participation in the study. Have a history of myocardial infarction or coronary artery bypass graft surgery within the preceding 12 months Have a history of migraine or frequent headaches, seizures, or are currently taking anticonvulsants. Have active or recent (within 6 months) gastrointestinal ulceration or bleeding. Have a known bleeding disorder or be taking agents affecting coagulation. Have another painful physical condition that may confound the assessments of post operative pain. Have evidence of a clinically significant 12 lead ECG abnormality. Have a history of alcohol abuse (regularly drinks &gt; 4 units of alcohol per day; 8 oz. beer, 3 oz. wine, 1 oz. spirits) within the past 5 years or a history of prescription/illicit drug abuse. Have positive results on the urine drug screen or alcohol breath test indicative of illicit drug or alcohol abuse. Have been receiving or have received chronic opioid therapy defined as greater than 15 morphine equivalents units per day for greater than 3 out of 7 days per week over a onemonth period within 12 months of surgery. Use concurrent therapy that could interfere with the evaluation of efficacy or safety, such as any drugs which in the investigator's opinion may exert significant analgesic properties or act synergistically with N1539. Unable to discontinue medications, that have not been at a stable dose for at least 14 days prior to the scheduled bunionectomy procedure, within 5 half lives of the specific prior medication (or, if half life is not known, within 48 hours) before dosing with study medication. Have utilized corticosteroids, either systemically or by intraarticular injection, within 6 weeks prior to the surgical procedure. Have received any investigational product within 30 days before dosing with study medication. Be receiving warfarin, lithium, or a combination of furosemide with either an angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitor or an angiotensin receptor blocker Be currently receiving treatment with oral meloxicam (Mobic®) within 7 days prior to surgery Have previously received N1539 in clinical trials, or had major surgery in the last 3 months that would interfere with study outcomes or increase the risk of study participation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Abdominoplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Analgesia</keyword>
	<keyword>N1539</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase 3</keyword>
</DOC>