<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02678143</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to evaluate the overall safety and feasibility of using haploidentical or one antigen mismatch unrelated hematopoietic stem cell transplant (HSCT) for adult patients with severe sickle cell disease (SCD) who undergo a non-myeloablative preparative regimen consisting of total body irradiation (TBI), cyclophosphamide and alemtuzumab and graft vs. host disease (GvHD) prophylaxis consisting of post-transplant cyclophosphamide (PT-Cy), mycophenolate mofetil (MMF), and sirolimus. The investigators anticipate that this approach will expand the donor pool and offer a safe and less toxic curative intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nonmyeloablative Conditioning for Mismatched Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation for Severe Sickle Cell Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alemtuzumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Recipient Diagnosis of sickle cell disease (HB SS, SC, or SBetathal(0)); confirmed by hemoglobin electrophoresis, highperformance liquid chromatography, DNA testing when necessary or both. At high risk for diseaserelated morbidity or mortality, defined by having severe endorgan damage (one or more of A, B, C, or D below) or potentially modifiable complication(s) not ameliorated by hydroxyurea (E): Stroke (defined as a clinically significant neurologic event that is accompanied by an infarct on cerebral MRI or cerebral arteriopathy requiring chronic transfusion therapy) Sickle cellrelated renal insufficiency with a kidney biopsy consistent with sickle cell nephropathy or nephrotic syndrome. Pulmonary hypertension (defined as tricuspid regurgitant jet velocity (TRV) ≥2.5 m/s at baseline (without vasoocclusive crisis)) Sickle hepatopathy (defined as direct bilirubin &gt; 0.4 mg/dL not explained by severe acute hemolysis, viral hepatitis, extrahepatic obstruction, or hepatic sequestration.) Any one of the below complications not ameliorated by hydroxyurea at the maximum tolerated dose for at least 6 months: Vasoocclusive crises with more than 1 hospital admission per year while on maximal tolerated dose of hydroxyurea Acute chest syndrome occurring while on hydroxyurea Age greater than or equal to 19 years. Availability of one antigen mismatched unrelated or haploidentical related donor Ability to comprehend and willing to sign an informed consent Recipient Detectable antibody to ABO, Rh, or other red blood cell antigen of their donors Presence of donor specific antibodies detected by donor specific antibody screen (if using product from a haploidentical donor). ECOG performance status ≥ 3. Evidence of uncontrolled bacterial, viral, or fungal infections (currently taking medication and progression of clinical symptoms) within one month prior to starting the conditioning regimen. Patients with fever or suspected minor infection should await resolution of symptoms before starting the conditioning regimen. Poor cardiac function defined as left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 35%. Poor pulmonary function defined as FEV1 and FVC &lt; 40% predicted. Pulmonary hypertension moderate to severe by echocardiographic standards. Poor liver function defined as direct bilirubin &gt; 3.1 mg/dl Poor kidney function defined by creatinine clearance &lt; 70mL/min. HIVpositive. Prior transfusions from donor or recipient if caused alloimmunization vs. donor cells. Pregnant or breastfeeding. Diagnosis of any debilitating medical or psychiatric illness that would preclude giving informed consent or receiving optimal treatment and followup. Donor Selection: Must be one antigen mismatched unrelated donor or firstdegree relative who shares at least one HLA haplotype with the recipient. Must not have SCD or another hemoglobinopathy. In good health based on institutional standards. Weight ≥ 20kg. If donor is &lt; 18 years old must have ability to give informed assent based on institutional standards for pediatric donors. Able to undergo peripheral blood stem cell mobilization with GCSF Hemoglobin S ≤ 50%. HIV1&amp;2 antibody, HTLVI&amp;II antibody, HBV and HCV seronegative. Note: When more than one donor is available, the donor with the lowest number of HLA allele mismatches will be chosen, unless there is HLA crossmatch incompatibility or a medical reason to select otherwise, in which case donor selection is the responsibility of the PI, in consultation with the immunogenetics laboratory. In cases where there is more than one donor with the least degree of mismatch, donors will be selected based on the most favorable combination of (i) HLA compatibility in crossmatch testing, (ii) ABO compatibility, (iii) CMV status and (iv) noninherited maternal antigens (NIMAs) mismatching. HLA crossmatching (in order of priority) Mutually compatible (no crossmatching antibodies) Recipient noncrossreactive with donor, donor crossreactive with recipient Mutually crossreactive ABO compatibility (in order of priority) Compatible Major incompatibility Minor incompatibility Major and minor incompatibility CMV negative donor is preferred NIMA mismatched donor is preferred</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>