<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02678442</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a clinical trial to compare two needles used in biopsy techniques to acquire tissue from pancreatic cancer. The hypothesis is that the tissue yield, as measured by tumor DNA and cellular material is superior for Flexible Needle Biopsy (FNB) compared with conventional Fine Needle Aspiration (FNA). Specifically, FNB will increase the proportion of cases in which sufficient DNA is obtained to allow genomic profiling and whole exome sequencing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Endoscopic Ultrasound Guided Fine Needle Biopsy (EUS-FNB-SC) Using a Novel Fork Needle</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single-blinded randomized controlled trial with paired evaluation of conventional FNA needle versus FNB needle stratified by lesion location (pancreas head tumor versus pancreas body/tail). A minimum of 4 passes ( 2 with each needle) will be performed from all the lesions. After each pass of needle, the on-site cytopathologists will evaluate the adequacy and the degree of the pathological changes in the obtained material. Based on the information provided by the onsite cytopathologists, the endosonographer will repeat the FNA until enough histological material is obtained to confirm a diagnosis. Patients will be assessed immediately after procedure and during the first 30 days with a follow-up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female patients who are 18 years old or older and are referred for the evaluation of pancreatic mass lesion. International Normalized Ratio (INR) less than 1.5 and platelet count of more than 50,000. Medically stable to undergo sedation for EUS. Signed informed consent Medical condition that preclude the patient from having a therapeutic procedure regardless of the EUS finding Pregnant patients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>