<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01461928</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This multicenter, randomized, open-label, parallel-group study will evaluate the efficacy and safety of subcutaneously administered rituximab in comparison with observation only as maintenance therapy in participants with relapsed or refractory indolent Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma (NHL). All participants will receive induction therapy with rituximab (375 milligrams per square meter [mg/m^2] intravenously [IV] in Cycle 1, then 1400 mg subcutaneous [SC] every 3-4 weeks) plus standard chemotherapy for 6-8 months; followed by 24 months of maintenance I period with rituximab (1400 mg SC every 8 weeks). Participants completing therapy and showing partial or complete response will be randomized to receive either rituximab (1400 mg SC every 8 weeks) or observation with no treatment during maintenance II period and will be followed for at least 15 months. Anticipated time on study treatment is until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity or end of study, whichever occurs first.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Comparing Maintenance Subcutaneous Rituximab With Observation Only in Participants With Relapsed or Refractory Indolent Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma Who Had Responded to Rituximab-based Immunochemotherapy Induction and 2-year Maintenance With Subcutaneous Rituximab</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed Cluster of Differentiation 20positive (CD20+) follicular NHL Grade 1, 2 or 3a, or other CD20+ indolent NHL (Waldenström's macroglobulinemia or lymphoplasmacytic lymphoma, marginal zone lymphoma) according to World Health Organization (WHO) classification system Participants must have received and must have relapsed or been refractory to, one or more lines of adequate therapy prior to enrollment, including at least one line consisting of immunotherapy and/or chemotherapy and/or radiotherapy Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status less than or equal to (&lt;=) 2 Transformation to highgrade lymphoma Aggressive lymphoma (for example, mantle cell lymphoma [MCL]) Presence or history of central nervous system (CNS) lymphomatous disease Other malignancy within 5 years prior to enrollment, except for curatively treated carcinoma in situ of the cervix, squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or basal cell skin cancer, or cervical carcinoma Stage 1B or less, breast cancer in situ or localized prostate cancer Stage T1c if treated with curative intent and relapse and metastasisfree for at least 2 years prior to enrollment Inadequate hematological, hepatic or renal function Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection Active and/or severe infection (e.g. tuberculosis, sepsis and opportunistic infections, active hepatitis B or C) Pregnant or breastfeeding women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>