<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02180672</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This double-blind, randomized controlled trial will evaluate the use of nasal corticosteroids for the treatment of the childhood obstructive sleep apnea syndrome (OSAS). Efficacy, duration of action and side-effects will be determined.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Steroids for Pediatric Apnea Research in Kids</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Several studies have suggested that NCS or leukotriene antagonists may be effective in the treatment of childhood OSAS. However, these studies have been limited by factors such as small size, lack of randomization and blinding, short-term follow-up, involvement of children with only very mild OSAS, and/or lack of stratifying for the presence of atopy. Therefore, investigators will plan a randomized controlled trial evaluating the efficacy and safety of NCS vs placebo in children with mild to moderate OSAS. The overall hypothesis is that NCS will be safe and efficacious in the treatment of mild to moderate childhood OSAS, particularly in children with asthma/atopy, but will require ongoing maintenance therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 1. 510 years of age. 2. Mild to moderate OSAS, defined as an obstructive apnea index of 120/hr of total sleep time or obstructive apnea hypopnea index of 230/hr of total sleep time. 3. Parentrelated symptoms of habitual snoring (&gt;3 nights per week) 4. No history of adenotonsillectomy. 5. Parental/guardian permission (informed consent) and if appropriate, child assent Exclusion Criteria 1. Severe OSAS or significant hypoxemia or hypercapnia on polysomnography, such that definitive treatment should not be delayed (AHI &gt; 30/hr, more than 2% total sleep time with SpO2 &lt;90%, endtidal PCO2 &gt; 60 mm Hg for &gt; 5 minutes, pathologic arrhythmias). 2. History of recurrent throat infections (as defined by the American Academy of OtolaryngologyHead and Neck Surgery Clinical Practice Guidelines For Tonsillectomy (7)) in the past few years as follows: &gt; 7 episodes in the past year or &gt; 5 episodes/year over the past 2 years or &gt; 3 episodes/year over the past 3 years. 3. Abnormalities on baseline safety screening tests, i.e., DXA scan showing spine or whole body bone mineral density &lt; 2.0 standard deviations using race specific curves with adjustment for height Zscore; morning cortisol &lt; 3 µg/dl or morning ACTH &lt; 10 pg/ml; or ophthalmologic exam demonstrating cataracts (except those with &lt; 2 mm anterior polar cataracts), aphakia or other ocular abnormalities such as glaucoma, retinal coloboma, intraocular inflammation or microphthalmia. 4. Failure to thrive (weight/height &lt; 5th percentile for age and gender), as this may be secondary to OSAS. 5. Severe obesity (BMI zscore &gt; 3) as OSAS is likely to persist in these subjects. 6. Previous adenoidectomy unless adenoidal tissue has been documented to have regrown. 7. Previous tonsillectomy. 8. CPAP therapy. 9. Any NCS use in the past 3 months or NCS use for &gt; 2 weeks in the past year. 10. Current immunotherapy or daily antihistamine use. 11. Recent (past month) nasal septum ulcers, surgery or trauma. 12. Other major illness other than asthma, such as craniofacial anomalies, endocrine or neuromuscular disease, or past history of cancer. This includes children with conditions that may be worsened by OSAS, such as hypertension or diabetes. 13. Current use of ketoconazole or other potent CYP3A4 inhibitors. 14. Families planning to move out of the area within the year. 15. Subjects who do not speak either English or Spanish well enough to complete the validated neurobehavioral instruments. 16. Parents/guardians or subjects who, in the opinion of the Investigator, may be noncompliant with study schedules or procedures.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obstructive sleep apnea syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>OSA</keyword>
	<keyword>sleep apnea</keyword>
	<keyword>nasal steroids</keyword>
	<keyword>corticosteroids</keyword>
</DOC>