<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02180230</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study was to evaluate the 7 mm long implants NobelSpeedy Shorty and Brånemark System Mk III Shorty: by determining the marginal bone remodeling, implant survival rate, soft tissue health and maintenance.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immediate Function of NobelSpeedy Shorty and Brånemark System® Mk III Shorty Implants in Daily Use</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary endpoint was the change in marginal bone levels (in mm) from the time of implant insertion to follow-up visits (3, 6, 12, 36 and 60 months). Further endpoints were: - cumulative survival rates of the implants - soft tissue parameters (papilla index, bleeding on probing) - plaque formation</detailed_description>
	<criteria>The subjects should have an osseous architecture enough to receive an implant with a diameter of at least 3.75 mm for Brånemark System Mk III Shorty or 4 mm for NobelSpeedy Shorty and a sufficient amount of bone for placing implants with a length of 7 mm. The final tightening torque at installation should be 3545 Ncm without further rotation and should not exceed 45 Ncm. The subject as well as the implant site(s) should fulfill criteria for immediate provizionalization. Immediate insertion (e.g. placement of the implant immediately after extraction) will not constitute an exclusion criterion. The implants site(s) should be free from extraction remnants. The subject should be healthy and compliant with good oral hygiene. The subject should be available for the 5year term of the investigation. Favorable and stable occlusal relationship Alcohol or drug abuse as noted in patient records or in patient history. Health conditions, which do not permit the surgical procedure. Reason to believe that the treatment might have a negative effect on the subject's total situation (psychiatric problems), as noted in patient records or in patient history. The subject is not able to give her/his informed consent to participate. Any disorders in the planned implant area such as previous tumors, chronic bone disease, or previous irradiation. Severe bruxism or other destructive habits.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Short implants</keyword>
	<keyword>prospective multicenter study</keyword>
	<keyword>maxilla &amp; mandible</keyword>
</DOC>