<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01355029</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will be evaluating to a 4 week education and support program for stroke caregivers. The 4 week program will provide education, information, and strategies for dealing with areas that caregivers may find challenging in their caregiving role. The study will evaluate the effectiveness of the program to decrease the caregiver's stress, strain and burden, increase the caregiver's knowledge of strategies and community services and increase their role satisfaction as a stroke caregiver and quality of life two weeks after the program and 6 months after the program.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Stroke Caregiver Education and Support Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The modules in the program are: 1) Program Introduction, sharing Caregiving Stories and an introduction to Self Management; 2) Community Connections; Session 3 and 4 are chosen by the participants during session 1 from 6 possible options: Communication in your relationship; Cognition, Memory and Personhood; Dealing with your Emotions; Managing your Stress; Changing roles in your relationships and How to be Caregiver Smart? The programs provides education, information and strategies to deal with the areas that caregivers struggle with as caregivers in order to help them feel better able to prepared to manage as caregivers. Also, the investigators also hope to develop some beginning understanding of when is the best time to provide the program to stroke caregivers to be most helpful to them in their caregiving role.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informal unpaid family stroke caregivers Informal unpaid family stroke caregivers 18 years of age or older; Have provided care to stroke survivor within the home for at least 2 months; Have the ability to communicate in English; Live within Central South Ontario Stroke Region or the West GTA Stroke Region. Caregivers who: Paid to provide care; Are friends who provide care to stroke survivor; Are providing palliative care to stroke survivor within the home.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Stroke caregivers</keyword>
	<keyword>Family Caregivers</keyword>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
</DOC>