<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01483599</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of CNTO 1959 in the treatment of patients with moderate to severe plaque psoriasis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate CNTO 1959 in the Treatment of Patients With Moderate to Severe Plaque-type Psoriasis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multicenter, dose-ranging study of CNTO 1959 in patients with moderate to severe plaque psoriasis. Patients who satisfy all inclusion and exclusion criteria will be assigned by chance to one of 7 treatment groups: a placebo group (a placebo is a treatment identical in appearance to CNTO 1959 but does not contain active drug), 1 of 5 dose groups for CNTO 1959, or adalimumab. Patients assigned to adalimumab will be dosed according to the labeled dosing for psoriasis. At Week 16, patients initially assigned to placebo will begin receiving CNTO 1959. Patients initially assigned to CNTO 1959 will continue to receive the same assigned dose level of study agent from Week 16 through Week 40. Patients receiving adalimumab will continue the labeled dosing regimen. All patients will be reassessed for clinical response every 4 weeks from Week 4 through Week 40. Patients will continue dosing through Week 40, with a subsequent efficacy and safety follow-up visit at Week 52. Patient safety will be monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of plaquetype psoriasis with or without psoriatic arthritis for at least 6 months prior to first administration of any study agent Must be a candidate for phototherapy or systemic treatment for psoriasis (either new to treatment or having had previous treatment) Must be considered, in the opinion of the investigator, suitable candidates for adalimumab therapy If a woman, she must be postmenopausal, or if premenopausal, she must be either surgically sterile, practicing a highly effective method of birth control, or not heterosexually active during the study and for 5 months after receiving the last dose of study drug If a man, he must agree to use a doublebarrier method of birth control (or must have been surgically sterilized) and to not donate sperm during the study and for 5 months after receiving the last dose of study drug. History of or current signs or symptoms of severe, progressive, or uncontrolled renal, hepatic, hematological, gastrointestinal, endocrine, pulmonary, cardiac, neurologic, cerebral, or psychiatric disease Has a contraindication to antiTNF therapy Has a history of chronic or recurrent infectious disease Has a nonplaque form of psoriasis or has druginduced psoriasis Has been previously treated with adalimumab Has received any therapeutic agent directly targeted to IL12, IL17, or IL23, (including but not limited to ustekinumab, briakinumab [ABT874], AIN457, and SCH900222) within 6 months of the first administration of study agent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Moderate to Severe Plaque-Type Psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Plaque-type psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>CNTO 1959</keyword>
	<keyword>adalimumab</keyword>
</DOC>