<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01483781</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate the effects of canagliflozin on plasma volume and renal parameters in patients with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus who are currently taking metformin and being treated for high blood pressure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of the Effects of Canagliflozin on Plasma Volume in Patients With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a double-blind (neither the patient or study staff will know the identity of the treatment assigned) in patients with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus (T2DM) who have inadequate glycemic (blood sugar) control on metformin monotherapy (metformin taken alone for control of T2DM) and who are currently being treated for hypertension (high blood pressure) with agents called angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors (ACEIs) or angiotensin receptor blockers (ARBs). In the study, patients will be randomized (assigned by chance) to receive treatment with canagliflozin or a placebo (a treatment identical in appearance to canagliflozin but does not contain active drug) for 12 weeks. During the 12-week treatment period, patients will also take metformin at a dose of at least 1500 mg/day in addition to their prescribed ACEI or ARB for hypertension. Patients will participate in the study for up to approximately 22 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Canagliflozin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiotensin-Converting Enzyme Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All patients must have a diagnosis of T2DM with inadequate glycemic control (ie, HbA1c of &gt;=7.0% and &lt;=9.0% at Screening) on metformin monotherapy and be receiving therapy with an antihypertensive agent (an ACEI or ARB) for at least 4 weeks prior to Screening History of diabetic ketoacidosis, type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM), pancreas or beta cell transplantation, or diabetes secondary to pancreatitis or pancreatectomy; or a severe hypoglycemic episode within 6 months before screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</keyword>
	<keyword>Plasma Volume</keyword>
	<keyword>Canagliflozin</keyword>
	<keyword>Metformin</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemoglobin A1c</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Angiotensin-Converting Enzyme Inhibitors (ACEIs)</keyword>
	<keyword>Angiotensin Receptor Blockers (ARBs)</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacodynamics</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
</DOC>