<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00920439</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will evaluate the safety and reactogenicity of PoliorixTM given as a single booster dose to Chinese children at 18-24 months of age.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Reactogenicity of GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) Biologicals' IPV Vaccine (PoliorixTM) in Toddlers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Poliomyelitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A male or female toddler between, and including, 18 and 24 months of age at the time of the booster vaccination. Subjects who received three doses of OPV as primary vaccination in the first year of life as per Chinese recommendations. Subjects who the investigator believes that their parents/ guardians can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol should be enrolled in the study. Written informed consent obtained from the parent or guardian of the subject. Healthy subjects as established by medical history and clinical examination before entering into the study. Use of any investigational or nonregistered product other than the study vaccine within 30 days preceding the booster dose of study vaccine, or planned use during the study period. Chronic administration of immunosuppressants or other immunemodifying drugs within six months prior to the booster vaccination Administration of a vaccine not foreseen by the study protocol within 30 days prior to vaccination, or planned administration during the study period, with exception of DTP and/or Hib vaccine(s). Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within the three months preceding the booster vaccination, or planned administration during the study period. Concurrently participating in another clinical study, at any time during the study period, in which the subject has been or will be exposed to an investigational or a noninvestigational product Previous booster vaccination against poliomyelitis since the end of the primary vaccination series. History of poliomyelitis disease. History of seizures or progressive neurological disease. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, based on medical history and physical examination History of allergic disease or reactions likely to be exacerbated by any component of the vaccines. Major congenital defects or serious chronic illness. The following condition is temporary or selflimiting and a subject may be vaccinated once the condition has resolved and no other exclusion criteria are met: • Current febrile illness or axillary temperature &gt; 37.0 ºC or other moderate to severe illness within 24 hours of study vaccine administration.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Poliomyelitis Vaccines</keyword>
	<keyword>IPV</keyword>
</DOC>