<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03019250</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Enteral administration of immune-modulating nutrients such as glutamine, omega-3 fatty acids, selenium, and antioxidants has been suggested to reduce infections and improve recovery from critical illness. However, the effects of colostrum on clinical outcomes in critical ill patients has not been investigated. In current trial, intensive care unit patients with enteral feeding will receive either enteral colostrum or maltodextrin as placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Trial of Enteral Colostrum on Clinical Outcomes in Critically Ill Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A randomized, double blind, controlled trial will be conducted in general intensive care unit (ICU) in Tehran, Iran. After a full review of the inclusion and exclusion criteria and explanation of the risks and benefits of the study, written consent form will be completed. Intervention patients will be received 20 g/day of colostrum along with enteral formula and control patients will be received maltodextrin along with enteral formula. Patients will be assessed for occurrence of new infection, organ failure, duration of stay in ICU, 28 days and 6 months mortality and inflammatory and immune markers.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Organ Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients (&gt;18 years old) admitted to ICU Start of study intervention within 48 hours after ICU admission Expected to require enteral nutrition for at least 72 hours aiming for full enteral nutrition and receive at least 80 percent of enteral formula during the first 48 hour Written informed consent of patient or written informed consent of legal representative Enrollment in a related ICU interventional study Requiring other specific enteral nutrition for medical reason Death or Discharge before 5th day Having any contraindication to receive enteral nutrition Pregnant patients or lactating with the intent to breastfeed BMI &lt;18 or &gt; 40.0 kg/m2 Have life expectancy of &lt;6 mo Patients who are moribund History of allergy or intolerance to the study product components Receiving colostrum during two weeks before start study product Have other reasons</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Colostrum</keyword>
	<keyword>Critical Care Outcomes</keyword>
	<keyword>Intensive Care Unit</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>Infection</keyword>
	<keyword>mortality</keyword>
</DOC>