<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03019848</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if the oral supplementation with curcumin reduces proteinuria, improves the redox and pro-inflammatory state in patients with chronic kidney disease associated to Diabetes mellitus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Oral Supplementation With Curcumin in Patients With Proteinuric Diabetic Kidney Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Diabetic Kidney Disease (DKD) represents the fist cause of end-stage kidney disease in Mexico and the world, and it is characterized by the presence of hyperfiltration, glomerular hypertrophy, tubular albuminuria and mesangial matrix expansion, mainly by the oxidative stress and the pro-inflammatory state. Current treatments are limited on controlling proteinuria and delay progression of the disease, but even with an optimal management, a significant number of patient progress to end-stage renal disease. Curcumin, found in the extracts of the rhizome of the plant Curcuma longa L., has a wide spectrum of biological and pharmacological activities, such as anti-oxidant, anti-inflammatory, anti-carcinogenic and anti-diabetic effects. It has the capacity to act directly with highly reactive oxygen species, induce the expression of various cytoprotective proteins through Keap1/Nrf2/ARE pathway and reducing inflammatory transcription factors such as NF-κB and TNF-α. Curcumin could be an adjuvant treatment in the management of DKC due to his pleiotropic nature, low cost and few side effects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Proteinuria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Curcumin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of Diabetes Mellitus type 2 and proteinuric kidney disease with 1000 mg of more proteins in daily recollection Glomerular filtration rate between 1560 mL/min/ 1.73 m2 calculated by CKDEPI Patients taking Angiotensin II Receptor Blocker or ACE inhibitors Renal replacement therapy Autoimmune disease or malignancy Pregnancy Hepatic damage Congestive heart failure classification III or IV (NYHA) History of organ transplantation History of chemotherapy or immunosuppression within 2 years prior to screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Redox and pro-inflammatory status</keyword>
</DOC>