<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00645060</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Radiolabeled monoclonal antibodies, such as yttrium Y 90 DOTA anti-CEA monoclonal antibody M5A, can find tumor cells and carry tumor-killing substances to them without harming normal cells. This may be an effective treatment for advanced cancer. PURPOSE: This phase I trial is studying the side effects and best dose of yttrium Y 90 DOTA anti-CEA monoclonal antibody M5A in treating patients with advanced solid tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Yttrium Y 90 DOTA Anti-CEA Monoclonal Antibody M5A in Treating Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - To establish the maximum tolerated dose of yttrium Y 90 DOTA anti-CEA monoclonal antibody M5A and describe the toxicities at each dose studied. - To estimate radiation doses to whole body, normal organs, and tumor through serial nuclear imaging studies after intravenous infusion of the yttrium Y 90 DOTA anti-CEA monoclonal antibody M5A. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study of yttrium Y 90 DOTA anti-CEA monoclonal antibody M5A (MOAB M5A). - Biodistribution: Patients receive indium In 111 radiolabeled anti-CEA MOAB M5A IV over 30 minutes. Patients undergo serial nuclear scans, single photon emission computed tomography (SPECT), and blood and urine sampling over 1 week to estimate absorbed radiation doses to tumor, normal organs (i.e., liver, lung, kidney, and bone marrow), and whole body. - Treatment: No more than 2 weeks later, patients with adequate biodistribution receive yttrium Y 90 DOTA anti-CEA MOAB M5A IV over 30 minutes on day 1. Patients then undergo serial nuclear scans, SPECT, and blood and urine sampling over 1 week to estimate absorbed radiation doses to tumor, normal organs (i.e., liver, lung, kidney, and bone marrow), and whole body. Treatment repeats every 6-10 weeks for up to 2 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Blood and urine samples are collected periodically for analysis of total activity by radiometric high performance liquid chromatography and to acquire data on antibody metabolism and pharmacokinetics. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 3 months for up to 6 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed advanced solid tumor for which no standard or effective treatment is available Patients who refuse an available standard but noncurative treatment may also be eligible Tumors must produce CEA as documented by either an elevated serum CEA above the upper limit of normal (ULN) or by immunohistochemical (IHC) methods Positive CEA IHC stain is determined if more than 30% of the tumor cells have an intensity of 2+ or greater Measurable disease Estimated &lt; 1/3 of liver involvement if tumor involves the liver No brain or leptomeningeal involvement with cancer PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Karnofsky performance status 60100% Life expectancy ≥ 3 months WBC ≥ 4,000/μL ANC ≥ 1,500/μL Platelet count ≥ 125,000/μL Creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL and/or creatinine clearance &gt; 60 mL/min Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 mg/dL ALT and AST ≤ 2 times ULN Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception Patients currently being treated for severe infections or recovering from other intercurrent illnesses (such as poorly controlled diabetes or hypertension) are ineligible until recovery is deemed complete by the investigator Serum antiantibody testing must be negative for human antihumanized antibodies (if patient received prior monoclonal antibody) Serum HIVnegative Serum hepatitis B antigen and hepatitis C antibodynegative PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy, immunotherapy, or chemotherapy (6 weeks for mitomycin C or nitrosoureas) and recovered Recovered from prior major surgery No prior radiotherapy to &gt; 50% of bone marrow No other concurrent chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or immunotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>unspecified adult solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
</DOC>