<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00732940</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test the safety and tolerability of repeated subcutaneous (SC) doses of belimumab in subjects with SLE.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 2 Study of Belimumab Administered Subcutaneously to Subjects With Systemic Lupus Erythematosus (SLE)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This clinical trial will evaluate the safety, pharmacokinetics (PK), and effect on biomarkers of repeated subcutaneous (SC) administration of belimumab in subjects with SLE. As data permit, an exploratory pharmacodynamic analysis will be performed to evaluate the correlation between belimumab serum exposure, PGA, SELENA SELDAI, and biomarker effects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Belimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of SLE by American College of Rheumatology (ACR) criteria Active SLE disease On stable SLE treatment regimen Pregnant or nursing Have received treatment with an B cell targeted therapy Have received treatment with a biologic investigational agent in the past year Have received intravenous (IV) cyclophosphamide within 180 days of Day 0 Have severe lupus kidney disease Have active central nervous system (CNS) lupus Have required management of acute or chronic infections with the past 60 days Have current drug or alcohol abuse or dependence or within the past year Have a historically positive test or test positive at screening for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B, or hepatitis C Have a history of an allergic or anaphylactic reaction to drugs, food, or insects requiring medical intervention</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>SLE</keyword>
	<keyword>Lupus</keyword>
	<keyword>Systemic Lupus Erythematosus</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibodies</keyword>
	<keyword>Autoimmune Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Belimumab</keyword>
</DOC>