<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01291771</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cardiovascular diseases are the leading cause of mortality in patients with end stage renal disease (ESRD). They often have myocardial ischemia (a major predictor of mortality) on non invasive testing (Stress echocardiography and/or myocardial perfusion scintigraphy) but the incidence of significant coronary stenosis (&gt;70%) is low. The goal of this observational study is to evaluate the incidence and clinical outcomes of proven myocardial microvascular disease in patients with end stage renal disease scheduled or not for kidney transplantation. These patients routinely undergo non invasive detection of myocardial ischemia. Patient included in the study will be followed up for 2 years for major cardiovascular events. Patients with detected myocardial ischemia during non invasive testing are being explored by coronary angiography. During coronary angiography additional detection of myocardial microvascular disease is being performed by simultaneous measurement of Fractional Flow Reserve (FFR) and Coronary Flow Reserve (CFR) followed by calculation of the index of microcirculatory resistance (IMR). Comparison of cardiovascular outcomes between patients with and without myocardial ischemia and patients with and without myocardial microvascular disease will be performed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Myocardial Microvascular Disease in ESRD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients age &gt; 18 years with end stage renal disease under dialysis and/or scheduled for kidney or kidney + pancreatic transplantation Having a non invasive detection of myocardial ischemia and agreeing to participate (signed informed consent document) Past medical history of Acute coronary syndrome Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy severe aortic and/or mitral valvular disease (grade ≥ 3) Known contraindications to adenosine injection: AV block grade ≥ 2 and/or sinoatrial block unless prior implantation of a pace maker, asthma, allergic reaction to adenosine.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>End stage renal disease</keyword>
	<keyword>myocardial microvascular disease</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiorenal syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>coronary flow reserve</keyword>
	<keyword>index of microvascular resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>Patients with end stage renal disease scheduled or not for kidney or kidney + pancreatic transplantation</keyword>
</DOC>