<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01291602</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a single and multiple dose study in healthy male and female (of non-childbearing potential) Japanese volunteers, to assess the safety, tolerability, and blood and urine drug levels of intravenous (IV) NXL104 alone and when given in combination with ceftazidime.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess the Safety, Tolerability and Pharmacokinetics of NXL104 Alone and in Combination With Ceftazidime Administered as Single and Repeated Intravenous Doses in Healthy Japanese Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Avibactam</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ceftazidime</mesh_term>
	<criteria>To be considered as 'Japanese', both of the volunteer's parents, and all grandparents must be Japanese. The volunteer must have been born in Japan, have a valid Japanese passport and must not have lived outside Japan for more than 5 years Have a body mass index (BMI) between 17 and 27 kg/m2 inclusive and weigh at least 45 kg and no more than 100 kg. Females must not be lactating, and must be of nonchildbearing potential (postmenopausal at least 12 months or documented irreversible surgical sterilization by hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy, or bilateral salpingectomy but not tubal ligation History or presence of gastrointestinal, liver or kidney disease, or other conditions known to interfere with the absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of drugs Symptoms of a clinically significant illness in the 3 months before the study History of hypersensitivity (eg, anaphylaxis), serious allergy, or any serious reaction to carbapenem, cephalosporins, or other βlactam antibiotics Use within 14 days prior to the first study dose of any overthecounter (including St. John's Wort or any herbal products) or prescription medication Smoker of more than 5 cigarettes/day or equivalent use of nicotine products during the previous 3 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>NXL104</keyword>
	<keyword>ceftazidime</keyword>
	<keyword>CAZ104</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy Japanese volunteers</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase 1</keyword>
	<keyword>Single and Multiple Dose Study</keyword>
</DOC>