<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01291693</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to investigate whether motivation-tailored alcohol interventions are more effective when delivered by person or by computer-generated feedback letters. A sample of 920 general hospital inpatients with risky drinking will be recruited through a computerized screening procedure. Patients with more severe alcohol problems will be excluded from the study. Participants will be allocated by time frame randomization to one of three study arms: (1) personal counseling based on Motivational Interviewing, (2) computer-expert system intervention that generates individualized feedback-letters, and (3) control group (treatment-as-usual). The interventions differ in their channel of delivery, but not regarding their content. Both intervention groups receive interventions at three time points: directly after the baseline-assessment at the general hospital, and 1 and 3 months later by mail and phone, respectively. Outcome will be assessed six, 12, 18 and 24 months after baseline.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Testing Delivery Channels of Brief Motivational Alcohol Intervention</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>General hospital inpatients with risky drinking (AUDITC &gt;= 4/5 (women/men) and AUDIT &lt; 20) Patients already recruited during an earlier hospital stay Patients physically and mentally not capable of participating in the study Patients with a hospital stay of less than 24 hours Patients with insufficient language/ reading skills Patients employed at one of the departments participating in the study or conducting the study Patients with more severe alcohol problems (AUDIT &gt;= 20)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hazardous drinking</keyword>
	<keyword>general hospital</keyword>
	<keyword>brief intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Motivational Interviewing</keyword>
	<keyword>computer-generated feedback</keyword>
	<keyword>stage-tailored</keyword>
	<keyword>delivery channel</keyword>
</DOC>