<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02630966</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate perianal fistula healing at Week 30 in 2 different dose regimens of vedolizumab intravenous (IV) 300 milligram (mg) in participants with fistulizing Crohn's disease (CD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vedolizumab IV 300 mg in the Treatment of Fistulizing Crohn's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The drug being tested in this study is called vedolizumab IV. Vedolizumab IV is being tested to treat people who have fistulizing CD. This study will look at fistula healing in people who take vedolizumab IV. The study will enroll approximately 126 patients. Participants will be randomly assigned (by chance, like flipping a coin) to one of the two treatment groups—which will remain undisclosed to the patient and study doctor during the study (unless there is an urgent medical need): - Group 1: Vedolizumab IV 300 mg dose at Weeks 0, 2, 6, 14 and 22, and a placebo infusion at Week 10 (dummy inactive infusion - this is a solution that looks like the study drug but has no active ingredient). - Group 2: Vedolizumab IV 300 mg dose at Weeks 0, 2, 6, 10, 14 and 22. This multi-center trial will be conducted worldwide. The overall time to participate in this study from screening to 18 weeks after the last dose is 44 weeks. Participants will make multiple visits to the clinic, and will be contacted by telephone 6 months after last dose of study drug for a follow-up assessment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vedolizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. In the opinion of the investigator, the participant is capable of understanding and complying with protocol requirements. 2. The participant or, when applicable, the participant's legally acceptable representative has signed and dated a written, informed consent form and any required privacy authorization prior to the initiation of any study procedures. 3. Has a diagnosis of CD established at least 3 months prior to randomization by clinical and endoscopic evidence and corroborated by a histopathology report. 4. Has a diagnosis of a minimum of 1 perianal draining fistula of at least 2 weeks duration as a complication of moderately to severely active CD, as identified on magnetic resonance image (MRI) at Screening. Other types of fistulae (enterocutaneous, abdominal) except rectovaginal fistulae are permitted, but the number of perianal draining fistulae is limited to 3. 5. The participant, historically, had an inadequate response with, lost response to, or was intolerant to either conventional therapy or a tumor necrosis factoralpha (TNFα) antagonist for their underlying CD (does not require treatment failure for currently active draining fistula). 6. Had noncutting perianal seton placement as part of standard care within 1 to 4 weeks prior to randomization. 7. Is willing and able to undergo MRI per protocol requirements. 8. Is willing and able to take antibiotic treatment (metronidazole or ciprofloxacin, as per local label) from Day 1 through study Week 6. 9. A male participant who is nonsterilized and sexually active with a female partner of childbearing potential agrees to use adequate contraception from signing of informed consent throughout the duration of the study and for 18 weeks after last dose. 10. A female participant of childbearing potential who is sexually active with a nonsterilized male partner agrees to use routinely adequate contraception from signing of informed consent throughout the duration of the study and for 18 weeks after last dose. 11. Has a family history of colorectal cancer, personal history of increased colorectal cancer risk, age &gt;50 years, or other known risk factors must be uptodate on colorectal cancer surveillance (may be performed during Screening as standard of care). 1. Has a diagnosis of ulcerative colitis or indeterminate colitis. 2. Has a perianal abscess greater than (&gt;) 2 centimeter (cm) or an abscess that the investigator feels requires drainage based on either clinical assessment or MRI. 3. Has a Crohn's Disease Activity Index (CDAI) score &gt;400. 4. Has an ileostomy, colostomy, or known fixed symptomatic stenosis of the intestine. 5. Has significant anal or rectal stenosis. 6. Has active or latent tuberculosis (TB), regardless of treatment history, as evidenced by any of the following: 1. History of TB. 2. A diagnostic TB test performed during Screening that is positive, as defined by: I. A positive test for tuberculosis (QuantiFERON) or 2 successive indeterminate QuantiFERON tests OR II. A tuberculin skin test reaction greater than or equal to (≥) 10 millimeter (mm) (≥5 mm in participants receiving the equivalent of &gt;15 mg/day prednisone) 7. Has a known history of infection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus (HCV) or is found to be seropositive at Screening. 8. Has evidence of active Clostridium difficile (C. difficile) infection or is having treatment for C. difficile infection or other intestinal pathogens during Screening. 9. Has evidence of an active infection during Screening (eg, sepsis, cytomegalovirus, or listeriosis), other than related to the fistula(e). 10. Currently requires or has a planned surgical intervention for CD during the study. 11. Has a contraindication for MRI. 12. Has allergies to and/or contraindications for metronidazole and ciprofloxacin (including interacting drugs such as tizanidine). 13. In the opinion of the investigator, the participant is likely to require greater than 6 weeks of treatment after Day 1 with metronidazole or ciprofloxacin for the treatment of abscess. 14. Is taking, has taken, or is required to take any excluded medications. 15. Has received nonbiologic investigational therapy within 30 days prior to randomization. 16. Has received an approved nonbiologic therapy (including 5aminosalicylate [5ASA], corticosteroid, azathioprine, 6mercaptopurine [6MP], etc.) in an investigational protocol within 30 days prior to randomization. 17. Has received any investigational or approved biologic or biosimilar agent within 60 days or 5 halflives (whichever is longer) of randomization. 18. Has a history of hypersensitivity or allergies to vedolizumab or its components. 19. Has any prior exposure to vedolizumab, natalizumab, efalizumab, or rituximab. 20. Has received any live vaccinations within 30 days prior to randomization. 21. Has current rectovaginal fistula. 22. Currently has more than 3 draining perianal fistulae. 23. Has a positive progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy (PML) subjective symptom checklist at Screening or Day 1 visit. 24. Has a history of malignancy, except for the following: adequatelytreated nonmetastatic basal cell skin cancer; squamous cell skin cancer that has been adequately treated and that has not recurred for at least 1 year prior to Screening; or history of cervical carcinoma in situ that has been adequately treated and that has not recurred for at least 3 years prior to Screening. Participants with a remote history of malignancy (eg, &gt;10 years since completion of curative therapy without recurrence) will be considered based on the nature of the malignancy and the therapy received, and must be discussed with the sponsor on a casebycase basis prior to randomization. 25. Has a history of any major neurological disorders, including stroke, multiple sclerosis, brain tumor, demyelinating or neurodegenerative disease. 26. Has conditions which, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with the participant's ability to comply with the study procedures. 27. Has any unstable or uncontrolled cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic, renal, gastrointestinal (GI), genitourinary, hematological, coagulation, immunological, endocrine/metabolic, neurologic or other medical disorder that, in the opinion of the investigator, would confound the study results or compromise participant safety. 28. Has any of the following laboratory abnormalities during the Screening Period: I. Hemoglobin level less than (&lt;) 8 gram per deciliter (g/dL). II. White blood cell (WBC) count &lt;3 * 10^9 per liter (/L). III. Lymphocyte count &lt;0.5 * 10^9/L. IV. Platelet count &lt;100 * 10^9/L or &gt;1200 * 10^9/L. V. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt;3 * the upper limit of normal (ULN). VI. Alkaline phosphatase &gt;3 * ULN. VII. Serum creatinine &gt;1.5 * ULN. Note: Retesting laboratory values during the screening interval maybe considered with consultation from the medical monitor. 29. If female, the participant is pregnant or lactating or intending to become pregnant before, during, or within 18 weeks after participating in this study; or intending to donate ova during such time period. 30. If male, the participant intends to donate sperm during the course of this study or for 18 weeks thereafter. 31. Is an immediate family member, study site employee, or is in a dependent relationship with a study site employee who is involved in conduct of this study (eg, spouse, parent, child, sibling) or may consent under duress. 32. Has a history of drug abuse (defined as any illicit drug use) or a history of alcohol abuse within 1 year prior to Visit 1.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug therapy</keyword>
</DOC>