<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02630186</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical research study is being carried out in two parts, Phase 1 and Phase 2. The primary purpose of the Phase 1 portion of the study is to observe the safety of the combination of rociletinib and MPDL3280A in EGFR-mutant NSCLC patients. The primary purpose of the Phase 2 portion of the study is to evaluate the safety and anti-tumor effects of the combination of rociletinib and MPDL3280A, at the best doses for the combination determined in Phase 1, in patients with EGFR-mutant NSCLC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 1b/2 Study of Safety and Efficacy of Rociletinib in Combination With MPDL3280A in Patients With Advanced or Metastatic EGFR-mutant NSCLC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 1b/2, open-label, non-randomized, multicenter study evaluating the safety and efficacy of rociletinib administered in combination with MPDL3280A. Phase 1: This will be the dose finding phase of the study. Patients will be enrolled to available Dosing Cohort. Patients who have progressed after prior first- or second-generation EGFR TKI, regardless of T790M mutation status, will be enrolled. Phase 2: Patients will be enrolled into 2 groups. Group A will enroll eligible first-line patients who are EGFR TKI treatment-na誰ve and chemotherapy-na誰ve. Group B will enroll eligible patients who have progressed after prior first- or second-generation EGFR TKI, regardless of T790M mutation status.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ECOG performance status of 0 or 1 Adequate hematological and biological function, confirmed by defined laboratory values Histologically or cytologically documented metastatic or unresectable, locally advanced or metastatic NSCLC, with one or more activating EGFR mutation (eg, G719X, exon 19 deletion, L858R, L861Q) and absence of exon 20 insertion Measurable disease as defined by RECIST v1.1 Biopsy of tumor tissue for central evaluation, within 60 days prior to the first day of study treatment For Phase 1 and Phase 2 Group B, progression after prior 1st or 2nd generation EGFR TKI (eg, erlotinib, gefitinib, afatinib). Previous chemotherapy for NSCLC is allowed. For Phase 2 Group A, EGFR TKI treatmentna誰ve and chemotherapyna誰ve Unresolved toxicities from prior therapy Symptomatic, untreated or unstable central nervous system or leptomeningeal metastases Previous treatment with rociletinib or MPDL3280A, or other 3rd generation EGFR TKI (eg, AZD9291, HM61713), or PD 1 axis targeted therapy (eg, anti PD 1 or antiPD L1) Prior treatment with CD137 agonists or other immune checkpoint blockade therapies, including antiCTLA4 therapeutic antibodies Uncontrolled pleural effusion, pericardial effusion or ascites requiring recurrent drainage procedures Uncontrolled hypercalcemia or symptomatic hypercalcemia requiring continued use of bisphosphonate therapy or denosumab (bisphosphonate use for prevention of skeletal events allowed) Known hypersensitivity to any component of the MPDL3280A or rociletinib formulations or history or hypersensitivity to chimeric humanized antibodies or fusion proteins History of autoimmune disease History of prior allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation or prior solid organ transplantation Treatment with systemic immunosuppressive medications within 2 weeks prior to first day of study treatment (inhaled corticosteroids and mineralocorticoids allowed) Live attenuated vaccine within 4 weeks prior to first day of study treatment Active tuberculosis, active hepatitis, or positive HIV status Class II to IV heart failure as defined by the New York Heart Association functional classification system Untreated or uncontrolled cardiovascular disease or other symptomatic cardiac dysfunction QTCF &gt; 450 ms, inability to measure QT interval on ECG, personal or family history of long QT syndrome, requirement for medications that have the potential to prolong the QT interval History of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, organizing pneumonia, druginduced pneumonitis, idiopathic pneumonitis, or evidence of active pneumonitis on screening chest computerized tomography (CT) scan (history of radiation pneumonitis in radiation field may be allowed) Other malignancies within 5 years prior to enrollment, with the exception of carcinoma in situ of the cervix, basal or squamous cell skin cancer, localized prostate cancer, or ductal carcinoma in situ</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>