<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02630563</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is planned to be conducted in 2 parts. The first part (open label, multi-center, non-controlled) of the study will estimate a dose that would provide a mycophenolic acid (MPA) exposure in pediatric participant that is comparable to that achieved in adult liver transplant participants receiving the approved dose of mycophenolate mofetil (MMF, CellCept). The second part (open-label, multi-center, single-arm Phase IV study) of the study will provide the pharmacokinetics, efficacy and safety profile of the proposed dose in the immediate post-transplant period. This study will be conducted at two centers based in the United States of America. Twelve pediatric transplant participants receiving a first liver allograft from a cadaveric or living donor will be enrolled in this study. Stable pediatric liver transplant participants who are at least 6 months post-transplant and who were already receiving stable dose of MMF in combination with cyclosporine will be enrolled into the study. Participants should have received stable MMF dose according to center practice for at least seven days in order to get steady state pharmacokinetics (PK). Participants also should have received stable concomitant doses of cyclosporine (for at least 2 days) and corticosteroids per center practice. Participants will be aged between 9 months and 12 years, with at least 6 participants greater than or equal to (&gt;/=) 9 months and less than (&lt;) 36 months, of whom at least 2 will be &lt;24 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Tolerability and Pharmacokinetics of Oral CellCept (Mycophenolate Mofetil) in Pediatric Liver Transplant Recipients on Concomitant Treatment With Cyclosporine and Corticosteroids</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female participant must be between 3 months and 12 years of age Participant is a recipient of a first liver allograft from cadaveric or living donors Participant is a singleorgan recipient (liver only) Female participants of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test with a sensitivity of at least 50 milli International Units per milliliter (mIU/mL) within one week prior to PK sampling Female participants of childbearing potential must use two reliable forms of contraception simultaneously unless abstinence is the chosen method Effective contraception must be used before beginning of PK sampling Participants must be able to receive oral medication Participants must be at least 6 months posttransplant and had started on MMF in the early posttransplant period (within 2 weeks of transplant) Participants must be receiving stable doses of MMF per center practice for at least 7 days prior to PK sampling In addition, participants must be receiving stable doses of cyclosporine and corticosteroids, according to center practice Participants' parent/guardian are capable of understanding the purposes and risks of the study and must sign an informed consent for the study Pregnant or nursing adolescents Participants who had undergone dialysis within two weeks before PK sampling Participants with active systemic infections Participants with absolute neutrophil counts (ANC) of less than 1300 per microliter (µL), or platelets counts less than 50 000/µL or hemoglobin at a concentration below a set lower limit (according to center practice, but not less than 8 grams per deciliter) at the time of study entry Participants with active peptic ulcer disease Participants with severe diarrhea (more than 5 watery stools per day) or other gastrointestinal disorders which might interfere with their ability to absorb oral medication History of positive human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) test</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>