<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02630459</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group, multicenter study followed by an open-label treatment phase. To evaluate the effect of AMG 334 compared to placebo on the change from baseline in monthly migraine days.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Safety and Efficacy Study to Evaluate AMG 334 in Migraine Prevention</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 2, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study in subjects with episodic migraine. The study is designed to evaluate if treatment with AMG 334 once a month for 6 months compared with placebo is effective in reducing the mean monthly migraine days. Additionally, this study will continue to evaluate the efficacy and safety of AMG 334 during the open label treatment phase where subjects will continue to receive active treatment monthly.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Migraine Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Initial Screening and Baseline Phase History of migraine (with or without aura) for ≥ 12 months prior to screening according to the IHS Classification ICHD3 (Headache Classification Committee of the International Headache Society, 2013), Migraine frequency: ≥ 4 and &lt; 15 migraine days per month on average across the 3 months prior to screening, Headache frequency: &lt; 15 headache days per month on average across the 3 months prior to screening and during baseline, Demonstrated at least 80% compliance with the eDiary. Older than 50 years of age at migraine onset, History of cluster headache or hemiplegic migraine headache, Unable to differentiate migraine from other headaches, Used prohibited medication, device, or procedure prior to the start of the baseline phase or during the baseline phase, More than 1 migraine prophylactic medication within 2 months, Botulinum toxin in the head or neck region within 4 months, Ergotaminederivatives, steroids, and triptans used for migraine prophylaxis within 2 months. Devices and procedures used for migraine prophylaxis, No therapeutic response with &gt;2 medication categories for prophylactic treatment of migraine after an adequate therapeutic trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Migraine Prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>Headache</keyword>
	<keyword>Prophylaxis</keyword>
</DOC>