<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01600794</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Because the society convention is changed, people are late for getting married, leading to increasing the bearing age in women. According to the previous study, if the age is over 30, the oocyte number in ovary has left only 10％ and 3％ in over 40 years old. The data is collected by Bureau of Health Promotion, Department of Health shows that there are about 7000 people treating the infertility and it spends about 150000 to 250000 NT dollars in every in vitro fertilization (IVF) cycle, but the live birth rate is only 30％. So it is important to know how to estimate and approve the ovary function that lead to increase the live birth rate. The investigators plan to estimate the correlation between the serum androgens levels and pregnancy outcome in the women who have infertility problem. Furthermore, for the repeated IVF cycle, the ovary function might be re-evlauated because of the possible effect from stimulated drugs used on previous cycle. It's important to understand the ovary function for IVF patient to choose the appropriate drugs and dose. The investigators use blood and clinical test to analyze, the items for analysis are below: 1. Routine blood test: FSH、LH、E2、P4、Anti-Mullerian Hormone(AMH)、 2. Studied blood test: Inhibin B、total testosterone (TT)、Androstenedione、DHEA-S 3. Clinical test: Ultrasound 4. Personal condition. In order to finishing the test, every patient will be asked to collect about 10 to 15 cc blood for the research.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>To Evaluate The Anrogens and Ovary Function in In Vitro Fertilization</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>This study include the patients who are evaluated by the doctors and are sure to process the IVF cycle. This study exclude the patients who are not evaluated by the doctors and are not sure to process the IVF cycle.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>In Vitro Fertilization (IVF)</keyword>
	<keyword>androgens</keyword>
	<keyword>ovary function</keyword>
	<keyword>This study include the patients who are evaluated by the doctors and are sure to process the In Vitro Fertilization cycle.</keyword>
</DOC>