<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00039507</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Radiofrequency ablation uses high-frequency electric current to kill tumor cells. Combining radiofrequency ablation with surgery may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of combining radiofrequency ablation with surgery in treating patients who have stage I or stage II non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Radiofrequency Ablation During Surgery in Treating Patients With Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the acute effects of intraoperative radiofrequency tumor ablation (RFA) in patients with resectable non-small cell lung cancer. - Determine the treatment-related toxicity in patients treated with this therapy. - Determine the dimensions of the RFA lesion produced by the ablation procedure in these patients. OUTLINE: Patients undergo intraoperative radiofrequency tumor ablation over 10-15 minutes for each tumor immediately followed by tumor resection. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A maximum of 20 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of malignant nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC) Intraoperative needle biopsy confirmation allowed Resectable disease (stage I or II) All tissue to be treated by radiofrequency tumor ablation must be completely contained within boundaries of planned lung resection Medically fit to undergo lung resection PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: Over 18 Performance status: Not specified Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Other: Not pregnant or nursing PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: No prior or concurrent biologic therapy Chemotherapy: No prior or concurrent chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: No prior or concurrent endocrine therapy Radiotherapy: No prior or concurrent radiotherapy Surgery: See Disease Characteristics Other: No other prior therapy for NSCLC</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage I non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>