<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00003794</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Quality-of-life assessment of patients undergoing cancer treatment may help determine the intermediate- and long-term effects of treatment in patients with cancer. PURPOSE: This clinical trial studies the quality of life in patients with previously treated ovarian cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Quality-of-Life Study of Patients With Previously Treated Ovarian Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Compare quality of life in terms of health status, sexual functioning, psychological/emotional well being, and social functioning in ovarian germ cell cancer survivors vs a matched healthy control group. II. Predict quality of life in these patients through the additive effects of cancer diagnosis and treatment, sociodemographic characteristics, other stressors, and social network variables. OUTLINE: Patients identify up to 3 healthy acquaintance controls within 3 years of the same age. Patients and controls complete a written questionnaire, which takes about 30 minutes, and a telephone interview, which takes about 1 hour, to assess quality of life. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 190 patients and 190 healthy controls will be accrued for this study within 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: History of early or advanced ovarian germ cell tumors Continuously disease free for at least 2 years prior to study Must have been enrolled on GOG protocols 45, 78, 90, and 116 or similar protocols of cisplatinbased chemotherapy at M.D. Anderson Cancer Center PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: Not specified Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Other: Must be able to complete a written questionnaire and telephone interview in English PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: See Disease Characteristics Endocrine therapy: Not specified Radiotherapy: No prior radiotherapy Surgery: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2005</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage I ovarian germ cell tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II ovarian germ cell tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III ovarian germ cell tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV ovarian germ cell tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent ovarian germ cell tumor</keyword>
</DOC>