<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00003526</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Antineoplastons are naturally-occurring substances that may also be made in the laboratory. Antineoplastons may inhibit the growth of cancer cells. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well antineoplaston therapy works in treating patients with cancer of unknown primary origin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Antineoplaston Therapy in Treating Patients With Cancer of Unknown Primary Origin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Provide treatment with antineoplastons A10 and AS2-1 for patients with incurable adenocarcinoma of unknown primary. - Describe response, tolerance to, and side effects of this regimen in these patients. OUTLINE: This is an open-label study. Patients receive gradually escalating doses of antineoplastons A10 and AS2-1 by intravenous injection 6 times daily until the maximum tolerated dose is reached. Treatment continues for at least 3 months in the absence of unacceptable toxicity or disease progression. Patients achieving complete response (CR) continue treatment for an additional 8 months after reaching CR. Tumors are measured every 2 months for 1 year and then every 3 months for 1 year. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: Approximately 20-40 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Unknown Primary</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of unknown primary that is unlikely to respond to existing therapy, including surgery, radiotherapy, and chemotherapy Evidence of tumor by MRI, CT scan, chest xray, or radionuclide scan PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 6 months and over Performance status: Karnofsky 60100% Life expectancy: At least 2 months Hematopoietic: WBC at least 2,000/mm^3 Platelet count at least 50,000/mm^3 Hepatic: No hepatic insufficiency Bilirubin no greater than 2.5 mg/dL SGOT and SGPT no greater than 5 times upper limit of normal Renal: No renal insufficiency Creatinine no greater than 2.5 mg/dL No history of renal conditions that contraindicate high dosages of sodium Cardiovascular: No uncontrolled hypertension No history of congestive heart failure No history of other cardiovascular conditions that contraindicate high dosages of sodium Pulmonary: No severe lung disease, such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease Other: Not pregnant or nursing Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 4 weeks after study participation No active infection No nonmalignant systemic disease Not a high medical or psychiatric risk PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: At least 4 weeks since prior immunotherapy No concurrent immunomodulating agents Chemotherapy: At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy (6 weeks for nitrosoureas) Endocrine therapy: Concurrent corticosteroids allowed Radiotherapy: At least 8 weeks since prior radiotherapy Surgery: Recovered from prior surgery Other: Prior cytodifferentiating agents allowed No prior antineoplastons No other concurrent antineoplastic agents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma of unknown primary</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent carcinoma of unknown primary</keyword>
</DOC>