<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00003898</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Glutamine may be able to decrease inflammation of the mouth and digestive system in children who are undergoing stem cell transplantation. PURPOSE: Randomized double-blinded phase II trial to study the effectiveness of glutamine in reducing inflammation of the mouth and digestive system in children who are undergoing peripheral stem cell transplantation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Glutamine in Treating Side Effects in Children Who Are Undergoing Stem Cell Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the efficacy of supplemental oral glutamine in reducing the severity and duration of mucositis in children undergoing stem cell transplantation. II. Determine the safety of this regimen in these patients. III. Determine serum glutamine levels achieved during this regimen in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, double blind, multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to inclusion of total body irradiation in the conditioning regimen (yes vs no). Patients receive either oral glutamine or oral placebo (glycine) twice a day beginning on the day of admission for the stem cell transplant and continuing for 28 days or until hospital discharge, whichever is first. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 120 patients (60 per arm) will be accrued for this study within 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Undergoing allogeneic or autologous stem cell transplant (including bone marrow, cord blood, or peripheral blood stem cells) Conditioning regimen must have at least 50% risk of grade III or IV mucositis No grade III or IV hepatic toxicity PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 1 to 21 Performance status: Not specified Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: See Disease Characteristics Renal: Not specified Other: No grade III or IV toxicity at admission for stem cell transplant No altered mental status PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: No concurrent vancomycin paste or nonabsorbable antibiotics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>unspecified childhood solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
	<keyword>oral complications</keyword>
</DOC>