<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00003974</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Vaccines made from a person's tumor may help the body build an immune response to kill tumor cells. PURPOSE: Phase I trial to study the effectiveness of vaccine therapy in treating patients who have undergone surgery to remove stage I, stage II, or stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer or stage I or stage II mesothelioma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vaccine Therapy in Treating Patients With Stage I, Stage II, or Stage IIIA Non-small Cell Lung Cancer or With Stage I or Stage II Mesothelioma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Define the immunological parameters of cytolytic T cell and T helper cell activity associated with skin testing and vaccination with autologous lung tumor associated antigen and detoxPC in patients with curatively resected stage I, II, or IIIA non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) or stage I or II mesothelioma. II. Evaluate any responses associated with an enhanced antitumor immune status in this patient population with this treatment regimen. OUTLINE: Patients undergo delayed type hypersensitivity skin testing with autologous tumor associated antigen (TAA) and memory antigens (i.e., Monilia, PPD, and Trichophyton) intradermally at 1-4 weeks following surgical tumor resection. At week 4-9, patients receive low dose cyclophosphamide IV once. At 3 days following chemotherapy, patients receive autologous TAA with DetoxPC intradermally for up to 3 doses over 4 weeks. At 2-3 weeks following vaccination, patients undergo repeat skin testing. At week 6-12, patients with a positive skin test undergo biopsy of the skin test/vaccination site followed by leukapheresis at week 12-20 if T cells exhibit active antitumor reactivity. Patients with stable or regressive disease receive additional vaccination courses at week 20 and thereafter. Patients are followed for 5 years. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 20 patients will be accrued for this study within 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mesothelioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically proven primary stage I (T2, N0), II, or IIIA nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC) curatively resected by pneumonectomy, lobectomy, or wedge resection OR Stage I or II mesothelioma Measurable disease Lesions must be at least 3 cm in diameter PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 20 to 70 Performance status: Not specified Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Other: No other malignancy except nonmelanoma skin cancer No history of severe allergies No history of autoimmune disease Not pregnant PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: Not specified Endocrine therapy: No concurrent glucocorticoids Radiotherapy: Not specified Surgery: See Disease Characteristics Other: No concurrent nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage I non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>localized malignant mesothelioma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>