<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00003290</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Radiation therapy uses high-energy x-rays to damage tumor cells. It is not yet known whether standard radiation therapy is more effective than high-dose radiation therapy in treating patients with prostate cancer. PURPOSE: Randomized phase III trial to compare the effectiveness of standard radiation therapy with that of high-dose radiation therapy in treating patients with stage II or stage III prostate cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Radiation Therapy in Treating Patients With Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Compare local tumor control in patients with stage II or III prostate cancer treated with neoadjuvant androgen deprivation therapy with standard vs high-dose conformal radiotherapy. - Compare the incidence of biochemical failure (prostate-specific antigen (PSA) greater than 2 ng/mL at 6 or more months after initiation of radiotherapy and PSA rising from nadir level by at least 50%), development of metastases, and survival in patients treated with these regimens. - Compare the acute and late radiation-induced side effects of these regimens in this patient population. - Compare aspects of quality of life, health economics, models of normal tissue, and tumor control in patients treated with these regimens. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to prostate-specific antigen, T stage, and Gleason score. Patients are randomized to one of two treatment arms. All patients receive neoadjuvant androgen deprivation with luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone agonists every 4 weeks beginning 3-6 months before initiation of radiotherapy and continuing until completion of radiotherapy. - Arm I: Patients undergo standard conformal radiotherapy for 6.5 weeks. - Arm II: Patients undergo high-dose conformal radiotherapy for 7.5 weeks. Quality of life is assessed at baseline, every 6 months for 2 years, and then annually thereafter. Patients are followed every 6 months for 2 years and then annually thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 800 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed prostate cancer T1bT3a, N0, M0 (stage II or III) Prostatespecific antigen at least 50 ng/mL PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: Not specified Performance status: WHO 01 Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: WBC greater than 4,000/mm^3 Platelet count greater than 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin greater than 11 g/dL Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Other: No significant past medical history that would preclude radical radiotherapy No condition that would preclude standard radiotherapy No hip prosthesis PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: Not specified Endocrine therapy: No prior androgen deprivation therapy Radiotherapy: No prior pelvic radiotherapy Surgery: No prior radical prostatectomy</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2001</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IIB prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIA prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III prostate cancer</keyword>
</DOC>