<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00003122</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Surgery may be an effective treatment for neuroblastoma. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well surgery works in treating patients with neuroblastoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Surgery in Treating Patients With Neuroblastoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Evaluate the safety and efficacy of surgical treatment alone for stage II neuroblastoma without N-myc amplification (NMA). - Describe predictive factors of relapse and survival for stages I and II neuroblastoma without NMA treated by surgery alone. OUTLINE: Patients with localized resectable tumors undergo surgery. Postoperative evaluations are performed 30 days following surgery. Study patients with stage I (without N-myc amplification) tumors and trial patients with stage II tumors receive no further therapy. Study patients (except stage I patients) receive surgery and/or chemotherapy according to other protocols as necessary for disease progression or relapse. Patients are followed every 3 months for the first year, then every 4 and 6 months for the second and third year respectively, then yearly for 5 years. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: This study will accrue 140 stage II patients for the trial portion at a rate of 40 per year over 3.5 years. At least 70 more patients will be accrued for the study portion.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Trial: Histologically proven International Neuroblastoma Staging System (INSS) stage IIA and IIB neuroblastoma without amplification of the Nmyc oncogene Study: Histologically proven neuroblastoma Stage I Stage II with amplified Nmyc Stage II without evaluation of Nmyc Stage II with symptomatic spinal cord compression Stage III No metastases diagnosed within 1 month of study PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 20 and under Performance status: Not specified Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: No prior chemotherapy No adjuvant chemotherapy planned Endocrine therapy: Prior use of steroids allowed Radiotherapy: Not specified Surgery: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>20 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>localized resectable neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>localized unresectable neuroblastoma</keyword>
</DOC>