<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00003600</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Epoetin alfa may stimulate red blood cell production and treat anemia in patients with cancer who are receiving chemotherapy. It is not yet known whether epoetin alfa is more effective than a placebo in treating anemia in patients receiving chemotherapy. PURPOSE: Randomized double blinded phase III trial to compare the effectiveness of epoetin alfa with a placebo in treating anemia in cancer patients who are receiving chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Epoetin Alfa in Treating Anemia in Patients Who Are Receiving Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine whether epoetin alfa treatment improves the quality of life in anemic patients who are undergoing chemotherapy for advanced malignancy. II. Determine whether epoetin alfa increases hemoglobin levels and decreases transfusion requirements in these patients. III. Validate or refute the use of an algorithm using pre- and posttreatment epoetin alfa, ferritin, and hemoglobin levels to predict 16 weeks response or no response to therapeutic doses of epoetin alfa as set forth by these patients. IV. Explore whether anemic patients receiving platinum-containing chemotherapy regimens experience less nephrotoxicity if they receive concurrent epoetin alfa compared to those who receive placebo. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, double blind study. Patients are stratified by primary malignant disease (lung vs breast vs other), life expectancy (4-6 months vs greater than 6 months), planned concurrent radiotherapy (yes vs no), and degree of anemia (mild or at least 9 g/dL vs severe or less than 9 g/dL). Patients receiving chemotherapy are randomized to receive epoetin alfa subcutaneously once a week for a maximum of 16 weeks (arm I) or placebo subcutaneously once a week for a maximum of 16 weeks (arm II). Quality of life is assessed at randomization and monthly throughout study. Patients are followed every 6 months for 1 year.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Plasmacytoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myeloproliferative Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intestinal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precancerous Conditions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Anemic: Hemoglobin in males less than 11.5 g/dL; hemoglobin in females less than 10.0 g/dL No anemia secondary to B12, folic acid, or iron deficiency No anemia secondary to gastrointestinal bleed or hemolysis No anemia secondary to a primary or chemotherapyinduced myelodysplastic syndrome No anemia secondary to acute lymphocytic leukemia Histologically confirmed advanced malignancy Lung Breast Other Currently receiving myelosuppressive, cytotoxic chemotherapy for advanced cancer No patients receiving adjuvant therapy for cancer that has been surgically removed PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: ECOG 01 Life expectancy: At least 4 months Hematopoietic: See Disease Characteristics Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Cardiovascular: No uncontrolled hypertension (systolic at least 180, diastolic at least 100) Other: Normal or elevated ferritin No known hypersensitivity to epoetin alfa Must be able to reliably take oral medication Must be alert and mentally competent Not pregnant or nursing PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: At least 1 year since prior epoetin alfa At least 2 weeks since prior red blood cell transfusions No concurrent peripheral blood stem cell or bone marrow transplantation Chemotherapy: See Disease Characteristics Endocrine therapy: Not specified Radiotherapy: Concurrent radiotherapy allowed Surgery: See Disease Characteristics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>