<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00003846</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Radiation therapy uses x-rays to damage tumor cells. Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Peripheral stem cell transplantation may allow doctors to give higher doses of radiation therapy and chemotherapy and kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of radiation therapy, chemotherapy and peripheral stem cell transplantation in treating patients with primitive neuroectodermal tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Radiation Therapy, Chemotherapy, and Peripheral Stem Cell Transplantation in Treating Patients With Primitive Neuroectodermal Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the safety of postradiotherapy high-dose consolidation chemotherapy with peripheral blood stem cell (PBSC) support in patients with high-risk primitive neuroectodermal tumors. - Determine the safety of delaying radiotherapy by approximately one month in these patients. - Determine the maximum tolerated dose of thiotepa in these patients. - Determine the toxic effects of intensive chemotherapy with PBSC support in these patients. - Assess the time to hematopoietic recovery after PBSC infusion when intensive chemotherapy is used after craniospinal radiotherapy in these patients. - Determine the overall and event-free survival of patients treated with this regimen. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study of thiotepa during consolidation therapy. - Induction: Within 31 days of initial surgery, patients receive induction therapy comprising vincristine IV on day 0, cyclophosphamide IV over 2 hours on days 0 and 1, and filgrastim (G-CSF) subcutaneously (SC) beginning on day 2 and continuing for at least 7-10 days. Peripheral blood stem cells (PBSC) are then collected. - Chemoradiotherapy: After blood cell counts recover, and within 28 days of starting induction, patients begin chemoradiotherapy. Patients receive vincristine IV once weekly for 8 doses. Radiotherapy is administered 5 days a week, for 6 weeks, beginning within the same week as the start of vincristine. - Consolidation: Therapy begins 4-6 weeks after the last radiation treatment in the absence of disease progression. The first and third course are the same and comprise vincristine IV on day 0, carboplatin IV over 1 hour on days 0 and 1, thiotepa IV over 3 hours on days 2-4, and G-CSF SC daily beginning on day 7. PBSC are reinfused on day 7. The second course comprises vincristine IV on day 0, carboplatin IV over 1 hour on days 0 and 1, cyclophosphamide IV over 2 hours on days 2 and 3, and G-CSF SC daily beginning on day 5. PBSC are reinfused on day 5. Each course lasts 21 days. For consolidation therapy, cohorts of 6-12 patients each receive escalating doses of thiotepa until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose at which no more than 2 of 12 patients experience dose-limiting toxicity. Patients are followed every 3 months for 1 year, every 6 months for 2 years, and then annually thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 24-56 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuroectodermal Tumors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuroectodermal Tumors, Primitive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thiotepa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vincristine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically proven primitive neuroectodermal tumor (PNET) of one of the following types: Atypical teratoid/rhabdoid tumor Medulloblastoma Desmoplastic medulloblastoma Ependymoblastoma Medullomyoblastoma Spongioblastoma Spongioblastoma polare Primitive polar spongioblastoma Medulloepithelioma Neuroblastoma Pineoblastoma Posterior fossa PNET must be M13 or M0 with greater than 1.5 cm2 residual disease Non posterior fossa PNET and other types must be M03 If M3, must show clear evidence of tumor on MRI No marrow involvement or other extraneural metastases No M4 disease No cord compression requiring emergency radiotherapy PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 3 to 21 Performance status: Not specified Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Absolute neutrophil count at least 1,000/mm^3 Platelet count at least 150,000/mm^3 (no platelet transfusions) Hemoglobin at least 10 g/dL (red blood cell transfusions allowed) Hepatic: Bilirubin less than 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) AST or ALT less than 2.5 times ULN Renal: Creatinine clearance or glomerular filtration rate at least 70 mL/min Cardiovascular: Shortening fraction greater than 27% by echocardiogram OR Ejection fraction greater than 47% by MUGA Pulmonary: FEV_1/FVC greater than 60% except for children who: Are uncooperative Have no dyspnea at rest Have no exercise intolerance Have pulse oximetry greater than 94% on room air Other: Not pregnant or nursing PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: Not specified Endocrine therapy: Steroids for increased intracranial pressure allowed Radiotherapy: See Disease Characteristics No prior urgent radiotherapy Surgery: Not specified Other: No prior therapy for tumor</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>regional neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>disseminated neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage 4S neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>untreated childhood supratentorial primitive neuroectodermal tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>untreated childhood medulloblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>newly diagnosed childhood ependymoma</keyword>
</DOC>