<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00003648</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Determination of genetic markers for colorectal cancer may help doctors to identify patients who are at risk. PURPOSE: Genetic testing study of patients and families with a history of colorectal cancer to identify patients who are at risk of developing colorectal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Genetic Study of Patients and Families With a History of Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Select patients with colon cancer and families at high-risk for colon cancer and collect leukocyte DNA, immortalized cell lines, plasma, and tumor specimens from these individuals and from control individuals. II. Develop patient education, counseling, and follow up plans for these individuals. III. Compare the frequency of defective DNA mismatch repair in individuals with familial colon cancer versus all colon cancers by using antibodies to the hMSH2 and hMLH1 protein products. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients, family members, and control individuals complete an extended telephone interview, an extended personal interview, and an epidemiological survey, and contribute a blood specimen. Blood and tumor specimens are examined for the specific pattern of immunohistochemical expression of hMSH2 and HMLH1 to determine the frequency or lack of expression of these two protein products. Patients may be contacted periodically (about every 3 years) to update information about health, health practices, and family history. Patients do not receive the results of the genetic testing and the results do not influence the type or duration of treatment. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: At least 500-600 families (approximately 1500 patients) and the same number of matched controls will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Primary colorectal cancer and participating in one of the following NCCTG protocols: NCCTG784852: No Treatment Control Versus Levamisole Versus Levamisole Plus 5Fluorouracil NCCTG794604: No Treatment Control Versus 5FU by Portal Vein Infusion NCCTG794751: Postoperative Radiation Versus Postoperative Radiation Plus Sequential Chemotherapy with Methyl CCNU and 5FU NCCTG844652: An Intergroup Study An Evaluation of Levamisole Alone or Levamisole Plus 5Fluorouracil as Surgical Adjuvant Treatment for Resectable Adenocarcinoma of the Colon NCCTG864751: Phase III Protocol for Surgical Adjuvant Therapy of Rectal Carcinoma: A Controlled Evaluation of (A) ProtractedInfusion5Fluorouracil (5FU) as a Radiation Enhancer and (B) 5FU Plus MethylCCNU Chemotherapy NCCTG874651: M/N A Controlled Evaluation of Recombinant InterferonGamma (IFNGM) and 5FU and Folinic Acid With or Without Levamisole as Adjuvant Treatment for Resectable Adenocarcinoma of the Colon NCCTG894651: A Controlled Phase III Evaluation of 5Fluorouracil with Levamisole and Leucovorin as Adjuvant Treatment for Resectable Colon Cancer NCCTG914653: A Phase III Evaluation of HighDose Levamisole Plus 5Fluorouracil and Leucovorin as Surgical Adjuvant Therapy for HighRisk Colon Cancer Adequate tissue for review OR Families of patients meeting the above criteria OR Colon cancer patient and population controls not in a highrisk family OR Spouse of a highrisk colon cancer patient PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: Not specified Performance status: See Disease Characteristics Life expectancy: See Disease Characteristics Hematopoietic: See Disease Characteristics Hepatic: See Disease Characteristics Renal: See Disease Characteristics PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage I colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I rectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II rectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III rectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV rectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent rectal cancer</keyword>
</DOC>