<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00003404</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Radiation therapy uses high-energy x-rays to damage tumor cells. Radiation therapy following surgery may be effective in treating patients with phyllodes tumor of the breast. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well radiation therapy works after surgery in treating women with phyllodes tumor of the breast.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Radiation Therapy After Surgery in Treating Women With Phyllodes Tumor of the Breast</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the local recurrence rate in women with phyllodes tumors of the breast previously treated with local excision with negative margins and are now treated with adjuvant radiotherapy. - Determine the survival rate in patients treated with this regimen. OUTLINE: Within 12 weeks after prior local excision or breast reexcision, patients undergo adjuvant radiotherapy 5 days a week for a total of 28 treatments. Patients are followed every 6 months for 10 years. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 50 patients will be accrued for this study within approximately 6-7 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Phyllodes Tumor</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically proven phyllodes tumors of the breast with borderline or malignant grade, defined as 1 of the following: Borderline, defined as 59 mitoses/10 high power fields (HPF), pushing or infiltrating margins, 2+ atypia Malignant, defined as 10 or more mitoses/10 HPF, predominantly infiltrating margins, usually 3+ atypia with occasional 2+ atypia Must have been excised with breastconserving resection No positive margins Local recurrence of a previously excised phyllodes tumor allowed if the recurrence is in the area of the prior excision No prior breast carcinoma or ductal carcinoma in situ in the ipsilateral breast Hormone receptor status: Not specified PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Sex: Female Menopausal status: Not specified Performance status: Not specified Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Other: Not pregnant Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy Not specified Chemotherapy Not specified Endocrine therapy Not specified Radiotherapy No prior radiotherapy to the ipsilateral breast Surgery See Disease Characteristics</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>phyllodes tumor</keyword>
</DOC>