<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00003382</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Combining more than one drug may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: Phase I trial to study the effectiveness of combination chemotherapy consisting of gemcitabine and topotecan in treating patients with refractory or recurrent ovarian or fallopian tube cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination Chemotherapy Consisting of Gemcitabine And Topotecan in Treating Patients With Refractory or Recurrent Ovarian or Fallopian Tube Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the maximum tolerated doses of the combination of gemcitabine and topotecan administered with and without filgrastim (G-CSF) in patients with refractory ovarian or fallopian tube cancer. - Describe and quantitate the clinical toxicities of these regimens in this patient population. OUTLINE: This is a dose escalation study. Patients receive gemcitabine IV over 30 minutes on days 1 and 8 and topotecan IV over 30 minutes on days 2-4. Some patients receive filgrastim (G-CSF) subcutaneously on days 9-14. Treatment repeats every 28 days for up to 5-10 courses. Cohorts of 3-6 patients receive escalating doses of topotecan until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose below that at which 2 of 6 patients experience dose limiting toxicity (DLT). Dose escalation of gemcitabine then continues in cohorts of 3-6 patients until the MTD is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose below that at which 2 of 6 patients experience DLT. Patients are followed every 2-3 months for 2 years, every 6 months for 3 years, then annually thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: Approximately 24 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peritoneal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Topotecan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically documented refractory or recurrent ovarian epithelial or fallopian tube cancer No borderline ovarian cancer Extraovarian papillary serous tumors eligible Must not be eligible for any higher priority phase II or III GOG protocol PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: GOG 02 Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Granulocyte count at least 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm^3 Hepatic: SGOT no greater than 3 times upper limit of normal (ULN) Bilirubin no greater than 1.5 mg/dL Elevated levels of alkaline phosphatase allowed Renal: Creatinine no greater than 1.5 mg/dL Cardiovascular: No angina pectoris or clinically significant multifocal uncontrolled cardiac dysrhythmias No uncontrolled hypertension Other: No other active malignancy No prior malignancy within the past 5 years except nonmelanomatous skin cancer No active infection No underlying medical problem that would prevent compliance No known hypersensitivity to E. coliderived drug preparations Fertile patients must use effective contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: Must have received at least 1 prior platinum and paclitaxelbased regimen At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy No prior topotecan and/or gemcitabine No prior chemotherapy for a different prior malignancy Endocrine therapy: Not specified Radiotherapy: No prior radiotherapy to more than 10% of bone marrow At least 2 weeks since limited field radiation therapy Surgery: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage I ovarian epithelial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II ovarian epithelial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III ovarian epithelial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV ovarian epithelial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent ovarian epithelial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>fallopian tube cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>primary peritoneal cavity cancer</keyword>
</DOC>