<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01289093</DOC>
	<brief_summary>LIFE-IN. Quality of life after operation for hernias are not well investigated and lack a good and easy-to-understand-tool to measure it. Carolina Comfort Scale (CCS) is a disease-specific quality of life questionnaire, designed by an American group, to monitor quality of life in patients undergoing operation for hernias. The investigators wish to test this questionnaire against Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) scores for core-hernia symptoms, to see if the CCS is a good way to monitor the changes in quality of life and other well-known core-symptoms before and after herniotomies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Quality of Life After Laparoscopic Inguinal- Incisional and Umbilical Herniotomy.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators include consecutively all in all 140 patients. 100 with inguinal hernias; 50 who is getting a Lichtenstein operation and 50 who is getting a laparoscopic operation. Furthermore minimum 20 patients who is getting a laparoscopic operation for incisional hernia and minimum 20 who went through umbilical herniotomy. The investigators monitor their pain, sensation of mesh, movement limitations, over-all well-being, fatigue and life-quality, with both CCS and VAS questionnaires 5 times. One time preoperative and 4 times after operation, on the 1sth, 7th, 30th and 90th day after operation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hernia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hernia, Inguinal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Incisional Hernia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hernia, Umbilical</mesh_term>
	<criteria>elective laparoscopic and open operations for inguinal hernia elective laparoscopic operation for incisional and umbilical hernia primary hernia unibilateral hernias and one or more incisional hernias expected bad compliance to the study acute operations reoperations secondary operations primary operation with reoperation within 30 days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>inguinal hernia</keyword>
	<keyword>incisional hernia</keyword>
	<keyword>quality of life</keyword>
	<keyword>disease-specific</keyword>
</DOC>