<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00683553</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1, randomized, double-blind, dose escalation, safety and pharmacokinetic study. The study will be conducted in approximately 10 sites in the United States. Up to 48 patients at high risk for AKI (CCF score ≥ 5 OR an estimated GFR (eGFR) &lt;60 mL/min/1.73 m2) who have undergone major cardiovascular surgery will participate. Patients will receive a single IV injection of I5NP or placebo following cardiovascular surgery. I5NP will be administered 4 hours (+/- 30 minutes) following removal of the cardiopulmonary bypass machine (CBM). The duration of the study is approximately 44 days, inclusive of a 14 day screening period. Patients will be contacted by phone at 6 and 12 months for follow-up questions. Patient visits are screening, day of surgery, hospital in-patient Days 1, 2, 3 - 5 and Day 7 or hospital discharge. Safety follow-up will continue until 30 days post-surgery. 2 phone calls will be made at 6 and 12 months after date of surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Dose Escalation and Safety Study of I5NP to Prevent Acute Kidney Injury (AKI) in Patients at High Risk of AKI Undergoing Major Cardiovascular Surgery (QRK.004)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The drug (I5NP) is a small interfering RNA that is being developed to protect patients from acute kidney injury after cardiac bypass surgery. This study will test the safety of I5NP and measure how long the drug stays in the blood stream after injection. This study is not meant to test if I5NP protects kidneys from the damage that may occur in rare cases during surgery. Another purpose of this dose escalation study is to find out the right dose of the experimental drug to be given to study subjects in future studies. Even though there were no harmful effects seen in the animals tested, we do not know what side effects the experimental drug might cause in humans.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria (before surgery): Patient age between 21 years and 85 years old Patient is capable of giving consent Patient is willing and able to comply with the visit schedule and study procedures including posthospitalization discharge followup Patient is undergoing any major cardiac or vascular surgery requiring the use of cardiopulmonary bypass machine (CBM) Patient has a cumulative score of ≥ 5 on the Cleveland Clinic Foundation (CCF) Acute Kidney Injury (AKI) risk factor scale OR the patient has an estimated GFR (eGFR) &lt;60 mL/min/1.73 m2, as determined from the simplified (4variable) MDRD (Modification of Diet in Renal Disease) equation at the time of the Screening/Baseline examination The patient reports that they are up to date and have had normal findings on their age and sexappropriate cancer screening, per American Cancer Society guidelines, for breast cancer, cervical cancer, rectal cancer, and prostate cancer. If a patient is not up to date, the relevant screening test must be performed and a normal result documented prior to dosing. Inclusion Criteria (during surgery): Patient must have been on cardiopulmonary bypass machine (CBM) Inclusion Criteria (after surgery): Patient must be in the ICU for dosing to facilitate study procedures including PK blood draws and PK urine sampling Exclusion Criteria (before surgery): Patient has had cancer or may be predisposed due to a family history of: a clinical syndrome predisposing to malignancy, such as Familial Polyposis Coli, Von Hippel Landau disease (associated with renal cell cancers and renal cysts) and LiFraumeni syndrome (associated with inherited mutations of the p53 tumorsuppressor gene) the same malignancy in two or more first or seconddegree relatives Patient has a history of any abnormality on chest Xray that could represent a malignancy Patient has a clinically significantly elevated pancreatic and/or hepatic enzyme level, defined as any grade 2, 3 or 4 value according to the National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE), version 3.0 Women of childbearing potential are to be excluded from this study. Every female subject is considered of childbearing potential unless she has had sterilization surgery, or is postmenopausal. Women 2159, postmenopausal is defined as no menses for at least 12 months and an elevated follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) level. Women 6085, postmenopausal is defined as no menses in at least 12 months. Patient has participated in a study of an experimental therapy in the last 30 days Patient is currently receiving immunosuppressive therapy [this criterion does NOT apply to topical steroids and inhalation steroids for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and/or asthma] Preoperative extracorporeal membrane oxygenation Patient has IntraArterial Balloon Pump (IABP) or other Left Ventricular Assist Device (LVAD) Evidence that patient is experiencing possible AKI prior to surgery, defined as a &gt; 1.5 times increase in serum creatinine from screening to any time prior to surgery Patient has comfort measures only or do not resuscitate (DNR) status Patient is participating in a concurrent interventional study Patient has received intravenous contrast material &lt; 24 hours prior to surgery In the opinion of the investigator a preoperative concomitant disease or clinical/laboratory finding that significantly raises the risk of complications in the postoperative period and therefore precludes dosing of the patient Exclusion Criteria (during surgery): In the opinion of the investigator, an intraoperative complication has occurred that significantly raises the risk of complications in the post operative period and therefore precludes dosing of the patient Exclusion Criteria (after surgery): In the opinion of the investigator, a complication has occurred in the postoperative period at any time prior to dosing that significantly raises the risk of further complications and therefore precludes dosing of the patient</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute Renal Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute Kidney Injury</keyword>
</DOC>