<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00819286</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to evaluate sternal osteosynthesis, chest wall pain and return to normal activity in open heart surgery patients who had their breast bone closed either with wires or plates.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Primary Plating in Sternotomy Patients for Osteosynthesis and Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Median sternotomy patients will be randomized to either wire or rigid fixation groups. A scheduled evaluation period will record clinical parameters. Enrollment has ended with one hundred forty (140) patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wound Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mediastinitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients undergoing median sternotomy; Patients eighteen (18) years of age or older; Patients presenting two or more risk factors such as diabetes mellitus, Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease, obesity (BMI &gt; 30), osteoporosis, Renal failure, Chronic steroid use, Immunosuppression, Redo sternotomy, Neurologic dysfunction severely affecting ambulation, Off midline sternotomy bilateral IMA use Long cardiopulmonary bypass runs Transverse fractures of the sternum Patients with a nonstandard sternotomy; Patients with an offmidline sternotomy that reduced the bony margin to &lt;2mm Patients under eighteen (18) years of age; Patients that are pregnant or currently lactating; Patients presenting intraoperative conditions that would require the use of rigid fixation and/or additional poststernotomy mechanical support beyond wire cerclage due to surgical evaluation, Patients defined within the New York Heart Association (NYHA) or Canadian Cardiovascular Society (CCS) functional Class IV for congestive heart failure, Patients presenting emergent/salvage cardiac acuity as defined per the Society of Thoracic Surgeons (STS) guidelines: i.e., patients undergoing cardiopulmonary resuscitation en route to the operating room or prior to induction of anesthesia; Patients undergoing postoperative revision procedures that treat the original sternotomy in such a way as to affect outcome (antibiotic irrigation, debridement or other treatment to the osteotomy); Patients unwilling or unable to return for followup; Lacking the ability to follow instructions; Intraoperative death.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>open heart surgery</keyword>
</DOC>