<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00819117</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate that epicardial and transvenous left ventricular leads are safe and effective for cardiac resynchronization therapy in heart failure patients implanted with a CRT device.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Investigation of Transvenous Versus Epicardial Left Ventricular Stimulation Technique</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This clinical trial is a multicenter, prospective, randomized, parallel, open study designed to compare epicardial left ventricular pacing to transvenous left ventricular pacing for delivering cardiac resynchronization therapy. After a pre-implant baseline evaluation, patients will be randomized in a 1:1 fashion to one of two groups: - Control group: resynchronization via a transvenous left ventricular lead (TVN CRT); - Treatment group: resynchronization via an epicardial left ventricular lead (EPI CRT). All patients taking part in this study will undergo the implantation of a CRT device with or without ICD back-up (depending on the physician's decision), with right atrial and right ventricular transvenous leads. Patients will attend protocol scheduled visits before implant (pre-implant baseline evaluation), and post-implant: before hospital discharge, 6 weeks post-implant (optional visit), 3 months (optional visit), and 6 months after implant, time of study termination.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have an approved indication for implantation of an CRT device (ESC guidelines , including any update); Have a stable pharmacological therapy. Have a contraindication to general anesthesia; Have a scheduled cardiac surgery; Have had a recent myocardial infarction, unstable angina or cardiac revascularization (PTCA or CABG) within 1 month of enrollment; Have a life expectancy of less than 6 months; Are unable to provide informed consent; Are unable to comply with the followup schedule and tests; Are minor (age below 18 years); Are pregnant or are planning for pregnancy in the next 6 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Epicardial leads</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac Resynchronization Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>