<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00130494</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label, randomized, multicenter phase III trial to assess the efficacy of early administration of zoledronate versus observation in delaying bone-related symptoms in metastatic breast cancer patients. Patients will be randomised to receive 4 mg zoledronate every 3-4 weeks versus observation until bone-related symptoms appear, or up to 12 months. One hundred twelve patients per treatment arm will be enrolled in the study. Once bone-related symptoms appear, study participation is over. During the study, the following will be assessed: - quality of life, - performance status, - pain rating, - analgesic administration and - adverse events The principal objective is the delay in bone-related symptoms in those patients with early zoledronate administration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Zoledronic Acid Administration to Metastatic Breast Cancer Patients With Non-Symptomatic Bone Lesions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zoledronic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diphosphonates</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent. Age &gt;= 18 years old. Metastatic breast cancer patients with lytic, sclerotic or mixed bone lesions. Nonsymptomatic bone lesions, defined as pain absence, lack of bone complications (fracture, hypercalcemia, central nervous system [CNS] compression), no need of analgesic chronic administration for bone disease. A maximum of two chemotherapy lines for metastatic disease. A maximum of two hormone therapy lines for metastatic disease. Normal, minimally altered renal function (serum creatinine &lt; 1.5 x upper normal limit [UNL]). Normal serum calcium levels. Performance status 0,1 (World Health Organization [WHO]). Negative pregnancy test before study recruitment. Previous treatment with bisphosphonates or raloxifene in the 30 days prior to randomization. Metastasis in CNS. History of hypersensitivity to bisphosphonates. Pregnant or lactating women. Third chemotherapy line for metastatic disease. Third hormone therapy line for metastatic disease. Males.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-symptomatic bone metastases.</keyword>
</DOC>