<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02784119</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The success of orthotopic liver transplantation (OLT) in treatment of liver malignancy and endstage liver disease has led to an increase in the gap between patients on waiting-lists and available liver grafts. In order to compensate for this scarcity, use of liver grafts harvested from extended criteria donors (ECD) has become more and more frequent. However, these ECD grafts are known to be associated with a higher rate of primary non function (PNF) or early allograft dysfunction (EAD) because of a greater vulnerability to ischemia-reperfusion injury (IRI). During OLT, the clamping of the portal vein induces blood congestion in the splanchnic territory leading to increased gut permeability, bacterial translocation and release of endotoxin and pro-inflammatory cytokines at revascularisation, which exacerbate IRI. Realisation of a temporary porto-caval shunt (TPCS) (i.e. end to side anastomosis between the portal vein and infrahepatic vena cava) during the anhepatic phase, avoids splanchnic congestion and could therefore decrease IRI and improve liver graft function. However, TPCS remains poorly used as no randomised trial succeeds to show its benefit on liver function due to lack of power.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>APCext : Effect of Temporary Porto-caval Shunt During Liver Transplantation on Function of Liver Graft From Extended Criteria Donor</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years old Candidate of liver transplantation With cirrhosis from any etiology Model For EndStage Liver Disease (MELD) score &lt; 25 Transplanted with a liver graft harvested from an extended criteria donor defined as presence of at least one of the following criteria: Donor age &gt; 65 years old Intensive care unit stay &gt; 7 days BMI &gt; 30 Natremia &gt; 155 mmol/L Aspartate aminotransferase (ASAT) &gt; 150 IU/mL Alanine aminotransferase (ALAT) &gt; 170 IU/mL Occurrence of a cardiac arrest before graft harvesting Proven biopsy macrosteathosis &gt; 30% Nonopposition from the patient Non Fulminant hepatitis Retransplantation Combined organ transplantation (kidney, pancreas, heart, lung) Non heart beating donor Complete portal vein thrombosis on preoperative imaging finding Complete portal vein thrombosis found during procedure Split liver graft Realisation of a bilioenteric anastomosis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>temporary porto-caval shunt</keyword>
	<keyword>liver graft</keyword>
	<keyword>extended criteria donor</keyword>
</DOC>