<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="23975">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02794649</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RKSC6416</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02794649</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Descriptive Analysis of Gut Microbiome Alterations in Hyperoxaluric Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Descriptive Analysis of Gut Microbiome Alterations in Hyperoxaluric Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA New York Harbor Healthcare System</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Mayo Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>New York University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA New York Harbor Healthcare System</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To characterize the microbiome in 4 groups of subjects (primary hyperoxaluria type I (PH1),
      idiopathic CaOx stone, enteric hyperoxaluria (EH) and healthy participants) by comparing the
      number of species and diversity of the microbial populations and pathway for oxalate
      metabolism by paralleling the gene expression of enzymes involved in oxalate degradation by
      gut bacteria.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Kidney stones are a disease of worldwide prevalence with significant public health
      implications. About 60-80% of stones are composed of calcium oxalate (CaOx) for which high
      urinary oxalate, hyperoxaluria, is a major risk factor. Calcium and oxalate are components
      of the urine that can bind to each other, and form calcium oxalate kidney stones. Currently,
      the treatments and preventive measures of kidney stones are limited. Therefore, with this
      study, the investigators aim to learn about differences in the bacteria that live in the gut
      of people with diseases that lead to hyperoxaluria.

      Hypothesis: The diversity and number of bacterial populations are different between
      individuals with conditions that predispose them to CaOx kidney stones formation and healthy
      individuals. The expression of genes involved in oxalate metabolism will be different in
      individuals predisposed with these conditions. At the strain level, the investigators expect
      a difference in the characteristics of the bacteria Oxalobacter formigenes (OxF) between
      healthy participants and patients with primary hyperoxaluria.

      Study design: The investigators will collect 2 different stool samples within one week. The
      investigators will include participants in their study who are at risk of forming kidney
      stones. The investigators will include 1) healthy (non stone forming) participants, 2)
      patients with a history of calcium oxalate kidney stones, 3) patients with genetic diseases
      that predispose them to form calcium oxalate kidney stones and, 4) patients with fat
      malabsorption due to a bariatric surgical procedure (Roux-en Y gastric bypass; RYGB) that
      causes enteric hyperoxaluria and calcium oxalate kidney stones. The investigators will
      review the charts of the recruited patients with primary, enteric hyperoxaluria and
      idiopathic CaOx stones to collect their clinically obtained 24 hours urine parameters. The
      investigators will collect data for up to 3 years prior to enrollment on kidney function
      (Cr, GFR), kidney stone history, kidney stone removal procedures, kidney imaging,
      medications, serum electrolytes, 24 hour urine parameters and antibiotic use.

      The investigators plan to include 15 participants in each group for a total of 60
      participants in the study.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in composition of the fecal microbiome as measured by 16S ribosomal ribonucleic acid (rRNA) sequencing and whole genome shotgun sequencing between the study groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Diversity and abundance of operational taxonomic units (OTUs) between different groups of subjects will be tested. Data from shotgun sequencing and degenerate quantitative polymerase chain reactions (qPCRs) will yield comparative expressions of the oxalate metabolism genes between the groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Oxalate, Primary Hyperoxaluria, Microbiome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>healthy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals without a history of kidney or bowel disease</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>primary hyperoxaluria</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients diagnosed with type I PH by genetic testing</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>enteric hyperoxaluria</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with Roux-en-Y-gastric-bypass.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>calcium oxalate stone formers</arm_group_label>
    <description>History of passing or having surgically removed a calcium oxalate kidney stone within 5 years of recruitment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      fecal samples
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Individuals diagnosed with either Primary hyperoxaluria, Enteric hyperoxaluria, or
        Idiopathic CaOx stone.

        Healthy participants with no history of kidney or bowel disease will also be included.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Primary hyperoxaluria: Patients diagnosed with type I PH by genetic testing and part
             of the Rare Kidney Stone Consortium (RKSC) Primary hyperoxaluria registry

          -  Enteric hyperoxaluria: Patients with Roux-en-Y-gastric-bypass

          -  Idiopathic CaOx stone : History of passing or having surgically removed a calcium
             oxalate kidney stone within 5 years of recruitment

          -  Healthy participants with no history of kidney or bowel disease

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  History of kidney or liver transplant

          -  History of antibiotics use within 6 months of recruitment
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lama Nazzal, MD</last_name>
    <phone>212-686-7500</phone>
    <phone_ext>3877</phone_ext>
    <email>lama.nazzal@nyumc.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Arielle Radin, BA</last_name>
    <phone>646-501-4159</phone>
    <email>arielle.radin@nyumc.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>June 4, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 25, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>VA New York Harbor Healthcare System</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lama Nazzal</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD, MSc</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hyperoxaluria, Primary</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
