<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01427283</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective is to assess the efficacy of oxycodone/naloxone controlled-release tablets (OXN) for the management of opioid-induced constipation (OIC) compared with oxycodone controlled-release tablets (OXY) in subjects with moderate to severe low back pain and opioid-induced constipation who require around-the-clock opioid therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Oxycodone/Naloxone Controlled-release Tablets (OXN) to Assess Analgesic Efficacy and Management of Opioid-induced Constipation (OIC) in Opioid-experienced Subjects With Moderate to Severe Chronic Low Back Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Constipation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Analgesics, Opioid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxycodone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Naloxone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Analgesics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria include: Male and female subjects ≥ 18 years of age with moderate to severe, chronic low back pain (lasting at least several hours daily) as their predominant pain condition for at least 3 months prior to screening period; The low back pain must be related to nonmalignant and nonneuropathic conditions and may be with or without radiation; Subjects must have a selfreported history of opioid induced constipation (OIC). Exclusion Criteria include: Subjects with rheumatoid arthritis or other inflammatory arthritis; Subjects with neuropathic conditions that have been painful or required therapy within the past 3 months; Subjects with evidence of significant structural abnormalities of the gastrointestinal (GI) tract or other significant conditions affecting GI motility; Subjects with chronic constipation not related to opioid use; Subjects who had surgical procedures directed towards the source of chronic low back pain within 6 months of the screening visit or planned during the study; Subjects with a history of malignancy within past 2 years, with exception of basal cell carcinoma that has been successfully treated. Other protocol specific inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Low back pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Opioid</keyword>
	<keyword>Constipation</keyword>
	<keyword>Moderate to severe</keyword>
</DOC>