<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00095381</DOC>
	<brief_summary>BCX-1777 may stop the growth of cancer cells by blocking the enzymes necessary for their growth. The Phase II trial is designed to study the effectiveness of BCX-1777 in treating patients who have recurrent or refractory advanced T-cell leukemia. Patients will receive an infusion of BCX-1777 on days 1-5. Treatment may be repeated every week for up to six courses. Patients are not required to be hospitalized for the administration of BCX-1777. Some patients may continue to receive an infusion of BCX-1777 twice a week for 6 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Repeat-Dose of Forodesine Hydrochloride (BCX-1777) Infusion in Patients With Advanced T-Cell Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>BCX-1777 may stop the growth of cancer cells by blocking the enzymes necessary for their growth. The Phase II trial is designed to study the effectiveness of BCX-1777 in treating patients who have recurrent or refractory advanced T-cell leukemia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, T-Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Documented Tcell leukemia (precursor Tlymphoblastic leukemia/lymphomia or TPLL) Failure to have responded to one or more standard regimens for their disease. Performance status of &lt;=2 by Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) criteria All ages are eligible Life expectancy of at least 3 months Adequate liver function (aspartate transaminase [AST] and/or alanine transaminase [ALT] not &gt;3 times upper limits or normal [ULN]) Adequate kidney function (calculated creatinine clearance &gt;50 mL/min) Negative urine pregnancy test within 2 to 7 days prior to the start of study treamtment in females of childbearing potential Females of childbearing potential and males must be willing and able to use an adequate method of contraception to avoid pregnancy for the duration of the study Signed informed consent/assent form (ICF) prior to start of any study specific procedures Patients with known HIV infection or human Tcell leukemia virus type (HTLV1) Patients with known Hepatitis B and/or Hepatitis C active infection Patients with active CMV infection Tumorrelated central nervous system (CNS) leukemia requiring active treatment Active serious infection not controlled by oral or IV antibiotics Treatment with any investigational antileukemic agent or chemotherapy agent within 7 days prior to study entry, unless full recovery from side effects has occurred. Rapidly progressive disease with compromised organ function judged to be lifethreatening by the investigator Concurrent treatment with other anticancer agents (corticosteroid use will not be excluded, but patient must remain on the stable dose) Cutaneous Tcell lymphoma (CTCL) diagnosis (including Sezary Syndrome) Pregnant and/or lactating women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, T-Cell</keyword>
	<keyword>Entry Term Lymphocytic Leukemia, T-Cell</keyword>
	<keyword>T-Cell Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>T-Lymphocytic Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, T Cell</keyword>
	<keyword>T Lymphocytic Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>BCX-1777</keyword>
	<keyword>forodesine hydrochloride</keyword>
	<keyword>BioCryst</keyword>
</DOC>