<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00095901</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as capecitabine, work in different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of capecitabine in treating patients who have locally recurrent or metastatic nasopharyngeal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Capecitabine in Treating Patients With Locally Recurrent or Metastatic Nasopharygeal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the overall response rate (complete response and partial response) in patients with previously treated recurrent locoregional or metastatic carcinoma of the nasopharynx treated with capecitabine. Secondary - Determine median progression-free survival of patients treated with this drug. - Determine median overall survival of patients treated with this drug. - Correlate tissue thymidine phosphorylase (TP) levels with response to this drug in these patients. - Correlate the Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) status of these patients with response to this drug. - Correlate survival with the EBV status of patients treated with this drug. - Correlate TP levels with EBV status of patients treated with this drug. OUTLINE: This is a nonrandomized, multicenter study. Patients receive oral capecitabine twice daily on days 1-14. Treatment repeats every 21 days. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 39 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed carcinoma of the nasopharynx WHO type I, II, or III Recurrent locoregional or metastatic disease The following primary tumor sites or types are excluded: Nasal cavity Paranasal sinus Sinonasal neuroendocrine carcinoma Primary malignancy of the salivary gland Received at least 1, but no more than 2, prior chemotherapy regimens for recurrent locoregional or metastatic disease Patients who are intolerant of OR have a condition that precludes platinumbased chemotherapy are eligible Available tumor tissue Measurable disease At least 1 lesion that has not been irradiated within the past 6 months More than 10 mm by spiral CT scan (20 mm by conventional techniques) Pleural effusion or bone metastases are not considered measurable disease No CNS metastases unless stable for &gt; 3 months PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 18 and over Performance status ECOG 01 Life expectancy More than 3 months Hematopoietic Neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Hepatic Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) AST and ALT ≤ 2.5 times ULN (5 times ULN if due to liver metastases) Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2.5 times ULN (5 times ULN if due to liver metastases; 10 times ULN if due to bone metastases) Renal Creatinine clearance ≥ 30 mL/min OR Creatinine ≤ 1.5 times ULN Cardiovascular No congestive heart failure No symptomatic coronary artery disease No cardiac arrhythmias not well controlled by medication No myocardial infarction within the past year No other clinically significant cardiac disease Neurologic No history of uncontrolled seizures No clinically significant CNS disorder or psychiatric disability that would preclude giving informed consent or complying with study treatment Immunologic No prior unanticipated severe reaction to fluoropyrimidines No extreme sensitivity to fluorouracil No serious, uncontrolled infection Other No other malignancy within the past 5 years except nonmelanoma skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix No malabsorption syndrome of the upper gastrointestinal tract No other serious uncontrolled medical condition that would preclude study participation Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy Not specified Chemotherapy See Disease Characteristics More than 6 months since prior fluoropyrimidines, including fluorouracil More than 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy and recovered Endocrine therapy Not specified Radiotherapy See Disease Characteristics More than 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy Surgery More than 4 weeks since prior major surgery and recovered Other More than 4 weeks since prior investigational drugs</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2005</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
</DOC>