<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02382939</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted in Europe and Asia. The aim of the trial is to compare the safety of once weekly dosing of somapacitan (administered with an investigational pen) with daily Norditropin速 FlexPro速 (somatropin delivered within a prefilled pen) for 26 weeks in previously human growth hormone (hGH) treated adults with growth hormone deficiency.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Trial to Compare the Safety of Once Weekly Dosing of Somapacitan With Daily Norditropin速 FlexPro速 for 26 Weeks in Previously Human Growth Hormone Treated Adults With Growth Hormone Deficiency</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Endocrine System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dwarfism, Pituitary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female of at least 18 years of age and not more than 79 years of age at the time of signing informed consent Adult growth hormone deficiency diagnosed for 6 months or longer (defined as 180 days) prior to screening Treatment with hGH (human growth hormone) for at least 6 months at screening If applicable, hormone replacement therapies for any other hormone deficiencies, adequate and stable for at least 90 days prior to randomisation as judged by the investigator Active malignant disease or history of malignancy. Exceptions to this exclusion criterion: Resected in situ carcinoma of the cervix and squamous cell or basal cell carcinoma of the skin with complete local excision. / Subjects with GHD (growth hormone deficiency) attributed to treatment of intracranial malignant tumours or leukaemia, provided that a recurrencefree survival period of at least 5 years is documented in the subject's file For patients with surgical removal or debulking of pituitary adenoma or other benign intracranial tumour within the last 5 years: Evidence of growth of pituitary adenoma or other benign intracranial tumour within the last 12 months (defined as below or equal to 365 days) before randomisation. Absence of growth must be documented by two postsurgery MRI or CT scans. The most recent MRI or CT scan must be performed below or equal to 9 months (defined as below or equal to 270 days) prior to randomisation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>