<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00205153</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This Team Education and Adherence Monitoring (TEAM) trial will evaluate the cost-effectiveness of a pharmacy-based intervention in a randomized controlled trial involving 597 treated hypertensive African American patients in five Wisconsin cities. The study involves 28 community pharmacies (14 intervention, 14 control) owned by two pharmacy corporations. Intervention pharmacists and pharmacy technicians implemented a 6-month blood pressure (BP) monitoring program that involved working together as a team with patients and their physicians to achieve improved medication adherence, healthy lifestyles, drug therapy, and hypertension control.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Team Model of Hypertension Care in African Americans</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Researchers screened and enrolled 20-25 subjects in each study pharmacy. Intervention pharmacists and technicians attended a 7-hour TEAM training program on BP monitoring, JNC 7 guidelines, and specially designed tools for assessing and improving medication adherence, lifestyle, patient scheduling and retention, and collaboration with physicians. Intervention teams received specially designed tools, automatic BP monitors, and furniture for setting up and implementing a blood pressure clinic at their pharmacy. Staff from control pharmacies received printed information only and provided "usual care". Outcomes will be determined by blinded data collectors who will re-check patients' BPs and administer follow-up surveys after 6 and 12 months. Researchers also will survey pharmacy staff and review pharmacy records to determine changes in refill adherence and prescribing.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<criteria>is African American and 18 years old or older; has active prescription for BP drug; obtains all BP drugs at the study pharmacy; is able to read and fill out short questionnaires; is able to come to pharmacy for 6 monthly pharmacy visits if needed; has screening BP between 140/90 mm Hg and 210/115 mm Hg. history of organ transplant or kidney dialysis, symptoms of advanced congestive heart failure, memory impairment that interferes with daily functioning,terminal illness,pregnancy, alcohol or substance abuse problem,physician recommendation of exclusion for other condition that may require special care or limit participation in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>hypertension in African Americans</keyword>
</DOC>