<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01605136</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized placebo-controlled study to be conducted in two parallel study arms for a six month period (three doses). Between 75 and 100 eligible patients will be enrolled. Patients will receive afamelanotide (16 mg implants) or placebo according to the following dosing regimen: - Group A will be administered afamelanotide implants on Days 0, 60 and 120 - Group B will be administered placebo implants on Days 0, 60 and 120 The number and severity of phototoxic reactions, the type and duration of sun exposure, treatment-emergent adverse events and the use of concomitant medication will be recorded by patients in study diaries between Days 0 and 180. Quality of life will be measured using the DLQI and EPP-QoL at Days 0, 60, 120 and 180. Participants will visit the clinic on Days 60, 120 and 180 for assessments of adverse events. A subset of patients will be photoprovoked on the lower back and dorsal surface of the hand and the minimal symptom dose (MSD) will be determined on Days 0, 30, 60, 90 and 120.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase III Confirmatory Study in Erythropoietic Protoporphyria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Afamelanotide is a man-made drug being studied for use as a preventative medication for Erythropoietic Protoporphyria (EPP) sufferers. It is a synthetically produced analogue of human alpha melanocyte stimulating hormone (alpha-MSH) and is not yet available on the market. The purpose of this study is to look at whether afamelanotide can reduce the number and severity of EPP symptoms when patients are exposed to light. This study will also look at how the drug is tolerated when taken by people with EPP. The study will involve the use of an implant, which comes in the form of a small rod to be administered under the skin. The implant may contain the study drug afamelanotide or a placebo (inactive medication). Over 620 subjects have been treated with afamelanotide to date with no serious safety concerns identified. For this study, afamelanotide has been formulated as a controlled release depot injection (implant). This means that the afamelanotide will be released slowly into the body over a few days. This study aims to confirm the photoprotective properties if afamelanotide demonstrated in the earlier Phase II and phase III studies.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Protoporphyria, Erythropoietic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>alpha-MSH</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subjects with characteristic symptoms of EPP phototoxicity and a biochemicallyconfirmed diagnosis of EPP. Aged 18 years old and above (inclusive). Able to understand and sign the written Informed Consent Form. Willing to take precautions to prevent pregnancy until completion of the study (Day 180). Any allergy to afamelanotide or the polymer contained in the implant or to lidocaine or other local anesthetic to be used during the administration of the study medication EPP patients with significant hepatic involvement Personal history of melanoma or dysplastic nevus syndrome. Current Bowen's disease, basal cell carcinoma, squamous cell carcinoma, or other malignant or premalignant skin lesions. Any other photodermatosis such as polymorphic light eruption, actinic prurigo, discoid lupus erythematosus, chronic actinic dermatitis or solar urticaria. Any evidence of clinically significant organ dysfunction or any clinically significant deviation from normal in the clinical or laboratory determinations. Acute history of drug or alcohol abuse (in the last 6 months). Patient assessed as not suitable for the study in the opinion of the Investigator (e.g. noncompliance history, allergic to local anesthetics, faints when given injections or giving blood). Participation in a clinical trial for an investigational agent within 30 days prior to the screening visit. Prior and concomitant therapy with medications which may interfere with the objectives of the study, including drugs that cause photosensitivity or skin pigmentation. Female who is pregnant (confirmed by positive serum βHCG pregnancy test prior to baseline) or lactating. Females of childbearing potential (premenopausal, not surgically sterile) not using adequate contraceptive measures (i.e. oral contraceptives, diaphragm plus spermicide, intrauterine device).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Erythropoietic Protoporphyria</keyword>
	<keyword>EPP</keyword>
	<keyword>Afamelanotide</keyword>
</DOC>