<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01605253</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if eszopiclone relative to placebo (sugar pill) is effective and tolerable for people with posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD)-related sleep disturbance. The investigators will also examine the impact of treatment on sleep patterns, memory recall bias, and level of inflammatory markers (cytokines). The investigators predict eszopiclone will lead to greater improvement than placebo in measures of PTSD symptoms, memory recall bias, and level of inflammatory markers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Eszopiclone for the Treatment of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eszopiclone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female outpatients age 1865 with a primary diagnosis of PTSD and associated sleep disturbance Good physical health Willingness and ability to comply with the requirements of the study protocol Women pregnant, lactating, or of childbearing potential not using medically accepted contraception Concurrent use of other psychotropic medications at least two weeks prior to baseline Concurrent use of other antiinflammatory medications or anticytokine medications. If used on an asneeded (PRN) basis, subjects may enter the study, but will be excluded from cytokine analyses Concurrent use of betablockers less than one month prior to baseline Serious medical illness or instability for which hospitalization may be likely within the next year Seizure disorders with the exception of a history of febrile seizures if they occurred during childhood Sleep apnea or restless leg syndrome Concurrent psychotherapy initiated within 3 months of randomization or ongoing psychotherapy of any duration directed specifically toward treatment of PTSD and/or sleep disturbance Patients with significant suicidal ideation Current legal actions related to trauma or an ongoing relationship with assailant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Post-traumatic stress disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>sleep disturbance</keyword>
	<keyword>insomnia</keyword>
	<keyword>cytokines</keyword>
	<keyword>anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>traumatic event</keyword>
	<keyword>memory</keyword>
</DOC>