<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01605721</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objectives: 1. To evaluate the safety and long-term effectiveness of coronary stenting with the XIENCE PRIMETM in a cohort of "real world" patients and lesion subsets. 2. To determine clinical device and procedural success during commercial use of XIENCE PRIMETM coronary stent Study population : Approximately consecutive 2000 patients treated with XIENCE PRIMETM Study period - Patient enrollment: 2011.05 ~ 2012.04 - End of follow-up period: 2015. 02 (3 years of follow-up) Primary endpoint : Target Lesion Failure (TLF) rate at 12 months Secondary endpoint: - In-stent &amp; In-segment Late Loss at 9 months - Stent Thrombosis at 24 hours (acute), 30 days (subacute), 1 year (late), yearly up to 3 years (very late) - Target Vessel Failure at 12 months (composite of cardiac death, MI, and TVR) - Any death, cardiac death, MI, TLR, TVR at 30 days, 9months, 1 year, 3 years - Composite rate of cardiac death and any MI up to 3 years - Composite rate of all death and any MI up to 3 years - Composite rate of all death, any MI (Q-wave and non Q-wave) and any repeat revascularization up to 3 years - Compliance and therapy interruptions with prescribed adjunctive antiplatelet therapy up to 3 years - Procedural success up to 1 day - Angiographic success up to 1 day</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Xience in Coronary arEry Disease aLL-comers After stENTing Using the PRIME Platform (EXCELLENT-PRIME Registry)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria The patient agrees to participate in this study by signing the informed consent form. Alternatively, a legally authorized patient representative may agree to the patient's participation in this study and sign the informed consent form. Angiographic Inclusion Criteria There are no angiographic inclusion criteria for this study. Exclusion criteria There are no exclusion criteria for this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Everolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>XIENCE PRIME</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug eluting stent</keyword>
</DOC>