<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02950064</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase 1, Open-label, multicenter Dose Escalation study of BTP-114, a novel platinum product, in patients with advanced solid tumors and BRCA or other DNA repair mutation. This clinical study is comprised of 2 sequential parts: Part 1 (Dose Escalation) and Part 2 (Expansion). The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, pharmacokinetics and the anti-cancer activity of BTP-114.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Determine the Safety of BTP-114 for Treatment in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors With BRCA Mutations</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION: All Patients 1. Male or female aged ≥18 years. 2. ECOG PS score of 01. 3. Adequate organ function. 4. Ability to understand and willingness to sign informed consent form prior to initiation of study procedures. 5. Measurable disease per RECIST, OR for patients with a primary diagnosis of castration resistant prostate cancer, progressive disease (PD) by prostate surface antigen (PSA) or imaging in the setting of medical or surgical castration. 6. Documented BRCA mutation, with the following exceptions: a) Patient is intended to be enrolled in a Singlepatient Cohort; b) Patient has an advanced DNA repair mutationpositive solid tumor and is intended to be enrolled in Expansion Cohort 5. Patients in the Doseescalation Phase: 7. Locally advanced solid tumor other than a primary central nervous system (CNS) tumor for which the patient has received ≤3 prior lines 8. Confirmed solid tumor in one of the following categories: BRCA mutationpositive pancreatic cancer for which the patient received up to 1 prior line of cytotoxic chemotherapy in the advanced disease setting. Advanced BRCA mutationpositive castrationresistant prostate cancer (CRPC) for which the patient received up to 2 prior lines of cytotoxic chemotherapy in the advanced disease setting. Advanced BRCA mutationpositive ovarian cancer for which the patient received up to 3 prior lines of cytotoxic chemotherapy in the advanced disease setting. Advanced BRCA mutationpositive triplenegative breast cancer (TNBC) for which the patient received up to 3 prior lines of cytotoxic chemotherapy in the advanced disease setting. Advanced DNA repair mutationpositive solid tumors, including, but not limited to BRCA and nonBRCA DNA mutations, who have received up to 3 prior lines of cytotoxic chemotherapy in the advanced disease setting. DNArepair mutations may include, but are not limited to ATM, CHEK2, PALB2, and RAD51D. Abnormal homologous repair deficiency (HRD) tests will also be allowed. Note that in both dose escalation and dose expansion portions of the study, prior targeted therapy including prior poly ADP ribose polymerase (PARP) inhibitor therapy, prior immunotherapy, or prior hormonal therapy is permissible. Patients with castration resistant prostate cancer may have received unlimited prior hormonal therapies. EXCLUSION: 1. History of leptomeningeal disease or spinal cord compression. 2. Underwent major surgery within 4 weeks before first treatment. 3. Received cancerdirected therapy 14 days (6 weeks for mitomycin C and nitrosoureas) before start of treatment. 4. Grade 2 or greater peripheral neuropathy at start of treatment. 5. If female, pregnant or breastfeeding. 6. Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection or hepatitis B or C infection 7. Any primary brain tumor (e.g., astrocytoma, glioblastoma). 8. Hypersensitivity or history of anaphylactic reaction to any platinumcontaining agents.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>BRCA</keyword>
	<keyword>BRCA1</keyword>
	<keyword>BRCA2</keyword>
	<keyword>Pancreatic cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Ovarian cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Castrate resistant prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Triple negative breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>DNA repair mutation-positive solid tumors</keyword>
</DOC>