<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02950454</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a pilot trial to explore the cardiovascular of eight weeks of twice weekly high intensity interval training in people with progressive multiple sclerosis. A control group of people with progressive multiple sclerosis will undergo continuous moderate intensity exercise, twice weekly for 8 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of High Intensity Interval Training on Cardiovascular Fitness in People With Progressive Multiple Sclerosis.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a pilot trial to explore the cardiovascular of eight weeks of twice weekly high intensity interval training in people with progressive multiple sclerosis. A control group of people with progressive multiple sclerosis will undergo continuous moderate intensity exercise, twice weekly for 8 weeks. The training program will entail 6x1.5 minute intervals working at 80-95% heart rate max on a cycle ergometer. Each interval will be interspersed with 1.5 minutes of working rest at a light resistance of the participant's choosing. The continuous moderate intensity exercise program will entail 20 minutes on a cycle ergometer working at 60-70% heart rate max.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosed with a progressive form of MS Aged 18 years or older Known to members of staff of the MS service NHS Ayrshire &amp; Arran Ability to attend Douglas Grant Rehabilitation centre twice a week for eight weeks EDSS 46.0 Able to cycle on ergometer A relapse of symptoms requiring treatment within the past three months. A respiratory condition that would be exacerbated by high intensity exercise including but not limited to: chronic obstructive pulmonary disorder, uncontrolled or poorly controlled asthma. Uncontrolled high pressure at screening (&gt;190/100 mmHg) Cognitive impairment affecting ability to understand instructions as noted in patient's notes. Currently engaging in another research trial for their MS or that may affect their physiological or cardiovascular outcomes Weighing more than 110 kg (weight limit of ergometer) Any pathology or medical intervention that would preclude high intensity exercise, maximal exertion testing or could attenuate the cardiovascular effect of exercise including but not limited to: unstable angina; diabetes; peripheral vascular disease or intermittent claudication; having a pace maker or medicine pump; surgical clips; having another neurological condition other than MS; and pregnancy. To be established from patient's notes and at screening session. A serious cardiovascular event in the past year including but not limited to: transient ischaemic attack, cerebrovascular event and myocardial infarction. Taking any of the following medication: beta blockers; vasodilators; ACE inhibitors; diuretics or any other medication that could cause exercise induced hypotension; hypoglycaemic insulin; metformin or other oral insulin medicine.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Progressive Multiple Sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
</DOC>