<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02950103</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Synthetic phosphoethanolamine is a primary amine which has a critical role in the biosynthesis of cell membranes. Pre-clinical models have shown potential anticancer activity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Synthetic Phosphoethanolamine in Solid Tumor Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Phase II multi-cohort study based on two-stage Simon design. The primary goal of the study is response rate at 8 weeks in participants with advanced solid tumors treated with synthetic phosphoethanolamine, as defined by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors version 1.1 (RECIST v 1.1) or specific criteria for prostate cancer.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Histologically proven advanced solid tumor patients (recurrent or metastatic), not amenable to curative therapy. Patients must have progressed to standard treatment proven to prolong survival or no standard treatment exists. Tumor types include head and neck squamous cell carcinoma, nonsmall cell lung cancer, colorectal adenocarcinoma, breast cancer, cervix cancer, prostate cancer, melanoma, pancreas adenocarcinoma, gastric adenocarcinoma, hepatocellular carcinoma No concurrent active systemic treatment Measurable disease by RECIST v1.1 Clinical or radiological progression in the last three months Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status 01 Ability to consent Adequate organ function Life expectancy greater than 12 weeks Ability to swallow No previous malignancy in the last 5 years Pregnancy Corticosteroid therapy for prostate cancer Uncontrolled comorbidity Known hepatitis B, C and HIV Central nervous system involvement, except if controlled symptoms and without corticosteroids Previous use of phosphoethalonamine</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>solid tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>phase II</keyword>
	<keyword>phosphoethanolamine</keyword>
</DOC>