<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01815996</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators are developing a test that is expected to measure the amount of radiation a patient has been exposed to after a nuclear bomb. The investigator will do this by measuring the DNA in the patients blood from cells killed by the radiation. Many diseases and medical conditions can put DNA in the blood. The investigator needs to know how much DNA in order to better interpret our radiation detection test. Therefore, the investigator is collecting blood from several patients with different diseases or medical conditions and also healthy volunteers to measure their DNA content. Patients that will be included in this study are pregnant women, patients who have suffered a pulmonary embolism within the past 48 hours, patients who have suffered from myocardial infarction in the past 48 hours, patients with autoimmune diseases and health patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Identify Clinical Conditions That Increase Circulating DNA Levels</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigator will collect 8 mL (one and one half teaspoons) of blood one time only. The investigator may also collect the patient's past medical history, test results and disease treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Embolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Embolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autoimmune Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients must be adults in one of the following categories: Pregnant Suffered a pulmonary embolism within the past 48 hours Myocardial infarction in the past 48 hours Diagnosed with an autoimmune disease Adults age 1880 Selfdeclared healthy adults 2. Patients must be willing to undergo a blood draw 3. Patients must provide studyspecific informed consent prior to study entry 1. Patients not meeting the above inclusion criteria</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>pulmonary embolism</keyword>
	<keyword>myocardial infarction</keyword>
	<keyword>autoimmune disease</keyword>
	<keyword>healthy controls</keyword>
</DOC>