<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02861820</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study purpose is to examine whether there are structural or functional differences in the brains of individuals who use cocaine or amphetamines as opposed to control participants who have never used cocaine or amphetamines. More specifically, it will allow the investigator to see how the brain changes once people get sober and how those changes relate to successful recovery. This study will allow the investigator to examine the interaction between cocaine/amphetamines and impulsivity (meaning to act on impulse rather than thought). Results from this study will inform new biologically-based interventions to compliment existing treatment programs, in the hope of leading the field in a new direction.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Functional Connectivity Changes During Early Recovery as a Marker for Relapse</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 18 but no more than 45 years old at the time of consent. Able to provide written consent and comply with study procedures. Must meet the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSMV) diagnostic criteria for stimulant use disorder. Substance Use Disorder Participants may have current comorbid alcohol use, but their primary substance use disorder diagnosis needs to be based on stimulant use. Substance Use Participants must have five (5) weeks of abstinence (+/ 2 weeks). Substance Use Participants must have the intention to remain in their treatment program. Any medical condition or treatment with neurological sequelae (i.e. stroke, tumor, loss of consciousness for more than 30 minutes, seizures, HIV). Any contraindications to MRI scanning (i.e. metal implants, pacemakers, etc.). Intellectual developmental disorder as defined in the DSMV. Participant may have a diagnosis of an Axis I disorder (i.e. anxiety disorders, mood disorders, eating disorders, psychotic disorders), but it must be considered stable. Actively suicidal. Positive screen for alcohol and/or drugs. Participants who screen positive for drugs and/or alcohol may return at a later date to screen for the study again. Evidence for WernickeKorsakoff syndrome. Substance Use Disorder participants may not have a primary current substance use disorder diagnosis on any substance other than a stimulant, except for caffeine or nicotine. Healthy Controls may never have had any form of substance use disorder other than caffeine or nicotine. Nicotine use will be recorded but will not be an exclusion criterion.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>fMRI</keyword>
	<keyword>brain networks</keyword>
	<keyword>biomarker</keyword>
	<keyword>relapse</keyword>
	<keyword>stimulants</keyword>
</DOC>