<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02861118</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the impact of the co-morbidities profile on treatment response in inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Retrospective Observational Study to Assess the Impact of Co-morbidities on Treatment Response in Inflammatory Bowel Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a retrospective, non-interventional, observational study that will include consecutive participants diagnosed with Ulcerative Colitis (UC) or Crohn's Disease (CD) who started treatment with biologics between June 2011 and June 2013. This study will look at the impact of the co-morbidities on treatment response in IBD patients. The study will enroll approximately 400 patients: 200 UC patients and 200 CD patients. This multicenter trial will be conducted in Spain. Investigator will collect retrospective data in a single visit from participants who started biologic treatment between June 2011 and June 2013. Time since participants started biological treatment until study visit or until lack of treatment response or until treatment change will constitute the reference period for the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Intestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult participants (aged ≥18). Were diagnosed with UC or CD according to the "World Gastroenterology Organization Practice Guidelines for the Diagnosis and Management of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) in 2010". Who are naive to biologics that started treatment with biologics between June 2011 and June 2013. Participants in whom biological treatment was prescribed according to clinical practice. Who gave written informed consent. Were participating in a clinical trial during the study reference period. Participant that, according to investigator's criteria is not capable to understand and fill in the study questionnaires or to give written informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>