<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02861755</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Major depressive disorder affects over 120 million people worldwide. Only 50% of Americans with depression receive adequate treatment, and one-third of those receiving treatment do not benefit. In this pilot project investigators will bring together two approaches that have the promise to reach large numbers of depression sufferers: a skills-based intervention for increasing positive affect and experiences in depressed individuals, delivered in an inexpensive self-paced mobile format. The study will make use of smartphone technology to improve conventional outcome measurement via in-the-moment emotion sampling and mobile assessment of heart rate variability, a predictor of cardiac health that may mediate some of the health effects of depression. The aims are: 1) Retool the existing web-based positive emotion intervention for use on smartphones, with innovative exercises that help participants bring the skills they are learning into real-life situations; 2) Perform a small feasibility trial of the mobile intervention on individuals with clinical depression recruited online 3) Eventually incorporate feedback from the small feasibility trial to improve the online intervention and conduct a full randomized trial on a larger scale</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Online Positive Emotion Skills Intervention for Symptoms of Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress, Psychological</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Daily internet access Cell phone ownership Score of 5 or higher on PHQ8 scale Lives in US or Canada Speaks and reads English, able to provide informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Depressive Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychological Stress</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavioral Symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>Mental Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Mood Disorders</keyword>
</DOC>