<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02861612</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study seeks to evaluate the efficacy of nerve transfers in restoring hand function in patients with cervical spinal injuries.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nerve Transfers to Restore Hand Function in Spinal Cord Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cervical spinal cord injury is a life‐altering injury that results in profound loss of upper limb function. Hand function is essential to basic activities of daily living and consequently has a significant impact on patients' quality of life. Tendon transfers and/or tenodesis have traditionally been used to restore hand function in spinal cord injuries - however, in recent years there is growing interest in the role of nerve transfers as a means of accomplishing this goal. Although preliminary results indicate nerve transfers may be well‐suited for patients with spinal cord injury, their long term efficacy has not been demonstrated. This study seeks to evaluate the efficacy of nerve transfers in restoring hand function in patients with cervical spinal injuries. Eligible patients will receive nerve transfer procedure(s) (e.g. brachialis to anterior interosseous nerve, supinator to posterior interosseous) and will be followed post-operatively to assess for changes in strength, functional independence, and quality of life.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Quadriplegia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with a spinal cord injury AIS level C5 to C7. Those with motor complete injuries (AIS A or B) will be considered for surgical intervention if they are ≥ 5 months post injury. Motor incomplete patients (AIS C or D) will be considered if they are ≥ 1.5 years post injury. Patients will require ≥ MRC 4 strength of the muscle supplied by the donor nerve (e.g. brachialis, supinator). Finger flexor and extensor strength should be ≤ MRC 1 strength. Muscles supplied by the donor nerve, will need to have no or minimal of evidence of lower motor neuron injury as dictated by evidence of fibrillations, positive sharp waves, or moderate or severely decreased recruitment on needle electromyography. Those being evaluated for surgery outside ninemonths post injury recipient muscles will be required to be free of lower motor neuron pathology. Ability to comply and participate in rigorous postsurgical therapy regimen. Comorbidities precluding safe surgery including autonomic/hemodynamic instability, pulmonary instability, active infection, chronic pressure sores or untreated urinary tract infections as determined by physician. Simultaneous tendon transfer or tenodesis surgery (which would preclude separation of the effect of nerve transfer alone).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>peripheral nerves</keyword>
	<keyword>quadriplegia</keyword>
	<keyword>nerve transfer</keyword>
	<keyword>surgical procedures, operative</keyword>
	<keyword>hand</keyword>
	<keyword>upper extremity</keyword>
	<keyword>quality of life</keyword>
</DOC>