<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02612805</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates the effects of the combined exercise training (aerobic more resistance) and of the aerobic exercise training isolated compared to control group, which performed only stretching and relaxation, in the treatment of type 2 diabetes (T2DM). The two exercise interventions and the control procedure are performed in aquatic environment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Diabetes and Aquatic Training Study (DATS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The fact that aquatic training can provide similar benefits to land training has important clinical implications, because the aquatic environment provides some interesting advantages to this population, such as no impact on walking and running in deep water or reduced, as in water-based exercises. This minor impact and consequent reduced chance of injury allows consider the aquatic environment favorable to the principle of continuity with progression of physiological stimuli and metabolic benefits. From these peculiarities of the training in aquatic environment, and of the association between T2DM with obesity and hypertension, conditions that create difficulties for individuals performing exercise supporting their own body mass and need both benefits from aerobic and resistance training, is believed to be necessary to carry out physical training programs of the same duration, differing in training mode (aerobic or combined) in the aquatic environment in order to answer of in a adequated duration of training, the diabetes control through training differs between the different mode of exercise.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 2 diabetes; Be under medical treatment with oral hypoglycemic agents and / or insulin; Not engaged in regular exercise (regular exercise was defined as performing any type of physical training for at least 20 minutes three or more days a week). Severe autonomic neuropathy; Severe nonproliferative and proliferative diabetic retinopathy; Decompensated heart failure; Limb amputations; Severe foot injuries; Chronic renal failure (Modification Diet in Renal DiseaseMDRD, Glomerular Filtration RateGFR &lt; 30 ml/min); Body mass index (BMI) &gt; 45.0 kg/m2; Any muscle or joint impairment which prevented individuals from engaging in physical exercise.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>