<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02612636</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sleep is a complex physiologic and behavioral process essential for rest, repair, well-being, and survival. Sleep is defined as a periodic, reversible state of cognitive and sensory disengagement from the external environment. Critically ill patients experience poor sleep quality. Surveys of ICU survivors have shown that sleep disruption, pain and intubation for mechanical ventilation are the major sources of anxiety and stress during the ICU stay. Many physiological, psychological and environmental factors contribute to the incidence of sleep disruption for the ICU patients. The primary physiologic factors documented in the literature are pain, medications and illness.The primary psychological factors documented in the literature are stress and worry. Environmental factors include noise, patient care activities and therapeutic modalities as mechanical ventilation. Our research aim will be the impact of effective interventions like use of ear plugs and eye mask on decreasing light exposure and promoting sleep in ICU patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Ear Plug and Eye Mask on Sleeping Quality in Critically Ill Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>50 patients in the age range 18- 60 years admitted to ICU of Assiut university hospitals will be randomly allocated into into two groups (control group and intervention group).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt;18 years old. Mechanically ventilated patient. Conscious patient. No hearing problems. No eye disease. Not receiving narcotic drugs five to six hours before sleep time at night. No underlying disease that is affecting sleep such as rheumatoid arthritis and migraine. Exclusion Criteria Head injury. Psychiatric disease. Shocked patients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Delirium</keyword>
	<keyword>Ear Plug</keyword>
	<keyword>Eye Mask</keyword>
	<keyword>Mechanical ventilation</keyword>
	<keyword>Sleep</keyword>
</DOC>