<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02612246</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this First-in-Human study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability after single ascending oral doses of GLPG1972 given to healthy subjects, compared to placebo. Also, the safety and tolerability of multiple ascending oral doses of GLPG1972 given to healthy subjects daily for 14 days compared to placebo, will be evaluated. Furthermore, during the course of the study after single and multiple oral dose administrations, the amount of GLPG1972 present in the blood and urine (pharmacokinetics) will be characterized. The effect of food on the pharmacokinetics of GLPG1972 will also be evaluated. The potential of cytochrome P450 (CYP)3A4 interaction after repeated dosing with GLPG1972 will be explored as well. During the course of the study after multiple oral dose administrations, the effect of GLPG1972 on biomarkers present in the blood (pharmacodynamics) will be characterized.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>First-in-Human Single and Multiple Dose of GLPG1972</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males between 1850 years of age Subjects must have a body mass index between 1830 kg/m² Subjects must be judged to be in good health based upon the results of a medical history, physical examination, vital signs, 12lead electrocardiogram and laboratory profile A subject with a known hypersensitivity to study drug ingredients or a significant allergic reaction to any drug Concurrent participation or participation within 8 weeks prior to the initial study drug administration in a drug/device investigational research study A subject with active drug or alcohol abuse within 2 years prior to the initial study drug administration Current sexually active (and/or child wish) male; a contraception method should be used</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>