<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00976560</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this randomized, double-blind, multi-centre, placebo controlled, exploratory, adaptive design study, the antidepressant and plasma cytokine lowering effects of the GW856553 will be investigated in adult subjects diagnosed with MDD. Subjects will receive oral doses of GW856553 or placebo for six weeks. Safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics, defined as biomarkers in blood and clinical symptoms, will be assessed. The primary endpoint is the change from baseline associated with GW856553 versus placebo at Week 6 in the Bech (6-item HAMD-17) score. Interim analyses of the primary endpoint will be performed throughout the study to potentially adapt the study design by changing the randomization ratio and/ or reducing the total number of subjects to be randomized into the study. Exploratory analyses will be performed by associating changes in cytokine levels and selected clinical symptoms; PK/PD modelling will also be used to identify the most sensitive clinical and biological markers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Study to Test a New Drug to Treat Major Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Adult subjects with primary diagnosis of moderate to severe MDD without psychotic features, for at least 4 weeks and one previous MDD episode Males or Females who agree to use protocol specified contraception if of child bearing potential BMI 18.535.0 kg/m2 Normal liver function tests Key History of liver disease or positive hepatitis B surface antigen or hepatitis C antibody in the last 3 months Elevated liver function tests on &gt;2 ocassions in the last 7 months Significant medical illness, autoimmune disease or infectious disease Pregnant or nursing females Excessive and regular alcohol consumption History of substance abuse or dependence in past 6 months or positive urine drug screen Significant suicidal or homicidal risk Currently receiving chronic biological or pharmacologic antiinflammatory therapy or is not euthyroid Psychoactive drugs within 1 week or 5 half lives of randomization visit Treatment resistant subjects</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lack of interest and energy</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychomotor retardation</keyword>
	<keyword>Cytokines</keyword>
	<keyword>Major Depressive disorder</keyword>
</DOC>