<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00976456</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Multi-center, open, randomized (parallel) and comparative phase III. Eligible patients will receive bevacizumab + chemotherapy for a minimum of 4 cycles followed by bevacizumab (+ pemetrexed, if appropriate) maintenance therapy until disease progression. Arm A: Bevacizumab + pemetrexed Arm B: Bevacizumab + pemetrexed + carboplatin</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Study of Avastin® With Pemetrexed +/- Carboplatin to Treat Elderly Patients With Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary: - Proof of non-inferior efficacy of a monochemotherapy regimen of pemetrexed plus bevacizumab versus a combination chemotherapy regimen of pemetrexed-carboplatin plus bevacizumab in elderly patients(&gt; 65 years) as first-line treatment of advanced metastatic or recurrent non-squamous NSCLC by progression free survival Secondary: - To assess the efficacy of bevacizumab as measured by overall response rate and overall survival. - To assess the safety of bevacizumab in combination with pemetrexed and pemetrexed and carboplatin. - To assess quality of life by EORTC questionnaire QLQ-C30 and its lung cancer module LC-13 - To assess activity of daily life (iADL) in relation to ECOG performance status prior to study treatment - To assess patient`s outcome and treatment delivery in relation to the Charlson comorbidity score and the Simplified Comorbidity Score</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Stage IIIb and IV NSCLC, excluded squamous cell NSCLC Age ≥ 65 years ECOG 02 Mixed, nonsmall cell and small cell tumours or mixed adenosquamous carcinomas with a predominant squamous component History of haemoptysis Evidence of tumour invading major blood vessels on imaging Radiotherapy within 28 days prior to enrolment Patients who are unable to interrupt aspirin or other nonsteroidal antiinflammatory agents, other than an aspirin dose ≤ 1.3 grams per day, for a 5day period (8day period for longacting agents, such as piroxicam) Current or recent (within 10 days of first dose of bevacizumab) use of fulldose oral or parenteral anticoagulants or thrombolytic agent for therapeutic purposes. Prophylactic use of anticoagulants is allowed Clinically significant (i.e. active) cardiovascular disease for example CVA (≤6 months before enrolment), myocardial infarction (≤6 months before enrolment), unstable angina, CHF NYHA Class ≥II, serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication during the study and might interfere with regularity of the study treatment, or not controlled by medication Nonhealing wound, active peptic ulcer or bone fracture History of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation or intraabdominal abscess within 6 months of enrolment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
	<keyword>elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>non-squamous</keyword>
	<keyword>Elderly patients at least 65 years old</keyword>
	<keyword>first line therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>non-squamous non-small cell lung cancer stage IIIb or IV</keyword>
</DOC>