<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01082003</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this research study is to determine if the use of Trental and Vitamin E will decrease the incidence and severity of contractures (shrinking and or hardening of tissue surrounding the implant) associated with breast implant reconstruction following radiation treatment. Another goal is to find out the impact that Trental and Vitamin E have on implant loss or need for surgical intervention in the setting of chest wall radiation after reconstruction. In addition, the investigators want to evaluate the patient's sense of well being and quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prevention of Capsular Contracture Using Trental and Vitamin E</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single center, 18-month study in which 30 women will receive Trental (pentoxifylline) 400 milligrams three times a day in combination with vitamin E, 400 international units orally twice daily for six months. Subjects will begin the treatment regimen within four weeks after completion of radiation treatment and will remain on the study drugs for six months. Following completion of active treatment, all subjects will enter the twelve-month observational phase of the trial in which they will be evaluated for changes in breast tissue using the following objective tools: Bakers Grade Assessment, Visual Analog Scale (VAS), implant revision or loss, breast photographs, adverse event assessment and the Quality of Life tool (SF-12).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Contracture</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin E</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tocopherols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tocotrienols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>alpha-Tocopherol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pentoxifylline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female subjects &gt; 18 years of age Expected survival at least &gt; 6 months Undergone mastectomy with expander or implant reconstruction &gt; 3 weeks before radiation therapy Completed chest wall irradiation in the past two weeks Willing to stop herbal medications as directed by physician Willing to stop daily use of supplemental vitamin E (Multivitamin with vitamin E component is acceptable) Willing to travel to a Legacy Health System facility Agree to attend study visits outside of standard of care visits Normal PTINR for subjects taking Coumadin &lt; 18 years of age Pregnant or lactating Have final implant placed &lt; 3 weeks before start of radiation therapy Have evidence of ongoing infection or implant exposure before start of radiation therapy Radiation completed more than 16 days prior to study start Retinitis Pigmentosa Unable to comply with protocol Unable to provide written informed consent Unwilling or unable to stop supplemental vitamin E PTINR outside of acceptable range for subjects taking Coumadin Investigator does not believe study participation, for any reason is in the best interest of the patient</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Capsular contractures in breast cancer patients</keyword>
</DOC>