<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01416571</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial will assess the immunogenicity and safety of GSK Biologicals' vaccine GSK1557484A, prepared from old concentrated monobulk material, in adults aged 18 to 64 years, when administered up to 5 years following production.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunogenicity and Safety Study of GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) Biologicals' Monovalent Pandemic H5N1 Vaccine in Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who the investigator believes can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol. A male or female 18 to 64 years of age at the time of the first vaccination. Written informed consent obtained from the subject. Stable general health as established by medical history and clinical examination before entering into the study. Subject access to a consistent means of telephone contact, land line or mobile, but NOT a pay phone or other multipleuser device. Female subjects of nonchildbearing potential may be enrolled in the study. Female subjects of childbearing potential may be enrolled in the study, if the subject: has practiced adequate contraception for 30 days prior to vaccination, and has a negative pregnancy test on the day of vaccination, and has agreed to continue adequate contraception for 2 months after completion of the vaccination series. Previous vaccination at any time with an H5N1 vaccine. Use of any investigational or nonregistered product other than the study vaccine within 30 days preceding the first dose of study vaccine, or planned use during the study period. Presence of significant acute or chronic, uncontrolled medical or psychiatric illness. Presence of evidence of substance abuse or of neurological or psychiatric diagnoses which, even if stable, are deemed by the investigator to render the potential subject unable/unlikely to provide accurate safety reports. Presence of a temperature ≥ 38.0ºC, or acute symptoms greater than "mild" severity on the scheduled date of first dose. Diagnosed with cancer, or treatment for cancer, within 3 years. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, based on medical history and physical examination. Receipt of systemic glucocorticoids within 1 month prior to study enrolment, or any other cytotoxic or immunosuppressive drug within 6 months of study enrolment. Topical, intraarticularly injected, or inhaled glucocorticoids, topical calcineurin inhibitors or imiquimod are allowed. Receipt of any immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within 3 months before first study vaccination or planned administration of any of these products during the study period. Any significant disorder of coagulation or treatment with warfarin derivatives or heparin. Persons receiving individual doses of low molecular weight heparin outside of 24 hours prior to dosing, are eligible. Persons receiving prophylactic antiplatelet medications, and without a clinicallyapparent bleeding tendency, are eligible. An acute evolving neurological disorder or history of GuillainBarré syndrome within 6 weeks of receipt of seasonal influenza vaccine. Administration of an inactivated or a live, attenuated seasonal influenza vaccine within 14 days before the first study vaccine dose, or of any other vaccine(s) not foreseen by the study protocol within 30 days before the first study vaccine dose. Planned administration of any vaccine(s) not foreseen by the study protocol through completion of the Day 42 visit. Any known or suspected allergy to any constituent of influenza vaccines, or history of severe reaction to a previous influenza vaccination. Known pregnancy or a positive urine betahuman chorionic gonadotropin test result prior to the first study vaccine dose. Lactating or nursing women.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>H5N1</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>influenza infection</keyword>
	<keyword>GSK1557484A</keyword>
</DOC>