<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00995293</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Primary Objective is to evaluate the progression-free survival after treatment with docetaxel plus cisplatin plus 5-Fluorouracil (5-FU) (DCF) in comparison with cisplatin plus 5-FU (CF) in patient with locally advanced inoperable SCCHN The Secondary Objective is to evaluate and compare the clinical response rate both before and after radiotherapy, the local symptoms, the duration of response, the time to treatment failure, the survival, the toxicity and the quality of life in the 2 study groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Taxotere (Docetaxel) New Indication: Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Head and Neck (SCCHN) Treatment Registration Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Tumor type: Histologically or cytologically proven squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck (SCCHN) presenting with locally advanced disease at diagnosis. Primary tumor sites eligible are: oral cavity, oropharynx, hypopharynx and larynx. Extent of the disease: Patients are required to have at least one measurable lesion. Stage III or IV without evidence of distant metastases, according to the TNM staging system. Absence of metastases must be checked by chest Xray (with or without Computed tomography (CT) ), abdominal ultrasound or CT in case of liver function test abnormalities, and bone scan in case of local symptoms. Tumor considered as inoperable after evaluation by a multidisciplinary team. Reason for inoperability will be reported in the CRF World Health Organization (WHO) performance status 0 or 1 Laboratory data: Haematology: Neutrophil count &gt; or = 2.0*10^9/L Platelet count &gt; or = 100*10^9/L Hemoglobin &gt; or = 10 g/dl (6.2 mmol/L) Hepatic function: Total serum bilirubin &lt; or = 1 time the upper normal limit (UNL) of the participating center Aspartate transaminase (ASAT/SGOT) and Alanine transaminase (ALAT/SGPT) &lt; or = 2.5UNL Alkaline phosphatase &lt; or = 5 UNL Patients with ASAT or ALAT &gt; 1.5UNL associated with alkaline phosphatase &gt;2.5UNL are not eligible for the study Renal function: serum creatinine &lt; or = 120µmol/L (1.4 mg/dl) if values are &gt;120µmol/L, creatinine clearance should be &gt; or = 60 ml/min Absence of any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially hampering compliance with the study protocol and followup schedule, those conditions should be discussed with the patient before registration in the trial Patients informed consent form obtained Exclusion criteria: Tumors of the nasopharynx, the nasal and paranasal cavities. Previous chemotherapy or radiotherapy for any reason and previous surgery for SCCHN at time of study entry. Prior treatment within a therapeutic clinical tria within 30 days prior to study entry Concurrent treatment with any other anticancer therapy Chronic treatment (&gt; or = 3 months) with corticosteroids at a daily dose &gt; or = 20mg methylprednisolone or equivalent. Concomitant use of drugs which could interact with 5fluorouracil (e.g. cimetidine, allopurinol, folic or folinic acid, methotrexate and metronidazole) Previous or current malignancies at other sites with the exception of adequately treated in situ carcinoma of the cervix uteri, basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or other cancer curatively treated by surgery and with no evidence of disease for at least 5 years Symptomatic peripheral neuropathy &gt; or = grade 2 by NCICCTG criteria Clinical altered hearing Pregnant, lactating women or of childbearing potential unless adequate with other serious illness or medical condition including but not limited to: unstable cardiac disease despite treatment myocardial infarction within 6 months prior to study entry history of significant neurologic or psychiatric disorders including dementia or seizures active uncontrolled infection active peptic ulcer chronic obstructive pulmonary disease requiring hospitalization during the year preceding study entry The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>