<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00995553</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim of the study is to test the efficacy of a novel cognitive remediation intervention that targets working memory-related functions. To accomplish this goal, 80 volunteer patients with schizophrenia will be enrolled and randomized to either a cognitive remediation condition that targets working memory or a computer skills training intervention that teaches computer applications. In both conditions participants will receive computer training three times a week for 4 months. The investigators hypothesize that patients who receive the cognitive remediation intervention will demonstrate significantly greater change on neuropsychological measures of working memory and executive abilities than patients who receive the computer skills course. In addition, the investigators hypothesize that the intervention-induced cognitive change will be associated with concurrent improvements in functional capacity and psychosocial functioning in the community. A second study goal is to examine the stability of the intervention-induced changes in cognition. Cognition and psychosocial functioning will be reassessed 4 and 8 months after treatment termination to examine the stability of treatment effects and to assess whether a less intense maintenance training (once a week sessions) provides any additional benefit to participants. Lastly, this study will examine in an exploratory manner whether there are individual differences in treatment response. The Val158Met polymorphism of the COMT gene has been found to be associated with working memory and prefrontal dysfunction in schizophrenia. The study will test whether the COMT polymorphism is predictive of response to cognitive remediation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Remediation of Working Memory in Schizophrenia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Veterans with a DSMIV diagnosis of schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder No hospitalizations in the previous 4 weeks No antipsychotic medication changes in the previous 4 weeks Age 1860 Does not meet DSMIV criteria for substance dependence in the previous 6 months or substance abuse in the previous month History of clinically significant head injury or neurological disease Poor comprehension of the English language History of diagnosis of mental retardation or pervasive developmental disorder Unable to give informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>