<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00595049</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this study is to investigate whether bosentan (Tracleer®) affects the wall thickness of the pulmonary arteries in patients with idiopathic pulmonary arterial hypertension (iPAH) and PAH related to systemic sclerosis (PAH-SSc). The second purpose is to investigate if bosentan affects the enlargement of small vessels in the lungs in response to natural chemicals in patients with iPAH and PAH-SSc.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pulmonary Artery Remodelling With Bosentan</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bosentan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria : · Men or women &gt;18 years of age.· Symptomatic (modified NYHA class III) iPAH or PAHSSc· PAH confirmed by right heart catheterization performed within 3 months before enrolment mPAP &gt; 25 mmHg, PCWP &lt; 15 mmHg and PVR &gt; 3 mmHg/l/min. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pretreatment pregnancy test and use a reliable method of contraception during study treatment and for 3 months after study treatment termination. Bosentan naïve patients Exclusion Criteria : · PAH other than iPAH or PAHSSc Significant vasoreactivity during right heart catheterization defined as a fall in mPAP to &lt; 40 mmHg with a decrease &gt;= 10 mmHg and with a normal cardiac index (&gt;= 2.5 l/min.m2)· Severe obstructive lung disease: FEV1/FVC &lt; 0.5 Severe restrictive lung disease: TLC &lt; 0.7 of normal predicted value Hemoglobin &lt;75% of the lower limit of the normal range· Systolic blood pressure &lt; 85 mmHg Body weight &lt; 40 kg Pregnancy or breastfeeding Moderate to severe hepatic impairment, i.e., ChildPugh Class B or C. Baseline aminotransferases, i.e., aspartate aminotransferases (AST) and/or alanine aminotransferases (ALT) &gt; 3 times the upper limit of the normal (ULN) range. Treatment for iPAH or PAHSSc within 1 month before start of study treatment, excluding warfarin and acute administration of vasodilators for vascular reactivity testing during heart catheterization. Treatment with epoprostenol or other prostacyclin analogs for iPAH or PAHSSc within 1 month before start of study treatment Treatment with glibenclamide (glyburide), fluconazole ketoconazole or ritonavir within 1 week before start of study treatment. Current treatment with cyclosporine A or tacrolimus Hypersensitivity to bosentan or any of the excipients of its formulation. Patient who received an investigational drug (such as sildenafil) within 3 months before start of study treatment Conditions that prevent compliance with the protocol or adherence to therapy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>pulmonary</keyword>
	<keyword>arterial</keyword>
	<keyword>artery</keyword>
	<keyword>hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>systemic</keyword>
	<keyword>sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>scleroderma</keyword>
	<keyword>remodelling</keyword>
	<keyword>bosentan</keyword>
	<keyword>tracleer</keyword>
	<keyword>intravascular</keyword>
</DOC>