<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00595972</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of the ECF regimen (epirubicin, cisplatin and FU) combined with endostar-- a inhibitor of angiogenesis, in patients with advanced or metastatic gastric cancer (A/MGC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Epirubicin Cisplatin and Fluorouracil (FU) Combined With Endostar in Patients With Advanced or Metastatic Gastric Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Although there is no standard regimen in the treatment of metastatic gastric cancer, ECF regimen (epirubicin, cisplatin and FU) is often considered as a reference regimen. And ECF regimen has been suggested as the first line therapy for A/MGC by FDA. According to the result of a Chinese phase III clinical trial in metastatic lung cancer, endostar-- a new angiogenesis inhibitor prolonged the overall survival, time to progression and improved response rate. So we designed this clinical trial to evaluate whether endostar can bring survival benefits to patients with advanced and metastatic gastric cancer patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epirubicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed advanced or metastatic adenocarcinoma of the stomach ECOG performance scale ≤ 2 At least one measurable lesion (larger than 10 mm in diameter by spiral CT scan) Adequate hepatic, renal, heart, and hematologic functions (platelets＞80×109/L, neutrophil＞ 2.0 × 109/L, serum creatinine ≤ 1.5mg/dl, total bilirubin within upper limit of normal(ULN), and serum transaminase ≤ 2.5×the ULN) Pregnant or lactating women Concurrent cancer History of other malignancies except cured basal cell carcinoma of skin and carcinoma insitu of uterine cervix Neuropathy, brain, or leptomeningeal involvement Clinically relevant coronary artery disease or a history of a myocardial infarction within the last 12 months or high risk/uncontrolled arrhythmia Uncontrolled significant comorbid conditions and previous radiotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Time to Progression</keyword>
	<keyword>Overall survival</keyword>
	<keyword>Response rate</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Live</keyword>
	<keyword>Toxicities</keyword>
</DOC>