<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01079832</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Stereotactic radiosurgery can send x-rays directly to the tumor and cause less damage to normal tissue. PURPOSE: This clinical trial studies stereotactic radiosurgery using CyberKnife works in treating women with advanced or recurrent gynecological malignancies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Stereotactic Radiosurgery Using CyberKnife in Treating Women With Advanced or Recurrent Gynecological Malignancies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. The primary goal of this study is to estimate the rate of grade 3 or higher acute toxicities observed during a 6 month period following CyberKnife radiosurgery for gynecologic cancers. II. To evaluate clinical response to radio-surgery for gynecologic tumors. III. To assess general and site specific quality of life (using SF-12, FACT-En, FACT-O, FACT-Cx or FACT-V) and to evaluate patient's level of pain. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. As a secondary objective, toxicities during the 2 years following CyberKnife radiosurgery will also be described. OUTLINE: Patients undergo 3 fractions of CyberKnife stereotactic radiosurgery. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed at 1, 3, 6, 12, 18 and 24 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Germ Cell and Embryonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Glandular and Epithelial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Germinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vulvar Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaginal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Pathologically proven gynecologic malignancy No prior cryosurgery or radiofrequency ablation, in target lesion Patient is able to give and sign study specific informed consent Measurable disease, according to RECIST criteria Laboratory parameters and appropriate clearance from anesthesia based on other medical comorbidities for placement of fiducials; these would include CBC, basic metabolic panel, BUN, and creatinine &gt;= 4 weeks from previous treatment (chemotherapy or radiation) of malignancy ECOG performance status of 03 as this procedure is minimally invasive and considered palliative in these patients Exclusion Any patient with active connective tissue disease such as lupus or dermatomyositis is excluded Any patient with active Crohn's disease or active ulcerative colitis is excluded Major medical or psychiatric illness, which would prevent completion of treatment or interfere with followup is excluded</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>