<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01079572</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Complications following total joint arthroplasty are rare, and the majority of follow-up visits are routine. The technology now exists to conduct annual follow-up assessments without having to physically see the patient. This study will investigate the cost-effectiveness of web-based follow-up assessments compared to standard in-clinic follow-ups. We will also assess patient satisfaction, preference, and the validity of the web-based follow up assessments. Patients coming up to their 1 year follow-up or greater will be randomized to either the web-based group or the usual care group. Web-based patients will complete all questionnaires using an online database system, and have their x-ray taken at their local radiology facility. The surgeon will review radiographs online. If there are any concerns with the x-ray or responses to questionnaires, arrangements will be made for the patient to be seen at the clinic. Patients in the Usual Care group will come into the clinic for their follow-up assessment and have their x-ray taken at University Hospital as usual. Online assessment could significantly decrease wait times in orthopaedic clinics, as well as increase availability for OR time and new consultations. This approach could also potentially reduce patient burden by decreasing travel distances, financial burden and time requirements.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cost-Effectiveness of Web-Based Follow Ups</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients who have had a primary total hip or total knee arthroplasty patients with osteolysis, or previous complications from their joint replacement</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>osteoarthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>arthroplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>web-based</keyword>
	<keyword>electronic follow-up</keyword>
</DOC>