<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02194582</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators are trying to learn more about the cause of kidney diseases such as Focal Segmental Glomerulosclerosis (FSGS) and Nephrotic syndrome by studying genetics. The investigators are interested in discovering which genes play a role in causing a predisposition to FSGS/NS. The investigators also want to learn why FSGS/NS can run in families. Participation in our study involves a saliva sample and a urine sample that you can give from home. There is no cost to participate. All information is kept private and confidential. The investigators also like to include healthy volunteers (parents, spouses) if interested/available but of course this is completely optional.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Genetic Causes of FSGS, Nephrotic Syndrome, or Kidney Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Proteinuria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nephrotic Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nephrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glomerulosclerosis, Focal Segmental</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects with FSGS (focal segmental glomerulosclerosis) Subjects with NS (nephrotic syndrome) Subjects with unexplained kidney failure (have had a transplant or on dialysis) Subjects with unexplained proteinuria Family members of a person with FSGS, NS, kidney failure, or unexplained protein in their urine Healthy volunteers Patients whose kidney disease is already explained by another syndrome such as (Branchio Oto Renal Syndrome or Alports syndrome) Patients who already know the genetic cause of their kidney disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>FSGS</keyword>
	<keyword>NS</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal disease</keyword>
	<keyword>nephrotic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>focal segmental glomerulosclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>familial kidney disease</keyword>
	<keyword>minimal change disease</keyword>
	<keyword>proteinuria</keyword>
</DOC>