<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02194569</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Rationale: A higher citrate dose during continuous venovenous hemofiltration provides better anticoagulation but possibly a higher risk of citrate accumulation in case of metabolic limitations. A higher citrate dose also increases magnesium loss in ultrafiltrate, while a negative magnesium balance is unwanted. Objective: Aim of this study is to determine the magnesium balance of citrate-based continuous veno-venous hemofiltration (CVVH) and to determine whether and to which extent the magnesium balance depends on citrate dose. Study design and methods: A prospective randomized study conducted in critically ill patients with acute kidney injury (AKI), treated with CVVH, with either low dose citrate (2.5 mmol/L blood flow in the filter) or high dose citrate (4.5 mmol/L blood flow in the filter) as anti-coagulant, targeting a postfilter ionized Calcium (iCa) of resp. 1.3-1.6 mg/dL (0.325-0.4 mmol/L) and 0.8-1.1 mg/dL (0.2-0.275 mmol/L). Post-filter blood as well as effluent aliquots and bloodconcentrations in the patient are tested for the following variables: (0 , 2 , 4, 6, 12 and 24 hrs): Total Magnesium (tMg) and total Calcium (tCa), ionized Ca (iCa)(bloodgas analyzer). In addition, hematocrit, albumin, total protein, ureum and creatinine and parathormone (PTH) are determined in arterial blood at 0 and 24 hrs or at the time of protocol exit and citrate concentrations in postfilter and arterial blood at 1 and 24 hrs or at protocol exit. Sample sites: arterial line, postfilter port (after postdilution and calcium compensation), effluent sample. All flow rates to be noted. Study population: Twenty patients admitted to intensive care, requiring continuous renal replacement therapy (CRRT) for AKI. Intervention: Anti-coagulation with either low dose citraat (2.5 mmol/L blood flow) or high dose citraat (4.5 mmol/L blood flow) targeting postfilter iCa of resp. 1.3-1.6 and 0.8-1.1 mg/dL. Both regimens are within standard protocolled CVVH treatment in the intensive care department.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Magnesium Balance of Citrate-based Continuous Venovenous Hemofiltration, Effect of Citrate Dose.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citric Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Critically ill patients requiring CRRT for AKI (RIFLE criteria) Written informed consent from the patient or legal representative preexisting chronic renal insufficiency requiring dialysis chronic immunosuppression liver cirrhosis ChildPugh C severe or shockrelated hepatitis Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>