<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02194790</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is a major health problem in Thailand. Previous studies have demonstrated that integrated pre-dialysis care may slow the decline in renal function (Nephrol Dial Transplant.2009 Nov;24(11):3426-33). It is interesting to know whether early intervention especially in high risk groups like Diabetic may also improve outcome of these patients in primary health care setting resulting in delay of CKD progression.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Integrated CKD Care Program in Early Diabetic Nephropathy in Primary Health Care Setting.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We conducted a 12-month longitudinal study at district A (control) and B (intervention) at Kamphaeng Phet Province, Thailand. Diabetic patients with eGFR ≥ 60 ml/min/1.73m2 were recruited from both districts. Patients in district A (control group) received standard CKD care according to NKF-K/DOQI guidelines1 whereas those in district B (intervention) received, in addition to the standard care, educational activities provided by nutritionist, pharmacist and physiotherapist, and quarterly home visits. Our home visits team consisted of nurse, health care officers and village health volunteers. During each hospital visit of both groups clinical data were assessed. All laboratory parameters were collected every 3 months, and LDL and HbA1C every 6 months. The primary end point was rate of eGFR decline. Secondary outcomes were random urine albumin to creatinine ratio (ACR), blood pressure, waist circumference, HbA1C and LDL .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Nephropathies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diabetic patients with eGFR are equal or more than 60 ml/min/1.73m2 estimated twice at 3 months. Active glomerular disease, obstructive uropathy, endstage renal disease, HIV infection, pregnancy, body mass index (BMI) less than 18 or more than 40 kg/m2, being under treatment for malignancy, urine proteincreatinine ratio more than 3.5 g/g creatinine and active urinary sediment (urine red blood cells &gt;3 cells/high power field or urine white blood cells &gt;10 cells/high power field).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Kidney Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetic Nephropathy</keyword>
	<keyword>Integrated Chronic Kidney Disease Care</keyword>
</DOC>