<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02066090</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research is planned to build a basis about the effect of acupuncture on serum metabolic parameters in pre-menopausal obese women with economic evaluation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acupuncture for Obesity on Serum Metabolic Parameters</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>It is consisted with two sub research. First, clinical research to assess the effect of acupuncture for obesity on serum metabolic parameters will be processed with randomized, patient-assessor blinding, and sham-acupuncture controlled study design. 120 subjects would be collected and divided into two groups(experimental and placebo, 60 subjects each). Experimental group will undergo with real acupuncture treatment(manual acupuncture + electroacupuncture) twice a week, for 6 weeks. The effect on serum metabolic parameters will be assessed at 0 and 6 weeks. Second is qualitative research to make a basis through the evaluation of economic efficacy and patients' satisfaction with acupuncture treatment for obesity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>volunteers through announcements and advertisements premenopausal adult women (19 years of age or more) clinical diagnosis of obesity (Body mass index: 25 kg/m2 or more) previously or currently having endocrine disease such as hypothyroidism or Cushing's syndrome, heart disease, lung disease, diabetes, malignant tumor, cholelithiasis, severe kidney impairment, severe liver impairment, anorexia nervosa or hyperorexia experience of taking medicines which might affect body weight and the concentration of serum metabolic parameters such as anorectic, laxative, oral steroid, thyroid hormone, amphetamine, cyproheptadine, phenothiazine, or medicines affecting absorption, metabolism, and excretion in the past 3 months experience of taking betablocker or diuretic for the treatment of hypertension in the past 3 months surgical treatment for the treatment of obesity currently or might be pregnant or breastfeeding experience of taking other experimental medicines in the past month weight loss of 10% or more of previous body weight in the past 6 months who stopped smoking in the past 3 months or who have irregular smoking habit pacemaker currently receiving any treatment for obesity other inadequate subjects assessed by the study investigators</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>acupuncture</keyword>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolomics</keyword>
</DOC>