<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02066025</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Octava has two versions, each with a different intend of use. OctavaPink is a qualitative in vitro diagnostic test service, performed by authorized clinical laboratories. The product is used for two following indications: - Intend of Use #1: OctavaPink is indicated for women above 18 years old, who performed mammography and were determined negative for breast cancer. Being moderately sensitive (&gt;55% sensitivity) the test is able to detect 55% of mammography false negatives. In addition, being highly specific (&gt;95% specificity) it supplies additional evidence for true mammography negative result which will reduce examinees anxiety of being misdiagnosed as a result of high false negative mammography rate (10-30%) - Intend of Use #2: OctavaPink is indicated for women above 18 years old, who performed biopsy after positive mammography and the biopsy result was negative. Being moderately sensitive (&gt;55% sensitivity) the test is able to detect 55% of biopsy false negatives. In addition being highly specific (&gt;95% specificity) it supplies an additional evidence for true biopsy negative result which reduces examinees anxiety of being misdiagnosed. OctavBlue is a qualitative in vitro diagnostic test service, performed by EventusDx authorized laboratories. Intend of use of OctavBlue is the following: • OctavBlue is indicated for women above 18 years old, who performed mammography and received doubtful results. Being highly sensitive (&gt;95% sensitivity) the test can help to reveal 95% of positive cases; and being moderately specific (&gt;55% specificity) - about half of negative cases. The test is not intended to be used as a standalone diagnostic technique but to supply additional information to a physician and help deciding about the further course of diagnosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Blood Test for Breast Cancer Associated Auto Antibodies - Improvement of Octava Blood Test</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objectives - To improve the specifications of the OctavaPink test and the OctavaBlue test. The current specifications being 1. For the OctavaPink - 95% specificity and 50% sensitivity. 2. For the OctavaBlue - 50% specificity and 95% sensitivity. The study will be considered as successful in any of the below options - 1. If the new antigens incorporated in the OctavaPink chip will maintain specificity of at least 95% and increase the sensitivity to at least 85%. 2. If the new antigens incorporated in the OctavaBlue chip will maintain sensitivity of at least 95% and increase the specificity to at least 85%.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autoantibodies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female subjects 18 years or over. Subjects following a mammography test. Subject with pathological evaluation after mammography with BIRADS 3456. Female Subjects less than 18 years of age Previous or concurrent malignancies Autoimmune disorders diagnosed subjects Hematological malignancies Subjects under active chemotherapy treatment or chemotherapy in the past 6 months Steroid treatment in the past 3 months Subject undergoing immunosuppressive treatments Subject with verified breast cancer other than invasive ductal or invasive lobular as verified by biopsy/cytology</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer associated auto antibodies</keyword>
	<keyword>breast cancer blood test</keyword>
</DOC>