<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01665989</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research project has two primary specific aims in the Partners HealthCare clinical population and setting: 1. To compare the effects of two interventions, a translation of the Look AHEAD lifestyle behavioral intervention program with usual care (UC) (brief nutrition counseling and referral to Nutrition Services, the current standard), on the primary outcome of weight loss and secondary outcomes of HbA1c, blood pressure, fasting lipid levels, and prescription medication (doses and costs) for diabetes and its related conditions. We hypothesize that participants who receive the translation of the Look AHEAD program will lose significantly more weight and have lower glycemia, blood pressure, cholesterol, and drug doses and costs for these conditions than participants who receive UC. 2. To compare the effects of the two interventions on health behaviors, self-efficacy, diabetes-specific quality-of-life and patient satisfaction with quality of care. We hypothesize that participants who receive the translation of the Look AHEAD program will be more satisfied with their care and will experience greater improvements in health behavior, self-efficacy, and diabetes-specific quality-of-life compared to participants who receive UC. Secondary specific aim: To assess the cost-effectiveness of the two interventions and the potential cost savings in terms of reductions in medication doses. In the current environment, a cost effective approach to lifestyle change is imperative. The costs and benefits of the interventions in this project will be carefully analyzed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Diabetes Outcomes Through Lifestyle Change (IDOLc)Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of type 2 diabetes Age 18 years or older Overweight or obese (BMI &gt; 25) HbA1c level 7.5&lt; 11% Systolic blood pressure (SBP) &lt; 160 mmHg, diastolic blood pressure (DBP) &lt; 100 mmHg Triglyceride levels &lt; 600 mg/dL Be on at least one nonmetformin diabetes medication If taking medication for a chronic disease such as hypothyroidism, must be on a stable dose for the previous 6 months Willing to lose 57% of body weight Willing to increase activity to at least 175 minutes/week Willing to commit to random assignment to either attend and participate in the 19week lifestyle change program or be referred to Nutrition Services for usual care Stable health, with no severe medical comorbidities that might interfere with their ability to participate in an intervention that includes increasing activity or decreasing calories, such as severe psychiatric illness or significant heart disease Have a primary care physician at Partners HealthCare Be able to understand and communicate effectively in English Have a blood glucose meter to self monitor blood glucose Be willing to keep a food, exercise and blood glucose diary Must not be on Byetta (exenatide), Victoza (liraglutide), Bydureon (exenatide extended release), or Symlin (pramlintide) Must not be pregnant or planning pregnancy in the next year Must not be currently seeing a dietitian or participating in a weight loss program Must not have had a weight change of more than 5 pounds in the previous 3 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>