<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03052855</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Suicidal behaviors (SB) are a major health problem in France : 10 000 suicides and 220 000 suicide attempts every year. SB management is therefore a major public health issue. Evidence associated dysregulation of the serotonergic system and the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis to vulnerability to SB. Recent data point to linke these abnormalities with neuroinflammatory clues, glutamatergic function and neuronal plasticity. There is a need to better understand the physiopathology and develop diagnostic and therapeutic tools in SB. The investigators hypothesize that increased peripheral biomarkers of inflammation would correlate to a disturbance of the cerebral metabolites, such as glutamate and NAA, especially in suicidal patients. Our aim is to compare rates of cerebral metabolites, in particular the complex glutamine/glutamate, in cerebral areas involved in suicidal vulnerability (the anterior cingulate cortex and the orbito-frontal cortex) between person with unipolar disorder with and without suicidal attempt.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Inflammatory Biomarkers and Brain Metabolites, a Study Based on Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>69 patients : 23 with suicidal thoughts and attempt, 23 with suicidal thoughts without attempt and 23 healthy volunteers. 2 visits : - Inclusion visit (V0) : (Day 1) o Clinical interview : self and hetero assessment questionnaire - Visit V1 (as soon as possible, day 1 if available) : - MRI (spectroscopy)</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Nonspecific inclusion criteria: Having signed informed consent Able to understand nature, aims and methodology of the study Specific inclusion criteria : Suicidal patient with suicide attempt : Persistent depressive disorder according to the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders V (DSMV) criteria, and evaluated by the Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI) Hamilton Depression Scale &gt; 7 Suicide attempt &lt; 1 week Suicidal patient without suicide attempt : Persistent depressive disorder according to the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders V (DSMV) criteria, and evaluated by the Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI) Hamilton Depression Scale &gt; 7 No history of suicide attempt Healthy volunteers : No psychiatric history No history of suicide attempt Exclusion criteria: Actual somatic, neurological or inflammatory pathology (CReactive Protein &gt; 10mg/L) Traumatic brain injury with loss of consciousness Antibiotic treatment or antiinflammatory treatment Actual toxic abuse according to DSMV (except tobacco and alcohol) Actual or passed history of psychotic disorder Patient on protective measures (guardianship or trusteeship) Deprived of liberty subject (judicial or administrative decision) Pregnant women or breastfeeding Contraindications to MRI scan</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Psychiatry</keyword>
	<keyword>Suicidal behaviour</keyword>
	<keyword>Cerebral metabolites</keyword>
	<keyword>MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammatory markers</keyword>
</DOC>