<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03052075</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to estimate the percent change in baseline bone mineral density (BMD) starting at one year after parathyroidectomy and all the following available dates in patients presenting with primary hyperparathyroidism. The secondary objective is to identify patient factors associated with change in BMD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Percent Change in Baseline Bone Mineral Density (BMD) After Parathyroidectomy in Patients With Primary Hyperparathyroidism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The research plan is for a retrospective review to be performed of a prospectively maintained parathyroid database within the Department of Surgical Oncology at the University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center. The patient cohort for this study consists of all patients with primary hyperparathyroidism who underwent parathyroidectomy and also had pre- and post-operative DEXA studies performed. The database will be reviewed to obtain patient and disease characteristics, laboratory values, DEXA imaging results, and surgical outcomes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hyperparathyroidism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperparathyroidism, Primary</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. The patient cohort for this study consists of all patients within the prospectively maintained parathyroid database within the Department of Surgical Oncology at the University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center. 2. Patients with a diagnosis of primary hyperparathyroidism who underwent parathyroidectomy during the period of September 27, 1990 to December 31, 2013 were considered. 3. All patients who had a preoperative and one year postoperative DEXA study over the time period will be included.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Primary Hyperparathyroidism</keyword>
	<keyword>Parathyroidectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone mineral density</keyword>
	<keyword>BMD</keyword>
	<keyword>Data Review</keyword>
</DOC>