<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03007862</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Early Aspiration Pneumonia is a frequent and dreadful complication in survivors of cardiac arrest. Therapeutic Hypothermia widely used in Intensive Care Unit for its benefice on post cardiac arrest syndrome may otherwise hide signs of early pneumonia that may occur without use of a reliable screening biological marker. The goal is to assess the diagnostic accuracy of bronchial alpha amylase measure to predict a risk of early aspiration pneumonia in patients successfully resuscitated after out-of-hospital cardiac arrest. In this prospective non interventional study we included patients resuscitated after cardiac arrest and treated with Targeted Temperature Management (TTM). A distal bronchoalveolar lavage using specific display (Combi-Cath) was executed immediately after admission for each patient with both biochemic and bacteriological analysis including dosage of bronchial salivary alpha amylase. Urea was used as a marker of dilution in the measure of bronchial and plasmatic alpha amylase. Aspiration pneumonia diagnosis was established with clinical and biological criteria. On this basis we intended to determine a threshold measure of alpha amylase predicting occurrence of aspiration pneumonia and allowing a guidance in antibiotherapy prescription. Sensibility and Specificity of this technique were determined.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bronchial Alpha Amylase as a Marker for Early Aspiration Pneumonia in Therapeutic Hypothermia.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypothermia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Out-of-Hospital Cardiac Arrest</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia, Aspiration</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Well resuscitated patients after outofhospital cardiac arrest Indication of Therapeutic Temperature Management Patients aged over 18 years Immediate or deferred acceptation of study Patients aged under 18 years. Pregnant women. Against indication to therapeutic hypothermia. Active therapeutic limitation after admission. Patient without social security.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>