<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03007173</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Umbilical pilonidal sinus (UPS) is a rare disease of young, hirsute, dark men with deep navels and poor personal hygiene; however, it can be seen in females. UPS could easily be misdiagnosed and mistreated due to its rarity and lack of awareness in physicians. Diagnosis is easy to establish with physical examination and a detailed history. Treatment is generally depending on the severity of the disease, ranging from good personal hygiene to surgical excision of umbilical complex. The treatment of choice for chronic, intermittent cases is surgical removal of the affected portion; paying special attention to cosmetic appearance especially in female patients. In this report, we present two cases of UPS, one in a man and one in a woman with the explanation of its etiopathogenesis and surgical treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Umbilical Pilonidal Sinus: a Case Report</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Introduction: Umbilical pilonidal sinus (UPS) is a rare disease of young, hirsute, dark men with deep navels and poor personal hygiene. It is being diagnosed and reported more frequently; however, there is still no consensus regarding its best treatment options. Presentation of cases: In this report, we present two cases of UPS, one in a man and one in a woman who had typical symptoms with pain, swelling and intermittent malodorous discharge from the umbilicus. They had small sinus openings with hair protruding deep in the navel. Because patients had previous history of failed conservative treatments an umbilicus preserving surgery was performed for both cases.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pilonidal Sinus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urachal Cyst</mesh_term>
	<criteria>no limitation patients followedup less than 2 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>umbilical pilonidal sinus</keyword>
</DOC>