<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01362361</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study: To explore the comparative effectiveness of BIBF 1120 in terms of : - Progression-free survival (PFS), objective response, overall survival - Evaluate and compare safety</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TRICC-C (AIO-KRK-0111): BIBF 1120 Versus Placebo in Patients Receiving Oxaliplatin Plus Fluorouracil and Leucovorin (mFOLFOX6) for Advanced, Chemorefractory Metastatic Colorectal Cancer (mCRC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nintedanib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Histologically proven colorectal adenocarcinoma 2. Intended treatment with mFOLFOX6 after one prior palliative chemotherapy for metastatic CRC 3. Age &gt; 18 years 4. Metastatic disease not suitable for curativeintent surgery 5. Measurable (&gt; 1 cm) and evaluable disease (according to RECIST 1.1 criteria) 6. Prior bevacizumab, cetuximab or panitumumab are allowed. 7. Previous adjuvant oxaliplatincontaining therapy is allowed, if the end of adjuvant chemotherapy is &gt;12 months prior to inclusion into the trial 8. ECOG performance status 0 or 1 (see appendix 10.4) 9. Adequate hepatic function 10. Adequate Renal function 11. Adequate bone marrow function 12. Other lab parameters: proteinuria &lt; CTCAE grade 2, Prothrombin time and/or partial thromboplastin time &lt; 50 % deviation from normal limits 13. Life expectancy at least 3 months 14. Signed and dated written informed consent prior to admission to the study in accordance with ICHGCP guidelines and to the local legislation 1. Known hypersensitivity to the trial drugs or their excipients. 2. Treatment with any investigational drug within 28 days of trial onset. 3. Prior treatment with more than one line of palliative standard chemotherapy for colorectal cancer, prior treatment with a tyrosine kinase inhibitor, prior palliative treatment with an oxaliplatincontaining regime. 4. History of other malignancies in the last 5 years, in particular those which could affect compliance with the protocol or interpretation of results. Patients with adequately treated basal or squamous cell skin cancer are generally eligible. 5. Serious concomitant disease, especially those that would limit compliance with trial requirements or which are considered relevant for the evaluation of the efficacy or safety of the trial drug, such as neurologic, psychiatric, infectious disease or active ulcers (gastrointestinal tract, skin) or laboratory abnormality that may increase the risk associated with trial participation or trial drug administration, and in the judgment of the investigator would make the patient inappropriate for entry into the trial. 6. Major injuries and/or surgery or bone fracture within 4 weeks of trial inclusion, or planned surgical procedures during the trial period. Portimplantation prior to therapy is allowed. 7. Significant cardiovascular diseases (i.e. uncontrolled hypertension, unstable angina, history of infarction within past 9 months, congestive heart failure &gt; NYHA II) (see appendix 10.3). 8. History of severe haemorrhagic or thrombotic events in the past 12 months (excluding central venous catheter thrombosis and peripheral deep vein thrombosis). Known inherited predisposition to bleeds or to thrombosis. 9. Patient with brain metastases that are symptomatic and/or require therapy. 10. Therapeutic anticoagulation (except low dose heparin and/or heparin flush as needed for maintenance of an indwelling intravenous device) or antiplatelet therapy (except for chronic lowdose therapy with acetylsalicylic acid ≤ 325mg per day) 11. History of major thrombotic or clinically relevant major bleeding event in the past 6 months 12. Current peripheral neuropathy ≥ CTCAE grade 2 except due to trauma 13. Serious infections requiring systemic antibiotic (e.g antiviral, antimicrobial, antifungal) therapy 14. Gastrointestinal disorders or abnormalities that would interfere with absorption of the study drug 15. Active alcohol or drug abuse. 16. Women and men who are sexually active and unwilling to use a medically acceptable method of contraception 17. Pregnancy or breastfeeding 18. Leptomeningeal disease 19. Radiographic evidence of cavitary or necrotic tumours 20. Centrally located tumours with radiographic evidence (CT or MRI) of local invasion of major blood vessels 21. Severe chemotherapyassociated toxicity during or after adjuvant or palliative firstline chemotherapy like 5FUassociated cardiac toxicity (coronary spasm) or persistent oxaliplatinassociated peripheral neuropathy (≥ CTCAE grade 2) with paresthesia associated with pain or functional impairment (after adjuvant oxaliplatincontaining chemotherapy).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Second line colorectal cancer</keyword>
</DOC>