<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01781052</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This prospective, non-interventional, multi-center study documents observational data on subjects under routine treatment of Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension, functional class III with inhaled Iloprost administered with I-Neb AAD (Adaptive Aerosol Delivery) device. The observation period for each subject covers a one year treatment period with inhaled Ventavis. For each subject, the investigator or a delegate collects data as defined in the case report form at an initial visit, routine follow-up visit at 6 months and final visit at 12 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Observational Description of Compliance for the Daily Ventavis Use Via the Insight Program in Class III Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Familial Primary Pulmonary Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iloprost</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subjects aged ≥18 years Newly Treated with Ventavis or treated with Ventavis for less than 6 months, with I Neb AAD device for the application, as described in the SmPC (Summary of Product Characteristics), complemented by the Insight With Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension, Group I of the Dana point Pulmonary Hypertension Classification. WHO (World Health Organization) /NYHA (New York Heart Association) Functional class III Able and willing to give written informed consent for participation in the study Key contra indications: Hypersensitivity to the active substance or to any of the excipients. Conditions where the effects of Ventavis on platelets might increase the risk of haemorrhage (e.g. active peptic ulcers, trauma, intracranial haemorrhage). Severe coronary heart disease or unstable angina; Myocardial infarction within the last six months; Decompensated cardiac failure if not under close medical supervision; Severe arrhythmias; Cerebrovascular events (e.g. transient ischaemic attack, stroke) within the last 3 months. Pulmonary hypertension due to venous occlusive disease. Congenital or acquired valvular defects with clinically relevant myocardial function disorders not related to pulmonary hypertension</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Iloprost Compliance</keyword>
</DOC>