<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01781806</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, acceptability and feasibility of delivery of PrEP or PEP as part of combination HIV prevention services for high-risk MSM and transgender women.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Demonstration Project to Add Pre- or Post-exposure Prophylaxis to Combination HIV Prevention Services</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Two community-based sites (Los Angeles Gay and Lesbian Center [LAGLC] and The OASIS Clinic) will serve as facilities at which participants may present for screening for prevention services. At the sites, eligibility criteria will be assessed, HIV, STD and laboratory testing will be performed, and HIV prevention service referrals will be initiated. Follow-up will be on a monthly basis for the first three months, and then de-escalated to an every-3-month interval. The program stratifies participants into two cohorts on the basis of sexual risk behavior: a low-moderate risk cohort (LM) and a high-risk cohort (H). Participants in the LM cohort will be provided a customized prevention package (CPP) including access to post-exposure prophylaxis (PEP) for emergency HIV prevention in the event of unanticipated HIV exposure. Participants in the H cohort will be provided a CPP including daily Truvada-based PrEP. All participants will be followed for 48 weeks. Participants in the LM cohort who, on longitudinal sexual risk behavior surveillance, report increased levels of sexual risk-taking such that they meet enrollment criteria for the H-cohort will be transitioned to the H-cohort. At each follow-up visit, a careful safety assessment will be made, including signs/symptoms and laboratory assessments. STI testing will be performed at 3 month intervals. An escalating-intensity adherence intervention will be implemented based on real-time serum tenofovir levels. A computer-assisted self-interview (CASI) will be used to capture detailed sexual risk, adherence, and substance use behavior.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine, Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 18 years of age Able to understand and provide consent in English or Spanish Self identified MSM, MSM/W, or Transgender (MTF) At least one male sex partner for anal intercourse in the prior 12 months HIV negative by EIA and VL Creatinine clearance ≥ 60 ml/min (via CockcroftGault formula) No signs or symptoms suggestive of primary HIV infection (PHI). Participants &lt;18 years of age Unable to understand and provide consent in English or Spanish Known or found on testing to be HIV positive Any condition, which in the opinion of the intake provider, will seriously compromise the participant's ability to comply with the protocol, including adherence to PEP or PrEP medication dosing Use of Antiretroviral therapy (ART) taken for any indication (i.e. PEP or PrEP) within 60 days of study entry Previous participation in an HIV vaccine trial. Participants that were documented to have received only placebo are not excluded. Signs or symptoms suspicious for PHI.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>