<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02218138</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Type 2 diabetes is a chronic disease that puts people at risk for major health problems like heart disease. Type 2 diabetes is the most common type of diabetes in adults. However, there has been a concerning rise in type 2 diabetes among teenagers. Diabetes develops through poor insulin sensitivity, meaning that insulin - an important chemical the body makes to keep blood sugar normal - isn't working properly. Type 2 diabetes can be prevented by improving insulin sensitivity. Stress is related to insulin sensitivity. Individuals who feel stressed have worse insulin sensitivity than individuals who do not feel stressed. In adults, decreasing stress leads to improvements in insulin sensitivity, but this hasn't been tested in teenagers. The purpose of this study is to find out if taking part in a brief group program to decrease stress will improve insulin sensitivity and lower diabetes risk in teenage girls.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Learning to BREATHE: A Randomized Controlled Trial to Lower Diabetes Risk in Adolescent Girls</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After a screening to determine eligibility, girls are randomly assigned to take part in one of two 6-week group programs: 1) Learning to BREATHE - a mindfulness-based program, or 2) Colorado Blues - a cognitive-behavioral program. After the group, girls return for three follow-up visits over the course of a year. The main outcomes are depressive symptoms and insulin resistance. We also are assessing stress, eating behavior, fitness, and mindfulness.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1217 years Female Overweight or obese, defined as a body mass index (BMI; kg/m2) ≥ 85th percentile for age Family history of type 2 diabetes or prediabetes in 1st degree relative (e.g., parent or sibling) or 2nd degree relative (e.g., aunt, uncle, or grandparent) Elevated stress/symptoms of depression as indicated by a Center for Epidemiological StudiesDepression Scale Total Score ≥ 16 Good general health as reported by adolescent and parent/guardian English speaking (required for adolescent only, because the groups will be conducted in English) Pregnancy Current psychiatric disorder such as major depressive disorder necessitating treatment Type 2 diabetes as indicated by fasting glucose &gt; 126 mg/dL Use of medication affecting insulin resistance, body weight, or mood such as antidepressants or stimulants Current psychotherapy or weight loss treatment</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Adolescent</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Stress</keyword>
</DOC>