<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01799863</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the evolution of the symptoms of acute viral conjunctivitis using preservative free ketorolac trometamol 0.45% associated with carboxymethylcellulose compared with isolated use of preservative-free artificial tears.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Artificial Tears Versus Preservative Free Ketorolac Trometamol 0.45% for Acute Viral Conjunctivitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the evolution of the symptoms of acute viral conjunctivitis using preservative free ketorolac trometamol 0.45% associated with carboxymethylcellulose compared with isolated use of preservative-free artificial tears. A randomized double-masked study will include 60 patients divided into two groups: Group 1: using a formulation of ketorolac tromethamine 0.45% associated with carboxymethylcellulose (Acular CMC®, Allergan, Irvine, USA) and Group 0: using artificial tears (Optive UD®, Allergan, Irvine, USA), both drugs without preservatives.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Conjunctivitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Conjunctivitis, Viral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketorolac</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketorolac Tromethamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lubricant Eye Drops</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboxymethylcellulose Sodium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Acute conjunctivitis (unilateral or bilateral) for less than two weeks, Signs and symptoms consistent with viral conjunctivitis and at least one of the following: preauricular lymphadenopathy, upper tract respiratory infection or recent contact with someone with conjunctivitis pregnant women allergies to nonsteroidal antiinflammatories history of seasonal allergic conjunctivitis contact lens wearers history of ocular herpes infection blepharitis severe dry eye purulent discharge defects in the corneal epithelium</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Conjunctivitis, Viral</keyword>
	<keyword>Ketorolac</keyword>
	<keyword>Artificial tears</keyword>
</DOC>