<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02235298</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Dapagliflozin is a new and emerging anti-diabetes medication. Dapagliflozin is a selective sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitor, reduces hyperglycemia in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) by increasing urinary glucose excretion, and weight loss is a consistent associated finding. Because dapagliflozin increases urinary glucose excretion, weight loss could result from reduced body fat secondary to caloric loss or from fluid loss secondary to osmotic diuresis or from a combination of both factors. Nevertheless, whether Dapaglifozin may cause a reduction in visceral fat is unknown. Hence, in this study the investigators would like to test the hypothesis that Dapaglifozin causes a rapid and significant reduction of the epicardial fat, the visceral fat of the heart, in type 2 diabetic patients. This hypothesis would be tested in a prospective interventional study in 100 overweight or obese type 2 diabetes subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Dapagliflozin on Epicardial Fat in Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>• Type 2 diabetes, as defined by ADA criteria HbA1c ≤ 8% measured at least 1 week prior to the study BMI ≥27 kg/m2 Pretreatment with Metformin as monotherapy Age &gt; 18 and &lt; 70 years old • Known contraindications to Farxiga, in accordance with risks and safety information included in the latest updated Prescribing Information Type 1 diabetes, as defined by American Diabetes Association (ADA) criteria Insulin dependent or treated type 2 diabetes Current use of other SGLT2 inhibitors, GLP 1 analogs or DPP4 inhibitors Glomerular Filtration Rate (GFR) &lt; 60 mL/min/1.73 m2 Patients with poor glycemic control will be excluded to maximize longterm patient retention without need History of diabetes ketoacidosis Clinical signs or symptoms of New York Heart Association (NYHA) class IIIIV heart failure Clinical or laboratory evidences of chronic active liver diseases Acute or chronic infective diseases Cancer or chemotherapy Current use of systemic corticosteroids or in the 3 months prior this study Known or suspected allergy to Dapaglifozin, excipients, or related products Pregnant, breastfeeding or the intention of becoming pregnant Females of childbearing potential who are not using adequate contraceptive methods</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>epicardial fat</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>dapagliflozin</keyword>
</DOC>