<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02780687</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary objective is to investigate the efficacy in terms of 6 month progression free survival (PFS6) and objective response rate (ORR) of afatinib, in patients with advanced/metastatic urothelial tract carcinoma who have progressed despite prior platinum based chemotherapy. Other measures of efficacy include progression free survival (PFS), overall survival (OS), disease control rate (DCR), duration of objective response (DOR), and tumour shrinkage.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Afatinib Monotherapy in Patients With ERBB (Epidermal Growth Factor Family Receptors)-Deregulated Metastatic Urothelial Tract Carcinoma After Failure of Platinum Based Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Urologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Recurrent or metastatic urothelial cancer Patients must have failed prior platinum based treatment (adjuvant or 1st line) Archival tissue sample available for biomarker testing at prescreening and tissue banking. Patients should complete a prescreening biomarker analysis and should fulfill the following: for Cohort A tumour should show a ERBB2 (epidermal growth factor family receptor 2) or ERBB3 mutation, or ERBB2 gene amplification; for Cohort B tumour should show EGFR (Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor) amplification. Further inclusion criteria apply Exclusion criteria: Prior use of EGFR, ERBB2 or ERBB3 targeted treatment Chemotherapy within 4 weeks prior to the start of study treatment. Biological therapy or investigational agents within 4 weeks prior to the start of study treatment or prior to passing 5 halflives, i.e. systemic clearance, whatever comes first Known brain metastases or signs hereof, uncontrolled spinal cord compression or leptomeningeal carcinomatosis Further exclusion criteria apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>