<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02780908</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This project will consist of two studies, each investigating resting and exercise cardio-respiratory responses during exposure to hypoxia in individuals born prematurely and individuals born at full term of two different age groups: Kids (10-14 yrs) and Adults (18-22 yrs).Additional study will be performed on a preterm adult cohort (15 participants) that will investigate potential differences between hypobaric and normobaric hypoxia as outlined in the following section.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cardio-respiratory Responses During Hypoxic Exercise in Individuals Born Prematurely</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study protocol in each age group will comprise two visits to the laboratory testing sessions in a randomized order. On one occasion the participants will perform a resting hypoxia test and a graded exercise test to voluntary exhaustion in normoxic condition ((NORM; fraction of inspired oxygen (FiO2)=0.209, placebo). On a second visit the participants will perform a hypoxia sensitivity test and a graded exercise test to voluntary exhaustion in hypoxic condition (HYPO; FiO2=0.120 corresponding to terrestrial altitude of approx. 4000 m). Indirect calorimetry, near infrared spectroscopy and ECG measurements will be performed throughout all tests. During both testing sessions the participants will also undergo anthropometry measurements and pulmonary function testing. The outline of the research visits is presented in the bellow figure:</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Altitude Sickness</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy male individuals PRETERM group; gestational age: ≤ 32 weeks; gestational weight ≤ 1500 g CONTROL group: full term born individuals ≤ 38 weeks Medication required that may interfere with the interpretation of the results Chronically illnesses Hormonal therapy Recent substandard nutritional status Family history of respiratiory, cardiovascular, renal or hematological disease History of: thyroid dysfunction, renal stones, diabetes, allergies, hypertension, hypocalcaemia, uric acidaemia, lipidaemia or hyperhomocystinaemia History of mental illness Smoker within six months prior to the start of the study Abuse of drugs, medicine or alcohol Participation in another study up to two months before study onset No signed consent form before the onset of the experiment Blood donors in the past three months before the onset of the experiment Vegetarian and Vegans Migraines History of vestibular disorders Claustrophobia</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>