<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02780089</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates the different patterns of care for patients who have unresectable or metastatic melanoma. The dosing, duration, regimen, indication, and treatments will be observed. The survival rate of these patients will also be observed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study in Patients With Unresectable And Metastatic Melanoma: The Optimize Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a non-interventional, observational study with the primary objective to assess and describe "real world" patterns of care in the treatment of patients with unresectable or metastatic melanoma. A sample size of 1,600 prospective patients will provide sufficient information to explore this primary objective. There will be no forced number of patients enrolled into a specific treatment cohort. Setting or controlling specific treatment enrollment cohort counts would invalidate the results of the primary objective of the study. No primary hypothesis is being tested.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Prospective cohort patients: Diagnosis date must occur on or after March 24, 2011 (date of ipilimumab approval in US) Diagnosis of stage III (unresectable) or stage IV melanoma (includes mucosal, uveal acrallentiginous, leptomeningeal disease) Age ≥ 18 years at time of entry into study Patients must be actively receiving or scheduled to receive systemic treatment (any line, eg, first, second, third line [including investigational drugs]). For patients initiating new treatment, treatment must be started within 28 days after signing informed consent. For patients currently receiving treatment, patients must enroll within the first 21 days of starting new treatment Retrospective cohort patients: Patients with diagnosis of confirmed unresectable stage III or stage IV melanoma (including mucosal, uveal, acrallentiginous, leptomeningeal disease) Age ≥ 18 years at time of unresectable or metastatic melanoma diagnosis Initiated therapy for unresectable or metastatic melanoma within 4 years prior to approval of ipilimumab (first immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy approved in US) March 25, 2007 March 24, 2011 One year of followup data is required from date of therapy initiation, if a patient passed away within the one year of followup; such patients are still eligible and the date of death will be collected. 1. If retrospective patients have at least one year of followup data and are then treated with immunooncology, immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy, or targeted therapy, these patients will be analyzed separately. Prospective patients: Patients participating in a clinical study that does not allow enrollment into a non interventional study or clinical studies in which the investigational treatment is blinded Patients who started new treatment &gt; 21 days Patients who enrolled in study but did not initiate treatment before 28 days Patients with current malignancies (except nonmelanoma skin cancer and the following in situ cancers: bladder, gastric, colon, endometrial, cervical/dysplasia, melanoma, or breast) that requires additional systemic therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic</keyword>
	<keyword>Unresectable</keyword>
</DOC>