<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02780414</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Preeclampsia (Pre-E) is a hypertensive disease of pregnancy with multi-system involvement that usually occurs in the second half of pregnancy. Pre-E occurs in 5% to 7% of U.S. pregnancies, and is the third-leading cause of U.S. maternal death. Improvements to the current diagnostic paradigm have been evaluated. However, no stand-alone diagnostic method has emerged that more accurately identifies women at risk for preeclampsia, warranting improvements in diagnosing Pre-E. This sample collection study will obtain serum and urine samples from pregnant women who present with clinical signs, symptoms, or conditions contributing to the suspicion of Pre-E. Samples will be used to evaluate and validate the performance of an assay intended to aid in assessing the risk of Pre-E.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Collection of Samples From Pregnant Women for the Evaluation of Preeclampsia (Pre-E) Biomarkers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Eligible subjects will provide written informed consent after which demographic and baseline clinical data will be recorded. Collection of whole blood and urine samples will be performed at one or more clinic visits from pregnant women carrying a single fetus with no known fetal abnormalities. Interim study visits will continue every 14 days [+/- 3 days] until the subject either: 1) reaches 37 0/7 weeks' gestation, 2) develops Pre-E, 3) delivers, or 4) is lost to follow-up. In addition, a group of pregnant women diagnosed with Pre-E will be enrolled as positive control cases.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thrombocytopenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Proteinuria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Edema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Eligibility criteria for the STUDY COHORT (CASES and NEGATIVE PREE CONTROLS): Subject is willing to provide informed consent and comply with study procedures 18 to 45 years of age Singleton fetus of 28 0/7 to 36 6/7 weeks' gestational age using the 2014 American Congress of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (ACOG) Dating Criteria (pregnancies starting as twins but complicated with either vanishing twin syndrome or fetal demise of one twin before 14 weeks, are eligible for inclusion) Patient presenting with clinical suspicion of PreE based on either: New onset elevated blood pressure in otherwise normotensive patient, worsening hypertension in a patient with preexisting hypertension, new onset proteinuria or worsening of preexisting proteinuria, or any other clinical finding requiring a workup to ruleout PreE. Pregnancy is nonviable or absence of fetal cardiac activity Diagnosis of PreE or anticipated delivery within 24 to 48 hours because of PreE with severe features including: persistent severe hypertension (systolic ≥160 or diastolic ≥110; thrombocytopenia &lt;100,000; liver enzymes 2x above upper normal limit or &gt;70 with severe persistent right upper quadrant (RUQ) or epigastric pain, new development of renal insufficiency; pulmonary edema; newonset persistent cerebral or visual disturbances. Major fetal anomaly or chromosomal aneuploidy Current dialysis for kidney failure, including continuous ambulatory peritoneal dialysis Eligibility criteria for the POSITIVE CONTROL group: Subject is willing to provide informed consent and comply with study procedures 18 to 45 years of age Singleton fetus of 28 0/7 to 36 6/7 weeks' gestational age using 2014 ACOG Dating Criteria (pregnancies starting as twins but complicated with either vanishing twin syndrome or fetal demise of one twin before 14 weeks, are eligible for inclusion) Patient diagnosed with PreE using 2013 ACOG guidelines Pregnancy is nonviable or absence of cardiac activity Major fetal anomaly or chromosomal aneuploidy Current dialysis for kidney failure, including continuous ambulatory peritoneal dialysis</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Proteinuria</keyword>
	<keyword>Thrombocytopenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal Insufficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Impaired Liver Function</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulmonary Edema</keyword>
</DOC>