<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00146016</DOC>
	<brief_summary>* Adding Amantadine to standard anti-viral treatment can improve sustained response rates in patients with chronic hepatitis C</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study on Chronic Hepatitis C Treatment With Interferon Alpha, Ribavirin and Amantadine in Naive Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The CIRA-study is a double blind, placebo controlled, randomised, multicentre study in previously untreated patients suffering from chronic hepatitis C comparing double therapy, consisting of (PEG-)interferon alpha 2b ((PEG)Intron-A®) and ribavirin (Rebetol®), with triple therapy, consisting of (PEG-)interferon alpha 2b, ribavirin and amantadine, for 52 weeks. Follow-up is completed at week 104. 150 Subjects per treatment group will be included. Patients will be stratified before randomisation according to genotype (1 versus non-1). Viral load will not be a discriminating factor. The aim is to investigate the efficacy of the adjunct amantadine to the currently used combination therapy with interferon alpha and ribavirin.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amantadine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
	<criteria>AntiHCV positivity &gt;6 months ALT and/or AST elevation on at least once in the previous 6 months Positive HCVRNA Liver biopsy within one year before the start of therapy in non cirrhosis. In the case of known cirrhosis, liver biopsy is not necessary Intention to be treated and participate treatment Obtained written informed consent Age &lt; 18 years Pregnancy or intention to get pregnant within the 12 months period of treatment and up to 6 months after discontinuation of therapy, no adequate contraception, lactation Men not practicing or willing to practice acceptable methods of contraception during the treatment period and up to 6 months after discontinuation of therapy Life expectancy &lt; 1 year Child Pugh B or C (Appendix III) Creatinine &gt; 150 μmol/L or &gt; 1.70 mg/dl Haemoglobulin &lt; 6.5 mmol/l or &lt; 10.5 g/dl White blood cell count &lt; 2,5 x 109/L, neutrophil &lt; 1,5 x 109/L Platelet count &lt; 70 x 109/L HIV positivity Chemotherapy, systematical antiviral treatment during the 6 months prior to study entry Other serious disease (e.g. malignancy, uncontrolled myocardial disease or severe arrhythmias) Active uncontrolled psychiatric disorders and suicidal leanings Patients with a history of uncontrolled seizure or other significant CNS dysfunction Any condition which in the opinion of the (co)investigator might interfere with the evaluation of the study objectives</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2005</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Hepatitis C</keyword>
	<keyword>Amantadine</keyword>
	<keyword>Triple therapy</keyword>
</DOC>