<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00146588</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out what effects (good and bad) a combination of cytoxan, epirubicin, and capecitabine have on women with Stage II/II/IIIA breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cytoxan, Epirubicin and Capecitabine in Women With Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>- Each treatment cycle lasts 21 days and patients will participate in a least 4 cycles, but no more than 6 cycles of treatment. - Patients will receive cytoxan (cyclophosphamide) and epirubicin intravenously on day 1 of each treatment cycle. On days 4-17 of each cycle, patients will take capecitabine orally twice a day. - While on the study patients will be required to complete a diary of they capecitabine treatment. - Blood tests will be performed each week along with surveys at the beginning of the trial and certain follow-up visits to evaluate the patient's experience with the oral chemotherapy. - Patients will be on the treatment for 12-18 weeks depending upon whether or not the disease progresses or the patient develops inacceptable side effects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epirubicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed Stage IIII breast cancer. If Stage I, should be deemed of sufficiently high risk of developing recurrent disease to warrant participation. 18 years of age or older ANC &gt; 1,000/mm3 Platelet count &gt; 100,000/mm3 Hemoglobin &gt; 10 Creatinine &lt; 2.0 SGOT &lt; 2 x ULN Bilirubin &lt; 1.5mg/dl Able to swallow and retain oral medication LVEF greater than or equal to 50% ECOG performance status of 0 or 1 Pregnant or lactating Prior malignancy within 5 years (excluding squamous or basal cell skin cancers) Prior chemotherapy within 5 years Prior anthracycline therapy Serious comorbid physical or psychological condition</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>cytoxan</keyword>
	<keyword>epirubicin</keyword>
	<keyword>capecitabine</keyword>
</DOC>