<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02353845</DOC>
	<brief_summary>One purpose of this study is to construct the diagnosis system for early Alzheimer's disease(AD), which is also called amnestic mild cognitive impairment (aMCI), and then further construct the predictable classifier from aMCI to AD based on Multi-Modality MRI characteristics of aMCI patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Construction of Diagnosis System for Early AD Based on Multi-Modality MRI Technology</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The cognition of aMCI is between normal aging and dementia, which is thought the transitional stage of dementia. Patients with aMCI have heavy risk to convert to AD, so in this study, the investigators focus on the construction of the diagnosis system for early AD based on multi-modality MRI characteristics of aMCI patients. Every patient underwent β-Amyloid PET, fluorodeoxyglucose-PET(FDG-PET), structural MRI, diffusion tensor imaging and functional MRI. Then investigators further study the patients who convert to AD and explore their MRI and metabolism characteristics on baseline, in order to construct the predictable classifier from aMCI to AD. The investigators want to achieve the early diagnosis of AD and help clinicians interfere with the progress of this disease.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Memory loss complaint and confirmed by an informant Cognitive impairment in single or multiple domains, adjusted for age and education Normal or nearnormal performance on general cognitive function and no or minimum impairment of daily life activities A Clinical Dementia Rating (CDR) score is 0.5 and consistent with the boundary of neuropsychological scale Failure to meet the criteria for dementia Must be able to accept examination of MRI, sight and hearing allow to complete test Right handedness Other diseases that cause cognitive impairment, such as thyroid disease, stroke and so on People who have severe visual and hearing impairment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>