<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02147106</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Rationale: Patients with neuroendocrine tumors (NET) have a rare disease. Due to treating patients with a neuroendocrine tumor in 'NET knowledge centers' patients often have to travel long distances for follow-up visits at the outpatient clinic. Patients whose medical condition allows videoconsultation could save time by replacing outpatient clinic visits through videoconsultation for receiving follow-up care. Therefore, in this study we aim to introduce videoconsultation as a alternative for follow-up outpatient clinic visits in NET patients. Objective: The primary objective is to assess if use of videoconsultation in follow-up care for NET patients is feasible. We hypothesize that videoconsultation is a suitable medium for providing follow-up care in NET patients. Secondary objectives are to explore the amount of time videoconsultation takes in comparison with outpatient clinic visits and the acceptability and satisfaction of physicians and patients with using videoconsultation in follow-up care. Study design: The present study is a single-centre prospective feasibility study. Study population: Adult NET patients under surveillance or treatment of the department Medical Oncology at the University Medical Centre Groningen (UMCG) whose medical condition allows videoconsultation will be invited to participate. Intervention: Patient who give informed consent will participate in the study. Participants will receive follow-up care through videoconsultation instead of conventional visits at the outpatient clinic. Main study parameters/endpoints: The main endpoint is the feasibility of videoconsultation for follow-up care in NET patients. We hypothesize that videoconsultation is a suitable medium for providing follow-up care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of Video Consultation in Follow-up Care for Patients With a Neuroendocrine Tumor: a Feasibility Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neuroendocrine Tumors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoid Tumor</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed informed consent Age ≥ 18 yrs Grade I or II (low and intermediate grade) NET with any primary tumor type or disease stage Have access to required equipment/technology for performing videoconsultation Newly referred NET patients, who are visiting the department of Medical Oncology at the UMCG for the first time Recently diagnosed NET patients, who are in the diagnostic phase of the disease NET patients who frequently require blood tests, consultation or physical examination A hearing or visual impairment, which would make videoconsultation difficult</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neuroendocrine tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>Videoconsultation</keyword>
	<keyword>Feasibility</keyword>
</DOC>