<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02147015</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The hypothesis is that in acute exacerbated Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (AECOPD), personalized variable dose glucocorticoid treatment will result in superior clinical outcome when compared to fixed or experiential dose therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Personalized Variable Versus Experiential or Fixed Dose Glucocorticoid Therapy in AECOPD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Treatment with glucocorticoid for acute exacerbations of COPD results in the improvement of clinical outcomes. However, the optimal doses of glucocorticoid for each individual patient has not been determined. According to GOLD Report 2014, a dose of 40 mg prednisone per day for 5 days is recommended (Evidence B), although there are insufficient data to provide firm conclusions concerning the optimal duration of corticosteroid therapy of acute exacerbations of COPD. The purpose of the current study is to compare clinical outcomes of personalized or fixed or experiential dose of glucocorticoid in patients with acute exacerbations of COPD.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibiotics, Antitubercular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucocorticoids</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Muscarinic Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Exacerbation of COPD as defined by the presence of at least 2 of the following: change in baseline dyspnea, cough, or sputum quantity or purulence. Signs of severe exacerbation (arterial pH &lt; 7.26 or PaCO2 &gt; 9.3 kPa) History of asthma Significant or unstable comorbidity Participated in another study 4 weeks before admission Previously randomized to this study Known hypersensitivity to prednisolone Inability to give written informed consent Radiological diagnosis of pneumonia Estimated survival of less than 6 months due to severe comorbidity Use of glucocorticoid within 1 month before admission</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute Exacerbations</keyword>
	<keyword>Corticosteroids</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Doses</keyword>
</DOC>