<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02147093</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A comparative evaluation of a newly marketed multifocal contact lens with a single vision contact lens when used with near vision spectacles. The evaluation was to quantify the difference between the two test corrections.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CLARITI (TM) 1-Day Multifocal Contact Lenses Performance and Acceptance Evaluation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Presbyopia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 45 years or more 2. Spectacle or soft contact lens wearer 3. Refraction: best sphere (corrected for back vertex distance) 6.00 Diopters (D) to +4.00 D; Astigmatism 0.00 D to 0.75 D; Near addition for 40 cm; Medium Add: +1.50 D to +2.00 D; High Add: +2.25 D to +2.50 D 4. Best spectacle corrected visual acuity of 6/9 or better in each eye 5. Willingness to adhere to the instructions set forth in the clinical protocol 6. Signature of the subject Informed Consent form after review of Information to Participant document. 1. Systemic or ocular allergies which might interfere with contact lens wear 2. Systemic disease which might interfere with contact lens wear 3. Ocular disease which might interfere with contact lens wear (e.g. hypothesia, insufficient lacrimal secretion) 4. Use of medication which might interfere with contact lens wear 5. Active ocular infection 6. Use of ocular medication 7. Significant ocular anomaly 8. Presence of two or more corneal scars in either eye 9. Monovision contact lens wearers 10. Pregnancy or lactation 11. Any medical condition that might be prejudicial to the study 12. Participants nonable to give consent or from a vulnerable group 13. Infectious disease (for example, hepatitis, tuberculosis, etc.) or a contagious immunosuppressive disease (such as HIV, AIDS, etc.) 14. Employees or family member of the investigational clinic (e.g. investigator, coordinator, technician)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>