<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01397838</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Recent studies have shown that inhibition of Aquaporine-9 channels may ameliorate the bone degradation process. Pro-bone is an AQ - 9 channels inhibitor. This study is design to evaluate the safety of Pro-bone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of an Oral Pro-boneTM, Administered to Post Menopausal Osteopenic Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Bone Diseases, Metabolic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>BMD as measured by DEXA at screening, should range between (1)to (2.5) SD from normal values. At least 12 months of spontaneous amenorrhea or at least 6 weeks postsurgical bilateral oophorectomy with or without hysterectomy. Study participants not taking estrogen alone or estrogen/progestin containing drug products. Study participants not taking any antiosteoporosis treatment for at list one year. The following washout periods should be before baseline assessments are made for subjects previously on estrogen alone or estrogen/progestin containing products: 1. 8 weeks or longer for any prior use of estrogen and/or progestin products. 2. 6 months or longer for prior progestin injectable drug therapy. 3. Women between 45 and 65 years (inclusive) of age. 4. BMI 2230 (inclusive) 5. Nonsmoking (by declaration) for a period of at least 6 months. 6. Subjects able to adhere to the visit schedule and protocol requirements and be available to complete the study. Subjects who provide written informed consent. Women have documentation of a positive screening mammogram (obtained at screening or within 9 months of study enrolment) or abnormal clinical breast examination prior to enrolment in clinical studies. Known history of significant medical disorder, which in the investigator's judgment contraindicates administration of the study medications. Any clinically significant abnormality, upon physical examination or in clinical laboratory test, at screening visit. Known history of drug or alcohol abuse according to participant declaration at screening visit. Any acute medical situation (e.g. acute infection) within 48 hours of study start, which is considered of significance by the Principal Investigator. Subjects who are noncooperative or unwilling to sign consent form.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Osteopenia</keyword>
</DOC>