<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01157247</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background and Objectives: Spinal puncture is painful procedure which may cause patient refusal of spinal anesthesia in future surgery. It could be minimized with topical and infiltration local anesthetic or intravenous opioid application before procedure. Objective was efficacy of intravenous fentanyl in alleviating pain during spinal needle insertion. Methods: Prospective, randomized study included 88 adults (33-55 ages, ASA I/II), scheduled for lower leg surgery. Patients were divided in four equal study groups: spinal needle (Quincke, 26G) with introducer (20G) was inserted alone, three minutes after local anesthetic infiltration (2 ml of 2% lidocaine, 25Gx11/4" needle) or intravenous fentanyl application (0.001 mg kg-1) and without local anesthetic, fentanyl and introducer. Pain was assessed immediately after procedure by VAS score. MAP, HR and SaO2 were recorded. Sedation was assessed by Ramsay score. Statistical analysis was performed by SPSS 11.0.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intravenous Fentanyl or Local Anesthetic Infiltration for Pain Reducing During Spinal Needle Insertion</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics, Local</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults ASA I or II status Scheduled for trauma or orthopedic surgeries of lower leg in spinal anesthesia Patients with scoliosis Degenerative spine deformity A history of back surgery or back pain Pregnancy Perence of coagulopathy Systemic or local infection Allergy to amidelocal anesthetics Neurologic damages and mental disability More than one spinal puncture attempt Patient who was unable to estimate pain score High Ramsay sedation score</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anesthetic techniques</keyword>
	<keyword>regional, spinal</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>lumbar puncture</keyword>
	<keyword>Analgesia, local</keyword>
	<keyword>Analgesia, intravenous</keyword>
</DOC>