<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01805544</DOC>
	<brief_summary>National, multicenter, prospective, observational, non-interventional study. The objective is to determine if the switch from Vitamin K antagonists (VKA) to Xarelto in subjects treated with VKA with issues in deep venous thrombosis (DVT), and prevention of recurrent DVT and pulmonary embolism (PE) is associated with an improvement of the treatment satisfaction after 3 months. The treatment satisfaction will be measured by the Anti Clot Treatment Scale (ACTS) score.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Satisfaction/Quality of Life With Rivaroxaban in DVT (Deep Venous Thrombosis) Indication</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female or male subject ≥ 18 years of age, With a diagnosis of acute DVT treated with VKA with issues for at least the 4 previous weeks (issues are assessed on medical judgment) Who intends to start rivaroxaban for treatment of deep vein thrombosis (DVT), and prevention of recurrent DVT and pulmonary embolism (PE) following an acute DVT With anticoagulation therapy planned for at least 3 months Contra indication to the use of Xarelto as described in the Summary of Product Characteristics (SmPC); key contra indications are: Hypersensitivity to the active substance or to any of the excipients listed in SmPC section 6.1. Lesion or condition at significant risk of major bleeding Concomitant treatment with any other anticoagulant agent Clinically significant active bleeding Hepatic disease associated with coagulopathy and clinically relevant bleeding risk including cirrhotic patients with Child Pugh B and C Pregnancy and breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>SF36 questionnaire</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti Clot Treatment Scale</keyword>
	<keyword>Satisfaction</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
	<keyword>Rivaroxaban</keyword>
	<keyword>Prevention &amp; control</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulmonary embolism</keyword>
</DOC>