<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01805674</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In menopause, the vasomotor symptomatology, accompanied or less by affective and behavioural symptoms, globally worsens the quality of daily life. The improvement of the quality could be reached with adequate food supplements, named phytoestrogens, in particular Soy Isoflavones (SI), which are natural substances with estrogen-like and estrogen-antagonistic activity, which are active in the control of menopausal vasomotor symptoms. Besides, combined with magnolia extract it could improve the psychological symptomatology also improving the quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Isoflavones and Magnolia Extract in the Quality of Life in Menopausal Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Multicenter, observational, prospective, longitudinal study of clinical practice conducted in 10 gynecological centers. The study will be conducted in patients with typical mild to moderate vasomotor symptoms and psycho symptoms such as mood disorders, or sleep, anxiety / depression, which do not require specific drug treatment. Quality of life will be analyzed by the scale of Cervantes.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Women with at least 12 months of amenorrhea Presence of 1 or more vasomotor symptoms as hot flushing, nocturnal sweating or palpitations One or more psychological symptoms as insomnia, irritability, anxiety, depressed mood. Also with concomitant symptoms of sexual area as reduction of libido and vaginal dryness. Women must give the informed consent clinical history of medical or surgical pathologies that could affect the results of the study, including serious cardiovascular, metabolic, kidney or liver diseases Patients with the habit of eating soy foods or dietary supplements with soy extract patients diagnosed with breast or uterine mass (neoplasia hormone sensitive) patients that were treated with estrogens (HRT or phytoestrogens)in the 2 months before the beginning of the study. patients with treatment with antibiotics, antidepressant and/or anxiolytic products</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>59 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>menopause</keyword>
	<keyword>quality of life</keyword>
	<keyword>soy isoflavones</keyword>
	<keyword>magnolia extract</keyword>
</DOC>