<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01084135</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if short term use of rivastigmine can improve functional abilities (for example, language, memory, and executive function) in adolescents with Down syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rivastigmine Study in Adolescents With Down Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This 24 week, double-blind, placebo controlled trial will be completed at the Clinical Research Unit of Duke University Medical Center and at the Kennedy Krieger Institute (KKI). Sixteen evaluable subjects will be enrolled at Duke and 24 evaluable subjects will be enrolled at KKI. The study consists of four visits, a screening visit (-4 weeks), a baseline visit (week 0); a safety visit at week 10, and a final/termination visit at week 20. The specific aims of this study are to: a) investigate efficacy of rivastigmine tartrate treatment; b) build upon our open-label treatment results of overall function and language improvement in adolescents with Down syndrome (DS) in a double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial; and c) investigate other specific cognitive domains that may selectively respond to rivastigmine tartrate treatment. The original IRB-approved protocol included the Parent/Caregiver Rating Form of the Vineland Adaptive Behavior Scales- Second Edition (VABS-II) . The protocol was amended to replace the Parent/Caregiver Rating Form of the Vineland Adaptive Behavior Scales- Second Edition (VABS-II) with the Vineland Adaptive Behavior Scales, Second Edition, Survey Interview Form. The protocol was also amended to extend the trial from 12 weeks to 20 weeks. Due to the changes in the amended protocol the subject enrolled prior to the IRB amendment will not be included in the data analysis section.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Down Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivastigmine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Correct VERBAL responses for 7/9 of the Expressive One Word Picture Vocabulary Test items. 2. Subject able to put at least 23 words together in conversational speech. 3. Subject's speech is understandable to the examiner for the majority of the time. 4. Subjects are in good health and medically stable 1. Subject uses sign language as a primary means of communication 2. Subject has a medical history that contraindicate the use of rivastigmine (For example, patients with active seizure disorders, asthma, celiac disease, heart disease or heart rhythm disorders).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Clinical trial</keyword>
	<keyword>Down syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>adolescents</keyword>
	<keyword>cognitive</keyword>
	<keyword>rivastigmine</keyword>
</DOC>