<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00112099</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the role of splenectomy in potentially curative total gastrectomy for proximal gastric carcinoma in terms of survival benefit and post-operative morbidity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>GCSSG-SPNX: Trial to Evaluate Splenectomy in Total Gastrectomy for Proximal Gastric Carcinoma: JCOG0110</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>European clinical trials of gastrectomy showed that splenectomy is an important risk factor for post-operative morbidity and mortality. Retrospective comparisons suggested that splenectomy is associated with poor long term survival. However, Japanese studies revealed that 20 - 30 % of patients with non-early carcinoma in the proximal stomach have nodal metastasis in the splenic hilum and therefore, pancreas-preserving splenectomy is part of the standard operation in specialized centers where splenectomy is not considered a risk factor for operative mortality. There have been no prospective randomized trials to evaluate the survival benefit of splenectomy in total gastrectomy for proximal gastric cancer. Comparison: Total gastrectomy with pancreas-preserving splenectomy versus total gastrectomy without splenectomy</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Preoperatively Histologically proven adenocarcinoma T2 or deeper lesion in the upper third of the stomach without involvement of the greater curvature or esophageal invasion, irrespective of the primary tumor location or existence of multiple foci No distant metastasis, not linitis plastica ('Borrmann 4'), not stump carcinoma, no prior treatment for 364 Randomized trial for splenectomy gastric cancer Sufficient organ function Written informed consent. Intraoperatively T2/T3/T4 and N0/N1/N2, no tumor on the greater curvature, no direct invasion of the pancreas or spleen, negative peritoneal lavage cytology No apparent nodal metastasis in the splenic hilum or along the splenic artery Liver cirrhosis or portal hypertension Idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura Severe pulmonary dysfunction Synchronous or metachronous (within 5 years) malignancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>gastric neoplasm</keyword>
	<keyword>gastrectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>splenectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>randomized trial</keyword>
	<keyword>T2, T3 and T4 carcinoma in the proximal third of the stomach</keyword>
</DOC>