<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02934360</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The TR(ACE) Assay is a quantitative in vitro diagnostic test run on the TR(ACE) Instrument intended for the measurement of high molecular weight human DNA from plasma as an aid to monitoring disease progression or response to therapy or recurrent or residual disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TR(ACE) Assay Clinical Specimen Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is to establish the clinical performance of the TR(ACE) Assay. Deltas of serial TR(ACE) Assay measurements will be compared to the standard of care physician clinical assessment and RECIST 1.1 criteria evaluation relative to the previous visit. Significant changes in serial TR(ACE) Assay measurements are hypothesized to correlate with disease progression or response.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Nonsmall cell lung: Male or Female Adult patient &gt;= 21 years old Breast only: Female Adult patient &gt;= 21 years old Previously diagnosed with one of the following cancers: Breast or Nonsmall Cell Lung Cancer has progressed to at least Stage III or higher for lung cancer or, Cancer has progressed to stage IV (metastatic) breast cancer Participating in standard of care cancer therapy requiring frequent treatments, typically intravenous chemotherapy visits (or as determined by the standard of care for the particular cancer assessed), of a minimum of three (3) treatment visits planned in 9 months from date of enrollment where a clinical assessment will be conducted Physician assessment that obtaining two extra whole blood specimens with minimum volume of 5 mL per treatment visit is contraindicated Stage I and II Nonsmall Cell Lung Cancer Stage I through III breast cancer Pregnant or planning to become pregnant during the course of the study Unable to obtain informed consent from subject or their legal representative Life expectancy is less than 9 months Presence of one or more of the following other chronic diseases Another type of cancer except for nonmelanomatous skin tumors Autoimmune disease requiring DMARDS or Biologics Infectious disease requiring prolonged intravenous antibiotics or hospitalization Renal disease specifically those in End Stage Renal Failure Recent (&lt; 3 weeks) major trauma or major surgical procedure(s) or radiation therapy prior to enrollment in the study Recent (&lt; 2 months) major occlusive arterial event such as MI or CVA prior to enrollment in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>cell free DNA</keyword>
	<keyword>biomarker</keyword>
</DOC>