<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02934009</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The determination of fluid status in dialysis patients is a major clinical problem. In this study the NMR-MOUSE is used to determine if it can be used to non-invasively determine hydration status of the skin. This evaluation will be performed in dialysis patients and healthy volunteers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dermal Profile Analysis Using the NMR-MOUSE</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Excretion of urine is impaired in terminal chronic kidney disease patients often requiring dialysis. Fluid management of dialysis patients is solely based on body weight differences before and after dialysis. Patients can suffer from either hypotension if too much fluid is eliminated by dialysis or from fluid-overload symptom (e.g. shortness of breath, edema) if not enough fluid is eliminated. In this study a mobile non-invasive NMR-MOUSE setup (a nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy measurement) is used to measure the hydration status of the skin.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypotension</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1880 Dialysis ability to perform NMRmeasurement Eligibility to sign informed consent signed informed consent implanted cardiac device implanted cranial device implanted cochlea device intrauterine device other metallic implants tattoo, any skin disease or scars from surgery (in the area of measurement) previous skin treatment with cosmetics (of any kind) 24 hours prior to measurement wearing of earrings, piercings or hearingsaids during measurement participation in other clinical trials 30 days prior to participation in the SHN study no written informed consent any conditions, as determined by the examiner, that excludes the patient from participation in the study subjects with legal guardian pregnancy or lactation (a possible pregnancy of a participant before menopause will be excluded before inclusion in the study) subjects under employment or with any relation to the the sponsor or the investigator participation in any other study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>