<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01623180</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate that a BioFreedom™ Drug Coated Stent is non-inferior to a bare metal stent at one year as measured by the composite safety endpoint of cardiovascular death, myocardial infarction and definite/probable stent thrombosis, and that its efficacy is superior to a bare metal stent as measured by clinically driven TLR at one year.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomized Clinical Evaluation of the BioFreedom™ Stent</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angina, Stable</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Restenosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Any indication for PCIS in patients deemed at high risk for bleeding and candidates for 1 month DAPT. This includes candidates with stable angina, silent ischemia, ACS (STEMI and nonSTEMI), nonnative lesions and instent restenosis. Patients must provide written informed consent. 1. Pregnancy 2. Patients expected not to comply with 1 month DAPT 3. Patients requiring a planned staged PCI procedure more than one week after the index procedure 4. Procedure planned to require nonstudy stents, or stand alone POBA or standalone atherectomy 5. Active bleeding at the time of inclusion 6. Reference vessel diameter &lt;2.25 &gt;4.0mm 7. Cardiogenic shock 8. Compliance with longterm single antiplatelet therapy unlikely 9. A known hypersensitivity or contraindication to aspirin, clopidogrel (or prasugrel, or ticagrelor if applicable), stainless steel, Biolimus A9 or a sensitivity to contrast media, which cannot be adequately premedicated. 10. Participation in another clinical trial (12 months after index procedure).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>DES</keyword>
	<keyword>coronary stent</keyword>
	<keyword>bare metal stent</keyword>
	<keyword>high bleeding</keyword>
	<keyword>MI</keyword>
	<keyword>angina</keyword>
</DOC>