<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02594943</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Endodrill is a new instrument for biopsy sampling in the GI-channel. The purpose of this study is as follows: - Compare the Endodrill instrument with conventional biopsy forceps in terms of ability to establish the correct diagnosis of diffuse gastric cancer based on collected biopsies from tumor tissue.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Endodrill vs. Conventional Biopsy. Evaluation of Diagnostic Capacity in Diffuse Gastric Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Endodrill is a newly constructed biopsy tool for flexible endoscopic use. It uses a drilling motion within a casing to harvest solid biopsies from tissue through the biopsy channel of a conventional flexible endoscope. It was originally designed for sampling of tissue from submucosal lesions. The investigators´ first study of the instrument is now finished. Endodrill is safe to use and generates more submucosal tissue compared to biopsies with a conventional biopsy forceps. In this study, the investigators want to compare the Endodrill instrument´s ability to obtain representative tissue samples from a group of patients diagnosed with or suspected diffuse gastric cancer. 20 patients will be enrolled for this study. For each patient the investigators will collect 8 biopsies, 4 biopsies each with conventional biopsy and the Endodrill instrument respectively. The order will be randomized for each patient. For each specific biopsy the investigator will choose a particular site on the suspected tumor tissue without knowing which instrument that will be used for the biopsy. This procedure will be repeated for all 8 biopsies.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with suspected or with an established diagnosis of diffuse gastric cancer who are capable of stating a formal consent to participate in the study. Mental illness Extreme comorbidity (ASA&gt;3)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diagnostics</keyword>
	<keyword>Biopsy</keyword>
	<keyword>Diffuse gastric cancer</keyword>
</DOC>