<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02594436</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective, non-interventional study of adult patients prescribed topical treatment with ingenol mebutate gel (Picato速) as part of provision of care for the treatment of Non-hyperkeratotic, non-hypertrophic Actinic Keratosis (AK). Patients with complete clearance at 8 weeks will be followed for one year or until retreatment of AK in the area initially treated, whatever comes first. For patients with incomplete clearance in the treated area at 8 weeks the treatment strategy for this area will be recorded but no further follow-up will take place. The effectiveness, tolerability, adherence, patient satisfaction and health-related quality of life (HRQoL) associated with Picato速 treatment will be evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Use of Picato速 (Ingenol Mebutate) to Treat Actinic Keratosis in Standard Clinical Practice</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Actinic Keratosis (AK) is caused by exposure to UV radiation and has the potential to regress to normal skin or to progress to squamous cell carcinoma. Ingenol mebutate gel is a relatively new topical treatment option for AK in Greece. Taking into consideration the limited real-world evidence that is attributed to the recent advent of Picato in the Greek market, this non-interventional observational study aims primarily at assessing the characteristics of patients selected for this treatment, the effectiveness and tolerability of the treatment, patient satisfaction and the impact of the therapy on patients' HRQoL in standard clinical practice.The study will be carried out by approximately 30 physicians practicing in private or public hospitals and clinics in representative geographical regions of Greece.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Keratosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Keratosis, Actinic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Planned to receive topical ingenol mebutate gel for treatment of Actinic Keratosis according to current labelling in Greece. Written informed consent obtained to use the patient's data for the study. Contraindications according to prescribing information. Previous treatment with PICATO in the selected treatment area.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Actinic Keratosis</keyword>
	<keyword>topical</keyword>
	<keyword>ingenol mebutate</keyword>
	<keyword>Picato速</keyword>
</DOC>