<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01592656</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this multicenter study the comparison of the mass flow distribution and redistribution versus the relative blood flow per lobe (as a surrogate for Ventilation/ Perfusion (V/Q) matching) with functional respiratory imaging (FRI) and arterial blood gas (ABG) values will be evaluated in hypercapnic Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) patients. Therefore a low dose Computed Tomography (CT) scan will be taken in a population of 30 patients with non-invasive ventilation (NIV) and in a control group of 10 patients without NIV. The CT-scan will be used for FRI.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-term Effects of Non-invasive Ventilation in Hypercapnic Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypercapnia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: ≥ 40 years old Men and women Written informed consent obtained COPD patients GOLD II, III and IV Persisting hypercapnia (pCO2 &gt; 45 mmHg ) notwithstanding adequate treatment modalities (including oxygen) as proposed by the GOLD guidelines Stopped smoking Total lung capacity (TLC) &gt; 85% Treatment with home NIV or Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) Asthma Restrictive lung disease Symptomatic or uncontrolled heart failure Current malignancy Suspected bad compliance for NIV treatment Pregnant women Not be able to speak the language of the participating center Received an investigational product within 4 weeks prior to inclusion in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>GOLD stages II, III and IV</keyword>
	<keyword>Computed Tomography scan</keyword>
	<keyword>Functional Respiratory Imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-Invasive Ventilation</keyword>
	<keyword>Arterial Blood Gas</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypercapnic</keyword>
	<keyword>Health Related Quality of Life</keyword>
	<keyword>Lung compliance</keyword>
</DOC>