<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01592617</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators identified three cancer-testis antigens, as targets for cancer vaccination against lung cancer. In this clinical study, the investigators examine using a combination of three peptides from these three antigens (S-488410) the safety, immunogenicity, and antitumor effect of vaccine treatment for advanced non-small cell lung cancer patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II Study of S-488410 to Treat Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the clinical efficacy and safety of S-488410 for advanced non-small cell lung cancers who failed to standard therapy. The investigators previously identified three novel HLA-A*2402-restricted epitope peptides, which were derived from three cancer-testis antigens, as targets for cancer vaccination against lung cancer. In this phase II trial, we examine using a combination of these three peptides the safety, immunogenicity, and antitumor effect of vaccine treatment for HLA-A*2402-positive advanced small cell lung cancer patients who failed to standard therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Advanced NSCLC that cannot undergo curative surgery. Patients that are refractory to standard chemotherapy or cannot be treated with further therapy due to severe adverse effects of chemotherapy. Histologically diagnosed NSCLC. Clinical efficacy can be evaluated by radiologic methods within 4 weeks prior to receiving treatment. ECOG performance status 02 within 2 weeks prior to receiving treatment. Life expectancy &gt; 3 months. Age between 20 to 79 Male or Female. In patients or out patients. Able and willing to give valid written informed consent. Other malignancy requiring treatment radiation, immunotherapy, hyperthermia, or surgery. Active and uncontrolled infectious disease Active and uncontrolled hepatic dysfunction, kidney dysfunction, cardiac disease, or lung disease (i.e. interstitial pneumonia). Autoimmune disease. HIVAb or antigen positive Prior anticancer therapy within 4 weeks Laboratory values as follows: 2000&lt;mm3 &lt; WBC &lt; 15000/mm3, Platelet count &lt; 50000/mm3, Asparate transaminase &gt; 5 X cutoff value, Alanine transaminase &gt; 5 X cutoff value, Total bilirubin &gt; 3 X cutoff value, and Serum creatinine &gt; 3X cutoff value. Patients knows HLAA type. Breastfeeding and Pregnancy (woman of child bearing potential) Refusal of pregnancy conception. Treated with S488401, S488402, or S488403. Treated with other investigational drug within 3 months prior to receiving S48810 treatment. Decision of nonenrollment of the patients by principal investigator or physicianincharge from the view point of patient's safety.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>cancer vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>HLA-A*24:02</keyword>
	<keyword>lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>CTL</keyword>
</DOC>