<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02781064</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Statins are known to cause rare but serious side effects such as rhabdomyolysis (breakdown of muscle tissue) but many patients stop taking statins due to less severe symptoms, such as muscle pain or fatigue. This study aims to determine whether symptoms occurring during statin use are caused by statins. The trial will compare patient-reported side effects of statins (20mg atorvastatin) vs. placebo. Patients will be randomized to alternating treatment blocks of either statin or placebo split into six two-month treatment periods. At the end of each period, patients will be asked to self-report side effects using a website or mobile app.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>STATIN: Web-based Investigation of Side Effects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>INTRODUCTION Statins reduce cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk and are recommended as part of the treatment strategy for primary and secondary prevention of CVD in the NHS. Although statins are the most commonly prescribed treatment in the UK, there is still uncertainty about adverse effects. Severe statin adverse effects are extremely rare (rhabdomyolysis 0.1 and myopathy 0.5 per 1000 people over 5 years). However, there has been widespread reporting of other less well-defined statin-related symptoms in the media, notably muscle pain and weakness. These reports have largely been prompted by data from non-randomised, non-blinded observational studies but have not been confirmed in blinded randomised controlled trials (RCTs). A major limitation of observational studies is lack of blinding: patients taking a medication expect to experience adverse effects10 and therefore reporting of symptoms may be higher than in a comparable statin-free population. This phenomenon, the "nocebo" effect, can lead to bias in unblinded studies. In RCTs expectations of adverse effects can lead to inflated reporting in both active and placebo groups. In the Odyssey ALTERNATIVE trial, statin 'intolerant' patients initially underwent a double blind four week phase where they received placebo. Interestingly, during this time, 7% dropped out due to myalgia. In the main phase of this three armed trial (alirocumab vs ezetimibe vs atorvastatin), rates of adverse events were the same across all groups at roughly 80%, but dropped to 55% among alirocumab when unblinded. Therefore in some trials of statins, expectation of adverse effects among both placebo and active treatment arms may have diluted any true effect of statins on muscle symptoms. A systematic review of randomised trials of statins found that the prevalence of myalgia varied from 0% to 30%, but was not different in the active and placebo arms. There have also been two other important criticisms of the existing RCT evidence. First, not all trials have collected data on subjective symptoms and recording may be inconsistent due to the definitions used. Studies have shown that adverse events are rarely fully presented in journal publications. Second, while there have been trials among specific vulnerable patient groups, there is a perception that trial participants do not reflect populations taking statins in routine care. The investigators are working closely with the Cholesterol Treatment Trialists' Collaboration performing a meta-analysis of statin adverse events reported in RCTs of statins, which will determine using individual participant data whether there is an excess of adverse events among those allocated statin compared with placebo, and whether to date there has been any bias in the reporting of adverse events in statin trials. However, for the reasons outlined above, re-analysis of the existing evidence may not alleviate individual patient concerns. Despite evidence-based recommendations about the risks and benefits of statin use, many patients believe their symptoms are due to statins, leading to discontinuation, and are therefore potentially missing out needlessly on an effective drug intervention. GPs are faced with the challenge of decision making when patients present with symptoms during statin use as there is currently no diagnostic tool allowing clinicians to empirically evaluate whether symptoms reported by an individual statin-user are caused by the statin itself or by the 'nocebo' effect. N-of-1 trials offer the opportunity for individual patients to discover whether the symptoms that they are experiencing are attributable to statins. Each patient acts as their own control, and therefore their optimal treatment can be established. Importantly, N-of-1 trials offer individual patients the opportunity to observe their own response to active and placebo treatments. The investigators anticipate that this knowledge will be an important determinant of subsequent statin use and therefore the investigators will follow patients for three months after their blinded treatment period has ended. At the end of these three months the investigators will be ascertain as to whether they are using statins. The proposed trial will address some of the criticisms of previous evidence. The trial will be blinded and placebo-controlled to minimise bias and the sequence of statin and placebo treatments will be randomised to avoid confounding. Additionally, the within-patient comparisons of symptoms experienced while on placebo and statins will allow us to determine, definitively: (i) whether individual patient symptoms are caused by statins and (ii) the extent to which symptoms attributed to statins appear to be causally related. Trial design 2.1 Overview StatinWISE is a randomised, double blind, placebo controlled N-of-1 trial taking place in a primary care setting, to quantify the occurrence of self-reported muscle symptoms whilst taking daily atorvastatin. A total of 200 patients who fulfill the eligibility criteria will be recruited. 2.2 Optional Genetic study A genetic component to statin myopathy (pain accompanied by rises in CK or ALT) has been suggested (the SLCO1B1 variant). However, it is not clear whether this variant will be found among the patients included in our study (who have experienced muscle symptoms while on statins but no substantial rises in CK or ALT). Therefore, as part of the trial, the investigators will ask patients to provide a blood sample for an optional genetic analysis as part of a larger collaborative effort investigating genetic associations with statins effects. Specific results will not be fed back to clinicians or to patients. Where patients have consented for the genetic blood test, one nine milliliters blood sample will be obtained in an EDTA Vacutainer tube, labelled with the genetic study ID number, patient's gender, and the date and time of sample collection. It will then be sent to the genetics laboratory at the University of Liverpool via first class post in pre-paid Royal Mail Safeboxes (each containing a maximum of four tubes) as soon as possible after collection. No patient identifiable data will be included or separately provided to the University of Liverpool. 2.3 NUMBER OF PARTICIPANTS NEEDED A feasibility study in the Clinical Practice Research Datalink has indicated that on average 35 patients per practice per year will be eligible to take part in the trial. The investigators anticipate an average uptake of 15% among primary care patients invited to participate in our trial. Therefore, the investigators estimate that the investigators will need to invite approximately 1300 patients from over 50 general practices to the trial to achieve our recruitment target of 200. Power calculations: Our power calculation was performed via simulation. An initial sample size, n, was chosen. The treatment allocation sequence for each of the n patients was drawn by randomly allocating the participant to either statin or placebo separately for periods 1, 3, and 5, thereby determining the order of the 6 treatment periods. For each participant, a random effect was drawn from a normal distribution, with zero mean and variance equal to 302. Residual errors (6 for each participant; one for each period) were drawn from a normal distribution with zero mean and variance equal to 252. Then a VAS pain score was simulated for each participant in each period, adding a treatment effect of 13 to each statin period, incorporating the patient random effect and the participant's residual error for that period. This simulated dataset was analysed using the primary analysis model (as if this were the real data) and the two-sided P-value for the treatment effect was stored. After repeating this process a large number of times (e.g. 500), the statistical power was estimated by the proportion of simulated datasets in which the P-value was less than 0.05. If the power was less than 90%, the sample size was increased and the power re-estimated. The rationale for the parameters chosen within this model is detailed below. Minimum clinically significant difference in VAS pain score (10 mm): This value was chosen to represent the smallest VAS change in pain which patients would perceive as being beneficial, and might therefore change the patient's decision regarding subsequent statin use. Two studies conducted within an Accident and Emergency setting both concluded that the smallest change in VAS pain score corresponding to "a little more" or "a little less" pain was 13mm, with confidence intervals (95% CI: 10 to 17mm) and (95% CI: 10 to 16mm). The investigators took the lower limit of the confidence interval to represent the smallest change likely to be perceived as being beneficial. Within and between-participant variability in VAS pain score: (〖30〗^2 and 〖35〗^2, respectively). These values were obtained by fitting a mixed model to the data from a pilot series of N-of-1 trials for statin adverse effects (data obtained by approximation from figures presented therein). These variance components can be poorly estimated, thus we took values from the higher end of the confidence intervals, giving conservative estimates of these components. 2.4 SAMPLE SIZE A sample size of 64 participants provides approximately 90% power to detect a treatment effect of at least 10mm, assuming a Type I error of 5%. Allowing for loss to follow-up of 40% of participants through the trial inflates the required sample size to 107 participants. Period effects (changes in underlying VAS pain score due to factors other than randomised treatment, e.g. seasonal, activity-related, etc.), variability in individual statin effects across patients, and imperfect adherence to the assigned treatment were investigated by further detailed simulations. VAS pain scores are not normally distributed, since they are bounded (0-100mm) and can display large fluctuations in response. Therefore, further power calculations were performed drawing the outcome from a Beta distribution, and from a distribution with normal variance components on a logit scale, to assess the robustness of the sample size estimates to the distribution chosen. These factors all have the effect of decreasing power, thus increasing the sample size required. An approximate 80% increase in the sample size required in the absence of these effects provided approximately 90% or more power across a plausible range of these potential effects, thus the investigators determined that a final sample size of 200 was required. Multiple testing: Rather than making formal adjustments for multiple testing, the investigators follow an approach advocated by Pocock of clearly specifying our primary analysis (which provides a single test for treatment effect), while explicitly presenting and interpreting all other tests as secondary analyses. Power for individual N-of-1 trials: In order to increase the statistical power for the analysis of individual N-of-1 trials, the investigators will ask participants to report symptoms daily in the last week of each period, rather than once per period. Full adherence through the trial will provide between 55 and 70% power to detect effects of 10mm or greater for individual treatment comparisons. Estimates of recruitment and retention rates: The investigators anticipate that some patients will not complete data in each treatment period, and that some will not complete their 12-month follow-up. By designing this study as a series of N-of-1 trials, which offer individual participant benefit in the form of an individualised estimate of effect, the investigators hope to minimise this type of dropout. However, the investigators have accounted for this in their sample size calculation by allowing for 40% loss to follow-up. 2.5 SETTINGS General Practitioner (GP) Practices will be recruited through the Clinical Research Network across England and Wales and the investigators will continue to add practices to ensure the sample size is achieved. Suitable collaborating practices and investigators will be assessed on their ability to conduct a trial. In advance of the trial starting at a practice, the Principal Investigator (PI) must agree to follow Good Clinical Practice Guidelines and all relevant regulations. All relevant regulatory and ethics approvals must be in place prior to practices recruiting their first patient. 2.6 RECRUITMENT OF PARTICIPANTS Participating practices will recruit eligible patients from two groups as follows: Patients who are considering discontinuation of their statin due to muscle symptoms: These patients will be invited to take part in the trial when they visit the GP to report muscle symptoms believed to be associated with statins and where the patient/GP is considering stopping statins because of the muscle symptoms. The GP or Research Nurse will approach the patient and give the patient information sheet (Appendix 6). If interested, patients will be able to consent (Appendix 7) and complete the screening visit with the GP or the Research Nurse during this appointment or it can be arranged for another suitable time. Patients who have stopped taking a statin in the last 3 years due to muscle symptoms: A search of the practice electronic records will be performed by the Research Nurse on a two-monthly basis for one year (or until recruitment targets are reached) to identify potentially eligible patients. All screened patients will be documented on a screening log. The list will be reviewed by the GP to confirm clinical eligibility before patients are invited to take part. A letter inviting them to attend a screening visit, accompanied with the patient information sheet (Appendix 6) for the patient to consider, will be sent by the trial team from their GP practice. Contact details of the Research Nurse will be provided should the patient have any questions. A reply slip will be enclosed for the patient to complete if they wish to attend the screening visit, which will be returned to the Clinical Trials Unit (CTU), during which the trial will be explained, and they will have the opportunity to ask questions. Patients will be sent a letter of invitation to consider participation up to a maximum of three times. Once informed consent has been obtained, eligibility, demographic and medical history data (Appendix 1) will be collected directly onto an online trial database. 2.7 ELIGIBILITY Inclusion criteria: Adults (aged 16 and over) Registered in a participating GP practice Previously prescribed statin treatment in the last 3 years Stopped OR is considering stopping statin treatment due to muscle symptoms Provided fully informed consent. Exclusion criteria: Any previously documented serum alanine aminotransferase (ALT) levels at or above three times the upper limit of normal Have persistent, generalised, unexplained muscle pain (whether associated or not with statin use) and have creatinine kinase (CK) levels greater than 5 times the upper limit of normal Should not participate in the trial in the opinion of the general practitioner. 2.8 RANDOMISATION Patients eligible for inclusion will be randomised by the Research Nurse/GP practice trial team using the online London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine (LSHTM) CTU randomisation system to a sequence of blinded placebo and atorvastatin treatment periods. There are six paired (statin-placebo or placebo-statin) treatment periods each of two months' duration. In practice, this means that each individual is randomised (with equal probability) to one of the following eight sequences (with P=placebo, S=statin): Treatment Period 1 2 3 4 5 6 Sequence 1 S P S P S P Sequence 2 S P S P P S Sequence 3 S P P S S P Sequence 4 S P P S P S Sequence 5 P S S P S P Sequence 6 P S S P P S Sequence 7 P S P S S P Sequence 8 P S P S P S Randomisation codes will be generated and secured by the Information Technology team at LSHTM CTU, who has procedures to ensure the trial team remains blinded. The codes will be made available to a Good Manufacturing Practice (GMP) certified clinical trial supply company explicitly for the treatment packs to be created in accordance with the randomisation list. 2.9 TREATMENT The trial treatment consists of once-daily oral administration of Atorvastatin (20mg) capsules, which will be compared with matching placebo (Microcrystalline Cellulose). The treatment phase of the trial will be one year in duration for each patient. A blinded placebo, identical in size, colour, smell and packaging to the active statin, has been chosen to prevent knowledge of treatment from affecting symptom scores. Two months' supply of allocated treatment will be posted to the patient every 2 months. Treatment should start within 4 weeks of randomisation. Patients who have not started by the 3rd week post randomisation will be contacted by the CTU. Such patients will therefore have a longer study period. 2.9.1 DOSE SELECTION Atorvastatin is recommended by the current NICE guidelines for lipid modification; 20mg is the recommended dose for primary prevention of cardiovascular disease. Atorvastatin is also recommended by NICE for secondary prevention2 and for patients with a high risk of adverse events (our patient population), a dose lower than 80mg is recommended. The most commonly used dose is 20mg. A visually matched placebo has been chosen as an appropriate comparator for two reasons. Firstly, patient expectation of symptoms while on statins is likely to affect their experience of symptoms. A placebo control should minimise bias arising from knowledge of allocation. Secondly, withholding statin treatment from patients during placebo treatment periods is justified because the trial will recruit patients who have recently stopped using statins (and therefore are not currently receiving any benefit from statins) and those who wish to discontinue. If patients in the trial tolerate the active treatment periods with few symptoms, then this trial is likely to increase their usage of statins in the long term. 2.9.2 DRUG MANUFACTURE, BLINDING AND SUPPLY OF TRIAL MEDICATION The active trial drug atorvastatin (as atorvastatin calcium trihydrate) will be purchased on the open market. Placebo will be manufactured specially to match the atorvastatin by a GMP certified manufacturer. Capsules and packaging will be identical in appearance for both active treatment and placebo. DBcaps® capsules which has a unique locking mechanism to help with assuring the integrity of the blind will be used for over encapsulation of both active and placebo treatments. Additionally, patients will be asked to swallow the capsule whole without chewing or breaking it. The blinding process and first stage Qualified Person (QP) release will be done by the designated clinical trial supply company. The blinding process will involve encapsulating the active tablet, complete removal of the original manufacturer's label and replacement with the clinical trial label bearing the randomisation number which will be used as the pack identification. Other pack label text will be identical for both atorvastatin and placebo treatments and will be in compliance with requirements for investigational medicinal products. 2.9.3 ADMINISTRATION OF TRIAL MEDICATION Patients will receive their allocated trial medications through the post and they will be asked to take the study medication daily through the six two-month treatment periods. Ideally there should be no break between treatment periods. However, if for any reason there is a break, patients can simply restart taking the trial medication as soon as possible. Patients will be asked to take one capsule orally once daily at a time of day convenient to them. Capsules should be swallowed whole. Patients will be given written instructions on how to take the study medication. At the start of each two-month treatment period, patients will be asked to inform the trial team about their first date of study medication use using the trial's mobile application (app), email, text message, Freephone telephone service or a pre-paid postage reply slip - whichever is easier to ensure data collection occurs on the correct days. A Freephone telephone number will be provided for patients to call if they have any questions. Adherence to the study medication will be collected on the same days as other data as part of the outcome data collection. 2.10 DATA COLLECTION This trial will be coordinated from the CTU at LSHTM and conducted at GP practices in England and Wales. Baseline data will be collected at each GP practice by the GP or Research Nurses, and will be entered directly online to the trial database provided by the LSHTM CTU. Follow up data will be collected directly from each patient at the end of each two-month period. Patients will be allowed to choose the method of data collection most suitable for them from the following: Bespoke mobile app which will require patients to use their own smartphone. On-line database using a computer, phone or tablet. Paper forms which they will receive by post at the same time with their trial treatment and which they can complete themselves or they can request a trial team member to contact them by phone to help with completing the forms. Trial staff will telephone the patient on each data collection day and complete the questionnaire based on the patient answers. For patients with a smartphone who choose to submit outcome data using the trial's bespoke mobile app, the Research Nurse will help the patient to install and set-up the app for use. The Research Nurse will also give a demonstration to ensure the patient understands how to use it. Each nurse will have access to internet so that the patient can download the app without using their own mobile network (ensuring that download of the app is free of charge to the patient). The GP or Research Nurse will also help the patient to complete the symptoms data for the Baseline form (Appendix 1) using their preferred method. Any questions can be addressed at this stage. Once baseline procedures have been completed and the patient confirmed as being eligible and consented, the patient can then be randomised. A screening log will be used to record all patients who were identified as potentially eligible using the GP practice database, including those who were ineligible and those who declined participation. The Screening Log will remain at the relevant GP practice and only anonymised information regarding number of screened patients and number and reasons for screen failure will be shared with the Trial Coordinating Centre. Only data outlined on the baseline, follow up, end of trial and adverse events data forms will be collected as part of this trial database. 2.10.1 BASELINE AND RANDOMISATION DATA Baseline data will be collected by the GP or Research Nurse performing the assessment at the Screening Visit (Appendix 1). Baseline data will be collected via a bespoke online trial database, to which each GP and Research Nurse will have a unique log-in ID and password. Eligible patients will then be randomised and data about the randomisation (date, time and randomisation number) is generated. 2.10.2 TREATMENT PHASE FOLLOW UP DATA In the seventh week of each treatment period, patients will receive reminders (format agreed at baseline) to alert them that follow-up data collection is approaching. During the 8th week of each treatment period, the Patient Questionnaire and VAS Pain Scale forms (Appendices 4 and 5) will be completed by the patient. Patients can choose to receive daily reminders on each day their data is due to be collected. Non-responders will automatically receive a reminder after 24 hours of due date by the trial team. 2.10.3 END OF TRIAL DATA During the seventh week of treatment period 6, the Research Nurse will contact patients to thank them for their participation so far, inform them that this is the last treatment period, and that they, together with their GP, will receive their individual results at the beginning of month 14. The Research Nurse and patient will arrange a telephone or face-to-face appointment to discuss the individual results during month 14. The Research Nurse will also inform patients that if they want to continue taking statin without a break, to arrange a separate clinical appointment with their GP prior to the end of the treatment period. At month 15, trial staff will email/telephone the patient to document their decision on future statin use and whether their results helped reach this decision. This will be the last data collection point of the trial. Throughout the trial, continued patient care will be at the discretion of their GP. In primary care, the patient will be recorded as having an ongoing statin prescription. Where treatment with an interacting drug is needed that will be for less than one-month duration, the patient will be asked to stop the trial treatment for that period. Where treatment with an interacting drug is needed for longer than one month, the patient will be asked to withdraw from study treatment completely. When the patient is randomised, a temporary Read code indicating StatinWISE participation will be recorded in their primary care record, the code will be removed at the end of the trial. Patients will also be given an alert card that identifies them as a StatinWISE patient. Patients will be asked to present this card to anyone providing medical care outside of their usual general practice. This card will have a link to the trial website and a trial contact number. 3. OUTCOME MEASURES Primary outcome: The primary outcome is self-reported 'muscle symptoms', defined as pain, weakness, tenderness, stiffness or cramp to the body of any intensity, recorded where the participant believes they are associated with the study medication; these are the symptoms most commonly reported by patients and are often the reasons for discontinuation. The primary outcome will be assessed by the mean difference in VAS scores (range 0 to 100) between treatment periods with the trial treatment and treatment periods with placebo, estimated via a linear mixed model. Secondary outcomes: Secondary outcomes relating to participant belief about the cause of their muscle symptoms, the site of muscle symptoms, how the muscle symptoms affected the participant and information about any other symptoms will be collected on the last day of each two-month treatment period, using a questionnaire (Appendix 5). The other secondary outcomes are adherence to medication, the participant's decision about statin treatment following the trial, and whether they found their own trial result helpful. Specifically, secondary outcomes will be: The proportion of patients with muscle symptoms during each two-month period who report that they believe their symptoms were caused by the study medication, comparing periods of IMP treatment with placebo. Site of muscle symptoms (single or multiple; head and neck/upper limbs/lower limbs/trunk). Among patients reporting muscle symptoms, the difference in mean VAS scores (range 0 to 100) for the following, comparing periods of IMP treatment with placebo: General activity Mood Walking ability Normal work (includes both work outside the home and housework) Relations with other people Sleep Enjoyment of life Other symptoms that the patient believes can be attributed to the study medication (grouped: musculoskeletal; gastrointestinal; respiratory; neurological; psychological; other). Adherence to study medication as assessed by: (a) self-report and (b) counting pills remaining in returned packages, and the relationship between adherence and muscle symptoms. Participant decision regarding future statin use and the relationship to their primary outcome. Whether patients found their own trial result helpful in making the decision about future statin use. 4. ANALYSIS Individual N-of-1 trials: The purpose of these analyses is to inform the individual patient of the effect of the IMP on their VAS muscle symptom score. The analysis and presentation of individual level results will be developed in collaboration with the Patient and Public Involvement (PPI) group. The investigators will examine a range of graphical summaries and statistical analyses in order to identify the most informative presentation of individual results. As a result of this process, at the end of each individual trial the participant will be shown numerical and graphical summaries of their individual data, in relation to their IMP and placebo periods. Combined analysis of N-of-1 trials Primary analysis: To estimate the population average estimate of the trial treatment n VAS muscle symptom score, data from each N-of-1 trial will be aggregated to form a powerful dataset. The investigators will adopt an intention-to-treat approach. Patients who enter data on muscle symptoms at least once during a treatment period with the IMP and at least once during a treatment period with placebo will be included in the primary analysis. The primary analysis will be a linear mixed model for VAS muscle symptom score with random effects for participant and treatment and fixed period effects. Residual errors will be modelled using a first-order auto-regressive error structure within each treatment period to account for correlation between the 7 daily measurements, with robust standard errors to account for non-normality of the VAS scores. Although VAS muscle symptom scores are unlikely to be exactly normally distributed, analysing such data using normal-based methods is likely to be a sufficiently robust approach. All tests will be two-sided. P&lt;0.05 will be considered statistically significant. Secondary analyses: Secondary outcomes relating to the impact of the IMP on other aspects of life will be analysed in a similar manner to the primary outcome, omitting the auto-regressive correlation structure since these secondary outcomes are measured once per treatment period. The investigators will investigate whether the excess muscle symptoms, if any, experienced during treatment periods with the IMP appears to be concentrated in multiple sites. Descriptive statistics will be used to summarise the measures of adherence to randomised treatment, and their relationship to the IMP and placebo periods. The investigators will use the measures of adherence to randomised treatment to perform an efficacy analysis based around an instrumental variables approach. Because these analyses require much stronger assumptions than the intention-to-treat analysis above, the results of the efficacy analysis will be presented and interpreted as a secondary analysis. The secondary outcomes include a single binary measure of whether the participant reports having muscle symptoms during that treatment period or not. This will be combined with the follow-up question pertaining to attribution, to obtain a single binary measure of whether the participant reports having muscle symptoms that they attribute to the study medication or not. These two binary outcome measures will be assessed using a logistic mixed model with random participant and treatment effects and fixed period effects. The investigators will relate the patients' decision regarding future statin use, and whether or not the participant found their own result helpful in making their subsequent treatment decisions, to their individual estimated effect of the IMP. Subgroup analyses: There are no priori subgroup analyses planned. If an overall population-level effect is detected, the investigators may investigate whether the effect varies within subgroups defined by measured baseline characteristics. These analyses will be regarded and interpreted as being exploratory.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atorvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults (aged 16 and over) Prescribed statin treatment in the last 3 years Stopped OR considering stopping statin treatment due to muscle symptoms Provided fully informed consent. Any previously documented serum alanine aminotransferase (ALT) levels at or above three times the upper limit of normal; Have persistent, generalised, unexplained muscle pain (whether associated or not with statin use) and have creatinine kinase (CK) levels greater than 5 times the upper limit of normal Should not be using atorvastatin 20mg daily in the opinion of the general practitioner.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>