<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02781142</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Motor imagery training facilitates the neural plasticity with increasing the neuronal cortical pathways in the brain. Motor imagery training is an effective way in stroke survivors. However, its effects in persons with multiple sclerosis (MS) are not known. Additionally, telerehabilitation based motor imagery training is very rare treatment way which requires more research. Therefore, this study aims to investigate the effect of telerehabilitation based motor imagery training on gait and balance performance of the persons with MS. The participants will be allocated into three groups, including motor imagery training, wait-list control group, and age, gender, and education matched healthy control group. Each group will include at least 25 participants (i.e. in total 75 participants). All the assessments will be performed before and after the training in the 6-week motor imagery training group. The participants in the wait-list control group will underwent the assessment with a 6-week interval. The healthy participants will be assessed only one. The motor imagery training will be designed for the individual basis with following standard protocols. It will be applied three times a week for 6 weeks. The first three sessions will be performed in the clinic, the other will be performed at the patients' home with a telerehabilitation technique.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Motor Imagery Training in Persons With Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a chronic, inflammatory, and demyelinating disease of the central nervous system. It is the most common neurological disease which causes progressive gait and balance disorders in young adults. The previous studies have indicated that home care and treatment services, which accelerates the healing process and makes the one feel better, are more preferred by the patients. Persons with MS are commonly not able to access the institutional rehabilitation services because of their disability and/or home location. It restricts the participation of the persons with MS and their treatment benefits. In recent years, the telerehabilitation programs are increasing to overcome this problem. Motor imagery training also stands as a good option in the rehabilitation programs. Motor imagery is a mental process by which an individual rehearses or simulates a given action. Motor imagery training facilitates the neural plasticity with increasing the neuronal cortical pathways in the brain. Motor imagery training is an effective way in stroke survivors. However, its effects in persons with MS are not known. Additionally, telerehabilitation based motor imagery training is very rare treatment way which requires more research. The aim of this study is to investigate the effect of telerehabilitation based motor imagery training on gait and balance performance of the persons with MS. The participants will be allocated into three groups, including motor imagery training, wait-list control group, and age, gender, and education matched healthy control group. Each group will include at least 25 participants (i.e. in total 75 participants). The persons with MS will be recruited from the outpatient MS clinic of Dokuz Eylul University, and the healthy participants will be recruited from the stuff of Dokuz Eylul University. The inclusion and exclusion criteria assessments and the neurological examination will be performed by a blinded neurologist specialized in MS. The cognition, fatigue, depression, and quality of life assessment will be performed by a blinded neuropsychologist. The remaining assessments, including walking, balance, and motor imagery abilities will be assessed by a blinded physiotherapist. All the assessments will be performed before and after the training in the 6-week motor imagery training group. The participants in the wait-list control group will underwent the assessment with a 6-week interval. The healthy participants will be assessed only one. The motor imagery training will be designed for the individual basis with following standard protocols. It will be applied three times a week for 6 weeks. The first three sessions will be performed in the clinic, the other will be performed at the patients' home with a telerehabilitation technique.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of multiple sclerosis Having the Expanded Disability Status Scale 2.0 4.0 Relapsefree period at the last 3 months Enough computer use ability Having computer and internet connection Having severe musculoskeletal, cardiovascular, pulmonary, or metabolic disease Severe cognitive impairment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>