<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01064232</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Single-dose, Randomized, two-Period, Cross over Study</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Risperidone Tablets, 1 mg Bioequivalence Study of Dr.Reddy's Under Fasting Condition</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Randomized, single-dose, two-way, crossover study was conducted to compare the relative bioavailability of two formulations of 1 mg risperidone tablets under fasting conditions. The test formulation was Dr. Reddy's Laboratories Limited's Risperidone Tablets, 1 mg, and the reference formulation was Risperdal® (risperidone) tablets, 1 mg (Janssen Pharmaceutica Products, L.P.). The study was conducted with 30 healthy adults. In each study period, a single 1 mg dose was administered to all subjects following an overnight fast.The subjects received the test product in one study period and the reference product in the other period; the order of administration was according to the dosing randomization schedule. There was a 7-day interval between treatments.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Risperidone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Males and females, 18 55 years of age. 2. Female subjects of child bearing potential must either abstain from sexual intercourse or use a reliable method of contraception (e.g. condom with spermicide, IUD, hormonal contraceptives) for at least 30 days prior to dosing and during the duration of the study. 3. A body mass index (BMI) of 1830 kg/m² inclusive as calculated according to Novum Standard Operating Procedures. 4. Good health as determined by lack of clinically significant abnormalities in health assessments performed at screening. 5. Signed and dated informed consent form, which meets all criteria of current FDA regulations. 1. If female, pregnant, lactating or likely to become pregnant during the study. 2. History of allergy or sensitivity to risperidone, or similar drugs, or history of any drug hypersensitivity or intolerance which, in the opinion of the Investigator, would compromise the safety of the subject or the study. 3. Significant history or current evidence of chronic infectious disease, system disorder or organ dysfunction. 4. Presence of gastrointestinal disease or history of malabsorption within the last year. 5. History of psychiatric disorders occurring within the last two years that required hospitalization or medication. 6. Presence of a medical condition requiring regular treatment with prescription drugs. 7. Use of pharmacologic agents known to significantly induce or inhibit drugmetabolizing enzymes within 30 days prior to initial dosing. 8. Receipt of any drug as part of a research study within 30 days prior to dosing. 9. Drug or alcohol addiction requiring treatment in the past 12 months. 10. Donation or significant loss of whole blood (480 ml or more) within 30 days or plasma within 14 days prior to dosing. 11. Positive test results for HIV, Hepatitis B surface antigen, or Hepatitis C antibody. 12. Positive test results for drugs of abuse at screening. 13. Positive serum pregnancy test. 14. Subjects who smoke more than 10 cigarettes/day or equivalent tobacco use. 15. Subjects who have been on a special diet during the 28 days prior to dosing 16. Subjects who consume on average more than 3 units of alcohol/day.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>