<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01064700</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim of this research was to examine the influence of bright light on anxiety in high-anxious young adults. In an acute exposure study, participants were randomly assigned to 45 min of either (1) bright light (3,000 lux) or (2) a placebo inactivated negative ion generator. Treatments were initiated ≤1 hr after awakening. At 10 min before and 30 min after the treatments, state anxiety, mood, and blood pressure were assessed. Following the acute exposure study, participants performed a 5-week study. Following a a 1-week baseline, participants were randomly assigned to four weeks of daily exposure to either (1) bright light (45 min/day; 3,000 lux) or (2) placebo inactivated negative ion generator, which were initiated ≤1 hr after awakening. Before and after the experiment, clinical ratings were conducted with the Hamilton Anxiety Scale, the Hamilton Depression Scale, and the Clinical Global Impressions scale (CGI). Following baseline, and following each week of treatment, blood pressure, as well as questionnaires for state anxiety, depression, mood, sleep, and side effects were assessed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bright Light: A Novel Treatment for Anxiety</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Having a level of trait anxiety [Spielberger StateTrait Anxiety Inventory (Form Y1)]{23642} that was ≥ the 75th percentile for their age (i.e., ≥ 46 and ≥ 44 for women and men, respectively) Current treatment for anxiety or depression; History of bipolar disorder, mania, or psychotic disorders; History of winter depression, which might bias towards positive response to light; Hypertension; Ophthalmic abnormalities; and Usual exposure to high levels of light such that the intervention would add little to usual exposure.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>Phototherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychic Anxiety</keyword>
</DOC>