<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01944501</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aimed at trying transcranial magnetic stimulation and transcranial direct current stimulation as potential treatments to decrease tinnitus in patients with significant hearing loss.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neuromodulation Techniques in the Treatment of Chronic Tinnitus With Hearing Loss</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Tinnitus is a very common condition and affects approximately 15% of the population, disrupting sleep, emotional balance and social life of the patients. Acoustic deprivation causes hearing loss and is responsible for a cascade of processes that result in the reorganization of the cortex through a synchronization of neuronal activity related to a cortical re-mapping. Consistent with the hypothesis that tinnitus is caused by abnormal activation of the auditory cortex, repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) can temporarily reduce cortical hyperactivity through direct neuromodulation of the temporal cortex. Furthermore, studies have shown that transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) can also suppress tinnitus. Objective: To determine the effectiveness of rTMS and TDCS in the treatment of patients with chronic tinnitus and auditory loss. Methods: We performed an analytical experimental double-blind study using rTMS and tDCS in patients with chronic tinnitus and hearing loss.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hearing Loss</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deafness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tinnitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>chronic tinnitus hearing loss neurological diseases use of drugs affecting the central nervous system evidence of dementia clinical diagnosis of depression</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>tinnitus</keyword>
	<keyword>hearing loss</keyword>
	<keyword>Transcranial magnetic stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Transcranial direct current stimulation</keyword>
</DOC>