<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00488761</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Tigecycline's activity against resistant organisms, as well as significant coverage of both gram-positive and gram-negative bacteria, may provide a valuable therapeutic alternative in treating patients with complicated skin and/or skin structure infections.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Evaluating the Safety and Efficacy of Tigecycline in Hospitalized Patients With cSSSI</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To evaluate the safety and the efficacy of tigecycline in treating hospitalized patients with complicated skin and/or skin structure infections.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Skin Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Skin Diseases, Infectious</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tigecycline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Minocycline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Hospitalized male and female patients, 18 years of age or older. Anticipated need for intravenous antibiotic therapy of 5 days or longer. Patients known or suspected to have a complicated skin and skin structure infection. Patients with any concomitant condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would preclude an evaluation of a response or make it unlikely that the contemplated course of therapy could be completed. Patients with severely impaired arterial blood supply and insufficiency such that the likelihood of amputation of the infected anatomical site within one month is likely. Infected diabetic foot ulcers or decubitus ulcers where the infection is present for greater than one week's duration or chronically infected decubitus ulcers in patients who can not be compliant with measures necessary for chronic wound healing.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tigecycline</keyword>
	<keyword>cSSSI</keyword>
	<keyword>complicated skin and skin structure infections</keyword>
</DOC>