<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02833610</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research study is studying a possible therapy as a possible treatment for the consequences of Multiple Myeloma with renal insufficiency.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Denosumab in Multiple Myeloma Patients With Renal Insufficiency</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This research study is a Phase II clinical trial. This study will assess the safety and tolerability of denosumab in Multiple Myeloma participants, by studying drug interactions with different parts of the body. The FDA (the U.S. Food and Drug Administration) has not approved Denosumab for this specific disease but it has been approved denosumab for use in other cancers to treat cancer-related bone disease such as prostate and breast cancer.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Denosumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with symptomatic MM as defined by IMWG requiring antimyeloma therapy. Monoclonal plasma cells in the bone marrow greater than or equal to 10% and/or presence of a biopsyproven plasmacytoma Monoclonal protein present in the serum and/or urine Creatinine clearance &lt; 30 mL/min, not eligible for bisphosphonate. Estimated glomerular filtration rate will be calculated using CockcroftGault equation. Serum calcium or albuminadjusted serum calcium ≥ 2.1 mmol/L (8.4 mg/dL) and ≤ 2.9 mmol/L (11.5 mg/dL) (Reference range 8.510.8 mg/dL) Able to tolerate daily supplementation of calcium and vitamin D Vitamin D level ≥ 30 ng/mL after repletion Participants must have normal organ as defined below: Total bilirubin ≤ 2.0 x ULN AST(SGOT) ≤2.5 × institutional upper limit of normal ALT(SGPT) ≤2.5 × institutional upper limit of normal Plan to receive antimyeloma therapies. Age ≥ 18 years. ECOG performance status ≤ 2 Life expectancy greater than 6 months 03 lines of prior antimyeloma therapy. Subjects with reproductive potential must be willing to use, in combination with his/her partner, 2 highly effective methods of effective contraception or practice sexual abstinence throughout the study and continue for 5 months after the study duration. Subjects who are surgically sterile (e.g. history of bilateral tubal ligation, hysterectomy) or whose sexual partner is sterile (e.g. history of vasectomy) are not required to use additional contraceptive measures. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document. Prior administration of denosumab. Active IV bisphosphonate use in the last 3 months. POEMS syndrome (polyneuropathy, organomegaly, endocrinopathy, monoclonal protein, and skin changes). Plasma cell leukemia. Prior history or current evidence of osteonecrosis/osteomyelitis of the jaw. Active dental or jaw condition which requires oral surgery, including tooth extraction. Nonhealed dental/oral surgery, including tooth extraction. Planned invasive dental procedures during the course of study. Evidence of any of the following conditions per subject selfreport or medical chart review Any prior invasive malignancy within 5 years of enrollment that may affect outcome of study Any noninvasive malignancy not treated with curative intent or with known active disease within 5 years before enrollment that may affect outcome of study Major surgery or significant traumatic injury occurring within 4 weeks before enrollment Active infection with Hepatitis B virus or Hepatitis C virus known infection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) Active infection requiring IV antiinfective therapy Subject is pregnant or breast feeding, or planning to become pregnant within 5 months after the end of treatment. Female subject of childbearing potential is not willing to use, in combination with her partner, 2 methods of highly effective contraception during treatment and for 5 months after the end of treatment. Clinically significant hypersensitivity to denosumab 120 mg. Known sensitivity to any of the products to be administered during the study (e.g. calcium, or vitamin D). Subject is receiving or is less than 14 days since ending other experimental drug (no marketing authorization for any indication). Any major medical or psychiatric disorder that, in the opinion of the investigator, might prevent the subject from completing the study or interfere with the interpretation of the study results.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
</DOC>