<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00192023</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is a phase IIIb multicentre, randomised, placebo controlled, trial in paediatric patients with Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity (ADHD) and Oppositional Defiant Disorder (ODD). The primary aim of the study is to evaluate the efficacy of atomoxetine in improving ADHD and ODD symptoms in patients non responders to a previous psychological intervention with parent support. Moreover, the potential role of atomoxetine in treating other psychiatric comorbid conditions associated with ADHD and ODD will be assessed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Italian Study of the Efficacy of Atomoxetine in the Treatment of Children and Adolescents With Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) and Comorbid Oppositional Defiant Disorder (ODD).</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit and Disruptive Behavior Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atomoxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Child or adolescent patients, male or female outpatients, who are at least 6 years of age, but must not yet have reached their 16th birthday prior to Visit 1, when informed consent is obtained. Patients must meet Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders Fourth Edition (DSMIV) diagnostic criteria for ADHD (any subtype) and ODD and score at least 1.5 standard deviations above the age norm for their diagnostic subtype using published norms for the Swanson, Nolan and Pelham Questionnaire: AttentionDeficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (SNAPIV ADHD) Subscale score at both Visit 1 and 2. They must also have a SNAPIV ODD subscale score of at least 15 at both Visit 1 and Visit 2. Other comorbid conditions, are allowed but the diagnosis of ADHD and ODD must be the patient's primary diagnosis. Patients must be of normal intelligence in the judgment of the investigator (that is, without a general impairment of intelligence and likely, in the investigator's judgement, to achieve a score of greater than or equal to 70 on an Intelligence Quotient (IQ) test). The administration of a formal IQ test is not an entry requirement for the study. Specific learning disabilities are not considered general impairment of intelligence. Patients who weigh less than 20 kilograms (kg) at study entry (Visit 1). Patients who have a documented history of Bipolar I or II disorder, any history of psychosis or pervasive development disorder. Patients with a history of any seizure disorder (other than febrile seizures) or patients who have taken (or are currently taking) anticonvulsants for seizure control are not eligible to participate. Patients at serious suicidal risk as assessed by the investigator. Patients who, in the investigator's judgment, are likely to need psychotropic medications apart from the drug under the study, including healthfood supplements that the investigator feels have central nervous system activity (for example, St. John's Wort, melatonin).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
</DOC>