<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT02729116</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluate oral antimicrobial agent treatment non-bacteremic acute urinary tract infection cause Extended Spectrum Beta Lactamase produce Escherichia coli Klebsiella pneumoniae Post-kidney transplantation . Patients treat intravenous ( IV ) antibiotic follow oral sitafloxacin IV ertapenem .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sitafloxacin Ertapenem Treatment Acute Urinary Tract Infection Caused E. Coli K. Pneumoniae Post-kidney Transplantation Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A prospective randomized control trial patient presumptive diagnosis acute urinary tract infection cause Extended Spectrum Beta Lactamase-producing Escherichia coli Klebsiella pneumoniae Post-kidney transplantation . Intravenous ( IV ) antibiotic initially give patient . After day 3 , patient randomize receive either oral sitafloxacin ( 100 mg twice daily ) intravenous ertapenem . The course treatment complete within 14 day .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Tract Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Klebsiella Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Escherichia coli Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ertapenem</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sitafloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluoroquinolones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt; 18 year Acute urinary infection definition Positive urine culture Extended Spectrum Beta Lactamase E. coli K. pneumoniae ≥105 colony form unit/mL Postkidney transplantation Voluntarily consent enrolled study Sepsis Positive blood culture Mixed organism urine culture Immunocompromised condition postkidney transplantation Pregnancy lactation Previous urinary tract infection within 4 week Contraindicated fluoroquinolones carbapenems</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Extended-Spectrum ß-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli</keyword>
	<keyword>Extended-Spectrum ß-lactamase-producing Klebsiella pneumoniae</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Urinary Tract Infections</keyword>
</DOC>