<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01069263</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the efficacy of hyperbaric oxygen therapy (HBOT) to intravesical Dimethyl Sulfoxide (DMSO) instillation for the treatment of patients who suffers from Interstitial Cystitis / Painful bladder syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparative Study Between Hyperbaric Therapy and Intravesical Dimethyl Sulfoxide Instillation for Interstitial Cystitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Interstitial cystitis / painful bladder syndrome (IC/PBS) presents as a pelvic pain condition associated with urinary urgency and frequency. These symptoms impair significantly the patient's quality of life. The etiology is yet not obvious. The current acceptable theory is injury or dysfunction of the Mucus (Glycosaminoglycans) layer that covers the inner surface of the urinary bladder. Abnormal diffusion of toxins from the urine to the walls of the bladder leads to inflammation, pain and scarring. Many types of treatments were described but most of them were not evaluated in well designed randomized controlled studies. For now, there is no one single treatment that gives good outcome to every patient. Therefore, the treatment of patients with IC/PBS is challenging. In this study, we will compare the efficacy of hyperbaric oxygen therapy (HBOT) to intravesical dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) instillation for the treatment of patients who suffers from IC/PBS. Patients with IC (NIDDK criteria) will be randomized to have either DMSO instillation or HBOT. Before and after treatments the patients will fill out questionnaires (O'Leary-Sant Interstitial Cystitis Symptom and Problem Index), visual analogue scale for pain and bladder diaries. In addition, urodynamics will be performed before and after treatments. In case of incomplete symptoms remission, patients will be crossed over to have the other treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cystitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystitis, Interstitial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dimethyl Sulfoxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>NIDDK diagnosis of interstitial cystitis Previous treatment of hyperbaric therapy Contraindication for hyperbaric therapy (midear pathology, abnormal chest Xray, Claustrophobia, pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Interstitial cystitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Painful bladder syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic pelvic pain</keyword>
	<keyword>DMSO</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperbaric oxygen therapy</keyword>
</DOC>