<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02384954</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase I/II, open-label, multi-center, competitive enrollment and dose escalation study of ALT-803 in patients with relapse/refractory indolent B cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma in conjunction with rituximab.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>QUILT-3.002: ALT-803 in Patients With Relapse/Refractory iNHL in Conjunction With Rituximab</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability, identify the Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) or the Minimum Efficacious Dose (MED) and designate a dose level for Phase 2. Also characterize the immunogenicity, pharmacokinetic profile, and biomarker serum levels of ALT-803 in treated patients. The effect of ALT-803 on the peripheral absolute lymphocyte counts and white blood cell counts, the number, phenotype and repertoire of peripheral blood T (total and subsets) and NK cells will be evaluated. In addition, a subset of patients will be evaluated for changes in lymph node immune composition. Anti-tumor responses and survival data will also be collected in this trial.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed diagnosis of iNHL (Follicular lymphoma grade 1, 2, 3a; marginal zone lymphoma; small lymphocytic lymphoma or lymphoplasmacytic lymphoma) after treatment with at least 1 or more prior rituximabcontaining regimens. AntiCD20 mAbrefractory disease is defined as progressive disease while on rituximab (or another treatment of an antiCD20 monoclonal antibody) or progression within 6 months of rituximabcontaining (or another treatment of an antiCD20 antibodycontaining) therapy. AntiCD20 mAbsensitive disease is defined by a response to a prior rituximabcontaining (or another treatment of an antiCD20 monoclonal antibody) regimen, and relapse more than 6 months from the last administration of rituximabcontaining (or another treatment of an antiCD20 antibodycontaining) therapy. Measurable disease: At least one lymph node group ≥ 1.5 cm in longest transverse dimension. Patients with cutaneous only disease may be enrolled if they have a clearly measurable skin lesion. Relapsed or Refractory iNHL that has progressed during or following 1 or more prior systemic rituximabcontaining (or another treatment of an antiCD20 antibodycontaining) regimens for lymphoma PRIOR/CONCURRENT THERAPY: No antilymphoma treatments within 28 days before the start of study treatment. Must have recovered from side effects of prior treatments. PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Performance Status • ECOG 0, 1, or 2 Renal Function • Glomerular Filtration Rate (GFR) &gt; 40mL/min or Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 X ULN Bone Marrow Reserve Platelets ≥30,000/uL Hemoglobin ≥ 8g/dL Absolute Lymphocytes ≥800/uL ANC/AGC ≥750/uL Hepatic Function Total bilirubin ≤ 2.0 X ULN (unless Gilbert's Syndrome or disease infiltration of liver is present) AST, ALT ≤ 3.0 X ULN, or ≤ 5.0 X ULN (if liver lymphoma is present) No positive Hep C serology or active Hep B infection Cardiovascular No congestive heart failure &lt; 6 months No unstable angina pectoris &lt; 6 months No myocardial infarction &lt; 6 months No history of ventricular arrhythmias or severe cardiac dysfunction No history of uncontrollable supraventricular arrhythmias No NYHA Class &gt; II CHF No marked baseline prolongation of QT/QTc interval Pulmonary • Normal clinical assessment of pulmonary function Other Negative serum pregnancy test if female and of childbearing potential Women who are not pregnant or nursing Subjects, both females and males, with reproductive potential must agree to use effective contraceptive measures for the duration of the study No known autoimmune disease other than corrected hypothyroidism No known prior organ allograft or allogeneic transplantation Not HIV positive No active CNS involvement with lymphoma No psychiatric illness/social situation that would limit compliance No other illness that in the opinion of the investigator would exclude the subject from participating in the study Must provide informed consent and HIPPA authorization and agree to comply with all protocolspecified procedures and followup evaluations No active systemic infection requiring parenteral antibiotic therapy No disease requiring systemic immunosuppressive therapy (inhaled or topical steroids are allowed). Adrenal replacement steroid doses ≤ 10 mg daily prednisone equivalent are permitted in the absence of active autoimmune disease. No known histologic transformation from iNHL to DLBCL</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>indolent B Cell</keyword>
	<keyword>non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Relapsed</keyword>
	<keyword>Refractory</keyword>
	<keyword>Rituximab</keyword>
	<keyword>Interleukin-15</keyword>
	<keyword>Absolute Lymphocyte Count</keyword>
	<keyword>White Blood Cell</keyword>
	<keyword>Follicular Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Marginal Zone Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphoplasmacytic Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>anti-CD20</keyword>
</DOC>