<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02472600</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This investigator initiated,international, multicenter open-label, randomized controlled trial aims to assess whether a 5 day course of oral nonabsorbable antibiotics (colistin sulfate 2 million IU per os 4x/day and neomycin sulfate 500 mg (salt) per os 4x/day ) followed by fecal microbiota transplantation (administered either via nasogastric administration or via capsules) is effective at eradicating intestinal carriage of beta-lactamase producing Enterobacteriaceae (ESBL-E) and carbapenemase producing Enterobacteriaceae (CPE). compared to no intervention (current standard of care) in adult non-immunosuppressed patients .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Eradication of Antibiotic-resistant Bacteria Through Antibiotics and Fecal Bacteriotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In recent years a certain family of bacteria (Enterobacteriaceae) that colonizes the human gastrointestinal tract but can also cause severe infections has increasingly become resistant to antibiotics by acquiring enzymes that can inactivate a wide array of these valuable drugs. Depending on the class of beta-lactam antibiotics that these enzymes can inactivate, these bacteria are either designated as extended spectrum beta-lactamase producing Enterobacteriaceae (ESBL-E) or carbapenemase producing Enterobacteriaceae (CPE). The R-GNOSIS project which is financed by the European Commission combines five separate international clinical studies (work packages 2 to 6) that examine intervention strategies to reduce carriage, infection and spread of these bacteria. This study (work package 3 of R-GNOSIS) will be conducted in 4 centers in 3 European countries (Switzerland, France, The Netherlands) and Israel. The study will examine whether it is possible to eradicate intestinal carriage with ESBL-E and CPE by administering a 5 day course of oral nonabsorbable antibiotics (colistin sulfate and neomycin sulfate) followed by administration of "healthy" stool flora obtained from a healthy volunteer donor ("fecal microbiota transplantation" or FMT). The "healthy" stool flora for this procedure will be obtained from carefully selected healthy volunteers that have been tested for a wide variety of infectious diseases and do not show any risk factors or risky behavior for transmittable diseases. Once the fecal material has been processed it will be frozen at -80°C for up to six months until administration to patients (via capsules or via a nasogastric tube). FMT has been successfully used to treat recurrent infections with a specific pathogen (Clostridium difficile) and has proven safe and effective for this indication but has never been studied with the aim of eradicating multidrug-resistant organisms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colistin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neomycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Omeprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients (&gt;= 18 years at date of inclusion) Ability to provide informed consent Documented intestinal carriage of ESBLE and / or CPE by stool culture at baseline (visit 0) IF COLONIZED WITH ESBLE ONLY (WITHOUT CPE): At least one episode of symptomatic infection with ESBLE requiring systemic antibiotic therapy within the last 180 days before date of inclusion (based on the last day of antibiotic therapy for that infection) Pregnancy or planned pregnancy Breastfeeding Difficult / impossible followup Allergy or other contraindication to one of the study drugs Recurrent aspirations / chronic dysphagia Resistance to colistin (defined as MIC&gt; 2 mg/l) of any of the ESBLE or CPE strains isolated at baseline Estimated life expectancy &lt; 6 months Treatment with any systemic antibiotic on the day of inclusion Severe immunodeficiency Systemic chemotherapy ≤30 days from baseline or planned chemotherapy within the next 6 months Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) with CD4 count &lt; 250/mcl Prolonged use of steroids (prednisone equivalent ≥ 60 mg per day for &gt;= 30 days) or other immunosuppressive medications neutropenia with absolute neutrophil count &lt;1000/μL, Solid organ transplant Hematopoeitic stem cell transplant recipients Other causes of severe immunodeficiency Current hospitalization in an Intensive Care Unit Estimated glomerular filtration rate (CKDEPI) &lt; 15 ml/min/1.73m2 Severe food allergy (anaphylaxis, urticaria) Unavailability of compatible FMT preparation (with regard to donor / recipient cytomegalovirus, EpsteinBarr virus and toxoplasma serology) Anatomic contraindication to the placement of a nasogastric tube (only if FMT application via nasogastric tube)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>extended spectrum beta-lactamase producing enterobacteriaceae</keyword>
	<keyword>carbapenemase producing enterobacteriaceae</keyword>
	<keyword>multidrug resistant bacteria</keyword>
</DOC>