<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02472054</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this project is to study the number of surviving patients until hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) after first line treatment of hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis (HLH) by Alemtuzumab</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Familiar Lymphohistiocytosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis (HLH) or lymphohistiocytic activation syndrome is an inflammatory condition caused by a uncontrolled proliferation of activated lymphocytes and macrophages secreting an excess of inflammatory cytokines. Familial hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis (FHL) is a rare disorder of the immune system, which is invariably fatal when untreated. Treatment requires the achievement of remission of HLH prior to allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation, the only curative therapy to date. Despite significant progress in the treatment, mortality remains high and an important number of patients will die before being eligible for HSCT. A better understanding of the pathophysiology of FHL has opened new avenues for immunotherapy. Based on previous observations concerning the utilization of Anti-thymoglobulins (ATG) for the treatment of patients with FHL, the protocol propose a new therapeutic strategy using Alemtuzumab in association with steroids as first line treatment in FHL. This proposition is based on the hypothesis that Alemtuzumab, capable of killing T lymphocytes efficiently in vivo, should be better tolerated than ATG. In fact, in contrast to the mechanism of action of ATG, Alemtuzumab does not activate T lymphocytes. A better tolerance and efficacy of Alemtuzumab is expected in the treatment of the hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytic syndrome. This may have a positive impact not only on survival until HSCT, but also on overall survival and quality of life with regard to long-term neurological sequelae. This is a multicenter, open, phase I/II, non-comparative, non randomized study. Patients are recruited by the investigators during hospitalization for a first episode of lymphohistiocytic activation syndrome requiring specific treatment. Several visits (including the final visit) are scheduled within the trial over a period of approximately 10 months for all patients, from the signature of the consent up to 6 months after hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. The recruitment period will be 30 months; the total period of the study is 40 months. The treatment consists in an intravenous administration of CAMPATH®. For the research purpose, investigators will collect specific samples for: - biobank (Cytokine dosage) at the inclusion visit and the day prior to the conditioning; - pharmacokinetics of CAMPATH® : at every cure of CAMPATH® and every week. Also diagnostic lumbar puncture at the inclusion visit, day 14 is required to document the response to treatment and to determine the result of the therapeutic care. The efficacy of the treatment will be measured to Day14, Day21 and Day28. All adverse events must be reported in the e-Case Report Form (e-CRF)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphohistiocytosis, Hemophagocytic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alemtuzumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria : Patient &lt; 18 years Patient with diagnosis of hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytic syndrome confirmed by at least one of the following two criteria : Genetic diagnosis FHL or other genetic disease predisposing to HLH like ChediakHigashi syndrome, Griscelli syndrome type II and Xlinked lymphoproliferative syndrome type I and II (XLP1 and XLP2) or positive family history of HLH Presence of at least 5 of the following 8 criteria (diagnostic criteria as defined by the "Histiocyte Society" ) : Fever Splenomegaly Cytopenia (affecting at least two cell lineages : Hemoglobin &lt;9.0 g / dl, Platelets &lt;100.000/μl, Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt;1.000/µl) Hypertriglyceridemia and / or hypofibrinogenemia (Fasting triglycerides ≥ 3 mmol / l, Fibrinogen ≤ 1.5 g / l) Haemophagocytosis found in a histological specimen (without evidence of a malignant process and rheumatic disease) Decreased or absent NK function (&lt;10% of the laboratory standard) Ferritin ≥ 500μg / l Soluble CD25 ≥ 2.400U/ml or presence of activated T cells in the immune phenotyping Patient without prior specific treatment of lymphohistiocytic activation syndrome or under treatment with corticosteroids and / or ciclosporin. Patient beneficiary of a health insurance scheme Holder (s) of parental authority who signed the informed consent Man or woman in reproductive age willing to take reliable contraceptive measures during the treatment and 6 months after the end of the treatment Specific situation of patients with neurological involvement : Most patients with neurological involvement caused by a HLH will meet the inclusion criteria. However some patients may present an isolated neurological involvement as the first manifestation of familiar lymphohistiocytosis as described in the literature. These patients do not always present all the inclusion criteria. However their clinical condition may justify their inclusion prior to the confirmation of a genetic diagnosis and/or the detection of all required diagnostic inclusion criteria. In the absence of the required 5 out of 8 diagnostic criteria, the eventual inclusion of patients with predominant neurological involvement will be evaluated by a scientific committee to judge their inclusion or not in the study. The remaining inclusion and exclusion criteria must be fulfilled. A written report will be established. Exclusion Criteria : Age ≥ 18 years Patients previously treated with AntiThymoglobulin (SAL), etoposide (VP16) or Alemtuzumab. Confirmed or suspected diagnosis of a malignant or rheumatic disease Contraindication (s) to the administration of Alemtuzumab : Hypersensitivity to murine proteins or to any of the excipients (sodium chloride, dibasic sodium phosphate, potassium chloride, potassium dihydrogen phosphate, polysorbate 80, disodium edetate dihydrate, and water for injection) General evolving infection except infections that are the triggering factor of the HLH . HIV Progressing malignant tumors Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis (HLH)</keyword>
	<keyword>Alemtuzumab (CAMPATH®)</keyword>
</DOC>