<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02079246</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the long-term safety and tolerability of idalopirdine (Lu AE58054) as adjunctive therapy to donepezil in patients with mild-moderate Alzheimer's Disease (AD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-term Safety and Tolerability of Idalopirdine (Lu AE58054) as Adjunctive Treatment to Donepezil in Patients With Mild-moderate Alzheimer's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an interventional, multi-national, multi-site, open-label extension study in patients with mild to moderate AD who completed study 14861A (NCT01955161) or 14862A (NCT02006641). Patients will receive 28-weeks of treatment with idalopirdine 60 mg/day (option to reduce to 30 mg/day) as adjunctive treatment to donepezil. Approximately 100 patients, who have completed the initial 28-week period, will be included in an 24 weeks open-label treatment period with memantine (sub-study) that will evaluate the safety and tolerability of adding memantine therapy in patients who are already on a stable treatment of idalopirdine and donepezil and for whom memantine treatment is clinically indicated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Memantine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Donepezil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient has completed Visit 7 (Completion Visit) in the leadin doubleblind, placebo controlled clinical studies 14861A/NCT01955161 or 14862A/NCT02006641. For patient in the memantine substudy: The patient has completed Visit 6 (Week 28) of the openlabel extension study The patient, according to the judgement of the investigator, requires initiation of treatment with memantine as per local label/SmPC/treatment guidelines The patient has a moderate or severe ongoing adverse event from the leadin study considered a potential safety risk by the investigator. The patient has experienced seizures before Completion Visit in the leadin study. The patient has evidence of clinically significant disease. The patient's donepezil treatment is likely to be interrupted or discontinued during the study. The patient is receiving therapy with another acetylcholinesterase inhibitors (AChEI) Other protocoldefined inclusion and exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>