<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02831140</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This prospective, randomized study is designed to evaluate the effectiveness of postoperative care pathway using the Fast Track Rehabilitation protocol (FTR) in comparison with the traditional postoperative care. In order to conduct this study, patients having a thoracic surgery will be randomly attributed to FTR protocol group or control group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Fast Track Rehabilitation in Thoracic Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Traditionally, patients who underwent thoracic surgery have been treated with a classical protocol which include; bed rest, ambulation prohibited for 24-48 hours and starvation for several postoperative days till the recovery of bowel. Some studies reported the efficacy of early rehabilitation protocols or FTR protocols in thoracic surgery to reduce postoperative complications and to minimize hospital stay. But these studies are few and retrospective. Prospective randomized trials focuses based on the "fast track regimen" or medical fast track that interest only on the medical component . This prospective, randomized study is designed to evaluate the effectiveness of postoperative care pathway using FTR protocol in comparison with the traditional postoperative care. In order to conduct this study, patients having a thoracic surgery will be randomly attributed to FTR protocol group or control group.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>All patients who have lung surgery during the study period after their consents are included. Patients who have bad general state are unable to move or require a wake in the resuscitation. The Patients with thoracic soft tissue surgery. patients having mediastinoscopy, surgery of the chest wall or mediastinum.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fast track</keyword>
	<keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>post operative complications</keyword>
</DOC>