<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01433744</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The hypotheses tested were that levels of C-Reactive Protein (CRP) would be higher in patients with chronic periodontitis in comparison with those without periodontal disease and that the non-surgical periodontal treatment would decrease levels of CRP in patients with chronic periodontitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Short-term Changes on C-Reactive Protein (CRP) Levels After Non-surgical Periodontal Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients should have ≥ 20 teeth present; (ii) absence of oral soft tissue lesions; (iii) have ≤ 3 carious lesions in all teeth. In addition, to be included in the Test group the subject had to present chronic periodontitis (involvement of at least 5 teeth with at least one site presenting probing depth (PD) ≥ 5 mm and clinical attachment loss (CAL) ≥ 3 mm) while to be included in the Control group the patient had to exhibit periodontal healthy (bleeding on probing (BOP) &lt; 30% of the sites and absence of any PD &gt; 4mm associated with BOP). (i) periodontal disease treatment in the previous six months; (ii) aged less than 35 years; (iii) systemic conditions such as history of CVD or any other chronic or immunologic diseases and the use of related drugs in the previous six months; (iv) smokers or former smokers; (v) pregnant or lactating women; (vi) hypertension (&gt;140 systolic and &gt; 90 diastolic mmHg); (vii) obesity (Body Mass Index (BMI) ≥ 30 kg/m²); (viii) levels of HDLcholesterol &gt; 35.0 mg/dL (ix) levels of LDLcholesterol &lt; 160.0 mg/dL (x)levels of triglycerides &lt; 400.0 mg/dL and (xi) levels of glucose levels &lt; 100 mg/dL.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>C-Reactive protein</keyword>
	<keyword>risk</keyword>
</DOC>