<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01433250</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will assess the long-term safety and tolerability of AIN457 in patients with relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis (RRMS). In addition the long-term pattern of maintenance of efficacy and health related quality of life will be explored.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability and Efficacy of AIN457 in Patients With Relapsing-remitting Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis, Relapsing-Remitting</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Was exposed to AIN457 or placebo in study CAIN457B2201 and completed the CAIN457B2201 study, up to at and including Visit 10 (week 24). 1. Have been treated with: immunosuppressive medications such as azathioprine or methotrexate within 1 month prior to enrollment, if lymphocyte count normal. immunoglobulins and/or monoclonal antibodies (with the exception of AIN457) within 2 month prior to enrollment, or if the immunosuppressive effects are likely to persist at enrollment (such as presence of B cell depletion after rituximab treatment). 2. Have received total lymphoid irradiation, bone marrow transplantation, alemtuzumab, cladribine, cyclophosphamide, mitoxantrone or other immunosuppressive treatments with longlasting (over 6 months) or permanent effects. 3. Have received any live or live attenuated vaccines (including live vaccines for varicellazoster virus or measles) within 2 months prior to enrollment. 4. A diagnosis of chronic disease of the immune system other than MS, or of an immunodeficiency syndrome. 5. Current severe depression. 6. Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women. 7. Malignancy diagnosed since enrollment in the core study (except for successfullytreated basal or squamous cell carcinoma of skin). 8. A new diagnosis of diabetes 9. Positive testing for tuberculosis (QuantiFeron or chest Xray). 10. Subjects with clinically significant cardiac abnormalities 11. Unable or unwilling to undergo multiple venipunctures 12. Unable to undergo MRI scans due to newly acquired claustrophobia or metallic implants incompatible with MRI. Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Sclerosis,</keyword>
	<keyword>demyelinating autoimmune diseases,</keyword>
	<keyword>interleukin-17,</keyword>
	<keyword>monoclonal human antibody</keyword>
</DOC>