<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02407743</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to determine what causes pain after surgery to increase or decrease over time.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TEMporal PostOperative Pain Signatures</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Before surgery, study participants will be asked questions about age, gender, race/ethnicity, annual income, and education level. Study participants will also be questioned regarding prior pain experiences, their mood and how they think about pain. A small test tube of blood, a cheek swab or a saliva sample will be taken to see what genetic differences may influence individuals pain after surgery. After surgery, study participants will be asked questions about their pain intensity while in the hospital. Additional information will be collected about the effects of pain medicine, and their recovery from surgery. Following discharge from the hospital, study participants will be contacted monthly to confirm continued communication. Study participants will also be contacted six months after surgery, and asked to complete a final survey about their pain after surgery.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years of age or older anticipated length of hospital stay of 72 hours or greater expected postoperative survival greater than 6 months &lt; 18 years of age anticipated need for prolonged postoperative intubation (greater than 24 hours) urgent or emergent surgical procedure inability to understand or participate in questionnaires, surveys or data collection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>postoperative pain</keyword>
	<keyword>surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>pain resolution</keyword>
	<keyword>pain intensity</keyword>
	<keyword>persistent postsurgical pain</keyword>
	<keyword>pain-related genes</keyword>
	<keyword>analgesic</keyword>
</DOC>