<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02407444</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims to evaluate whether a combination of cycling training as part of physiotherapy treatment will contribute more than conventional physiotherapy treatment for elderly patients after hip fracture surgery in their subacute phase of rehabilitation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment Efficacy of Leg Cycling as Part of Physiotherapy Treatment in Elderly Patients With Hip Fracture</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Adults who have experienced a fall, followed by proximal hip fracture that required surgery, suffer from specific problems that interrupt the rehabilitation period in their subacute phase. Various modes of treatment available as part of the physical rehabilitation but there is not enough data in the literature regarding the contribution of cycling training with leg cycle ergometer as part of conventional physiotherapy treatment in elderly patients after hip fracture surgery. This study evaluates whether the additional cycling to physiotherapy treatment will improve the functional ability, the balance performance while standing, hip muscle strength and pain level in those patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Proximal hip fracture with full or partial weight bearing indication. Surgical fixation ( nailing or total hip replacement or hemiarthroplasty) Premorbid function: walking independently or under supervision with or without assistance aid Cognitive function: Minimental state examination score above 21 Pathological hip fracture. Unstable heart or pulmonary disease. Presence of other fractures as a result of the current fall. Neurological comorbidities ( CVA, Parkinson, MS ). Entering the rehabilitation center more than three weeks after hip surgery</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>95 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Proximal hip fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>Elderly patients</keyword>
	<keyword>Physiotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Leg cycling ergometer</keyword>
</DOC>