<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02407197</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Myocardial fibrosis is the fundamental substrate for the development of heart failure. Cardiovascular magnetic resonance (CMR) allows non-invasive assessment of myocardial fibrosis based on late gadolinium enhancement (LGE) and T1 mapping. Patients: Prospective longitudinal observational multicenter study of consecutive patients with suspected or known non-ischemic cardiomyopathy. Imaging: Non-invasive measures of myocardial fibrosis: native T1, extracellular volume fraction (ECV) and LGE. Primary endpoints: all cause and cardiovascular mortality. Secondary endpoints: arrhythmic composite and HF composite endpoints.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>International T1 Multicentre CMR Outcome Study in Patients With Nonischaemic Cardiomyopathies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients fulfilling the criteria of NICM OR presence of structural heart disease OR exhibiting myocardial LGE in nonischemic pattern of LGE on CMR OR subjects with high pretest probability for cardiomyopathy persistent symptoms comorbidities first degree relative of a patient with known cardiomyopathy family history of sudden cardiac death (SCD) known or suspected myocardial infiltration due to amyloidosis, iron accumulation, lipidstorage disease or edema due to active myocardial inflammation known ischemic heart disease (IHD) based on at least one of the following: significant documented coronary artery disease (CAD), previous coronary revascularization, previous a history of myocardial infarction, or evidence of ischemic typeLGE or significant inducible ischemia on CMR history of renal disease with a current eGFR&lt;30 mL/min/1.73m2 signifact structural valvular disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>T1 mapping</keyword>
	<keyword>CMR</keyword>
	<keyword>Outcome</keyword>
	<keyword>multicenter</keyword>
</DOC>