<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02344784</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to show that Prepulse inhibition test of acoustic startle response is an indicator of objective diagnostic characteristics of attention deficit disorder in children and adolescents. by demonstrating that Prepulse inhibition test of acoustic startle response is impaired in children and adolescents suffering from attention deficit disorder in the relation to the normal function described in the literature. The investigators will try to prove our hypothesis by an experiment that consists of two phases: Phase I (about 25 minutes): The patient will enter the room, will be asked to sit on a chair, and will be asked to look at a computer screen showing silent video of aquarium fish, then the patient will be connected to both the Prepulse inhibition test device and the Galvanic skin response device and pass the tests. Phase II (about 25 minutes): After completion of Phase I, each participant will receive his daily regular dose of methylphenidate and after an hour and a half from taking the drug, will repeat the tests, both the Prepulse inhibition test and the Galvanic skin response test. Duration of the entire experiment is 140 minutes (two hours and twenty minutes).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Characteristics of Prepulse Inhibition in Children and Adolescents Suffering From Attention Deficit Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylphenidate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Between the ages of 718 2. Diagnosed with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder according to Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders, fifth edition Clinical diagnostic interview was performed. 3. Receive drug therapy with methylphenidate doses ranging from 0.3 mg / kg to 1 mg / kg. 4. The participant is treated with methylphenidate at least two months prior to the experiment. 1. Autism. 2. Chronic neurological diseases. 3. Developmental delay. 4. Psychotic or major effective disorder (psychotic state now or in the past, schizophrenia, schizoaffective, depression, bipolar disorder) 5. Substance abuse. 6. Mental retardation. 7. Contraindicated for the treatment of methylphenidate. 8. Hearing problems. 9. Pregnancy week 20 and thereafter</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ADD</keyword>
	<keyword>ADHD</keyword>
	<keyword>PPI</keyword>
</DOC>