<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02344849</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase I clinical trial is designed to evaluate the safety of autologous Mesenchymal Stem Cells (MSC) injected intracavernously.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety of Autologous Bone Marrow Derived Mesenchymal Stem Cells in Erectile Dysfunction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cellgram-ED is autologous bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells ex vivo expanded for approximately 30 days. Ten patients (Diabetes -associated ED; 5 patients, Postprostatectomy; 5patients) will be injected Cellgram-ED directly into the intracavernous. Patient will be evaluated the safety and potential efficacy of MSC.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Erectile Dysfunction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Postprostatectomy Erectile Dysfunction A man aged 20 or older Who is willing to consent to participate in the study concerned with improving sexual activity after prostatectomy, the man has maintained normal sexual activity prior to prostatectomy Prior to prostatectomy PSA (prostate specific antigen) level&lt;10 ng/mL At the time of Prostatectomy, Pathological Gleason sum ≤7 At the time of Prostatectomy, Pathological stage ≤ T2c 2 years or more postprostatectomy patients with PSA level ≤ 0.04 ng/mL without additional therapy after prostatectomy Who cannot satisfy sexual activity(more than 4 times) with proper sexual stimulation in spite of taking maximum dose of oral PDE5I(phosphodiesterasetype5 inhibitors) within last 8weeks. IIEF, EF(erectile function) domain score is under 17 Have a consistent partner who is willing to engage in sexual activity more than twice per month during the study. Diabetesassociated Erectile Dysfunction HbA1c is between 6.5% and 10% of man over 20 years of age with diabetes Who cannot satisfy sexual activity(more than 4 times) with proper sexual stimulation in spite of taking maximum dose of oral PDE5I within last 8weeks. IIEF, EF domain score is under 17 Who is willing to consent to participate in the study concerned with improving sexual activity Have a consistent partner who is willing to engage in sexual activity more than twice per month during the study. History of bone marrow disorders Serum AST/ALT &gt; 3 X upper limit of normal or Creatinine &gt; 1.5 X upper limit of normal History of hypersensitivity against a gentamycin Severe cardiovascular disease(angina, arrhythmia, cardiac failure, stroke), kidney failure, respiratory failure Positive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B virus (HBV), hepatitis C virus (HCV) and syphilis test Positive for PSA or CEA or AFP (Carcinoembryonic antigen), history of cancer in the last five years (except Prostatic cancer) Uncontrolled hypertension or hypotension (systolic blood pressure &gt; 170 or &lt; 90 mm Hg, diastolic pressure &gt; 100 or &lt; 50 mm Hg) HbA1c exhibit greater than 10% Men on anticoagulant treatment Have a severe infectious disease Testosterone level is less than 200ng/dl Have a penile implant or willing to it Patients with morphological changes of the penis Patient's partner is trying to conceive during the trial period Unwilling to participate in the study Participating in other clinical trials in the past 30 days Unable to compliance with protocol Inappropriate patients to participate in the study according to the investigator</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>