<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01926002</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary hypothesis of the study is single doses of MK-8351 will reduce the baseline early asthmatic response (EAR) as assessed by area under the curve from 0-3 hours (AUC0-3hr) of forced expiratory volume (FEV1) when compared to placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Single-Dose Study of MK-8351 in a Lung Allergen Challenge (MK-8351-003)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, 4-period study. Eligible patients will undergo a single-blind phase in Period 1, followed by 3 periods during which they will receive low-dose MK-8351, high-dose MK-8351, or matching placebo as a single dose in a random sequence crossover study design.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Females of nonchildbearing potential (at least 1 year postmenopausal, posthysterectomy, postoophorectomy, or with tubal ligation); Males with a female partner of childbearing potential must agree to use a medically acceptable method of contraception during and up to 120 days after the last dose of study medication; Body Mass Index (BMI) &gt;=17 kg/m^2 and &lt;=33 kg/m^2 Nonsmoker and nonuser of nicotine or nicotinecontaining products for at least 6 months prior to enrollment; History of allergeninduced asthma for at least 6 months prior to enrollment; Able to perform reproducible pulmonary function testing; Positive methacholine challenge test prior to receiving study medication; Allergic response to house dust mite allergen or standardized cat pelt or hair allergen extract; Ability to tolerate sputum induction and to produce adequate sputum. History of clinically significant disease or disorder; History of malignancy; History of significant multiple and/or severe allergies; History of milk or lactose allergies or intolerance; History of anaphylactic reaction or significant intolerability to prescription or nonprescription drugs or food; Positive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B surface antigen, or hepatitis C antibodies; History of major surgery within 3 months prior to enrollment; Participation in another investigational trial within 4 weeks of screening; Lactating females; Inability to refrain from, or anticipates the use of, any medication including herbal remedies during the trial period; History of receiving antiimmunoglobulin E (IgE) or immunotherapy; History of serious allergies to drug or a history of hypersensitivity to inhaled salbutamol, antihistamines, or any other potential asthma/anaphylaxis rescue medication; History of hospitalization for asthmarelated illness within 3 months of screening; History of emergent care more than twice in the last 12 months for asthmarelated illness; History of lifethreatening asthma; Consumes &gt;4 glasses of alcoholic beverage per day; Consumes &gt;6 servings of coffee, tea, cola, energy drinks or other caffeinated beverages per day; History or or current use of illicit drugs within past 24 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>