<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01960309</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a cross-sectional pilot study to assess coronary artery disease with minimal invasive techniques in patients with asymptomatic troponin elevation after noncardiac surgery. The primary objective is to quantify coronary artery disease, as determined by coronary CT and MR, as a cause of postoperative myocardial injury. The secondary objective is to correlate coronary calciumscore to postoperative levels of troponin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Minimal Invasive Imaging of Coronary Artery Disease in Patients With Asymptomatic Myocardial Injury After Major Non-cardiac Surgery.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Major noncardiac surgery with a planned minimal postoperative hospital stay of 2 days Age &gt; 59 years Troponin_I elevation &gt; 0.06 ng/ml in the first 3 postoperative days No clinical symptoms of myocardial ischemia Perioperative troponin elevation due to other factors than coronary artery disease such as proven pulmonary embolism or sepsis Perioperative STelevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) Perioperative symptomatic angina with troponin elevation Patients with a history or ECGsigns of myocardial infarction Patients with preexistent heart failure, left ventricular dysfunction, significant valvular disease or left ventricle hypertrophy Patients with significant valvular disease or left ventricle hypertrophy determined postoperatively with echocardiography. Contraindication for CMR such as claustrophobia or metal prosthesis Allergic reaction to CTcontrast or gadolinium Renal dysfunction with GFR &lt; 50 ml/min, as determined after the operation Unstable hemodynamics or other conditions disabling transport to the Radiology department Expected major discomfort or substantial increase in pain sensation by undergoing CCTA or CMR Admission at the ICU Poor prognosis due to other medical conditions e.g. malignancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>