<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00382174</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability and effectiveness of Thymosin Beta 4 administered topically in patients with Pressure Ulcers</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Thymosin Beta 4 in Patients With Pressure Ulcers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-escalation study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability and effectiveness of Thymosin Beta 4 (Tβ4), administered topically, in patients with Pressure Ulcers (PU). PU is caused by prolonged pressure or rubbing of the body in areas prone to moisture and friction. PU affects primarily elderly, bedridden patients. Tβ4 is a synthetically-produced copy of a naturally-occurring 43 amino acid peptide that has wound healing and anti-inflammatory properties and can up-regulate the expression of laminin-5.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pressure Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Informed Consent Form signed by the patient or patient's legal representative Inpatients and outpatients At least 1 PU with fullthickness skin loss and no joint capsule or bone exposure Surface area between 5 and 70 cm2 Ulcer present and stable for at least 1 month before enrollment Use of any experimental drug, or participation in any clinical study, within the 60 days before enrollment Use of immunotherapy, or cytotoxic chemotherapy within the 60 days before enrollment. Systemic steroids not allowed 30 days prior to enrollment. Topical therapy other than steroidal is allowed up to 7 days prior to enrollment History of adverse events to any ingredients of study medication Neurological, cardiovascular, respiratory, hepatic, renal, or metabolic disease likely to interfere with the patient's participation in or completion of the study Arterial or venous disorder resulting in ulcerated wounds Diabetes mellitus except if disease is determined to be under control with a glycosylated hemoglobin ≤8.5% of total hemoglobin Pregnancy or breastfeeding during the study. (A serum pregnancy test will be performed at Screening for female patients of childbearing potential.)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>pressure ulcers</keyword>
	<keyword>cutaneous wound- healing</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic wound-healing</keyword>
	<keyword>Thymosin Beta 4</keyword>
	<keyword>laminin-5</keyword>
</DOC>