<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01081834</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of 2 different doses of canagliflozin administered as monotherapy compared with placebo in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) inadequately controlled with diet and exercise.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The CANTATA-M (CANagliflozin Treatment and Trial Analysis - Monotherapy) Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Canagliflozin is a drug that is being tested to see if it may be useful in treating patients diagnosed with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). This is a randomized (study drug assigned by chance), double blind (neither the patient or the study doctor will know the name of the assigned treatment), parallel-group, 3 arm (patients will be assigned to 1 of 3 treatment groups) multicenter study to determine the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of canagliflozin (100 mg and 300 mg) compared to placebo (a capsule that looks like all the other treatments but has no real medicine) in patients diagnosed with T2DM who are not achieving an adequate response from diet and exercise to control their diabetes. Approximately 450 patients with inadequate glycemic control with diet and exercise will receive once-daily treatment with canagliflozin 100 mg or 300 mg once daily for 52 weeks or 26 weeks of double-blind treatment with placebo followed by 26 weeks of sitagliptin 100 mg (sitagliptin is an antihyperglycemic agent that will allow patients randomized to the placebo group to improve glycemic control and remain in the study). Patients will participate in the study for approximately 60 to 68 weeks (referred to as the Main Study). The study will also include a High Glycemic Substudy in 50 to 100 patients with T2DM who have poorer glycemic control with diet and exercise. Patients in the substudy will be assigned to receive double-blind canagliflozin 100 mg or 300 mg for 26 weeks and the total duration of patient participatation in the substudy will be approximately 34 to 42 weeks. During treatment, if a patient's fasting blood sugar remains high despite treatment with study drug and reinforcement with diet and exercise, the patient will receive treatment with metformin (rescue therapy) consistent with local prescribing information. Study drug will be taken orally (by mouth) once daily before the first meal each day unless otherwise specified. Patients will take single blind placebo for 1 or 2 weeks (wks) before randomization to the Main Study or the High Glycemic Substudy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Canagliflozin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sitagliptin Phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All patients must have a diagnosis of T2DM Patients in the main study must have a Hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) between &gt;=7% and &lt;=10% and a fasting plasma glucose (FPG) &lt;270 mg/dL (15 mmol/L) Patients in the High Glycemic Cohort Substudy must have an HbA1c between &gt;10% and &lt;=12% and a FPG &lt;=350 mg/dL (19.44 mmol/L) History of diabetic ketoacidosis, type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM), pancreas or beta cell transplantation, diabetes secondary to pancreatitis or pancreatectomy, or a severe hypoglycemic episode within 6 months before screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</keyword>
	<keyword>Canagliflozin</keyword>
	<keyword>Placebo</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemoglobin A1c</keyword>
	<keyword>Type 2 diabetes mellitus</keyword>
</DOC>