<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03028701</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall objective is to asses the bronchodilator effect of single dose of Formoterol/Budesonide 12/400 mcg fixed combination delivered via Discair® in patients with COPD. Spirometric measurements (FEV1, FVC) will be performed for a period of 12 h at 12 different times: pretreatment (prior to the first dose) and posttreatment (15. min, 30. min, 1 hr, 2 hr, 3 hr, 4 hr, 5 hr, 6 hr, 8 hr, 10 hr ve 12 hr).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of Bronchodilator Efficacy of Formoterol/Budesonide 12/400 mcg Via Discair in COPD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The overall objective is to asses the bronchodilator effect of single dose of Formoterol/Budesonide 12/400 mcg fixed dose combination delivered via Discair® in patients with COPD. Patients will be assigned to receive single dose of Formoterol/Budesonide 12/400 mcg fixed dose combination delivered via Discair® (test product, n = 33). Patients will be evaluated at 4 consecutive visits: baseline (enrollment), screening, treatment, and end of treatment (24h after treatment). For newly diagnosed and formerly diagnosed patients who are not on COPD medication, the screening visit will be performed on the day of enrollment. For formerly diagnosed patients receiving COPD treatment, the day of the screening visit will be based on the completion of a run-in period, with the length determined by the specific medication. During the run-in period, salbutamol (100 μg inhaler) will be prescribed as a rescue medication. Spirometric measurements (FEV1, FVC) will be performed for a period of 12 h at 12 different times: pretreatment (prior to the first dose) and posttreatment (15. min, 30. min, 1 hr, 2 hr, 3 hr, 4 hr, 5 hr, 6 hr, 8 hr, 10 hr ve 12 hr).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bronchodilator Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Formoterol Fumarate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Budesonide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients aged ≥40 years with newly or formerly diagnosed moderate to severe COPD (Patients with postbronchodilator FEV1/FVC ratio &lt;0.70, and FEV1 &lt;80% of predicted normal. Patients have chronic cough or chronic productive cough with breathlessness even walking slowly along flat ground.) Current smokers or exsmokers with a smoking history of at least 10 packyears Patients who have no exacerbation within last 4 weeks Females patients with childbearing potential using effective birth control method Patients who has a capability of communicate with investigator Patients who accept to comply with the requirements of the protocol Patients who signed written informed consent prior to participation Patients who have history of hypersensitivity to drugs contains longacting beta2agonist or corticosteroids Patients who have abnormal blood glucose level ((≥140 mg/dl) Patients who have unregulated diabetes mellitus Patients who have a serum potassium level of ≤3.5 mEq/L or &gt;5.5mEq/L Patients who have asthma Patients who have a history of myocardial infarction, severe hearth failure, acute ischemic coroner disease or severe cardiac arrhythmia requiring treatment within least 6 weeks Patients who have lung cancer Patients vaccinated with live attenuated vaccines within 2 weeks prior to screening visit or during runin period. Patients who had COPD exacerbation or lower respiratory track infections that required antibiotic, oral or parenteral corticosteroid treatment within 4 weeks prior to screening visit or during runin period. Women who are pregnant or nursing History of allergic rhinitis or atopy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Formoterol</keyword>
	<keyword>Budesonide</keyword>
	<keyword>Dry powder inhalation</keyword>
	<keyword>Discair</keyword>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
</DOC>