<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="142847">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01241253</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NTS0020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01241253</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Glycemic Response of Bean-and-rice Meals in Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
  <official_title>Glycemic Response of Bean-and-rice Meals in Persons With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Arizona State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Dry Bean Council</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Arizona State University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study uses a randomized, placebo-controlled experimental design consisting of 4
      different test treatments matched on carbohydrate (CHO) content. The three beans are similar
      in their CHO content amount for ½ cup at ~20 grams CHO. Each of the bean varieties will be
      served in a ~½ cup serving size with ~ ½ cup of plain steamed white rice (30 grams CHO) for
      a total of 50 grams of CHO per meal for each of the three test treatments. The 4th placebo
      or control treatment consists of ~ 7/8 cup of rice alone, an amount consistent with the CHO
      content of the test meals. Most diabetic meal plans recommend no more than 45-60 grams of
      CHO per meal. Fifty grams of CHO is a standard amount for glycemic response testing in
      general.

      The investigators hypotheses were:

        -  The test meals containing the three bean types in combination with white rice will
           decrease the participants' glycemic response when eaten as part of a meal.

        -  The reduction in post-prandial glycemia will not differ between bean types in the
           elicited responses among individuals with type 2 diabetes.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The 4 test treatments will be administered randomly on a different morning, at least one
      week apart. Participants will be required to consume the entire test treatment meal in 7
      minutes while being observed. All test foods will be purchased from local markets. Capillary
      blood samples will be collected (~50µl) at time 0 (fasting) and at 30, 60, 90, 120 and 180
      minutes post-treatment (timing of the post-treatment blood draws started at time 0
      [post-treatment], which is when the participant finishes consuming the treatment meal).
      Venous blood draws for insulin assessment will also be acquired at fasting and then every
      hour for the three hour study period. Anthropometric measures such as weight, height and
      waist circumference will be collected at screening and at the start of each test day.
      Thirteen hours before testing, participants will eat a control meal to reduce variation in
      glycemic responses on test days due to varying dietary intakes. This control meal will be
      selected by each participant before the start of the study. They will be provided a gift
      card to the chain restaurant to use to purchase their own meal. Since subjects serve as
      their own controls, the meals must be identical before each test draw. Participants will
      complete 24 hour recall food records the morning of each test day to provide information
      related to dietary protocol compliance.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Net blood glucose changes over time</measure>
    <time_frame>fasting baseline glucose at time 0, then 30, 60, 90, 120, 150, and 180 minutes postprandial</time_frame>
    <description>Capillary blood samples were collected via fingerstick using Safe-T-Fill® Lithium Heparin Mini Capillary Collection 125µl tubes (RAM Scientific, Yonkers, NY). Whole blood samples were analyzed for glucose content using the Yellow Springs Instrument Stat Plus Analyzer (YSI Life Sciences, Yellow Springs, OH) immediately after blood collection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">17</enrollment>
  <condition>Blood Glucose</condition>
  <condition>Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cross-over study</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>beans and rice in a 50 gram carbohydrate dose</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Whole cooked beans with rice meals</intervention_name>
    <description>Three types of bean-and-rice meals all equal to 50 grams available CHO. Control treatment was 50 grams available CHO in the form of white rice alone.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cross-over study</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Bush Brothers &amp; Company brand canned beans</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Eligible subjects will be between the ages of 35 and 75, have a body mass index value
             (BMI) between 22-40 kg/m2, be physician diagnosed with type 2 diabetes for at least
             six (6) months and currently controlling their blood glucose levels using dietary
             methods, exercise and/or through the use of oral hypoglycemic agents such as
             Metformin for at least three(3)months, and have an HbA1c &lt;10%.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Exclusion criteria included: the presence of unresolved health issues (e.g.
             hypertension not controlled by medication), evidence of condition(s) that would
             influence the participant's ability to complete the study such as gastrointestinal
             disease, weight changes of ≥10% of the participants body weight within a 6 month
             period, women who are either pregnant or breastfeeding, allergy to beans or latex, an
             HbA1c level &gt;10% at screening, and the inability to follow study protocol.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Donna M Winham, DrPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Arizona State University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Arizona State University, Nutrition Program</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mesa</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85212</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 12, 2010</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>October 27, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Donna M Winham</name_title>
    <organization>Arizona State University</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>legumes</keyword>
  <keyword>glycemic response</keyword>
  <keyword>glucose</keyword>
  <keyword>type 2 diabetes mellitus</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
