<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02078648</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the safety and efficacy of SL-701 as a treatment for recurrent glioblastoma multiform (GBM).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of SL-701, a Glioma-Associated Antigen Vaccine To Treat Recurrent Glioblastoma Multiforme</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Poly ICLC</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Poly I-C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboxymethylcellulose Sodium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years of age or older. Histologically confirmed GBM or World Health Organization (WHO) Grade IV variants (gliosarcoma, glioblastoma with oligodendroglial features, or giant cell glioblastoma). Uneqivocal evidence of a first tumor recurrence or progression on the initial treatment regimen (prior to enrollment on this study), consisting of surgical intervention (biopsy and/or resection), radiation, and temozolomide chemotherapy, as assessed by MRI or CT scan of the brain with or without contrast within 14 days prior to the start of SL701. If receiving corticosteroids, the dose must be stable or decreasing for at least 5 days prior to the scan. Patients unable to undergo MRI because of noncompatible devices can be enrolled, provided CT scans are obtained and are of sufficient quality. For each patient, the same imaging technique should be performed throughout the study, for purposes of assessing tumor response or PD. For patients who have undergone resection of recurrent or progressive tumor prior to study enrollment, the following conditions must apply: Recovery from the effects of surgery. Residual disease following resection of recurrent tumor is not mandated for eligibility into the study. To best assess the extent of residual disease postoperatively, an MRI should be performed: No later than 96 hours (h) in the immediate postoperative period; or At least 4 weeks postcraniotomy (7 days for stereotactic biopsy), within 14 days prior to the start of SL701, and on a corticosteroid dosage that has been stable or decreasing for at least 5 days. Patients who have not had resection of recurrent or progressive disease must have measurable disease. At least 56 of the approximately 76 patients treated must have measurable disease, defined as at least one, contrastenhancing lesion measuring at least 1 cm in 2 planes (axial, coronal, or sagittal). No evidence of hemorrhage on the baseline MRI or CT scan other than those that are Grade ≤ 1 and either postoperative or stable on at least two consecutive scans. Recovery from prior therapy toxicity, defined as resolution of all treatmentrelated adverse events (AEs) to Grade ≤ 1 or pretreatment baseline (except alopecia and lymphopenia). At least 12 weeks from prior radiotherapy to the start of SL701 unless there is new enhancement outside of the radiation field or unequivocal histopathologic evidence of recurrent tumor. No chemotherapy or investigational agent for at least 3 weeks prior to the start of SL701, with at least 6 weeks of elapsed time from last dose of nitrosoureas. Human leukocyte antigen (HLA)A2 positive. A tumor tissue sample is provided for immunohistochemical analysis of relevant antigens, immune markers and potential prognostic factors. Preferably a paraffin block or 1012 unstained slides will be submitted prior to study entry. Patients for whom tumor samples are unavailable or inadequate are permitted to participate in the study; however, the absence of available/adequate tumor specimen must be documented. Karnofsky performance status (KPS) score ≥ 70%. Adequate organ function, including the following: Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1,000/μL, platelets ≥ 100,000/μL. Serum creatinine &lt; 1.5 × the upper limit of normal (ULN). Bilirubin &lt; 1.5 × ULN. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &lt; 2.5 × ULN. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 3 days prior to the start of SL701 treatment. Female patients of childbearing potential and sexually active male patients must agree to use an acceptable form of contraception for heterosexual activity (ie, oral contraceptives, double barrier methods, hormonal injectable, transdermal, or implanted contraceptives, tubal ligation, or vasectomy of their sexual partner(s) for &gt; 40 days before Screening, during the study, and for 60 days after the last dose of study drug. Men should not donate semen during the study and for 60 days after the last dose of study drug. Female patients without childbearing potential (spontaneous amenorrhea for &gt; 12 months or surgically sterilized by tubal ligation, hysterectomy, or bilateral oophorectomy &gt; 6 months before Screening) are eligible for inclusion without contraceptive use restriction. Able and willing to comply with protocol requirements, in the opinion of the investigator. A written and voluntarily signed informed consent must be obtained from the patient or legally authorized representative, in accordance with local regulations, before the initiation of any study related procedures. The patient or legally authorized representative must be able to read and understand the informed consent form (ICF). Prior cancer chemotherapy, bevacizumab (or other vascular endothelial growth factor [VEGF]/VEGF receptor [VEGFR]directed agent), or an investigational agent for recurrent/progressive GBM or prior bevacizumab as part of initial therapy (prior chemotherapy or investigational agents are permitted as part of initial therapy; VEGF/VEGFRdirected agents are not permitted). Contrastenhancing tumor that is any of the following: Multifocal (defined as two separate areas of contrast enhancement measuring at least 1 cm in 2 planes that are not contiguous on either fluidattenuated inversion recovery (FLAIR) or T2 sequences); Associated with either diffuse subependymal or leptomeningeal dissemination; or ≥ 4 cm in any dimension. Requirement of systemic corticosteroid therapy &gt; 4 mg/day of dexamethasone or equivalent or requirement of increasing dose of systemic corticosteroids during the 7 days prior to the start of SL701 treatment. Surgical resection or major surgical procedure within 4 weeks prior to the start of SL701, or stereotactic biopsy within 7 days prior to the start of SL701. Radiation therapy, local therapy (except for surgical reresection), or systemic therapy following first recurrence/progressive disease. Excluded local therapies include stereotactic radiation boost, implantation of carmustine biodegradable wafers (Gliadel), intratumoral or convectionenhanced delivery administered agents, etc. Active infection requiring intravenous antibiotics. History of cancer (other than GBM) within the past 2 years that has metastatic or local recurrence potential and could negatively impact survival and/or potentially confound tumor response assessments within this study. Clinically significant cardiovascular disease (eg, uncontrolled or any New York Heart Association Class 3 or 4 congestive heart failure, uncontrolled angina, history of myocardial infarction or stroke within 6 months of study entry, uncontrolled hypertension or clinically significant arrhythmias not controlled by medication). Known immunosuppressive disease or active systemic autoimmune disease such as systemic lupus erythematosus, human immunodeficiency virus infection, Hepatitis B, or Hepatitis C, or has taken an immunosuppressive agent within 4 weeks prior to the start of SL701 treatment. Patients with vitiligo, type 1 diabetes mellitus, hypothyroidism due to autoimmune condition only requiring hormone replacement therapy, psoriasis not requiring systemic therapy, or conditions not expected to recur in the absence of an external trigger are permitted to enroll. Any condition which in the investigator's opinion makes the patient unsuitable for study participation. Requires therapeutic anticoagulation with warfarin at baseline; patients must be off warfarin or warfarinderivative anticoagulants for at least 7 days prior to starting study drug; however, therapeutic or prophylactic therapy with lowmolecular weight heparin is allowed. Has history of known coagulopathy that increases risk of bleeding or a history of clinically significant hemorrhage within 12 months of start of study drug. Has evidence of intratumoral or peritumoral hemorrhage on baseline MRI scan other than those that are ≤Grade 1 and either postoperative or stable on at least 2 consecutive MRI scans Has gastrointestinal bleeding or any other hemorrhage/bleeding event National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) &gt;Grade 3 within 6 months of start of study drug.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Glioma Associated Antigen</keyword>
	<keyword>Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Adult</keyword>
	<keyword>Recurrent Glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>