<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00564954</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study compared the efficacy of dex-methylphenidate extended release 20 mg versus placebo during an 8-hour laboratory classroom day.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Dex-methylphenidate Extended Release in Children (6-12 Years) With Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylphenidate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexmethylphenidate Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female subjects aged 612 years, inclusive. Subjects meeting the DSMIV criteria for ADHD of any type, as established by the KSADSPL (Kiddie Schedule for Affective Disorders and SchizophreniaPresent and Lifetime Version). If a DSMIVdefined ADHD diagnosis is difficult to establish due to possible comorbidity, the subject will not be enrolled into the study. Subjects should be on a stabilized total daily dose or nearest equivalent of 4060 mg methylphenidate or 2030 mg of dmethylphenidate for at least two weeks prior to screening visit (Concerta® 36 mg and 54 mg is allowable) Parent or guardian unable or unwilling to complete the Conner's ADHD/DSMIV Scale for Parents (CADSP) and the Daily Diary Card Diagnosed with a tic disorder or Tourette's syndrome History of seizure disorder The presence of a known medical condition that would preclude the use of methylphenidate. A history (within the past year) or presence of clinically significant cardiovascular, cerebrovascular, renal, hepatic, gastrointestinal, pulmonary, immunological, hematological, endocrine, or neurological disease ALT, AST, GGPT or serum creatinine greater then 2X the ULN at Screening A history of psychiatric illness or substance use disorder (e.g., schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, autism, abuse or dependence, depression, severe Conduct Disorder or severe Oppositional defiant disorder) Subjects who have participated in an investigational trial within the past 4 weeks (28 days) are excluded Subjects who are currently taking antidepressants or other psychotropic medication Subjects who have initiated psychotherapy during the three months prior to randomization Subjects with a positive urine drug screen Subjects who have a history of poor response or intolerance to methylphenidate or dmethylphenidate Other protocol defined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>ADHD</keyword>
	<keyword>children</keyword>
	<keyword>laboratory classroom</keyword>
	<keyword>Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</keyword>
</DOC>