<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00564811</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study was to verify the influence of Agaricus blazei (Murrill) ss. Heinemann (A. blazei) on the evolution of nutritional state and liver function in hepatitis C patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Agaricus Blazei (Murrill) ss. Heinemann (Sun Mushroom)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Ten patients were studied (5 - GI - not taking A. blazei - and 5 - G2 - taking A. blazei), from both sexes, with positive Anti-VHC and a healthy nutritional state, admitted into in the viral hepatitis ward. Diagnosis and treatment for hepatitis C concurred with the regulations of the Ministry of Health and nutritional evaluation was performed in 3 moments according to anthropometrical, bioimpedance, biochemical and dietary standards, with duration of 6 months. The consumption of A. blazei (10g/day) in dehydrated powder was concomitant with antiviral therapy (conventional or pegylated interferon associated with ribavirin) with duration of 5 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Viral, Human</mesh_term>
	<criteria>To have been informed and signed adequately the free and clarified assent Initiating the antiviral treatment (interferon or pegylated interferon associate the ribavirin) Age: 2470 years Gender :both the gender Race : all races To present serology positive to the antiVHC ELISA To present genotype type 1,2,or 3 Body mass index &gt;18,5 e &lt; 35kg /m2 Conditions full to the ORAL ingestion Don't agree to the project or don't have signed the term of clarified free assent Restriction for oral ingestion The existence of surface of antigen of the hepatitis B virus(Ag HBs) The existence of antibody for the human immunodeficiency virus To be enclosed in another project of research or form of treatment Pregnant women Suckles Cirrhosis Patients with hepatitis autoimune.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>24 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Agaricus blazei (Murrill) ss. Heinemann,</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C</keyword>
	<keyword>Nutritional status</keyword>
	<keyword>Liver Function Tests</keyword>
	<keyword>Antiviral Agents</keyword>
</DOC>