<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00588809</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II clinical trial is studying how well selumetinib works in treating patients with recurrent or refractory acute myeloid leukemia. Selumetinib may stop the growth of cancer by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Selumetinib in Treating Patients With Recurrent or Refractory Acute Myeloid Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the response rate (includes complete response-CR, complete response with incomplete count recovery CRi, partial response-PR, and minor response-MR) to AZD6244 (selumetinib). SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the effects of AZD6244 in AML samples on p-ERK and evaluate the potential utility of p-ERK inhibition as a surrogate marker of biologic activity. II. To correlate the effects of AZD6244 with the presence (or absence) of mutated RAS or FLT-3 at baseline. III. To assess the safety profile of AZD6244 in patients with AML. OUTLINE: Patients receive selumetinib orally (PO) twice daily (BID) on days 1 -28. Treatment repeats every 4 weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed for 52 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myeloproliferative Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic-Myeloproliferative Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Promyelocytic, Acute</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of 1 of the following: Relapsed or refractory acute myeloid leukemia (AML) Secondary AML including AML arising from antecedent hematologic diseases (e.g., myelodysplastic syndrome, myeloproliferative disorders, or therapyrelated AML) Elderly patients ≥ 60 years of age, previously untreated, and who are not candidates for or have refused standard chemotherapy are eligible for this trial Patients with relapsed acute promyelocytic leukemia (APL) who are FLT3+ and have failed both tretinoin and arsenic therapy are eligible for this trial No known active CNS disease ECOG performance status (PS) 02 or Karnofsky PS 60100% Total bilirubin ≤ 2 mg/dL (unless due to disease, hemolysis, or Gilbert disease) In patients with associated hemolysis or Gilbert disease, a bilirubin of &gt; 2 mg/dL is allowed as a result of predominantly unconjugated hyperbilirubinemia AST/ALT &lt; 3 times upper limit of normal Creatinine &lt; 2 mg/dL Baseline pulse oximetry &gt; 92% Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception prior to, during, and for 4 weeks (16 week for males) after completion of study treatment Recovered from prior therapy At least 2 weeks since prior chemotherapy (6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin C) or radiotherapy Hydroxyurea may be administered for the first 7 days of therapy in patients with rapidly rising white count (WBC &gt; 20 K/μL) At least 4 weeks since prior investigational agents No prior MEK inhibitors No concurrent medication that can prolong the QT interval No other concurrent investigational agents No concurrent combination antiretroviral therapy for HIVpositive patients History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biological composition to AZD6244 or its excipient Captisol® QTc interval &gt; 450 msecs or other factors that increase the risk of QT prolongation or arrhythmic events (e.g., heart failure, hypokalemia, or family history of long QT interval syndrome), including New York Heart Association class III or IV heart failure Refractory nausea and vomiting, chronic gastrointestinal diseases (e.g., inflammatory bowel disease), or significant bowel resection that would preclude adequate absorption Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection or psychiatric illness or social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>