<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00588666</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Gemcitabine and carboplatin are two standard chemotherapy drugs used to treat tumors of the urothelial tract. These drugs do not shrink tumors in all patients and when they do, it is generally for a limited amount of time. This has led scientists to look for different ways to treat cancer. New drugs have been developed to treat cancer that work differently than standard chemotherapy drugs. One new class of drugs are called 'angiogenesis-inhibitors'. These drugs attempt to decrease the blood supply to tumors. By doing so, this may limit the tumor's source of oxygen and nutrients and prevent the tumor from growing. Bevacizumab is an anti-angiogenic drug. In some other cancers such as colon cancer and lung cancer, combining bevacizumab with standard chemotherapy shrinks tumors in a greater proportion of patients and makes patients live longer than using standard chemotherapy alone. This has never been tested in urothelial cancer and we do not know if bevacizumab will have the same effects in this disease. The purpose of this study is to find out what effects, good and/or bad, the combination of gemcitabine, carboplatin, and bevacizumab has on you and your cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II Trial of Gemcitabine, Carboplatin, and Bevacizumab in Chemotherapy Naive Patients With Advanced/Metastatic Urothelial Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase II trial of gemcitabine, carboplatin, and bevacizumab in chemotherapy naïve patients with advanced/metastatic transitional cell carcinoma (TCC) of the urothelial tract.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myeloproliferative Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologic documentation: diagnosis of transitional cell carcinoma of the bladder,urethra, ureter, or renal pelvis. Unresectable or metastatic disease Ineligible for cisplatin (or incurable with cisplatin) ≥ 4 weeks since prior RT Karnofsky Performance Status ≥ 60% Age ≥ 18 years of age Required Initial Laboratory Values: Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1.2 x 109/L; Platelets ≥ 100 x 109/L; Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times the upper limit of normal (x ULN) for the institution; Aspartate transaminase (AST) and alanine transaminase(ALT) ≤ 3.0 x ULN;Serum creatinine &lt; 2.0 or calculated creatinine clearance (CrCl) ≥ 30 mL/min Prior treatment with systemic chemotherapy (prior intravesical therapy is permitted) Current, recent (within 4 weeks of the first infusion of this study), or planned participation in an experimental drug study other than a Genentechsponsored bevacizumab cancer study Blood pressure of &gt;150/100 mmHg Unstable angina New York Heart Association (NYHA) Grade II or greater congestive heart failure History of myocardial infarction within 6 months History of stroke within 6 months Clinically significant peripheral vascular disease Evidence of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy Presence of central nervous system or brain metastases Major surgical procedure, open biopsy, or significant traumatic injury within 28 days prior to Day 0 Anticipation of need for major surgical procedure during the course of the study Minor surgical procedures such as fine needle aspirations or core biopsies within 7 days prior to Day 0 Pregnant (positive pregnancy test) or lactating Albuminuria as demonstrated by a urinary albumin of greater or = to 1.0 g/24 hr at screening History of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation, or intra abdominal abscess within 6 months prior to Day 0 Serious, nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture Inability to comply with study and/or followup procedures History of persistent gross hematuria</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Myeloproliferative Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>urinary bladder</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>ureter</keyword>
	<keyword>renal pelvis</keyword>
	<keyword>chemotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>