<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02036996</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to collect heart rate, respiration data and motion data of patients admitted to sleep lab and to determine the current accuracy level of the EarlySense system vs. the standard system, and predicate device for EarlySense (Embla) used in sleep lab in monitoring heart rate and respiration rates monitors (ECG, respiratory belts, oximeter) that are currently used in the sleep lab among different population (Obese, patients with or without apnea, patients with or without arrhythmia). It is emphasized that no interpretations or clinical decisions will be made based on data received from the ES study device.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of EarlySense; a Contact-less Heart and Respiration Rate Monitoring in Sleep Lap Examined</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study objective is to collect heart rate, respiration rate and motion data of patients admitted to sleep lab and to determine the accuracy level of the EarlySense system vs. the monitors used in sleep lab (e.g., Polysomnography, respiratory belts, ECG, etc..) . Data regarding sleep condition, scoring and quality of sleep and in and out of bed status, patient turns will also be collected and compared to data collected by EarlySense contactless monitor. Different patient population will be monitored including obese, morbidly obese, patients with or without obstructive/central apnea, patients with or without arrhythmia as well as healthy population who arrive to sleep lab for general evaluation will be monitored</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 18 years or more 2. Is willing to sign the consent form. Age &lt; 18 years Is not willing to sign the consent form.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>