<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02036580</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of multiple-doses of tralokinumab in Japanese patients with Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>D2212C00002 J-Phase II Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase II, multicenter, blinded within cohort, dose-escalation study to evaluate the safety and tolerability of two ascending doses of tralokinumab in Japanese patients aged ≥ 50 years with mild to moderate Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Idiopathic Interstitial Pneumonias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Provision of informed consent prior to any study specific procedures Confirmed IPF diagnosis for ≤ 5 years prior to Visit 1 (screening). Confirmation of diagnosis of IPF Mild to moderate IPF to include all of the following at Visit 1 1. FVC ≥ 50% and ≤ 90% predicted normal 2. Partial pressure of oxygen in arterial blood (PaO2) of ≥ 55 mmHg on room air, or oxygen saturation by pulse oximetry (SpO2) of ≥ 90% on room air at rest 3. Hemoglobincorrected diffusion capacity for carbon monoxide (DLCO) ≥ 30% and ≤ 90% predicted normal History of clinically significant environmental exposure (eg, domestic and occupational) to a known cause of pulmonary fibrosis Diagnosis of connective tissue disease or drug toxicity as the likely cause of the interstitial disease A suspected IPF exacerbation not fully resolved and treatment completed ≤ 14 days prior to Visit 1 A suspected IPF exacerbation during the screening period A FEV1/FVC ratio &lt; 0.70 at the time of Visit 1 (postbronchodilator) The extent of emphysema on the HRCT is greater than the extent of fibrosis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Japan</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase2</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Tolerability</keyword>
	<keyword>Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>IPF</keyword>
	<keyword>CAT-354</keyword>
	<keyword>Tralokinumab</keyword>
</DOC>