<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02542839</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary cervical dystonia (PCD) is the most common form of focal dystonia. PCD is frequently reported as a source of disability, decreased quality of life, and social stigma. Botulinum toxin (BoNT) is the gold standard treatment for PCD. The average duration of benefits from BoNT injections was about 9.5 weeks and BoNT treatment is known to provide only pure symptomatic benefits and does not seem to modify the disease pathophysiology. The investigator plans to use repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) therapy as an adjunctive therapy in combination with BoNT injections as a novel approach to treat PCD. The primary goal of this study is to compare standard treatment with BoNT versus BoNT combined with a two week course of rTMS.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>rTMS and Botulinum Toxin in Primary Cervical Dystonia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>rTMS refers to the application of transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) pulses to a specific target at predefined stimulation parameters. Repeated sessions of rTMS therapy have been demonstrated to induce cumulative persistent benefits that can last weeks after the conclusion of the rTMS sessions The central hypothesis of this study is that rTMS therapy in PCD can potentiate the effects of BoNT injections. With the current standard treatment, the peak-dose benefits seen with BoNT are seen at about 4-6 weeks after the administration of injections. The investigator will introduce a 2 week course of rTMS at this peak-dose period (6 weeks after BoNT). The investigator will examine the effects of combined therapy at 10 weeks after BoNT and 12 weeks after BoNT injections follow-up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dystonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dystonic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Torticollis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of PCD in accordance with the Consensus Statement of the Movement Disorder Society Subjects who report Botulinum Toxin benefits lasting 10 weeks or less only (suboptimal benefits with standard care) Pregnancy Active seizure disorder Presence of a metallic body such as pacemaker, implants, metal rods and hearing aid.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Botulinum Toxin</keyword>
	<keyword>Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</keyword>
</DOC>