<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02542072</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the subjective performance of comfilcon A lens against samfilcon A lens after 4 weeks of reusable lens wear.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multi-Center Clinical Evaluation of Two Reusable Soft Contact Lenses</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This will be a 90 subject, randomized, bilateral, subject-masked, dispensing, cross-over study comparing comfilcon A versus samfilcon A lenses over 8 weeks of daily wear (2 x 4-weeks). Both eyes will wear the same lens (test or control) for 4 weeks in a randomized fashion. Subjects will be masked to lens type and investigators will be masked to the lens codes.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Inclusion: Spherical distance Contact Lens prescription between 1.00 and 6.00D or +1.00 to +4.00D in both eyes (inclusive) Adapted soft Contact Lens wearers (i.e. &gt;1 month), daily disposable and reusable lens wearers. Spectacle cylinder 0.75D in both eyes. Correctable to 6/9 (20/30) in both eyes Be between 18 and 50 years of age (inclusive) Able to read, comprehend and sign an informed consent Own a mobile phone and be willing to respond to Short Message Service (SMS) survey Willing to comply with the wear and study visit schedule Exclusion: Existing Biofinity or Ultra wearers Any active corneal infection, injury or inflammation Systemic or ocular allergies, which might interfere with Contact Lens wear Systemic disease, which might interfere with Contact Lens wear Ocular disease, which might interfere with Contact Lens wear Strabismus or amblyopia Subjects who have undergone corneal refractive surgery Subjects with keratoconus or other severe corneal irregularity contraindicating lens wear Pregnant or lactating Use of systemic/topical medication contraindicating Contact Lens wear Diabetic Site employees or family members of site employees</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>