<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01463241</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall objective of the project is to develop and assess the feasibility of a brief, practice-friendly approach to psychotherapy for children, entitled Behavioral and Affective Skills in Coping (BASIC) and designed for use as a first step toward evidence-based practice by practitioners in clinical service settings.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Behavioral and Affective Skills in Coping (BASIC) Open Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators seek to develop a treatment protocol that integrates five core intervention principles that are common to evidence-based treatments for youth depression, anxiety, and disruptive behavior problems. The protocol will be designed for implementation in everyday community practice settings by practitioners. Because many empirically supported treatments for youth disorders address only one area of impairment, they may not be an ideal fit to community clinics, where (a) most practitioners treat an array of disorders rather than specializing in just one, (b) most referred youths present with multiple disorders, and (c) priority problems and treatment needs may shift for many youths during an episode of care. Moreover, because many evidence-based treatments have been developed in research settings, they may not be designed in ways that are ideal for front-line therapists in community settings. The investigators hope to reduce the difficulty of transporting treatments into community practice by incorporating the perspectives of community practitioners in the development and design of the protocol. By incorporating the feedback of expert treatment developers, the investigators hope to ensure that BASIC is not only appealing to users but also consistent with what has been learned through treatment research over the years. Finally, the trial will provide preliminary evidence on whether this brief "first course" in evidence-based treatment is beneficial for youths with depression, anxiety, and disruptive behavior problems—three clusters that account for a large percentage of youth referrals.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Problem Behavior</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit and Disruptive Behavior Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>815 yearold youth The youth will meet diagnostic criteria for one or more target disorders in the broad areas of anxiety (including Generalized Anxiety Disorder, Separation Anxiety Disorder, Social Phobia, Obsessive Compulsive Disorder, Specific Phobia, Panic Disorder, Anxiety Disorder Not Otherwise Specified, Adjustment Disorder with Anxiety), depression (including Major Depressive Disorder, Dysthymic Disorder, Minor Depression, Depressive Disorder Not Otherwise Specified, Adjustment Disorder with Depressed Mood), and conduct (Oppositional Defiant Disorder, Conduct Disorder, Disruptive Behavior Disorder Not Otherwise Specified, Adjustment Disorder with Disturbance of Conduct). Youth with primary ADHD Youth with developmental disorders Youth with symptoms of a thought disorder including delusions and hallucinations</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>