<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01463553</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to: 1. Evaluate the validity of using abnormal characteristics of the pneumothorax line, as evaluated from chest X-ray film, as the operative indications for video-assisted thoracic surgery (VATS) on primary spontaneous pneumothorax (PSP). 2. Through a randomized double blind controlled trial on patients whose PSP was caused by lung bullae, evaluate the effectiveness of pleurodesis in terms of the rate of recurrence of PSP and the trauma of the operation on patients. 3. Based on the findings, establish selection standards for the timing of surgery to treat PSP by VATS and establish technical specifications for performing operations on different types of lung bullae. The goal is to improve the diagnosis and treatment of PSP so as to reduce the recurrence rate of pneumothorax, reduce the trauma of operation, shorten hospital stays and postoperative recovery time, and provide better services for returning to everyday life and improving the quality of life for patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Primary Spontaneous Pneumothorax (PSP) Treatment Techniques in VATS</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pneumothorax</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. patients in whom obvious bullous forms are seen in PSP pneumothorax lines, or whose pneumothorax lines are rough and interrupted with or without thoracentesis, thoracic close drainage 2. patients whose lung compression exceeded 30% for the first incidence of pneumothorax 3. patients between the ages of 14 and 40, with normal vital signs (body temperature, breathing, blood pressure, pulse) and normal results on routine examination (routine blood test, liver and kidney functions) 4. no language barrier, such as surdimutism, aphasia 5. patients who voluntarily joined the group and signed the informed consent after reviewing the substance, significance and risks of this experiment 1. patients who refuse VATS operation 2. patients who refuse the followup 3. patients with secondary spontaneous pneumothorax including that caused by emphysema, COPD, asthma, pulmonary lymphangiomyomatosis, thoracic injury and other diseases 4. patients with mental illness, low IQ, or inability to understand the informed consent 5. substance abusers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>primary spontaneous pneumothorax</keyword>
	<keyword>VATS</keyword>
	<keyword>pleurodesis</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrence rate</keyword>
</DOC>