<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01426867</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to describe the ocular discomfort immediately upon instillation of Brinzolamide 1%/Brimonidine 0.2% Tartrate Ophthalmic Suspension, Brinzolamide 1% Ophthalmic Suspension, and Brimonidine Tartrate 0.2% Ophthalmic Solution in subjects with open-angle glaucoma and/or ocular hypertension.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Comfort Study of Brinzolamide 1% / Brimonidine 0.2% Fixed Combination, Brinzolamide 1% and Brimonidine 0.2%</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma, Open-Angle</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ocular Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brimonidine Tartrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brinzolamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Sign Informed Consent document. Diagnosis of openangle glaucoma or ocular hypertension Other protocolspecified inclusion criteria may apply. Females of childbearing potential if pregnant, lactating, or not using highly effective birth control measures. Severe central vision loss in either eye. Any chronic or recurrent inflammatory eye disease. Ocular trauma within the preceding 6 months. Ocular infection or ocular inflammation within the preceding 3 months. Bestcorrected visual acuity score worse than 55 letters using the Early Treatment Diabetic Retinopathy Study chart. Any intraocular surgery within the preceding 6 months. Any ocular laser surgery within the preceding 3 months. History or current evidence of severe illness or any other conditions which would make the subject, in the opinion of the Investigator, unsuitable for the study. Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Open-Angle Glaucoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Ocular Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Intraocular Pressure</keyword>
	<keyword>Brinzolamide</keyword>
	<keyword>Brimonidine</keyword>
</DOC>