<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02299570</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is the first prospective, multi-center, double-blinded, randomized controlled study of a microbiota suspension derived from intestinal microbes. Patients who have had at least two recurrences of C. difficile infection (CDI) after a primary episode and have completed at least two rounds of standard-of-care oral antibiotic therapy or have had at least two episodes of severe CDI resulting in hospitalization may be eligible for the study. Patients whose CDI returns in less than 8 weeks after the last assigned study treatment may be eligible to receive up to 2 treatments with RBX2660 in the open-label portion of the study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Microbiota Restoration Therapy for Recurrent Clostridium Difficile Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is the first prospective, multi-center, double-blinded, randomized controlled study of a microbiota suspension derived from intestinal microbes. The primary assessments for this study are (i) efficacy of RBX2660 compared to placebo at 8 weeks and (ii) safety via assessment of adverse events. Study visits are at 1-, 4- and 8-weeks after treatment with additional follow-up at 3, 6 12 and 24 months post treatment. Patients who have had at least two recurrences of C. difficile infection (CDI) after a primary episode and have completed at least two rounds of standard-of-care oral antibiotic therapy or have had at least two episodes of severe CDI resulting in hospitalization may be eligible for the study. Patients whose CDI returns in less than 8 weeks after the last assigned study treatment may be eligible to receive up to 2 treatments with RBX2660 in the open-label portion of the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Enterocolitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>≥ 18 years Medical record documentation of recurrent CDI either: a) at least two recurrences after a primary episode and has completed at least two rounds of standardofcare oral antibiotic therapy or b) has had at least two episodes of severe CDI resulting in hospitalization. Documented history that the subject's recurrent CDI is controlled while on antibiotics even if the subject is not currently on antibiotics. A positive stool test for the presence of C. difficile within 60 days prior to enrollment. A known history of continued C. difficile diarrhea while taking on a course of antibiotics prescribed for CDI treatment. Requires antibiotic therapy for a condition other than recurrent CDI. Previous fecal transplant prior to study enrollment. History of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), e.g., ulcerative colitis, Crohn's disease, or microscopic colitis. History of irritable bowel syndrome (IBS). History of chronic diarrhea. History of celiac disease. Colostomy. Planned surgery requiring perioperative antibiotics within 6 months of study enrollment. Life expectancy of &lt; 12 months. Compromised immune system.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Clostridium difficile</keyword>
	<keyword>C diff</keyword>
	<keyword>CDI</keyword>
	<keyword>CDAD</keyword>
	<keyword>Fecal transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Fecal Microbiota Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Diarrhea</keyword>
	<keyword>FMT</keyword>
	<keyword>Microbiota restoration therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Microbiota suspension</keyword>
	<keyword>Fecal bacteriotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>C diff diarrhea</keyword>
</DOC>