<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02299505</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Phase I study to assess the systemic exposure, effiacy, and safety of 450 mg ceritinib taken with a low-fat meal and 600 mg ceritinib taken with a low-fat meal as compared with that of 750 mg ceritinib taken in the fasted state in adult patients with ALK rearranged (ALK-positive) metastatic non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetic and Safety Study of Lower Doses of Ceritinib Taken With a Low-fat Meal Versus 750 mg of Ceritinib in the Fasted State in Adult Patients With (ALK-positive) Metastatic Non-small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ceritinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion: 1. Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of stage IIIB (and is not a candidate for definitive multimodality therapy) or IV ALKpositive NSCLC. 2. Patients may have received one prior treatment regimen with crizotinib (all other ALK inhibitors are excluded). 3. Patients may have received prior chemotherapy, biologic therapy, or other investigational agents. ALK inhibitors other than crizotinib are excluded. 4. Patient has a World Health Organization (WHO) performance status 02. Exclusion: 1. Prior treatment with an ALK inhibitor other than crizotinib. 2. History of carcinomatous meningitis. 3. Presence or history of a malignant disease other than an ALKpositive advanced tumor that has been diagnosed and/or required therapy within the past 3 years. 5. Clinically significant, uncontrolled heart disease and/or recent cardiac event (within 6 months) 6. Patient has history of interstitial lung disease or interstitial pneumonitis, including clinically significant radiation pneumonitis (i.e., affecting activities of daily living or requiring therapeutic intervention). 7. Patient has other severe, acute, or chronic medical conditions 8. Patient is currently receiving treatment with warfarin sodium (Coumadin®) or any other coumarinderivative anticoagulants.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>LDK378</keyword>
	<keyword>ceritinib</keyword>
	<keyword>Alk+</keyword>
	<keyword>Alk positive</keyword>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
	<keyword>lung Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>