<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02299154</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims to prospectively examine the memory problem perceptions of patients with memory complaints [MCs] and their accompaniers during the diagnostic process.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Memory Problems Perceptions Among Patients and Accompaniers During Diagnosis Process :</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Through the french adaptation of the "illness perception questionnaire memory", this study aims to prospectively examine the memory problem perceptions of patients with memory complaints [MCs] and their accompaniers during the diagnostic process. The investigators plan to recruit 125 patients with MCs who come for the first time at the Research and Resources Memory Center in Nancy, France. Participants have to express MCs and must be free of dementia diagnosis at the first visit. Participants also need to be accompanied by an accompanier and both have to be fluent in French. This study has been approved by our local Ethics Committee (Committee for the Protection of Persons) and the French Health Security Agency. After giving their informed consent, patients and accompaniers are followed up throughout the diagnostic process with three visits : at their first visit, at one month after the first visit, and at six months after the diagnosis disclosure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Memory Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For patients with memory complaints: Age over 18 years Have a memory complaints with a QPC score greater than or equal to 3 Be accompanied by a next of kin Folstein MMSE greater than or equal to 15/30 Have given their written consent after receiving clear and intelligible oral and written information Social security coverage For Accompaniers : Age over 18 years Consent to participate at the study with the patient Have given their written consent after receiving clear and intelligible oral and written information Social security coverage Be in contact with the patient at least 8 hours per week. It could be physical contact or telephone contact. For patients with memory complaints: Sensory deficit interfering with the completion of the questionnaires Level of French insufficient to complete the questionnaires Legally protected person Diagnosis of neurocognitive disorders already established Treatment for Alzheimer Disease Refusal or inability to obtain written informed consent form from the patient Included in another experimental study at inclusion visit For Accompaniers: Sensory deficit interfering with the completion of the questionnaires Level of French insufficient to complete the questionnaires Refusal or inability to obtain written informed consent form from the accompanier</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>