<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02299102</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This single center, randomized, controlled trial will compare the manual standard bone marrow aspiration device to the powered ported bone marrow aspiration device for use in the iliac crest in healthy adult volunteers. The study will compare the subjects' perceived level of pain, time to sample acquisition, and quality of specimen yield of these devices. To serve as their own control, each subject will receive bilateral bone marrow aspiration procedures using both the manual standard and powered ported devices.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Comparing Powered Ported Bone Marrow Aspiration Procedures to Manual Standard Bone Marrow Aspiration Procedures Using Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This single center, randomized, controlled trial will compare the manual standard bone marrow aspiration needle to the power ported aspiration needle for use in the posterior iliac crest of healthy volunteers for bone marrow aspiration specimen collection. The study will compare the quality of specimen yield of the devices, subject reported level of pain with needle insertion and aspiration, and time from needle/skin contact to needle insertion and to sample acquisition. Each subject will serve as his/her own control and will receive bilateral bone marrow aspiration procedures using both the manual standard and power ported needles. The order in which the devices are used for each subject's procedures and on which side each device will be used will be randomized.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Adults 21 years of age and over Able to lay flat in prone position on a table for up to 1 hour Selfreported as healthy, as confirmed by the investigator during the medical history review and physical examination Female subjects with a negative urine pregnancy test at screening visit Reported fever within 7 days of the screening visit Reported active infection within 7 days of the screening visit Fever on day of study procedure Signs/symptoms of active infection on day of study procedure Imprisoned Self identified as pregnant or lactating Cognitively impaired Patients with one or more conditions precluding bone marrow aspiration Excessive tissue and/or absence of adequate anatomical landmarks in target bone Allergy to local anesthetics Unable to lay flat in prone position Prothrombin time and International Normalized Ratio (PT/INR) results outside of normal range on screening lab work and deemed clinically significant by the investigator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Aspiration Procedures</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Marrow</keyword>
	<keyword>To compare powered ported bone marrow aspiration procedures to manual standard bone marrow aspiration procedures</keyword>
</DOC>