<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01562938</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1, double-blind, placebo controlled study enrolling 42 healthy adult subjects (18-45yrs) from 1 site. Subjects will be randomized in a 2:3:2 ratio to receive MEDI-557 or placebo. Subjects will receive 1 intravenous dose on Study Day 1. Subjects will be followed for safety from the time of Informed Consent through 360 days post dose.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>MEDI-557 Adult Dosing</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Phase 1, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study evaluating the safety and tolerability of MEDI-557 administered IV to healthy adult subjects (18-45yrs). A maximum of 42 subjects from 1 site will be enrolled in a 2:3:2 ratio (12 placebo, 18 MEDI-557 low-dose, 12 MEDI-557 high-dose) to allow for greater data collection in the low-dose group. Subjects are evaluated for safety from time of Informed Consent through Study Day 360 post dose.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1845 years written informed consent obtained from subject prior to performing any protocol related procedures healthy by medical history and physical exam females of childbearing potential must use 2 effective methods of birth control for 14 days prior to 1st dose and through 1 year after administration of study drug nonsterilized, sexually active males with female partner of childbearing potential must use 2 effective methods of birth control from Day 1 through Day 361 weight &lt;/= 110kg with a body mass index of &lt;32kg/m2 ability to complete a followup period of approximately 360 days inability to complete a followup period of 360 days any condition in the opinion of investigator that would interfere with evaluation of IP or interpretation of subject safety or study results concurrent enrollment in another clinical study employees of the site or other individuals involved with the conduct of the study or immediate family members of such individuals receipt of immunoglobulin or blood products within 60 days prior to randomziation receipt of any investigational drug therapy within 6 months prior to IP dosing clinically abnormal ECG at screening blood donation in excess of 400mL, wihtin 6 months prior to randomization previous receipt fo biologics history of immunodeficiency history of allergic disease or reactions likely to be exacerbated by any component of the IP previous medical history or evidence of interurrent illness that may compromise the safety of the subject positive lab test for Hep A, B, C or HIV pregnancy or nursing mother history of alcohol or drug abuse within past 2 years positive urine Class A drug screen acute illness within 7 days prior to randomization fever &gt;/= 99.5F witin 7 days prior to randomization any drug therapy within 7 days prior to randomization systolic BP &gt;150mmHG and/or diastolic BP&gt;90mmHg receipt of vaccine within 14 days prior to randomization abnormal study labs (hem/wbc/platelet/BUN see protocol for specific information)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Respiratory Syncytial Virus</keyword>
</DOC>