<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01089803</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this prospective, multi-institutional, observational cohort study is to determine if an initial surgical approach leads to better function and quality of life than primary chemoradiation in a subset of patients with advanced hypopharyngeal and laryngeal cancers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Observational Study of Swallowing Function After Treatment of Advanced Laryngeal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>At the time of registration patients will be categorized into 2 groups based on the initial treatment plan as either chemoradiation-based or surgically-based (laryngectomy). Treatment will be assigned by the patient's physician, it will not be assigned by the study. Patients will be asked to complete a series of 4 questionnaires addressing swallowing function, generic health status, head and neck cancer-specific quality of life, and self-reported speech function at 3 time points (baseline, 6 months and 12 months after the end of treatment). The treating physician will provide basic clinical information at these same time points. In centers where swallowing and voice assessments are done as part of standard of care, data from these studies will also be provided. Study entry is open to all adults regardless of gender or ethnic background. Specific information regarding the definitive treatment (surgery or chemoradiation) will be provided to the patient by the treating physician as part of the routine standard of care. Any treatment related side effects, as well as the duration of therapy and follow-up will be managed by the treating physician. Participation in this study will have no effect on the initial treatment decisions or the course of care.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Laryngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Willingness and ability to complete selfadministered followup questionnaires over the course of one year as determined by a member of the research team Voluntary written informed consent with the understanding that consent may be withdrawn by the patient at any time without prejudice to future medical care Must be at least 18 years of age Require a resection that would involve more than the standard laryngectomy (total pharyngectomy, esophagectomy) Undergo partial laryngectomy, when open or endoscopic Have previously altered anatomy of the upper aerodigestive tract Have preexisting dysphagia unrelated to the tumor, or neurologic disorders that could affect swallowing (Parkinson's, cerebrovascular accidents) Have prior malignant disease of the upper aerodigestive tract Have prior radiation therapy to the head and neck region Metastatic disease Unable to complete selfadministered questionnaires written in simple English for cognitive, psychiatric, or other reasons that in the opinion of the enrolling investigator is likely to interfere with participation in this clinical study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>laryngectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>hypopharynx</keyword>
</DOC>