<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01468740</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Standard therapy for HIV-related Hodgkin lymphoma (HIV-HL) has not been defined. This trial was initiated to investigate a risk adapted treatment strategy in patients (pts) with HIV-HL as established in HIV-negative patients with HL. Treatment schedule: - Early stage favorable Hodgkin Lymphoma (HL): 2 cycles of doxorubicin, bleomycin, vinblastine, and dacarbazine (ABVD) plus 30 Gy involved field (IF) radiation - Early stage unfavorable HL: 4 cycles of bleomycin, etoposide, doxorubicin, cyclophosphamide, vincristine, procarbazine, and prednisone (BEACOPP)-baseline or 4 cycles of ABVD plus 30 Gy IF radiation - Advanced HL: 8 cycles of BEACOPP-baseline. BEACOPP should be replaced by ABVD in pts with far advanced HIV-infection. After the completion of chemotherapy sites of initial bulky disease (those at least 5 cm in diameter) and residual tumor larger than 2.5 cm in diameter receive 30 Gy of irradiation. - Primary outcome measure: tolerability, treatment-related mortality - Secondary outcome measure: complete remission rate, progression-free survival (PFS), overall survival (OS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Study on HIV-related Hodgkin Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vinblastine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bleomycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Procarbazine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vincristine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age 18 75 years proven infection with HIV 1 (Elisa and Western Blot) histologyproven newly diagnosed Hodgkin lymphoma written, informed consent. severe cardiac, hepatic or pulmonary insufficiency severe renal insufficiency (creatinine &gt; 2,0 mg/dl) not caused by lymphoma bone marrow failure, not caused by lymphoma or HAART (neutrophils &lt; 1000/µl, platelets &lt; 70.000/µl) uncontrolled infection uncontrolled drug addiction or psychiatric disease pregnancy or lactation period prior chemotherapy of Hodgkin lymphoma life expectancy &lt; 6 weeks HIVrelated wastingsyndrome active secondary malignancy with cervix carcinoma in situ, basalioma and Kaposi`s sarcoma being excepted</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>