<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02086682</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The introduction of unfractionated heparin (UFH), which prevents clotting of the extracorporal circuit, was one of the key advances that led to the rapid development and expansion of hemodialysis services. However, anticoagulation during hemodialysis of the patient at high risk for bleeding remains a frequently encountered problem in both inpatient and outpatient dialysis practice. Streamline bloodlines are designed to eliminate blood-air contact. This is thought to help reduce heparin use and decrease clotting rates. The goal of this study is to prospectively examine impact of the Streamline airless blood tubing set, in an inpatient setting, on dialysis circuit clotting rates, anticoagulation use, and dialysis efficiency.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Prospective Study of Airless Tubing in an Inpatient Acute Hemodialysis Unit in Hospitalized Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The introduction of unfractionated heparin (UFH), which prevents clotting of the extracorporeal circuit, was one of the key advances that led to the rapid development and expansion of hemodialysis use, and remains the mainstay in hemodialysis practice today. However, anticoagulation during hemodialysis of the patient at high risk for bleeding remains a frequently encountered problem in the nephrology practice. The need for anticoagulation to prevent clotting of the extracorporeal blood circuit and the need to prevent anticoagulation related bleeding complications in the patient has led to the development of numerous strategies; the safest from a bleeding standpoint being anticoagulant-free hemodialysis. Streamline® bloodlines (Medisystems® Corporation, Lawrence, MA) are designed to eliminate blood-air contact. A pressure pod measures arterial and venous pressures without any blood-air contact. The venous chamber is run without an air gap. It is also designed so that blood flows in a circular vortex manner. This airless system is thought to provide several benefits: improved dialysis efficiency and blood flow rates, reduced heparin use and clotting rates. The goal of this study is to prospectively examine the Streamline® airless tubing system in an inpatient setting and its association with clotting rates, and dialysis efficiency.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Blood Coagulation Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemostatic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All adult nonpregnant patients requiring inpatient hemodialysis at our center during the recruitment period until the target sample (n=1200) is reached. Pregnant females Children</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>hemodialysis</keyword>
	<keyword>dialysis</keyword>
	<keyword>renal dialysis</keyword>
	<keyword>clotting</keyword>
	<keyword>coagulation</keyword>
	<keyword>blood lines</keyword>
</DOC>