<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02849431</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study explores the feasibility of a mindfulness-based intervention for people with a diagnosis of borderline personality disorder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mindfulness for Intense Emotions: A Feasibility Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an uncontrolled feasibility trial of an eight-week mindfulness-based intervention for people with a diagnosis of borderline personality disorder. A battery of measures will be administered at baseline, in a time window of six to zero weeks prior to the start of the intervention. Outcome measures will be repeated in the two weeks after the end of the eight-week intervention, along with a qualitative interview.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Personality Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Borderline Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Are on the caseload of a United Kingdom National Health Service Assessment and Treatment Service in the recruitment area and have had contact with that service in the past three months Have received the diagnosis of Borderline Personality Disorder from a suitably qualified health care professional, and continue to meet criteria for this diagnosis according to the SCIDII (Structured Clinical Interview for DSM Disorders Version II) at their screening assessment Have sufficient English language speaking and comprehension abilities to access group discussions and handout materials Have not previously engaged in a mindfulnessbased intervention. As in other similar trials, a minimum dose has been operationally defined as having undertaken 50% or more of a mindfulnessbased intervention delivered facetoface by a suitably qualified health care professional Are not currently receiving, nor have plans to receive any other form of psychological therapy during the course of the study Exclusion criteria: Have psychosis Misuse alcohol or drug to a level that requiring detox Have a intellectual disability Present a high level of risk requiring inpatient management at the time of their screening assessment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>mindfulness</keyword>
</DOC>