<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02849613</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Stroke is the second leading cause of death in the world population. When not fatal, stroke often results in disability, and secondary health problems affecting not only patients but also their families. Building on emerging preclinical and pilot clinical evidences, RESSTORE will focus on the clinical assessment of regenerative cell therapy to improve stroke recovery and patients quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Regenerative Stem Cell Therapy for Stroke in Europe</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>RESSTORE European multicentre randomised phase IIb will explore the efficacy (functional recovery) and safety of intravenous infusion of allogenic adipose tissue derived mesenchymal stem cells (ADSC) in 400 stroke patients. Therapeutic effects of ADSCs will be assessed and monitored in patients using clinical rating scales, multimodal MRI and blood biomarkers. The European regenerative therapy capacities (France, Spain, Finland, United Kingdom and Czech Republic), developed in RESSTORE will cover the full value chain in the field (large scale GMP cell production, clinical testing, biomarkers discovery, understanding of the restoring mechanisms, biobanking...).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Hemispheric ischemic stroke (&gt;1.5cm) Inclusion from 1 to 4 days poststroke NIHSS &gt; or = 7 No craniectomy Able to follow a rehabilitation program Modified Rankin scale = 0 before stroke onset Coma Severe leucoariosis Previous stroke Active endocarditis, pneumonia, AIDS, active hepatic disease due to HBV or HCV History of cancer Pregnancy, breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cell therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>stem cell</keyword>
	<keyword>transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>graft</keyword>
	<keyword>recovery</keyword>
	<keyword>repair</keyword>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>mesenchymal stem cell</keyword>
	<keyword>regenerative</keyword>
</DOC>