<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02849158</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Single center interventional study to explore activity of fibroblasts in the tumor and away in the healthy rectal tissue.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fibroblast Before and After Neoadjuvant Chemo-radiotherapy in Patient With Locally Advanced Rectal Adenocarcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients included in the trial will have new biopsy performed before starting the Radiation Therapy and Chemotherapy (RT-CT). These biopsies will study the activity of fibroblasts in the tumor and away in the healthy rectal tissue. Within 8 to 10 weeks after the end of RT-CT, patients will have cancer surgery by proctectomy (with complete removal of the meso-rectum). On the resection specimen, new samples will be taken at the level of the tumor and away from the rectum.This study is single center interventional exploratory .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Middle rectum adenocarcinoma Tumor(T)x Node (N)+ or T3 /T4 N0 or N+ 2. Classification done on pelvic Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) and rectal ultrasonography 3. Age ≥ 18 4. No contraindication to treatment with capecitabine 5. Able to receive radiotherapy 50 Grays in 5 weeks 6. No contraindication for surgery after chemoradiotherapy which will be 8 to 10 weeks after completion of chemoradiotherapy 7. Patient or legal representative provided with information and signature of informed consent 1. High rectum adenocarcinoma 2. Contraindication to rectal biopsy: including anticoagulants or antiplatelet agents (vitamin K antagonists, clopidogrel, aspirin &gt; 160 grams) that cannot be interrupted 3. Pregnant woman or breastfeeding 4. Persons deprived of their liberty, or under guardianship 5. Impossibility of undergoing the trial's medical followup for geographical, social or psychological reasons. 6. Patient already included in another therapeutic trial with an experimental medication during the realization of protocol biopsies and surgery 7. Patient not covered by health insurance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Rectoscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>Proctectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>Fibroblasts</keyword>
</DOC>