<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02849067</DOC>
	<brief_summary>It is known that laughter can bring benefits in terms of physiological and psychological parameters, in addition to improving the individual's quality of life. However, the literature is still scarce as to the existence of studies investigating the effects of a comedy film specifically in hemodynamics.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hemodynamic Responses of Stable Ischemic Heart Disease Patients to a Comedy Session</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objective: To evaluate the effect of a comedy film session on the cardiac index, Systemic Vascular Resistance and Vascular Resistance Index Systemic in stable ischemic heart disease patients. Method: Randomized Clinical Trial. Patients will be coming from Ischemic Heart Disease clinic at the Hospital de Clínicas de Porto Alegre (HCPA), all in regular monitoring.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ages between 40 and 80 years Both female and male Diagnosis of ischemic heart disease by cardiac catheterization , with 50% lesion in at least one epicardial vessel Participants enrolled in another Randomized Clinical trial Autoimmune diseases Valvulopathy with mechanical or biological cardiac prosthesis Presence of pacemakers and implantable cardioverter Left bundle branch block in the electrocardiogram (ECG) of 12 derivations Severe lung disease Depression or Bipolar Disorder Atrial Chronic Fibrillation Left ventricular dysfunction (ejection fraction &lt;45%) Active Infection or neoplasia (not Basal cell carcinoma) Chronic Renal Failure Illiteracy and inability to understand the consent form</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ischaemic heart disease</keyword>
	<keyword>comedy session</keyword>
	<keyword>laughter therapy</keyword>
</DOC>