<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02849080</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is globally conducted. The aim of this trial is to investigate Efficacy and Safety of Oral Semaglutide Using a Flexible Dose Adjustment Based on Clinical Evaluation versus Sitagliptin in Subjects with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Oral Semaglutide Using a Flexible Dose Adjustment Based on Clinical Evaluation Versus Sitagliptin in Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sitagliptin Phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent obtained before any trialrelated activities. Trialrelated activities are any procedures that are carried out as part of the trial, including activities to determine suitability for the trial Male or female, age above or equal to 18 years at the time of signing informed consent.For Korea only: Male or female, age above or equal to 19 years at the time of signing informed consent Diagnosed with type 2 diabetes mellitus for at least 90 days prior to day of screening HbA1c (glycosylated haemoglobin) 7.59.5% (5880 mmol/mol) (both inclusive) Treatment target of HbA1c below 7.0% (53 mmol/mol), as judged by the investigator Stable daily dose(s) of 12 of the following antidiabetic drugs within 90 days prior to the day of screening: Metformin (equal or above 1500 mg or maximum tolerated dose as documented in the subject medical record) Sulfonylureas (equal or above half of the maximum approved dose according to local label or maximum tolerated dose as documented in subject medical record) Sodium glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors Thiazolidinediones (equal or above half of the maximum approved dose according to local label or maximum tolerated dose as documented in subject medical record) Female who is pregnant, breastfeeding or intends to become pregnant or is of childbearing potential and not using an adequate contraceptive method (adequate contraceptive measure as required by local regulation or practice) For certain specific countries: Additional specific requirements apply Any disorder, which in the investigator's opinion might jeopardise subject's safety or compliance with the protocol Family or personal history of Multiple Endocrine Neoplasia Type 2 or Medullary Thyroid Carcinoma History of pancreatitis (acute or chronic) History of major surgical procedures involving the stomach potentially affecting absorption of trial product (e.g. subtotal and total gastrectomy, sleeve gastrectomy, gastric bypass surgery) Any of the following: myocardial infarction, stroke or hospitalisation for unstable angina or transient ischaemic attack within the past 180 days prior to the day of screening and randomisation Subjects presently classified as being in New York Heart Association Class IV Planned coronary, carotid or peripheral artery revascularisation known on the day of screening Subjects with alanine aminotransferase above 2.5 x upper normal limit Renal impairment defined as Estimated Glomerular Filtration rate 60 mL/min/1.73 m^2 as per Chronic Kidney Disease Epidemiology Collaboration formula Treatment with any medication for the indication of diabetes or obesity other than stated in the inclusion criteria in a period of 90 days before the day of screening. An exception is shortterm insulin treatment for acute illness for a total of below or equal to 14 days Proliferative retinopathy or maculopathy requiring acute treatment. Verified by fundus photography or dilated fundoscopy performed within 90 days prior to randomisation History or presence of malignant neoplasms within the last 5 years (except basal and squamous cell skin cancer and carcinoma in situ) History of diabetic ketoacidosis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>