<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02849483</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Ramosetron is effective in preventing postoperative nausea and vomiting. Several studies reported that ramosetron is also effective treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. The investigators examine the effect of ramosetron on postoperative bowel motility.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Ramosetron on Bowel Motility After Gynecological Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Ramosetron, a new potent and long-acting selective 5-HT3(5-hydroxytryptamine3) receptor anatagonist, is effective for preventing postoperative nausea and vomiting. Also several studies reported that ramosetron is effective treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome because it inhibits the accelerated colonic transit, abnormal colonic water transport, defecation abnormality, and the lowered colonic perceptual threshold by corticotrophin-releasing hormone, There is no study about the effect of ramosetron used for preventing postoperative nausea and vomiting on postoperative bowel motility. In this study, the investigators examine the effect of ramosetron on postoperative bowel motility.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Nausea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ramosetron</mesh_term>
	<criteria>2070 yrs of age ASA(American Society of Anesthesiologists) physical status class I or II Scheduled for gynecological laparoscopic surgery Allergic to study drugs Antiemetics or steroids use within 24 hrs prior to surgery Dependence upon opioids Insulin dependent Diabetes Mellitus Cardiovascular or pulmonary disease Renal or hepatic insufficiency BMI&gt;=35kg/m2 History of motion sickness or PONV Cigarette smoker Conversion to open laparotomy from laparoscopic surgery Pregnants</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>PONV</keyword>
	<keyword>digestive signs and symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>vomiting</keyword>
	<keyword>antiemetics</keyword>
	<keyword>nausea</keyword>
	<keyword>ramosetron</keyword>
</DOC>