<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01980043</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and feasibility of endoluminal rectal prolapse repair under sedation and local anesthesia using CO2 colonoscopy to fix the rectum with sutures to the abdominal wall under needlescopic control. Further, investigators will evaluate the short and long-term clinical outcomes after this novel approach to treating rectal prolapse.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Endoluminal and Needlescopic Assisted Repair of Rectal Prolapse</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>.Aims/Objective The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and feasibility of endoluminal rectal prolapse repair under sedation and local anesthesia using CO2 colonoscopy to fix the rectum with sutures to the abdominal wall under needlescopic control. Further, we will evaluate the short and long-term clinical outcomes after this new procedure. Primary Outcomes 1. Feasibility: successful completion of endoluminal rectal prolapse repair with needlescopic assistance 2. Safety: measured by the incidence of the Intraoperative complications (bowel perforation, organ injury and bleeding requiring blood transfusion) 3. Sedation and local anesthesia feasibility: surgery completed without patient intubation 4. Clinical Outcomes: rectal prolapse recurrence within 30 days, length of hospital stay and postsurgical complications 5. Long Term Clinical Outcomes: Rectal Prolapse Recurrence Methods Design: A prospective pilot study with 10 patients who will be undergoing Combined Needlescopic and Endoluminal (Colonoscopic) Surgery under sedation and local anesthesia for Rectal Prolapse Repair with the Colon and Rectal Surgeons at WCMC. Data will be collected prospectively before, during, and after surgery. Settings: Colon and Rectal Surgery at WCMC-NYPH Population: Patients male and female above 75 years of age, with rectal prolapse will be invited to participate in the study after surgery is deemed necessary for standard treatment of their medical conditions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prolapse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rectal Prolapse</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age, 75 years and older, Male and Female BMI above 18 and ≤30 ASA class 13 willing to participate in the study ASA class 45 Previous Abdominal Surgeries including abdominal wall repair with mesh</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>75 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>