<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01980095</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The "test and treat" strategy for treating dyspeptic patients who are H. pylori positive is rapidly becoming the standard of care. This study will test the effectiveness of RHB-105, a new triple therapy to treat H. pylori infection in dyspeptic patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ERADICATE Hp - Treating Helicobacter Pylori With RHB-105</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of RHB-105 in adult subjects complaining of epigastric discomfort that have been screened and found to be positive for H. pylori infection via 13C Urea Breath Test (UBT) and either fecal antigen test or CLO test. Eligible subjects will be randomized in a ratio of 1:2 between placebo arm (n=30) and the active arm (RHB-105) (n=60). Subjects will receive study drug for 14 consecutive days. Eradication of H. pylori infection will be determined based on 13C UBT conducted between 28 to 56 days after completion of study drug therapy. Subjects will be unblinded upon 13C UBT analysis. This will provide timely active therapy to all subjects enrolled in this study. Subjects in the placebo arm will be entitled to receive standard-of-care as prescribed by the treating physician following un-blinding. Eradication failures (13C UBT-positive) in the active study drug arm will undergo upper endoscopy with sampling for culture and sensitivity testing (to rifabutin, amoxicillin, clarithromycin, and metronidazole). Culture and sensitivity directed therapy as prescribed by the treating physician will be offered to these subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyspepsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Helicobacter Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Be ≥18 years of age and ≤ 65 years 2. Have symptoms consistent with dyspepsia of at least two weeks duration (defined as recurrent pain or discomfort centered in the upper abdomen, often with a relation to meals) 3. Be positive for H. pylori by 13C Urea Breath Test (UBT) and also by fecal antigen test 4. Be informed of the nature of the study and provide written informed consent before any study specific procedures are performed (or have a legally authorized representative sign consent) 1. Have alarm symptoms/signs (including unexplained anemia [iron deficiency), melena / hematemesis, anorexia, dysphagia, jaundice, weight loss) 2. Have taken antibiotics in the 4 weeks prior to screening 3. Have taken bismuth containing medications such as peptobismol in the 4 weeks prior to screening 4. Have a history of any previous esophageal or gastric surgery, except for simple closure of perforated ulcer 5. Have a history of gastric outlet obstruction 6. Have a history of hypersecretory state such as ZollingerEllison Syndrome 7. Have a history of gastric cancer 8. Have the presence of active gastric and duodenal ulcers or presence of 3 or more active ulcers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Helicobacter pylori</keyword>
	<keyword>H. pylori</keyword>
	<keyword>Dyspepsia</keyword>
</DOC>