<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01980420</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Improved results for sleeve gastrectomy could be possible if more was known about the surgical / mechanical factors that affect outcome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Study of the Impact of Sleeve Gastrectomy on Gastro-esophageal Junction Function</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Effectiveness of sleeve gastrectomy is between gastric banding and gastric bypass. However, a proportion of patients that undergo surgery, report troublesome and persistent dysphagia, pain, new onset or worsening of gastro-esophageal reflux (GER) requiring treatment. Improved results for sleeve gastrectomy could be possible if more was known about the surgical / mechanical factors that affect outcome. Current investigations based on traditional intra-luminal imaging (endoscopy) and radiology (UGI series) may not provide adequate preoperative assessment of esophago-gastric dynamics. Current practice in the creation of a sleeve gastrectomy involves the use of a bougie or endoscope around which the sleeve is stapled. There is no consensus on the diameter of this bougie and this intraoperative calibration may alter the gastro-esophageal junction (GEJ) anatomy, does not provide real time physiology feedback, and allows only for a rough approximation of the size of the sleeve providing no information about the distensibility and pressure gradient of the newly created gastric tube as it is filled. A more distensible sleeve will have lower intra-gastric pressure, and thus will theoretically be expected to reduce the incidence of side effects. As laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy is performed with increasing frequency, there is a need for development of tools to assist the surgeon in modeling properly and standardize the gastroplasty. This study will be based on a strict assessment of the anatomical and functional characteristics of the "ideal "gastric sleeve, using existing imaging modalities (endoscopy - CT scan- MRI - HRM).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity, Morbid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient, male or female over 18 years old Patient scheduled to undergo a sleeve gastrectomy for obesity Patient with surgical indication validated by the obesity multidisciplinary meeting (RCP) Patient able to understand the study and to provide written informed consent Patient registered with the French social security regime Noninclusion criteria: Patient unable to give written informed consent Patient presenting contraindication to the conduct of an MRI (claustrophobia, implantable medical devices) Patient presenting risks of allergic reaction to MRI contrast agents (gadolinium) Patient presenting, in the investigator's judgment, a condition or disease preventing their participation to study procedures Patient pregnant or breastfeeding Patient within exclusion period from other clinical trial Patient having forfeited their freedom of an administrative or legal obligation Patient being under guardianship</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sleeve gastrectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>Oesogastric junction - GEJ</keyword>
	<keyword>Dynamic MRI Imaging</keyword>
</DOC>