<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00789295</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this intervention study was to evaluate in type 2 diabetic patients the effects on postprandial lipemia and other metabolic parameters (in both everyday life conditions and after a standard test meal) of two diets, one moderately rich in CHO, rich in fibre and with a low glycemic index (Mediterranean diet), and the other low in CHO and rich in MUFA (Low-CHO diet).Since adipose tissue, mainly through its lipolytic activities, is considered as having a pivotal role in the regulation of postprandial lipid metabolism, a further aim of our study was to clarify the role of adipose tissue in modulating the postprandial lipid response induced by the two dietary approaches by evaluating the activities of lipoprotein lipase (LPL) and hormone-sensitive lipase (HSL).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mediterranean Diet and Postprandial Lipemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hyperlipidemias</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 2 diabetes Stable metabolic control (HbA1c&lt;8.0%) on diet or diet alone or diet+metformin BMI&lt;30 kg/m2 and body weight stable during the last six months. Both sexes; only postmenopausal women. Normal fasting lipid levels No use of hypolipidemic drugs Patient with renal (serum creatinine &gt;1.5 mg/dl) or hepatic (serum transaminases &gt;three times upper normal values) impairment. Patients with history of cardiovascular disease. Premenopausal women. Any other acute or chronic degenerative disease. Anemia (Hb&lt;12 g/dl). Uncontrolled blood pressure. Use of any drugs able to interfere with the study medications</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mediterranean diet</keyword>
	<keyword>Postprandial lipids</keyword>
	<keyword>Postprandial glucose</keyword>
	<keyword>High fibre diet</keyword>
	<keyword>Low- CHO diet</keyword>
	<keyword>High MUFA diet</keyword>
	<keyword>Dietary approach</keyword>
</DOC>