<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00999193</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Fractures of the proximal humerus are common in elderly patients. The optimal treatment of comminuted, displaced fractures is subject to controversy, and the results of operative treatment have not been shown to be superior to conservative treatment. The aim of the study is to compare locking plate osteosynthesis versus treatment with fracture hemiarthroplasty versus conservative treatment in a randomised, controlled protocol. The results of treatment are measured at 6 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 12 months and 24 months. Main outcome measures are Pain at rest and activity (NRSs) and functional assessment of the shoulder with Constant Score. Secondary outcome measures are Simple Shoulder test (SST), Disabilities of the Arm, Shoulder and Hand (DASH), quality of life assessment (15D), subjective patient satisfaction and costs. The study also has a cohort follow-up of the patiens who decline randomisation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Proximal Humeral Comminuted Fractures in the Elderly - PERCELE Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Humeral Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 65 years and older Acute trauma: 1. randomisation (op vs cons) within 7 days of injury. 3 or 4part fracture with &gt;5mm dislocation of the anatomic neck. AO classification C12 for nonluxation fractures AO classification C3 for luxation fractures Head Splitting fracture Open fracture Additional fractures in the shoulder region Other injuries requiring surgical treatment Clinically significant injury of the brachial plexus or vasculature Pathological fracture associated with cancer History of a fracture of the clavicle, scapula or humerus, or history of a very significant disease or trauma of the shoulder region (hemiparesis, tumour, osteomyelitis, grave arthrosis etc) Rheumatoid Arthritis in the shoulder requiring active treatment Reduced cooperation or incapability for independent living (dementia, mental illness, drug or alcohol abuse etc) unwillingness to accept some of the treatment options.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Shoulder</keyword>
	<keyword>Fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>Locking Plate</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemiarthroplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Conservative</keyword>
	<keyword>Comminuted Proximal Humerus Fracture</keyword>
</DOC>