<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00999999</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Main objective of this trial is to assess the hypothesis whether the application of TachoSil速 as a dural sealant improves the quality of craniotomy procedure and outcome in general compared with standard dural closure techniques in a controlled and randomized way. As a primary endpoint the investigators look at possible postoperative occurrence of CSF pads or leakages needing any kind of intervention until day 30 after the primary craniotomy. Furthermore, the investigators will look at other surgery-related complications and at pharmacoeconomic endpoints such as hospital stay or cost of the implant. Overall, the results of this study will provide important information on whether or not the adjunct of a relatively expensive implant on a routinely basis for the closure of elective craniotomies is safe and effective, or not. To date, TachoSil速 is often used in neurosurgery and other surgical disciplines in a non-standardized fashion also to prevent CSF leakage after dural closure. So far, adverse events directly related to the product have not been reported. Theoretically, any implant may be associated with a higher incidence of postoperative infections (e.g. epidural, subdural or subgaleal empyema). On the other hand, it is not known whether or not the application of TachoSil速 on the dural suture may reduce CSF leakage.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Tachosil as Dural Sealant Compared to Standard Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Neurosurgical indication for craniotomy and opening of dura to access cerebral structures/pathologies (discussed in the indication conference of board certified neurosurgeons at the University Hospital of Basel). The list of pathologies includes: primary or secondary benign/malignant brain tumors aneurysms arteriousvenous malformations cavernomas pituitary adenomas temporal lobectomy (epilepsy surgery) longterm posttraumatic revisions. Presence of subdural empyema/abscess or any kind of infection affecting/infiltrating the dura mater Emergency for trauma Previous surgery on the same site Cases, where watertight dural suture is not possible (intraoperative exclusion decision) Known hypersensitivity to TachoSil速 Participation in another study Pregnancy Inability to read and understand the participant's information</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Craniotomy outcome</keyword>
	<keyword>CSF leakage</keyword>
	<keyword>Dural sealant</keyword>
</DOC>