<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01473875</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase 2/3, open-label extension study will evaluate the long-term efficacy and safety of intravenous (IV) infusions of SBC-102 in children with Lysosomal Acid Lipase (LAL) Deficiency who previously received treatment with SBC-102.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Children With Lysosomal Acid Lipase Deficiency Who Previously Received Treatment With SBC-102</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Early onset LAL Deficiency is a very rare form of LAL Deficiency, with an estimated prevalence of less than 2 lives per million (Meikle et al., 1999). This form of the disease, named after the physician who first described it (Abramov et al., 1956), is the most aggressive presentation of LAL Deficiency and is characterized by gastrointestinal and hepatic manifestations including marked growth failure, malabsorption, steatorrhea, and hepatomegaly. Early onset LAL Deficiency is rapidly progressive and fatal usually within the first year of life (Assmann &amp; Seedorf, 2001). The primary objective of the study is to evaluate the effect of SBC-102 therapy on overall survival at 12 months of age in children with growth failure due to LAL Deficiency. All subjects will receive repeat IV infusions of SBC-102, beginning at least 1 week after the preceding infusion in study LAL-CL03 or under an expanded access treatment regimen.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wolman Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject's parent or legal guardian provides written consent/permission prior to any study procedures Subject completed treatment in study LALCL03 or Subject received treatment with SBC102 for at least 4 months under an expanded access treatment regimen Subject had no lifethreatening or unmanageable study drug toxicity during treatment with SBC102 under LALCL03 or expanded access treatment regimen. Clinically important concurrent disease Myeloablative preparation, or other systemic pretransplant conditioning, for hematopoietic stem cell or liver transplantation Previous hematopoietic stem cell transplant.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>LIPA</keyword>
	<keyword>Wolman Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Wolman Phenotype</keyword>
	<keyword>Acid Lipase Deficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Acid Cholesteryl Hydrolase</keyword>
	<keyword>Acid Lipase Disease Deficiency, type 2</keyword>
	<keyword>Cholesteryl Ester Storage Disease (CESD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Cholesteryl Ester Hydrolase Deficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Early Onset LAL-Deficiency (Wolman Disease)</keyword>
	<keyword>LAL Deficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Late Onset Lysosomal Acid Lipase Deficiency (CESD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Wolman Disease (early onset LAL Deficiency)</keyword>
	<keyword>Related Disorders:</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-alcoholic Steatohepatitis (NASH)</keyword>
	<keyword>Alcoholic Liver Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Cryptogenic Cirrhosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Niemann-Pick Disease (NPD) Type C</keyword>
	<keyword>Chanarin Dorfman Syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>