<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01473784</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot clinical trial studies transoral robotic surgery (TORS) in treating patients with benign or malignant tumors of the head and neck. TORS is a less invasive type of surgery for head and neck cancer and may have fewer side effects and improve recovery</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Transoral Robotic Surgery in Treating Patients With Benign or Malignant Tumors of the Head and Neck</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To conduct a pilot single-arm study to assess transoral robotic surgery (TORS) for oral and laryngopharyngeal benign and malignant lesions using the Da Vinci Robotic Surgical System.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Laryngeal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Laryngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Verrucous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Adenoid Cystic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Mucoepidermoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mouth Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypopharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lip Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tongue Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma in Situ</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient must present with indications for diagnostic or therapeutic approaches for benign and/or malignant diseases of the oral cavity or laryngopharynx (including the neoplastic lesions of the tongue, tongue base, retromolar trigone, tonsils, palate, posterior and lateral pharynx, glottic, supraglottic and subglottic larynx) Patients must have adequate transoral exposure of the oral cavity and laryngopharynx for TORS instrumentation Written informed consent and/or Consent waiver by institutional review board (IRB) Unexplained fever and/or untreated, active infection Patient pregnancy Previous head and neck surgery that would preclude transoral/robotic procedures. This is at the investigator's discretion. This is not an exclusion criterion for the nonsurgical arm. The presence of medical conditions contraindicating general anesthesia or transoral surgical approaches Inability to grant informed consent INTRAOPERATIVE EXCLUSION CRITERIA: Inability to adequately visualize anatomy to perform the diagnostic or therapeutic surgical approach transorally</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>