<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02021630</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This proposal is designed to examine the impact of bariatric surgery on the health of patients and their families. The shared environment of spouses/cohabitating partners suggests that patients' families are exposed to the extensive diet and lifestyle changes required of patients following bariatric surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Collateral Impact of Bariatric Surgery on Families</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The specific aims of this proposal are to: 1. Collect clinical data (e.g., weight, blood pressure, body composition, blood sample), as well as monitor physical activity and eating patterns, before and after bariatric surgery (Adults Only). 2. Analyze clinical data, physical activity and eating patterns to determine how the health of patients and their families change after one family member completes bariatric surgery (Adults Only). 3. Determine the feasibility of recruiting patients, spouses/partners and their children.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All patients who receive surgery have been cleared medically and psychosocially for surgery. Thus, surgical candidacy criteria will serve as eligibility criteria for the current study for surgical patients. Cohabitation with patients will be considered inclusion criteria for partners/spouses. Children between the ages of ≥5 ≤ 16, who cohabitate with the patient the majority of the time will be asked to participate by providing assent. Report current or planned use of weight loss medications (including OTC), or other weight loss strategy. Report pregnancy, lactation, or plans to become pregnant during study duration.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Bariatric Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Weight Loss</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical Activity</keyword>
	<keyword>Body Composition</keyword>
</DOC>