<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00360971</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Growth factors, such as palifermin, may lessen the severity of mucositis, or mouth sores, in patients receiving radiation therapy and chemotherapy for head and neck cancer. It is not yet known whether palifermin is more effective than a placebo in lessening mucositis in patients receiving radiation therapy and chemotherapy for head and neck cancer. PURPOSE: This randomized phase III trial is studying palifermin to see how well it works compared to a placebo in lessening oral mucositis in patients undergoing radiation therapy and chemotherapy for locally advanced head and neck cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Palifermin in Lessening Oral Mucositis in Patients Undergoing Radiation Therapy and Chemotherapy for Locally Advanced Head and Neck Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Compare the efficacy of palifermin vs placebo, in terms of burden of acute mucositis (defined to be 105 days [15 weeks] or less from the start of treatment), in patients with squamous cell carcinoma of the oral cavity, oropharynx, hypopharynx, or larynx undergoing concurrent radiotherapy and chemotherapy. Secondary - Compare incidence and time to onset of Grades 3 or 4 oral mucositis in patients treated with these regimens. - Compare overall and progression-free survival and time to second primary in patients treated with these regimens. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to disease stage (III vs IVA or IVB), tumor site (oral cavity or oropharynx vs hypopharynx or larynx), and radiotherapy technique used on study (intensity-modulated radiotherapy [IMRT] vs 3-dimensional conformal radiotherapy [3D-CRT]). Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. Mucositis, pain, and symptom burden are assessed at baseline, during radiotherapy, and post radiotherapy. Xerostomia is assessed at baseline, during radiotherapy, and several times after completion of study therapy. After completion of study therapy, patients are followed periodically for 10 years. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 298 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mucositis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stomatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Radiation Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed squamous cell carcinoma of the oral cavity, oropharynx, hypopharynx, or larynx, meeting all of the following criteria: At least 2 mucosal sites of the oral cavity/oropharynx mucosa that will be irradiated are assessable by visual transoral inspection Tumors of the larynx or hypolarynx are allowed only if it is anticipated that the 2 index sites in the oral cavity/oropharynx mucosa will be irradiated Selected stage III (excluding T1, N1, M0), or IVA or IVB disease No distant metastases or stage IVC disease (any T, any N, M1) No prior squamous cell cancer of the head and neck PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Zubrod performance status 01 Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,800/mm³ Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm³ Hemoglobin ≥ 8.0 g/dL (transfusion allowed) Bilirubin &lt; 1.5 mg/dL Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &lt; 2 times upper limit of normal Creatinine &lt; 1.5 mg/dL Creatinine clearance ≥ 50 mL/min Able to eat at least soft solids and does not require a feeding tube for nutrition or hydration Calcium normal Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception No prior invasive malignancy (except nonmelanomatous skin cancer) unless disease free for ≥ 3 years No severe, active comorbidity, including any of the following: Symptomatic and/or uncontrolled cardiac disease (i.e., New York Heart Association class IIIIV cardiac disease) Transmural myocardial infarction within the past 6 months Acute bacterial or fungal infection requiring intravenous antibiotics Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease exacerbation or other respiratory illness requiring hospitalization Hepatic insufficiency resulting in clinical jaundice and/or coagulation defects Seropositive for hepatitis B virus or hepatitis C virus Seropositive for HIV or confirmed AIDS History of pancreatitis Collagen vascular disease, such as scleroderma No prior allergic reaction or known sensitivity to any of the agents administered during study dosing, including E. coliderived products, such as any of the following: Somatropin (somatren) Filgrastim (GCSF) Insulin Interferon alfa2a Neumega® Oprelvekin (interleukin11) Interferon alfa2b Pegfilgrastim Interferon beta1b PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: No prior systemic chemotherapy for this cancer Prior chemotherapy for a different cancer is allowed No prior radiotherapy to a region that would result in overlap of radiation therapy fields No prior radical or modified neck dissection No prior initial surgical treatment, excluding diagnostic biopsy of the primary site or nodal sampling of neck disease No prior palifermin or other keratinocyte growth factors (i.e., velafermin or repifermin) Concurrent topical anesthetics allowed No concurrent administration of any of the following during radiotherapy: 'Magic' mouthwash, 'Miracle' mouthwash, or other mouthwash solutions containing chlorhexidine, Gelclair®, hydrogen peroxide, or diphenhydramine Pilocarpine hydrochloride Cevimeline hydrochloride Amifostine Benzydamine hydrochloride Interleukin11 Sargramostim (GMCSF) Epoetin alfa Sucralfate in suspension form Tablets allowed Steroid rinses Povidoneiodine rinses Glutamine as a prophylactic agent for mucositis Other investigational agents Other biologic response modifiers, with the exception of hematopoietic growth factors for the management of anemia or myelosuppression</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>mucositis</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>radiation toxicity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
</DOC>