<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00360568</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Long term safety and efficacy (12 months) of levodopa-carbidopa intestinal gel.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety/Efficacy Study of Levodopa-Carbidopa Intestinal Gel in Parkinson's Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study S187.3.003 (NCT00360568) is a Phase 3, 12-month, open-label, multicenter continuation treatment study of the safety, tolerability, and efficacy of levodopa-carbidopa intestinal gel (LCIG) in the treatment of participants with levodopa-responsive Parkinson's disease (PD) with persistent motor fluctuations despite optimized treatment with available PD medications. All participants received LCIG. Only participants who completed 12 weeks of double-blind, double-dummy treatment in Study S187.3.001 or S187.3.002 (NCT00357994/ NCT00660387) qualified for enrollment in this 12-month continuation treatment study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyskinesias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carbidopa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carbidopa, levodopa drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levodopa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Idiopathic Parkinson's disease (PD) according to United Kingdon Parkinson's Disease Society (UKPDS) Brain Bank Criteria Levodoparesponsive with severe motor fluctuations Completion of protocol S187.3.001 (NCT00357994) or S187.3.002 (NCT00660387) and continue to meet the inclusion criteria for the preceding study Patients with medically relevant abnormal findings (labs, electrocardiogram [ECG], physical examination, adverse events, psychiatric, neurological or behavioral disorders, etc.) at end of the doubleblind phase (Week 12) of Study S187.3.001 (NCT00357994) or Study S187.3.002 (NCT00660387)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>carbidopa</keyword>
	<keyword>severe motor fluctuations</keyword>
	<keyword>intestinal gel</keyword>
	<keyword>levodopa</keyword>
	<keyword>efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>levodopa carbidopa intestinal gel</keyword>
	<keyword>dyskinesia</keyword>
	<keyword>Parkinson's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Duodopa</keyword>
	<keyword>levodopa-carbidopa</keyword>
	<keyword>DUOPA</keyword>
</DOC>