<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01772290</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized, open-label, 4-arm, multiple-dose study will evaluate the effect of coadministration of a protein pump inhibitor, an inhibitor of P-glycoprotein and CYP3A4, or an inhibitor of CYP2C9 on the pharmacokinetics of vismodegib in healthy female subjects of non-childbearing potential. Subjects will be randomized to receive multiple oral doses of vismodegib, alone or in combination with multiple oral doses of either rabeprazole, itraconazole or fluconazole. Anticipated time on study treatment is up to 11 days.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Drug-Drug Interaction Study of the Effect of Rabeprazole, Itraconazole or Fluconazole on the Pharmacokinetics of Vismodegib</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rabeprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Itraconazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluconazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxyitraconazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Females of nonchildbearing potential Body mass index (BMI) 18 to 32 kg/m2, inclusive In good health, determined by no clinically significant findings from medical history, physical examination. 12lead ECG, and vital signs Clinical laboratory evaluations, complete blood count and urinalysis within the normal range for the test laboratory, unless not deemed clinically significant by the investigator Negative test for drugs of abuse at screening and checkin (including alcohol) Negative for hepatitis B, hepatitis C and HIV infection Nonchildbearing potential is defined as: nonpregnant, nonlactating, and either postmenopausal for at least 1 year or surgically sterile (e.g. bilateral oophorectomy and/or hysterectomy) Significant history or clinical evidence of any metabolic (including type 1 or 2 diabetes). allergic, dermatological, hepatic, renal, hematological, pulmonary, cardiovascular, endocrine, GI (including gastric or duodenal ulcers), ZollingerEllison syndrome, Barrett's esophagus, urological, neurological, or psychiatric disorder History of inflammatory arthritis History of symptomatic hypotension History of seizure disorders History of bipolar or major depressive disorder History of stomach or intestinal surgery or resection that would potentially alter absorption and/or excretion of orally administered drugs (appendectomy, hernia repair, and/or cholecystectomy will be allowed) History of alcoholism or drug addiction within 1 year prior to checkin Use of any tobacco or nicotinecontaining products within 6 months prior to checkin Participation in any other investigational study drug or biological agent trial in which receipt of investigational study drug occurred within 5 halflives or 30 days, whichever is longer, prior to checkin Use of PPIs, H2receptor antagonists, or antacids within 1 month prior to checkin History of chronic PPI use (&gt; 30 days of continuous daily dosing) within 6 months of checkin</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>