<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02429037</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objectives of this study are to investigate the efficacy and safety of rAd-p53 gene combined with radio- and chemo-therapy vs. radio- and chemo- therapy only in treatment of unresectable, locally advanced head and neck cancer. This is a phase 2, open labeled, and active-controlled study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>P53 Gene Combined With Radio- and Chemo-therapy in Treatment of Unresectable Locally Advanced Head and Neck Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To evaluate benefits of rAd-p53) gene therapy combined with radio- and chemo-therapy in treatment of unresectable, locally advanced head and neck cancer, total of 60 patients with above condition will be randomly assigned to two groups: the experiment group (EG) and the control group (CG). The EG received multi-point injections of rAd-p53 into tumor on day 1, 8 and 15 at a dose of 2 × 10^12 viral particles (VP) in a 21-days cycle. Both EG and CG were given radiotherapy at a total dose of 60 Gy and chemotherapy (Cisplatin 100 mg/m2 IV on days 1 plus paclitaxel 30 mg/m2 IV on day 1, 8 and 15). The patients will be treated until disease progression, withdrawal from study, or untolerated adverse events. study endpoints are efficacy (Progression-free survival, overall survival) and safety variables.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. histopathologically diagnosed head and neck cancer; 2. unresectable, locally advanced; 3. 18 years or older; 4. with an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) score of 02; 5. with normal tests of hemogram, blood coagulation, liver and kidney function; 6.signed the informed consent form. 1. Serious blood coagulation disorder, bleeding tendency, platelet &lt; 6 * 1000000000/L; 2. have serious heart, lung function abnormalities or severe diabetes patients; 3. active infection; 4. severe atherosclerosis; 5. AIDS patients; 6. serious thrombotic or embolic events within 6 months; 7. renal insufficiency requiring hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis; 8. pregnant or lactating women; 9. mental disorder or disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>p53</keyword>
	<keyword>gene therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>head and neck cancer</keyword>
</DOC>