<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00534274</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Diagnostic procedures, such as positron emission tomography (PET) using 3'-deoxy-3'-(18F) fluorothymidine, may be effective in assessing the response to chemotherapy before surgery in treating locally advanced breast cancer. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is studying how well positron emission tomography using 3'-deoxy-3'-(18F) fluorothymidine works in treating women with locally advanced cancer in one breast who are receiving chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Positron Emission Tomography Using 3'-Deoxy-3'-(18F) Fluorothymidine in Treating Women With Locally Advanced Cancer in One Breast Who Are Receiving Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Evaluate the efficacy of positron emission tomography (PET) utilizing 3'-deoxy-3'-(18F) fluorothymidine (^18F-FLT) to correctly identify response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in women with locally advanced unilateral breast cancer. - Correlate PET-^18F-FLT results with histological response. Secondary - Evaluate the correlation of early changes in tumor uptake of ^18F-FLT after the first course of chemotherapy with complete response after treatment completion. - Evaluate the correlation of early changes in tumor uptake of ^18F-FLT with histologic response in biopsies obtained after 1 course of chemotherapy. - Determine if the initial intensity of tumor uptake is a predictive value of response to chemotherapy. - Determine if initial intensity of tumor uptake of ^18F-FLT varies according to histologic type of tumor, indices of proliferation, and tumor cellularity before therapy. - Determine if the tumor uptake of ^18F-FLT during therapy varies according to histologic type of tumor, indices of proliferation, and tumor cellularity before therapy. - Evaluate the role of TK1 on the kinetics of ^18 F-FLT. - Analyze serum. - Research biomarkers of genomics, transcription, and proteomics. - Evaluate the toxicity of ^18F-FLT. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients receive 3'-deoxy-3'-(18F) fluorothymidine (^18F-FLT) IV and undergo positron emission tomography (PET) before the first and second courses of neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Patients receiving bisequential chemotherapy undergo ^18F-FLT-PET before the change in drugs (usually the fourth or fifth course). All patients undergo a final ^18F-FLT-PET after the last chemotherapy course but before surgery. After completion of study therapy, patients are followed for 1 month.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alovudine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dideoxynucleosides</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Inclusion criteria: Histologically confirmed unilateral breast cancer T2 or T3, any N, M0 Unifocal by mammography and ultrasound Negative for cerbB2 by immunohistochemistry (IHC) Planning neoadjuvant chemotherapy comprising anthracyclines and/or taxanes, alone or combined Measurable disease by ultrasound Hormone receptor status not specified Exclusion criteria: Bilateral disease Multifocal tumor Invasive grade I lobular cancer Metastatic disease Stage ≥ T4 disease Cutaneous invasion, major adherence, or inflammatory disease Tumor overexpressing cerbB2 by IHC (HER 2+++) Suspected clinical or radiological lesion (examined or not) PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Inclusion criteria: ECOG performance status 01 Female Menopausal status not specified Hematologic, hepatic, and renal function normal Not pregnant or nursing Fertile patients must use effective contraception Exclusion criteria: Alcohol dependency or prior reaction to ethanol injection Impossible to receive study therapy due to geographical, social, or psychological reasons Prisoners or patients under supervision PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Inclusion criteria: See Disease Characteristics Exclusion criteria: Participation in another concurrent therapeutic study with an experimental drug</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage II breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIA breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>