<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00460369</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Malaria is a life-threatening disease especially in small children. A high degree of Plasmodium falciparum resistance to chloroquine has already spread to South-Benin where this study is taking place. In the past few years, the recommendation for a first-line treatment in this area has moved from chloroquine to sulfadoxine-pyrimethamine (SP). There is growing evidence that Plasmodium falciparum resistance to SP has come to South-Benin. The aim of the study is to compare the efficacy of SP to two compact artemisinin-based therapies (ACT): artemether-lumefantrine and the amodiaquine-artesunate coformulation. ACT will be unsupervised. The primary endpoint is an effectiveness comparison (PCR corrected) at day 28. Secondary outcomes are effectiveness comparisons (PCR corrected) at day 14 and 42 and a study on the relationships between ACT PK data (day 3) and outcome. Expected total enrollment: 225 patients Study start: April 2007; expected completion: December 2007</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Uncomplicated Malaria in Benin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lumefantrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artemether</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artemisinins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sulfadoxine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amodiaquine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artemether-lumefantrine combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fanasil, pyrimethamine drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pyrimethamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artesunate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>6119 months old fever or history of fever of less than 24 hours p falciparum parasitemia &gt; 1000 trophozoïtes/µL informed consent signed &lt; 5 kg danger or severity signs of malaria known underlying chronic disease Hb &lt; 5g/dL adequate malaria treatment taken within 3 days before visit</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>119 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>uncomplicated malaria</keyword>
	<keyword>children</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>effectiveness</keyword>
</DOC>