<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00460304</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective is to establish the mean percentage of change in the insulin-to-carbohydrate ratio due to pramlintide treatment once a maximum tolerated dose or 6 mcg before each meal is reached. The secondary objective is to establish which insulin bolus wave form is associated with the lowest post-bolus without hypoglycemia in subjects treated with maximum pramlintide dosage.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Pramlintide on Meal Time Insulin Bolus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Pramlintide. an amylinomimetic, is effective in reducing post-meal glucose by non-insulin means. As such, when patients requiring insulin treatment are treated with pramlintide, the bolus insulin does must be reduced. Current recommendations suggest a 50% reduction but in our experience and that of a recent study this appears excessive. By using continuous glucose monitoring(CGM) to guide pre-meal insulin treatment, we will determine the percentage reduction in meal time insulin bolus comparing pre-pramlintide to maximum pramlintide treatment. We anticipate that the reduction in bolus dosage will be about 25%. In addition, the secondary aim of this study is to determine which bolus pattern, standard, square or dual wave, provides the best post-meal glucose control with pramlintide therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pramlintide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Islet Amyloid Polypeptide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: &gt;17 Type I diabetes Onset of diabetes &gt;3 months Use of insulin pump &gt;3 months Hb A1C &lt;8.9% Demonstrated compliance to clinic visits Demonstrated knowledge and use of bolus dosing calculations, carbohydrate counting, use of insulin pump and blood glucose meter Monitor blood glucose &gt;4/day Pregnancy or nursing Recent (within last 3 months) factor that may cause change in insulin sensitivity, e.g. severe emotional or physical stress, recent significant infection or surgery. etc. Renal failure (creatinine &gt;1.5 mg/dl Symptomatic gastroparesis Using a medication that would interfere with insulin sensitivity Treatment with extenatide or DPP IV inhibitor within the last 4 weeks HbA1C change &gt;0.9 % within the last 3 months Significant change in eating or activity pattern Weight change of &gt;1.9 kg within the last 3 months ALT &gt;3 times upper limits of normal</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type I diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin pump</keyword>
	<keyword>Continuous glucose monitoring</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin to carbohydrate ratio</keyword>
	<keyword>Correction factor</keyword>
	<keyword>Pramlintide</keyword>
</DOC>