<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01676792</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot clinical study is to evaluate the efficacy &amp; safety of SR-T100 gel (2.3% of SM in Solanum undatum plant extract) in patients with VIN(s) or EGW(s).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SR-T100 Gel Efficacy &amp; Safety Study for Vulva Pre-cancerous Lesions &amp; Cutaneous Condyloma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>An open-label, pilot study to evaluate the efficacy &amp; safety profiles of SR-T100 gel in treating patients with VINs or EGWs. Male &amp; female older than 20 years old have at least one VIN or EGW with lesion size greater than 5 mm in diameter are candidates for this study. The primary endpoint is evaluated based on patients who has received 16-week treatment and presents evaluable measurement datas by the end of 20th week. The secondary endpoints will be evaluated based on all patients with measurable values for VINs or EGWs, recruited patients in this study has never had experiencs associated with prior SR-T100 treatment of any sorts during their life time before becoming a participant in this study. The study plans to recruit 20 patients with VINs or EGWs, the enrollment duration will last two years with total of 40 patients involved.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma in Situ</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Condylomata Acuminata</mesh_term>
	<criteria>(EGW group) Male &amp; female patients older than 20 years old presents at least one pathologically confirmed with histopathology EGW with lesion size greater than 5mm in diameter. (EGW group) Patients with invasive neoplasia, enlarged lymph nodes invasive squamous cell carcinoma, having treated with other investigational drugs within 30 days, pregnancy &amp; lactating females, female with pregnancy potential without using effective boundary barrier or patients with immunedeficience. (VIN group) Female patients older than 20 years old presents at least one histopathologically confirmed VIN with lesion size greater than 5mm in diameter. (VIN group) Patients with invasive neoplasia, enlarged lymph nodes invasive squamous cell carcinoma, having treated with other investigational drugs within 30 days, pregnancy &amp; lactating females, female with pregnancy potential without using effective boundary barrier or patients with immunedeficience.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>condyloma acuminate</keyword>
	<keyword>ano-genital warts</keyword>
	<keyword>genital warts</keyword>
	<keyword>cutaneous condyloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Vulva pre-cancerous lesions</keyword>
	<keyword>Vulvar Intraepitheral Neoplasia</keyword>
	<keyword>VIN</keyword>
	<keyword>EGW</keyword>
</DOC>