<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01752608</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of an electronic cognitive behavioral therapy application (eCBT Mood) compared to a control group consisting of a mood monitoring handheld computer application in the treatment of patients with mild to moderate major depressive disorder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Electronic Cognitive Behavioral Therapy Application to Treat Major Depressive Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, randomized, comparator-controlled, two-arm, parallel group study to examine the safety and efficacy of eCBT Mood, a handheld, computerized, electronic cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) application, in patients with major depressive disorder (MDD). The study will involve 100 patients with mild to moderate MDD randomly assigned to daily use of either a CBT application focused on depression ('eCBT Mood'; MindApps, llc) or a comparator-controlled group using a mood monitoring application ('Mood Tracker'; GP International). This study design and duration of the study is consistent with other studies employing comparator-controlled designs in the study of CBT interventions, including computerized CBT interventions, among patients with MDD (e.g., Andrews et al., 2010; McKendree-Smith et al., 2003). After being screened to ensure that the patients meet the required diagnostic, depression severity, and other inclusion criteria, patients will be randomly assigned (1:1) to use either eCBT Mood, a computer application running on the Apple® iPhone™ or iPod Touch® handheld computer platforms. The application includes: (1) a psychoeducation module on the relationships among thoughts, feelings, and behaviors, (2) a 6-item daily depression assessment with the option to e-mail the summary score and suicidal ideation assessment response to a 3rd party, (3) a negative automatic thought identification module, (4) a feelings and thoughts log, (5) a module enabling the user to challenge their negative automatic thoughts, (6) an assessment and challenge module regarding core beliefs which underlie many automatic thoughts, (7) optional compliance reminders to use the application or take medicines, and (8) links to behavioral science-based online content regarding MDD from PsychCentral (see www.psychcentral.com). In contrast, the comparator control condition will use Mood Tracker, which is also a a computer application running on the Apple iPhone or iPod Touch handheld computer platforms. This application enables users to rate their mood using expressive faces on a daily basis, log about their daily feelings, and also has an option enabling an e-mail to be sent to a 3rd party regarding their daily mood ratings. Throughout the 8-week study period, patients will complete both in-person and telephone-based assessments of their depression severity, mood, frequency of negative automatic thoughts, and safety assessments.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patients between the ages of 18 and 65 at the date of consent. Diagnosis of MDD consistent with the DSMIVTR as assessment by the Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI). Owns and has access to an iPhone or iPod Touch capable of downloading and running either eCBT or the comparator mood monitoring application. At the screening and visits, must exhibit mild to moderate MDD with scores between 17 and 34 on the MADRS, inclusive. Subjects with scores &gt;34 on the MADRS will be referred by the Study Investigator for alternative psychotherapeutic and/or pharmacological care for their depression. Note that no subjects are to be discontinued from any pharmacotherapies used to treat depression solely for the purpose of qualifying for this study. Be willing and able to refrain from the following therapies for the duration of the study: All approved pharmacotherapies for MDD, including serotonin reuptake inhibitors, serotoninnorepinephrine reuptake inhibitors, monoamine oxidase inhibitors, tricyclic and tetracyclic antidepressants, bupropion, mood stabilizers, and adjunctive antipsychotics. Medical device therapies for depression, including transcranial magnetic stimulation, vagal stimulation, electroconvulsive shock therapy, and others. Beginning any type of group or individual psychotherapy. Beginning another clinical trial for major depressive disorder or other condition. Patients' primary language must be English. Subject is willing and has an understanding and ability to fully comply with study procedures and restrictions defined in this protocol. Depression severity, as measured by either: Clinician judgment that the patient's depression is too severe to make selfhelp resource a viable treatment option. Depression severity as measured by a scores &gt;34 on the MADRS. Clinician assessed high risk of suicide or selfharm. Intellectual disability or physical limitation that would prevent use of the computerized handheld intervention. Comorbid psychopathology where the primary disorder is not depression. Within the past 3 months has had a course of treatment with psychotherapy or pharmacotherapy for depression.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Real-time</keyword>
	<keyword>iPhone</keyword>
	<keyword>CBT</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive behavioral therapy</keyword>
</DOC>