<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01752582</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is a comparative evaluation of BuMA stent and of EXCEL stent in terms of the extent of neointima formation at 3 months after implantation using OCT. This is a prospective, single center, randomized, open-label, non-inferiority study, which will enroll a total of 70 patients in Fuwai Hospital.All patients will be randomly assigned undergoing implantation of BuMA stent or EXCEL stent (in a 1:1 ratio). If non-inferiority was met, superiority test will be planned.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>BuMA OCT Study(A Comparative Evaluation of the Extent of Neointima Formation at 3 Months After Implantation Using OCT)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>About 70 patients with clinical evidence of ischemic heart disease and / or a positive functional study and documented stable angina pectoris (Canadian cardiovascular society classification (CCS)1, 2, 3 or 4), or documented silent ischemia in de-novo, native, previously unstented vessel in Fuwai Hospital,will be randomly assigned undergoing implantation of BuMA stent or EXCEL stent (in a 1:1 ratio). All of the patients will receive 6 months dual antiplatelet therapy and they will be followed (at the outpatient clinic) for up to 2 years. The follow-up visits will be conducted at 3 months (including angiographic/OCT investigation), 6 months, 1 and 2 years post percutaneous coronary intervention(PCI),in order to observe the Primary Endpoint and Secondary Endpoints.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angina Pectoris</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angina, Unstable</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angina, Stable</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neointima</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorhexidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorhexidine gluconate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 to 85 years. Evidence of myocardial ischemia without raised troponin (e.g. stable or unstable angina, silent ischemia demonstrated by positive territorial functional study). The patient has a planned intervention of up to four de novo lesions, in different epicardial vessels. Lesion(s) must have a visually estimated diameter stenosis of ≥50% and &lt;100%. Reference Vessel Diameter(RVD) must be between 2.54.0 mm Written informed consent. The patient and the patient's physician agree to the followup visits including angiographic followup and OCT controls at 3 months. Evidence of ongoing acute myocardial infarction in ECG prior to procedure. Left ventricular ejection fraction(LVEF) &lt;30%. Documented or suspected liver disease (including laboratory evidence of hepatitis). Known renal insufficiency (e.g. estimated glomerular filtration rate(eGFR) &lt;60 ml/kg/m2 or serum creatinine level of &gt;2.5 mg/dL, or subject on dialysis). History of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy. The patient is a recipient of a heart transplant. Known hypersensitivity or contraindication to aspirin, both heparin and bivalirudin, antiplatelet medication specified for use in the study (clopidogrel and ticlopidine), sirolimus or stainless steel. Other medical illness (e.g. cancer, neurological deficiency) or known history of substance abuse (alcohol etc.) as per physician judgment that may cause noncompliance with the protocol or confound the data interpretation or is associated with a limited life expectancy. Pregnant or breastfeeding woman or woman in fertile period not taking adequate contraceptives OCT exclusion criteria Severe tortuous, calcified or angulated coronary anatomy of the study vessel that in the opinion of the investigator would result in suboptimal imaging or excessive risk of complication from placement of an OCT catheter Total occlusion or thrombolysis in myocardial infarction(TIMI) flow 0, prior to wire crossing.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>BuMA</keyword>
	<keyword>EXCEL</keyword>
	<keyword>OCT</keyword>
	<keyword>stent</keyword>
	<keyword>neointima formation</keyword>
</DOC>