<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02792400</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In normal physiology, glucagon from pancreatic alpha cells plays an important role in maintaining glucose homeostasis via its regulatory effect on hepatic glucose production. Patients with type 2 diabetes exhibit elevated plasma glucagon levels in the fasting state, and in response to ingestion of glucose or a mixed meal.glucagon, glucagon concentrations fail to decrease appropriately and may even increase. This diabetic hyperglucagonaemia may therefore contribute importantly to the hyperglycaemia of the patients. Several glucose-lowering treatment modalities have been shown to affect glucagon levels in patients with type 2 diabetes, but the role of glucagon in the glucose-lowering effects of these treatment modalities has been difficult to discern. By using a glucagon receptor antagonist (GRA) the investigators will exploit glucagon receptor antagonism to delineate the role of glucagon during treatment with sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors and dipeptidyl peptidase 4 (DPP-4) inhibitors, which have been shown to increase and decrease plasma glucagon levels, respectively.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Role of Glucagon in the Effects of Dipeptidyl Peptidase-4 Inhibitors and Sodium-glucose Co-transporter-2 Inhibitors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Empagliflozin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Linagliptin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon-Like Peptide 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dipeptidyl-Peptidase IV Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Caucasians above 30 years of age with diet or metformin treated type 2 diabetes for at least 3 months (diagnosed according to the criteria of the World Health Organization) Normal haemoglobin Informed consent Inflammatory bowel disease Intestinal resections Nephropathy (serum creatinine above normal range and/or albuminuria) Liver disease (serum alanine aminotransferase (ALAT) and/or serum aspartate aminotransferase (ASAT) &gt;2×normal values) Treatment with medicine that cannot be paused for 12 hours Pregnancy and/or breastfeeding Family history of pancreatic islet tumours Age above 75 years Treatment with loopdiuretics (applies only to arms with empagliflozin or empagliflozin placebo) Chronic heart failure</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>