<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02792816</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Efficacy and safety of the artemisinin combination therapy (ACT) in uncomplicated falciparum malaria patients in Myanmar and artemisinin molecular markers analysis</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Molecular Surveillance of Artemisinin Resistance Malaria in Myanmar</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators assessed the efficacy and safety of the ACT in uncomplicated falciparum malaria in different sentinel sites in Myanmar. The recruited patients were follow-up until day 28 or day-42 based on the ACTs. Day-0 samples were analysed for artemisinin molecular markers, (K13 kelch propeller, Pfmdr2, Pffd and Pfarps10).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malaria, Falciparum</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artemether</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dihydroartemisinin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Piperaquine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artesunate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mefloquine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antimalarials</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artemisinins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artemisinine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Plasmodium falciparum mono infection by microscopy Presence of axillary equal to or more than 37.5 degrees centigrade or history of fever during the past 24 hours Ability to swallow oral medication Ability and willingness to comply with the study protocol for the duration of the study and to comply with the study visit schedule Informed consent from the patient or from a parent or guardian in the case of children Presence of signs of severe falciparum malaria according to the definitions of World Health Organisation (WHO) Mixed or monoinfection with another Plasmodium species detected by microscopy Presence of severe malnutrition (defined as a child whose growth standard is below 3 zscore, has symmetrical oedema involving at least the feet or has a midupper arm circumference below 110 mm) Presence of febrile conditions due to diseases other than malaria (e.g. measles, acute lower respiratory tract infection, severe diarrhoea with dehydration) or other known underlying chronic or severe diseases (e.g. cardiac, renal and hepatic diseases, Human Immune Deficiency Virus (HIV)/Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrom (AIDS) Regular medication, which may interfere with antimalarial pharmacokinetics History of hypersensitivity reactions or contraindications to any of the medicine(s) being tested or used as alternative treatment(s) A positive pregnancy test or breastfeeding Unable to or unwilling to take a pregnancy test or contraceptives</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>69 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>