<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00627757</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine whether antipsychotic treatment is influence psychiatric patients due to endocrine and metabolic status and a quality of life. The investigators expect, that 30-50% of patients will show pharmacon - gene induced weight gain (&gt; 7% of initial bodyweight) while the rest of patients will maintain unaltered bodyweight.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Antipsychotic Medicine and Metabolic Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary aim of this study is to investigate status of neuro-and enteroendocrine axes with focus on beta - cell function in relation to insulin resistance, lipid profile abnormalities and inflammations adipokins in patients during treatment with antipsychotics (AP) in relation to weight gain. The second aim is to evaluate the connection between weight gain and patients´ own perception of their quality of life and health.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antipsychotic Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>gender : male age: 1845 treatment with minimum one Antipsychotic drug (AP) ethnicity: caucasians consent given to take part in the project One criteria is sufficient to exclude patients from the study: compliance problems unable to read, write and talk Danish patients with major lung,heart, lever and kidney problems patients with diagnose and treatment for Diabetes 1 and 2 patients taking cholesterolreducing, weightreducing and antihypertensive medication patients with abuse of alcohol or drugs patients who are under duress § patients who have been mentally ill for more than 15 years patients with diagnosis/treatment for NIDDM/IDDM</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>metabolic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>weight gain</keyword>
	<keyword>antipsychotic drugs</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic syndrome and treatment with antipsychotic drugs</keyword>
</DOC>