<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00627705</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to test the tolerability and efficacy of N-Acetyl Cysteine (NAC) in children with Autism. NAC is a compound that increases the levels of Glutathione, the body's main antioxidant. Glutathione is a compound in the blood that is part of a natural defense system (the antioxidant system). Anti-oxidants protect the body from damage caused by internal toxins called "free radicals." It is possible that children with Autism tend to have lower levels of glutathione, an important compound in our bodies that helps combat the effects of toxic free radicals. We hope that by studying the antioxidant system in more detail, we will increase our understanding of the reasons why people develop Autism so that we can design better ways to treat individuals with this condition. This study is meant to test the safety tolerability of NAC and its effectiveness in the treatment of behavioral difficulties in children with autism. It will also examine the possible benefit of this agent in improving the core deficits in autism such as social deficits.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of N-Acetyl Cysteine in Children With Autism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acetylcysteine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>N-monoacetylcystine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Outpatients between 3.0 and 12.11 years of age inclusive 2. Males and females who are physically healthy 3. diagnosis of autism based DSMIV TR criteria, the Autism Diagnostic InterviewRevised, and expert clinical evaluation 4. CGI Severity rating of 4 5. Care provider who can reliably bring subject to clinic visits, can provide trustworthy ratings, and interacts with subject on a regular basis 6. Ability of subject to swallow the compound 7. Stable concomitant medications for at least 2 weeks 8. No planned changes in psychosocial interventions during the openlabel NAC trial 1. DSMIVTR diagnosis of schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder, or psychotic disorder NOS 2. Prior adequate trial of NAC 3. Active medical problems: unstable seizures, significant physical illness (e.g., serious liver or renal pathology) 4. Pregnancy or sexually active females 5. Subjects taking antioxidant agents and GSH prodrugs will be excluded from the study except if they have been off these compounds for at least 4 weeks</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>