<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00677391</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study was to evaluate the efficacy and the safety of sibutramine vs. placebo in combination with a hypocaloric diet on weight-loss in overweight and obese Malaysian subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Study of Sibutramine in Overweight Non-Diabetic Malaysian Population</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sibutramine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The subject did not adequately respond (i.e., did not achieve or maintain &gt; 5%weight loss) to an appropriate nonpharmacologic weightreducing regimen (i.e., diet and exercise) within 3 months prior to Screening. The subject was male or female and between 18 and 65 years of age. The subject has nutritional obesity and BMI &gt;= 27 kg/m2 associated with dyslipidemia or has BMI &gt;= 30 kg/m2. Dyslipidemia was defined as having at least one of the following three conditions: Lowdensity lipoprotein (LDL)cholesterol level of &gt; 3.4 mmol/L (&gt; 130 mg/dL) total cholesterol level of &gt; 5.2 mmol/L (&gt; 200 mg/dL) triglyceride level of &gt; 1.7 mmol/L (&gt; 150 mg/dL). 254 If the subject was female she must either not of childbearing potential: defined as postmenopausal for at least 2 years or surgically sterile (bilateral tubal ligation, bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy), or was of childbearing potential and practicing one of the following methods of birth control: condoms, sponge, foams, jellies, diaphragm or intrauterine device (IUD)on contraceptives (oral or parenteral) for the 3month period prior to Week 0, a vasectomized partner, total abstinence from sexual intercourse If the subject was female, the results of a urine pregnancy test performed at Screening and Week 0 were negative. If the subject was female, the subject was not breastfeeding. The subject was judged to be in general good health based upon the results of medical history, complete physical examination and clinical laboratory tests. The subject was not taking any overthecounter or prescription drugs, or herbal products for weight loss during the 4 week period prior to Screening. The subject has voluntarily signed and dated an informed consent form, approved by an Institutional Review Board (IRB)/Independent Ethics Committee (IEC), prior to undertaking any studyspecific procedures History or evidence according to the 1997 American Diabetic Association (ADA)26criteria of type 1 or type 2 diabetes mellitus, i.e., fasting plasma glucose level &gt;= 7.0 mmol/L. Inadequately controlled hypertension having systolic blood pressure &gt;= 145 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;= 90 mmHg (average of three measurements) or any hypertensive subjects taking &gt; 3 medications to control blood pressure. History of Gilles de la Tourette's Syndrome. Use within 4 weeks prior to Week 0 of any of the following: Monoamine oxidase inhibitors (MAOIs): used to treat depression and Parkinson's disease. Medications that regulate the neurotransmitter serotonin in the brain (SSRIs): used to treat psychiatric disorders and to stop smoking. Amino acids: used to treat sleep disorders. Certain antimigraine drugs (such as sumatriptan, dihydroergotamine). Opioids (such as pentazocine, pethidine, fentanyl, dextromethorphan). Organic causes of obesity (e.g., hypothyroidism). History of major eating disorders, such as anorexia nervosa or bulimia nervosa. History of benign prostatic hyperplasia with urinary retention. History of neurological disorders such as seizures. History of documented psychiatric illnesses such as anxiety, depression, bipolar disorder or schizophrenia or having psychotic symptoms. History or evidence of severe renal or hepatic impairments. History of narrowangle glaucoma. History of coronary artery disease, congestive heart failure, peripheral arterial occlusive disease, arrhythmia or cerebrovascular disease (transient ischemic attacks or strokes).13. History or evidence of hyperthyroidism. Persistent tachycardia at rest, i.e., heart rate &gt;100 bpm (average of 3 measurements). History of primary or secondary pulmonary hypertension. Underlying or suspected phaeochromocytoma. Known hypersensitivity to sibutramine hydrochloride monohydrate or any other component of the product. Known history of drug or alcohol abuse. Has previous history with the use of sibutramine. Any other medical illnesses judged by the investigator that may compromise the efficacy or safety of sibutramine. Unlikely to cooperate in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
</DOC>