<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="108370">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01693523</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2012-0587</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1R21CA158902-01A1</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2012-02063</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01693523</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Minocycline Study in Pancreatic Cancer Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Placebo Controlled-Double Blind Study of Minocycline for Reducing the Symptom Burden for Pancreatic Cancer Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this research study is to learn if pancreatic cancer and the FOLFIRINOX
      chemotherapy are associated with symptoms such as fatigue, pain, disturbed sleep, lack of
      appetite, and drowsiness, among others. Researchers also want to learn whether any symptoms
      you may have are related to markers of inflammation. Markers of inflammation are found in
      the blood and may be related to symptoms you may have.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Visits:

      If you agree to take part in this study, you will have the following:

      At the time of enrollment:

        -  You will complete 2 questionnaires about pain and other symptoms, and your quality of
           life. It should take about 3-5 minutes to complete the questionnaires.

        -  If possible, blood (about 2 teaspoons) will be drawn to test for markers of
           inflammation at the same time you are having other routine blood draws.

        -  Your demographic information, such as your marital status, job status, education, and
           race will be recorded as well as information about the disease and any treatment you
           have received.

      During FOLFIRINOX treatment:

        -  You will complete the symptom questionnaire 2 times each week during the first cycle
           and 1 time each week during any remaining cycles. The symptom questionnaire asks about
           any symptoms you may be having and how they may be affecting your daily activities. You
           will also complete the quality of life questionnaire.

        -  You will complete the questionnaires in paper-and-pencil format or on an electronic
           tablet PC if you are in the clinic. When you are away from the clinic you will complete
           the questionnaires on the telephone or on your computer.

        -  If possible, during any clinic visits at the start of cycle 2, 3, and 4 (if
           applicable), blood (about 2 teaspoons) will be drawn to test for markers of
           inflammation at the same time you are having other routine blood draws.

      Length of Study Participation:

      You will be on study for up to 8 weeks from the time your chemotherapy starts.

      This is an investigational study.

      Up to 45 patients will take part in this study. All will be enrolled at MD Anderson.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2013</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom Reduction During FOLFIRINOX Chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Primary outcome variable for the study is area under the curve (AUC) value of 5 symptoms: fatigue, drowsiness, pain, disturbed sleep, and lack of appetite over 6 weeks. Estimates of treatment effect obtained using standard linear regression techniques in which AUC values are regressed on indicator variables that represent treatment received. AUC is calculated using a trapezoidal approximation. Area of trapezoid is derived by multiplying half of base with sum of two heights. Base is number of days in between two administration of M.D. Anderson Symptom Inventory (MDASI). Two heights correspond to two mean symptom scores computed at each of these assessments. AUC is measured in units of mean MDASI score in days. Area for subsequent trapezoid calculated in same way. AUC is sum of area of 6 trapezoids.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes Between Inflammation Biomarkers and Symptom Outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Relationship between dynamic changes in inflammation biomarkers and symptom outcomes, controlling for the grouping variable, disease progression (tumor markers, weight loss), evidence of infection, ECOG PS, age, and gender examined. Regression analyses performed to examine relationship between AUC values/MDASI values and CRP, IL-6 and p38 intensity values. Analyses include linear regression analyses of AUC values on the three measured CRP, IL-6 and p38 intensity values, as well as longitudinal analyses of the relationship between individual symptom scores as measured by MDASI and CRP, IL-6, and p38 intensity variables. Using linear regression analyses, effects of minocycline treatment examined on each of the serum markers.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">76</enrollment>
  <condition>Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Minocycline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Minocycline 100 mg by mouth two times a day (200 mg/day). Initial Dose (starts on first day of run-in phase or chemotherapy). Questionnaires completed at baseline, 1 time each week during drug/placebo administration, and at end of study visit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Matching placebo capsules by mouth twice a day. Initial Dose (starts on first day of run-in phase or chemotherapy). Questionnaires completed at baseline, 1 time each week during drug/placebo administration, and at end of study visit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Minocycline</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg by mouth two times a day (200 mg/day).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Minocycline</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Dynacin</other_name>
    <other_name>Minocin</other_name>
    <other_name>Minocin PAC</other_name>
    <other_name>Myrac</other_name>
    <other_name>Solodyn</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Matching placebo capsules by mouth twice a day.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sugar pill</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaires</intervention_name>
    <description>Questionnaires completed at baseline, 1 time each week during drug/placebo administration, and at end of study visit.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Minocycline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Surveys</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Minocycline Trial only: Patients with a pathological or clinical diagnosis of
             pancreatic cancer and beginning or continuing FOLFIRINOX or gemcitabine-based
             chemotherapy.

          2. Observational Arm only: Patients with a pathological or clinical diagnosis of
             pancreatic cancer and beginning or continuing FOLFIRINOX chemotherapy.

          3. Patients &gt; 18 years old.

          4. Minocycline Trial only: Patients with ECOG PS = 0-2.

          5. Patients who speak English or Spanish (due to MDASI language options, we are only
             accruing English-speaking or Spanish-speaking patients to the protocol).

          6. Patients willing and able to review, understand, and provide written consent before
             starting therapy.

          7. Minocycline Trial only: Patients with adequate renal function according to MD
             Anderson testing standards (screening cut off for serum creatinine &lt; 2 times the
             upper limit of normal).

          8. Minocycline Trial only: Patients with adequate hepatic function according to MD
             Anderson testing standards (screening results for total bilirubin must be &lt; 2 times
             the upper limit of normal; screening results for alanine aminotransferase (ALT) must
             be &lt; 3 times the upper limit of normal; screening results for aspartate
             aminotransferase (AST), if available, must be &lt; 3 times the upper limit of normal).

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Minocycline Trial only: Patients who are taking medication or have conditions that
             potentially preclude use of minocycline, as determined by the treating physician.

          2. Patients who are enrolled in other symptom management clinical trials.

          3. Minocycline Trial only: Patients who currently have bile duct obstruction or
             cholelithiasis.

          4. Minocycline Trial only: Patients with hypersensitivity to any tetracyclines.

          5. Minocycline Trial only: Patients who are pregnant. Pregnancy will be confirmed by
             negative urine test; patients with a positive urine test will be retested for
             doubling of HCG 48 hours after the first test, because of beta-HCG's role as a tumor
             marker. Patients without such a rise will be eligible for the study and will be
             enrolled at the investigator's discretion.

          6. Minocycline Trial only: Patients who are under treatment of warfarin with INR &gt; 1.5.

          7. Patients who, in the judgment of the investigator, may be unable to participate in
             the required study procedures.

          8. Minocycline Trial only: Patients who have had prior treatment for pancreatic cancer
             within the past six months may be excluded at the discretion of the investigator.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David Fogelman, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shelley Wang, MD,MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 15, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>September 21, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Pancreatic adenocarcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Locally advanced</keyword>
  <keyword>Metastatic disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Symptom reduction</keyword>
  <keyword>Minocycline</keyword>
  <keyword>Dynacin</keyword>
  <keyword>Minocin</keyword>
  <keyword>Minocin PAC</keyword>
  <keyword>Myrac</keyword>
  <keyword>Solodyn</keyword>
  <keyword>Placebo</keyword>
  <keyword>Sugar Pill</keyword>
  <keyword>Questionnaires</keyword>
  <keyword>Surveys</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Minocycline</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
