<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="31816">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02692495</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200904010001MEBO</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02692495</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Potential Screening Tools for Metabolic Body Odor and Halitosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Gastrointestinal and Nutritional Diagnostic Tests as Potential Screening Tools for Metabolic Body Odor and Halitosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mebo Research, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mebo Research, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed as a prospective cohort study to evaluate the potential of diagnostic
      procedures in defining populations of patients self-reporting unexpected and uncontrollable
      episodes of body odor and/or halitosis. Our initial cohort is generally healthy individuals
      who already underwent multiple diagnostic tests recommended by their physicians and have not
      been diagnosed with any known condition. The investigators will analyze results of
      gastrointestinal and nutritional diagnostic tests offered by Biolab Medical Unit to
      determine if these tests are useful as potential screening tools for metabolic body odor and
      halitosis.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Many yet uncharacterized medical conditions including inborn and acquired errors of
      metabolism or skewed microbiome could be responsible for unpredictable and uncontrollable
      episodes of body odor and halitosis. These conditions have dramatic impact on the quality of
      life and socioeconomic outcomes of sufferers. Yet clinics and specialized malodor centers do
      not provide tests for diagnosing malodor other than trimethylaminuria (TMAU). Self-reported
      odor problems are often dismissed if are not organoleptically evaluated by trained odor
      judges that are not readily available during malodor flare-ups.

      The aim of this study is to analyze effectiveness of existing gastrointestinal and
      nutritional tests for the assessment and investigation of self-reported malodors.

      Diagnostic tests include:

        -  Gut Permeability Profile. PEG 400 is used as a probe and measured in urine passed for
           the following 6 hours at 11 different molecular weights to establish the quantity of
           each absorbed through the gut wall. Extraction and separation of PEG from urine is done
           by ion exchange chromatography and capillary GLC.

        -  Gut Fermentation Profile. Blood alcohols - ethanol, methanol, butanol, propanol and
           short chain fatty acids - are measured by gas-liquid chromatography.

        -  D-lactate test. D-lactate is measured by centrifugal analysis using the specific enzyme
           D-lactate dehydrogenase, which does not react with L-lactate

        -  The urine indicans (Obermeyer) test. Detection of indican in the urine depends upon its
           decomposition and subsequent oxidation of indoxyl to indigo blue and its absorption
           into a chloroform layer

        -  Breath test for small intestinal dysbiosis. Breath hydrogen and methane are measured by
           gas-liquid chromatography. The patient is given 10 gm of lactulose in 200 ml of water
           and alveolar air samples are collected every 20 minutes for 3 hours

        -  Functional B vitamins profile, by measuring the activation of a red cell enzyme that is
           dependent upon an adequate concentration of a particular vitamin for full activity. The
           assay relies on normal metabolism of the vitamin to its native form and the presence of
           other non-vitamin cofactors.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of test results outside the normal range</measure>
    <time_frame>four years</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators would like to validate if diagnostic tests taken by participants (see the list in the detailed description of the study) can be used for diagnosing malodor. Values measured by the laboratory (Biolab Medical Unit) will be compared against the reference range specific to that laboratory.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identification of sensitive and specific biomarkers that correlate with subjective reports of malodor symptoms (questionnaires)</measure>
    <time_frame>three years</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will comprehensively analyze diagnostic ability of tests taken by participants to correlate with their symptoms and discriminate between different subgroups of malodor.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Nutritional and Metabolic Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Body odor</arm_group_label>
    <description>individuals self-reporting recurrent episodes of uncontrollable body odor with or without halitosis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Halitosis</arm_group_label>
    <description>individuals with extra-oral halitosis, not complaining of body odors</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Individuals reporting idiopathic malodor production
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  idiopathic malodor experienced over a period of several months or years

          -  willing and able to complete the study

          -  good general health

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  elect not to participate in the study
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Irene Gabashvili, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>MeBO Research</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MeBO Research LTD</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>England</state>
        <zip>W10 5LE</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chadwick VS, Phillips SF, Hofmann AF. Measurements of intestinal permeability using low molecular weight polyethylene glycols (PEG 400). I. Chemical analysis and biological properties of PEG 400. Gastroenterology. 1977 Aug;73(2):241-6.</citation>
    <PMID>873124</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sivakumaran T, Jenkins RT, Walker WH, Goodacre RL. Simplified measurement of polyethylene glycol 400 in urine. Clin Chem. 1982 Dec;28(12):2452-3.</citation>
    <PMID>7139937</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hunnisett A., Howard J., Davies S. Gut fermentation (or the 'Auto-brewery') Syndrome: A new clinical test with initial observations and discussion of clinical and biochemical implications J.Nutr.Med.1:33-8, 1990</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sheedy JR, Wettenhall RE, Scanlon D, Gooley PR, Lewis DP, McGregor N, Stapleton DI, Butt HL, DE Meirleir KL. Increased d-lactic Acid intestinal bacteria in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. In Vivo. 2009 Jul-Aug;23(4):621-8.</citation>
    <PMID>19567398</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ludvigsen CW, Thurn JR, Pierpont GL, Eckfeldt JH. Kinetic enzymic assay for D(-)-lactate, with use of a centrifugal analyzer. Clin Chem. 1983 Oct;29(10):1823-5.</citation>
    <PMID>6616831</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jenq RR. How's your microbiota? Let's check your urine. Blood. 2015 Oct 1;126(14):1641-2. doi: 10.1182/blood-2015-08-661504.</citation>
    <PMID>26429966</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Khoshini R, Dai SC, Lezcano S, Pimentel M. A systematic review of diagnostic tests for small intestinal bacterial overgrowth. Dig Dis Sci. 2008 Jun;53(6):1443-54. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17990113</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Drossman DA. The functional gastrointestinal disorders and the Rome III process. Gastroenterology. 2006 Apr;130(5):1377-90. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16678553</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mount JN, Heduan E, Herd C, Jupp R, Kearney E, Marsh A. Adaptation of coenzyme stimulation assays for the nutritional assessment of vitamins B1, B2 and B6 using the Cobas Bio centrifugal analyser. Ann Clin Biochem. 1987 Jan;24 ( Pt 1):41-6.</citation>
    <PMID>3827183</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 22, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 16, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>body odor</keyword>
  <keyword>halitosis</keyword>
  <keyword>dysbiosis</keyword>
  <keyword>leaky gut</keyword>
  <keyword>microbiome</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Halitosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>de-identified individual participant data will be made partially available</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
