<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00506272</DOC>
	<brief_summary>ISMAS is designed to test the hypothesis that self management of insulin dependent diabetes mellitus by selected patients admitted for elective surgery is more efficacious than standard care with respect to overall glycemic control, attaining finger-stick blood sugars, and administering insulin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Inpatient Self Monitoring and Administration Study (ISMAS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypoglycemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperglycemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 1. Male or female, age &lt; 80 2. Most recent hemoglobin A1C within the past 6 months &lt; 12% 3. Recent history of regular selfadministered peripheral blood glucose checks as an outpatient 4. Recent history of insulin selfadministration at least twice a day as an outpatient 5. Admitted for a hospitalization anticipated to last at least 3 days 6. Mini Mental Status Examination (MMSE) ≥ 25 at admission and the same or better postoperatively 7. All patients will be actively followed by the Endocrinology inpatient consultation team during the hospitalization. Exclusion criteria: 1. Currently receiving peritoneal or hemodialysis 2. Patients with unstable angina 3. History of myocardial infarction within 3 weeks prior to enrollment 4. Current admission due to or associated with altered mental status or encephalopathy 5. History of an episode of altered mental status or encephalopathy within the 4 weeks prior to enrollment 6. A confirmed diagnosis of dementia 7. Inability to selfadjust insulin 8. No recent history of ability to perform regular peripheral blood glucose checks 9. Frequency of hypoglycemia (&lt; 60 mg/dL) &gt; twice/week by history 10. Inability to eat without assistance 11. Study objectives will not be pursued in patients during stays in any intensive care unit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>hyperglycemia</keyword>
	<keyword>hypoglycemia</keyword>
	<keyword>self care</keyword>
</DOC>