<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00506168</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of combination chemotherapy with irinotecan and capecitabine in previously untreated metastatic colorectal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Irinotecan &amp; Capecitabine in Metastatic Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single center, single arm, open-label, phase II study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of combination chemotherapy with irinotecan and capecitabine in previously untreated metastatic colorectal cancer. Patients younger then 65 will be treated with irinotecan 100 mg/m2 on day 1 and 8 and capecitabine 1,000mg/m2 twice daily from day 1 to 14 every 3 weeks.For patiens equal to or older then 65, doses of irinotecan and capecitabine will be reduced to 60 mg/m2 and 750 mg/2, respectively. Response assessment will be performed every 3 cycles of chemotherapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed metastatic colorectal cancer ECOG performance status 02 Mesurable lesions No prior chemotherapyk or radiotherapy for metastatic disease. Prior radiotherapy is permitted if it was not administered to target lesions selected for this study and provided it has been completed at least 4 weeks before registration Adjuvnat chemo or radiotherapy was completed at least 6 months prior to start study treatment Adequate organ functions Expected survival is longer then 6 months Informed consent Prior systemic chemotherapy for metastatic disease Prior treatment with oxaliplatin or irinotecan CNS metastases Uncontrolled or severe cardiovascular disease Serious concurrent infection or nonmalignant illness that is uncontrolled or whose control may be jeopardized by complications of study therapy Other malignancy within the past 3 years except cured nonmelanomatous skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix Psychiatric disorder or uncontrolled seizure that would preclude compliance Pregnant, nursing women or patients with reproductive potential without contraception Patients receiving a concomitant treatment with drugs interacting with capecitabine such as flucytosine, phenytoin, or warfarin et al. Prior unanticipated severe reaction to fluoropyrimidine therapy, or known dihydropyrimidine dehydrogenase (DPD) deficiency Major surgery within 3 weeks prior to study treatment starts, or lack of complete recovery from the effects of major surgery</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Colorectal neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Secondary</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug therapy, combination</keyword>
	<keyword>Irinotecan</keyword>
	<keyword>Capecitabine</keyword>
</DOC>