<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00506415</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to support the optimal use of rivastigmine patch in long-term treatment of Alzheimer's Disease in patients demonstrating functional and cognitive decline at the target maintenance dose of rivastigmine patch 10 cm^2.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparative Efficacy, Safety, and Tolerability of Rivastigmine 10 and 15 cm^2 Patch in Patients With Alzheimer's Disease (AD) Showing Cognitive Decline</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivastigmine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patients between 50 and 85 years of age with a diagnosis of probable Alzheimers Disease, Baseline MiniMental State Examination (MMSE) score 1024 inclusive, A primary caregiver willing to accept responsibility for supervising treatment, assessing the patient's condition throughout the study, and for providing input into efficacy assessments. For double blind only: Meet the decline criteria of functional (as assessed by the investigator) and cognitive (assessed by a 1 point reduction in MiniMental State Examination) score between visits or a 3 point reduction from baseline) decline at weeks 23, 36 or 48. Presence of an advanced, severe, progressive, or unstable disease of any type that could interfere with efficacy and safety assessments or put the patient at particular risk, Any medical or neurological condition other than Alzheimers Disease that could explain the patient's dementia, A diagnosis of probable or possible vascular dementia, A current diagnosis of unsuccessfullytreated depression, or any other mental disorder that may interfere with the evaluation of the patient's response to study medication, A history or current diagnosis of cerebrovascular disease (e.g. stroke), A current diagnosis of severe or unstable cardiovascular disease (e.g. unstable coronary artery disease). Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's</keyword>
	<keyword>Patch</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive</keyword>
	<keyword>Decline</keyword>
</DOC>