<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01039818</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether higher doses of radioiodine increase treatment efficacy in severe Graves' disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Different Doses of 131I in Severe Graves' Hyperthyroidism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Graves' disease (GD) is the most frequent cause of hyperthyroidism, affecting mainly women aged 40-60 years. Radioiodine (¹³¹I), introduced in 1941, has become a cornerstone in the treatment of GD hyperthyroidism. Because of its safety, low costs and rapid effect, it is considered a first line therapy in the United States. However, treatment failure occurs in about 15-25% of patients treated with radioiodine. Patients not cured with the first dose of radioiodine usually present severe hyperthyroidism, characterized by large goiter, high 24-hour radioiodine uptake (24h-RAIU) and very high levels of thyroid hormones. We have previously shown that large goiter (≥48ml) is an independent predictor of treatment failure. In these patients, the therapeutic failure was 40.0% while in patients with smaller goiter was only 6.5% (P=0.005; unpublished). It is generally accepted that higher doses of radioiodine improves cure rates. Indeed, a recent meta-analysis found a correlation between radioiodine dose and therapeutic success in GD patients. To our knowledge, there are no published studies evaluating cure rates with different radioiodine doses in severe GD.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Graves Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperthyroidism</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Consecutive patients with a recent diagnosis of Graves' disease and goiter ≥ 48 ml, attending the Endocrine Division at Hospital de Clinicas de Porto Alegre are eligible. Patients with previous treatment with radioiodine or thyroidectomy, Signs of moderate or severe ophthalmopathy (proptosis &gt; 22 mm, ophthalmoplegia, chemosis, or lagophthalmos), Severe heart disease (symptomatic coronary heart disease, class III heart failure, New York Heart Association criteria), Debilitating conditions, and Large and compressive goiters (&gt; 150 g).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Graves Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperthyroidism</keyword>
	<keyword>Radioiodine</keyword>
	<keyword>Clinical trial</keyword>
</DOC>