<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01039467</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The COMPARE-Adapta study is a randomized, multi-center, prospective study conducted in China. The purpose of the study is to compare the ability of Search AV™+ and Managed Ventricular Pacing® (MVP®) to reduce ventricular pacing in dual chamber pacemaker-indicated patients. The COMPARE-Adapta study will also observe atrial fibrillation (AF) burden as demonstrated by Cardiac Compass® and the clinical profile Adapta® pacemaker patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Comparison of the Pacemaker Automatic Features in Reduction of Ventricular Pacing</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Recent studies suggest that chronic right ventricular pacing is associated with a variety of adverse effects in patients, particularly those with intact or intermittent atrioventricular (AV) conduction. Medtronic Adapta® pacemakers include Managed Ventricular Pacing®, a pacing mode designed to promote intrinsic conduction, and also Search AV™+, a feature designed to reduce unnecessary ventricular pacing in patients with intact or intermittent AV conduction.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Signed and dated study informed consent Class I or Class IIa pacemaker indication Geographically stable and available for followup at the center for the length of the study Age greater than 18 To be implanted with Adapta dual chamber pacemaker Unwillingness or inability to give written informed consent to participate in the Study Patient with a previously implanted pacemaker/Implantable CardioverterDefibrillator (ICD)/Cardiac Resynchronization Therapy (CRT) device Life expectancy of less than one year Patient has a mechanical tricuspid heart valve Medical conditions that preclude the testing requirement by the protocol or limit study participation Patient has persistent 3rd degree atrioventricular (AV) block Patient has persistent atrial fibrillation (AF) Patient has neurogenic syncope Patient has carotid sinus syndrome Patient has hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy Inclusion in another clinical trial or study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Managed Ventricular Pacing</keyword>
</DOC>