<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02775123</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Investigators are planning a single center pilot randomized controlled trial to assess the potential of a Cytoadsorbant filter (Cytosorb®, Germany) to remove cytokines from the blood during cardiac surgery. Investigators will screen all patients undergoing cardiac surgery and approach those deemed at risk of post surgical complications [≥ 1 among: age &gt;75 years old, double valvular replacement, complex surgery with expected CPB time &gt;100 min, redo cardiac surgery, pre-op chronic renal failure (plasma creatinine level &gt;120 mcmol/l) or chronic heart failure (LVEF &lt;35%)]. Patients with end-stage renal disease (dialysis dependence), undergoing an emergency procedure or an off-pump procedure, those who decline informed consent as well as those enrolled in another conflicting study will be excluded. Eligible patients will be approached, consented and enrolled in the trial. Patients will then be randomized to either receive conventional CPB (control arm) or CPB plus Cytosorb (intervention arm). The target population is 30 patients (15 per arm). For this pilot study, investigators main outcome will be differences between the two arms in measurement of serum levels for IL-2, IL-6, IL-10 and TNF alpha at baseline (pre-operatively), on ICU admission, as well as 6 and 24 hrs post CPB. Secondary outcomes will be changes in coagulation factors serum levels, the need for vasopressors, inotropes, mechanical ventilation and renal replacement therapy, ICU and hospital length of stay as well as in-hospital mortality. Recruitment period should span from May 2016 to April 2017.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cytokine Clearance With Cytoabsorbant Device During Cardiac Bypass</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Valve Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients planned for elective cardiac surgery requiring CPB and (≥1 among): Age &gt;75 years' old AND / OR Double valvular replacement AND / OR Complex surgery with expected CPB time &gt;120 min AND / OR Redo cardiac surgery AND / OR Preop chronic renal failure (GFR&lt;30 ml/min) AND / OR Chronic heart failure (LVEF &lt;40%) End stage renal disease (dialysis dependence) Emergency procedure Active infectious endocarditis Offpump procedure planned Non steroidal antiinflammatory treatment in the previous 7 days Corticosteroids administration in the previous 7 days No informed consent Enrolment in another conflicting study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>