<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02980523</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Hypothesis PRO-157 (Project-157) ophthalmic solution is as safe and effective, demonstrating non-inferiority, when compared against Moxifloxacin and Gatifloxacin in the treatment of conjunctivitis. General objective: assess the safety and efficacy of the PRO-157 ophthalmic solution in three different dosing regimens, versus Moxifloxacin, versus Gatifloxacin in patients with bacterial conjunctivitis. Specific objectives: determine the safety of the PRO-157 ophthalmic solution in three different dosages versus Moxifloxacin versus Gatifloxacin in patients with bacterial conjunctivitis by the incidence of adverse events. evaluate the efficacy of the PRO-157 ophthalmic solution in three different dosing regimens, versus Moxifloxacin, versus Gatifloxacin in patients with bacterial conjunctivitis through evaluation of ocular signs and symptoms such as: burning, tearing, foreign body sensation, pruritus, photophobia, Conjunctival hyperemia, chemosis, secretion, membranes and / or pseudomembranes, scales and eyelid edema, epitheliopathy. Number of participants: 300 eyes, 60 per group. Inclusion criteria: Patients with bacterial conjunctivitis (signs and / or symptoms and / or culture) Treatment duration: Recruitment: 4 months Treatment: 7 days Follow-up: 15 days Criteria for evaluation: Measurements of effectiveness: Main efficacy criterion It will be determined as effective if there is a reduction in number or species of bacterial flora by comparing the basal culture against the final culture among the five different patient groups. Reduction or absence of infection with the clinical evaluation through signs and symptoms such as burning, tearing, foreign body sensation, pruritus, photophobia, conjunctival hyperemia, chemosis, secretion, eyelid edema, membranes or pseudomembranes, palpebral scales and epitheliopathy Safety Measurements: it will be determined by visual acuity and adverse events This is a phase II multicenter, evaluating 5 treatment arms. Patients recruited diagnosed with bacterial conjunctivitis will be treated for 7 days with any of three doses of PRO-157, Moxifloxacin, or Gatifloxacin. The randomization will be coordinated by a member of the research team previously designated by principal investigator (PI) who will not be masked and will instruct the patients about how to apply the drops, emphasizing patients not mention to the evaluating physician about frequency of the study medication. For protocol purpose, the infected eye (s) will be taken into account at the time of baseline, however the study medication and procedures will be applied and performed in both eyes to protect the healthy eye. The study is divided into the following evaluation periods: Visit 1 baseline (day 1), visit 2 (day 3), final visit (day 8). and a telephone call (day 23) for the evaluation of adverse events after 15 days of the last drug application. In each visit the PI will take a photograph of both eyes to make a visual clinical comparison at the end of the study. Subjects will be allocated to any of the following regimen dosages: - PRO-157 1 drop 2 times daily in both eyes - PRO-157 1 drop 3 times daily in both eyes. - PRO-157 1 drop 4 times daily in both eyes. - Moxifloxacin 1 drop 3 times daily in both eyes. - Gatifloxacin 1 drop 3 times daily in both eyes. All regimen dosage will have a duration of 7 days. An artificial tear preservative free (Lagricel Ofteno®) will also be applied 15 minutes before instillation of study drug, during study period. Data Analysis The data will be analyzed by Intention to Treat (ITT) and per Protocol (PP) , in which each of the variables is described, the ITT population will be constituted by all subjects recruited who have received at least one dose of the study, the PP population will be the subset of ITT composed of all subjects without any major deviation from the protocol and the bivariate analysis will be performed in this group. Continuous quantitative variables are expressed and presented by measures of central tendency and dispersion (mean, standard deviation and ranges). Qualitative nominal and ordinal variables are presented by means of frequencies and proportions. The Kolmogorov-Smirnov test was performed to know the normal distribution or not of the results obtained in each study group. The differences between-group were determined by the ANOVA test, for the quantitative variables. For the qualitative variables, Pearson's chi-square will be used. Intra-group differences were analyzed using the T-test in the case of quantitative variables. For the qualitative variables differences were calculated by Pearson's chi-square. The level of significance was an alpha of 0.05 or less.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of PRO-157 vs Moxifloxacin vs Gatifloxacin in Patients With Bacterial Conjunctivitis (Pazufloxacin)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Lagricel Ofteno® is a registered trademark, therefore the use of the same throughout the document can not be translated into the English language. PRO-157, the acronym is part of an internal code used to record formulations or research projects and the numbers indicate consecutive of the molecule under study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Conjunctivitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Conjunctivitis, Bacterial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyaluronic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gatifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluoroquinolones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Moxifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pazufloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Norgestimate, ethinyl estradiol drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Obtained from physician office visit. Diagnosis of bacterial conjunctivitis (signs and / or symptoms and / or culture). Informed Consent signed and dated (consent of the parents for minor patients). absence of written informed consent. Women of childbearing age, without contraceptive use (oral contraceptive pill, contraceptive intrauterine device, contraceptive implant, patch or condom). Pregnant or breastfeeding women. Subjects that could not be evaluated partially or totally according to the protocol. Subjects with topical, systemic or intravenous medication with any type of antibiotic on the day of the baseline visit. Subjects with topical, systemic or intravenous medication with any type of medication that interferes decisively with the results of the study. Subjects with a hypersensitivity history to any component or analogues of the formulation product. Positive drug addiction (smoking, alcoholism, marijuana). Subjects with a history of participation in any clinical study in the last 40 days prior to their evaluation. incapacity to give informed consent owing to mental disorder or legal condition. Any major anomaly detected during the clinical examination, tests that could interfere with the performance of the study or with the efficacy and safety evaluations.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>