<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00318565</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective is to provide additional corroborative safety and efficacy data for the Navistar Thermocool catheter for the treatment of subjects with typical atrial flutter (AFL).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Catheter Evaluation for Endocardial Ablation in Patients With Typical Atrial Flutter</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a prospective, non-randomized, single-arm, multi-center condition of approval evaluation. The device is currently FDA approved for commercial distribution. Subjects with symptomatic typical atrial flutter will be considered for the condition of approval study. This study will be conducted at up to 30 centers in a minimum of 221 evaluable subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Flutter</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Two symptomatic episodes of typical atrial flutter (or chronic atrial flutter) during the oneyear period prior to enrollment. This may include typical AFL occurring while receiving antiarrhythmic drug (AAD) therapy for nonAFL tachyarrhythmia, including atrial fibrillation. At least one episode of typical (clockwise or counterclockwise) atrial flutter documented by 12 lead electrocardiogram (ECG), Holter monitor, transtelephonic event monitor, telemetry strip, or implanted device within 6 months prior to enrollment. 18 years of age or older Informed consent Intracardiac thrombus Uncontrolled heart failure, or New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III or IV heart failure Women who are pregnant Cardiac surgery (ventriculotomy or atriotomy) within the past two months Intraatrial thrombus, tumor, or other abnormality that precludes catheter introduction and placement Unstable angina or acute myocardial infarction within 3 months Awaiting cardiac transplantation Heart disease in which corrective surgery is anticipated within 6 months Presence of condition that precludes appropriate vascular access Enrolled in any investigational device exemption (IDE) investigating study for a device or drug High risk for noncompliance with the protocol (e.g., inaccessible for followup by the investigator or patient's physician) Radio frequency (RF) ablation for typical atrial flutter within the past 2 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Heart Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Atrial Flutter</keyword>
	<keyword>Typical Atrial Flutter</keyword>
</DOC>