<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00297674</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this clinical trial is to clarify the clinical efficacy of clarithromycin as immunotherapy for the management of septic syndrome by ventilator-associated pneumonia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intravenous Clarithromycin in Septic Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The rationale of the trial is based on the favorable results of experimental studies of sepsis by multidrug-resistant Pseudomonas aeruginosa and by susceptible Escherichia coli in rabbits where clarithromycin was administered intravenously. Data from these latter studies suggest that administration of clarithromycin extended survival and attenuated systemic inflammatory response. Their major endpoint was successful immunotherapy achieved when clarithromycin was administered on presentation of symptoms of sepsis-induced pulmonary edema; on the contrary, former clinical trials for immunotherapies of sepsis were based on animal studies where the under evolution immunomodulator was administered before bacterial challenge. The efficacy of administration of clarithromycin upon presentation of septic syndrome in animal studies, renders its application promising in the clinical field.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sepsis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia, Ventilator-Associated</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Systemic Inflammatory Response Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clarithromycin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. written informed consent provided by first or second degree relatives; 2. intubation and mechanical ventilation at least 48 hours prior to enrolment; c) age of patients equal to or more than 18 years; d) diagnosis of Ventilator Associated Pneumonia; and e) signs of sepsis 1. neutropenia, defined as less than 500 neutrophils/mm3; 2. HIV infection; 3. oral intake of corticosteroids at a dose equal to or higher than 1mg/kg equivalent prednisone for a period greater than one month; 4. administration of drotrecogin alpha the last five days prior to enrolment; and e) atrioventricular block of second or third degree.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2004</verification_date>
	<keyword>clarithromycin</keyword>
	<keyword>sepsis</keyword>
	<keyword>immunomodulation</keyword>
</DOC>