<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00685750</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study intends to analyze the expression of specific sets of markers in tumor samples and in serum from patients with Non-Small Cell lung Cancer (NSCLC) or Stage III or IV melanoma. The data obtained in this study will be used to guide future development of immunotherapies for melanoma or NSCLC patients. Moreover, the analyses will contribute to definition of markers potentially predictive of clinical response to specific anticancer therapies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Expression Analysis of Specific Markers in Non-small Cell Lung Cancer or Melanoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This protocol posting has been updated due to a protocol amendment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient (male or female) is at least 18 years of age. The investigator believes that the patient can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol. The patient has given his/her written informed consent to take part in the study. The investigator believes that it will be possible to obtain a tumor tissue sample of at least 3 mm3 before treatment and all required tumor tissues several weeks after the initiation of the treatment. The patient has cancer in one of the following histological types, fulfilling all of the characteristics listed for the respective cancer type: Cutaneous Melanoma, unresectable stage III or stage IV • The patient has histologically documented unresectable stage III or stage IV metastatic cutaneous melanoma. AND • The patient is a candidate for one of the following treatments: Firstline chemotherapy with DTIC or TMZ as monotherapy [group ME1], Firstline chemotherapy with an agent other than DTIC/TMZ as monotherapy or a combination (that may, but need not, include DTIC, TMZ, IL2 or IFNγ) [group ME2], Second or higherline chemotherapy with any agent or combination of agents (that may, but need not, include DTIC, TMZ, IL2 or IFNγ ; i.e., systemic chemotherapy after isolated limb perfusion should be considered as secondline) [group ME3], Palliative irradiation of skin lesion(s)/region, irrespective of what line of treatment is planned [group ME4], Topical palliative treatment by imiquimod of skin lesion(s), irrespective of what line of treatment is planned [group ME5]. First or higher line treatment with ipilimumab [group ME6]. NSCLC, any stage if the patient is eligible for neoadjuvant chemotherapy with subsequent resection • The patient has NSCLC at any stage (as defined by the International Staging System) if the patient is eligible for neoadjuvant chemotherapy with subsequent resection. AND • The patient is a candidate for chemo(radio)therapy induction doublet neoadjuvant chemotherapy with platinum plus a second chemotherapy drug. [Note: Induction radiotherapy is permitted.] The recruitment of patients to the NSCLC group has been ended prematurely. The patient has any family history of congenital or hereditary immunodeficiency. The patient has in the two weeks before baseline received any of the following: Chemotherapeutic agents, Immunemodulating agents such as (but not confined to) IFNα, IL2, BCG and anticancer therapeutic vaccines, Immunosuppressive agents such as corticosteroids [except for prednisone, or equivalent, &lt;0.5 mg/kg/day (absolute maximum 40 mg/day, maximum duration of treatment three weeks), and inhaled and topical steroids, which are allowed]. The patient is currently receiving an anti cancer treatment in another clinical trial. However, if the patient has finished the drug administration phase of that trial and has entered the followup phase, this patient can be included.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>tumor antigen</keyword>
	<keyword>biomarkers</keyword>
</DOC>