<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02346734</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study will be to assess the feasibility and patient acceptance of a Home Automated Telemanagement (HAT) system in multiple sclerosis patients. Our hypothesis is that home telemanagement will be effective and useful in the rehabilitation of multiple sclerosis patients. Specifically, the investigators hypothesize that home telemanagement using a daily exercise diary, monitoring of compliance with a tailored exercise program and regular assessment of strength and motor functions will: 1. Be feasible and acceptable in patients with multiple sclerosis 2. Improve patient compliance with home exercise program 3. Increase patient mobility and motor functions 4. Be a feasible and effective mechanism for affecting multiple sclerosis patient self-efficacy 5. Improve quality of life</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physical Telerehabilitation in Veterans With Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: 1865 Clinical Diagnosis of MS based on McDonald criteria Functional disability defined by the PDDS in the range of 2 to 6 Have a working telephone line in their home or a cell phone Willingness and ability to use MS HAT platform with individual modifications based on preferred user interface Patient demonstrates ability to successfully perform physical therapy exercises and procedures independently or with assistance of a caregiver. Ability to complete 25foot walk test in at least 3 minutes Age less than 18 years old No diagnosis of MS Other musculoskeletal diagnoses, unstable cardiovascular, respiratory, metabolic or other conditions that would interfere with this study One or more exacerbations in the preceding 3 months Received a course of steroids (IV or oral) within 60 days of screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Telerehablitation</keyword>
</DOC>