<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="53157">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02414165</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Tg 511-15-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02414165</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>P2/3 Randomized Study of Toca 511 &amp; Toca FC Versus SOC in Subjects Undergoing Surgery for Recurrent GBM/AA</brief_title>
  <acronym>Toca5</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 2/3 Randomized, Open-Label Study of Toca 511, a Retroviral Replicating Vector, Combined With Toca FC Versus Standard of Care in Subjects Undergoing Planned Resection for Recurrent Glioblastoma or Anaplastic Astrocytoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tocagen Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tocagen Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, randomized, open-label phase 2/3 study of Toca 511 and Toca FC versus
      standard of care that comprises Investigator's choice of single agent chemotherapy
      (lomustine or temozolomide) or bevacizumab administered to subjects undergoing resection for
      first or second recurrence (including this recurrence) of GBM or AA. Subjects meeting all of
      the inclusion and none of the exclusion criteria will be randomized prior to surgery in a
      1:1 ratio to receive either Toca 511 and Toca FC (Experimental arm, Arm T) or control
      treatment with one option of standard of care (Arm SOC). Due to the prognostic influence of
      molecular subgroups such as isocitrate dehydrogenase mutation, the trial will be stratified
      based on this determination from the primary pathology or subsequent biopsy known locally or
      otherwise determined centrally. A second stratification factor is based on the patient's
      Karnofsky Performance Score (KPS) (70-80 vs 90-100). Further, to account for potential
      differences in treatment choices for the control arm in regions, the trial will be
      stratified by geographical region during the randomization process. The study will be
      conducted in 2 parts; enrollment in the phase 3 will begin after phase 2 results are
      available.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>No masking</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare overall survival between two arms (requires 116 events)</measure>
    <time_frame>21 months from first patient randomized</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">187</enrollment>
  <condition>Glioblastoma Multiforme</condition>
  <condition>Anaplastic Astrocytoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Toca 511/Toca FC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Resection followed by administration of up to 4 mL Toca 511 (vocimagene amiretrorepvec). Toca 511 is administered by injection into the wall of the subject's tumor resection cavity on Day 1 (up to 40 injections of 0.1 mL)
Toca FC is an extended-release formulation of flucytosine. Toca FC will be administered at 220 mg/kg/day orally for 7-day courses beginning at least 6 weeks after resection and repeated approximately every 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lomustine, temozolomide, or bevacizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Investigator selects one of the following:
Bevacizumab: Beginning 6 weeks after tumor resection, bevacizumab will be administered by IV infusion at 10 mg/kg and repeated every 2 weeks. Refer to the prescribing information and to institutional guidelines for details on the administration procedure.
Lomustine: Beginning 6 weeks after tumor resection, lomustine will be administered as a single oral dose of 110 mg/m2 and repeated every 6 weeks. Refer to the prescribing information and to institutional guidelines for details regarding the administration procedure.
Temozolomide: Beginning 6 weeks after tumor resection, temozolomide will be administered per 1 of 2 options:
at a dose of 50 mg/m2 PO once daily continuously, or
at an initial dose of 150 mg/m2 IV or PO once daily for 5 consecutive days per 28-day treatment cycle that may be raised to 200 mg/ m2 once daily for 5 consecutive days in the following 28-day treatment cycles</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Toca 511</intervention_name>
    <description>Toca 511 consists of a purified retroviral replicating vector encoding a modified yeast cytosine deaminase (CD) gene. The CD gene converts the antifungal 5-flurocytosine (5FC) to the anticancer drug 5-FU in cells that have been infected by the Toca 511 vector.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Toca 511/Toca FC</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>vocimagene amiretrorepvec</other_name>
    <other_name>RRV</other_name>
    <other_name>retroviral replicating viral</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Toca FC</intervention_name>
    <description>Toca FC is an extended-release formulation of flucytosine. Toca FC is supplied as 500 mg white, oblong tablets with &quot;TOCA FC&quot; embossed on one side and &quot;500&quot; embossed on the other side</description>
    <arm_group_label>Toca 511/Toca FC</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>flucytosine</other_name>
    <other_name>5-FC</other_name>
    <other_name>5-fluorocytosine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lomustine</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Lomustine, temozolomide, or bevacizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CCNU</other_name>
    <other_name>CeeNU</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Temozolomide</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Lomustine, temozolomide, or bevacizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Temodar</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bevacizumab</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Lomustine, temozolomide, or bevacizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Avastin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Subject has given written informed consent

          2. Subject is between 18 years old and 75 years old, inclusive

          3. Subjects must have histologically proven GBM or AA in first or second recurrence
             (including this recurrence) or progression following initial definitive multimodal
             therapy with surgery, temozolomide (unless MGMT promoter unmethylated) and radiation
             (confirmed by diagnostic biopsy with local pathology review or contrast enhanced
             MRI). If first recurrence of GBM is documented by MRI, an interval of at least 12
             weeks after the end of prior radiation therapy is required unless there is either: i)
             histopathologic confirmation of recurrent tumor, or ii) new enhancement on MRI
             outside of the radiotherapy treatment field

          4. Subjects must have measurable disease preoperatively, defined as at least 1 contrast
             enhancing lesion, measuring at least 1 cm in 2 planes (axial, coronal, or sagittal)

          5. Subjects must be at least 4 weeks post last dose of temozolomide

          6. Prior gamma knife, stereotactic radiosurgery, or other focal high-dose radiotherapy
             is allowed but the subject must have either histopathologic confirmation of recurrent
             tumor, or new enhancement on MRI outside of the radiotherapy treatment field

          7. Based on the pre operative evaluation by neurosurgeon, the subject is a candidate for
             ≥ 80% resection of enhancing region

          8. IDH mutation status of the primary tumor must be available or tumor samples must be
             available for pre randomization testing

          9. Laboratory values adequate for patient to undergo surgery, including:

               -  Platelet count ≥ 60,000/mm3

               -  Hgb ≥ 10 g/dL

               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1,500/mm3

               -  Absolute lymphocyte count (ALC) ≥ 500/mm3

               -  Adequate liver function, including:

                    -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN (unless has Gilbert's syndrome)

                    -  ALT ≤ 2.5 x ULN f. Estimated glomerular filtration rate of at least 50
                       mL/min by the Cockcroft Gault formula below:

         10. Women of childbearing potential (≥12 months of non-therapy-induced amenorrhea or
             surgically sterile) must have had a negative serum pregnancy test within the past 21
             days and must use a birth control method in addition to barrier methods (condoms).

         11. Subject or subject's partner is willing to use condoms for 12 months after receiving
             Toca 511 or until there is no evidence of the virus in his/her blood, whichever is
             longer.

         12. The subject has a KPS ≥ 70

         13. The subject is willing and able to abide by the protocol

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. History of more than 2 prior recurrences (including this recurrence) of GBM or AA

          2. History of other malignancy, unless the patient has been disease free for at least 5
             years. Adequately treated basal cell carcinoma or squamous cell skin cancer is
             acceptable regardless of time, as well as localized prostate carcinoma or cervical
             carcinoma in situ after curative treatment

          3. Histological confirmed oligodendroglioma or mixed glioma

          4. Known 1p/19q co deletion

          5. A contrast enhancing brain tumor that is any of the following:

               -  Multi focal (defined as 2 separate areas of contrast enhancement measuring at
                  least 1 cm in 2 planes that are not contiguous on either fluid attenuated
                  inversion recovery (FLAIR) or T2 sequences);

               -  Associated with either diffuse subependymal or leptomeningeal dissemination; or
                  &gt; 5 cm in any dimension

          6. The subject has or had any active infection requiring antibiotic, antifungal or
             antiviral therapy within the past 4 weeks

          7. The subject has any bleeding diathesis, or must take anticoagulants, or antiplatelet
             agents, including nonsteroidal anti inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), at the time of the
             scheduled resection that cannot be stopped for surgery

          8. The subject is HIV positive

          9. The subject has a history of allergy or intolerance to flucytosine

         10. The subject has a gastrointestinal disease that would prevent him or her from being
             able to swallow or absorb flucytosine

         11. The subject received cytotoxic chemotherapy within the past 4 weeks (6 weeks for
             nitrosoureas) of the planned surgery date

         12. The subject received any investigational treatment within the past 30 days or prior
             immunotherapy or antibody therapy within the past 45 days.

         13. The subject is breast feeding

         14. The subject intends to undergo treatment with the Gliadel® wafer at the time of this
             surgery or has received the Gliadel® wafer &lt; 30 days from W1D1 (surgery)

         15. The subject has received bevacizumab for their disease unless in the context of
             primary therapy for newly diagnosed glioma

         16. For subjects planned to potentially receive bevacizumab, they have no evidence of
             uncontrolled hypertension (defined as a blood pressure of ≥ 150 mm Hg systolic and/or
             ≥ 100 mm Hg diastolic on medication) or active GI perforation

         17. The subject has received systemic dexamethasone continuously at a dose &gt; 8 mg/day for
             8 weeks prior to the date of the screening assessment

         18. Severe pulmonary, cardiac or other systemic disease, specifically:

               -  New York Heart Association &gt; Grade 2 congestive heart failure within 6 months
                  prior to study entry, unless asymptomatic and well controlled with medication

               -  Uncontrolled or significant cardiovascular disease, clinically significant
                  ventricular arrhythmia (such as ventricular tachycardia, ventricular
                  fibrillation, or Torsades des pointes), clinically significant pulmonary disease
                  (such as ≥ Grade 2 dyspnea, according to CTCAE 4.03)

               -  Subjects who have any other disease, either metabolic or psychological, which as
                  per Investigator assessment may affect the subject's compliance or place the
                  subject at higher risk of potential treatment complications
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Timothy Cloughesy, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, Los Angeles</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Barrow Neurological Institute at Dignity Health St. Joseph's Hospiutal and Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Phoenix,</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85013</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, Irvine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Irvine</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92868</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>La Jolla</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92093</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, Los Angeles</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90095</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Joseph Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orange</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92868</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California San Francisco, Department of Neurological Surgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94143</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stanford</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94305</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Colorado Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80045</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Colorado Neurological Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Englewood</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80113</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Associated Neurologists of Southern Connecticut</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fairfield</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06824</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale University/Yale Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06520</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Florida McKnight Brain Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32611</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Miami</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33136</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Moffitt Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NorthShore University Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Evanston</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66160</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21287</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Michigan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Henry Ford Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Abbott Northwestern Hospital / Allina Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55407</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>HCA Midwest Division</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64132</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University St. Louis</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Nebraska Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Omaha</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68198</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>JFK Medical Center Neuroscience Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edison</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>08820</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>John Theurer Cancer Center at Hackensack University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hackensack</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07601</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Overlook Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Summit</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07901</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>North Shore University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lake Success</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11042</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NYU Langone Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10016</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Weill Cornell Medical College</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10021</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Rochester Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14642</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stony Brook University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stony Brook</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11794</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sanford Research - Fargo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fargo</city>
        <state>North Dakota</state>
        <zip>58122</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cincinnati's Children's Hospital Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinnati</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>45229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospitals - Case Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cleveland Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ohio State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Thomas Jefferson University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19101</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical University of South Carolina</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29425</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sanford Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sioux Falls</city>
        <state>South Dakota</state>
        <zip>57104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baylor University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75246</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Houston Methodist Hospital Outpatient Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Virginia Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlottesville</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22908</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Inova Dwight and Martha Schar Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fairfax</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22031</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sentara Neurosurgery Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Norfolk</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23507</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>West Virginia University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Morgantown</city>
        <state>West Virginia</state>
        <zip>26506</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Wisconsin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madison</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53792</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alberta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edmonton</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T6G 2B7</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of British Columbia / Vancouver General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V5Z 1M9</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CancerCare Manitoba</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winnipeg</city>
        <state>Manitoba</state>
        <zip>R3E 0V9</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>London Regional Cancer Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>N6A 5W9</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ottawa Hospital Regional Cancer Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ottawa</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>K1H 8L6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sunnybrook Hospital / Sunnybrook Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M4N 3M5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Toronto Western Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5T 2S8</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Montreal Neurological Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montreal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H3A2B4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jewish General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montreal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H3T 1E2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sherbrooke hospital university centre (CHUS)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sherbrooke</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>J1H 5N4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rambam Health Care</name>
      <address>
        <city>Haifa</city>
        <zip>3109601</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hadassah Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jerusalem</city>
        <zip>91120</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tel-Aviv</city>
        <zip>6423906</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Severance Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>03722</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Samsung Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>06351</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seoul St. Mary's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>06591,</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seoul National University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seul</city>
        <zip>03080</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Israel</country>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ballman KV, Buckner JC, Brown PD, Giannini C, Flynn PJ, LaPlant BR, Jaeckle KA. The relationship between six-month progression-free survival and 12-month overall survival end points for phase II trials in patients with glioblastoma multiforme. Neuro Oncol. 2007 Jan;9(1):29-38. Epub 2006 Nov 15.</citation>
    <PMID>17108063</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Batchelor TT, Mulholland P, Neyns B, Nabors LB, Campone M, Wick A, Mason W, Mikkelsen T, Phuphanich S, Ashby LS, Degroot J, Gattamaneni R, Cher L, Rosenthal M, Payer F, Jürgensmeier JM, Jain RK, Sorensen AG, Xu J, Liu Q, van den Bent M. Phase III randomized trial comparing the efficacy of cediranib as monotherapy, and in combination with lomustine, versus lomustine alone in patients with recurrent glioblastoma. J Clin Oncol. 2013 Sep 10;31(26):3212-8. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2012.47.2464. Epub 2013 Aug 12.</citation>
    <PMID>23940216</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Braun CJ, Boztug K, Paruzynski A, Witzel M, Schwarzer A, Rothe M, Modlich U, Beier R, Göhring G, Steinemann D, Fronza R, Ball CR, Haemmerle R, Naundorf S, Kühlcke K, Rose M, Fraser C, Mathias L, Ferrari R, Abboud MR, Al-Herz W, Kondratenko I, Maródi L, Glimm H, Schlegelberger B, Schambach A, Albert MH, Schmidt M, von Kalle C, Klein C. Gene therapy for Wiskott-Aldrich syndrome--long-term efficacy and genotoxicity. Sci Transl Med. 2014 Mar 12;6(227):227ra33. doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.3007280.</citation>
    <PMID>24622513</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Central Brain Tumor Registry of the United States. 2014 CBTRUS Fact Sheet. Accessed March 30, 2015 at http://www.cbtrus.org/factsheet/factsheet.html.Chamberlain, M. Treatment options for glioblastoma. Neurosurg Focus 20 (4):E19, 2006.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cornetta K, Moen RC, Culver K, Morgan RA, McLachlin JR, Sturm S, Selegue J, London W, Blaese RM, Anderson WF. Amphotropic murine leukemia retrovirus is not an acute pathogen for primates. Hum Gene Ther. 1990 Spring;1(1):15-30.</citation>
    <PMID>1964393</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gil-Gil MJ, Mesia C, Rey M, Bruna J. Bevacizumab for the treatment of glioblastoma. Clin Med Insights Oncol. 2013 Jun 6;7:123-35. doi: 10.4137/CMO.S8503.</citation>
    <PMID>23843722</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hacein-Bey-Abina S, Von Kalle C, Schmidt M, McCormack MP, Wulffraat N, Leboulch P, Lim A, Osborne CS, Pawliuk R, Morillon E, Sorensen R, Forster A, Fraser P, Cohen JI, de Saint Basile G, Alexander I, Wintergerst U, Frebourg T, Aurias A, Stoppa-Lyonnet D, Romana S, Radford-Weiss I, Gross F, Valensi F, Delabesse E, Macintyre E, Sigaux F, Soulier J, Leiva LE, Wissler M, Prinz C, Rabbitts TH, Le Deist F, Fischer A, Cavazzana-Calvo M. LMO2-associated clonal T cell proliferation in two patients after gene therapy for SCID-X1. Science. 2003 Oct 17;302(5644):415-9. Erratum in: Science. 2003 Oct 24;302(5645):568.</citation>
    <PMID>14564000</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hegi ME, Diserens AC, Gorlia T, Hamou MF, de Tribolet N, Weller M, Kros JM, Hainfellner JA, Mason W, Mariani L, Bromberg JE, Hau P, Mirimanoff RO, Cairncross JG, Janzer RC, Stupp R. MGMT gene silencing and benefit from temozolomide in glioblastoma. N Engl J Med. 2005 Mar 10;352(10):997-1003.</citation>
    <PMID>15758010</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hess KR, Wong ET, Jaeckle KA, Kyritsis AP, Levin VA, Prados MD, Yung WK. Response and progression in recurrent malignant glioma. Neuro Oncol. 1999 Oct;1(4):282-8.</citation>
    <PMID>11550320</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Huang RY, Neagu MR, Reardon DA, Wen PY. Pitfalls in the neuroimaging of glioblastoma in the era of antiangiogenic and immuno/targeted therapy - detecting illusive disease, defining response. Front Neurol. 2015 Feb 23;6:33. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2015.00033. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25755649</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kaufmann JK, Chiocca EA. Glioma virus therapies between bench and bedside. Neuro Oncol. 2014 Mar;16(3):334-51. doi: 10.1093/neuonc/not310. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24470549</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Logg CR, Logg A, Tai CK, Cannon PM, Kasahara N. Genomic stability of murine leukemia viruses containing insertions at the Env-3' untranslated region boundary. J Virol. 2001 Aug;75(15):6989-98.</citation>
    <PMID>11435579</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Murphy AM, Rabkin SD. Current status of gene therapy for brain tumors. Transl Res. 2013 Apr;161(4):339-54. doi: 10.1016/j.trsl.2012.11.003.</citation>
    <PMID>23246627</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ostertag D, Amundson KK, Lopez Espinoza F, Martin B, Buckley T, Galvão da Silva AP, Lin AH, Valenta DT, Perez OD, Ibañez CE, Chen CI, Pettersson PL, Burnett R, Daublebsky V, Hlavaty J, Gunzburg W, Kasahara N, Gruber HE, Jolly DJ, Robbins JM. Brain tumor eradication and prolonged survival from intratumoral conversion of 5-fluorocytosine to 5-fluorouracil using a nonlytic retroviral replicating vector. Neuro Oncol. 2012 Feb;14(2):145-59. doi: 10.1093/neuonc/nor199. Epub 2011 Nov 9.</citation>
    <PMID>22070930</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Perez OD, Logg CR, Hiraoka K, Diago O, Burnett R, Inagaki A, Jolson D, Amundson K, Buckley T, Lohse D, Lin A, Burrascano C, Ibanez C, Kasahara N, Gruber HE, Jolly DJ. Design and selection of Toca 511 for clinical use: modified retroviral replicating vector with improved stability and gene expression. Mol Ther. 2012 Sep;20(9):1689-98. doi: 10.1038/mt.2012.83. Erratum in: Mol Ther. 2013 Feb;21(2):494.</citation>
    <PMID>22547150</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rainov NG. A phase III clinical evaluation of herpes simplex virus type 1 thymidine kinase and ganciclovir gene therapy as an adjuvant to surgical resection and radiation in adults with previously untreated glioblastoma multiforme. Hum Gene Ther. 2000 Nov 20;11(17):2389-401.</citation>
    <PMID>11096443</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rans TS, England R. The evolution of gene therapy in X-linked severe combined immunodeficiency. Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2009 May;102(5):357-62; quiz 363-5, 402. doi: 10.1016/S1081-1206(10)60504-2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19492655</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Le Rhun E, Taillibert S, Chamberlain MC. The future of high-grade glioma: Where we are and where are we going. Surg Neurol Int. 2015 Feb 13;6(Suppl 1):S9-S44. doi: 10.4103/2152-7806.151331. Erratum in: Surg Neurol Int. 2015 Mar 5;6:37. Rhun, Emilie Le [corrected to Le Rhun, Emilie].</citation>
    <PMID>25722939</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shibahara I, Sonoda Y, Shoji T, Kanamori M, Saito R, Inoue T, Kawaguchi T, Yamashita Y, Watanabe T, Kumabe T, Watanabe M, Suzuki H, Tominaga T. Malignant clinical features of anaplastic gliomas without IDH mutation. Neuro Oncol. 2015 Jan;17(1):136-44. doi: 10.1093/neuonc/nou112.</citation>
    <PMID>24958096</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stein S, Ott MG, Schultze-Strasser S, Jauch A, Burwinkel B, Kinner A, Schmidt M, Krämer A, Schwäble J, Glimm H, Koehl U, Preiss C, Ball C, Martin H, Göhring G, Schwarzwaelder K, Hofmann WK, Karakaya K, Tchatchou S, Yang R, Reinecke P, Kühlcke K, Schlegelberger B, Thrasher AJ, Hoelzer D, Seger R, von Kalle C, Grez M. Genomic instability and myelodysplasia with monosomy 7 consequent to EVI1 activation after gene therapy for chronic granulomatous disease. Nat Med. 2010 Feb;16(2):198-204. doi: 10.1038/nm.2088.</citation>
    <PMID>20098431</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Taal W, Oosterkamp HM, Walenkamp AM, Dubbink HJ, Beerepoot LV, Hanse MC, Buter J, Honkoop AH, Boerman D, de Vos FY, Dinjens WN, Enting RH, Taphoorn MJ, van den Berkmortel FW, Jansen RL, Brandsma D, Bromberg JE, van Heuvel I, Vernhout RM, van der Holt B, van den Bent MJ. Single-agent bevacizumab or lomustine versus a combination of bevacizumab plus lomustine in patients with recurrent glioblastoma (BELOB trial): a randomised controlled phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2014 Aug;15(9):943-53. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(14)70314-6.</citation>
    <PMID>25035291</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vermes A, Guchelaar HJ, Dankert J. Flucytosine: a review of its pharmacology, clinical indications, pharmacokinetics, toxicity and drug interactions. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2000 Aug;46(2):171-9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10933638</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wen PY, Kesari S. Malignant gliomas in adults. N Engl J Med. 2008 Jul 31;359(5):492-507. doi: 10.1056/NEJMra0708126. Review. Erratum in: N Engl J Med. 2008 Aug 21;359(8):877.</citation>
    <PMID>18669428</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wick W, Hartmann C, Engel C, Stoffels M, Felsberg J, Stockhammer F, Sabel MC, Koeppen S, Ketter R, Meyermann R, Rapp M, Meisner C, Kortmann RD, Pietsch T, Wiestler OD, Ernemann U, Bamberg M, Reifenberger G, von Deimling A, Weller M. NOA-04 randomized phase III trial of sequential radiochemotherapy of anaplastic glioma with procarbazine, lomustine, and vincristine or temozolomide. J Clin Oncol. 2009 Dec 10;27(35):5874-80. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2009.23.6497. Epub 2009 Nov 9. Erratum in: J Clin Oncol. 2010 Feb 1;28(4):708.</citation>
    <PMID>19901110</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wick W, Puduvalli VK, Chamberlain MC, van den Bent MJ, Carpentier AF, Cher LM, Mason W, Weller M, Hong S, Musib L, Liepa AM, Thornton DE, Fine HA. Phase III study of enzastaurin compared with lomustine in the treatment of recurrent intracranial glioblastoma. J Clin Oncol. 2010 Mar 1;28(7):1168-74. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2009.23.2595. Epub 2010 Feb 1.</citation>
    <PMID>20124186</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wogan GN. Tumors of the mouse hematopoietic system: their diagnosis and interpretation in safety evaluation tests. Report of a study group. Crit Rev Toxicol. 1984;13(2):161-81. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>6380960</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 8, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 3, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Recurrence</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Astrocytoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lomustine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Flucytosine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
