<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02546804</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Periodontal Disease is a ubiquitous in nature affecting about 80% population of India. The Periodontal Disease is a multifactorial but the dental plaque is considered as main etiological agent.The dental plaque, a adhesive bacterial coating accumulate around and in between teeth, if not removed by effective daily brushing and flossing, plaque can cause Gum infection and tooth loss. Though, many scientific periodontal procedures are available to get the treatment but because of lack of man power and poor socioeconomic condition it is not possible for every group of population in our India.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Trial to Study the Effects of Two Home Made Mouthwashes in Patients With Gum Diseases</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The need exist for continued research to find the use of home made mouthwashes in preventing periodontal diseases. Although, Chlorhexidine mouthwash is regarded as Gold standard mouthwash as antiplaque but have some limitations like cost factor and side effects like staining of teeth, loss of taste, oral mucosal ulcerations,paresthesia and may enhanced supragingival calculus formation. Use of various indigenous products and home made preparations are easily available and are being used since ancient time in India and still in practice in various parts of India especially rural and remote areas. At the same time the use of potassium permanganate is still in practice in various parts of India and also it was in practice before the availability of Chlorhexidine, povidone iodine and other antiseptic solutions, as they are used since about 30 years only. Use of hot salt water rinsing is in practice especially to reduce the symptoms of various throat infections such as pharyngitis, tonsillitis and also to improve oral hygiene.It is also being used in oral surgery and their effects are also mention in literature. Hence, the aim of this study is to assess and compare the efficacy of home made remedies like hot salt water and potassium permanganate as a mouthwash in reducing Plaque accumulation and improving Gingival conditions with Gold standard Chlorhexidine mouthwash if found effective may be used as affordable mouthwash for the benefit of population of India.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gingivitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorhexidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorhexidine gluconate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject of Chronic Generalized Gingivitis and Mild Generalized Periodontitis. Not undergone any major periodontal treatment earlier in last 06 months . Otherwise Clinically Healthy Patient. Subjects with significant systemic diseases (e.g. Diabetes Mellitus, Cancer or Coronary heart disease etc.). Pregnant or lactating women. Smoker. Patients on antiinflammatory drugs or antibiotics Patients allergic to any material used for the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>