<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="118445">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01561027</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CNV1014802/201</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01561027</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Crossover Study of CNV1014802 in Subjects With Neuropathic Pain From Lumbosacral Radiculopathy</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Double Blind, Cross-over Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of CNV1014802 in Subjects With Neuropathic Pain From Lumbosacral Radiculopathy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Convergence Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Convergence Pharmaceuticals</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study is a randomized, double blind, cross-over study to evaluate the safety and
      efficacy of CNV1014802 in subjects with neuropathic pain from lumbosacral radiculopathy.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study consists of two treatment periods of 22 days with randomized CNV1014802 350mg or
      placebo administered twice daily. In addition, single blind placebo will be administered
      during a two week run-in, a two week wash-out period between the two treatment periods, and
      a one week run-out phase.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in average daily neuropathic pain score from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Three weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in average daily neuropathic pain score from baseline (average days 10-14) to week 3 based on the 11 point Pain Intensity Numerical Rating Scale (PI-NRS) (0=no pain, 10=maximum pain imaginable).
Subjects should specifically rate the pain intensity for the neuropathic pain associated with lumbosacral radiculopathy and not pain from other concomitant causes</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Numerical pain rating scale</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in average daily pain score from baseline (average days 10-14) to week 1 and week 2 of treatment and 1 week following the end of randomized treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Responder rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients who have &gt;= 30% and &gt;=50% reduction in average daily pain score relative to baseline during weeks 1, 2 and 3 of treatment and 1 week following the end of randomized treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Galer neuropathic pain scale</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Galer Neuropathic Pain Scale from baseline to week 3 of treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oswestry Disability Index</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in average disability score from baseline to week 1, week 2 and week 3 of treatment based on Oswestry Disability Index</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PGIC</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients who have &quot;improved&quot;, &quot;much improved&quot; or &quot;very much improved&quot; relative to baseline on the Patient Global Impression of Change (PGIC) on week 3 of treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CGIC</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients who have &quot;improved&quot;, &quot;much improved&quot; or &quot;very much improved&quot; relative to baseline on the Clinical Global Impression of Change (CGIC) on week 3 of treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">82</enrollment>
  <condition>Lumbosacral Radiculopathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CNV1014802</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CNV1014802</intervention_name>
    <description>CNV1014802 350mg bid for 21 days Matching placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>CNV1014802</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Male or female aged between 18 and 65 years, with a diagnosis of neuropathic pain due
             to lumbosacral radiculopathy (LSR).

          -  Female subjects must be of non-child bearing potential or agree to use an approved
             form of contraception

          -  Body weight &lt; 50 kg for men and &lt; 45 kg for women.

          -  Capable of giving written informed consent.

          -  Approved concomitant medications must have been stable for at least 4 weeks prior to
             day 1.

          -  Average baseline daily pain score for neuropathic pain due to LSR on the 11-point
             numerical rating scale of 4 or greater.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Subjects who are unable to reliably delineate or assess their own pain by anatomical
             location/distribution.

          -  Subjects with lumbar canal stenosis in which the pain in the lower limbs occur solely
             on walking and not at rest.

          -  Subjects with causes for their neuropathic pain other than LSR.

          -  Subjects who have received nerve blocks and/or steroid injections for neuropathic
             pain within 4 weeks prior to day 1.

          -  Subjects who are indicated for surgical treatment of lumbosacral radiculopathy.

          -  A positive pre-study drug screen.

          -  A positive history of HIV.

          -  A positive pre-study Hepatitis B surface antigen or positive Hepatitis C antibody
             result within 3 months of screening.

          -  History of any liver disease within the last 6 months, with the exception of known
             Gilbert's disease.

          -  History of excessive regular alcohol consumption within 6 months of the study.

          -  Subjects with a history or risk of seizures or a history of epilepsy, head injury or
             related neurological disorders

          -  Subjects with a history of uncontrolled or poorly controlled hypertension, with
             systolic BP frequently exceeding 160mmHg and/or diastolic BP frequently exceeding
             100mmHg, or subjects who have BP greater than or equal to 160mmHg systolic and/or
             greater than or equal to 100mmHg diastolic at screening after repeated measurements

          -  History or presence of significant cardiovascular, gastro-intestinal, or renal
             disease or other condition known to interfere with the absorption, distribution,
             metabolism, or excretion of drugs.

          -  Subjects with conditions known to affect cardiac conduction or a personal or familial
             history of Brugada syndrome

          -  Pregnant females or lactating females.

          -  History or presence of any clinically significant abnormality in vital signs / ECG /
             laboratory tests or have any medical or psychiatric condition, which, in the opinion
             of the Investigator may interfere with the study procedures or compromise subject
             safety.

          -  History of suicidal ideation and/or suicide attempts or clinical evidence of recent
             major depression.

          -  Subjects who are unable to maintain their same medications for the treatment of
             neuropathic pain at a stable dose during the study.

          -  Unable to refrain from excessive use of sedatives.

          -  Unable to comply with the prohibited concomitant medication restrictions as detailed
             in the protocol. This includes but is not limited to sodium channel blockers or drugs
             that adversely interact with a monoamine oxidase-B inhibitor: MAOI's,
             antidepressants, opioids and sympathomimetic agents.

          -  Unable to stop and remain abstained from non-pharmacological treatments for their
             neuropathic pain during the study.

          -  History of hypersensitivity to CNV1014802.

          -  The subject has participated in a clinical trial and has received an investigational
             product within 5 half-lives or twice the duration of the biological effect of the
             investigational product (whichever is longer) prior to the start of this study.

          -  Exposure to more than four new chemical entities within 12 months prior to the first
             dosing day.

          -  Where participation in the study would result in donation of blood or blood products
             in excess of 500 mL within a 56 day period.

          -  Subject is mentally or legally incapacitated.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bjorn Bragee, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Bragee Medect AB, Stockholm, Sweden</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>August 2, 2012</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 19, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Radiculopathy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
