<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02998645</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a two-part study, interventional Phase II, single-arm, multicenter, open-label study to investigate the efficacy and safety of a combination regimen of eltrombopag and cyclosporine in patients with severe aplastic anemia (SAA) as first line therapy and an extension with up to 60-months follow-up. All patients will receive eltrombopag for 6 months with cyclosporine. Patients who respond (who had overall hematologic response by 6 months) will continue tapering down cyclosporine for up to 30 months and will be followed up for a post-treatment follow-up up to 60 months by regular clinic visits. Patients who do not have an overall hematologic response (non-responders) by the end of 6 month time point will be discontinued from the treatment and will be followed up for non-responder post-treatment follow-up up to 60 months The usage of eltrombopag and cyclosporine combines two therapies with different modes of action. Cyclosporine acts as an immunosuppressant and eltrombopag acts as a stimulator of bone marrow progenitor cells. Given that SAA is currently viewed as having an autoimmune pathogenesis resulting in bone marrow progenitor cell destruction, the combination of eltrombopag and cyclosporine is attractive. Preliminary experience with their combined use appears favorable, with no untoward toxicity observed to date.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Eltrombopag Combined With Cyclosporine as First Line Therapy in Patients With Severe Acquired Aplastic Anemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Aplastic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patient has signed the Informed Consent (ICF) prior to any screening procedures being performed. 2. Patient is male/female ≥6 years old at the time of informed consent and able to swallow a tablet. 3. Patient has SAA characterized by: 1. Bone marrow cellularity &lt;30% (excluding lymphocytes) and 2. At least two of the following (peripheral blood): Absolute neutrophil count &lt;500/ µL Platelet count &lt;20,000/ µL Absolute reticulocyte count &lt;60,000/ µL 4. Normal ECG defined as the following as determined via the mean of a triplicate ECG Resting heart rate 6&lt;12 years: 60130 bpm 12&lt;18 years: 60120 bpm ≥18 years: 5090 bpm QTcF at screening &lt;450 msec (male patients), 460 msec (female patients) 1. Diagnosis of Fanconi anemia. 2. Evidence of a clonal hematologic bone marrow disorder on cytogenetics. Patients with very severe neutropenia (ANC &lt; 200 /μL) will not be excluded initially if cytogenetics are not available or pending. If a clonal disorder is identified, the patient will be excluded. 3. Prior immunosuppressive therapy with cyclosporine, alemtuzumab, rabbit or horse ATG and thrombopoietin receptor (TPOR) agonists. 4. Hypersensitivity to eltrombopag or its components. 5. AST or ALT &gt;3 x ULN. 6. Creatinine, total bilirubin, and alkaline phosphatase &gt;3 x ULN . 7. Patient with liver cirrhosis. 8. Infection not adequately controlled with appropriate therapy. 9. Moribund status or concurrent hepatic, renal, cardiac, neurologic, pulmonary, infectious, or metabolic disease of such severity that it would preclude the patient's ability to consent, be compliant with study procedures, tolerate protocol therapy, or that death within 30 days is likely. 10. Patients with cancer who are not considered cure, are on active chemotherapeutic treatment or who take drugs with hematological effects. 11. Administration of an investigational drug within 30 days or 5 halflives, whichever is longer, preceding the first dose of study treatment. 12. Pregnancy statements and contraception requirements: Pregnancy or nursing (lactating) women Women of childbearing potential, defined as all women physiologically capable of becoming pregnant (or female partners of male patients), unless they are using highly effective methods of contraception during dosing and for 3 months after stopping medication. 13. Not able to understand the investigation nature of the study or to give informed consent. 14. Clinically significant ECG abnormality including cardiac arrhythmias (e. g. ventricular tachycardia) complete left bundle branch block, high grade atrioventricular block, or inability to determine the QTcF interval on the ECG. 15. Presence of cardiac disease, or family history of idiopathic sudden death or congenital long QT syndrome. 16. Risk factors for Torsades de Pointe including uncorrected hypokalemia or hypomagnesemia, or use of concomitant medication(s) with a known risk to prolong the QT interval that cannot be discontinued.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>severe acquired aplastic anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>SAA</keyword>
	<keyword>first line</keyword>
	<keyword>eltrombopag</keyword>
	<keyword>cyclosporine</keyword>
	<keyword>h-ATG</keyword>
	<keyword>severe aplastic anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>aplastic anemia</keyword>
</DOC>