<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02998502</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will test the efficiency of the Freespira Breathing System in youth.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Use of a FDA Cleared, Drug-free, Breathing System for Anxiety and Panic Disorders in Children and Teens</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Freespira Breathing System (FBS; www.freespira.com) developed by Palo Alto Health Sciences, Inc, is a portable home device , and has been employed in breathing biofeedback in adults with panic disorder (PD). The FBS has now received FDA clearance for the treatment of PD adults and is currently commercially available and more than 150 therapist have provided the service nationally. However, FBS has not yet been tested for efficacy in a pediatric populations. Due to its portability, FBS may pose an advantage for use in younger age groups, compared to multiple therapy sessions required for cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) or lower acceptability for long-term medication use for adolescent PD. In this pilot intervention study, the efficacy of the FBS system in youth will be tested. In children adolescents, PD itself is less common than in adults, but when present, PD is commonly associated with and/or preceded by other anxiety conditions, including generalized anxiety disorder (GAD), social phobia (SoP) and separation anxiety (SAD). Thus, in children and adolescents, the breathing biofeedback intervention for panic, should include other anxiety disorders.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Panic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must meet at least 1 of the 3 following conditions: 1. SCARED score ≥ 25 + presence of OCD symptoms with &gt; 1 h of clinical interference; or 2. SCARED score ≥ 25 + prior diagnosis of Panic Disorder; or 3. SCARED score ≥ 25 + prior clinical diagnosis of 2 of the following 3 anxiety disorders: GAD, SoP, SAD Participants must be 917 years of age Participants must receive a Clinician's Global Impression (CGI) score of ≥ 4, denoting at least moderate anxiety illness. If on psychotropic medication(s), participant must be on a stable dose for a minimum of three months prior to study enrollment Anxiety has occurred exclusively during a major depressive episode, dementia, intellectual disability, or brain disease Currently enrolled in another device or drug study or less than 30 days has elapsed since participation in such a study Currently undergoing breathing biofeedback elsewhere Demonstrate evidence of severe suicidal ideation or psychosis There is an active condition of asthma</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>9 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obsessive Compulsive Disorder (OCD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>Pediatrics</keyword>
</DOC>