<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02998385</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A phase III, multicenter, randomized, open-label, french study comparing: - Arm A : Radiotherapy alone (66 to 70 Gy; 5 fractions/week; 1fraction/day; 2 Gy/fraction) - Arm B: Radiotherapy (66 to 70 Gy; 5 fractions/week; 1fraction/day; 2 Gy/fraction) + concomitant cisplatin 100 mg/m2 IV on day 1 - J22 - 43 (3 cycles)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chemo-radiotherapy Versus Radiotherapy in the Treatment of Salivary Glands and Nasal Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Carcinomas of the sinuses and the salivary glands are rare. They are heterogeneous in terms of anatomical sites and histology subtypes. For this reason and in the absence of prospective study, their treatment is still largely extrapolated from data of frequent carcinomas of the upper digestive tract. These tumors are most often diagnosed lately. Their treatment is based on a multimodal management of care, with a central place for the surgery and radiotherapy (Proof level Grade C). Despite the advances in surgical techniques, and the addition of radiation therapy, the 5-year overall survival probability does not exceed 65% mainly due to a loco regional development. In this context, a chemotherapy administered concomitantly to radiotherapy, could increase the efficacy of the locoregional treatment by a radiosensibilization process and regardless of the histology. This point is regularly discussed in multidisciplinary concertation meeting, including bi-monthly national REFCOR meeting (network of French Expertise on rare Cancers of the head and neck). At present, the lack of data brings even to discuss the addition of cisplatin to exclusive irradiation of unresectable or not operable tumors. No randomized study has been published in this context. The first comparative prospective study addressing the addition of weekly cisplatin to the adjuvant irradiation of salivary, is a phase II randomized study (Radiation Therapy Oncology Group - RTOG 1008) currently enrolling patients in the United States of America. The Sponsor propose to conduct a phase III randomized study evaluating the impact of the addition of cisplatin to a treatment by radiotherapy in adjuvant setting (≥ 65 Gy) in case of a high risk of recurrence: case of radioresistant histologies (e.g. cystic fibrosis adenoids carcinomas), or case of unfavourable histo-prognostic criteria (incomplete resection, presence of emboli, etc.) in this population.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Resected tumors of the sinus or the salivary glands T34, N13 or T12 N0, with overgrown banks or positive margins (&lt; 5 mm) or Unresectable or not operable tumors of salivary glands or sinuses Carcinomas of the major salivary glands (Parotid, submandibular and sublingual glands) and accessories with the following histologies: adenoid cystic Carcinoma, adenocarcinoma without another indication (SAI) of highgrade, mucoepidermoid of intermediate grade or high grade Carcinoma, salivary ductal carcinoma, carcinomas to turn cells (with dedifferencie contingent or Ki 67 &gt; 10%), Sebaceous Carcinoma, large cell carcinoma, small cell carcinomas Mucinous adenocarcinoma, carcinoma on massively invasive Pleomorphic adenoma, oncocytic carcinomas, myoepithelial Carcinoma or Malignant tumors of the sinus with the following histology: adenocarcinomas of the ethmoid (ADE) of bowel and no intestinal type, CF adenoids carcinomas and other carcinomas of salivary origin (COS). Age ≥ 18 years Performance status 0 2 (WHO criteria) For patients ≥ 70 years, the score to the G8 questionnaire must be &gt; 14 with no fall in the previous 12 months or with a geriatric assessment consistent with the administration of chemotherapy Estimated life expectancy greater than or equal to 6 months Neutrophils &gt; 1.5 x 109/l, platelets &gt; 100 x 109/l, hemoglobin ≥ 9.5 g/dl, bilirubin ≤ 3 x upper normal value (ULN), AST/ALT &lt; 5 ULN, PAL &lt; 3 ULN Creatinin Clearance ≥ 60 mL/min Adequate cardiac function according to the investigator, compatible with the administration of cisplatin 100 mg/m² Affiliation to a social insurance or beneficiary of such a regimen Patient having given his written consent signed before any study specific procedure. History of radiation therapy in the ENT area Synchronous metastases Contraindications for administration of cisplatin or carboplatin Allergy to cisplatin and/or its excipients Melanoma, lymphoma, tumors of mesenchymal (of type Sarcoma), epidermoid carcinomas, (SCUNC) neuroendocrine carcinomas and carcinoma undifferentiated (SNUC), nasopharyngeal carcinomas type 1, 2, and 3. Vaccination against yellow fever, recent or planned Administration of phenytoin with prophylactic purpose Other cancer, except for cancer in situ of the cervix, skin Carcinoma (except melanoma) or cancer controlled for more than 5 years Pregnant, breastfeeding or without birth control woman. Woman having the ability to procreate should have (serum or urinary) negative pregnancy test within 14 days prior to study treatment decisionmaking. (Men or women) patients should use a reliable contraceptive method throughout the treatment and at least 6 months after the end of chemotherapy. Persons deprived of liberty under supervision or under curatorship, or unable to adhere to medical followup of the study for geographical, social or psychological reasons.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>salivary glands</keyword>
	<keyword>sinus carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>radiochemotherapy concomitant</keyword>
	<keyword>cisplatin</keyword>
</DOC>