<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02998307</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objectives: The primary objective is to determine the least frequent CPR training interval associated with continued performance of guideline-compliant CPR. The secondary objective is to determine whether certain physical characteristics, such as age, gender, exercise tolerance, height, and weight may be able to identify HCPs at high risk of being unable to perform high-quality CPR. Design: Randomized trial to compare the effect of different training frequencies on long-term CPR performance. Participants and setting: Nurses in all adult departments at Health Sciences North. Subjects will be randomly assigned to a group that undertakes short CPR assessment and training sessions either 1) every month, 2) every 3 months, 3) every 6 months, or 4) every 12 months (control group) over the course of a twelve-month period. Analysis: The proportion of nurses in each group that is able to perform "excellent CPR" at the twelve-month time point will be determined. Excellent CPR is defined as a two-minute CPR session where 90% of compressions are performed with correct depth (50-60 mm), 90% with correct rate (100-120 /min), and 90% with full chest recoil. A subgroup analysis will also be performed where the demographic data of individuals who are unable to perform excellent CPR at the twelve-month time point regardless of intervention group are compared against those who are successful. Conclusion: The results of our study will help determine the longest CPR training interval associated with maintenance of high-quality CPR skills to minimize training sessions required and decrease associated costs. The results will also generate hypotheses for future study about optimizing role assignments and team performance in resuscitation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Optimal Training Frequency for Attainment and Maintenance of High-quality CPR on a High-fidelity Manikin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Practicing nurses from multiple clinical environments (operating room, intensive care unit, emergency room, medical and surgical wards) at Health Sciences North. Refusal to participate</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>