<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01651546</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to create and validate a specific test named Intermittent Catheterization Acceptance Test (I-CAT), assessing "the acceptance" of clean intermittent self catheterization (CISC) in a neurological and no neurological population with indication to self catheterization. CISC avoids urological complications in bladder with chronic and improves quality of life. Despite theses challenges, the learning of CISC can face some physical, cognitive and psychological difficulties. Recently, we have validate a new test for predicting the physical and cognitive abilities to practice CISC named "PP-Test". Meanwhile, psychological factors are not explored in this test. To our knowledge, no study has been conducted in order to demonstrate in a prospective trial, which kind of psychological barriers can exist. Likewise it would be interesting to create a new test assessing the psychological "acceptance" of the patients to CISC before learning (I-CAT). Based on the results of this self-assessment test, the specific nurse could then change her speech by playing down the importance of some fear and anxiety described by the patients. The learning of CISC would be facilitated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intermittent Catheterization Acceptance Test</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The first version of the questionnaire (I-CAT) has already been elaborated from some neuro-urology experts and patients's comments. The final version will be validated after a feasibility study. The psychometric criteria will be validated.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Patient diagnosed with neurological disease (brain, trauma and no trauma spinal injury, cauda equine syndrome) or non neurological disease Patients seen in consultation or in traditional hospital Indication for the realization of selfcatheterization Intermittent must be asked because of a bladdertype retentionist or overactive bladder with an indication of medical (anticholinergics or botulinum toxin intradetrusor injection) or surgical (kind of expansion enterocystoplasty) treatment to prevent bladder emptying without urinary catheterization PPTest score ≥10/15 Age &gt; 18 years Patient with social security Urethral injury preventing the practice of selfcatheterization Indication to installing a suprapubic catheter or probe Patients able to answer to questionnaire and communicate in French</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Clean Intermittent Self Catheterization</keyword>
	<keyword>acceptance</keyword>
	<keyword>test</keyword>
</DOC>