<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01651000</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the efficacy of CTAP101 Capsules versus placebo in reducing intact parathyroid hormone (iPTH) by at least 30% from pretreatment baseline; safety and tolerability of CTAP101 will also be evaluated</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of CTAP101 to Treat Secondary Hyperparathyroidism in Stage 3 or 4 CKD and Vitamin D Insufficiency</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase 3, multi-center, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of CTAP101 Capsules administered for 26 weeks to treat SHPT in subjects ≥18 years of age with stage 3 or 4 CKD and vitamin D insufficiency. The study will be conducted at approximately 40 sites within the United States (US). Approximately 550 subjects will be screened to randomize approximately 210 eligible subjects, stratified by CKD stage (approximately 105 subjects in each stage) in a 2:1 ratio to receive either CTAP101 Capsules or matching placebo. An Interactive Voice Response System (IVRS) will provide study treatment group assignments using the computer-generated randomization code provided by the IVRS vendor. Subjects will receive an initial daily dose of 1 capsule (CTAP101 Capsules, 30 µg, or matching placebo) for the first 12 weeks. After l2 weeks (visit 8) and per pre-defined criteria, the dose may be increased in a blinded fashion by the IVRS with oversight by an independent medical monitor.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperparathyroidism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperparathyroidism, Secondary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Urinary albumin excretion ≤ 3000 mcg/mg of creatinine 2. Stage 3 or 4 CKD 3. Plasma iPTH: ≥ 85 pg/mL and &lt; 500 pg/mL 4. Serum Ca: ≥ 8.4 mg/dL and &lt; 9.8 mg/dL 5. Serum P: ≥ 2.0 mg/dL and &lt; 5.0 mg/dL 6. Serum 25hydroxyvitamin D: ≥ 10 ng/mL and &lt; 30 ng/mL. 7. Stable dose of Vitamin D therapy ≤ 1600 IU/day and receiving same dose for at least 2 months 1. History of kidney transplant or parathyroidectomy 2. Spot urine calcium:creatinine ratio &gt; 0.2 (&gt;200 mg/g Cr) 3. Current serious illness, such as malignancy, HIV, liver disease, cardiovascular event or hepatitis 4. Currently on dialysis 5. Use of pharmacological dose of ergocalciferol or cholecalciferol (≥ 50,000 IU mcg per month) during the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Parathyroid Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal Insufficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney Failure, Chronic</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperparathyroidism, Secondary</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperparathyroidism</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</keyword>
</DOC>