<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01370915</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Pregabalin is used for the treatment of neuropathic pain and has shown analgesic efficacy in postoperative pain. The aim of this randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial was to investigate the efficacy and safety of pregabalin for reducing postoperative pain in patients after septoplasty. Persons who scheduled for elective septoplasty under general anesthesia were randomly assigned to groups that received either pregabalin (150 mg twice) or placebo, one hour before surgery and 12 hours after the initial dose. Assessments of pain (verbal numerical rating scale) and side effects were performed at one, six, 12, and 24 hours postoperatively.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Perioperative Administration of Pregabalin for Pain After Septoplasty</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Pregabalin is used for the treatment of neuropathic pain and has shown analgesic efficacy in postoperative pain. The aim of this randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial was to investigate the efficacy and safety of pregabalin for reducing postoperative pain in patients after septoplasty. Patients will be randomly assigned to one of two groups to receive either pregabalin (Lyrica®, Pfizer, Inc.) or placebo (vitamin complex). According to their assigned study group, patients received either pregabalin (75 mg) or placebo twice, one hour before surgery and 12 hours after the initial dose. The assessment of pain and side effects, such as nausea and vomiting, headache, dizziness, sedation, and blurred vision, were made at one, six, 12, and 24 hours postoperatively.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pregabalin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 20 ≥ and ≤ 65 years Patients with nasal packing after septoplasty previous septal surgery history postoperative complications including septal hematoma, bleeding ets. Current therapy with pregabalin, gabapentin, or any opioid Renal insufficiency History of seizure disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>postoperative pain, nasal septum surgery, pregabalin</keyword>
</DOC>