<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01370967</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess stool consistency, in combination with additional health-related parameters including gastrointestinal tolerance and health-related quality of life, in a large sample of Chinese infants. We will also assess the timing of, frequency, and reasons for changes in the choice of formula or method of feeding among infants in this sample, as well as incidence of common infant illness and associated healthcare usage. Anthropometric measures and the frequency and duration of physician- and parent-reported gastrointestinal and other adverse events will be evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gastrointestinal Tolerance And General Health Status Of Healthy Term Infants Fed A New Infant Formula</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Parents / legally acceptable representatives of eligible infants will be invited to volunteer.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Healthy, term (3742 weeks gestation), singleton infant at birth. Postnatal age between 35 and 49 days (date of birth = day 0) at time of study entry. At enrollment, weightforage ≥ 5th and ≤ 95th percentile according to World Health Organization growth tables / charts. Infants who are consuming any types/brands of formula other than the new study formula (either exclusively or in a mixed feeding regimen) at time of study enrollment. Suspected or documented severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory abnormality that may increase the risk associated with study participation or may interfere with the interpretation of study results, and in the judgment of the investigator, would make the infant inappropriate for entry into the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Days</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>49 Days</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>infant</keyword>
	<keyword>term birth</keyword>
	<keyword>human milk</keyword>
	<keyword>infant formula</keyword>
	<keyword>breast feeding</keyword>
	<keyword>bottle feeding</keyword>
	<keyword>gastrointestinal tract</keyword>
	<keyword>quality of life</keyword>
	<keyword>infant development</keyword>
</DOC>