<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01370343</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of this study is to evaluate the pharmacokinetics, safety and tolerability of a single dose of PF-04991532 in healthy adult subjects with and without co-administration of cyclosporine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Single Dose Study Of The Effect Of Cyclosporine On The Pharmacokinetics Of PF-04991532 In Health Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Niacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy male and/or female (nonchildbearing potential) subjects between the ages of 18 and 55 years, inclusive. Healthy is defined as no clinically relevant abnormalities identified by a detailed medical history, full physical examination, including blood pressure and pulse rate measurement, 12lead ECG and clinical laboratory tests. Women must be of non childbearing potential as defined in Lifestyle Guidelines. Body Mass Index (BMI) of 17.5 to 30.5 kg/m2; and a total body weight &gt;50 kg (110 lbs). An informed consent document signed and dated by the subject or a legally acceptable representative. Subjects who are willing and able to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plan, laboratory tests, and other study procedures. Evidence or history of clinically significant hematological, renal, endocrine, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, hepatic, sychiatric, neurologic, or allergic (including drug allergies, but excluding untreated, asymptomatic, seasonal allergies at time of dosing) disease or clinical findings at Screening. Subjects with clinically significant infections within the past 3 months (for example, those requiring hospitalization, or as judged by the Investigator), or evidence of any infection within the past 7 days. Screening supine blood pressure &gt;=140 mm Hg (systolic) or &gt;=90 mm Hg (diastolic), on a single measurement [confirmed by a single repeat, if necessary] following at least 5 minutes of rest.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>