<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01158287</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Sorafenib tosylate may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth and by blocking blood flow to the tumor. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well sorafenib tosylate works in treating patients with relapsed esophageal cancer and/or stomach cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sorafenib. ICORG 06-41, V4</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - To determine the disease control rate (complete response, partial response, and stable disease) of sorafenib tosylate after 4 months in patients with relapsed esophageal or gastric adenocarcinoma previously treated with platinum-based chemotherapy. Secondary - To determine the progression-free survival of patients treated with this drug. - To determine the overall survival of patients treated with this drug. - To determine the time to tumor progression in patients treated with this drug. - To determine the objective response rate in patients treated with this drug. - To determine the tolerability and toxicity in patients treated with this drug. - To assess biomarkers associated with response/resistance to therapy. (exploratory) OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients receive oral sorafenib tosylate twice a day on days 1-28. Treatment repeats every 4 weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Blood and tumor samples may be collected periodically and analyzed for biological markers. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up periodically.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Niacinamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed esophageal and/or gastric adenocarcinoma Relapsed or progressed disease after prior platinumbased chemotherapy and not a suitable candidate for radical therapy At least 1 unidimensionally measurable lesion as assessed by RECIST criteria No uncontrolled, symptomatic brain metastases Patients with intracranial bleeding into metastases allowed provided the disease is wellcontrolled and not undergoing acute steroid therapy or taper (chronic steroid therapy allowed provided the dose is stable for 1 month prior to and following screening radiographic studies) PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: ECOG performance status 02 Life expectancy ≥ 2 months Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1.5 x 10^9/L Platelet count ≥ 100 x 10^9/L Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) ALT/AST ≤ 2.5 times ULN (≤ 5 times ULN for patients with liver involvement) Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2.5 times ULN (≤ 4 times ULN for patients with bony involvement) INR ≤ 1.5 aPTT normal Creatinine ≤ 1.5 times ULN Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective barrier method contraception prior to and during study therapy (men and women) and for 3 months after completion of study therapy (men) Not planning pregnancy within 6 months after completion of study therapy No history of cardiac disease, including any of the following: NYHA class IIIIV congestive heart failure Active coronary artery disease (myocardial infarction more than 6 months prior to study entry allowed) Cardiac arrhythmias requiring antiarrhythmic therapy (beta blockers or digoxin are permitted) No uncontrolled hypertension (systolic BP &gt; 150 mm Hg or diastolic BP &gt; 90 mm Hg, despite optimal medical management) No known HIV infection or chronic hepatitis B or C No active, clinically serious infections &gt; CTCAE grade 2 No thrombotic or embolic events (e.g., cerebrovascular accident including transient ischemic attacks within the past 6 months) No pulmonary hemorrhage or bleeding event &gt; CTCAE grade 2 within the past 4 weeks No other hemorrhage or bleeding event &gt; CTCAE grade 3 within the past 4 weeks No serious, nonhealing wound, ulcer (apart from the tumor), or bone fracture No evidence or history of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy No current signs or symptoms of severe progressive or uncontrolled hepatic, hematological, renal, endocrine, pulmonary, or cardiac disease No known or suspected allergy to sorafenib or any agent given in the course of this trial No previous cancer that is distinct in primary site or histology from esophagogastric junction cancer except for carcinoma in situ of the cervix, treated basal cell carcinoma, superficial bladder tumors [Ta and Tis], or any cancer curatively treated &gt; 3 years prior to study entry No concurrent cancer that is distinct in primary site or histology from esophagogastric cancer No substance abuse, medical, psychological, or social conditions that may interfere with the patient's participation in the study or evaluation of the study results No condition that impairs the patient's ability to swallow whole pills No malabsorption condition No seizure disorder requiring medication (e.g., steroids or antiepileptics) No familial, sociological, or geographical condition potentially hampering compliance with the study protocol and followup schedule No significant traumatic injury within the past 4 weeks PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics At least 3 weeks since prior local radiotherapy At least 3 weeks since prior biologic response modifiers (e.g., GCSF) GCSF and other hematopoietic growth factors allowed in the management of acute toxicity (e.g., febrile neutropenia) when clinically indicated or at the discretion of the investigator, however they may not be substituted for a required dose reduction Concurrent chronic erythropoietin allowed provided no dose adjustment is undertaken within 2 months prior to the study or during the study At least 4 weeks since prior major surgery or open biopsy At least 4 weeks since prior and no concurrent radiotherapy Prior or concurrent palliative radiotherapy to symptomatic disease sites allowed (unless the site to be irradiated is one of the target lesions used for response assessment) At least 4 weeks since prior and no concurrent anticancer chemotherapy, immunotherapy, or hormonal therapy (except bisphosphonates) At least 30 days since prior and no concurrent investigational drug therapy At least 5 weeks since prior and no concurrent mitomycin C or nitrosoureas At least 4 months since prior autologous bone marrow transplant or stem cell rescue No history of organ allograft No prior licensed or investigational tyrosine kinase inhibitor or antiangiogenic agent (e.g., sunitinib or bevacizumab) No prior sorafenib tosylate No prior licensed or investigational drug treatment that targets the RAS, VEGF, VEGFR, or EGFR pathway No concurrent rifampin or St. John wort No concurrent therapeutic anticoagulation with vitamin K antagonists (e.g., warfarin, heparins, or heparinoids) Lowdose warfarin (1 mg by mouth once a day) allowed provided INR is &lt; 1.5 Lowdose aspirin allowed No concurrent renal dialysis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma of the esophagus</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent esophageal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent gastric cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma of the stomach</keyword>
</DOC>