<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01158638</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Individually tailored, mediated pedometer feedback will provide an effective method to promote physical activity adoption in the elderly</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Utilizing Tailored Step-Count Feedback to Enhance Physical Activity in the Elderly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>1. Male or female individuals living in the community. 2. Aged between 50 and 85 years, at screening. 3. Sufficient physical function not to have limitations to participate in physical activity demonstrated by: Habitual gait speed ≥ 1.5 mph, AND No use of a cane or walker, AND Able to walk ≥ 50 feet unaided 4. Sufficient cognitive function, as demonstrated by responses to the minimental state examination(&gt;23 score). 5. Be able to read and write in English 6. Sedentary behavior, demonstrated by no regular activity / exercise for previous 6 months and/or a Stage of Change 2 and 3 1. Presence of a rapidly progressive or terminal illness condition that is expected to result in significant functional decline during the course of the proposed studies. 2. Significant uncontrolled cardiovascular disease and conditions, e.g. unstable or new onset angina, unrepaired aortic aneurysms, critical aortic stenosis or CAD without bypass, persistent moderate to severe uncontrolled hypertension. 3. Significant uncontrolled metabolic disease, e.g. hemoglobin A1c levels greater than 8.0 and/or glucose levels greater than 300 mg/dL. 4. Fracture of lower extremity within three months. 5. Amputation other than toes. 6. Current history of severe arthritis or orthopedic condition precluding physical activity. 7. Participation in any regular structured exercise (resistance training, Tai Chi, high intensity walking, jogging, cycling, stair climbing, stepping, within the previous 6 months. 8. Individuals that start a new medication that can impact health variables examined during study period (e.g., beta blockers, glucose or cholesterol altering medications), or individuals who alter medication dose that can impact health variables examined within study period.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Physical Activity Enhancement</keyword>
</DOC>