<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01263496</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to evaluate the long-term safety and efficacy of SYR-322, once daily (QD), to an α-glucosidase inhibitor, three times daily (TID), administered for 40 consecutive weeks in participants who completed a phase 2 dose-ranging study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-term Safety Study of Alogliptin in Participants With Type 2 Diabetes in Japan</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Both insulin hyposecretion and insulin-resistance are considered to be involved in the development of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Takeda is developing SYR-322 (alogliptin) for the improvement of glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Alogliptin is an inhibitor of the dipeptidyl peptidase IV (DPP-IV) enzyme. DPP-IV is thought to be primarily responsible for the degradation of 2 peptide hormones released in response to nutrient ingestion. It is expected that inhibition of DPP-IV will improve glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes. To evaluate the long-term safety and efficacy of alogliptin, this extension study was administered for 40 consecutive weeks (52 weeks from the start of treatment in the phase 2 dose-ranging study) to participants who had completed the phase 2 dose-ranging study SYR-322/CCT-001 (NCT01263470).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alogliptin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Voglibose</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Had completed the phase 2 doseranging study (i.e., the subject had completed the study visit at Week 12). Had clinical manifestations of hepatic impairment (e.g., an aspartate aminotransferase or alanine aminotransferase value 2.5 times or more of the upper reference limit at Week 8 of treatment in the phase 2 doseranging study). Had clinical manifestations of renal impairment (e.g., a creatinine value of 2 mg/dL or more at Week 8 of treatment in the phase 2 doseranging study).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>29 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>87 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus - Type 2</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>