<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01263665</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to confirm the safety and performance of the 25 cm GORE® VIABAHN® Endoprosthesis with PROPATEN Bioactive Surface when used in the Superficial Femoral Artery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the 25 Centimeter (cm) GORE® VIABAHN® Endoprosthesis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Lifestylelimiting claudication or rest pain (meeting angiographic entry criteria) affecting a lower extremity (Rutherford Categories 24). A written informed consent form, which has been reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee, has been read, understood and signed by the subject (or their legally authorized representative). At least 21 years of age. Noninvasive lower extremity arterial studies (anklebrachial index, ABI) prior to (within 45 days) or at the time of the study procedure demonstrating a resting anklebrachial index (ABI) ≤ 0.9 in the study limb. If ABI &gt; 0.9, patient is eligible for study if toebrachial index (TBI) is ≤ 0.5. A staged ipsilateral vascular procedure was not completed less than 30days prior to the study procedure. Resting ABIs were completed prior to the study procedure a minimum of 30days after the staged vascular procedure. Vascular treatment on the nonstudy leg for bilateral claudication was not performed less than 30days prior to study procedure. Resting ABIs on the study limb were completed prior to the study procedure a minimum of 30days after treatment on the nonstudy leg. Male, infertile female, or female of child bearing potential practicing an acceptable method of birth control with a negative pregnancy test within 7days prior to study procedure. Projected life expectancy of greater than three years. The ability to comply with protocol followup requirements and required testing. Angiographic and Lesion Requirements (assessed intraoperatively): Lesion length of 2035 cm located in the region beginning 1 cm below origin of the profunda femoris artery and ending 1 cm above the origin of the intercondylar fossa. De novo, postpercutaneous transluminal angioplasty (PTA), or postatherectomy stenosis (&gt; 50% at some point within the lesion by visual estimate) or occlusion of native SFA. Origin and proximal 1 cm of SFA are patent. Popliteal artery is patent from 1 cm above the origin of the intercondylar fossa distal to the radiographic knee joint. Reference vessel diameter of 4.0 7.5 mm in proximal and distal treatment segments within the SFA. Angiographic evidence of at least one patent tibial artery to the ankle that does not require intervention. Guidewire has successfully traversed lesion and is within the true lumen of the distal vessel. Untreated flowlimiting aortoiliac occlusive disease. Any previous open surgical procedure in the target vessel or previous stent placement in the target vessel. Prior angioplasty on the target lesion performed less than 30 days prior to the study procedure (unless performed at time of the study procedure). Prior atherectomy on the target lesion performed less than 6 months prior to the study procedure (unless performed at time of the study procedure). Any previous treatment of the target vessel with a drugeluting balloon. Femoral artery or popliteal artery aneurysm. Nonatherosclerotic disease resulting in occlusion (e.g. embolism, Buerger's disease, vasculitis). Tibial artery disease requiring treatment. Prior ipsilateral femoral artery bypass. Severe medical comorbidities (untreated coronary artery disease, congestive heart failure, severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, metastatic malignancy, dementia, etc.) or other medical condition that would preclude postprocedural ambulation. Popliteal artery vascular access at any time during procedure. Antegrade and retrograde vascular access on the same common femoral artery at the time of the SFA intervention. Major distal amputation (above the transmetatarsal) in the study or nonstudy limb. Septicemia. Any previously known coagulation disorder, including hypercoagulability. Morbid obesity or operative scarring that precludes percutaneous approach (physician's discretion). Contraindication to anticoagulation or antiplatelet therapy. Known allergies to stent/stentgraft components, including heparin sensitivity, allergy, or previous incidence of heparininduced thrombocytopenia (HIT) type II. History of prior lifethreatening reaction to contrast agent. Currently participating in another clinical research trial, unless approved by W. L. Gore &amp; Associates in advance of study enrollment. Subject has one limb currently enrolled in the study. Current peritoneal or hemodialysis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>stent-graft</keyword>
	<keyword>superficial femoral artery</keyword>
	<keyword>SFA</keyword>
	<keyword>peripheral artery disease</keyword>
	<keyword>PAD</keyword>
</DOC>