<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01263236</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the safety and tolerability of ascending single and multiple oral doses of LY2940094 in healthy male subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of LY2940094 in Major Depressive Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males of any ethnic origin. Have a body mass index (BMI) between 19.0 and 30.0 kilogram/square meter (kg/m²), inclusive. Must be in good health, as determined by a medical history, physical examination, 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG) and clinical laboratory evaluations. Have a calculated creatinine clearance of greater than 70 milliliter/minute (mL/min). Have venous access sufficient to allow blood sampling as per the protocol. Will have given their written informed consent to participate in the study and to abide by the study restrictions. Male subjects who are not, or whose partners are not willing to use appropriate contraception from the time of the first dose until 3 months after the final dosing occasion. Have received any prescribed systemic or topical medication within 14 days of the first dose administration Have used any nonprescribed systemic or topical medication (including herbal remedies) within 7 days of the first dose administration (with the exception of vitamin/mineral supplements) unless in the opinion of the Investigator the medication will not interfere with the study procedures or compromise safety. Have received any medications, including St John's Wort, known to chronically alter drug absorption or elimination processes within 30 days of the first dose administration Currently enrolled in, have completed or discontinued within the last 30 days from, a clinical trial involving an investigational product or are concurrently enrolled in any other type of medical research judged not to be scientifically or medically compatible with this study. Have donated or lost 50 to 499 milliliter (mL) of whole blood within 30 days, or more than 499 milliliter (mL) whole blood within 56 days preceding first dose administration. Have a significant history of drug allergy as determined by the Investigator. Have any clinically significant allergic disease (excluding nonactive hay fever), or any known allergy to LY2940094 or excipients as determined by the Investigator. Have a semireclined blood pressure and pulse rate higher than 130/90 millimeters of mercury (mmHg) and 100 beats per minute (bpm), respectively, or lower than 90/50 millimeters of mercury (mmHg) and 40 beats per minute (bpm), respectively. Consume more than 28 units of alcohol per week or who have a significant history of alcoholism or drug/chemical abuse/dependence as determined by the Investigator. Have a positive urine drug screen or alcohol breath test result that indicates substance abuse at screening or at admission to any treatment period. Smoke more than 10 cigarettes or the equivalent in tobacco per day and willing to avoid smoking for durations of at least 10 hours. With, or with a history of, any clinically significant neurological, gastrointestinal, renal, hepatic, cardiovascular, psychiatric, respiratory, metabolic, endocrine, hematological or other major disorders as determined by the Investigator. Have had a clinically significant illness within 4 weeks of the start of dose administration as determined by the Investigator. Have serum hepatitis, or who are carriers of the hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) or hepatitis C antibody, or who have a positive result to the test for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antibodies. Have an abnormality in the 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG) that, in the opinion of the investigator, increases the risk of participating in the study. In addition, subjects with the following findings will be excluded: Confirmed Bazett's corrected QT (QTcB) interval greater than 450 millisecond (msec) in 2 of 3 electrocardiograms (ECGs). Bundle branch blocks and other conduction abnormalities (including 2nd or 3rd degree Atrioventricular block, complete left bundle branch block, complete right bundle branch block or WolffeParkinsonWhite Syndrome, defined as PR less than 110 milliseconds (msec),confirmed by a repeat electrocardiogram [ECG]) other than mild firstdegree atrioventricular block (AV) block. Irregular rhythms other than sinus arrhythmia or occasional rare supraventricular ectopic beats. History of unexplained syncope. Family history of unexplained syncope or sudden death due to long QT syndrome. T wave configurations are not of adequate quality for assessing QTc intervals. Have previously completed or been withdrawn from this study. Taking any excluded medications that cannot be discontinued at Screening. Have a personal or family history of recurrent seizures or complicated febrile seizures. Have a history of significant brain trauma. Have epileptiform activity on baseline electroencephalogram (EEG). The following exclusion criteria apply only to those subjects enrolling in the part of the study involving lumbar puncture (LP) procedures Have abnormalities in lumbar spine as determined by the investigator Have a history of clinically significant back pain and/or back injury Have evidence or history of significant active bleeding or coagulation disorder Have an allergy to lidocaine (Xylocaine®) or its derivatives Have medical or surgical conditions in which LP is contraindicated The following exclusion criterion applies only to those subjects enrolling in the part of the study involving alcohol interaction Have an intolerance or allergy toward alcohol (symptoms may include nausea, flushed face, vomiting, or hypotension) or who, in the opinion of the investigator, may not be able to tolerate 0.8 gram per kilogram (g/kg) alcohol</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
</DOC>