<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01286987</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a single-arm, open-label study to assess the safety, pharmacokinetics, pharmacodynamics, and preliminary efficacy of talazoparib in patients with advanced tumors with DNA-repair pathway deficiencies. There will be 2 parts to the study: a dose escalation phase in which the maximum tolerated dose will be defined, and a dose expansion phase.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Talazoparib, a PARP Inhibitor, in Patients With Advanced or Recurrent Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma, Ewing</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Glandular and Epithelial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Talazoparib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically documented, unresectable, locally advanced or metastatic solid tumor Must have available archived tumor tissue (formalinfixed paraffinembedded) [FFPE]. 18 years of age or older. Have measurable disease by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST, v1.1) or increased CA125 (ovarian cancer) or PSA (prostate cancer) and/or CA 199 (pancreatic cancer). Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status ≤ 1. Have adequate organ function Able to take oral medications. Willing and able to provide informed consent. Sexually active patients must be willing to use an acceptable method of contraception. Females of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test at screening. Willing and able to comply with all study procedures. Part 2 Dose Expansion Tumor Types: Breast and ovarian cancer patients with deleterious or pathogenic BRCA mutations who have received no more than 4 prior regimens for metastatic disease. Prostate or pancreatic cancer patients with deleterious or pathogenic BRCA mutations who have received no more than 2 prior regimens for metastatic disease. Small cell lung cancer (SCLC) patients who have received no more than one prior regimen for SCLC. Ewing's sarcoma patients who have received no more than 3 prior regimens for metastatic disease. Part 2 Expansion: Prior treatment with a PARP inhibitor. Has history of central nervous system (CNS) metastasis. * Exception: In patients with SCLC, history of adequately treated brain metastasis who do not require corticosteroids for management of CNS symptoms. Has had major surgery within 28 days before Cycle 1, Day 1. Has active peptic ulcer disease. Active gastrointestinal tract disease with malabsorption syndrome. Pregnant or breastfeeding at screening or planning to become pregnant (in each case, either oneself or one's partner) at any time during the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>BRCA1 Protein</keyword>
	<keyword>BRCA2 Protein</keyword>
</DOC>