<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01286103</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effects of canagliflozin on glucose levels in the blood and urine when taken at 2 dose levels as a once-daily or twice-daily dosing regimen in healthy adult volunteers</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pharmacokinetic and Pharmacodynamic Study of Once-Daily and Twice-Daily Dosing With Canagliflozin in Healthy Adult Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label (volunteers will know the names of treatments they are assigned), single-center study of canagliflozin (JNJ-28431754) in healthy adult volunteers. Canagliflozin (a Sodium-Glucose Cotransporter 2 inhibitor) is currently under development to lower blood sugar levels in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). Patients in Cohort 1 will be randomized to receive Treatment A (one 300-mg tablet orally, by mouth [PO] once daily for 5 days) followed 10 days later by Treatment B (one 50-mg and one 100-mg tablet PO twice daily for 5 days) or Treatment B followed by Treatment A. Patients in Cohort 2 will be randomized to receive Treatment C (one 100-mg tablet PO once daily for 5 days) followed 10 days later by Treatment D (one 50-mg tablet PO twice daily for 5 days) or Treatment D followed by Treatment C.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Canagliflozin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy volunteers with a body mass index (BMI, a measure of a person's weight in relation to height) between 18 and 30 kg/m2, inclusive, and a body weight of not less than 50 kg History of or current clinically significant medical illness as determined by the Investigator History of clinically significant allergies, especially known hypersensitivity or intolerance to lactose Known allergy to canagliflozin or any of the excipients of the formulation of canagliflozin</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Canagliflozin</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacodynamics</keyword>
</DOC>