<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00616434</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the study is to evaluate the clinical activity of interferon beta-1a in participants with moderate to severe ulcerative colitis (UC). Secondary objectives of this study are to determine (i) the safety and tolerability of interferon beta-1a in participants with moderate to severe UC, and (ii) the percentage of participants, with a decrease in the Simple Clinical Colitis Activity Index (SCCAI) score of ≥3 points at Week 8.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 2 Study of Interferon Beta-1a (Avonex®) in Ulcerative Colitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-beta</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon beta-1a</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Established diagnosis of ulcerative colitis (UC) for ≥6 months 20 cm active disease at Screening endoscopy Must have active UC with a Mayo Score/Disease Activity Index (DAI) of 6 to 13 points and moderate to severe disease on endoscopy (Mayo endoscopic score of at least 2) despite prior or concomitant treatment Colonoscopy within past 5 years for extent of disease and to exclude polyps For subjects with UC for more than 10 years, colonoscopy with appropriate biopsies within 1 year prior to Screening to exclude dysplasia and neoplasia. Must be willing and able to practice effective birth control during the study and for 1 month after the last dose of study treatment. Key Diagnosis of indeterminate colitis or Crohn's disease Need for imminent surgery Diagnosis of primary sclerosing cholangitis or toxic megacolon Hemoglobin ≤9 g/dL White blood cell count &lt; 3500 cells/mm^3 Lymphocyte count &lt;1000 cells/µL Platelet count &lt;100,000 cells/µL Female subjects who are pregnant or who wish to become pregnant during the study, or who are lactating Known symptomatic colonic stricture Stool cultures positive for enteric infection History of malignant disease History of major abdominal surgery (e.g., gastrectomy) within past 5 years History of small bowel or colonic obstruction or resection History of drug or alcohol abuse (as defined by the Investigator) within 2 years prior to Screening Use of antidiarrheal agents during the screening period Previous participation in this study Previous treatment with interferon beta or other interferon products NOTE: Other protocol defined Inclusion/Exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>