<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00616837</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients from 4 local communities in northern Norway referred (either new or follow up) to orthopaedic department, University hospital of Northern Norway for outpatient consultation, are randomly assigned to either remote consultation by use of telemedicine (camera and screen), or standard consultation at the hospital. There are x-ray facilities also at the remote site. The patients randomized to telemedicine consultation meet special trained nurses at the remote site, but doctor only by video conference. The patients will be followed for up to one year. The primary endpoint is quality of care achieved with the telemedicine consultation as compared to standard outpatient consultation (assessed by questionnaires filled out by the doctor involved). Secondary end points are patient satisfaction assessed by questionnaires and economic analyses. The study hypothesis is non-inferiority of telemedicine consultation vs. conventional, outpatient consultation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Remote Orthopedic Outpatient Consultation by Help of Telemedicine</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Informed consent given New referred patients to orthopaedic department (outpatient), UNN, for conditions suitable for telemedicine consultation Follow up consultation of trauma patients (operated/not operated) Follow up consultation after elective orthopaedic surgery (e.g hip prothesis) Follow up of other orthopaedic patients Senile dementia Soldiers, prisoners Patients not talking Norwegian, dependent on translator If specialized procedures are required during follow up (e.g. catscan, ultrasound etc) Patients requiring a specific doctor</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Remote consultation/*methods</keyword>
	<keyword>Orthopaedics methods</keyword>
	<keyword>Telemedicine</keyword>
	<keyword>Follow-up study</keyword>
	<keyword>Ambulatory care</keyword>
</DOC>