<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00950365</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Erlotinib may stop the growth of tumor cells, and even shrink the tumors in some patients, by blocking some of the enzymes such as epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) needed for cell growth and spread. Pemetrexed is a drug that inhibits several key proteins that require folic acid to synthesize DNA. Blocking DNA synthesis in tumor cells has been shown to decrease tumor growth. can block tumor growth in different ways. Giving erlotinib together with pemetrexed at a specific schedule may kill more tumor cells than giving only pemetrexed. PURPOSE: This phase I/II trial is studying the side effects and best dose of erlotinib and cetuximab and to see how well they work in treating patients with advanced solid tumors or progressive or recurrent stage III or stage IV non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacodynamic Separation of Pemetrexed and Erlotinib as Second-line Therapy in Patients With Advanced Non-small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have histologically or cytologically confirmed advanced (Stage IIIB with a malignant pleural effusion or Stage IV disease) or recurrent nonsquamous NSCLC. Patients must have at least one measurable disease per RECIST criteria Patient must have disease progression after one prior chemotherapy and/or targeted therapy other than pemetrexed or antiEGFR therapy for metastatic disease, or relapse while receiving adjuvant therapy, or within 12 months of completing adjuvant therapy Patients who have had immunotherapy, hormone, chemotherapy or radiotherapy within 4 weeks (6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin C) prior to entering the study or those who have not recovered from adverse events due to agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier. Patients with uncontrolled brain metastases should be excluded from this clinical trial because of their poor prognosis. Patients with immune deficiency</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>progressive or recurrent stage III or stage IV non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>