<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01894061</DOC>
	<brief_summary>NovoTTF-100A is a device and Bevacizumab is a study drug that have both been approved by the FDA (Food and Drug Administration) for use as monotherapy in treating glioblastoma multiforme. The NovoTTF-l00A is a portable battery operated device which produces TTFields within the human body using surface electrodes (transducer arrays). Intermediate frequency electric fields (TTFields) stunt the growth of tumor cells. The purpose of this study is to determine the efficacy of the combination of Bevacizumab and NovoTTF-100A in Bevacizumab naive (meaning have never received bevacizumab before) patients with recurrent glioblastoma (GBM) as measured by 6-month progression free survival.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>NovoTTF-100A With Bevacizumab (Avastin) in Patients With Recurrent Glioblastoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This will be an open label Phase II trial in adults with recurrent glioblastoma (GBM). The NovoTTF-100A treatment and Bevacizumab will be administered on an outpatient basis; NovoTTF-100A treatment will be initiated in the outpatient clinic. PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the efficacy of the combination of bevacizumab and NovoTTF-100A in bevacizumab-naive patients with recurrent glioblastoma (GBM) as measured by 6-month progression-free survival (PFS6). SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess safety and tolerability of the combination of bevacizumab and Novo-TTF-100A in this patient population. II. To evaluate overall survival in this population. III. To determine objective response rate (ORR) by modified Revised Assessment in Neuro-Oncology (RANO) criteria in this population. IV. To assess time-to-progression in this population. V. To assess neurocognitive function (NCF) and quality of life (QOL) in this population. OUTLINE: Patients receive bevacizumab intravenously (IV) on days 1 and 15. Patients also undergo electric field therapy with NovoTTF-100A for at least 18 hours daily. Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for at least 28 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gliosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with histologically confirmed glioblastoma or other grade IV malignant glioma (i.e. gliosarcoma, small cell glioblastoma, etc.), recurrent after prior externalbeam fractionated radiotherapy and temozolomide chemotherapy. Patients with up to two prior recurrences are allowed. Karnofsky performance status ≥70. Patients must have the following laboratory values: Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1.5 x 10^9/L Platelets ≥ 100 x 10^9/L Hemoglobin (Hgb) &gt; 9 g/dL Serum total bilirubin: ≤ 1.5 x ULN ALT and AST ≤ 3.0 x ULN Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN Blood coagulation parameters: INR ≤ 1.5 Minimum interval since completion of radiation treatment is 12 weeks Minimum interval since last drug therapy: 3 weeks since last noncytotoxic therapy 3 weeks must have elapsed since the completion of a nonnitrosoureacontaining chemotherapy regimen 6 weeks since the completion of a nitrosoureacontaining chemotherapy regimen. Patients must have signed an approved informed consent and authorization permitting release of personal health information. Patients with the potential for pregnancy or impregnating their partner must agree to follow acceptable birth control methods to avoid conception. The effects of bevacizumab on developing fetus or nursing infant are not known. Female patients of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test. Patients must have no concurrent malignancy except curatively treated basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix and breast, adequately treated stage I or II cancer from which the patient is in complete remission. Patients with other prior malignancies must be diseasefree for ≥ three years. Patients must be maintained on a stable corticosteroid regimen from the time of their baseline scan until the start of treatment and/or for at least 5 days before starting treatment. Patients who have had previous treatment with bevacizumab, and or NovoTTF 100A system. Patients who have undergone major surgery (e.g. intrathoracic, intraabdominal or intrapelvic), open biopsy or significant traumatic injury ≤ 4 weeks prior to starting study drug, or patients who have had minor procedures, percutaneous biopsies or placement of vascular access device ≤1 week prior to starting study drug, or who have not recovered from side effects of such procedure or injury Patients with impaired cardiac function or clinically significant cardiac diseases, including any of the following: History or presence of serious uncontrolled ventricular arrhythmias Any of the following within 6 months prior to starting study drug: myocardial infarction (MI), severe/unstable angina, Coronary Artery Bypass Graft (CABG), Congestive Heart Failure (CHF), Cerebrovascular Accident (CVA), Transient Ischemic Attack (TIA), Pulmonary Embolism (PE) Uncontrolled hypertension (defined by a systolic blood pressure (SBP) ≥ 160 mm Hg or diastolic blood pressure (DBP) ≥ 100 mm Hg while on antihypertensive medications) Patients with cirrhosis, or active viral or nonviral hepatitis. Implanted pacemaker, defibrillator or deep brain stimulator, other implanted electronic devices in the brain or documented clinically significant arrhythmias. Infratentorial tumor Evidence of increased intracranial pressure (clinically significant papilledema, vomiting and nausea or reduced level of consciousness) Known sensitivity to conductive hydrogels Known diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection (HIV testing is not mandatory) Other concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled concomitant medical conditions (e.g. active or uncontrolled infection, uncontrolled diabetes) that could cause unacceptable safety risks or compromise compliance with the protocol Pregnant or breastfeeding women Patients unwilling or unable to comply with the protocol Patients with leptomeningeal disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>22 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult giant cell glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult gliosarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult brain tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>Bevacizumab-naive</keyword>
	<keyword>NovoTTF-100A</keyword>
</DOC>