<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00071578</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will compare two different approaches for the treatment for Binge Eating Disorder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparing Two Group Therapy Treatments for Binge Eating Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Binge Eating Disorder (BED) is associated with impairments in physical, psychological, and social functioning. Research has revealed relationships between disordered eating and both low self-esteem and negative emotional states. Participants in this study will complete assessment interviews regarding their eating disorder and associated problems. Similar assessments will be conducted at the end of the study. Participants will then be randomly assigned to one of two therapy groups. Participants in one group will focus on the role of self-esteem, self-awareness, and personal effectiveness in binge eating. Participants in the other group will focus on the role of negative emotions and binge eating. Both treatments will involve a 30 to 40 minute pre-treatment individual orientation session, followed by 20 weeks of weekly group therapy. Sessions will take place over 22 weeks, or approximately 6 months (18 weekly sessions followed by 2 biweekly sessions). Follow-up assessments will take place at 3 months, 6 months, and 12 months after study completion to assess maintenance of treatment effects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Feeding and Eating Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Binge-Eating Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bulimia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of Binge Eating Disorder Reside in the San Francisco Bay Area Willing to commit to the study requirements Unstable medical problems History of bipolar illness or schizophrenia Receiving treatment for an eating disorder (or unwillingness to discontinue treatment upon study entry) Membership in weightloss groups such as Weight Watchers or Jenny Craig (or unwillingness to discontinue membership upon study entry) Use of medications affecting weight or appetite. Antidepressants are acceptable, but doses of any psychiatric medication must have been stable for at least 3 months prior to study start Breastfeeding Require gastricbypass surgery</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Psychotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment</keyword>
</DOC>