<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="158043">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01042158</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TAD-PH-001</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>P50HL084946</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01042158</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Clinical Trial of Ambrisentan and Tadalafil in Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension Associated With Systemic Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>ATPAHSS</acronym>
  <official_title>A Clinical Trial of Ambrisentan and Tadalafil in Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension Associated With Systemic Sclerosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>United Therapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health (NIH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eli Lilly and Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Cleveland Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Texas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>United Therapeutics</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This will be a 36-week, randomized, double-blind, parallel group study comparing the effects
      of tadalafil monotherapy, ambrisentan monotherapy and combination therapy with tadalafil and
      ambrisentan in patients with PAH-SSc. Standard outcome measures such as six-minute walk
      distance (6MWD), NYHA classification, and hemodynamic measurements will be assessed, as well
      as novel functional measures of RV-PV function including the transthoracic echocardiogram
      parameter tricuspid annular plane systolic ejection (TAPSE), contrast-enhanced cardiac MRI
      and heart rate variability assessed by Holter monitoring. This design (excluding a
      placebo-placebo arm) was selected for ethical concerns and to provide optimal efficiency and
      active therapy to all study subjects. It also allows for comparisons between the two
      monotherapies and with combination therapy.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension (PAH) includes a heterogeneous group of clinical entities
      sharing similar clinical and pathological features that have been subcategorized as
      idiopathic PAH (IPAH, formerly known as &quot;primary pulmonary hypertension&quot; or PPH), familial
      PAH, pulmonary hypertension related to connective tissue diseases (such as systemic
      sclerosis), portopulmonary hypertension and pulmonary hypertension related to HIV infection,
      drugs and toxins (10). PAH is clinically defined by a resting mean pulmonary artery pressure
      ≥ 25 mmHg and pulmonary artery wedge pressure ≤ 15 mmHg in the absence of left heart
      disease, underlying parenchymal lung disease, thromboembolic disease or other causes of
      pulmonary hypertension.

      PAH is characterized by increased pulmonary vascular resistance due to remodeling and
      occlusion of the pulmonary arterioles. Left untreated, PAH leads irremediably to right
      ventricular (RV) hypertrophy, pressure overload and dilation resulting in death within 2-3
      years (11). For the past two decades, it has been appreciated that the integrity of the RV
      function, rather than the degree of pulmonary vascular injury, is the major determinant of
      symptoms and mortality in patients with PAH. RV dysfunction at time of presentation, as
      reflected by an elevation in right atrial pressure (RAP), the presence of pericardial
      effusion or depressed cardiac output (CO), is a powerful prognosticator of death (12).

      Current PAH therapies consist of prostacyclin analogues, endothelin receptor antagonists
      (ETRA) and phosphodiesterase type V (PDE V) inhibitors (13). All have been shown to be
      effective in improving exercise capacity as measured by the 6 MWD in short term (12 - 16
      week) randomized, placebo-controlled clinical trials. However, the clinical response is
      highly variable and mortality remains high (14). Moreover, the majority of subjects enrolled
      in these trials have had IPAH. Over the past 10 years, the Johns Hopkins Pulmonary
      Hypertension Program and Scleroderma Center have worked closely to address the daunting
      clinical challenge of PAH associated with scleroderma or systemic sclerosis (PAH-SSc).
      Previous work from our group (15;16) and others (17-19) has clearly demonstrated a markedly
      worse prognosis in PAH-SSc compared with IPAH despite similar treatments. An intriguing and
      consistent finding when comparing these two groups is that whereas mPAP is, on average,
      lower in PAH-SSc, markers of RV dysfunction (e.g. CO and RAP) are similar, raising the
      possibility of maladaptive RV response to pressure overload and/or intrinsic myocardial
      disease. Current PAH therapies target pathways that have been implicated in the remodeling
      of the pulmonary vasculature (PV). However, there is no clear evidence that these therapies
      have altered PV and/or RV remodeling or offered significant beneficial effects in patients
      with PAH-SSc in whom mortality remains exceedingly high. In addition, their effects on RV
      dysfunction and RV-PV interaction remain poorly characterized.

      We hypothesize that improvement in PAH-SSc will only be achieved with therapy directly
      targeted at RV-PV dysfunction. Sildenafil and tadalafil inhibit phosphodiesterase type 5
      (PDE5) which is abundant in the lung and is the main enzyme responsible for cGMP hydrolysis.
      The resulting increase in cGMP probably mediates the relaxant and anti-hypertrophic actions
      of nitric oxide and natriuretic peptides in vascular tissues, and exerts a direct
      anti-hypertrophic action on cardiac muscle as demonstrated in compelling preliminary
      experiments by investigators of the NHLBI-funded Hopkins Scientific Center of Clinically
      Oriented Research (SCCOR) in Pulmonary Vascular Disease. In these experiments, sildenafil
      was capable of preventing and reversing RV hypertrophy and dysfunction in a model of
      pulmonary artery banding, similar to its effects on the left ventricle with aortic banding
      (20), indicating a direct beneficial action on RV remodeling.

      Both sildenafil (21) and tadalafil (22) have been demonstrated to be effective in PAH and
      are FDA approved for this indication. The endothelin-receptor antagonists, bosentan (23) and
      ambrisentan (24), are also FDA-labeled for this indication and represent alternative options
      for oral therapy of PAH (25). A small randomized study comparing sildenafil with bosentan
      suggested that sildenafil was superior in reducing RV mass and improving exercise capacity
      in patients with PAH (26). Recently, the results of a large multi-center randomized,
      controlled trial of tadalafil therapy for PAH have been presented. The data indicate, that
      similar to sildenafil, tadalafil at doses of 20 and 40 mg per day, improved exercise
      capacity. In addition, tadalafil 40 mg per day improved pulmonary hemodynamics, quality of
      life and reduced the incidence of clinical worsening.

      This study aims to compare the effects of tadalafil therapy, ambrisentan therapy and the
      combination of both agents in PAH-SSc on PVR and RV mass. It will also assess novel markers
      of RV function by cardiac MRI and echocardiography, as well as the conventional endpoints,
      including 6 MWD and functional class. The trial is unique in that it will enroll only
      PAH-SSc patients, the PAH subgroup with the poorest outcomes and will be considerably longer
      in duration (36 weeks) than previous studies. In addition, the effects of first line
      combination therapy with an ETRA/PDE V inhibitor will be compared with single agent
      regimens.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>January 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To compare the effects of ambrisentan monotherapy, tadalafil monotherapy and the combination in patients with PAH-SSc on right ventricular mass as assessed by cardiac MRI and pulmonary vascular resistance (PVR) by right heart catheterization.</measure>
    <time_frame>36 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the safety of combination therapy with ambrisentan and tadalafil in PAH-SSc.</measure>
    <time_frame>36 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To compare the change in: i. 6 MWD ii. Resting hemodynamics iii. Pressure/flow slopes with submaximal exercise iv. TAPSE by echocardiography v. Heart rate variability vi. Quality of life vii. Borg score viii. NYHA class</measure>
    <time_frame>36 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">63</enrollment>
  <condition>Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</condition>
  <condition>Systemic Sclerosis</condition>
  <condition>Scleroderma Spectrum of Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Connective Tissue Disease</condition>
  <condition>Pulmonary Hypertension</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tadalafil monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ambrisentan monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tadalafil and ambrisentan</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tadalafil monotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>tadalafil 20 mg once daily (qd) and placebo qd. Up-titration of study medications will occur at week 4 (tadalafil 40 mg qd). If a subject experiences an intolerable adverse event as a result of an uptitration in the study drug dose, the dose of study drug maybe down titrated to 20 mg of tadalafil. If the subject is still experiencing an intolerable adverse event, then the investigator will withdraw the subject from the study.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tadalafil monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Adcirca</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ambrisentan monotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>ambrisentan 5 mgs daily and placebo qd. Up-titration of study medications will occur at week 4 (ambrisentan 10 mgs daily). If a subject experiences an intolerable adverse event as a result of an uptitration in the study drug dose, the dose of study drug maybe down titrated to 5mg of ambrisentan. If the subject is still experiencing an intolerable adverse event, then the investigator will withdraw the subject from the study.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ambrisentan monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Letairis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>tadalafil and ambrisentan</intervention_name>
    <description>tadalafil 20 mg qd and ambrisentan 5 mg qd. Up-titration of study medications will occur at week 4 (ambrisentan 10 mgs daily and tadalafil 40 mg qd). If a subject experiences an intolerable adverse event as a result of an uptitration in the study drug dose, the dose of study drug maybe down titrated to 20 mg of tadalafil and/or 5mg of ambrisentan. If the subject is still experiencing an intolerable adverse event, then the investigator will withdraw the subject from the study.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tadalafil and ambrisentan</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Adcirca</other_name>
    <other_name>Letairis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. A right heart catheterization done at baseline with a mean pulmonary artery pressure
             (mPAP) ≥ 25mmHg, pulmonary artery wedge pressure (PAWP) ≤ 15mmHg, and pulmonary
             vascular resistance (PVR) ≥3 Woods units.

          2. Scleroderma defined as systemic sclerosis with diffuse or limited scleroderma meeting
             the American College of Rheumatology (ACR) criteria (33). Cases will be included if
             they meet clinical features that satisfy ACR criteria for a diagnosis of scleroderma
             or the presence of three of five features of the CREST syndrome are identified; or
             there is the presence of definite Raynaud's phenomenon, abnormal nail fold
             capillaries typical of scleroderma and the presence of a specific scleroderma related
             auto-antibody. Limited skin involvement is defined as skin tightening distal to
             elbows and knees with or without facial involvement; and diffuse skin involvement,
             tightening proximal to these joints or truncal involvement.

          3. Subjects will be older than 18 years of age with a diagnosis of PAH-SSc.

          4. Subjects will be NYHA functional class II or III.

          5. 6 minute walk distance ≥ 100 meters and ≤ 500 meters at screening and baseline.

          6. Negative urine pregnancy test for women of childbearing age at screening and baseline
             visits.

          7. Ability and willingness to provide written informed consent

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Right heart catheterization reveals evidence of pulmonary venous hypertension
             (pulmonary capillary wedge pressure &gt; 15 mm Hg).

          2. Significant chronic obstructive: Forced expiratory volume in 1 second to forced
             expiratory volume ratio &lt; 70% and a forced expiratory volume in 1 second less than
             60% of predicted.

          3. Interstitial lung disease

               1. Based on a combination of pulmonary function tests and chest radiography.

               2. Patients will be excluded if they have a total lung capacity less than 60% of
                  predicted and included if the total lung capacity was ≥ 70%. Patients with a
                  total lung capacity between 60 and 70% of predicted are included if their
                  computed tomography scan demonstrates only minimal interstitial fibrosis

          4. Portal hypertension.

          5. Severe obstructive sleep apnea.

          6. Chronic thromboembolic disease.

          7. Positive antibodies to the human immunodeficiency virus.

          8. History of anorexigen use including phen-fen.

          9. Any other disease known to be associated with pulmonary hypertension.

         10. Subjects with other etiology for pulmonary hypertension besides PAH-SSc.

         11. Subjects with liver function abnormalities (ALT or AST &gt; 3 times the upper limit of
             normal at screening or at baseline) or chronic liver disease.

         12. Advanced kidney failure (GFR &lt; 30 ml/min at screening or at baseline).

         13. Acute decompensation of underlying illness or hospitalization for pulmonary
             hypertension within 4 weeks prior to enrollment.

         14. Prior chronic therapy with an endothelin-receptor antagonist, PDE V inhibitor, or a
             prostacyclin analogue.

         15. History of hypersensitivity reaction or adverse effect related to ambrisentan or
             tadalafil.

         16. History of implantable permanent pacemaker or any metallic objects in the body.

         17. Participation in a clinical study involving an investigational drug or device within
             four weeks before the screening visit.

         18. Pregnant or lactating women.

         19. Concomitant use of nitrates (any form) either regularly or intermittently

         20. Concomitant use of potent CYP3A inhibitors (eg, ritonavir, ketoconazole,
             itraconazole)

         21. Any additional contraindications and precautions specified in the package inserts for
             Tadalafil (Adcirca) and Ambrisentan (Letairis) not listed above.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Paul Hassoun, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21287</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>July 16, 2014</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 4, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>United Therapeutics</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>UT Clinical Records Management</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Paul Hassoun, MD, Johns Hopkins University</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Tadalafil</keyword>
  <keyword>Ambrisentan</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypertension, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Familial Primary Pulmonary Hypertension</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Scleroderma, Systemic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Scleroderma, Diffuse</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Connective Tissue Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Tadalafil</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
