<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02279108</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The sentinel node has a fundamental role in the management of early breast cancer. Currently, the double detection of blue and radioisotope is recommended. A radioactive material requires the presence of a nuclear medicine department and the approval of health authorities. In many centers, this technique is not available. The use of blue is easier to implement technique. However, allergic reactions and prolonged breast tattoo led many teams to stop the practice. So in common practice, many center use a single method. However, with a single detection, the risk of false negatives and the identification failure rate increased to a significant extent and the number of sentinel lymph node detected and removed is not enough. Under these conditions, find another method of detection seems crucial. According to the literature, the fluorescence method (ICG) is a technique that seems safe and reliable. The investigators therefore propose a prospective, randomized study to investigate the interest of fluorescence associated with the isotopic method.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Assessing The Interest of Indocyanine Green Fluorescence Imaging With Radioisotope Method For Sentinel Lymph Node Biopsy in Patients With Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically proved infiltrating breast cancer (ductal, lobular carcinoma…) or a carcinoma insitu with an elevated risk of microinvasion. (High grade with necrosis, radiologically evaluated size more than 40mm, or immediate mastectomy…) Unifocal or multifocal but in same quarter Size &lt; 5cm clinically palpable or not Clinically or ultrasound axillary N0 Isotopic sentinel node detection Adult patient Signed informed consent by patient or legally responsable authority Patient registered to a social security system No surgical contraindication Mammary carcinoma recurrence Previous same side mammary reduction Previous lumpectomy Contraindication to surgery Pregnant or breast feeding patient Denial of participation</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>sentinel lymph node</keyword>
	<keyword>indocyanine green</keyword>
	<keyword>fluorescence method</keyword>
	<keyword>radioisotope conventional method</keyword>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>