<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02279459</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to utilize dual-energy computed tomography (DECT) to investigate changes in tumor iodine concentration in patients with head and neck squamous cell carcinomas (HNSCC). Dual-energy computerized tomography could easily replace a standard CT neck with the added benefit of providing functional information that would only be possible with advanced computerized tomography perfusion, magnetic resonance diffusion (MRI) or positron emission tomography (PET) imaging techniques.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dual-Energy CT in Patients With Head and Neck Squamous Cell Carcinomas</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with head and/or neck tumors routinely have head and neck imaging completed with a computerized tomography scan, commonly called a CT scan. A CT scan combines a series of x-ray views that are taken from many different angles and uses computer processing to create cross-sectional images inside your body. These cross-sectional images are very thin slices, often less than 1 mm thick and allow the radiologist to examine parts of your tissue very closely. Dual energy computed tomography (DECT) is a fairly new technology that uses both the normal x-ray and also a second less powerful x-ray to make the images. The Ottawa Hospital has scanners in use that are able to take the images that oncologists typically order for patients and can also be set to obtain DECT images at the same time. The purpose of this study is to investigate whether DECT images can provide helpful information to better predict how the tumor will respond to treatment and the likely course of head and neck tumors.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years and older untreated, histologically confirmed head and neck squamous cell carcinoma paranasal sinus involvement of head and neck squamous cell carcinoma</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>