<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00796731</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective is to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of SAR3419 according to the dose limiting toxicities (DLTs) observed when administered as a single agent once weekly. Secondary objectives are: - to characterize the global safety profile - to evaluate the pharmacokinetic (PK) profile of SAR3419 in the proposed dosing schedule - to assess preliminary evidence of anti-lymphoma activity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SAR3419 Administered Weekly in Patients With Relapsed/Refractory CD19-positive B-cell Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of Bcell non Hodgkin's lymphoma Relapsed or refractory after standard treatments and with no curative option with conventional therapy (Patients having undergone stem cell transplantation may be included) CD19 positive disease by flow cytometry or immunohistochemistry Burkitt's lymphoma, Lymphoblastic lymphoma, Chronic lymphocytic leukemia (Small lymphocytic lymphoma may be included) Evidence of cerebral or meningeal involvement by lymphoma Patients without bidimensionally measurable disease ECOG performance status &gt; 2 Life expectancy less than 3 months Chemotherapy or radiation therapy or other investigational agents within 4 weeks prior to entering the study Previous radioimmunotherapy within 12 weeks Known anaphylaxis to infused proteins HIV, HBV and HCV positivity Poor kidney, liver and bone marrow functions Any serious active disease or comorbid condition, which, in the opinion of the principle investigator, will interfere with the safety or the compliance with the study Pregnant or breastfeeding women Patients with reproductive potential without effective birth control methods The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>B-cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>NHL</keyword>
</DOC>