<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02453685</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted globally. The aim of this trial is to compare stepwise insulin intensification of biphasic insulin aspart (BIAsp) 30 and basal-bolus therapy with insulin glargine and insulin aspart in insulin naïve type 2 diabetic patients inadequately controlled on oral anti-diabetic therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Compare Insulin Intensification of Biphasic Insulin Aspart 30 and Insulin Analogues (Insulin Glargine and Insulin Aspart) in Insulin naïve Type 2 Diabetic Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin degludec, insulin aspart drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin aspart, insulin aspart protamine drug combination 30:70</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Biphasic Insulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Aspart</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Long-Acting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Glargine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Isophane</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent obtained before any trialrelated activities. Trialrelated activities are any procedures that are carried out as part of the trial, including activities to determine suitability for the trial Male or female, age at least 18 years at the time of signing informed consent Type 2 diabetes subjects clinically diagnosed at least 6 months prior to screening Treatment with stable daily dose (for at least 90 days prior to screening) of: Metformin (equal or above 1000 mg or maximum tolerated dose documented in the patient medical record) and Sulfonylurea and willing to discontinue any other oral antidiabetic drugs containing insulin secretagogues, DPP4i (dipeptidyl peptidase4 inhibitor), SGLT2 (sodium glucose cotransporter 2), colesevelam, bromocriptin and/or combination products at randomisation Insulinnaïve. Short term insulin treatment for acute illnesses for a total of 14 days or less is allowed as is prior insulin treatment for gestational diabetes HbA1c (glycosylated haemoglobin) 7.09.5 % (both inclusive) analysed by central laboratory Willing to consume 3 main meals daily (morning, midday and evening) throughout the entire trial. The definition for 'main meal' will be according to the investigator's discretion Anticipated initiation or change in concomitant medications known to affect weight or glucose metabolism, in excess of 14 days (i.e. sibutramine, orlistat, thyroid hormones, systemic corticosteroids and other weight loss/modifying agents) Impaired liver function, defined as ALT (alanine aminotransferase) at least 2.5 times upper limit of normal (central laboratory value measured at screening visit) Inadequately treated high blood pressure defined as Class 2 hypertension or higher (i.e. systolic blood pressure equal to or above 160 mm Hg or diastolic equal to or above 100 mm Hg) in accordance with the National High Blood Pressure Education Program, 7th Joint National Committee1 and ESH/ESC 2013 Guidelines2 Within the past 180 days prior to randomisation, any of the following: Myocardial Infarction, stroke or hospitalization for unstable angina and /or transient ischemic attack</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>