<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01150786</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to determine the effect of selenium supplementation as an antioxidant on serum adiponectin, HSCRP , ferritin , transferrin, albumin and homocysteine level.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Selenium on Serum Adiponectin, Homocystein and Malnutrition-inflammation Complex Syndrome in Hemodialysis Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After screening all of 280 patients under regular HD in Faghihi Hospital Hemodialysis Center, 80 stable patients in the age range of 18-80 years old were found to be eligible for enrollment and give their informed consent to participate in this trial.The Ethics Committee of Shiraz University of Medical Sciences reviewed and approved the protocol of this study.These patients are randomly assigned in a 1:1 ratio into 2 groups of selenium(200µg) or placebo and followed for 12 weeks.Before the onset of the treatment and after the end of the treatment phase of the study, 10cc blood samples were taken from each patient. The blood was taken from the patient's arm used for hemodialysis cannulae just before the beginning of the HD session. The serum was separated by centrifugation at 3000 g/min for 5 min and stored at -70°C. Serum levels of adiponectin,high sensitive C-reactive protein (HSCRP), ferritin, transferrin, homocysteine, calcium, phosphate, albumin, blood urea nitrogen (BUN), and creatinine as well as hemoglobin (Hb) levels (g/dL) were measured in all patients at the baseline and at the end of treatment phase of study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Selenium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who were dialysed three times a week for at least 3 months or more Patients who took multivitamins or immunosuppressive medications Patients consuming antioxidant supplements including vitamin E, vitamin C, lipoic acid, omega3 fatty acids, soy extracts and greentea preparations Patients who had active infection Patients who were hospitalized in the previous month. Being Pregnant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>oxidative stress</keyword>
	<keyword>selenium</keyword>
	<keyword>hemodialysis</keyword>
</DOC>