<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01150357</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This double-blind 8 week study will evaluate dose response, efficacy (blood pressure lowering effect) and safety of aliskiren in children 6 - 17 years old with hypertension at low, mid and high weight-based doses. The low dose ranges from 6.25 mg to 25 mg of aliskiren, the mid dose ranges from 37.5 mg to 150 mg of aliskiren and the high dose ranges from 150 mg to 600 mg of aliskiren. This study is being conducted to support monotherapy registration of aliskiren for the treatment of hypertension in children 6-17 years of age.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Aliskiren in Pediatric Hypertensive Patients 6-17 Years of Age</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Documented diagnosis of hypertension as defined in the NHLBI 4th Report, 2004 msSBP (mean of 3 measurements) must be ≥ 95th percentile for age, gender and height, at Visit 2 (randomization) measurement as defined by the NHLBI 4th Report, 2004 Patient receiving immunosuppressant medication (e.g. cyclosporine, MMF, etc) other than oral/topical steroids, for any medical condition Current diagnosis of heart failure (NYHA Class IIIV) or history of cardiomyopathy or obstructive valvular disease msSBP ≥ 25% above the 95th percentile Second or third degree heart block without a pacemaker AST/SGOT or ALT/SGPT &gt;3 times the upper limit of the reference range Total bilirubin &gt; 2 times the upper limit of the reference range Creatinine clearance &lt; 30 mL/min/1.73m² (calculated using Modified Schwartz formula to estimate glomerular filtration rate [GFR]), based on the serum creatinine concentration obtained at the screening visit) WBC count &lt; 3000/mm³ Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pediatric hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>primary hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>secondary hypertension</keyword>
</DOC>