<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03003806</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The DreaMed Advice4U Pro is a software which automatically analyses treatment information, learns patient's needs and accordingly suggests adjustments in insulin dosing. The DreaMed Advice4U Pro uses information gathered from glucose monitoring (sensor readings or capillary blood glucose measurements), insulin dosing and meal data during daily routine home care. Following a 5-minute data collection and analysis, the algorithm learns and suggests pump-setting changes for optimization of glucose control The algorithm is designed as an advisory tool and has three main components: 1. A statistical analysis of the insulin pump and sensor data: insulin delivery, bolus-calculator rate of use, sensor glucose variables, hypoglycemic and hyperglycemia patterns. 2. Practical recommendations, alert messages based on aforementioned data 3. Recommendation for new insulin pump settings: including basal intervals and rate, different carbohydrate ratio according to time of day, correction factor and insulin sensitivity time. The main goal of the DreaMed Advice4U Pro is to improve diabetes management for subjects with Type 1 Diabetes (T1D) by using an innovative Advisor to determine insulin dosing for pump users. The main objective of the proposed study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of using the DreaMed Advice4U Pro algorithm versus medical guided recommendation to determine insulin dosing for sub-optimal controlled subjects with type 1 diabetes using pump therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Dreamed Advice4U Pro for Automated Insulin Pump Setting Adjustments in Children and Adolescents With Type 1 Diabetes- The Advice4U Pro Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject with Type 1 diabetes (&gt;1yr since diagnosis) Age ≥ 10 years up to 21 years HbA1c at inclusion ≥ 7.0% and ≤ 10% Insulin infusion pump therapy: "OmniPod®" Insulin pump (insulet Corp., Bedford, "MA", USA) or Medtronic pump :"MiniMed 530G" system,"MiniMed VEO" or "MiniMed Revel" for at least 4 months BMI Standard Deviation Score (SDS) below the 97th percentile for age Patients willing to follow study instructions (at least 4 capillary blood glucose readings/day, use the boluscalculator feature of the pump) Patient/ parents are required to have minimum computer skills and understanding of navigating the internet Patients willing to use dexcom sensor for the study duration Patients/ parents will have to have a smart phone (Apple, Android, Windows) An episode of diabetic ketoacidosis within the month prior to study entry Concomitant diseases/ treatment that influence metabolic control Any significant diseases /conditions including psychiatric disorders and substance abuse that in the opinion of the investigator is likely to affect the subject's ability to complete the study or compromise patient's safety, Participation in any other interventional study Known or suspected allergy to trial products such as adhesives, tapes, needles. An allergy to contrast medium, use of other active medical devices (such as pacemaker, ICD) and planned imaging examinations (such as MRI). Female subject who is pregnant or lactating planning to become pregnant within the planned study duration Severe hypoglycemia six month prior to enrollment as defined by the American Diabetes Association (ADA) and Endocrine Society as follows: "Severe hypoglycemia is an event requiring assistance of another person to actively administer carbohydrates, glucagon, or take other corrective actions". Current use of the following medications: medications that are used to lower blood glucose such as Pramlintide, Metformin and GLP1 analogs. Beta blockers, glucocorticoids and other medications, which in the judgment of the investigator would be a contraindication to participation in the study (Anticoagulant therapy e.g. Plavix, LMW heparin, Coumadin, Immunosuppressant therapy) Relevant severe organ disorders (diabetic nephropathy, diabetic retinopathy, diabetic foot syndrome) or any secondary disease or complication of diabetes mellitus Subject has unstable or rapidly progressive renal disease or is receiving dialysis Subject has active proliferating retinopathy Active gastroparesis Patient suffers from an eating disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Insulin pump treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Type 1 diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Pump setting advisor</keyword>
</DOC>