<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03003403</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Up to 50% of obese patients are not interested in, or ready for, weight loss. Clinical practice guidelines clearly recommend that these patients avoid gaining weight. However, despite this clinical guideline, weight gain prevention interventions are not available in primary care practice. Balance is a pragmatic, randomized controlled effectiveness trial for weight gain prevention for patients within rural community health centers, using a digital health platform.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Balance: A Pragmatic Trial of a Digital Health Intervention to Prevent Weight Gain in Primary Care</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Clinical practice guidelines emphasize recommend weight gain prevention, but evidence-based treatments are not available in primary care. Balance, a pragmatic effectiveness trial, will test a scalable treatment approach for medically -vulnerable adults, those who suffer disproportionately from obesity and its adverse health effects. Balance builds on the design and findings of the Shape study (NCT00938535) to test a pragmatic intervention within rural community health centers. Balance will randomize overweight and obese adults who are clients at a local community health center network to either: 1) a 12-month weight gain prevention intervention or usual care, or 2) usual care. Intervention group components include tailored behavior change goals; mHealth self-monitoring and feedback; skills training videos; and stepped responsive coaching from clinic Registered Dieticians. The usual care group will receive standard primary care offered by their providers and automated text messages and health information about maintaining a healthy weight. All intervention components and materials will be provided in Spanish and English.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Signs and Symptoms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Gain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nutrition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Overnutrition</mesh_term>
	<criteria>BMI between 25 and 40 kg/m2 and weighs less than 380 lbs Speaks English or Spanish Had a nonurgent outpatient visit at a participating community health center clinic within the last 4 weeks Has a cell phone Willing to receive 312 studyrelated text messages per week Has past bariatric surgery or planned bariatric surgery (within next 2 years) Diagnosed with cancer in the last 6 months and is in active treatment Has a history of cardiovascular event (stroke/MI) in the last 12 months Was hospitalized for a mental health issue in the last 12 months Currently participating in a weight loss program/research study Plans to move out of area and not receive care within community health center network (within the next 2 years) Currently or recently pregnant (within the last 6 months) Females only Currently or recently lactating (with the last 2 months) Females only Plans to get pregnant in the next 12 months Females only</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>mHealth</keyword>
	<keyword>Digital Health</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Pragmatic Clinical Trial</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavior Change</keyword>
	<keyword>Weight Management</keyword>
</DOC>