<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02303795</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RIvaroxaban for Valvular heart diseasE and atRial fibrillation trial (RIVER trial).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>RIvaroxaban for Valvular Heart diseasE and atRial Fibrillation Trial -RIVER Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Phase 2, Randomized, Open label, Non-Inferiority Clinical Trial to Explore the Safety and Efficacy of Rivaroxaban compared with vitamin K antagonism in Patients with Atrial Fibrillation with Bioprosthetic Mitral valves - RIVER.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Valve Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Warfarin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male and female patients aged &gt;18 and &lt; 80 years at time of inclusion 2. Patients with Persistent or paroxysmal Atrial Fibrillation or flutter with bioprosthetic mitral valves. The patient must be able to give informed consent 1. Cardiovascularrelated conditions as known presence of cardiac thrombus or tumor Active endocarditis Uncontrolled hypertension 2. Hemorrhage riskrelated criteria Active internal bleeding History of, or condition associated with, increased bleeding risk 3. Concomitant conditions and therapies History of previous thromboembolism with high risk of bleeding: Severe, disabling stroke (modified Rankin score of 45, inclusive) within 3 months Acute thromboembolic events or thrombosis (venous/arterial) within the last 14 days prior to randomization Acute MI within the last 14 days prior to randomization Treatment with: Chronic aspirin therapy &gt; 100 mg daily or dual antiplatelet therapy; Intravenous antiplatelets; Fibrinolytics; Anticipated need for longterm treatment with a nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug; Systemic treatment with a strong inhibitor of cytochrome P450 3A4, such as ketoconazole or protease inhibitors; Treatment with a strong inducer of cytochrome P450 3A4, such as rifampicin, phenytoin, phenobarbital, or carbamazepine. Anemia Pregnancy or breastfeeding or women of reproductive age not using effective contraceptive methods Calculated creatinine clearance bellow 30 mL/min Known significant liver disease or alanine aminotransferase N3× the upper limit of normal Previous participation in this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>bioprosthetic mitral valve</keyword>
	<keyword>valvular heart disease</keyword>
	<keyword>anticoagulant agents</keyword>
	<keyword>NOACs</keyword>
	<keyword>rivaroxaban</keyword>
	<keyword>warfarin</keyword>
</DOC>