<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01545947</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this first study combining an investigational dual mTOR inhibitor, CC-223, with other agents (erlotinib or the investigational agent, oral azacitidine) is to establish a maximum tolerated dose level for each combination in order to evaluate their effects in future clinical trials for advanced non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Assessing Safety, Pharmacokinetics and Efficacy of CC-223 With Either Erlotinib or Oral Azacitidine in Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Azacitidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Men and women, 18 years or older, with histologically or cytologicallyconfirmed, Stage IIIB/IV NonSmall Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC) with tumor progression following at least one prior treatment regimen [(either chemotherapy or an Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor inhibitor (EGFR)] for advanced disease. There is no restriction on the number of prior treatment regimens allowed. 2. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Score of 0 to 1. 3. Adequate organ function. 4. Adequate contraception (if appropriate). 5. Consent to retrieve archival tumor tissue. 6. Consent to repeated tumor biopsy (dose expansion phase). 1. Prior systemic cancerdirected treatments or investigational drugs within 4 weeks or 5 half lives, whichever is shorter except erlotinib which may be continued with intervention in subjects allocated in Arm A. 2. Symptomatic central nervous system metastases. 3. Acute or chronic pancreatitis. 4. Persistent diarrhea or malabsorption &gt; Grade 2, despite medical management. 5. Impaired cardiac function or significant cardiac disease. 6. Diabetes on active treatment, fasting blood glucose &gt; 126 mg/dL, (glycated haemoglobin) HbA1c &gt; 6.5%. 7. Known Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV), chronic hepatitis B or C infection. 8. Prior treatment with an investigational dual target of ripamycin 1 (TORC1)/ target of ripamycin 2 (TORC2), Phosphatidylinositol 3Kinase (PI3K), or protein kinase B (Akt) inhibitor. Prior treatment with analogs of rapamycin (rapalogs) is allowed. 9. Major surgery &lt; 2 weeks prior to starting study drugs. No specific wash out is required for radiotherapy. Subjects must have recovered from any effects of recent therapy that might confound the safety evaluation of study drug. 10. Pregnant or breastfeeding, inadequate contraception. 11. History of concurrent second malignancies requiring ongoing systemic treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulmonary</keyword>
	<keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer of the Lung</keyword>
	<keyword>Stage IIIB Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>IV Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>