<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02682160</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to evaluate the effect of the use of Protein Assistant on the daily protein intake in obese patients who underwent a bariatric surgery (in the 3 months following surgery).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Study to Evaluate Daily Protein's Intake Following Bariatric Surgery by Using the Software Protein Assistant</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After a bariatric surgery, food intake is reduced. Patients should favor proteins to avoid loss of muscles. The guidelines recommend a minimal protein's intake of 60g per day. But this goal is achieved only for 55 to 60 % patients 4 months after surgery and 50 à 65 % patients at one year. Protein assistant is a software which can calculate the amount of proteins eaten per day and can propose solutions if the intake is insufficient. The main objective of this study is to evaluate the effect of the use of Protein Assistant on the daily protein intake in obese patients who underwent a bariatric surgery (in the 3 months following surgery). Protein Assistant is suggested 1 month after bariatric surgery on a digital tablet. The patient is educated to use Protein Assistant. The patient has to complete a dietary record every 2 weeks during 2 months. The aim is to intake 60g per day. If the aim is not reached, Protein assistant suggests qualitative and/or quantitative solutions.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Patients who underwent a bariatric surgery a month +/ one week ago Able to use a digital tablet With internet access at home Accepting modalities of formation and of digital tablet lending When the average of protein intake is under 60g/j on a 3 days dietary record, one month after bariatric surgery Lack of understanding of the use of a digital tablet Under the protection of justice Person participating to another trial Pregnant or breastfeeding women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>bariatric surgery</keyword>
</DOC>