<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02190565</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether a food supplement consisting of vitamins, minerals and fish oil taken during and after pregnancy can decrease the need for additional iron supplementation due to anemia during pregnancy, and optimize levels of nutritional markers such as vitamin D and docosahexaenoic acid (DHA, an omega 3 fatty acid) in maternal blood and breast milk, compared to placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of a Food Supplement for Pregnant and Lactating Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Healthy pregnant women aged 1840 years with a body mass index (BMI) above 18.5 and below 30 kg/m2 who visit prenatal clinics (midwife centres) to register. Nulliparous and multiparous women. The women must be able to understand verbal and written information in Swedish to give an informed consent to participate in the study. Women below the age of 18 or above 40 years old. Women with a BMI below 18.5 or above 30 kg/m2. Women with any form of anaemia as diagnosed at the first visit to the prenatal clinic. Women expecting two or more babies. Women who have undergone bariatric surgery. Women on medication with pharmaceuticals that could affect the result of the study, e.g., vitamin K antagonists. Women who are allergic to any of the components of WellnessPack mama, e.g., fish. Women who suffer from drug or alcohol abuse. Women who suffer from known severe eating disorders. Women who suffer from chronic diseases that could affect gastrointestinal absorption and metabolism. Women who want to continue or start using similar food supplements in addition to WellnessPack mama/placebo, unless recommended by a physician or midwife, will be excluded from the study. Upon miscarriage or transfer to prenatal care specialist, the subject is excluded from the study.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>pregnancy, lactation, food supplement, anaemia</keyword>
</DOC>