<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="119264">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01550302</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>42272-D</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01550302</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Superficial Cervical Plexus Block for Shoulder Pain After Lung Surgery</brief_title>
  <acronym>SCPB</acronym>
  <official_title>The Effect of Superficial Cervical Plexus Block on Post-Thoracotomy/Scopy Ipsilateral Shoulder Pain</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Washington</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Washington</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators want to know whether injecting numbing medication on the side of the neck
      (also called superficial cervical plexus block) can prevent or reduce shoulder pain that
      patients commonly experience after lung surgery. The investigators will perform the
      injection at the end of your surgery while the subjects are still under general anesthesia
      and before they wake up. The investigators will use a local anesthetic (bupivacaine or
      Marcaine®) that is routinely used for skin infiltration of the surgical wounds.

      This study is randomized and single-blind. This means that subjects will be assigned by
      chance (like flipping a coin) to receive either an injection with active medication
      (bupivacaine), or no injection at all.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Pain management following lung surgery is of outmost importance. Providing adequate pain
      control facilitates patient recovery and improves lung function, therefore, leading to
      reduced morbidity and mortality associated with lung surgery. It is now well-established
      that lung surgery is associated with significant incisional pain, which in some patients may
      lead to development of chronic post-thoracotomy pain syndrome. In addition, many patients
      report significant shoulder pain that is often resistant to increasing epidural infusions
      and intravenous opioid therapy. The incidence of shoulder pain varies from study to study
      with estimates anywhere between 41% to 97%. Although the cause of the shoulder pain is not
      well understood, there are only few therapies available for the treatment of shoulder pain
      including acetaminophen, non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, interscalene brachial plexus
      and stellate ganglion block. However, all of the currently available therapies have
      potentially significant side-effects. The investigators are not aware of any studies
      evaluating the effectiveness of superficial cervical plexus block in reducing or preventing
      shoulder pain following thoracotomy or thoracoscopic surgery. The superficial cervical
      plexus block is minimal risk procedure equivalent to an IV start.

      The primary aim of this study is to compare the effect of superficial cervical plexus block
      when added to thoracic epidural analgesia and intravenous patient controlled analgesia (PCA)
      to standard thoracic epidural analgesia and PCA used at our institution on the incidence of
      shoulder pain.

      Subjects participating in this study will receive standard clinical care in addition to the
      following research procedures:

        -  Intra-operative block: an injection of bupivacaine on the side of the neck at the end
           of the surgery while the subject is still under general anesthesia or no injection at
           all if in control group. If the subject is assigned to receive an injection, the
           investigators will be using a small needle similar to the one used to numb the skin for
           the IV start. There will be a single needle stick on the side of the neck (same side as
           the lung surgery) and injection of 15 mL of 0.25% bupivacaine under the skin.
           Regardless of whether the subject gets an injection or not, he/she will receive
           standard clinical care.

        -  Post-lung surgery pain assessment: the investigators will ask the subjects to rate
           their pain at the incision site, chest tube site and shoulder at rest and with movement
           at 6, 12, 18, 24 and 48 hours after lung surgery. The investigators will also ask the
           subjects about any side-effects that may be associated with the standard narcotic pain
           medications.

      The investigators will collect the following data from the medical record including:

        -  Presence or absence of shoulder pain

        -  The amount of pain medicines (narcotics) needed to treat subject's pain over 24 and 48
           hours after lung surgery

        -  The presence of any side-effects of narcotic pain medications

        -  Blood pressure, heart rate, EKG and oxygen levels when available in order to evaluate
           if improved shoulder pain and less narcotics used will have additional beneficial
           effects

      Subjects are eligible if they are age 18-75 years and undergoing lung surgery.

      Subjects are not eligible if they are non-English speaking, have had a previous lung
      surgery, are allergic to bupivacaine, have a history of chronic pain or have been taking
      pain medications for a long time, and already have shoulder pain.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Unable to continue enrollment due to lack of resources (research coordinator no longer
    available).
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>October 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single Blind (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of post-thoracotomy/scopy ipsilateral shoulder pain</measure>
    <time_frame>24 and 48 hours after lung surgery</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-operative opioid consumption expressed in morphine equivalents</measure>
    <time_frame>24 and 48 hours after the surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Numeric response scale pain scores around ipsilateral shoulder at rest and during movement</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, 18, 24 and 48 hours after the surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Numeric response scale pain scores at incision site at rest and during coughing</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, 18, 24 and 48 hours after the surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Numeric response scale pain scores around chest tube insertion site at rest and during coughing</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, 18, 24 and 48 hours after the surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the need for post-operative ibuprofen as a rescue medication</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours after the surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate post-operative side effects such as post-operative nausea and vomiting (PONV), pruritus, sedation, respiratory depression and hypotension</measure>
    <time_frame>24 and 48 hours after the surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Shoulder Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Controls</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects enrolled in this group will only have a line drawn on the side of their neck for superficial cervical plexus block, but we will not perform the injection. The subjects will not be aware whether they received an intra-operative block or not. In addition, neither the Post-Anesthesia Care Unit nurse nor the providers involved in the post-operative care will be aware of subjects group assignment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Superficial Cervical Plexus Block</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects enrolled in this group will have a line drawn and will receive a superficial cervical plexus block at the end of the surgery just prior to emergence from anesthesia.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Superficial Cervical Plexus Block</intervention_name>
    <description>At the end of the lung surgery while subjects are still under general anesthesia, one of the investigators will perform superficial cervical plexus. First, a line extending from the mastoid process to C6 transverse process is drawn. The site of needle insertion is marked at the midpoint of the line connecting the mastoid process with Chassaignac's tubercle of C6 transverse process. After skin cleansing with chlorhexidine prep, using a &quot;fan&quot; technique with superior-inferior needle redirections, 15 ml of 0.25% bupivacaine will be injected alongside the posterior border of the sternocleidomastoid muscle 2-3 cm below and above the needle insertion site.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Superficial Cervical Plexus Block</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cervical Plexus Block</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bupivacaine</intervention_name>
    <description>Single dose of 37.5 mg of bupivacaine subcutaneously</description>
    <arm_group_label>Superficial Cervical Plexus Block</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Marcain, Marcaine, Sensorcaine and Vivacaine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  subjects who clinically consented to elective thoracotomy or VATS procedure under
             general anesthesia and epidural analgesia

          -  ages between 18 and 75 years

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  inability to perform thoracic epidural

          -  violation of protocol (e.g., administration of medication that does not comply with
             the study protocol)

          -  subject has change of mind

          -  surgery has to be repeated

        Non-inclusion Criteria:

          -  subject refusal

          -  non-English speaking

          -  previous chronic or neuropathic pain

          -  previous chronic use of opioids

          -  history of psychiatric disorder

          -  allergy to local anesthetic

          -  previous ipsilateral thoracotomy or VATS

          -  prior history of shoulder pain
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Srdjan Jelacic, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Washington</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Washington</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>MacDougall P. Postthoracotomy shoulder pain: diagnosis and management. Curr Opin Anaesthesiol. 2008 Feb;21(1):12-5. doi: 10.1097/ACO.0b013e3282f2bb67. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18195603</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Burgess FW, Anderson DM, Colonna D, Sborov MJ, Cavanaugh DG. Ipsilateral shoulder pain following thoracic surgery. Anesthesiology. 1993 Feb;78(2):365-8.</citation>
    <PMID>8439033</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pandit JJ, Dutta D, Morris JF. Spread of injectate with superficial cervical plexus block in humans: an anatomical study. Br J Anaesth. 2003 Nov;91(5):733-5.</citation>
    <PMID>14570798</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 30, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 1, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Washington</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Srdjan Jelacic</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Superficial Cervical Plexus Block</keyword>
  <keyword>Thoracic Surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Thoracotomy</keyword>
  <keyword>Video-Assisted Thoracoscopic Surgery</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Shoulder Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
