<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00241592</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A study to evaluate the use of a vaporization system as a smokeless delivery system for inhaled marijuana.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vaporization as a Smokeless Cannabis Delivery System</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Our primary objective is to evaluate the use of a vaporization system ( the Volcano) as a smokeless delivery system for inhaled marijuana. We will compare plasma levels of delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol (THC), cannabinol, cannabidiol, and metabolites, including 11-OH-THC, in healthy volunteers after smoking ~400 mg each of approximately 1.8, 3.5, and 7% THC marijuana cigarettes (using the Foltin puff procedure) to those obtained when the same individuals inhale the vaporization product of the rest of the marijuana from the identical cigarette processed through the Volcano device. In addition to plasma levels, we will also compare the THC concentrations over an 8-hour time period, the subjective high experienced by the patients, and clinical evidence of cannabis effect by evaluating conjunctival hyperemia and heart rate. We will also compare the tolerability of the two methods of ingestion, and we will monitor expired carbon monoxide to evaluate whether the vaporizer reduces exposure to respiratory toxins.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Marijuana Abuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lobeline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 2145 years Current history use of marijuana. Subjects must have smoked marijuana within the past 30 days but an amount totaling less than 10 marijuana cigarettes or the equivalent. All men and women in this study must agree to use adequate birth control during the study. Acceptable barrier birth control methods are a male condom, female condom, diaphragm, or intrauterine (IUD). All women of reproductive potential (who have not reached menopause or undergone hysterectomy, oophorectomy,or tubal ligation) must have a negative urine BHCG pregnancy test performed 48 hours before initiating the protocolspecified medication. Able to understand and follow the instructions of the investigator and research personnel. Able and willing to provide informed consent. Severe coronary artery disease, uncontrolled hypertension, cardiac ventricular conduction abnormalities, or orthostatic mean blood pressure drop greater than 24mm/Hg, severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. History of renal or hepatic failure. Evidence of hepatic, hematological or renal dysfunction based on judgement of physician. Active substance abuse. Marijuana dependence as defined in DSMIV code#304.30. Any psychiatric dysfunction that would, in the opinion of the study investigator, interfere with a participant's ability to comply with the study protocol. Use of tobacco within the past 30 days. Subjects taking medications which may be vulnerable to drugdrug interactions such as those metabolized by the cytochrome P450 enzyme system. Blood donation in the past 30 days. Use of smoked marijuana within 48 hours of GCRC admission. Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding may not take part in this study. Unable to read or speak English.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cannabis</keyword>
	<keyword>Marijuana</keyword>
	<keyword>Vaporization</keyword>
	<keyword>Volcano</keyword>
	<keyword>THC</keyword>
</DOC>