<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00241150</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A STUDY ON WHETHER AN ANTIHYPERTENSIVE MEDICATION PREVENTS DAMAGE TO WALLS OF VEINS IN FEMALE PATIENTS WITH THE METABOLIC SYNDROME (OVERWEIGHT AND OTHER DISORDERS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Diva - The Effects Of 12 Weeks Of Treatment With High Dose Valsartan (320 Mg) To Amlodipine On Endothelial Function In Hypertensive Subjects With The Metabolic Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Valsartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amlodipine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Subjects must meet the following inclusion criteria at Visit 1, Visit 2 and Visit 3. Inclusion criteria for Group A (overweight postmenopausal females with highnormal blood pressure/ mild Stage I hypertension) 1. Nonsmoking female outpatients diagnosed as postmenopausal based on age (48 65 years) and selfreported absence of menstrual periods for at least one year. 2. Mean blood pressure between 130 149 mm Hg systolic and/or 85 94 mm Hg diastolic • When systolic blood pressure and diastolic blood pressure fall into different categories (high normal versus mild stage I hypertension), the higher category should be selected to classify or group the subject. 3. Body mass index greater than or equal to 26 but less than or equal to 41 kg/m2 4. Subjects who agree not to alter their diet or exercise routine during the study and comply with study specific restrictions 24 hours prior to the next scheduled study visit 5. Subjects who have read, signed and received a copy of the informed consent form prior to the initiation of any study procedures and who agree to participate in all aspects of the study 1. Nonsmoking female outpatients diagnosed as postmenopausal based on age (48 65 years) and selfreported absence of menstrual periods for at least one year. 2. Mean blood pressure between 90 129 mm Hg systolic and/or 50 84 mm Hg diastolic. 3. Body mass index greater than or equal to 26 but less than or equal to 41 kg/m2</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>valsartan</keyword>
	<keyword>hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>endothelial function</keyword>
</DOC>