<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00241982</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Trial to study the safety of a single, intravenous administration of long-circulating liposomal prednisolone disodium phosphate in patients with active rheumatoid arthritis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-Circulating Liposomal Prednisolone Versus Pulse Intramuscular Methylprednisolone in Patients With Active Rheumatoid Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A proof of concept, dose-escalating trial to study the safety of a single, intravenous administration of long-circulating liposomal prednisolone disodium phosphate in patients with active rheumatoid arthritis. Secondary goals: To compare the therapeutic effect of this intervention with that of a single intramuscular administration of 120 mg methylprednisolone (Depo-Medrol, Pharmacia). The latter is commonly used in the clinics as bridging therapy. To assess the effect of these interventions at the synovial tissue level. On the longer term, the goal of liposomal corticosteroids is to achieve an increased efficacy/safety ratio compared to standard treatment with free corticosteroids.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>In order to be enrolled in the study a patient must: Be aged 18 years or older Fulfill the revised 1987 ARA criteria for the classification of RA Have an active RA as defined by a Modified Disease Activity Score (DAS28) of more than 3.2 Have been on stable treatment with disease modifying antirheumatic drugs within 12 weeks prior to trial initiation Be able and willing to give voluntary written informed consent The indication for bridging therapy with systemic corticosteroids has been established by the caring rheumatologist The patient must not Have been treated with oral corticosteroids within 2 weeks prior to baseline or with intraarticular or intramuscular corticosteroids within 8 weeks prior to baseline Have diabetes mellitus or abnormal renal, liver or haematological tests Have a clinically severe or unstable medical condition involving cardiac, pulmonary, liver and endocrine disorders or malignancies Have a previous history of bleeding or infectious disorders Be currently pregnant or breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>rheumatoid arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>long circulating liposomes</keyword>
</DOC>