<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01993537</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients will undergo at baseline and regular intervals: - clinically indicated bloodwork/urine and echocardiogram testing - biomarker studies Upon enrolment in the study patients will be divided into 4 groups normal, mildly deficient and severely deficient. Normal and mild vitamin D levels will receive no treatment while severe Vitamin D deficiency will be randomized (50/50) to receive no treatment or vitamin D treatment. They will be seen in the heart failure clinic every 6 months. The patients will be followed for 26 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Role of Vitamin D in the Pathophysiology of Chronic Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The inclusion criteria for the study is: - an EF ≤40% within the last 12 months before recruitment - established diagnosis of heart failure - &gt;18 years of age - patients will vitamin d levels of sufficient, mild deficiency and severe deficiency The exclusion criteria is: - hypercalcemia - known hypersensitivity to Vitamin D - patient unwilling to comply with study requirements - any other disease other than heart failure that can alter the patients quality of life over a period of 6 months - women of child bearing potential - a patient currently taking vitamin d - severe renal impairment estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt;30</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<criteria>an ejection fraction (EF) ≤40% within the last 12 months before recruitment established diagnosis of heart failure &gt;18 years of age patients with Vitamin D levels of sufficient, mild deficiency and severe deficiency hypercalcemia known hypersensitivity to Vitamin D patient unwilling to comply with study requirements any other disease other than heart failure that can alter the patients quality of life over a period of 6 months women of child bearing potential a patient currently taking vitamin d severe renal impairment eGFR &lt;30</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>