<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02832544</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This program is a comprehensive evaluation of rheumatic valvular heart disease (RVHD), Atrial fibrillation (AF)/flutter and stroke. A prospective, randomized, parallel group, open-label clinical trial of rivaroxaban versus standard vitamin K antagonists (VKA) therapy to evaluate non-inferiority of rivaroxaban to VKA, with testing for superiority if non-inferiority is satisfied.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>INVestIgation of rheumatiC AF Treatment Using Vitamin K Antagonists, Rivaroxaban or Aspirin Studies, Non-Inferiority</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rheumatic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rheumatic Heart Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin K</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. RVHD diagnosed by echocardiography at any time prior to enrollment 2. Age ≥18 3. Increased risk of stroke by any of the following CHA2DS2VASc score ≥ 2 OR Moderate/Severe mitral stenosis with valve area ≤2.0 cm2 OR Left atrial spontaneous echo contrast OR Left atrial thrombus 4. Heart Rhythm *AF or Flutter should be documented on baseline 12lead ECG, or on a previous 12lead ECG, Holter monitor, inhospital ECG rhythm strip or Pacemaker or ICD electrogram. 1. Refusal to give informed consent 2. Actively involved in any study that would compromise the protocol of INVICTUS Trial 3. Severe comorbid condition with life expectancy &lt; 1 year 4. Other serious condition(s) or logistic factors likely to interfere with study participation or with the ability to complete the trial, as appropriate to country or region. 5. Likely to have valve replacement surgery within 6 months 6. Mechanical valve prosthesis or other condition requiring treatment with VKAs. Patients with deep vein thrombosis or recent pulmonary embolism can be enrolled where both VKAs and rivaroxaban are approved. 7. Contraindication to the study medication of the trial Allergy to rivaroxaban Allergy to VKAs ( noninferiority trial) Allergy to aspirin ( superiority trial) 8. Severe renal insufficiency with an calculated creatinine clearance (CockcroftGault) &lt;15 ml/min 9. Serious bleeding in the past six months or at high risk for bleeding 10. Moderate to severe hepatic impairment 11. Ongoing need for dual antiplatelet therapy (patients with ongoing aspirin therapy ≤100 mg per day are not excluded) 12. Ongoing need for dual strong inhibitors of CYP3a4 or pglycoprotein inhibitor. 13. Received an investigational drug in the past 30 days 14. Patients considered unsuitable for trial inclusion because of unwillingness to attend follow up visits 15. Women who are pregnant and/or breastfeeding 16. Women of child bearing age who do not use an effective form of birth control.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>atrial fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
</DOC>