<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00773955</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II trial is studying how well R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid works in treating patients with recurrent extensive-stage small cell lung cancer. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>R-(-)-Gossypol Acetic Acid in Treating Patients With Recurrent Extensive-Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the objective response rate of R-(-)-gossypol in patients with recurrent chemotherapy-sensitive extensive stage small cell lung cancer. II. To determine the time to disease progression. III. To determine the overall survival. IV. To assess the toxicities associated with this drug. V. To explore whether intratumoral Bcl-2 family member expression correlates with sensitivity to targeting by R-(-)-gossypol. VI. To explore whether the administration of R-(-)-gossypol causes specific induction of the intrinsic apoptotic pathway. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients receive oral R-(-)-gossypol once daily on days 1-21. Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Blood is collected periodically during treatment for pharmacodynamic analysis. Peripheral blood mononuclear cells are analyzed via protein isolation and western blotting for Bcl-2, cytoplasmic release of cytochrome c, and caspase activation. Available tumor tissue blocks are assessed by immunohistochemistry. After completion of study therapy, patients are followed periodically for up to 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gossypol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gossypol acetic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinol acetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed small cell lung cancer Extensive stage disease Recurrent disease Measurable disease Chemotherapysensitive disease, defined as: No progression during firstline chemotherapy No disease recurrence &lt; 2 months after completion of firstline chemotherapy Must have received prior platinumbased chemotherapy No symptomatic or progressive brain metastases Patients with previously treated brain metastases who are clinically and radiographically stable or improved and have been off steroids ≥ 14 days are eligible ECOG performance status 02 Life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks Leukocytes ≥ 3,000/μL ANC ≥ 1,500/μL Platelet count ≥ 100,000/μL Total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 mg/dL AST and ALT ≤ 2.5 times upper limit of normal Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL OR creatinine clearance ≥ 60 mL/min Hemoglobin &gt; 8 g/dL Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception before, during, and for 30 days after completion of study therapy Able to take oral medications on a regular basis Willing to provide blood samples for mandatory correlative studies No condition that impairs the ability to swallow and retain R()gossypol tablets, including the following: Gastrointestinal tract disease resulting in an inability to take oral medication or a requirement for IV alimentation Active peptic ulcer disease No malabsorption syndrome or disease significantly affecting gastrointestinal function No ulcerative colitis, inflammatory bowel disease, or a partial or complete small bowel obstruction No uncontrolled concurrent illness including, but not limited to, any of the following: Ongoing or active infection Symptomatic congestive heart failure Unstable angina pectoris Cardiac arrhythmia Psychiatric illness or social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements No symptomatic hypercalcemia &gt; grade 2 No requirement for routine use of hematopoietic growth factors (including GCSF, GMCSF, or IL11) or platelet transfusions to maintain ANC or platelet counts No history of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition to R()gossypol No HIV positivity Recovered from all prior therapy, including prior surgical procedures No prior surgical procedures affecting absorption No prior resection of the stomach or small bowel No more than one prior chemotherapy regimen No prior racemic gossypol or R()gossypol At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy (6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin C) At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy, hormonal agents, or biologic response modifiers At least 4 weeks since prior and no concurrent investigational agents or devices No concurrent prophylactic hematopoietic growth factors (including filgrastim [GCSF], sargramostim [GMCSF], or interleukin11 [IL11]) during course one No concurrent combination antiretroviral therapy for HIVpositive patients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>