<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02461537</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial compares outcome of two treatment strategies for patients with high-risk AML who failed to achieve or maintain a complete remission with standard therapy. Patients will be randomized between two strategies. The standard strategy is aimed at achieving a complete remission by aggressive salvage chemotherapy using high dose cytarabine and mitoxantrone, . The alternative is a less toxic disease-control strategy of disease monitoring and, if necessary, low-dose cytarabine or mitoxantrone prior to allogeneic transplantation, which should be performed as soon as possible.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Remission Induction Chemotherapy Prior to Allogeneic SCT in Relapsed and Poor-response Patients With AML (ETAL3-ASAP)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with high-risk acute myeloid leukemia (AML) who relapsed or showed a poor response to induction chemotherapy have a dismal prognosis. For these patients, allogeneic transplantation is the recommended treatment. While allogeneic transplantation may be considered as the ultimate treatment concept, the treatment path to transplantation is not well defined. The traditional approach to pursue a complete remission by means of aggressive reinduction chemotherapy prior to allogeneic transplantation. This approach is associated with potentially life-threatening toxicities and has limited efficacy. As a result, only some patients will reach allogeneic transplantation in complete remission. To reduce the number of patients who die or who are ineligible for transplantation due to the toxicity of aggressive induction chemotherapy, other bridging options have been explored. One promising alternative is to abstain from remission induction. Instead, disease control by means of less aggressive chemotherapy or simply monitoring leukemic proliferation can be considered. This randomized trial will identify if there is non-inferiority of the less toxic approach, compared to the standard approach of remission induction by aggressive chemotherapy prior to allogeneic transplantation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cytarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitoxantrone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female patients of 18 to 75 years of age. Diagnosis of AML according to WHO criteria. Patient is fit for aggressive induction chemotherapy and transplantation by assessment of an experienced hematologist. HLAidentical sibling. or HLAcompatible (8/8) unrelated donor with completed confirmatory typing. or One potential HLA compatible (8/8) donor plus at least two backup donors, who are at least 9/10 matches with &gt;90% probability for each of them. For the relapse stratum: First AML relapse, defined as ≥5% bone marrow blasts and / or extramedullary AML manifestation. For the poorresponders stratum: If patient ≤60 years old: High risk AML according to ELNcriteria and ≥5% bone marrow blasts after the first cycle of induction therapy. If patient &gt;60 years old: Nonfavourable risk AML according to ELNcriteria and ≥5% bone marrow blasts after the first cycle of induction therapy. Acute promyelocytic leukemia (APL). WBC count of ≥50 GPt/L at study inclusion. For patients in the poorresponder stratum the first cycle of induction therapy must not contain HDAC, defined as cytarabine at singledoses of ≥1g/ m2. Patient has received more than 80% of the tolerable cumulative anthracycline dose (see chapter 7.2. for definitions and worksheet for calculation). Severe organ dysfunction, . Uncontrolled infection at the time of enrollment. History of allogeneic transplantation. Manifestation of AML in the central nervous system. Pregnant or breastfeeding women.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>