<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02461121</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients with de novo AML enrolled in the study. Patient who has a HLA-identical donor is assigned to receive NST therapy with GVHD prophylaxis and who has no HLA-identical donor is assigned to receive MST therapy without GVHD prophylaxis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>HLA-mismatched MST vs HLA-matched NST for AML in Intermediate-risk</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The optimal therapy for intermediate-risk patients with acute myeloid leukemia (AML) in first complete remission (CR1) is uncertain. Recent studies shown that microtransplantation (MST) can improve survival in AML-CR1 patients. However, a comparison study between the MST and nonmyeloablative stem cell transplantation (NST) is lacking. 156 intermediate-risk AML-CR1 patients aged 9 to 59 years were enrolled in this study. Patients with de novo AML enrolled in the study. Patient who has a HLA-identical donor is assigned to receive NST therapy with GVHD prophylaxis and who has no HLA-identical donor is assigned to receive MST therapy without GVHD prophylaxis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antilymphocyte Serum</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have elderly (959 ages) AML pathologically confirmed per WHO guidelines. Patients WITH intermediaterisk AMLCR1 Patients must have ECOG Performance status of 0,1,or 2. If ECOG 2. Patients must have a HLA mismatched donor who should be able to provide informed consent. All genders and races are eligible. ALT and AST≤3 ×ULN, TBIL≤1.5 × ULN, Cr≤2 ×ULN or CrCl≥40 mL/min By means of ultrasonic Heartbeat map or multiple gated acquisition (MUGA) scanning determination of LVEF in the normal range. Donors must be able to safely undergo leukapheresis. received operation 4 weeks before randomization acute promyelocytic leukemia,Myeloid sarcoma, chronic myeloid leukemia in accelerated phase and blastic phase; active CNS disease, pregnancy, or other major medical or psychiatric illnesses that could compromise tolerance to this protocol Require the use of warfarin or equivalent of vitamin K antagonists (such as phenprocoumon) anticoagulant. There is clinical significance of cardiovascular disease, such as uncontrolled or symptomatic arrhythmias, congestive heart failure or myocardial infarction within 6 months before randomization, or any heart function grade 3 (moderate) or 4 (severe ) heart disease in accordance with the functional classification method of New York Heart Association (NYHA). Known to have the following history: human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or active hepatitis C virus or hepatitis B virus infection Any situation processed by the PI that will be damaged to the patients safety. Patients and / or authorized family member refuse to sign the consent. attend other clinical researchers in 3 months. Donors exclusion criteria include:active infection or malignancy, cardiovascular instability, severe anemia, severe coagulation disorder, pregnancy, inadequate venous access, inability to provide consent, or any other condition deemed unsafe by the treatment staff.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>9 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>59 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute Myeloid Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>microtransplantationHLA-mismatched microtransplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>nonmyeloablative stem cell transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>graft-versus-host disease</keyword>
</DOC>