<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02461667</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a 9 month randomised controlled clinical comparing the clinical efficacy of 1%metformin and 1%alendronate in chronic periodontitis subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Alendronate Compared to Metformin in Chronic Periodontitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>ABSTRACT Background: Since Metformin (MF) induces osteoblast growth and differentiation while Alendronate (ALN) act as an antiosteolytic agent. The aim of the present study is to evaluate and compare the efficacy of 1% ALN and 1% MF gel as a local drug delivery system in adjunct to scaling and root planing (SRP) for the treatment of intrabony defects in patients with chronic periodontitis. Methods: The study had 3 groups comprising of ninety subjects, divided into three groups 1% MF with SRP, 1% ALN with SRP and placebo gel with SRP. Clinical parameters (plaque index (PI), modified sulcus bleeding index (mSBI), probing pocket depth (PPD), and clinical attachment level (CAL) were recorded at baseline, 3, 6 and 9 months. Radiographic parameters intrabony defect depth (IBD) and defect depth reduction (DDR%) was calculated on standardized radiographs by using image analysis software at 6 and 9 months</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alendronate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All the subjects were systemically healthy subjects with sites having CAL ≥ 3 mm, PPD ≥ 5 mm, vertical bone loss ≥ 3 mm on intraoral periapical radiographs (IOPA) and subjects with no history of periodontal intervention in the last 6 months. patients with systemic diseases like cardiovascular disease diabetes or HIV infection or on medications like corticosteroids which may impede the healing in periodontal tissues. pregnant/lactating females tobacco users alcoholics patients with unsatisfactory oral hygiene (plaque index greater than 1.5) teeth having gingival recession, caries involving pulp, intrabony defect present interproximally, grade 2/3 mobility Furthermore, patients allergic to Metformin and alendronate or those taking Metformin and alendronate systemically were excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>alendronate, metformin</keyword>
</DOC>