<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00000999</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To obtain information about the long-term safety and toxicity of zidovudine (AZT). To ascertain whether interruption/resumption at a lower dosage is the optimal management of AZT toxicity. Because of the high incidence of toxicity and the relatively short-term follow-up of the patients due to the early ending of the Phase II placebo-controlled experiment, it is valuable to continue to get information on the long-term toxicity of AZT.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Safety and Effectiveness of Zidovudine (AZT) in the Treatment of HIV Infection in Patients With AIDS and Advanced ARC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Because of the high incidence of toxicity and the relatively short-term follow-up of the patients due to the early ending of the Phase II placebo-controlled experiment, it is valuable to continue to get information on the long-term toxicity of AZT. This study provides AZT for 6 months to AIDS patients who were previously enrolled in the AZT Treatment IND protocol and to patients who qualify for AZT under the drug labeling. Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 regimens for management of toxicity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zidovudine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Concurrent Medication: Allowed: For fever control and mild analgesia, modest doses of aspirin or nonprescription doses of ibuprofen may be used with caution; prolonged (&gt; 72 hours) administration is not advised without dose supervision. Patients must have a documented history of positive HIV antibody by ELISA, or positive result by ELISA at study entry and be in one of the following categories: AIDS patients recovered from one or more episodes of categorically confirmed Pneumocystis carinii pneumonia (PCP) who were previously enrolled in the zidovudine (AZT) treatment IND protocol. Patients who qualify for AZT under the labeling: (a) patients with a prior episode of cytologically confirmed PCP; (b) patients with a prior episode of any other AIDS defining opportunistic infection and &lt; 200 T4 cells; (c) patients with advanced AIDS related complex (ARC) as defined by the clinical diagnosis of mucocutaneous candidiasis and/or unexplained weight loss (= or &gt; 15 lbs or &gt; 10 percent of total body weight within the previous 3 months) and &lt; 200 T4 cells and one or more of the following symptoms: (1) fever &gt; 100 degrees F without infectious cause of &gt; 3 weeks duration; (2) clinical diagnosis of hairy leukoplakia; (3) herpes zoster infection within 3 months of entry; (4) unexplained diarrhea after 3 samples eliminating ova, parasites, cryptosporidia, and Mycobacterium aviumintracellulare. Note: Kaposi's sarcoma without any of the symptoms listed above, regardless of total T4 lymphocyte count, does not constitute an indication for AZT treatment under the labeling. Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients whose symptoms do not fit into the categories described in Disease Status and General Inclusion Criteria are excluded. Concurrent Medication: Excluded: Acetaminophen.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS-Related Complex</keyword>
	<keyword>Zidovudine</keyword>
</DOC>