<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00000823</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To determine the relative antiviral activity and safety of zidovudine ( AZT ) and didanosine ( ddI ) alone and in combination, as well as in various sequences of administration. The relative efficacy of the approved antiretrovirals in early HIV-1 disease is unclear; thus, a study is needed to evaluate the ability of these various nucleoside analogs to limit pathogenicity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Multicenter Phase II Double-Blind Exploratory Study to Evaluate Differences Among Various Zidovudine/Didanosine Regimens on Quantitative Measures of Viral Burden in Relatively Early HIV-1 Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The relative efficacy of the approved antiretrovirals in early HIV-1 disease is unclear; thus, a study is needed to evaluate the ability of these various nucleoside analogs to limit pathogenicity. Patients undergo observation for 2 weeks, then are randomized to one of six treatment arms to receive ddI alone or in sequence or combination with AZT for 16-32 weeks, followed by 4 weeks of post-treatment evaluation. The regimens are: ddI alone for 32 weeks; AZT for 16 weeks followed by ddI for 16 weeks; AZT for 16 weeks followed by AZT/ddI combination for 16 weeks; ddI for 16 weeks followed by AZT for 16 weeks; AZT/ddI combination for 32 weeks; and placebo for 32 weeks. PER AMENDMENT 6/18/96: NOTE: Patients enrolled under version 3 of the study will terminate treatment at week 16 and have a 4 week follow up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Didanosine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zidovudine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients must have: HIV1 seropositivity. CD4 count &gt;= 550 cells/mm3. Asymptomatic disease. No prior antiretroviral therapy. Consent of parent or guardian if less than 18 years old. PER AMENDMENT 6/18/96: Patients with an undocumented history of oral candidiasis or a history of candidiasis that was antibiotic associated may enroll. Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following symptoms or conditions are excluded: Medical condition that precludes study compliance. Concurrent Medication: Excluded: Antiretrovirals other than study drugs. Biologic response modifiers including erythropoietin and GCSF. Systemic corticosteroids. Systemic cytotoxic chemotherapy. Intravenous pentamidine. Concurrent Treatment: Excluded: Systemic radiation therapy. Patients with the following prior conditions are excluded: History of grade 2 or worse peripheral neuropathy. History of pancreatitis or factors predisposing to pancreatitis. Prior Medication: Excluded: Prior antiretrovirals. Systemic immunomodulators (e.g., gp120, gp160, IL2, interferons) within 3 months prior to study entry. Chronic alcoholism.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Didanosine</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy, Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>Zidovudine</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Administration Schedule</keyword>
</DOC>