<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00000833</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To compare the safety, toxicity, and tolerance of two doses of ribavirin in combination with didanosine (ddI) to HIV-infected children. To determine the toxicity of ddI/ribavirin and compare it to the expected toxicity of ddI monotherapy. To determine the effect of concurrent ribavirin on the pharmacokinetics of ddI. To determine a dosage of ribavirin that would be suitable for a Phase II/III evaluation of ddI/ribavirin. Ribavirin, a broad spectrum antiviral agent, may enhance the antiretroviral activity of didanosine ( ddI ) without a concomitant increase in toxicity. Ribavirin alters the intracellular metabolism of ddI, enhancing the antiretroviral activity of the active form of ddI.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase I Study of Combination Therapy With Didanosine (ddI) and Ribavirin in HIV-Infected Children.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Ribavirin, a broad spectrum antiviral agent, may enhance the antiretroviral activity of didanosine ( ddI ) without a concomitant increase in toxicity. Ribavirin alters the intracellular metabolism of ddI, enhancing the antiretroviral activity of the active form of ddI. Patients are divided into two cohorts. Subjects will be stratified by age 3 months to &lt; 24 months and &gt;= 24 months to 12 years. Fifty % of patients from each age group will be assigned to each cohort. Cohort 1 receives ddI monotherapy for 4 weeks, followed by combination ddl/ribavirin therapy for an additional 20 weeks. Cohort 2 receives combination ddI/ribavirin for 24 weeks. In both cohorts, after study medications are stopped, patients are treated with prescription antiretrovirals for 4 more weeks. [AS PER AMENDMENT 7/2/96: Note: In each cohort of 10 subjects at least 2 of 5 children from the older half of the cohort will have an ICD p24 antigen at entry.]</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Didanosine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Concurrent Medication: Recommended: PCP prophylaxis. Allowed: Acetaminophen for no more than 72 hours. Immunoglobulin. Corticosteroids. Erythropoietin. GCSF and GMCSF. Ethionamide or isoniazid for TB if no alternative available. Immunizations according to current recommendations. Patients must have: HIV infection. Immunologic abnormality or clinical symptoms as detailed in the Disease Status field. No active AIDSdefining opportunistic infection or malignancy, no progressive encephalopathy attributable to HIV and no chronic persistent diarrhea. Consent of parent or guardian. PER AMENDMENT 7/2/96: At least 2 of the 5 children in the older half of each cohort must have an ICD p24 antigen concentration &gt;= 70 pg/ml at screening. Prior Medication: Allowed: Up to 6 weeks of prior immunomodulator therapy. Maternal immunomodulator or antiretroviral therapy, including during pregnancy. Prior corticosteroids or intravenous immunoglobulin. Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following symptoms or conditions are excluded: Current grade 3 or worse neuropathy/lower motor neuropathy. Clinical or laboratory grade 3 or worse toxicities. Active serious bacterial infection. Concurrent Medication: Excluded: Chemotherapy for active malignancy. Antiretrovirals other than study drugs. Immunomodulators unless specifically allowed. Patients with the following prior condition are excluded: History of grade 3 or worse neuropathy/lower motor neuropathy. Prior Medication: Excluded: Prior ddI or oral ribavirin. Aerosolized ribavirin within 6 weeks prior to study entry. Antiretroviral or immunomodulator therapy (other than corticosteroids or IVIG) within 1 week prior to blood draws for study entry. Ongoing drug or alcohol abuse.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ribavirin</keyword>
	<keyword>Didanosine</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy, Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS-Related Complex</keyword>
	<keyword>Antiviral Agents</keyword>
</DOC>