<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01528150</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this observational study is the assessment (safety and efficacy) of the St. Jude Medical Tendril MRI™ leads. The Tendril MRI™ leads are a full part of the Accent MRI™ System, consisting of Tendril MRI™ leads and Accent MRI™ pacemaker. The subject population includes patients with a standard bradycardia pacing indication.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of Tendril MRI™ Leads in Standard Bradycardia Pacing Indication</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is a diagnostic method to view high quality two and three dimensional images of the body. However, magnetic resonance imaging systems generate three electromagnetic fields that are used to produce an image. These include a static magnetic field, a time varying gradient magnetic field, and a radiofrequency field. All three of these fields interact with implanted devices and could create hazards for the device, the patient, or both. Due to these issues, currently marketed pacemaker systems may be contraindicated for use in an MRI environment. St. Jude Medical has developed a system, the Accent MRI™ system, comprised of the Accent MRI™ device and the Tendril MRI™ lead, and an investigational MRI Activator™, designed to mitigate such interactions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Bradycardia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Approved Class I or Class II indication per: European Society of Cardiology (ESC) guidelines for implantation of a dual chamber pacemaker or single chamber pacemaker, OR American College of Cardiology (ACC) / American Heart Association (AHA) / Heart Rhythm Society (HRS) guidelines for implantation of a dual chamber pacemaker or single chamber pacemaker Require a new Accent MRI™ pacemaker and Tendril MRI™ lead (either initial implant or complete system change out with no abandoned devices). Is ≥ 18 years of age. Able to provide written informed consent prior to any investigational related procedure. Willing and able to comply with the prescribed followup tests and schedule of evaluations. Have an existing pacemaker or ICD (abandoned devices and/or leads are not allowed. A new pacemaker and lead or complete system change out is required for enrollment). Have an existing active implanted medical device (e.g., Implantable Cardioverter Defibrillator (ICD), neurostimulator, etc.). Have a nonMRI compatible device or material implant (e.g., intracranial aneurysm clip, nonMRI compatible devices or material, metals or alloys, etc.). Have a lead extender, plug or adaptor. Have a prosthetic tricuspid heart valve. Are currently participating in another investigational device or drug investigation. Are allergic to Dexamethasone sodium phosphate (DSP). Are pregnant or planning to become pregnant during the duration of the study. Have a life expectancy of less than 12 months from Screening due to any lifethreatening condition</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>