<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01528761</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this 12-month study is to compare how well two programs help older adults make physical activity a regular habit.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prosocial Behavior and Volunteerism to Promote Physical Activity in Older Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Although only a small percentage of older adults engage in habitual physical activity, previous studies have demonstrated interventions that include cognitive-behavioral strategies can enhance long-term, independent physical activity. In addition, there are episodic charity events, such as charity walks, that attract large numbers of participants of all age ranges to engage in moderate-intensity physical activity. These actions are a form of prosocial behavior, defined as voluntary, intentional behavior that results in benefits for another. The opportunity to help others seems to be a motive in inspiring these individuals to at least engage in one session of moderate physical activity. Thus, the current research project contemplates whether prosocial behavior may be implemented as a viable behavioral incentive for long-term physical activity. Participants in the Prosocial Behavior Physical Activity (PBPA) intervention will receive a cognitive-behavioral intervention to teach participants the behavioral skills necessary to engage in long-term (12-month) independent physical activity. Participants in the Healthy Aging (HA) intervention will receive excellent educational sessions based on a number of topics of relevance to older adults. Both programs will provide supervised stretching sessions so that participants learn how to safely and effectively improve flexibility, which helps reduce the likelihood of falls and disability. However, the PBPA intervention will also allow participants to earn food for donation to Second Harvest Food Bank based on their regular physical activity and volunteer time.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>age 55 years or older physically underactive no evidence of any major psychological illness residence within 20 miles of study site plans to remain in area for duration of study currently engaging in regular physical activity selfreported evidence of cardiovascular disease selfreported evidence of diabetes selfreported falling within the past year alcohol consumption greater than 14 drinks per week inability to understand English plans to move from area participation in another medical intervention study severe hearing or sight impairments</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>older adults</keyword>
	<keyword>physical function</keyword>
	<keyword>health-related quality of life</keyword>
	<keyword>prosocial behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>social cognitive theory</keyword>
</DOC>