<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02725099</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To examine chewing versus traditional oral administration of ticagrelor in ST-elevation Myocardial Infarction (STEMI) patients on platelet reactivity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chewing Versus Traditional Oral Administration of Ticagrelor in STEMI Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ticagrelor</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients presenting with STEMI 2. Informed, written consent 1. Age &lt; 18 years or Age &gt; 90 years 2. Active bleeding; bleeding diathesis; coagulopathy 3. Increased risk of bradycardic events 4. History of gastrointestinal or genitourinary bleeding &lt;2 months 5. Major surgery in the last 6 weeks 6. History of intracranial bleeding or structural abnormalities 7. Suspected aortic dissection 8. Any other condition that may put the patient at risk or influence study results or investigator's opinion (severe hemodynamic instability, unconsciousness, known malignancies or other comorbid conditions with life expectancy &lt;1 year) 9. Administration in the week before the index event of clopidogrel, ticlopidine, prasugrel, ticagrelor, thrombolytics, bivalirudin, lowmolecular weight heparin or fondaparinux. 10. Concomitant oral or IV therapy with strong CYP3A inhibitors or strong CYP3A inducers, CYP3A with narrow therapeutic windows 11. Known relevant hematological deviations: Hb &lt;10 g/dl, PLT&lt;100x10^9/l 12. Use of coumadin derivatives within the last 7 days 13. Chronic therapy with ticagrelor, prasugrel, clopidogrel or ticlopidine 14. Known severe liver disease, severe renal failure 15. Known allergy to the study medications 16. Pregnancy 17. Human immunodeficiency virus treatment 18. The use of IIBIIIA receptor antagonists in the 48 hours before enrollment (if abciximab use then in the last 14 days). 19. If the patients cannot sign percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) informed consent for any reason.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>STEMI</keyword>
</DOC>