<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02725580</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The proposed clinical trial is the first human, open-label, single dose study of self-complementary AAV9 carrying the CLN6 gene delivered one-time intrathecally inserted by a lumbar puncture into Batten CLN6 Disease subjects. One cohort of patients with Batten CLN6 Disease, with confirmed diagnosis, will undergo gene transfer. A minimum of six patients will be enrolled into the cohort.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Batten CLN6 Gene Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The proposed clinical trial is the first human, open-label, single dose study of self-complementary AAV9 carrying the CLN6 gene under the control of a hybrid CMV enhancer/chicken-β-actin promoter (scAAV9.CB.CLN6) delivered one-time through an intrathecal catheter inserted by a lumbar puncture into the interspinous into the subarachnoid space of the lumbar thecal sac. All six patients will receive a dose equivalent to (1.5 x10^13 vg/kg). This will be administered premixed with 2.5 mL of the contrast Omnipaque™ at a concentration of 180 mgI/mL of the contrast via a 10 mL syringe and a Spinal Needle. If no clinically significant improvement without toxicity is observed, the possibility of adding an additional escalation cohort at a higher dose will be discussed with the FDA, DSMB and relevant oversight regulatory agencies.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neuronal Ceroid-Lipofuscinoses</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of CLN6 disease determined by genotype available at sScreening Quantitative clinical assessment of the Hamburg motorlanguage aggregate score at Screening on CLN2 disease motorlanguage scale, as defined in the Ratings Assessment Guideline. Age ≥1 year Written informed consent from parent or legal guardian and assent from subject, if appropriate. Ability to comply with protocol required assessments (laboratory sample collection, EEG, ECG, MRI, etc. Another inherited neurologic disease, e.g., other forms of CLN or seizures unrelated to CLN2 disease (patients with febrile seizures may be eligible) Another neurological illness that may have caused cognitive decline (e.g., trauma, meningitis, hemorrhage) before screening Active viral infection Has received stem cell or bone marrow transplantation for CLN6 disease Contraindications for spinal tap procedure (e.g., spina bifida, meningitis, impairment, or clotting abnormalities) Contraindications for MRI scans (e.g., cardiac pacemaker, metal fragment or chip in the eye, aneurysm clip in the brain) Episode of generalized motor status epilepticus within 4 weeks before the First Dose visit Severe infection (e.g., pneumonia, pyelonephritis, or meningitis) within 4 weeks before the First Dose visit (enrollment may be postponed) Has received any investigational medication within 30 days before the first infusion of study drug Patients with AntiAAV9 antibody titers ≥ 1:1600 as determined by ELISA binding immunoassay. Has a medical condition or extenuating circumstance that, in the opinion of the investigator, might compromise the subject's ability to comply with the protocol required testing or procedures or compromise the subject's wellbeing, safety, or clinical interpretability Pregnancy any time during the study; a female subject judged by the investigator to be of childbearing potential will be tested for pregnancy Abnormal laboratory values considered clinically significant (GGT &gt; 3XULN, Bilirubin ≥ 3.0 mg/dL , Creatinine ≥ 1.8 mg/dL, Hgb &lt; 8 or &gt; 18 g/Dl; WBC &gt; 15,000 per cmm)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neuronal ceroid lipofuscinosis</keyword>
	<keyword>NCL</keyword>
	<keyword>Gene Transfer</keyword>
	<keyword>Gray Foundation</keyword>
</DOC>