<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01910389</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a multi-center, prospective, randomized, double blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Subjects in the study will be adults with New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class II-IV heart failure (HF) due to left ventricular systolic dysfunction (LVSD), left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt;0.40, and secondary pulmonary hypertension (PH). The purpose of the study is to evaluate the safety, effectiveness, and effects of tadalafil compared to placebo on the subjects' functional capacity / quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phosphodiesterase Type 5 Inhibition With Tadalafil Changes Outcomes in Heart Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tadalafil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female age 21 years or older. NYHA Class IIIV HF with LVSD (most recent LVEF &lt; 0.40). At high risk of future clinical instability, indicated by EITHER: a hospitalization for the primary reason of decompensated HF within the 12 months prior to screening; OR a plasma Btype Natriuretic Peptide (BNP) level ≥ 300 pg/ml or Nterminal prohormone of brain natriuretic peptide (NTproBNP) ≥1800pg/ml measured during a period of clinical stability in the 3 months prior to screening. Documented secondary PH within the last 6 months Medication and device treatment according to current American Heart Association/American College of Cardiology (AHA/ACC) guidelines. Stable medical therapy for 30 days prior to randomization AfricanAmerican patients intolerant of or otherwise unable or unwilling to utilize isosorbide dinitrate/hydralazine therapy will be included. Willingness to comply with protocol, attend followup appointments, complete all study assessments and provide written informed consent. Concurrent or anticipated nitrate use for any reason, or nitrate use within the 14 days prior to screening through the day of randomization. Known allergy, hypersensitivity (anaphylaxis), or adverse reaction to tadalafil or other Phosphodiesterase Type 5 (PDE5) inhibitor Erectile dysfunction treated with a PDE5 inhibitor. Severe renal dysfunction defined as an estimated glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt; 30 ml/min/1.73 m^2 or requiring chronic dialysis Current use of alpha antagonists (except carvedilol or tamsulosin) or use of cytochrome P450 3A4 inhibitors (ketoconazole, itraconazole, erythromycin, or cimetidine). Patients who have used a protease inhibitor that is a P450 3A4 inhibitor for longer than one week can be enrolled. Pulmonary arterial hypertension (World Health Organization (WHO) Group I, IIIV) for which PDE5 inhibitor therapy may be indicated Severe pulmonary disease requiring home oxygen therapy Comorbidities including clinically significant valvular stenosis (aortic valve area &lt; 0.8 cm^2 or a mitral valve area &lt;1.0 cm^2), uncontrolled hypertension (systolic blood pressure ≥180 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure ≥100 mmHg) or hypotension (systolic blood pressure &lt;85 mmHg) Chronic intravenous inotrope therapy Nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy (NAION) ST elevation MI (STEMI) within 90 days prior to screening Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting (CABG) or mitral valve surgery, initiation of cardiac resynchronization (CRT) or initiation of βblocker therapy within the 6 months prior to screening Infiltrative or inflammatory myocardial disease (e.g. amyloid, sarcoid) Heart transplant recipient United Network Organ Sharing (UNOS) status 1A or 1B Mechanical circulatory support (MCS) use or planned MCS use at time of consent Active malignancy (except nonmelanoma skin cancer) requiring therapy other than observation. Severe noncardiac illness resulting in life expectancy judged less than three years Known chronic hepatic disease defined as aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine transaminase (ALT) levels &gt; 3.0 times the upper limit of normal Inability to walk even a few steps due to noncardiac (e.g. orthopedic) reasons Participation in any clinical trial within the last 30 days (with exception of observational study) Previous randomization in PITCHHF</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Heart failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulmonary hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>tadalafil</keyword>
	<keyword>Phosphodiesterase Type 5 Inhibition</keyword>
</DOC>