<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00398060</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Life-style change achieved in controlled experimental condition has been shown to prevent type 2 diabetes. The purpose of this study is to evaluate to what extent the life-style change can be achieved in a routine health care setting.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>GOAL Life-Style Change Intervention to Prevent Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The GOAL (Good Ageing in Lahti region) Program Life-style change implementation trial to prevent type 2 diabetes was set to examine and enhance the effectiveness of life-style change counselling in the primary health care. In the intervention, specific nutritional, physical activity and weight loss objectives shown effective in diabetes prevention in an earlier randomised controlled trial are used as a benchmark, embedded in a structured group counselling model with an empowerment-oriented approach and adapted into the primary health care setting. In the trial, effectiveness and process are evaluated, the analyses including gender and socio-economic differences. Participants were 361 middle-aged (50-65 yrs) adults at an increased risk for type 2 diabetes, recruited in 16 primary health care centres in Paijat-Hame, Finland. Intervention and data collection took place in year 2003.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 2 diabetes risk test score &gt; 11 (Lindstrom &amp; Tuomilehto, 2003) mental health problem or substance abuse likely to interfere with participation acute cancer type 2 diabetes requiring pharmacological treatment myocardial infarction during the past six months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>life-style counseling</keyword>
	<keyword>type 2 diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>prediabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>diet</keyword>
	<keyword>cognitive-behavioral</keyword>
</DOC>