<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00398385</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as gemcitabine and cisplatin, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Giving chemotherapy before surgery may make the tumor smaller and reduce the amount of normal tissue that needs to be removed. Giving chemotherapy after surgery may kill any tumor cells that remain after surgery. It is not yet known whether giving chemotherapy before surgery is more effective than giving it after surgery in treating non-small cell lung cancer. PURPOSE: This randomized phase II trial is studying gemcitabine and cisplatin to compare how well they work when given before or after surgery in treating patients with stage I or stage II non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gemcitabine and Cisplatin Before or After Surgery in Treating Patients With Stage I or Stage II Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Compare the time to recurrence in patients with stage IB or II non-small cell lung cancer treated with neoadjuvant versus adjuvant gemcitabine hydrochloride and cisplatin. Secondary - Compare overall survival of patients treated with these regimens. - Compare the toxicity of these regimens in these patients. - Compare quality of life of these patients. - Compare the complete resection rate with and without neoadjuvant gemcitabine hydrochloride and cisplatin. OUTLINE: This is a randomized study. Patients are stratified by disease stage (IB vs II) and histology (squamous cell carcinoma vs nonsquamous cell carcinoma). Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. - Arm I (neoadjuvant chemotherapy): Patients receive gemcitabine hydrochloride IV over 30 minutes and cisplatin IV over 30 minutes on days 1 and 15. Treatment repeats every 4 weeks for up to 4 courses in the absence of disease recurrence or unacceptable toxicity. Within 8 weeks after initiating course 4 of chemotherapy, patients undergo complete surgical resection. - Arm II (adjuvant chemotherapy): Patients undergo complete surgical resection. Beginning within 8 weeks after complete surgical resection, patients receive gemcitabine hydrochloride IV and cisplatin IV as in arm I. Quality of life is assessed at baseline and periodically for up to 5 years. After completion of study therapy, patients are followed periodically for at least 5 years or until disease recurrence. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 170 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC) Squamous cell or nonsquamous cell histology Stage IB or II disease Tumor amenable to curative surgical resection PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: ECOG performance status 01 Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 6 months after completion of study therapy Medical fitness must be adequate for radical NSCLC surgery WBC ≥ 4,000/mm³ Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mm³ Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm³ Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dL Bilirubin normal ALT and AST ≤ 2.5 times upper limit of normal Creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL No second primary malignancy No active uncontrolled infection No concurrent serious disorder that would compromise patient safety or tolerance of study therapy No significant neurological or mental disorder No myocardial infarction within the past 6 months No symptomatic heart disease, including any of the following: Unstable angina Congestive heart failure Uncontrolled arrhythmia PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: No prior chemotherapy or anticancer therapy No prior surgery for NSCLC No prior or concurrent radiotherapy or immunotherapy (e.g., biologic response modifier) No major surgery (other than biopsy) within the past 2 weeks No other concurrent anticancer therapy No other concurrent investigational agents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>squamous cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma of the lung</keyword>
	<keyword>adenosquamous cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>bronchoalveolar cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>large cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IB non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIA non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIB non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>