<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02655822</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase 1/1b open-label, multicenter, dose-selection study of CPI-444, an oral small molecule targeting the adenosine-A2A receptor on T-lymphocytes and other cells of the immune system. This trial will study the safety, tolerability, and anti-tumor activity of CPI-444 as a single agent and in combination with atezolizumab, a PD-L1 inhibitor against various solid tumors. CPI-444 blocks adenosine from binding to the A2A receptor. Adenosine suppresses the anti-tumor activity of T cells and other immune cells.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 1/1b Study to Evaluate the Safety and Tolerability of CPI-444 Alone and in Combination With Atezolizumab in Advanced Cancers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase 1/1b open-label, multicenter, dose-selection study of CPI-444, an oral small molecule targeting the adenosine-A2A receptor on T-lymphocytes and other cells of the immune system. This trial will study the safety, tolerability, and anti-tumor activity of CPI-444 as a single agent and in combination with atezolizumab, an intravenous PD-L1 inhibitor. CPI-444 blocks adenosine from binding to the A2A receptor. Adenosine suppresses the anti-tumor activity of T cells and other immune cells.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triple Negative Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 1. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status 01. 2. Documented incurable cancer with one of the following histologies: nonsmall cell lung cancer, malignant melanoma, renal cell cancer, triple negative breast cancer, colorectal cancer with microsatellite instability (MSI), and bladder cancer. 3. At least 1 measurable lesion per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST 1.1). 4. At least 1 but not more than 5 prior systemic therapies for advanced/recurrent or progressing disease. Exclusion Criteria 1. History of severe hypersensitivity reaction to monoclonal antibodies. 2. Any active autoimmune disease or a documented history of serious autoimmune disease within the past 5 years requiring immunosuppressive therapy. 3. History of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, organizing pneumonia, druginduced pneumonitis, idiopathic pneumonitis, or clinical symptoms of active pneumonitis. 4. The use of any investigational medication or device in the 30 days prior to screening and throughout the study is prohibited. 5. If a patient is currently receiving denosumab, this must be discontinued prior to enrollment. Substitution with biphosphonates are acceptable.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
	<keyword>MEL</keyword>
	<keyword>RCC</keyword>
	<keyword>TNBC</keyword>
	<keyword>Triple Negative Breast Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>CRC</keyword>
	<keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Colon Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Rectal Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>