<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02655601</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1/2 study of newly diagnosed patients with high grade glioma (HGG) undergoing standard radiation therapy and temozolomide treatment. BMX-001 added to radiation therapy and temozolomide has the potential not only to benefit the survival of high grade glioma patients but also to protect against deterioration of cognition and impairment of quality of life. In Phase 1 safety and tolerability of BMX-001 will be assessed using a two-stage Continual Reassessment Method (CRM). BMX-001 will be given subcutaneously first with a loading dose zero to four days prior to the start of chemoradiation and followed by twice a week doses at one-half of the loading dose for the duration of radiation therapy plus two weeks. In Phase 2 both safety and efficacy of BMX-001 will be evaluated. Impact on cognition will also be assessed. Twenty-four patients will be randomized to the treatment arm that will receive BMX-001 while undergoing chemoradiation and 24 patients randomized to receive chemoradiation alone. The investigators hypothesize that BMX-001 when added to standard radiation therapy and temozolomide will be safe at pharmacologically relevant doses in patients with newly diagnosed high grade glioma. The investigators also hypothesize that in Phase 2 of this study, the addition of BMX-001 will positively impact the overall survival and improve objective measures of cognition in newly diagnosed high grade glioma patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial of Newly Diagnosed High Grade Glioma Treated With Concurrent Radiation Therapy, Temozolomide and BMX-001</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must have histologically confirmed diagnosis of World Health Organization (WHO) grade III or IV malignant glioma Subjects must be planning to start standard of care radiation therapy and chemotherapy Subjects must be within 12 weeks of last major neurosurgical procedure for the highgrade glioma (craniotomy, open biopsy, or stereotactic biopsy) Subjects must have had a definitive resection with residual radiographic contrast enhancement on postresection CT or MRI of less than or equal to 2 cm in any two perpendicular planes on any images Age * 18 years Karnofsky Performance Status (KPS) ≥ 70% Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dl, absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1,500 cells/µl, platelets ≥ 125,000 cells/µl Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dl, serum glutamate oxaloacetate transaminase (SGOT) and bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal Signed informed consent approved by the Institutional Review Board If sexually active, patients must agree to use appropriate contraceptive measures for the duration of the study and for 12 months afterwards as stated in the informed consent Stable and/or decreasing dose of corticosteroids for greater than or equal to 7 days. Pregnancy or breastfeeding Active infection requiring IV antibiotics 7 days before enrollment Signs of woundhealing problems or infection at the craniotomy/biopsy site. Prior, unrelated malignancy requiring current active treatment with the exception of cervical carcinoma in situ and adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin Comedication that may interfere with study results; e.g. immunosuppressive agents other than corticosteroids Prior treatment with radiotherapy or chemotherapy for a brain tumor, irrespective of the grade of the tumor Evidence of &gt; grade 1 CNS hemorrhage on baseline MRI on CT scan Systemic treatment with inducers or strong inhibitors of cytochrome P450 within four days before enrollment or planned treatment during the time period of the study. Metal in the body (except dental fillings) e.g., pacemaker, infusion pump, metal aneurysm clip, metal prosthesis, joint, rod or plate. Severe allergy to contrast agent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>