<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02001363</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators planned to research the cardioprotective effects of intravenous liraglutide on reperfusion injury.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Study of Glucagonlike Peptide-1 to Treat Reperfusion Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Acute myocardial infarction is a major cause of mortality and morbidity. Primary percutaneous coronary intervention (pPCI) is currently the most effective treatment strategy in acute myocardial infarction. However, a sizable number of patients fail to restore optimal myocardial reperfusion, mostly because of the 'no-reflow' phenomenon. Glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) is an incretin hormone that regulates plasma glucose, and recently GLP-1 analogues have been introduced for the treatment of type-2 diabetes. In experimental studies, GLP-1 or its analogues protect against reperfusion injury-induced cell death. Exenatide reduces reperfusion injury in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction. Liraglutide(GLP-1) is safe and effective to reduce weight,serum lipid levels and blood pressure. Liraglutide can reduce cardiac rupture (12 of 60 versus 46 of 60; P=0.0001) and infarct size (21±2% versus 29±3%, P=0.02) and improved cardiac output (12.4±0.6 versus 9.7±0.6 ml/min; P=0.002) in normal and diabetic mice. The investigators planned to research the cardioprotective effects of intravenous liraglutide administered prior to reperfusion and continued after restoration of coronary blood flow in patients with STEMI undergoing pPCI.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Reperfusion Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon-Like Peptide 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients were eligible if they were 18 years or older and presented within 12 h from the onset of symptoms and signs of STsegment elevation myocardial infarction to the catheterization laboratory. The patients were not considered for enrolment if they presented with unconsciousness, cardiogenic shock, hypoglycaemia, diabetic ketoacidosis, previous myocardial infarction, stent thrombosis, known renal insufficiency, or previous coronary artery bypass operation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Reperfusion injury</keyword>
	<keyword>Liraglutide</keyword>
</DOC>