<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02216188</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a follow-up study to assess safety and clinical activity of continued AFFITOPE速 PD01A vaccinations in patients with Parkinson's disease. Patients, who have already participated in AFF008 will be involved and will be receive one boost immunization with AFFITOPE速 PD01A. One study site in Vienna (Austria) will be involved. In addition, up to 8 patients will be offered participation within an untreated control group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Follow-up Study to Assess One Boost Immunization With AFFITOPE速 PD01A With Regard to Safety and Clinical Activity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Prior participation in AFF008 and AFF008E Written informed consent signed and dated by the patient and the caregiver (caregiver is not mandatory) In the investigator's opinion, does not have visual or auditory impairments that would reduce the patients' ability to complete study questionnaires or be unable to receive instructions for these Female patients of childbearing potential are eligible if they use a medically accepted contraceptive method Stable doses of PD medications for at least 3 months prior to Visit 0 and during the entire trial period and of all other medications for at least 30 days prior to Visit 1 if considered relevant by the investigator Women of childbearing potential without birth control or pregnant women Participation in another clinical trial (except AFF008E) within 3 months before Visit 0 History of questionable compliance to visit schedule; patients not expected to complete the clinical trial Autoimmune disease or allergy to components of the vaccine History of cancer (Exceptions: basal cell carcinoma, intraepithelial cervical neoplasia) Active infectious disease Immunodeficiency Significant systemic illness or psychiatric illness Alcoholism or substance abuse Prior treatment with experimental immunotherapeutics for PD including IVIG (with the exception of AFFITOPE 速 PD01A), with immunosuppressive drugs or treatment with deep brain stimulation Venous status rendering it impossible to place an i.v. access</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>68 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>