<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00381069</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to design, implement, and evaluate a recreation site-based obesity prevention &amp; control intervention for 7-9 year old children and their families by targeting physical activity and dietary behaviors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SDSU MOVE/Me Muevo Project</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary aim is to evaluate the effectiveness of a multi-level intervention to prevent the onset of overweight and obesity in 7-9 year old children. The recreation center site intervention emphasizes changes in quantity and quality of physical activity and nutrition-related offerings within the centers. The home site intervention targets the home environment and household rule setting delivered via Family Health Coaches and tailored to the needs of the family. Five hundred forty one (541) families were recruited to participate in this project. Participants were selected in part based on residence in proximity to participating recreation centers. Eighteen (18) families living up to 3 miles from each of the 30 recreation centers involved in the project were be recruited to participate. For each family, one child was recruited between the ages of 5 and 8 years old and this child's primary caregiver was enrolled in the study. The study's primary outcome is Body Mass Index (kg/m2). Comparisons: Control vs. Intervention</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Primary residence within 3 miles of recreation center Children ages 58 at baseline Commit to participate in study for 3 1/2 years Participating parent must be a legal guardian of the child Parent and child must be able to speak and read English or Spanish Willing to be randomly assigned to control or intervention Child has a medical/health/psychological condition or is taking a medication that may impact the child's physical activity, diet or weight to confound BMI Parent or child is unable to read and speak English or Spanish Family plans to move during the next 3 1/2 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Recreation Centers</keyword>
	<keyword>Families</keyword>
	<keyword>Obesity Prevention</keyword>
</DOC>