<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02157181</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will test the effectiveness (rate of complete remissions, total remission rate and duration of remission) and toxicity of the combined immuno/chemotherapy with subcutaneous cladribine (LITAK®) plus anti-CD20* antibody rituximab in patients requiring treatment for relapsed hairy cell leukaemia or hairy cell leukaemia variant independent of any previous therapy. CD20* = cluster of differentiation antigen 20</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Hairy Cell Leukaemia Variant and Relapsing Hairy Cell Leukaemia With Cladribine Plus Rituximab</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The trial is a prospective, multi-centre, open Phase II study on patients with hairy cell leukaemia variant or with relapsed hairy cell leukaemia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Hairy Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>2-chloro-3'-deoxyadenosine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cladribine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with histologically verified hairy cell leukaemia (HCL) Hairy cell leukaemia variant (HCLv) or Relapse of hairy cell leukaemia after therapy with cladribine or pentostatin Need for treatment is indicated (see 4.3 below) Age at least 18 years General state of health according to WHO 02 Written declaration of consent by the patient Current histology, which should not be older than 6 months, is necessary Patients, who do not fulfil the abovementioned inclusion criteria. Patients with severe functional limitations of the heart according to New York Heart Association III / IV, of the lung according to WHO degree III / IV, the liver (bilirubin &gt; 2mg/dl, alkaline phosphatase, raised GOT and GPT (glutamate pyruvate transaminase) values more than twice normal), diseases of the central nervous system, including psychoses. Creatinine &gt; 2 mg/dl, or creatinine clearance &lt; 50 mg/min Patients with proven HIV infections Patients with active hepatitis Patients with other florid infections Patients with anamnesis / diagnosis of another malignant disease (other than nonmelanoma associated skin tumours or stage 0 in situ carcinoma of the cervix) Pregnant or lactating women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>HCL variant</keyword>
	<keyword>HCL relapse</keyword>
	<keyword>Risk stratified</keyword>
</DOC>