<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02891538</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This will be a randomized, controlled pilot trial of patients with histological documentation of primary colon or rectal adenocarcinoma with resectable cancer, who have not received any treatments for cancer. If patient is a candidate for surgical resection, with no planned neoadjuvant chemotherapy, then the patient is eligible. All eligible subjects will be consented prior to surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chemopreventive Effects of Epigallocatechin Gallate (EGCG) in Colorectal Cancer (CRC) Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Part 1: Blood draw prior to surgery, followed by surgical resection, and surgical pathologic specimen will be archived. After surgery, patient will be seen in 4-12 weeks to determine if adjuvant chemotherapy is indicated, in which case patient will receive adjuvant therapy. At this visit a blood draw will be done. Part 2: If the patient is stage 0/1/2 and no plan for adjuvant treatments, then the patient will be randomized in a 2:1 manner to EGCG 900 mg daily vs observation (standard of care) for 1 year. Patients randomized to the EGCG arm, will start EGCG within 4-12 weeks of surgery and take EGCG 450 mg PO twice a day. Blood draw will be done at 0, 3, 6, 9, 12, 15, 18 months. Colonoscopy will be done at 1 year from diagnosis, at which time normal colonic tissue biopsies as well as any resected polyps will be collected.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colonic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epigallocatechin gallate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Cytologically or histologically confirmed of primary colon or rectal adenocarcinoma with resectable cancer, who have not received any treatments for cancer. Age 18 years and above Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 02 The patient is a candidate for surgical resection, with no planned neoadjuvant chemotherapy, and there is a planned surgery for the primary colorectal cancer. For women who are not postmenopausal (12 months of amenorrhea) or surgically sterile (absence of ovaries and/or uterus): agreement to use two adequate methods of contraception. For men: agreement to use a barrier method of contraception during the treatment period Hematologic, Biochemical, and Organ Function within 7 days prior to Cycle 1 Day 1: Granulocyte count &gt; 1000/mm3, Platelet count &gt; 50,000/ mm3, Hemoglobin &gt; 7 g/dL; Total bilirubin &lt; 2.0; Albumin &gt; 2.8g/dl; aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (SGOT) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (SGPT) &lt; 5 x upper limit of normal (ULN); Serum creatinine&lt; 2 x ULN Patients receiving prior chemotherapy. Patients with metastatic disease. Patients may not be receiving any other investigational agents. History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition to green tea or EGCG. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements Gastrointestinal tract disease resulting in an inability to take oral medication or a requirement for IV alimentation, prior surgical procedures affecting absorption, or active peptic ulcer disease. Patients with nasogastric tube (NGtube), Jtube, or Gtube will not be allowed to participate. Pregnant women are excluded from this study because of unknown effects of EGCG on teratogenic or abortifacient effects. For this reason, women of childbearing potential and men must also agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control) prior to study entry and for the duration of study participation. Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while participating in this study, she should inform her treating physician immediately. Because there is an unknown but potential risk for adverse events in nursing infants secondary to treatment of the mother with EGCG, breastfeeding should be discontinued. Informed Consent No study specific procedures will be performed without a written and signed informed consent document. Patients who do not demonstrate the ability to understand or the willingness to sign the written informed consent document will be excluded from study entry.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>EGCG</keyword>
	<keyword>Green Tea</keyword>
	<keyword>Colon Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>