<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02891174</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the effect of routine doses of ibuprofen on post-partum blood pressure control in women with gestational hypertension (gHTN) or preeclampsia without severe features (preE).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Ibuprofen on Post-partum Blood Pressure in Women With Hypertensive Disorders of Pregnancy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) are frequently prescribed for post-partum analgesia. This use is supported by limited data on post-partum pain specifically; however, ibuprofen and other NSAIDs are superior to acetaminophen in ameliorating uterine pain and cramping in dysmenorrhea. The effect of NSAIDs on blood pressure (BP) in women post-partum is less well-known. In non-pregnant hypertensive patients NSAIDs are associated with increased BP over short courses of days to months, though effects of various NSAIDs differ. Pooled analyses suggest changes in mean BP of up to 3-6 mm Hg depending on the measurement method.There are case reports of hypertensive crises after NSAID administration post-partum in both normotensive and hypertensive women. A larger, recent retrospective cohort study found no difference in mean arterial pressure (MAP) or need for antihypertensive therapy in women with severe hypertensive disorders of pregnancy who were exposed to NSAIDs post-partum. In light of the potential for worsening blood pressure in women with hypertensive disorders of pregnancy, the Task Force on Hypertension in Pregnancy of American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists stated that "providers should be reminded of the contribution of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory agents to increased BP." Additionally the task force recommends that NSAIDS "be replaced by other analgesics in women with hypertension that persists for more than 1 day postpartum". However, provider practices since the publication of these guidelines have varied. Hypothesis: When compared to acetaminophen, ibuprofen does not increase post-partum systolic blood pressure (SBP) above baseline to a clinically relevant degree (≥10 mmHg) in women with gHTN and preE. Aim 1: To assess the mean difference in SBP during 24 hours of exposure to ibuprofen and acetaminophen. Aim 2: To assess whether ibuprofen results in higher satisfaction with pain control in the immediate post-partum period (48 hours) compared to acetaminophen. Aim 3: To prospectively assess the need for post-partum anti-hypertensive therapy and readmission for blood pressure control in women with gHTN and preE. The post-partum period is defined as delivery through 6 weeks after delivery.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension, Pregnancy-Induced</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acetaminophen</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ibuprofen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Antepartum women Diagnosis of Gestational Hypertension or Preeclampsia by blood pressure ≥140 systolic or ≥90 diastolic, on at least 2 measurements ≥ 4 hours apart; with or without proteinuria (urine proteincreatinine ratio ≥0.3 or 24 hoururine protein ≥300 mg). Taking one or fewer oral medications for blood pressure control. Singleton gestation. Englishspeaking Allergy to nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs, aspirin, or acetaminophen More than 1 severe range blood pressure (≥160 systolic or ≥110 diastolic) prior to enrollment. Neurologic symptoms attributed to hypertension (headache, visual changes) prior to enrollment. Pulmonary edema. Elevated AST (&gt;60 international units/L) or ALT (&gt;70 international units/L) prior to enrollment. Low platelet count (&lt;100,000/microliter) prior to enrollment. Renal insufficiency (creatinine &gt; 1.1 or double the baseline creatinine if known) prior to enrollment. Chronic hypertension defined as hypertension preexisting pregnancy or diagnosed prior to 20weeks' gestation. Moderate or severepersistent asthma. Therapeutic anticoagulation. Chronic opiate use during the pregnancy (opiate therapy given daily for &gt; 2 weeks). Lactose intolerance or allergy due to placebo containing lactose. Cesarean delivery. Additional anesthesia at time of delivery (spinal anesthesia, sedation) that would change routine pain management.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ibuprofen</keyword>
	<keyword>acetaminophen</keyword>
	<keyword>blood pressure</keyword>
	<keyword>post-partum</keyword>
	<keyword>pain control</keyword>
	<keyword>pre-eclampsia</keyword>
	<keyword>gestational hypertension</keyword>
</DOC>