<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02891161</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open label, multi-institutional, single arm study of a phase Ib study, followed by a phase II study of durvalumab with radiation therapy (RT) in patients with urothelial cancer (UC). No randomization or blinding is involved.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Durvalumab And Radiation Therapy Followed by Adjuvant Durvalumab in Patients With Urothelial Cancer (T2-4 N0-2 M0) of the Bladder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OUTLINE: This is a multi-center study. The phase Ib study will evaluate the safety of combining durvalumab with RT followed by adjuvant durvalumab. The phase II study will estimate the Progression Free Survival (PFS) and Disease Control Rate (DCR) with durvalumab plus RT followed by single agent durvalumab for patients with UC of bladder. PHASE Ib INVESTIGATIONAL TREATMENT: Cohort 1 will consist of up to 6 patients who will receive durvalumab 1500mg 2 doses Q4 weekly with RT to gross disease, 64.8 Gy, 36 fractions on weekdays over about 7 weeks. Durvalumab will start on Day 1 of RT. Three patients will be enrolled initially. If 2 or more patients (out of 3) experience dose-limiting toxicity (DLT), the combined treatment will be considered unsafe. Otherwise, an additional 3 patients will be treated at the same dose. If 0 or 1 patient experience DLT, the dose of durvalumab will be deemed safe for phase 2 part of the study. If, however, 2 or more patients (out of 6) experience DLT, the combined treatment will be considered unsafe. Post-concurrent durvalumab and RT, single agent durvalumab will be given1500mg every 4 weeks (±7 days) for a total period of up to 12 months. Adjuvant durvalumab treatment will be started 3-4 weeks post completion of durvalumab and RT. PHASE II INVESTIGATIONAL TREATMENT: Subjects will receive durvalumab 1500mg 2 doses Q4 weekly with RT to gross disease, 64.8 Gy, 36 fractions on weekdays over about 7 weeks. Durvalumab will start on Day 1 of RT. Post-concurrent durvalumab and RT, single agent durvalumab will be given1500mg every 4 weeks (±7 days) for a total period of up to 12 months. Adjuvant durvalumab treatment will be started 3-4 weeks post completion of durvalumab and RT. Life expectancy of &gt;6 months per treating physician. Adequate organ and marrow function as defined below: 1. Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL 2. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 x 109/L (&gt; 1500 per mm3) 3. Platelet count ≥ 100 x 109/L (&gt;100,000 per mm3) 4. Serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x institutional upper limit of normal (ULN). This will not apply to subjects with confirmed Gilbert's syndrome (persistent or recurrent hyperbilirubinemia that is predominantly unconjugated in the absence of hemolysis or hepatic pathology), who will be allowed only in consultation with their physician. 5. AST (SGOT)/ALT (SGPT) ≤ 2.5 x institutional upper limit of normal unless liver metastases are present, in which case it must be ≤ 5x ULN. 6. Serum creatinine CL&gt;30 mL/min by the Cockcroft-Gault formula (Cockcroft and Gault 1976) or by 24-hour urine collection for determination of creatinine clearance:</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Phase Ib subjects must meet the following inclusion criteria: Locally advanced urothelial cancer of bladder with any of the following: 1. T34, N02 M0, OR Tx N12 M0 OR T2 N12 M0: Treatment naïve, unresectable, OR medically unfit for surgery, OR cisplatin ineligible. T3 N0 M0 patients can be included if they are cisplatin ineligible. 2. Patients who have T34, N02 M0 OR Tx N12 M0 OR T2 N12 M0 postneoadjuvant chemotherapy who become unresectable OR medically unfit for surgery. Phase II subjects must meet the following inclusion criteria: Locally advanced urothelial cancer of bladder with any of the following: 1. T34, N02 M0 OR Tx N12 M0 OR T2 N12 M0: Treatment naïve, unresectable, OR medically unfit for surgery OR cisplatin ineligible. T3 N0 M0 patients can be included if they are cisplatin ineligible. 2. T34, N01 M0 OR Tx N12 M0 OR T2 N12 M0 patients postneoadjuvant chemotherapy who become unresectable OR medically unfit for surgery. T2, N0, M0 who are ineligible to get cisplatin based chemotherapy. All subjects: Written informed consent and HIPAA authorization for personal health information, obtained from the subject prior to performing any protocolrelated procedures, including screening evaluations. NOTE: HIPAA authorization may be included in the informed consent or obtained separately. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 02. Subjects must have undergone maximal TURBT or be able to undergo maximal TURBT (the extent of TURBT may vary for each patient and will be determined by the treating urologist) prior to the start of treatment and tumor tissue must be available at baseline from TURBT (preferred) or LN for testing of PDL1 status. If the potential subject does not have tumor amenable to biopsy or there is insufficient tissue for PDL1 testing, enrollment must be disclosed with the sponsorinvestigator on a case by case basis. Histologically proven urothelial carcinoma of bladder with predominant transitional cell component. Adenocarcinoma, squamous cell differentiation, or other atypical histology (such as plasmacytoid or sarcomotoid) of the bladder will be allowed on the study, provided they form &lt;50% of the histology Females of childbearing potential must have a negative urine and serum pregnancy test within 3 days of study registration. NOTE: Female subjects are considered of child bearing potential unless they are surgically sterile (they have undergone a hysterectomy, bilateral tubal ligation, or bilateral oophorectomy) or they are ≥60 years old and naturally postmenopausal for at least 12 consecutive months. Subject is willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study including undergoing treatment and scheduled visits and examinations including follow up. Involvement in the planning and/or conduct of the study (applies to both AstraZeneca staff and/or staff at the study site). Participation in another clinical study with an investigational product within 2 weeks prior to registration. Any previous treatment with a PD1 or PDL1 inhibitor, including durvalumab. Previous systemic immunotherapy. Previous use of intravesical BCG is acceptable. History of another primary malignancy except for: 1. Malignancy treated with curative intent and with no known active disease ≥5 years before the first dose of study drug and of low potential risk for recurrence. However adequately treated prostate cancer &gt;3 years ago with no significant change in PSA for past 6 months can be included. Patients with a history of prostate cancer must not have any definitive radiation therapy to prostate area. 2. Adequately treated nonmelanoma skin cancer or lentigo maligna without evidence of disease. 3. Adequately treated carcinoma in situ without evidence of disease e.g., cervical cancer in situ. Receipt of the last dose of anticancer therapy (chemotherapy, immunotherapy, endocrine therapy, targeted therapy, biologic therapy, tumor embolization, monoclonal antibodies, other investigational agent) within14 days prior to the first dose of study drug (14 days prior to the first dose of study drug for subjects who have received prior TKIs [e.g., erlotinib, gefitinib and crizotinib] and within 6 weeks for nitrosourea or mitomycin C). Mean QT interval corrected for heart rate (QTc) ≥470 ms on electrocardiogram (ECG) using Frediricia's Correction. Current or prior use of immunosuppressive medication within 28 days before the first dose of durvalumab, with the exceptions of intranasal and inhaled corticosteroids or systemic corticosteroids at physiological doses, which are not to exceed 10 mg/day of prednisone, or an equivalent corticosteroid. Any unresolved toxicity (&gt;CTCAE grade 2) from previous anticancer therapy. (Subjects with irreversible toxicity that is not reasonably expected to be exacerbated by the investigational product may be included (e.g., hearing loss, peripheral neuropathy). Any prior Grade ≥3 immunerelated adverse event (irAE) while receiving any previous immunotherapy agent, or any unresolved irAE &gt;Grade 1. Active or prior documented autoimmune disease within the past 2 years NOTE: Subjects with vitiligo, Grave's disease, or psoriasis not requiring systemic treatment (within the past 2 years) are not excluded. Patients with h/o completely resolved childhood asthma or atopy will not be excluded. Patients with wellcontrolled hypothyroidism on thyroxine replacement will be eligible as well. Active or prior documented inflammatory bowel disease (e.g., Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis). History of and/or confirmed pneumonitis. History of primary immunodeficiency. History of allogeneic organ transplant. History of hypersensitivity to durvalumab or any excipient. History of hypersensitivity to the combination or radiation therapy. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, active peptic ulcer disease or gastritis, active bleeding diatheses including any subject known to have evidence of acute or chronic hepatitis B, hepatitis C or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements or compromise the ability of the subject to give written informed consent. Known history of previous clinical diagnosis of tuberculosis. Receipt of live attenuated vaccination within 30 days prior to study entry or within 30 days of starting treatment with durvalumab. Note: Seasonal influenza vaccines for injection are generally inactivated flu vaccines and are allowed; however intranasal influenza vaccines (e.g., FluMist®) are live attenuated vaccines, and are not allowed. Female subjects who are pregnant, breastfeeding or male or female patients of reproductive potential who are not employing an effective method of birth control. For this study male or female patients of reproductive potential need to employ two highly effective and acceptable forms of contraception throughout their participation in the study and for 90 days after last dose of study drug Any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with evaluation of study treatment or interpretation of patient safety or study results. Brain metastases or history of leptomeningeal carcinomatosis. Subjects with uncontrolled seizures. Previous definitive radiation to pelvic area.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>durvalumab</keyword>
	<keyword>MEDI4736</keyword>
	<keyword>anti-PD-L1</keyword>
</DOC>