<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02891343</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The early assessment of new symptomatic drugs for Alzheimer disease remains difficult because of the lack of predictive end-point. The use of a battery including different parameters could improve this early development. In healthy volunteers, to test the reverse effect of symptomatic drugs, it is necessary to induce transient and reversible cognitive impairment and cerebral activity changes by a challenge test. In this context, a transient hypoxia could be relevant.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Hypoxia on Cognitive Assessment and Cerebral Activity in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anoxia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Good health on the basis of the medical interview, physical examination and standard biology parameters. RightHanded Nonsmoker No cardiac nor pulmonary pathologies No use of chronic treatment or psychotropic drugs or substances BMI inferior to 25 Kg/m2 French speaker and able to understand the test instructions Informed consent form signed 1. Subject with history or current brain disease (severe brain trauma, transient ischemic attack, stroke, epilepsy, cerebral tumor…) or retinal pathologies (including familial DMLA) 2. Subject with history of Acute Mountain Sickness, High Altitude Cerebral Edema or High Altitude Pulmonary Edema 3. Subject with other major medical or surgical history including coronaropathy and pulmonary arterial hypertension 4. Subject with current chronic disease 5. Subject with vascular or metabolic risk factor 6. Subject with history of or current mental disease or addiction (MINI) 7. Subject with significant abnormality on biology 8. Subject with significant abnormality on ECG 9. Subject with significant abnormality on MRI 10. Subject with significant abnormality of electrical activities on EEG 11. Subject with family history of young onset dementia 12. Subject with family history of cardiac or pulmonary pathologies 13. Subject with family history of chronic or severe neurological or mental disease (first degree relatives) 14. Subject with claustrophobia or contraindication to MRI 15. Subject under guardianship 16. Subject not covered by Social Security 17. Subject participating in another clinical trial 18. Subject with anxiety (STAITrait Score T&gt; 51) or neuroticism personality (EPI Score N ≥13) 19. Subject bearded or refusing to shave</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cognitive Function</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypoxia</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurophysiological Function</keyword>
	<keyword>Effect of Alzheimer Disease symptomatic drugs</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy Subjects</keyword>
</DOC>