<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01183520</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall goal of this project is to identify an appropriate level of high omega-3 fish (salmon) consumption that will promote optimal omega 3 nutritional status without increasing the level of lipid oxidation in the body.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of High Omega-3 Fish Intake on Lipid Peroxidation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Studies have demonstrated that the intakes of fatty fish and fish oils are associated with decreases in cardiovascular disease and other chronic disease states. This is related to the long chain omega-3 fatty acid (n-3) content of fish and fish oil, specifically eicosapentaenoic acid and docosahexaenoic acid. Although the consumption of high n-3 fish is recommended in the 2005 US Dietary Guidelines for Americans, no specific consumption levels are made for the fatty acid eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA) and/or the fatty acid docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) or total fish intake. Consumption of high n-3 fish or dietary supplementation of fish oil will lead to increased levels of these fatty acids in plasma lipoproteins, cell and tissue lipid. This change in membrane lipid is thought to be responsible for the anti-inflammatory effects of n-3. Because highly unsaturated fatty acid are subject to peroxidation, the level of fish intake that is sufficient to modify membrane n-3 content and the exact level that enhances peroxidation is unknown. We will perform a dose-response feeling study in which varied levels of fish (salmon) will be provided in random order separated by 4 or more week washout periods. We will assess the level of cell membrane enrichment with n-3 and the effect on lipid peroxidation outcomes.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>BMI 2534.9 Nonsmoker Free of major medical conditions Willing to comply with protocol requirements Use of lipid modifying drugs or supplements Taking fish oil or flax supplements Regular fish consumer Planning to gain to lose weight Pregnant or lactating</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>