<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01183143</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This was a prospective, open-label, non-comparative, Phase IIIb trial to assess the convenience, safety and efficacy of the new Gonal-F fbm [recombinant follicle stimulating hormone (r-FSH)] liquid formulation, in common setting for ovulation induction (OI) and also in in-vitro fertilisation (IVF).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Convenience and Safety of Assisted Reproductive Technology Procedures Using a Gonal-F Filled by Mass (Fbm) Liquid Formulation Applied by Pen for Ovulation Induction and In-vitro Fertilization</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Ovarian stimulation in IVF or intracytosolic sperm injection (ICSI) currently includes suppression of endogenous luteinising hormone (LH) suppression by administration of either a gonadotropin releasing hormone (GnRH) agonist or a GnRH antagonist, followed by stimulation of multiple follicular development by exogenous follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) administration. When an adequate follicular development is achieved, a single human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) dose is administered to mimic the endogenic LH surge and induce final oocyte maturation. In common setting, the purpose of the ovarian stimulation is to obtain a monofollicular development, for ovulation induction and the first line treatment is represented by clomiphene. Follicle stimulating hormone gonadotropins are indicated in case of clomiphene failure. OBJECTIVES - To assess, in common setting, convenience, safety, and efficacy of protocols using Gonal-F fbm liquid formulation applied by pen for OI and IVF/ICSI procedures. The study was designed to primarily collect safety data related to the usage of the Gonal-F fbm liquid formulation, in addition to the post treatment assessment of convenience in subjects treated with Gonal-F fbm. In OI or intrauterine insemination (IUI), the objective of ovarian stimulation was monofollicular development and the initiation of treatment took place in the the first 7 days of the cycle. The initial daily dose of Gonal-F was 75-150 International Unit (IU) and then was increased preferably by 37.5 IU or 50 IU or 75 IU (maximal dose should not exceeding 225 IU) at 7 or preferably 14 day intervals if necessary, to obtain an adequate but not excessive response. In IVF or ICSI the objective was superovulation, with multiple follicules development and the initiation of treatment at J2-J3 of the cycle was at the starting dose of 150-225 IU. The study was continued till the confirmation of pregnancy or non pregnancy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Follicle Stimulating Hormone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female subjects aged between 18 and 43 years Ambulatory subjects Subjects who are willing to get pregnant and are infertile, that justifies ovarian stimulation treatment for mono/paucifollicular development (OI or IUI) or multiple follicular development for IVF/ICSI procedures Subjects who are able to communicate well with the investigator and to comply with the requirements of the entire study Subjects who have given written informed consent, prior to treatment Subjects with enlarged ovaries or cysts unrelated to polycystic ovaries Subjects with extrauterine pregnancy during the last 3 months Subjects with several endometriosis (Grade III &amp; IV) Subjects with history of severe ovarian hyperstimulation syndrome Subjects with history of thromboembolic event Subjects with malformative uterine pathology that could disturb either implantation or pregnancy processus Subjects with premature menopause Subjects with gynaecological bleeding of unknown origin Subjects with ovarian, uterine, or mammary cancer Subjects with tumors of the hypothalamus or the pituitary glands Subjects with history of serious allergia, atopic asthma disease, Subjects with known allergic reaction against one of the FSH and ingredients, On going pregnant, or breast feeding subjects Subjects who have participated in a trial during the last 3 months</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>43 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Infertility</keyword>
	<keyword>Ovulation induction</keyword>
	<keyword>Gonal-F</keyword>
	<keyword>Follitropin alpha</keyword>
	<keyword>Controlled ovarian stimulation.</keyword>
</DOC>