<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02096731</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: Recent observational studies have reported possible arrhythmogenic effects with long-acting beta-agonists (LABA), while the long-acting anticholinergic tiotropium has been associated with cardiovascular and cerebrovascular events. Finally, pneumonia was the object of a recent signal in trials of LABAs submitted for marketing approval. Aim: To assess the potential cardio-pulmonary risk arising from the concurrent use of two long-acting bronchodilators as well as from monotherapy use of each of the long-acting bronchodilators. Methods: A series of population-based cohort studies, using both cohort and nested case-control analyses will be conducted using data from the United Kingdom's Clinical Practice Research Datalink (CPRD). The base cohort will consist of new users of long-acting bronchodilators from Jan 2002 until Aug 2012, age &gt;= 55 with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and at least two years of baseline medical history information. The high-dimensional propensity score technique will be used to match new users of each long-acting bronchodilator and new users of two bronchodilators with comparable subjects from the base cohort, with one-year follow-up for outcomes of acute myocardial infarction, stroke, heart failure, arrhythmia and community acquired pneumonia. Data will be analysed using time-dependent Cox proportional hazard regression models and conditional logistic regression models.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combined Bronchodilators in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease and the Risk of Adverse Cardio-pulmonary Events</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Purpose:</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bronchodilator Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: New users of longacting bronchodilators, either a LABA or tiotropium, between January 2002 and August 2012 Age &gt;= 55 years Exclusion criteria: Use of LABA or tiotropium in the two years prior to cohort entry</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>