<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01720277</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this pilot evaluation is to help determine the feasibility and power needed to prospectively evaluate relative effectiveness of high dose influenza vaccine in preventing influenza mortality and hospitalization in a nursing home population in the U.S., compared to the standard dose influenza vaccine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>High Dose Influenza Vaccine in Nursing Home</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Lower respiratory tract infection (LRI), which includes pneumonia, bronchitis, and tracheobronchitis, is the leading cause of mortality and hospitalization in older adults and nursing home (NH) residents. Often, the signs and symptoms of pneumonia, in particular, are not apparent in elderly patients, making diagnosis more complicated. In addition, clinician visits to these residents are few and sporadic and radiological facilities are not readily available. LRI may or may not directly lead to hospitalization, but LRIs are associated with considerable other morbidity than can result in hospitalization. Hospitalization rates for NH residents vary considerably between facilities, but the majority of hospitalizations occur during the 12 weeks during which influenza peaks each year. Influenza vaccination has been associated with reduced hospitalization, strokes, heart attacks and death in non-institutional older adult populations, but the benefit of influenza vaccine for the oldest population has been questioned. The new HD influenza vaccine is considerably more immunogenic in older adults, and has recently been approved for use in individuals aged 65 years and older. No clinical data yet confirm whether the improved immunogenicity translates into added clinical benefit, such as further reduction in hospitalization or death. The primary objective is to: 1. estimate the differences in all-cause hospitalization rates during flu season experienced by long stay nursing home residents, in facilities using the HD vaccine vs. facilities using the SD vaccine, as pilot data to inform feasibility, design and power calculation for a subsequent larger study. 2. To develop estimates, at the nursing home resident level, about the relationship between influenza vaccination status (none, SD, HD) and Medicare Minimum Data Set (MDS) coded claims for all-cause hospitalization and overall mortality among the long-stay residents from a single season 2012-2013, for use in a subsequent longitudinal evaluation of national nursing home data and regional publicly reported influenza severity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Longterm care facilities in one of the 122 cities that serve as Center for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) surveillance sites Facilities already systematically administering HD vaccine to their residents Facilities for whom over half the residents are on Medicare (shortstay) Facilities in which over half the residents are on Medicare Part A (SNF) Facilities having fewer than 50 longstay residents Hospitalbased facilities Facilities with more than 20% of the population under age 65 Facilities with mandated (employmentdependent) seasonal influenza vaccination Facilities not submitting MDS data</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Randomized Controlled Trial</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Flu Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Fluzone</keyword>
	<keyword>HD Fluzone</keyword>
	<keyword>Nursing Homes</keyword>
	<keyword>Hospitalization</keyword>
	<keyword>Mortality</keyword>
	<keyword>Health Care worker vaccination</keyword>
	<keyword>ADL decline</keyword>
	<keyword>Pilot</keyword>
	<keyword>Effectiveness</keyword>
</DOC>