<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01312259</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose: 1. To demonstrate better symptoms control (pain, urinary urgency and frequency) with sacral neuromodulation (SNM) in patients with interstitial cystitis /painful bladder syndrome (IC/PBS) using a stimulation frequency of 40 hertz (experimental) compared to a frequency of 14 hertz (standard). 2. The evaluate the efficacy of the two frequency settings on the other associated conditions that often coexist in patients with IC/PBS, such as female sexual dysfunction (FSD), bowel dysfunction, high tone pelvic floor dysfunction (HTPFD, painful spasm of the pelvic floor muscles), Vulvodynia (pain at the opening of the vagina).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Efficacy of Changing the InterStim® Parameters in Patients With Interstitial Cystitis/Painful Bladder Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Purpose: 1. Primary: to demonstrate better symptoms control (pain, urinary urgency and frequency) with sacral neuromodulation (SNM) in patients with interstitial cystitis /painful bladder syndrome (IC/PBS) using a stimulation frequency of 40 hertz (experimental) compared to a frequency of 14 hertz (standard). 2. Secondary: The evaluate the efficacy of the two frequency settings on the other associated conditions that often coexist in patients with IC/PBS, such as female sexual dysfunction (FSD), bowel dysfunction, high tone pelvic floor dysfunction (HTPFD, painful spasm of the pelvic floor muscles), Vulvodynia (pain at the opening of the vagina).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystitis, Interstitial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female with diagnosis of IC/PBS with implanted IPG Interstim. Scores &gt; 8 on the Interstitial Cystitis Symptom index questionnaire (ICSI) and &gt; 8 on the Interstitial Cystitis Problem Index questionnaire (ICPI). Signed Informed Consent. Progressive neurologic disease or peripheral neuropathy. History of bladder surgery. Subjects implanted with other neuromodulation device. Current or planning pregnancy; Breastfeeding. Subjects who are not deemed able to fill questionnaires Mental illness or mentally unstable patients</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Painful Bladder Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Interstitial Cystitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Pelvic Floor dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Fecal incontinence</keyword>
	<keyword>Constipation</keyword>
	<keyword>Sexual dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Dyspareunia</keyword>
	<keyword>Vulvodynia</keyword>
</DOC>