<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01312961</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: Investigate the effects of SAR231893 (REGN668) administered subcutaneously (SC) once weekly for 12 weeks as compared to placebo on reducing the incidence of asthma exacerbations in patients with persistent moderate to severe eosinophilic asthma. Secondary Objectives: Assess the safety and tolerability of SAR231893 (REGN668) administered SC once weekly for 12 weeks in patients with persistent moderate to severe eosinophilic asthma. Assess SAR231893 (REGN668) serum concentrations following once weekly SC dosing for 12 weeks in patients with persistent moderate to severe eosinophilic asthma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy, Safety, and Tolerability of SAR231893 (REGN668) in Patients With Persistent Moderate to Severe Eosinophilic Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The total duration of the study period per patient is 18-20 weeks broken down as follows: - Screening period: up to 14 days, - Treatment period: 12 weeks, - Follow-up period: 6-8 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Eosinophilia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albuterol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Salmeterol Xinafoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone Propionate, Salmeterol Xinafoate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Medical diagnosis of persistent asthma for at least 12 months whose: airway inflammation likely to be eosinophilic, asthma partially controlled or uncontrolled on Inhaled Corticosteroid (ICS) plus LongActing Beta2 Agonist (LABA) therapy. On a stable dose of either Fluticasone/Salmeterol, Budesonide/Formoterol, Mometasone/Formoterol combination therapy for at least 1 month prior to screening. Signed an Informed Consent Form and Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) Authorization Form. Exclusion criteria: Less than 18 years or greater than 65 years of age. Clinically relevant abnormal laboratory values suggesting an unknown disease and requiring further evaluation. Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and/or other lung diseases impairing Pulmonary Function Tests. Betaadrenergic receptor blockers required for any reason. Current smoker or cessation of smoking within the 6 months prior to screening. Previous smoking with a smoking history &gt; 10 cigarette pack/years. Participation in another study within 6 months prior to screening if the study medication is an antibody or within 30 days prior to screening for all other study medications. Known or suspected noncompliance, alcohol or drug abuse. Inability to follow the procedures of the study (eg, due to language problems, psychological disorders). Concomitant severe diseases or diseases for which the use of ICS or longacting beta2 agonists are contraindicated. Known allergy to doxycycline or related compounds. Pregnancy or intention to become pregnant during the course of the study, breast feeding, or unwillingness to use a highly effective method of contraception throughout the study in women of childbearing potential. Recent history of a parasitic infection or travel to a parasitic endemic area within 6 months prior to screening. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>