<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03025711</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall study objective is to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of Trastuzumab emtansine (T-DM1) and Pertuzumab under real-world disease conditions in the Spain, and specifically in patients treated under compassionate use or early access program</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Outcomes Of The Spanish Cohort Of Early Access To Pertuzumab And Trastuzumab Emtansine</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a retrospective, non-interventional, non-comparative, observational cohort study / registry in the Spain. The study design will reflect real-life clinical management of patients with HER2-positive MBC. Type and frequency of actual patient visits and all evaluations will be done as for routine clinical practice. The analysis of the efficacy and safety results obtained in patients receiving pertuzumab or TDM1 in those early access systems is of utmost importance. These real-world patients with advanced breast cancer may have different characteristics than those enrolled in clinical trials and clinicians must often extrapolate into therapeutic decisions not fully supported by a robust evidence.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pertuzumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ado-trastuzumab emtansine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trastuzumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Maytansine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients (age ≥ 18 years at enrolment) with HER2positive metastatic or locally recurrent unresectable breast cancer and who are treated with Trastuzumab emtansine (TDM1) or Pertuzumab. Patients who initiate Trastuzumab emtansine (TDM1) and Pertuzumab under Spanish compassionate use or early access program. Given the characteristics of the study there are no exclusion criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Advanced HER2+ breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Pertuzumab</keyword>
	<keyword>Trastuzumab emtansine</keyword>
	<keyword>Compassionate use</keyword>
	<keyword>Early access program</keyword>
	<keyword>Effectiveness</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
</DOC>