<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00020852</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Cryosurgery kills cancer cells by freezing them. Cryosurgery followed by lumpectomy or mastectomy may be an effective treatment for breast lesions. PURPOSE: Phase I trial to study the effectiveness of cryosurgery in treating women who have breast lesions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cryosurgery in Treating Women With Breast Lesions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the feasibility of temperature-monitored, ultrasound-guided cryosurgery in women with highly suspicious breast lesions. - Determine the safety of this procedure in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients undergo cryoablation of up to two breast lesions. Within 3-21 days, patients undergo lumpectomy or mastectomy. Patients are followed at 1, 4, 8, and 12 weeks after lumpectomy or mastectomy. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A maximum of 25 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Highly suspicious breast lesion on prior mammogram and/or ultrasound with confirmation of malignancy on ultrasoundguided core biopsy Tumor no greater than 2.0 cm in diameter Eligible for lumpectomy or mastectomy No superficial breast lesions No prior open surgical biopsy Hormone receptor status: Not specified PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: Any age Sex: Female Menopausal status: Not specified Performance status: Not specified Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Other: No other illness that would preclude study participation PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: Not specified Endocrine therapy: Not specified Radiotherapy: Not specified Surgery: See Disease Characteristics No other surgery that would preclude study participation Other: No other medical treatment that would preclude study participation</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2004</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage I breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>