<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00968708</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the cardiovascular outcomes of alogliptin, once daily (QD), compared with placebo, in addition to standard of care, in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus and acute coronary syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cardiovascular Outcomes Study of Alogliptin in Patients With Type 2 Diabetes and Acute Coronary Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Alogliptin is a selective and potent dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor developed by Takeda for use in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Cardiovascular outcomes is of special interest in the type 2 diabetes mellitus population, particularly in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients who have cardiovascular disease and are at high risk for major adverse cardiac events, such as those patients who have had recent acute coronary syndrome. This study has been designed to evaluate the cardiovascular safety of alogliptin versus placebo in addition to Standard of Care in adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus and acute coronary syndrome.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alogliptin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dipeptidyl-Peptidase IV Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of type 2 diabetes mellitus Is receiving monotherapy or combination antidiabetic therapy with a glycosylated hemoglobin level between 6.5% and 11.0%, inclusive, at Screening (between 7.0 and 11.0%, inclusive, if the participant's antidiabetic regimen includes insulin) Diagnosis of acute coronary syndrome within 15 to 90 days prior to randomization. Signs of type 1 diabetes mellitus Currently receiving a glucagonlike peptide1 analogue for glycemic control of type 2 diabetes mellitus at Screening Received a dipeptidyl peptidase4 inhibitor for either more than 14 days total or within the 3 months prior to Screening.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus - Type 2</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiovascular outcomes</keyword>
	<keyword>heart attack</keyword>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>dipeptidyl-peptidase IV inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolic disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolic diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>glucose metabolism disorders</keyword>
</DOC>