<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02873494</DOC>
	<brief_summary>PhysioFlow速 (PF速) is a new cardiac output (CO) monitoring method by impedance cardiography (IC), never studied in pediatric intensive care unit (PICU). The aim of the study was to compare CO and cardiac index (CI) measurements (IC) by trans-thoracic Doppler echocardiography (TTE) (COTTE and CITTE) and PF速 (COIC and CIIC) in PICU.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PHYSIOFLOW/Comparison of Cardiac Output Measurement</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this monocentric prospective study in PICU of the CHRU of Lille, simultaneous sets of three measurements were realized by TTE and PF速 in 43 patients. In the study, the patient will receive a measure of CF by impedancemetry chest. This electrode will be glued on the torso and the neck of the child. We will collect information obtained through IT, to compare the results obtained by the ETT, carried out under the support of the child. The study will last 15 minutes maximum. No blood sampling will be conducted for the purpose of the study, apart from the exams necessary to its support and its treatment. At no time, the results of the impedance will affect support. The study will use only the data contained in the medical file of the child and would involve no additional intervention (no examination, no further treatment). The use of these data will then be anonymous. After anonymization, information recorded will computer processing of the data collected. Concordance correlation coefficient (CCC) and Bland-Altman analysis with log-transformed data were used to compare CO, CI, stroke volume (SV) and systemic vascular resistance (SVR) measurements.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Children aged from 28 days to 10 years hospitalized in Pediatric ICU, including therapeutic support requires a hemodynamic assessment by ETT. Refusal of the child or refusal of one of the holders of parental authority Cardiac rhythm disorders Greater than 240 beats per minute tachycardia Burns or skin lesions of thorax Poor Echogenicity Congenital heart disease complex (except a persistent ductus arterious and interventricular or interventricular communication) Aortic insufficiency</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hemodynamic monitoring</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiac output</keyword>
	<keyword>Transthoracic echocardiography</keyword>
	<keyword>Impedance cardiography</keyword>
	<keyword>Child</keyword>
	<keyword>Physioflow</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatric intensive care unit</keyword>
</DOC>