<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02959801</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to compare the efficacy of Percutaneous mechanical thrombectomy (PMT) followed by standard anticoagulant therapy, with anticoagulation therapy alone, for the treatment of acute proximal lower extremity deep vein thrombosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Outcome of Percutaneous Mechanical Thrombectomy to Treat Acute Deep Venous Thrombosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The conventional treatment of acute deep vein thrombosis (DVT) is anticoagulation therapy, as recommended in the international guidelines. Anticoagulation prevents recurrent venous thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, and death. Early thrombus removal is now considered as the standard of medical care for deep vein thrombosis (DVT). Early thrombus removal can offer the potential for early restoration of venous patency and preservation of valve function. Percutaneous mechanical thrombectomy (PMT) uses a number of catheter-based mechanical devices to deliver the thrombolytic agent as well as to produce some combination of thrombus fragmentation, distribution of thrombolytic drugs throughout the thrombus, and/or thrombus aspiration. The purpose of this study was to compare the efficacy of Percutaneous mechanical thrombectomy (PMT) followed by standard anticoagulant therapy, with anticoagulation therapy alone, for the treatment of acute proximal lower extremity deep vein thrombosis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>proven acute deep venous thrombosis, less than 21 days and who were referred to the interventional radiology department. presence of subacute or chronic DVT more than 21 days in duration, inability to lie in the prone position required for intervention, terminal systemic disease requiring palliative treatment, active bleeding (from a gastric/duodenal ulcer or the cerebrovascular system), a haemorrhagic stroke within the previous year, an impaired bleedingclotting profile, and any haemophilic disorder, or pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Deep Venous Thrombosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Percutaneous Mechanical Thrombectomy</keyword>
</DOC>