<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02496416</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will examine the effectiveness of aquatic therapy on a range of MS-related symptoms such as cognition, mood, fatigue and quality of life (QOL).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aquatic Exercise Intervention in Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Aim 1. Examine the impact of aquatic exercise on cognitive abilities. The proposed study will test the hypotheses that, compared to the wait-list control group, the treatment group will demonstrate significantly greater improvements in cognitive outcomes, specifically: processing speed, executive functioning, working memory and long-term memory. Aim 2. The current study will examine the impact of an aquatic exercise on fatigue, mood, wellness, QOL and physical functioning. Specifically the investigators predict that aquatic exercise will lead to improvements in: 1.Fatigue 2. Health related QOL 3. Depression/anxiety 4. Self-efficacy 5. Physical Functioning (i.e. gait and walking). Aim 3: Examine the long-term effects of aquatic exercise on all outcome measures.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>diagnosis of MS. between the ages of 1865. read and speak English fluently. no history of significant substance abuse. no history of neurological disease other than MS (for example, stroke, epilepsy, or brain injury). no history of significant psychiatric illness (for example, bipolar disorder or schizophrenia). completed at least 30 minutes of moderate to strenuous exercise at least one day per week for at least the past 6 months. no diagnosis of MS younger than 18 older than 65 do not read and speak English fluently. history of significant substance abuse. history of neurological disease other than MS (for example, stroke, epilepsy, or brain injury). history of significant psychiatric illness (for example, bipolar disorder or schizophrenia). have not completed at least 30 minutes of moderate to strenuous exercise at least one day per week for at least the past 6 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>