<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02653911</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) is a dysfunction of endocrine system of women of reproductive age. Approximately 5%-10% women in China have this syndrome. Irregular menstruation (oligomenorrhea or amenorrhea), hirsutism and obesity are the common clinical manifestations of PCOS. The aim of this study is to determine whether electroacupuncture normalizes hormonal and glycometabolic profiles in women with polycystic ovary syndrome when compared with placebo-needle.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Electroacupuncture on Hormonal and Glycometabolic Profiles in Women With Polycystic Ovary Syndrome: Study Protocol</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polycystic Ovary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>have at least two following features which meet the Rotterdam diagnostic criteria: Oligomenorrhoea or amenorrhoea: Oligomenorrhoea is defined as an intermenstrual interval &gt;35 days or &lt;8 menstrual bleedings in the past year. Amenorrhoea is defined as absent menstrual bleeding or no menstrual bleeding in the previous 90 days Clinical or biochemical hyperandrogenism: Biochemical hyperandrogenaemia is defined as a total serum testosterone concentration above 60 ng/dL, and/or clinical hyperandrogenism is defined as a FerrimanGallwey (FG) score ≥5 or acne defined by the global Acne Grading System (GAS) as "mild"/"moderate"/"severe"/"very severe" Polycystic ovary morphology is defined as presence of ≥12 follicles in each ovary measuring 29 mm in diameter and/or an ovarian volume &gt;10 mL on transvaginal scanning. are between 1840 years old join the research and sign the informed consent voluntarily Participants fulfilling all of the following criteria will be included. have endocrine disorders such as thyroid dysfunction, adrenal disorders and diabetes have ovulation disorder caused by hyperandrogenemia, premature ovarian failure or amenorrhea caused by hypothalamus or pituitary disorders have hyperandrogenemia caused by congenital adrenal hyperplasia, Cushing's syndrome and androgensecreting tumors have taken Diane35 in the past 3 months have a serious heart condition, hepatic disease, renal system disease, hematopoietic system disease, or malnutrition of the whole body have received treatment by the same protocol of this trial in the past 30 days Participants fulfilling any one of the following criteria will be excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acupuncture</keyword>
</DOC>