<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02653287</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Participants in the Chicago Lupus Database or individuals seen at Northwestern Medicine will be approached to enroll in a one year clinical trial looking at decreasing fatigue in persons with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). The intervention group will receive individual coaching and group educational sessions focusing on physical activity and nutrition while the control group will receive individual calls in relation to SLE self-management group educational sessions.This study is designed to evaluate the LIFT intervention to decrease fatigue (primary outcome), improve physical activity (secondary outcome) and dietary behavior (exploratory outcome) in persons with SLE.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lupus Intervention for Fatigue Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants in the Chicago Lupus Database or individuals seen at Northwestern Medicine will be approached to enroll in a one year clinical trial looking at decreasing fatigue in persons with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE). The intervention group will receive individual coaching based in motivational interviewing and group educational sessions focusing on physical activity and nutrition while the control group will receive individual calls and group sessions focusing on SLE self-management. This study is designed to evaluate the LIFT intervention to decreased fatigue (primary outcome), improve physical activity (secondary outcome) and dietary behavior (exploratory outcome) in persons with SLE.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: include meeting at least 4 of 11 American College of Rheumatology (ACR) classification criteria for definite SLE, or 3 out of 11 ACR classification criteria with also meeting at least one SLICC criteria be at least 18 years of age have a BMI between 1840 kg/m2 be able to ambulate at least household distances (50ft) be able to provide informed consent. Exclusion criteria: include pregnancy at baseline not meeting inclusion criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fatigue, Physical Activity, Lupus</keyword>
</DOC>