<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02653417</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the clinical safety of and whether RAD1901 reduces the frequency and severity of VMS in postmenopausal women regardless of uterine status.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of RAD1901 in Postmenopausal Women With Moderate to Severe Vasomotor Symptoms</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hot Flashes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>To participate in this study, a subject MUST: 1. be a postmenopausal woman between 40 and 65 years of age, inclusive 2. be seeking relief or treatment for moderate to severe VMS 3. be willing to discontinue and abstain from the following: vaginal hormonal products; transdermal or oral estrogen or estrogen/progestin combination; progestin implants; injectable estrogen; topical progesterone cream, selective estrogen receptor modulators [e.g., ospemifene, raloxifene, tamoxifen, Duavee® (conjugated estrogens and bazedoxifene) and intrauterine devices (IUDs)] 4. have a normal or clinically insignificant transvaginal ultrasound (TVU) 5. have a normal endometrial biopsy subsequent to the TVU without clinically relevant results 6. have a normal screening Papanicolaou (Pap) smear 7. have a mammogram within 9 months prior to randomization. Subjects must have a Breast Imaging Reporting and Data System (BIRADS) mammography result of 1 or 2 to enroll. Subjects with any of the following characteristics will not be eligible to participate in the study: 1. have a history of invasive breast cancer or ductal carcinoma in situ, melanoma or any gynecologic cancer. 2. using any of the following: oral estrogen, progestin, androgen, or selective estrogen receptor modulator containing drug products within 8 weeks before screening (visit 1) transdermal hormone products within 4 weeks before screening (visit 1) vaginal hormone products (rings, creams, gels) within 4 weeks before screening (visit 1) progestin implants/injectables, IUDs or estrogen pellets/injectables within 6 months before screening (visit 1) anabolic steroids 3. have been treated with a GnRH agonist within the last year 4. have been treated with antiestrogens, or aromatase inhibitors within 2 months prior to study entry 5. have been concurrently treated and will abstain from gabapentin and paroxetine or serotonin and norepinephrine reuptake inhibitors (SNRIs) for VMS or other indications for 3 months during the trial and have not taken within 4 weeks prior to screening 6. have an endometrial biopsy at baseline with a diagnosis by a gynecologic pathologist of proliferative, hyperplasia, polyp or cancer 7. unresolved findings suspicious for malignancy on the breast examination</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>