<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00114140</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as temozolomide, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Radiation therapy uses high-energy x-rays to kill tumor cells. Giving temozolomide together with radiation therapy may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well giving temozolomide together with radiation therapy works in treating patients with low-grade gliomas.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Temozolomide and Radiation Therapy in Treating Patients With Gliomas</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Compare the 3-year survival of patients with high-risk low-grade gliomas treated with temozolomide and radiotherapy followed by temozolomide alone with that of patients enrolled on European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer (EORTC)clinical trials EORTC-22844 and EORTC-22845. - Determine the toxicity of this regimen in these patients. - Determine the association between progression-free survival and O6-methylguanine-DNA methyltransferase (MGMT) methylation status in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the association between survival and MGMT methylation status in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the quality of life (QOL) of patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the neurocognitive function of patients treated with this regimen. - Evaluate the feasibility of collecting patient-reported QOL and neurocognitive assessments over 3 years. OUTLINE: This is a non-randomized, multicenter study. Patients receive oral temozolomide once daily on days 1-42 and undergo radiotherapy once daily on days 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26, 29-33, and 36-40. Beginning 28 days after completion of chemoradiotherapy, patients receive oral temozolomide once daily on days 1-5. Treatment with temozolomide repeats every 28 days for up to 12 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Quality of life is assessed periodically for up to 36 months. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed at 4 months, every 6 months for 2 years, and then annually thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 135 patients will be accrued for this study within 44 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed* supratentorial glioma of 1 of the following histologies: Astrocytoma (diffuse fibrillary, protoplasmic, or gemistocytic) Oligodendroglioma Oligoastrocytoma NOTE: *Histologic atypia allowed provided no other histologic features (i.e., frequent mitoses, endothelial proliferation, and/or acute necrosis) that would result in a designation of anaplastic astrocytoma, anaplastic mixed oligodendroglioma or oligoastrocytoma, or glioblastoma multiforme are present Unifocal or multifocal disease WHO grade II disease Neurofibromatosis allowed Surgical biopsy or resection for tumor tissue sampling required within the past 12 weeks Tissue block or core biopsy available for O6methylguanineDNA methyltransferase analysis and tissue banking Patients who have only had a stereotactic biopsy are not eligible Must have ≥ 3 of the following risk factors: Age 40 and over Largest preoperative tumor diameter ≥ 6 cm Tumor crosses the midline Astrocytomadominant tumor subtype Preoperative Neurological Function Status &gt; 1 No other lowgrade glioma histologies, including any of the following: Pilocytic astrocytoma Subependymal giant cell astrocytoma of tuberous sclerosis Subependymoma Pleomorphic xanthoastrocytoma Presence of a neuronal element, such as ganglioglioma Dysneuroembryoplastic epithelial tumor No highgrade glioma, including any of the following: Anaplastic astrocytoma Glioblastoma multiforme Anaplastic oligodendroglioma Anaplastic oligoastrocytoma No tumors in any nonsupratentorial location, including any of the following: Optic chiasm Optic nerve(s) Pons Medulla Cerebellum Spinal cord No evidence of disease progression to spinal meninges or noncontiguous cranial meninges (i.e., leptomeningeal gliomatosis) by MRI of the spine or cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) cytology MRI of the spine or CSF cytology are not required for patients without symptoms of spinal/cranial meningeal disease progression PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 18 and over Performance status Zubrod 02 Life expectancy Not specified Hematopoietic Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Hepatic Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 mg/dL Serum glutamate oxaloacetate transaminase (SGOT) or Serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase (SGPT) ≤ 2 times normal Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2 times normal Renal Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL Other Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception No known HIV positivity No other malignancy within the past 5 years except carcinoma in situ of the cervix or nonmelanoma skin cancer No active infection PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy No concurrent immunotherapy or biologic therapy Chemotherapy No prior chemotherapy No other concurrent chemotherapy Endocrine therapy Not specified Radiotherapy No prior radiotherapy to the head and neck unless head and neck radiotherapy clearly excluded the brain (e.g., localized radiotherapy to the vocal cords) No prior radiotherapy to the brain No concurrent intensity modulated radiotherapy No concurrent stereotactic boost radiotherapy Surgery See Disease Characteristics Other No other concurrent investigational agents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult diffuse astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult oligodendroglioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult mixed glioma</keyword>
</DOC>