<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01553305</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the effectiveness of a supervised high-intensity exercise programme followed by an unsupervised exercise programme to an unsupervised exercise programme in patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of the Effect of Supervised Exercise Programme in Patients With Rheumatoid Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis are in general less fit and more at risk of comorbidities such as cardiovascular events compared with healthy age-matched controls. Studies indicates that patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis have a lower level of physical activity than the general population and a low proportion of patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis exercises. Regular exercise with moderate to high intensity level of intensity has proven to be effective in reducing the cardiovascular risk by improving cardiovascular fitness and to increase muscle strength. Therefore, it is of interest to investigate if supervised exercise programme makes a difference making patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis participate in exercise.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>diagnosed with Rheumatoid Arthritis within the last three years at Aarhus University Hospital according to the 1987 revised ACR criteria or the 2009 ACR/EULAR criteria must be able to sit on an exercise bike must be able to participate in 6weeks exercise programme with training sessions twice a week at Aarhus University Hospital must be able to speak and understand danish high disease activity assessed by DAS28CRP Myocardial Infarction within the last six months Angina Pectoris treated with betablocker severe high blood pressure severe lung disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>exercise programme</keyword>
</DOC>