<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01553448</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Studying samples of blood and tumor tissue from patients with cancer in the laboratory may help doctors learn more about changes that occur in DNA and identify biomarkers related to cancer. It may also help doctors find better ways to treat cancer. PURPOSE: This research trial studies gene expression in samples from younger patients with neuroblastoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Studying Gene Expression in Samples From Younger Patients With Neuroblastoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine whether TβRIII expression and TGF-β signaling decrease in advanced-stage neuroblastoma (NBL) and whether these changes are confined to the Schwannian stroma. - Determine whether sTβRIII levels and TGF-β signaling correlate with NBL stage, tumor stroma content, surface TβRIII expression, and TGF-β signaling. OUTLINE: Archived paraffin-embedded tissue and plasma samples are analyzed for TβRIII expression, TGF-β signaling, and SMAD3 expression and phosphorylation by immunohistochemistry, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), and other assays. Surface expression of TβRIII in the neuroblastic and stromal tumor components are correlated with matched circulating levels of soluble TβRIII. Results are then correlated with each patient's outcome data, including stage.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Tissue samples and matched plasma samples available from 1 of the following groups: Patients with lowstage (International Neuroblastoma Staging System [INSS] stage 1 or 2) neuroblastoma (NBL) Patients with advancedstage (INSS stage 3 or 4) NBL Patients with stage 4S NBL Clinical and/or outcome data associated with the tissue and plasma samples including INSS stage, age, MYCN amplification status, chromosomal alterations, and 5year survival, if known PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Not specified PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>disseminated neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>hereditary neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>localized resectable neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>localized unresectable neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage 4S neuroblastoma</keyword>
</DOC>