<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02687503</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Probiotics are microorganisms that are believed to provide health benefits when consumed. The term probiotic is currently used to name ingested microorganisms associated with beneficial effects to humans and animals. Probiotics are popularized in the lay literature for many different clinical problems. They have been studied in infants and children as a preventive or treatment for a variety of infections. Studies on the medical benefits of probiotics have yet to reveal a cause-effect relationship, and their medical effectiveness has yet to be conclusively proven for most of the studies conducted thus far. The putative benefit of probiotics in the prevention of infection relates to potential benefits to the innate and adaptive immune systems of infants. The goals of this investigation are to study immune system cell function in children who are taking probiotics. To accomplish this goal, the investigators propose a pilot study for which blood samples will be obtained prior to and post probiotic use in children greater than or equal to 12 months-36 months at the end of 3 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Probiotic Use on Immune Cell Function in Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy children greater than or equal to 12 months36 months of age English speaking parent Asthma/allergic rhinitis Premature birth (&lt; 36 weeks gestation) Immunodeficiency or any underlying problem requiring the use of steroids or other immunosuppressive agents Use of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) such as ibuprofen in the last 2 weeks Currently taking probiotics, have received probiotics in the previous two weeks or are unwilling to refrain from the use of nonstudy probiotics during the next 3 months Any antibiotic treatment in the last 3 months Conditions which might interfere with dispersion of the probiotic after oral administration such as short gut or anomalies of the digestive tract Concurrently participating in another clinical study, in which the child has been or will be exposed to an investigational or a noninvestigational product (pharmaceutical product or device).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>36 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Immune system</keyword>
	<keyword>Probiotics</keyword>
</DOC>