<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00027911</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Vaccines may make the body build an immune response to kill tumor cells. Colony-stimulating factors such as sargramostim increase the number of immune cells found in bone marrow or peripheral blood. Combining vaccine therapy with sargramostim may be effective in treating soft tissue sarcoma. PURPOSE: Phase I trial to study the effectiveness of combining vaccine therapy with sargramostim in treating patients who have stage II, stage III, or stage IV soft tissue sarcoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vaccine Therapy and Sargramostim in Treating Patients With Soft Tissue Sarcoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the safety and tolerability of NY-ESO-1 peptide vaccine and sargramostim (GM-CSF) in patients with stage II, III, or IV soft tissue sarcoma expressing NY-ESO-1 or LAGE antigen. - Determine the immunologic profile (NY-ESO-1 antibody, CD8+ cells, and delayed-type hypersensitivity) in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine tumor responses in patients treated with this regimen. OUTLINE: Patients receive NY-ESO-1 peptide vaccine intradermally once every 2 weeks for a total of 6 vaccinations. Patients also receive sargramostim (GM-CSF) subcutaneously once daily beginning 2 days before every vaccination and continuing for 5 days. Treatment continues in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 15 patients will be accrued for this study within 12 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed highrisk stage II, III, or IV soft tissue sarcoma expressing NYESO1 or LAGE antigen (including, but not limited to, synovial sarcoma) HLAA2 allele for NYESO1 peptides Declined, failed, or completed standard therapy CNS metastases allowed if treated and stable PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: Not specified Life expectancy: At least 3 months Hematopoietic: Hemoglobin at least 9.0 g/dL Lymphocyte count at least 500/mm3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm3 No bleeding disorders Hepatic: Bilirubin no greater than 2 mg/dL Hepatitis B and C negative Renal: Creatinine no greater than 1.8 mg/dL Cardiovascular: No New York Heart Association class III or IV heart disease Other: Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception HIV negative No other serious illness (e.g., serious infection requiring antibiotics) No immunodeficiency disease No psychiatric or addictive disorders that would preclude study PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: No prior bone marrow or peripheral blood stem cell transplantation At least 4 weeks since prior immunotherapy Chemotherapy: At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy (6 weeks for nitrosoureas) No concurrent chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: No concurrent steroids except topical or inhaled steroids Concurrent noncytotoxic anticancer hormonal therapy allowed (e.g., hormones for breast or prostate cancer) Radiotherapy: At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy Surgery: At least 4 weeks since prior surgery Other: At least 4 weeks since prior participation in any other clinical trial involving another investigational agent No concurrent antihistamines No concurrent nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs except low doses for prevention of an acute cardiovascular event or pain control No concurrent immunosuppressive agents Concurrent noncytotoxic anticancer therapy allowed</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult synovial sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult soft tissue sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult soft tissue sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult soft tissue sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II adult soft tissue sarcoma</keyword>
</DOC>