<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00841594</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical study is to compare the pharmacokinetic profiles of a topical cream formulation of 0.9% nitroglycerin, MQX 503, and Nitroglycerin Ointment 2%, USP.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>MQX-503 Applied to the Hand Versus Nitroglycerin Ointment Applied to the Chest: A Pharmacokinetic Comparison</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Raynaud Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nitroglycerin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 to 50 years of age Subjects who do not take any prescription medication or who can safely discontinue use prior to visit 1. Negative pregnancy test for fertile women and agree to use effective contaception throughout the study. Subjects who can not safely discontinue current prescription medications. Subjects who have a known allergy to nitroglycerin or common topical formulation ingredients. Subjects with an unstable medical problem. Subjects who, within the past three months, have had either a myocardial infarction, uncontrolled congestive heart failure, unstable angina, uncontrolled hypotension, or uncontrolled hypertension. Subjects who participated in a study of any investigational drug or device within four weeks prior to Visit 1. Subjects who have screening laboratory values which are outside the normal range and which are considered to be clinically significant to the investigator. Subjects who have had major abdominal, thoracic, or vascular surgery within six months of Visit 1. Subjects with nonepithelialized skin lesions or interfering skin conditions at time of screening in the area where either study medication is to be applied. Pregnant or nursing women. Women of childbearing potential who are unable or unwilling to comply with the contraceptive requirements during the study period.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>healthy volunteers</keyword>
</DOC>