<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02093910</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Bortezomib was an important drug in the treatment of multiple myeloma (MM),and peripheral neuropathy (PN) is a significant dose-limiting toxicity of bortezomib that typically occurs within the first courses of bortezomib, reaches a plateau at cycle 5. Up to now, no effective prophylaxis have been developed for PN. Monosialotetrahexosylganglioside, a nerve-protecting drug,was often used to promote growth of nerve, and function restoration of damaged nerve.Thus,the investigators hypothesized that combination of Monosialotetrahexosylganglioside and bortezomib can reduce the incidence rate of peripheral neuropathy (PN) and promote the relief of peripheral neuropathy (PN) in multiple myeloma (MM) patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Monosialotetrahexosylganglioside in the Prophylactic Treatment of Bortezomib-induced Peripheral Neuropathy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologic diagnosis of multiple myeloma; Age:1880 years; Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) status 03, Estimated survival time &gt; 3 months; Acceptable liver function (bilirubin＜2.5×ULN, Alanine transaminase (ALT) or Aspartate Aminotransferase (AST)＜2.5×ULN), No history of other malignancies; No previous treatments including chemotherapy, radiotherapy, targeted therapy or stem cell transplantation; No other serious diseases which conflict with the treatment in the present trial; No concurrent treatments that conflict with the treatments in the present trial; Voluntary participation and signed the informed consent. The patients had the conditions below: clinically significant ventricular tachycardia (VT), atrial fibrillation (AF), heart block, myocardial infarction (MI), congestive heart failure (CHF), symptomatic coronary artery heart disease requiring medication; The patients participated in other clinical trials within the 30 days before enrollment or who are participating in other clinical studies; The patients with neuropathy; The patients with mentally ill / unable to obtain informed consent; The patients with drug addiction, alcohol abuse which affects the longterm evaluation of test results; The patients in pregnancy, lactation and women of childbearing age who do not want to take contraceptive measures subjects; The patients with a history of allergy to test drug; The patients not suitable to participate in the investigator judged by researchers.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>multiple myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>peripheral neuropathy</keyword>
	<keyword>prophylaxis</keyword>
</DOC>