<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02093377</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this randomized controlled trial is to test the effect of 12 weeks Adaptive Servo-Ventilation (ASV) therapy (additionally to optimal medical management of myocardial infarction) on myocardial salvage (MSI=myocardial salvage/area at risk, primary endpoint).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ASV for Sleep Apnea After Myocardial Infarction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary Outcome Measure: myocardial salvage index, MSI - To test the effect of 12 weeks of ASV (additionally to percutaneous coronary intervention, PCI, and optimal medical management of AMI) on myocardial salvage (myocardial salvage index, MSI, assessed by cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging, CMR). Secondary Outcome Measures: - To test whether ASV therapy in patients with SA early after AMI decreases infarct size and improves left ventricular remodelling (myocardial salvage, microvascular obstruction change of infarct size, infarct size at 12 weeks, change of left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF), left ventricular systolic volume (LVSV), left ventricular diastolic volume (LVDV) and LVEF at 12 weeks; assessed with CMR). B-type natriuretic peptide (NT-proBNP) - To test whether ASV therapy in patients with SA early after AMIimproves disease specific symptom burden (Seattle Angina Questionnaire) - To test whether ASV therapy in patients with sleep apnea early after AMI suppresses sleep apnea (apneas and hypopneas/hour of sleep, mean oxygen saturation). - To test whether ASV therapy in patients with sleep apnea early after AMI increases renal function (Glomerular Filtration Rate, calculated using the 4vMDRD formula).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. age 1880 years 2. first AMI (STelevation in ECG or acute occlusion of coronary artery) 3. Primary successful PCI achieved &lt;24 h after symptom onset 4. SA with an AHI &gt;=15 per hour recording time 5. written informed consent Exclusion criteria: 1. previous myocardial infarction 2. previous myocardial revascularization (PCI or surgical) 3. LVEF &lt;45% and central sleep apnea 4. indication for a surgical revascularisation 5. cardiogenic shock, mean supine blood pressure &lt;60mmHg or NYHA class IV 6. implanted cardiac device or other contraindications for CMR 7. known allergies or other contraindication to contrast medium (e.g. GFR&lt;30ml/min/1.73m²) 8. history of stroke 9. contraindications for positive airway pressure support (hypotension with mean supine BP &lt;60mmHg, dehydration, inability to clear secretions, patients at risk for aspiration of gastric contents, severe bullous lung disease, history of pneumothorax and/or pneumomediastinum, a history of epistaxis, causing pulmonary aspiration of blood, cerebrospinal fluid leak or recent skull operations or injury) patients on or with indication for oxygen therapy, mechanical/noninvasive ventilation 10. patients on nocturnal positive airway pressure support 11. severe obstructive or restrictive airway disease 12. heart failure due to primary valve disease 13. patients awaiting heart transplantation 14. diurnal symptoms of OSA requiring immediate treatment 15. pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>acute myocardial infarction</keyword>
	<keyword>sleep apnea</keyword>
	<keyword>adaptive servo-ventilation</keyword>
</DOC>