<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02093195</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Present treatment for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) has a certain role in reducing COPD exacerbation and hospitalization, improving the life quality, and postponing the lung function decline. But for some patients with severe COPD, current treatment only partially alleviates the symptoms and has little role in the lung function decline. In this randomized, multicenter study, the investigators evaluate the safety and efficacy of bosentan in the treatment of grade Ⅲ or Ⅳ COPD patients with pulmonary hypertension detected by echocardiography. The primary endpoint is the frequency of COPD exacerbation, and the secondary endpoint includes changes of lung function, 6-min-walk distance (6-MWD), SGRQ score and mMRC/CAT score.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Bosentan in the Treatment of Stable Severe Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Budesonide, Formoterol Fumarate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bosentan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged 18 to 75 Gold Ⅲ or Ⅳ stable COPD Pulmonary hypertension detected by echocardiography Acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease Untreated obstructive sleep apnea Restrictive (total lung capacity&lt;60% predicted) lung disease Portal hypertension Chronic liver disease Transaminase increased to normal line more than 3 times; total bilirubin increased 2 times more than the upper limit of the normal value Leftsided or unrepaired congenital heart disease Patients with other serious heart diseases Patients with 1, 2, 4 and 5 categories of pulmonary hypertension Unable to complete the 6 minutes walk test Patients receiving other endothelin receptor antagonists No cooperation to complete</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Treatment, COPD, bosentan</keyword>
</DOC>