<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01515150</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Previous multicentre study NCT 01008488 indicates that a patient with CT-proven uncomplicated diverticulitis has a very low risk (1.4%) of developing severe complications such as perforations or abscesses. The question is whether or not hospitalization is necessary, and if patients in that case could return home without antibiotics. The purpose of this study is to evaluate if out-patients managements in uncomplicated colonic diverticulitis is possible without readmission or complications.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Out-patient, Non Antibiotic Management of Patients With Acute Uncomplicated Colonic Diverticulitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>At the emergency room all patients with computed tomography verified acute uncomplicated diverticulitis will be asked about participation in the study. If They accept the participation, They will be send home with pain relief medicine. Every morning a nurse from our colorectal unit call the patient asking about the condition. The patients will have a visit at the surgery unit within 10 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diverticulitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diverticulitis, Colonic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults (age above 18 years, acute abdominal pain (Duration&lt; 3 days), abdominal tenderness, elevated inflammatory parameters, CT scan sign of uncomplicated diverticulitis(without sign of abscess or free air). diffuse peritonitis sepsis or abscess, drying Patients who are unable to intake of fluids orally, severe pain with need of repeated parenteral morphine treatment, immunological deficient patients incl. steroid treatment, pregnancy, dementia, patients who need hospitalization of other reasons</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>95 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>diverticulitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Out-patient management</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibiotics</keyword>
</DOC>