<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01515124</DOC>
	<brief_summary>WISER Survivor is a one year weight loss and exercise study for sedentary breast cancer survivors who are overweight or obese with breast cancer related lymphedema. There will be four groups in this trial: exercise only, weight loss only, exercise and weight-loss combined, and a control group. The purpose of this study is to test the effects of these interventions on lymphedema outcomes, breast cancer recurrence and quality of life. The cost analysis sub-study - will assess the cost-effectiveness of conducting the WISER Survivor interventions and also model the impact of the WISER Survivor interventions over an extended time frame.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Women In Steady Exercise Research (WISER) Survivor Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphedema</mesh_term>
	<criteria>breast cancer survivor overweight or obese (BMI of 25 or greater) must have breast cancer related lymphedema at least 2 months posttreatment (e.g. surgery, chemotherapy, or radiotherapy) but there will be no upper limit on time elapsed from diagnosis the eligible age range will have no lower or upper limit. currently free of cancer medical conditions or medications that would prohibit participation in an exercise program or would negatively impact our ability to test our primary aims inability to walk for 6 minutes unaided extremely obese (body mass index greater or equal to 50 kg/m2) plans for additional (e.g. curative or reconstructive) surgery during the study period selfreport of weightlifting within the past year already engaging in 3 or more times weekly aerobic activity of moderate intensity planning to move away from the area over the next year current use of weight loss medication (OTC or prescription) selfreport of alcohol or substance abuse within the past 12 months, including atrisk drinking (current consumption of more than 14 alcoholic drinks per week) weight loss of greater than 10 % in the past 3 months history of bariatric surgery women who are pregnant</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lymphedema</keyword>
	<keyword>Strength training intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Weight loss intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast cancer recurrence</keyword>
	<keyword>Cost Effectiveness</keyword>
</DOC>