<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01515176</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase I/II trial studies the side effects and the best dose of ofatumumab and dinaciclib and to see how well they work in treating patients with relapsed or refractory chronic lymphocytic leukemia, small lymphocytic lymphoma, or B-cell prolymphocytic leukemia. Monoclonal antibodies, such as ofatumumab, can find cancer cells and help kill them. Dinaciclib may stop the growth of cancer cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth. Giving ofatumumab together with dinaciclib may kill more cancer cells.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ofatumumab and Dinaciclib in Treating Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia, Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma, or B-Cell Prolymphocytic Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the tolerable dose of combination therapy with ofatumumab and dinaciclib (phase 1b component) in chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL), small lymphocytic leukemia (SLL), and B-cell prolymphocytic leukemia (B-PLL). II. To characterize the toxicity of combination therapy with ofatumumab and dinaciclib in CLL/SLL/B-PLL. III. To determine the overall response rate associated with this treatment as assessed by consensus response criteria. (Phase II) SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To estimate progression-free survival (PFS) after combination treatment with ofatumumab and dinaciclib. II. To characterize the pharmacokinetics of dinaciclib when given in combination with ofatumumab. III. To correlate pharmacokinetic features of dinaciclib with response, toxicity (particularly tumor lysis syndrome), and pharmacodynamic endpoints. IV. To perform detailed baseline and serial pharmacodynamic studies of combination therapy with ofatumumab and dinaciclib and correlate these with response to therapy. V. To correlate baseline disease-risk parameters (i.e., zeta-chain-associated protein kinase [ZAP]-70 expression, interphase cytogenetics, immunoglobulin heavy chain variable region [IgVH] mutational analysis, and other clinical prognostic factors) with response to therapy. OUTLINE: This is a phase I, dose-escalation study followed by a phase II study. Patients receive ofatumumab intravenously (IV) over 4-6 hours on days 1, 8, 15, and 22 of courses 1-2, and on day 1 of courses 4-7. Beginning on course 2, patients also receive dinaciclib IV over 2 hours on days 2, 8, and 15 of course 2, and on days 1, 8, and 15 of courses 3-7. Treatment repeats every 28 days for up to 7 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 3 months for 2 years and then every 6 months for up to 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Prolymphocytic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Prolymphocytic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have histologically confirmed Bcell chronic lymphocytic leukemia (BCLL)/small lymphocytic lymphoma (SLL) or a Bcell prolymphocytic leukemia (BPLL) according to 2008 World Health Organization (WHO) diagnostic criteria Patients must meet one or more of the following modified indications for treatment as described in the 2008 International Workshop on chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) (IWCLL) guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of CLL: Progressive disease or marked splenomegaly and/or lymphadenopathy or disease requiring debulking for future allogeneic transplantation Anemia (hemoglobin &lt; 11 mg/dL) or thrombocytopenia (platelets &lt; 100,000/μL) Unexplained weight loss exceeding 10% of body weight over the preceding 6 months Cancer Therapy Evaluation Program (CTEP) active version of the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) grade 2 or 3 fatigue Fevers &gt; 100.5 º F or night sweats for greater than 2 weeks without evidence of infection Progressive lymphocytosis, with an increase exceeding 50% over a 2month period or a doubling time of less than 6 months Need for cytoreduction prior to allogeneic stem cell transplant Patients must have received at least one prior therapy that includes either fludarabine or equivalent nucleoside analogue, or an alternative regimen if there was a contraindication (i.e. autoimmune hemolytic anemia) or patient elected not to receive fludarabine Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status =&lt; 2 (Karnofsky &gt;= 60%) Life expectancy &gt;= 12 weeks Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,000/μL in absence of bone marrow involvement Platelets &gt;= 30,000/μL in absence of bone marrow involvement Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 X institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) unless secondary to Gilbert's Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase [SGOT])/alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase [SGPT]) =&lt; 2.5 X institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) unless due to infiltration of the liver Creatinine =&lt; 2.0 mg/dL OR creatinine clearance &gt;= 50 mL/min/1.73 m^2 for patients(CockcroftGault estimated) Patients with a history of current/previous infection with hepatitis B virus will be eligible if receiving appropriate antiviral prophylaxis Women of childbearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry and for the duration of study participation; should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while she or her partner is participating in this study, she should inform her treating physician immediately Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document Patients who have had chemotherapy or radiotherapy within 4 weeks (6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin C) prior to entering the study or those who have not recovered from adverse events due to agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier; corticosteroids alone will not be considered prior therapy, but must be discontinued at least 24 hours prior to the first day of therapy unless continued for indications other than the primary malignancy Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents Patients who have received prior treatment with dinaciclib will not be eligible; patients previously treated with ofatumumab will be eligible as long as their disease responded to previous treatment (defined as achieving at least stable disease by consensus criteria) and did not subsequently progress &lt; 3 months from completing treatment Patients with known brain metastases should be excluded from this clinical trial History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition as dinaciclib History of anaphylactic reaction to rituximab or other anticluster of differentiation (CD)20 monoclonal antibody Because dinaciclib is metabolized by the cytochrome P450, family 3, subfamily A, polypeptide 4 (CYP3A4) liver enzyme, the eligibility of patients taking medications that are potent inducers or inhibitors of that enzyme will be determined following a review of their case by the principal investigator; every effort should be made to switch patients taking such agents or substances to other medications; any identified agent needs to be stopped at least 2 weeks prior to study registration; use of aprepitant will be permitted, however, based on drugdrug interaction study performed by the manufacturer showing no effect on dinaciclib pharmacokinetics (PK) Patients with glucose6phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency are excluded Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements Pregnant and/or breastfeeding women are excluded from this study; breastfeeding should be discontinued if the mother is treated with dinaciclib Prior malignancy, except for adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, in situ cervical cancer, or other cancer from which the subject is considered by his or her physician to have a 2 year survival expectation Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)positive patients on combination antiretroviral therapy are ineligible</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>