<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02064764</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical study is to evaluate the feasibility of performing both renal nerve denervation and pulmonary vein isolation on the same patient with the intent of characterizing both safety and effectiveness in a paroxysmal and persistent atrial fibrillation population with hypertension. To assess safety, the study will measure the occurrence of a composite safety endpoint and, to assess effectiveness, the study will measure freedom of chronic treatment failure through a minimum of six months of follow-up.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Renal Nerve Denervation in Patients With Hypertension and Paroxysmal and Persistent Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Drug refractory recurrent symptomatic paroxysmal or persistent atrial fibrillation Officebased systolic blood pressure of ≥150 mm Hg based despite treatment with 2 or more antihypertensive medications of different classes (one of these must be a diuretic) Age 18 years to 80 years old. Key Renal artery anatomy that is ineligible for treatment including: Lacks at least one renal artery for each kidney with ≥3 mm diameter and minimum treatable length per the Spyral Instructions for Use, Renal artery stenosis (&gt;50%) or renal artery aneurysm in either renal artery, A history of prior renal artery intervention including balloon angioplasty or stenting, Renal artery which contain calcification which does not allow at least four radio frequency ablations to be delivered , Diffuse fibromuscular dysplasia (FMD) or FMD which does not allow at least four radio frequency ablations to be delivered; FMD defined as visible beading of the artery on angiography , Unilateral kidney. Estimated Glomerular Filtration Rate of &lt;30 mL/min/1.73m2. Pregnant, nursing or planning to be pregnant. (Female participants of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) pregnancy test prior to angiography). Currently enrolled or plans to participate in a potentially confounding drug or device trial during the course of this study. Coenrollment in concurrent studies is allowed when documented preapproval is obtained from the Medtronic study manager.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>