<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02064868</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multinational, multicenter, randomized, open-label study to confirm and expand the efficacy, safety and tolerability evidence of 48 hours intravenous infusion of serelaxin (30 micrograms/kg/day) when added to Standard of Care (SoC) in patients admitted to hospital for Acute Heart Failure (AHF).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Serelaxin Versus Standard of Care in Acute Heart Failure (AHF) Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is aimed at generating clinical evidence, especially on the short term period (in-hospital and at 30 days) that will complement existing and future serelaxin data sets in Acute Heart Failure (AHF).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mineralocorticoid Receptor Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiotensin-Converting Enzyme Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Systolic blood pressure &gt; 125 mmHg Admitted for Acute Heart Failure (AHF) Received intravenous furosemide (or equivalent) at any time between presentation and the start of screening eGFR on admission: ≥ 25 and ≤75 mL/min/1.73 m^2 Dyspnea (noncardiac causes) T &gt; 38.5°C Clinical evidence of acute coronary syndrome currently or within 30 days prior to enrollment. Significant left ventricular outflow obstruction, uncorrected, such as obstructive hypertrophic cardiomyopathy or severe aortic stenosis (i.e., aortic valve area &lt;1.0 cm^2 or mean gradient &gt;50 mmHg on prior or current echocardiogram), severe aortic regurgitation and severe mitral stenosis. AHF due to significant arrhythmias Acute myocarditis or hypertrophic obstructive, restrictive, or constrictive cardiomyopathy (does not include restrictive mitral filling patterns seen on Doppler echocardiographic assessments of diastolic function). Other protocol defined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>AHF,</keyword>
	<keyword>RLX030,</keyword>
	<keyword>SOC,</keyword>
	<keyword>WHF,</keyword>
	<keyword>RELAX-AHF-EU</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal Impairment</keyword>
</DOC>