<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02064348</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted in Europe. The aim of the trial is to evaluate the effect of semaglutide on cardiac repolarisation in healthy subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Thorough QTc Evaluation of the Effect of Semaglutide on Cardiac Repolarisation in Healthy Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Moxifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluoroquinolones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Norgestimate, ethinyl estradiol drug combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>BMI (Body Mass Index): 2030 kg/m^2 Body weight: 60110 kg Normal ECG (electrocardiogram) Female who is pregnant, breastfeeding or intends to become pregnant or is of childbearing potential and not using an adequate contraceptive method. Women of childbearing potential must use an effective method of birth control for the duration of the trial and for 5 weeks following the last dose of semaglutide. Only highly effective methods of birth control are accepted (i.e. one that results in less than 1% per year failure rate when used consistently and correctly such as implants, injectables, combined oral contraceptives, some intrauterine devices), or sexual abstinence or vasectomised partner Any clinically significant disease history, in the opinion of the investigator, or systemic or organ History of seizures, epilepsy, syncope, cardiac arrest, cardiac arrhythmia or Torsades de Pointes, AV (Atrioventricular) block or structural heart disease Family history of long QT (Interval in the ECG: from the start of the QRS complex to the end) syndrome (either objectively diagnosed or suggested by sudden death due to cardiac causes before the age of 50 of a 1st degree relative) Family history of sudden cardiac death before the age of 50 of a 1st degree relative Use of prescription or nonprescription systemic or topical medicinal products (except routine vitamins, acetylsalicylic acid, paracetamol and contraceptives) within 3 weeks (or within 5 halflives of the medicinal product, whichever is longest) prior to the first dosing of semaglutide Smoking, drug or alcohol abuse</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>