<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00969280</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is about the effectiveness of acupuncture treatment on dry eye syndrome. Study hypothesis is that a standardized acupuncture would be more effective than a sham acupuncture in dry eye syndrome patients. This is a randomized, patients-assessor blinded, sham acupuncture controlled study. Additionally, the investigators will assess the safety of acupuncture treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acupuncture for Dry Eye Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Keratoconjunctivitis Sicca</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dry Eye Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who have had dry eye syndromes in single eye or in both eyes e.g. Other disorders of lacrimal gland: Dry eye syndrome (ICD10: H04.1). He or she must have both of the conditions below: 1. Patients who have had such symptoms like ocular itching, ocular foreign body sensation, ocular burning, ocular pain, ocular dryness, blurred vision, sensation of photophobia, ocular redness, sensation of tearing 2. Patient whose tear film breakup time (BUT) is below 10 seconds and measured tear amount is below 10mm/5sec by Schirmer 1 test Those who have defects of eyelid or eyelashes Those who have acute infection of eyelid, eyeball or accessories of eye Those who have StevensJohnson syndromes or Pemphigoids Those who have Vitamin A deficiency Those who have any defects of eye or accessories of eye by external injuries Those who have undergone any surgical operation for eye during last 3 months Those who are using contact lens Those who have any difficulties about eye opening or eye closing due to facial palsy Those who have undergone punctual occlusion surgery Those who have used any kinds of antiinflammatory eyedrops for recent 2 weeks (steroids, cyclosporin or autologous serum eyedrops) Those who have systemic immune therapy Those who are pregnant or have any plan for pregnancy Those who are not appropriate to this study by investigators decision</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acupuncture</keyword>
	<keyword>Dry eye syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Ocular Surface Disease Index</keyword>
	<keyword>Schirmer test</keyword>
	<keyword>Tear film Break-up time</keyword>
</DOC>