<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00969722</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicenter, randomized, controlled, open-label study. Patients meeting inclusion/exclusion criteria will be randomized (1:1) to receive two cycles of MAb-3F8 plus GM-CSF or RA plus GM-CSF. Patients who do not respond to their assigned treatment after two cycles may cross-over to receive the alternate treatment. Disease response and safety will be assessed in all patients after cycle 2 and after cycle 4.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of MAb-3F8 Plus Granulocyte-Macrophage Colony-Stimulating Factor (GM-CSF) Versus 13-cis-Retinoic Acid (RA) Plus GM-CSF in Primary Refractory Neuroblastoma Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tretinoin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isotretinoin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have a diagnosis of stage 4 neuroblastoma diagnosed in accordance with the International Neuroblastoma Staging System: either (a) histologic confirmation which may involve immunohistochemical, ultrastructural, and/or cytogenetic studies, or (b) elevated urinary catecholamines plus tumor cells/clumps in the bone marrow. Have evaluable disease or biopsyproven stable disease in BM by histology or MIBG scan with MIBGpositive disease confined to the bone or bone marrow, plus urine catecholamine results, documented &gt;3 weeks after conventional chemotherapy or &gt;6 weeks after stemcell transplantation. CT, MRI, or bone scan (if necessary) can be done at 23 weeks after conventional chemotherapy confirming that the chemotherapy, radiotherapy, and ABMT are not realistic curative options. Be between 18 months to 13 years old at diagnosis. Have recovered to grade 2 or better toxicities since their prior therapy. Must, if female of childbearing potential, be willing to use two forms of medically acceptable contraception (at least one barrier method) and have a negative pregnancy test at screening and monthly thereafter through the first four cycles of treatment. Have a performance score of at least 60 from Lansky Play Performance Scale if aged up to 16 years or at least 60 from Karnofsky Scale if aged more than 16 years. Have voluntarily agreed to participate. Have measurable disease ≥ 1 cm assessed by CT or MRI. Have progressive disease (any new lesion; increase of any measurable lesion by &gt;25%; or previous negative marrow positive for tumor). Have disease detectable in CNS (confirmed by CT or MRI of the brain at screening or within 8 weeks of randomization). Be receiving alternative therapy for the treatment of neuroblastoma, e.g. radiotherapy or chemotherapy within 3 weeks of randomization. Require additional therapy (such as radiotherapy) during the first two treatment cycles. Have detectable human antimouse antibody titers at screening. Have received prior antiGD2 investigational therapies. Have a history of allergies to mouse proteins. Have an active infection requiring IV infusion of antibiotics. Be currently receiving longterm chronic treatment with immunosuppressive drugs such as cyclosporine, adrenocorticotropic hormone (ACTH), or systemic corticosteroids.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>13 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>3F8</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary refractory</keyword>
</DOC>