<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01390532</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cardiac Resynchronization Therapy (CRT) is an established treatment for patients with advanced heart failure and left ventricular dyssynchrony (LVD). Too many patients do not clinically improve with CRT. New LVD markers other than QRS duration are needed. Study objective : feasibility assessment of rest and real-time stress 3D Blood-Pool Gated SPECT (BPGS) with a new designed cardiac imaging camera (DSPECT, Spectrum Dynamics®, Ceasaria, Israel) to quantify LVD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rest/Stress Quantification Of Left Ventricular Dyssynchrony By 3D Gated Blood Pool D-SPECT</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Sequential 5 min Gated blood pool D-SPECT acquisition at rest and during last stage of dobutamine and atropin infusion (&gt;85% PHR). Rest and stress left ventricular ejection fraction, phase standard deviation and entropy will be determined using a fully automatic commercial software (QBS, Cedars-Sinai, Los Angeles, CA).</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Chronic heart failure with LVEF &lt; 35 %, QRS &gt; 120 ms, NYHA III/IV, optimal medical therapy for more than one month. Patient with stable hemodynamic for more than one month, More than 18year old man or woman, Patient having given his free, inform and signed consent, Patient place setting by the social security system, Psychiatric disorder Any contraindication to Technetium, Any contraindication to dobutamin or atropin Personal or family history of sudden death Previous severe ventricular arrhythmia Obstructive cardiomyopathy, severe aortic stenosis, Pulmonary hypertension, History of renal, lung, hepatic, cardiac transplantation, Pregnant or breastfeeding Woman, Patient who can not conform to the requirements of the protocol, Patient included in another medical study,</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Left Ventricular Dyssynchrony</keyword>
	<keyword>Gated blood-pool</keyword>
	<keyword>D-SPECT</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacological stress</keyword>
	<keyword>NYHA III/IV</keyword>
	<keyword>LVEF &lt; 35 %</keyword>
	<keyword>QRS &gt; 120 ms</keyword>
	<keyword>optimal medical treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiac resynchronization therapy</keyword>
</DOC>