<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02728973</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) was first proposed by Kehlet in Copenhagen Denmark, this is a new concept for the integration of the latest study of the surgical, anesthesia, and nursing. The purpose of optimization measures, reduce patient trauma stress, promote early rehabilitation of patients. The investigators plan to compare the feasibility, clinical effectiveness, and cost savings of an ERAS program with traditional treatment program at a major teaching hospital in China.The investigators will apply ERAS plan or traditional treatment regimens in the treatment of 100 cases of colorectal cancer patients, respectively. And data Compare the two programs about the incidence of postoperative complications, postoperative hospital stay, cost of hospitalization, and readmission rate will be collected.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ERAS Protocol on the Incidence of Postoperative Complications Following Intestinal Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Major colorectal surgery usually requires a hospital stay of more than 12 days. Inadequate pain management, intestinal dysfunction and immobilisation are the main factors associated with delay in recovery. This study aims to assess the short and medium term results achieved by an enhanced recovery program based on previously published protocols. This prospective study will be performed at a major hospital in China, involved 200 patients. All patients underwent elective colorectal resection for cancer are divided into enhanced recovery program group or conventional treatment group. The main elements of this program were: preoperative advice, no colon preparation, provision of carbohydrate-rich drinks one day prior and on the morning of surgery, goal directed fluid administration, body temperature control during surgery, avoiding drainages and nasogastric tubes, early mobilization, and the taking of oral fluids in the early postoperative period. Perioperative morbidity and mortality data will be collected and the length of hospital stay and protocol compliance recorded.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Postoperative Complications</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Elective laparotomy or laparoscopic intestinal surgery. 2. Age ≥ 18 years old. 3. ASA grade II IV. 4. General anesthesia. 1. Patients with cognitive dysfunction and uncooperative subjects. 2. Failure to obtain informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>colorectal resection</keyword>
	<keyword>enhanced recovery after surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Postoperative Complications</keyword>
	<keyword>length of hospital stay</keyword>
</DOC>