<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02728895</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the initial tolerability, safety and recommended phase 2 dose of vedolizumab intravenous (IV) administered for Graft-Versus-Host Disease (GvHD) prophylaxis along with standard GvHD prophylaxis therapy (in participants undergoing allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation [allo-HSCT]).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose Finding Study of Vedolizumab for Graft-Versus-Host Disease (GvHD) in Participants Undergoing Allogeneic Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation (HSCT)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The drug being tested in this study is called Vedolizumab. Vedolizumab (also called MLN0002) is approved for the treatment of adult participants with moderately to severely active UC and CD who achieved an inadequate response, had a loss of response, or were intolerant to conventional and/or biologic treatments. This study will look at the tolerability and pharmacokinetics of Vedolizumab in participants undergoing allo-HSCT when added to standard GvHD prophylaxis (tacrolimus plus short-term methotrexate) for the prevention of acute GvHD (major complication in allo-HSCT). The study will enroll approximately 36 participants. Participants will be assigned to different dose-escalating cohorts in order to find out the recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) of the study: - Cohort 1: Vedolizumab 75 mg - Cohort 2: Vedolizumab 300 mg - Cohort 3: Vedolizumab Dose 1 All participants have to receive 1 injection of Vedolizumab on Day -1 before allo-HSCT and on Days 13 and 42 after allo-HSCT. If none of the participants receiving vedolizumab at 75 mg experience dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs), dose escalation will continue to 300 mg on Day -1 before allo-HSCT and on Days +13 and +42 after allo-HSCT. If the first 3 participants at 300 mg tolerate the treatment without experiencing DLTs, then the decision on whether to increase the vedolizumab IV dose in the next cohort will be guided by the PK results. Cohorts will be escalated in same manner until the identification of RP2D. The cohort at that dose level may be expanded to include approximately 18 additional participants undergoing myeloablative conditioning or reduced-intensity conditioning (RIC) and receiving either related or unrelated allo-HSCT for the treatment of hematologic malignancies or myeloproliferative neoplasms. This group of participants will allow the further assessment of the tolerability and clinical activity of vedolizumab. This multi-center trial will be conducted in the United States. The overall time to participate in this study will be approximately 2 years. Following the treatment period, participants who remain in remission will be followed for development of acute and chronic GvHD and safety during clinic visits at 4, 5, 6, 9, and 12 months after allo-HSCT or until death or withdrawal of consent or termination of the study by the sponsor. Participants who complete the study will attend a 12-month follow-up visit. Patients who have been discontinued from treatment will attend an end of treatment visit 30 to 40 days after the last dose of study drug using all study procedures outlined for the 12-month follow-up visit.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Graft vs Host Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vedolizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Is undergoing matched or singleantigen mismatched unrelateddonor myeloablative transplant for the treatment of ALL or AML; Is less than or equal to (&lt;=) 60 years of age For the cohort after Recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) 2. Is undergoing matched or singleantigen mismatched related or unrelateddonor transplant and receiving myeloablative conditioning or RIC for the treatment of hematologic malignancies or myeloproliferative neoplasms; Is less than or equal to (&lt;=) 75 years of age 1. Has received prior allogeneic transplants or who are planned to undergo umbilical cord blood transplant, receive ex vivo Tcelldepleted hematopoietic stem cells (HSCs), received any in vivo Tcell depleting antibodies, or nonmyeloablative conditioning. 2. Has active cerebral/meningeal disease, active cytomegalovirus (CMV) colitis, or signs and symptoms of progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy (PML) or any history of PML. 3. Is undergoing transplant for the treatment of nonmalignant hematological disorders (for example: aplastic anemia, sickle cell anemia, thalassemias, Fanconi anemia).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>