<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02728427</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Compared with traditional open proctectomy, laparoscopic surgery is associated with less pain, earlier recovery, and better cosmetic outcome, and its long-term oncologic outcomes have been demonstrated. However, the rate of urinary dysfunction after rectal cancer surgery was about 19-38% because of mesorectal excision. The type of drainage is unclear. Some studies show that the rates of urinary tract infection, second catheterization, and urinary symptom are lower with suprapubic catheterization (SPC) than with transurethral catheterization (TUC). Moreover，SPC allows for testing the bladder voiding without drainage removal. Furthermore，SPC using central venous catheter(CVC) is less invasive. Currently, there is lack of randomized controlled trial(RCT) to compare SPC with TUC. Therefore, investigators perform this prospective randomized trial to compare SPC using CVC with TUC in laparoscopic surgery for rectal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicenter Study on Suprapubic Catheterization Versus Transurethral Catheterization in Laparoscopic Surgery for Rectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age over 18 years Pathological rectal carcinoma Male patients Performance status of 0 or 1 on ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) scale ASA (American Society of Anesthesiology) score class I, II, or III Laparoscopic surgery for rectal cancer Written informed consent Emergency surgery due to complication (obstruction or perforation) caused by rectal cancer Preoperative T4b according to the 7th Edition of AJCC Cancer Staging Manual Basic diseases of urinary system (urinary bladder stones and tumors, prostate cancer, neurogenic bladder, urethral stricture) that affect voiding function History of previous pelvic surgery Severe mental disease</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Suprapubic Catheterization</keyword>
	<keyword>Transurethral Catheterization</keyword>
	<keyword>Rectal Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Laparoscopic Surgery</keyword>
</DOC>