<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="217993">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00246740</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Protect Study Protocol</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00246740</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Protection of the Heart With Doxycycline During Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting</brief_title>
  <official_title>Protection of the Heart With Doxycycline During Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting: A Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alberta</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alberta</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether doxycycline(Periostat)at a
      sub-antimicrobial dose will decrease reperfusion injury after coronary artery bypass
      grafting (CABG) surgery with cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB).
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This proposal is for a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blinded study of the use of
      doxycycline in patients requiring CABG surgery. Patients will be randomized 1:1 to receive
      either doxycycline or placebo.

      This study will be conducted in a blinded manner. The pharmacy will randomize patients and
      will have the randomization code. The code will only be broken in the case of an emergency
      and the event will be fully documented.

      In addition to standard care, patients will receive oral administration of 20 mg of
      doxycycline or placebo twice a day at least 2 days prior to surgery, on the day of surgery,
      and on postoperative days 1, 2, and 3.

      Myocardial atrial biopsies will be taken at 2 time points during the CABG procedure: during
      cannulation of the right atrium and 10 minutes after cross-clamp release. Tissue will be
      analyzed for MMP-2 and -9 activity and TnI and MLC-1 levels.

      A Swan-Ganz-Catheter will be placed in the pulmonary artery over 24 hours to measure
      hemodynamics (LVSWI).

      A coronary sinus catheter will be placed under echocardiographic guidance prior to
      initiation of CPB (will be removed 20 minutes after cross-clamp release).

      Patients will have an additional ECG on post-operative days 1 and 3.

      Additional blood will be drawn to determine doxycycline plasma levels, MMP-2 and -9
      activity, total gelatinolytic activity, and levels of troponin I and T products at the
      following time points: pre-induction, prior to initiation of CPB, 10 and 20 minutes
      following the release of the aortic cross clamp (arterial and venous) and 3, 6, 24 and 72
      hours post aortic cross clamp removal (venous). Each of the above samples will require 6 mL
      of blood for a study total of 72 mL. At the time of each blood draw we will measure and
      record the hematocrit value.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Doxycycline, a tetracycline antibiotic that also possesses secondary inhibitory effects on matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs), will attenuate myocardial and systemic activation of MMPs if administered to patients prior to the onset of CPB.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 days prior to surgery until 3 days post operative</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Attenuating the activation of MMPs will reduce cleavage of contractile protein regulatory elements such as troponin I (TnI) and myosin light chain 1 (MLC-1), which will improve cardiac functional recovery after CPB.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 days prior to surgery until 3 days post operative</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting</condition>
  <condition>Cardiopulmonary Bypass</condition>
  <condition>Reperfusion Injury</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Periostat</intervention_name>
    <description>In addition to standard care, patients will receive oral administration of 20 mg of doxycycline or placebo twice a day at least 2 days prior to surgery, on the day of surgery, and on postoperative days 1, 2, and 3.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Written informed consent

          -  Aged 18 through 80 years, inclusive

          -  Scheduled for primary CABG surgery with CPB

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Females of childbearing potential

          -  Emergency CABG

          -  Previous sternotomy

          -  Planned simultaneous surgery (i.e. valve repair or carotid endarterectomy)

          -  Myocardial infarction within 48 hours

          -  Pre-operative atrial fibrillation

          -  Pre-operative ventricular pacing or left bundle branch block (LBBB)

          -  Known hypersensitivity to tetracycline class antibiotics

          -  Renal failure requiring dialysis
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Barry A Finegan, MB, FFARS(I), FRCPC</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Pain Medicine, University of Alberta Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alberta Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edmonton</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T6G 2G3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 11, 2010</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>October 28, 2005</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Dr. Barry Finegan</name_title>
    <organization>University of Alberta</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Doxycycline</keyword>
  <keyword>coronary artery bypass grafting</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Reperfusion Injury</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Doxycycline</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
