<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01719081</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This project involves the assessment of the efficacy of two different image guided techniques in patients with low back pain due to arthritis of the sacroiliac joint (SIJ). Intra-articular injection of local anesthetics and steroids is performed to relieve pain originating from the SIJ. Fluoroscopy has been used traditionally for image guidance for this procedure but there is a growing interest in use of ultrasound (US) for this procedure. US avoids radiation exposure to the patient and the health care team (HCT) and is less expensive. We aim to compare procedural efficacy related outcomes for SIJ injections performed using these image-guided modalities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sacroiliac Joint Injection: Comparison of Xray Versus Ultrasound</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is a prospective, randomized trial. Patients with low back pain which is diagnosed secondary to SIJ disease will be identified beforehand in clinic and offered a therapeutic joint injection. Informed consent will be obtained. Patients will be randomized for SIJ block with 3 mL of 0.25% bupivacaine with 1:200,000 epinephrine and 40 mg depomedrol using guidance with ultrasound or fluoroscopy. In both groups, confirmation of needle placement will be obtained using contrast injection imaging before the injection is performed. Record will be made of the number of times the needle is correctly placed into the articular space, as well as the number of attempts to do so. The final position of the needle will be recorded. Pain scores will be assessed before the procedure, as well as post-procedure at 24 and 72 hours, as well as 1 week, 1 month, and 3 months. Patients will keep a pain diary and will be followed up at 3 months time in clinic.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sacroiliitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Suspicion of SIJ disease on history: pain below the lumbosacral junction; pain with full weightbearing on one leg; pain worse going down hills or inclines; very low back pain associated with groin pain and absence of lumbar symptoms Two positive responses to the following maneuver: FABER (flexion abduction and external rotation of hip), POSH (posterior shear test), REAB (resisted abduction) Baseline NRS pain score &gt; or = to 4 Refractory to oral analgesic therapy ongoing litigation issues related to the patient's pain pregnancy allergy to steroids or local anesthetics multiple comorbidities BMI &gt; 35</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sacroiliac Joint</keyword>
	<keyword>Ultrasound</keyword>
	<keyword>Fluoroscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Pain</keyword>
</DOC>