<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01719952</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A double-blinded randomised control trial conducted in the Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology of a tertiary hospital, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia Medical Centre (UKMMC) for two years duration from January 1st, 2012 till December 31st, 2013. The aim of the study is to compare the haemodynamic and cardiovascular effects between intravenous carbetocin 100 μg and intravenous oxytocin 5 IU in women undergoing elective Lower Segment Caesarean Section (EL LSCS). Study hypothesis: A single injection of carbetocin is haemodynamically and cardiovascularly safe and has similar efficacy in comparison to a single injection of oxytocin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Haemodynamic and Cardiovascular Effects of Carbetocin and Oxytocin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OUTCOME MEASURES systolic blood pressure (SBP), diastolic blood pressure (DBP), Heart Rate (HR), saturation of oxygen (SpO2) in certain time after drug injection. The presence of myocardial ischemia symptoms and side effects of both drugs, ECG changes such as ST depression and changes in T-waves. Hemoglobin and troponin-T level The need for additional oxytocin infusion and estimated blood loss The time interval between initial drug administration, type of additional oxytocic intervention that used and complication that happened.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carbetocin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxytocin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Viable, singleton pregnancy ≥ 37 weeks gestation undergoing EL LSCS. 2. Low risk for postpartum hemorrhage, such as no proven abruptio placentae, placenta previa, multiple pregnancy, preeclampsia / gestational hypertension, previous PPH, obesity (based on BMI pre pregnancy which is ≥ 30 kg/m2), big baby. 3. Ability to provide informed consent. 1. Emergency caesarean section 2. Preterm Labour 3. Grandmultipara 4. Multiple Pregnancy 5. Placenta Previa 6. Previous PPH 7. Maternal Obesity ( BMI pre pregnancy ≥ 30 kg/m2)) 8. Have comorbidity illness such as hypertension/preeclampsia, established cardiac diseases, history or evidence of liver, renal, vascular, or endocrine disease and bleeding disorder. 9. Contraindication to carbetocin and oxytocin 10. Language Barrier 11. Women undergoing general anaesthesia 12. Women who has abnormal baseline ECG that suggestive myocardial ischemia</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>anaesthesia</keyword>
	<keyword>caesarean section</keyword>
</DOC>