<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00465634</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the role of uterine artery and maternal serum leptin and lipids and their combination in screening for pre-eclampsia and small-for-gestational-age (SGA) fetuses at 20-24 weeks of gestation</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Doppler and Biological Second Trimester Placental Insufficiency Screening</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Pre-eclampsia (PE) and intrauterine growth restriction (IUGR) are known as major factors in perinatal morbidity and mortality. Routine antenatal care is focused on the detection of women at increased risk to apply this population a program of careful monitoring and appropriate intervention. Uterine artery Doppler during anomaly scan at 20 to 24 weeks in selected women at increased risk, has proved to be accurate to detect those who will develop PE or IUGR during the second half of pregnancy. Studies have reported detection rate of 50-70% for a 5% false positive rate in women developing early pre-eclampsia. A variety of proteins and hormones have been studied as potential markers for pre-eclampsia. Among these protein serum placental leptin has demonstrated higher levels in pregnant women who will subsequently develop pre-eclampsia. However, screening performance of leptin detection in early pregnancy has never been assessed. Our study is aimed to evaluate the performance of serum leptin measurement in association with uterine artery Doppler as a screening too for placental insufficiency.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fetal Growth Retardation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Placental Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronic hypertension under medication Diabetes Thrombophilia Previous history of preeclampsia Previous history of unexplained stillbirth Previous history of placental abruption Previous history of SGA (&lt; 10th centile) History of preeclampsia or chronic hypertension before 45 years in the mother or a sister Obesity (BMI&gt;30) Nulliparous after 40 years Assisted conception with donor Multiple pregnancy Complicated pregnancy with a high probability of required fetal extraction before term Pregnancy requiring termination Unability to understand the study</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Screening</keyword>
	<keyword>uterine artery Doppler</keyword>
	<keyword>HELLP syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>abruption</keyword>
</DOC>