<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00465985</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to provide efficacy and safety data for ACZ885 (a fully human anti-interleukin-1beta (anti-IL-1beta) monoclonal antibody) administered as an injection subcutaneously (s.c.) in patients with Muckle-Wells Syndrome. Part I is an 8-week open-label, active treatment period to identify ACZ885 responders. Part II is a double-blind, placebo-controlled period to assess primarily the efficacy of ACZ885 compared to placebo. Part III is an open-label, active treatment period where patients will receive ACZ885 every 8 weeks after withdrawal or completion of Part II.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy, Safety, and Tolerability of ACZ885 in Patients With Muckle-Wells Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cryopyrin-Associated Periodic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cellulitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eosinophilia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Molecular diagnosis of NALP3 mutations and clinical picture resembling MuckleWells Syndrome. MuckleWells Syndrome patients who participated in the CACZ885A2102 study, will have the option to participate in this study upon disease flare MuckleWells Syndrome patients requiring medical intervention either untreated or treated (i.e. under ACZ885, anakinra, or any other investigational IL1 blocking therapy). History of being immunocompromised, including a positive HIV at screening test result. No live vaccinations within 3 months prior to the start of the trial, during the trial, and up to 3 months following the last dose. History of significant medical conditions, which in the Investigator's opinion would exclude the patient from participating in this trial. History of recurrent and/or evidence of active bacterial, fungal, or viral infections. Positive tuberculin skin test at 48 to 72 hours after administration at the screening visit or within 2 months prior to the screening visit, according to national guidelines. Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Muckle-Wells Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>children</keyword>
	<keyword>systemic autoinflammatory disease</keyword>
	<keyword>CIAS-1 gene</keyword>
	<keyword>NALP-3</keyword>
	<keyword>ACZ885</keyword>
	<keyword>human monoclonal anti-human interleukin-1beta (IL-1beta)</keyword>
	<keyword>antibody</keyword>
	<keyword>autosomal dominant</keyword>
	<keyword>familial autoinflammatory syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>