<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00479739</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To compare a stable dose of salmeterol/fluticasone propionate with a variable dose of formoterol/budesonide where the dose is adjusted according to a physician-guided self-management plan</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CONCEPT: A 1-Year Comparison Of A Stable Dose Of SERETIDE速 Inhaler With An Adjustable Maintenance Dose Of SYMBICORT速 Inhaler. SERETIDE速 Inhaler is a Trademark of GSK Group of Companies. SYMBICORT速 Inhaler is a Trademark of Astra Zeneca.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A randomised, double-blind, double-dummy, 52-week, parallel group study of a standard dosing regimen with salmeterol/fluticasone propionate combination 50/250mcg bid (via the DISKUS/ACCUHALER inhaler) versus a symptom-driven variable dosing regimen with formoterol/budesonide combination 6/200mcg (via a breath-actuated dry powder reservoir inhaler)in adults asthmatics</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Budesonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Formoterol Fumarate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Salmeterol Xinafoate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Documented clinical history of asthma Forced expiratory volume in 1 second between 60% and 90% of predicted Using an inhaled corticosteroid (ICS)at a dose equivalent to 200 to 500 mcg daily of beclomethasone (BDP)or equivalent combined with a longacting beta2agonist or an ICS alone at a dose equivalent to &gt;500 to 1000mcg daily of BDP daily Lower respiratory tract infection within 1 month of study entry Use of systemic corticosteroids within 1 month of study entry Smoking history of 10 pack years or more Changes in regular asthma therapy within 12 weeks of study entry Any significant disorder that in the investigator's opinion might put the patient at risk or influence the study outcomes</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>formoterol/budesonide</keyword>
	<keyword>exacerbations</keyword>
	<keyword>Salmeterol/fluticasone propionate</keyword>
	<keyword>adjustable maintenance dosing</keyword>
	<keyword>asthma control</keyword>
</DOC>