<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02439125</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability and efficacy of eltoprazine to treat levodopa-induced dyskinesia in patients with Parkinson's disease</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Efficacy and Safety of Eltoprazine HCl for Treating Levodopa-induced Dyskinesia in Parkinson's Disease Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover, dose-range finding study in patients with Parkinson's disease and levodopa-induced dyskinesia. The study will examine the effects of three different doses of eltoprazine HCl, compared to placebo, on severity of dyskinesia, parkinsonian symptoms, patient function, safety and tolerability, using Parkinson's disease rating scales, patient diaries and physiological measurement of abnormal movement by means of motion sensors.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyskinesias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levodopa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eltoprazine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>outpatient with idiopathic PD stable dose of antiparkinsonian medication for at least four weeks before the Screening Visit daily levodopa dose ≥300 mg per day divided into at least three doses treated with levodopa for at least three years prior to study entry moderate to severely disabling levodopainduced dyskinesia for at least three months prior to study entry dyskinesia for, on average, &gt;25% of the waking day inability to use the motion sensors or electronic diaries correctly surgical treatment for PD, e.g. Deep Brain Stimulation, within the last six months or planned during the study unstable coexisting psychiatric disease including psychosis, depression or cognitive impairment Mini Mental State Examination score of &lt;24 moderate or severe renal, or severe hepatic, impairment treatment with selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRI) or any combined serotoninnorepinephrine reuptake inhibitors (SNRI), such as tryptizol, citalopram, escitalopram, sertraline, mianserin, mirtazapin, paroxetin, venlafaxine and St John's Wort, within four weeks prior to the Screening Visit treatment with medications with the potential for druginteractions (MAOA inhibitors, apomorphine, aripiprazol, carbamazepine, clozapine, phenytoin, tramadol, quetiapine, varfaine, valproic acid). Patients taking amantadine will comprise no more than 25% of the study population current history of a clinically significant and uncontrolled medical condition that may affect the safety of the patient or preclude adequate participation in the study pregnant or breastfeeding received any other investigational medicinal product within 30 days of Screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>levodopa</keyword>
	<keyword>dyskinesia</keyword>
	<keyword>parkinsons disease</keyword>
	<keyword>PD</keyword>
</DOC>