<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02439203</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, 2-way crossover study is to evaluate the efficacy, safety/tolerability and pharmacokinetics of JM-010 for the treatment of subjects with Parkinson's Disease (PD) with levodopa-induced dyskinesia (LID).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of JM-010 in PD With Levodopa-Induced Dyskinesia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyskinesias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levodopa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent. Subject with a diagnosis of moderate to severe idiopathic PD with showing responsiveness to levodopa. All antiParkinsonian medications and levodopa must be stable for at least 1 week prior to the start of the runin period. Subject with stable predictable peakeffect LID of at least 2 hours of the awake day and with at least moderately disabling. Amantadine and/or monoamine oxidase (MAO) inhibitor must be stopped at least 2 weeks prior to the start of Treatment Period 1(TP 1). Diagnosis is unclear or a suspicion of other Parkinsonian syndromes exists, such as secondary Parkinsonism, Parkinsonplus syndromes or other neurological degenerative diseases. History of any other brain surgery or surgery for the treatment of PD. Current primary psychiatric diagnosis of acute psychotic disorder or other primary psychiatric diagnoses. A history of psychosis and/or treatment with antipsychotics within 3 months prior to the start of Treatment Period 1(TP1). A history of, or current, seizure disorders and subjects requiring treatment with anticonvulsants. Clinically significant abnormal laboratory data at screening. Clinically relevant ischemic heart symptoms or history of myocardial infarction, coronary artery bypass surgery or percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty, within the previous 12 months prior to the start of TP1. History of cerebrovascular accident or transient ischemic attack, coronary vasospasm/Prinzmetal's angina. History of serotonin syndrome. Breast feeding or pregnant women.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Parkinson Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Levodopa Induced Dyskinesia (LID)</keyword>
	<keyword>Dyskinesia</keyword>
</DOC>