<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01295086</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim of this dose-finding study is to determine the maximum tolerated dose of taxotere, eloxatin and capecitabine (TEX) in combination with herceptin given every third week as first-line treatment in patients with HER2-positive advanced gastro-esophageal cancer. Secondary end points are to evaluate progression-free survival and overall survival.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Taxotere®, Eloxatin® and Xeloda® (TEX) in Combination With Herceptin® as Treatment for HER2 Positive Non-resectable Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary aim: To define the maximum tolerated dose of the combination of taxotere, eloxatin and capecitabine (TEX) in combination with herceptin given every third week as first- line treatment in patients with HER2-positive advanced gastro-esophageal cancer. Secondary aims: Estimating response-rate, progression free survival and overall survival Methods: This dose-finding study is planned to include 15 patients with HER2 positive gastro-esophageal cancer, adenocarcinoma. Patients will be included in cohorts of three at progressively higher dose levels. Chemotherapy will be repeated day 1 every third week to a maximum of eight cycles. Treatment with trastuzumab will continue until disease progression. Dose-limiting toxicity (DLT) will be evaluated after the first cycle. In case of DLT among one of the three patients during the first course of treatment additional three patients will be added at the respective dose level. Dose escalation is continued if 0/3 or 1/6 patients experience DLT. Patients will be evaluated with a ct- scan at baseline and after every three cycles to exclude progression and evaluate response. Response is assessed by investigators according to RECIST version 1.1. Blood counts regarding tumour biology will be collected at baseline before 2nd, 4th and 7th cycle and 4 weeks after ended treatment. After completion of treatment patients will be followed every third month until progression or death.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trastuzumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients with histologically proven ECVadenocarcinoma, nonresectable or metastatic disease 2. HER2positive tumor tissue (IHC 3 + or FISH positive) 3. LVEF &gt; 50 % (MUGA scan or echocardiography) 4. Age ≥ 18 years 5. No prior chemotherapy 6. WHO performance status 01 7. Life expectancy of at least 3 months 8. Neutrophils ≥ 1.5 x 109/L and platelets ≥ 100 x 109/L 9. Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x UNL (Upper Normal Limit) and ASAT and/or ALAT ≤ 3 x UNL. In case of liver metastases no UNL for ASAT and ALAT 10. Creatinine clearance ≥ 50 ml/min. Calculated with the CockroftGault formula 11. No neuropathy 12. Planned treatment start within 8 days after inclusion 1. Patients who cannot complete treatment or evaluation 2. Any condition or treatment which after the opinion of the investigator may expose the patients to a risc or influence the purpose of the study 3. Known hypersensitivity towards any of the study drugs 4. Other malignant disease within the last 5 days, except for nonmelanoma skin cancer 5. Other serious disease (e.g. cardiac disease, AMI within 1 year or infection) 6. Pregnant women or nursing women 7. Physical or mental conditions which may prevent absorption of oral treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Adenocarcinoma of the gastro-esophageal</keyword>
	<keyword>Her2</keyword>
	<keyword>Dose finding</keyword>
	<keyword>Taxotere (Docetaxel)</keyword>
	<keyword>Eloxatin (Oxaliplatin)</keyword>
	<keyword>Xeloda (Capecitabine)</keyword>
	<keyword>Herceptin (Trastuzumab)</keyword>
</DOC>