<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02225951</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is initiated to investigate the effect of a nutritional product on the 3-hr postprandial glucose response compared to a control standard breakfast at baseline and after 4 weeks of intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Meal Tolerance Trial in Pregnant Women Diagnosed With Gestational Diabetes Mellitus.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes, Gestational</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Pregnant women, aged 1840 years 2. 18.5 kg/m2 &lt; prepregnancy BMI &lt; 27.5 kg/m2 [representing low to moderate risk category, adapted from WHO expert panel recommendation on BMI categories for determining public health and clinical action (REF: Lancet, 2004)] 3. Singleton pregnancy 4. Newly GDM diagnosed women between 24 to (the latest) 32 weeks of gestation; 5. Diagnosed GDM according to either: World Health Organization (WHO) criteria if one or more glucose values equal to or exceed these threshold values [75g Oral Glucose Tolerance Test: fasting 126 mg/dl; 2h 140 mg/dl] or American Diabetic Association (ADA) criteria if two or more glucose values equal to or exceed these threshold values [100g Oral Glucose Tolerance Test: fasting 95 mg/dl; 1h 180 mg/dl; 2h 155 mg/dl, 3h 140/dl] 6. Willing and able to comply with the protocol 7. Signed informed consent 1. Any gastrointestinal disease that interferes with bowel function and nutritional intake (i.e. constipation or diarrhea secondary to neuropathy, diarrhea due to chronic inflammatory bowel disease, gastroparesis, gastrectomy, galactosaemia, hyperemesis) 2. Currently on antidiabetic therapy, for example on insulin or oral antidiabetic medication 3. Already using a diabetes nutritional/dietary supplement (e.g. Glucerna®, Nutrient Diabetes®) within 4 weeks prior to signing informed consent 4. Known allergy or intolerance for any of the following ingredients; fish, milk, protein, lactose, fiber or soy 5. Any significant medical condition, other than GDM, that might interfere with the study or known to affect intrauterine growth (e.g. Type 1 Diabetes, Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus, Crohn's disease, HIV/AIDS, liver disease, kidney disease etc.) 6. Currently or previously on special low/no carbohydrate diet (e.g. Atkin's diet) within 8 weeks prior to signing informed consent 7. Incapability to comply with study protocol or Investigator's uncertainty about the willingness or ability of the subject to comply with the protocol requirements 8. Participation in other studies involving investigational or marketed products concomitantly or within 4 weeks prior signing informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>