<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02354118</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the safest and most effective flushing solution for maintaining patency (unobstructed flow) in implanted port catheters. The complication rate in patients whose ports are flushed with saline only will be compared to the complication rate in patients whose ports are flushed with a combination of saline and heparinized saline.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Maintaining Patency in Implanted Port Catheters</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to determine the safest and most effective flushing solution for maintaining patency (unobstructed flow) in implanted port catheters. The complication rate in patients whose ports are flushed with saline only will be compared to the complication rate in patients whose ports are flushed with a combination of saline and heparinized saline. These complications include partial or complete obstruction, infection of the central line, and/or the onset of heparin induced thrombocytopenia.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Able to read and understand English Has an implanted port in place less than one (1) year Evidence of a patent (unobstructed) port catheter prior to enrollment in the study Is receiving active treatment (i.e., receiving a therapeutic drug through the implanted port) Current treatment protocol projected to continue for a minimum of three (3) months Anticipates receiving care at the identified centers for 12 months following enrollment in the study Does not receive care of implanted port at any other facility Has documented heparin platelet antibody (i.e., could not be randomized to either group) or other allergy to heparin Receiving therapeutic dose of an anticoagulant (e.g.,warfarin, heparin, enoxaparin) Does not meet one or more of the inclusion criteria</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>