<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="180557">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00744211</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SURG-001-07F</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00744211</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Proteolytic Enzyme Induction Within the Human Myocardial Interstitium</brief_title>
  <official_title>Proteolytic Enzyme Induction Within the Human Myocardial Interstitium</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Medical University of South Carolina</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aim 1: The purpose of this study is to test the hypothesis that the release of endothelin
      (ET) (protein), is directly involved in the induction/activation of MMPs (cardiac enzymes).
      MMPs released during and following Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting may result in different
      heart abnormalities after surgery. It is hoped that by measuring this protein and these
      enzymes, new protective treatments for the heart during surgery will be discovered, which
      could improve the safety of heart surgery for all patients. It is important that you
      understand why the research is being done and what it will involve. Please take time to read
      the following information carefully and discuss it with your family, friends and your doctor
      if you wish. Please ask questions if anything is unclear or if you would like further
      information. Take time to decide whether or not you wish to take part.

      Advanced age is a recognized risk of cardiac surgical procedures, such as coronary artery
      bypass grafting (CABG). Since you are having coronary artery bypass grafting surgery, your
      heart will be connected to a perfusion pump that acts as your heart to pump blood throughout
      your body during the surgical procedure. After surgery, your heart cells may not work
      correctly which may cause an increase in the risk of death or sickness. The cause of this is
      most likely by events happening inside your heart cells and mechanisms outside your heart
      cells. The changes in structure and function around and in the heart cells have been
      observed in the stopping and starting of blood during heart surgery and appear to be caused
      by the start up of proteins around heart cells called matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs).
      Earlier results from our laboratory and others have provided evidence that increased MMPs
      and their naturally occurring inhibitors, tissue inhibitors of metalloproteinase (TIMPs),
      which stop MMPs are released in patients having a heart attack or stopping of the heart and
      coronary artery bypass grafting. Past studies have shown that changes will occur outside
      your heart and vascular system, as well as in other tissues due to age and MMP expression.

      Endothelin is a protein that is made in a number of cell types within the cardiovascular
      system. Endothelin has properties that cause arteries to tighten and decrease blood flow
      after surgery that can have direct negative effects, i.e. an increase blood pressure.
      Clinical studies have reported that high endothelin levels in the early post-cardiopulmonary
      bypass (post-CPB) period can be associated with problems after surgery.

      Aim 2: The purpose of this study is to demonstrate that Sitaxsentan Sodium, which is an
      endothelin inhibitor is administered through the vein and reduces the activation of MMPs,
      which are cardiac enzymes that cause different heart abnormalities following surgery.

      Advanced age is a recognized risk of cardiac surgical procedures, such as coronary artery
      bypass grafting (CABG). Since you are having coronary artery bypass grafting surgery, your
      heart will be connected to a perfusion pump that acts as your heart to pump blood throughout
      your body during the surgical procedure. After surgery, your heart cells may not work
      correctly which may cause an increase in the risk of death or sickness. The cause of this is
      most likely by events happening inside your heart cells and mechanisms outside your heart
      cells. The changes in structure and function around and in the heart cells have been
      observed in the stopping and starting of blood during heart surgery and appear to be caused
      by the start up of proteins around heart cells called matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs).
      Earlier results from our laboratory and others have provided evidence that increased MMPs
      and their naturally occurring inhibitors, tissue inhibitors of metalloproteinase (TIMPs),
      which stop MMPs are released in patients having a heart attack or stopping of the heart and
      coronary artery bypass grafting. Past studies have shown that changes will occur outside
      your heart and vascular system, as well as in other tissues due to age and MMP expression.

      Endothelin is a protein that is made in a number of cell types within the cardiovascular
      system. Endothelin has properties that cause arteries to tighten and decrease blood flow
      after surgery that can have direct negative effects, i.e. an increase blood pressure.
      Clinical studies have reported that high endothelin levels in the early post-cardiopulmonary
      bypass (post-CPB) period can be associated with problems after surgery.

      Sitaxsentan sodium (pronounced &quot;sy-TAX-sen-tan&quot;, and called sitaxsentan) is an endothelin
      receptor blocker, which prevents the negative effects caused by endothelin. Sitaxsentan is
      an experimental medication and has not been approved by the FDA (Food and Drug
      Administration) for the purpose mentioned.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Problem to Be Investigated. Transient left ventricular (LV) dysfunction can occur following
      cardiac surgery requiring cardiopulmonary bypass/cardioplegic arrest (CPB) and contribute to
      a complex post-operative course.1-6 One factor that contributes to LV myocardial dysfunction
      is the ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) attendant to CPB. Myocardial contractile performance is
      predicated upon transduction of myocyte shortening into an overall muscle contraction. The
      extracellular matrix (ECM) plays a critical role in this process by providing coordination
      and connection of individually contracting myocytes which is then translated into an
      efficient muscle contraction.7-12 Acute changes within the ECM have been demonstrated with
      I/R, which in turn would affect myocardial contractile function.13-18 Specifically with I/R,
      increased release of ECM proteolytic enzymes, the matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs).15-19
      Moreover, we have demonstrated increased release of MMPs in patients following CPB.17 The
      ECM is also an important reservoir for bioactive molecules and signaling proteins.
      Neurohormonal activation, a common occurrence with I/R and CPB, evokes the release of potent
      bioactive peptides such as endothelin-1 (ET).20-25 Our laboratory and others have
      demonstrated that ET receptor activation (primarily the ET-A subtype) following I/R or CPB
      contributes to myocardial dysfunction.20,21,23,26-28 Importantly, ET-A receptor activation
      can induce the release of MMPs.29-33 Thus, while it is likely that a number of upstream
      signaling pathways contribute to MMP induction/activation with I/R, basic research has
      provided a link between ET receptor activation and MMP induction. This laboratory is now
      poised to establish that this mechanistic relation is operative in patients.

      Hypothesis. The central hypothesis of this project is that ET is released into the ECM in
      patients following cardioplegic arrest and reperfusion (I/R), which in turn stimulates the
      ET-A receptor and evokes MMP induction/activation.

      Specific Aims. Through a validated microdialysis approach,18,24,34,35 we can directly
      quantify myocardial interstitial ET and MMP activity in patients during cardiac surgery. We
      recently demonstrated that infusion of a selective ET-A receptor antagonist can be deployed
      in patients undergoing cardiac surgery.37 Finally, we have developed high sensitivity
      methods to measure MMP profiles in patients.17,19 Through these approaches, this project
      will address the following: (1) Demonstrate that in patients requiring CPB and reperfusion
      that a direct temporal relationship exists between myocardial interstitial ET release and
      MMP activation. Baseline and intra-operative myocardial interstitial ET levels and specific
      MMP activity (microdialysis/specific MMP fluorogenic substrates)18,24,34,35 will be measured
      in patients before, during and after CPB in order to establish direct relationships between
      ET release and specific MMP activation. (2) Demonstrate that selective ET-A receptor
      inhibition instituted at the time of reperfusion, reduces intra-operative myocardial
      interstitial MMP activation. Using the validated microdialysis approach and a selective
      infusible ET-A antagonist established by this laboratory,17,37 the direct inter-relationship
      between ET-A receptor activation to local myocardial MMP induction/activation can be
      established in humans. (3) Demonstrate that ET-A receptor activation which occurs early
      following I/R induces a cytokine signaling cascade which contributes to persistent MMP
      release. Our preliminary results and past studies have demonstrated a link between ET-A
      receptor activation and cytokine release such as tumor necrosis factor (TNF).13,14,30,38,39
      Since TNF can in and of itself cause MMP induction, then a significant feed-forward
      mechanism may be in place which causes persistent MMP release in patients following CPB.
      This will be directly addressed in the present study through serially profiling plasma
      collected from subjects aim #1 and 2 for ET, TNF and MMPs using a high sensitivity multiplex
      approach.40,41 Thus, biomarkers for ET/TNF receptor activation can be related to MMP release
      during the entire post-operative course. The findings from this clinical research
      investigation will establish for the first time, upstream signaling mechanisms which trigger
      a proteolytic cascade contributing to myocardial dysfunction within the human myocardium.
      These findings will identify potential therapeutic targets and set the stage for larger,
      outcomes based studies.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Interstitial Metalloproteinase Activity From Pre-Bypass Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>These studies were successfully performed by measuring the MMP activity in patients during and immediately following cardiac surgery using a novel microdialysis/fluorogenic activity assay system. In addition, full plasma profiling in patients undergoing cardiac surgery of the MMP system and integration to cytokine activation such as ET was performed. In this last study, which has been published in full, the use of an infusible ET receptor antagonist was successfully performed and compared to non-treated patients. Thus, these clinical studies, which were not clinical trials, but observational clinical based investigations, have been completed, fully reported, and have been administratively closed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Heart Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <description>Ralph H. Johnson VA Medical Center</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <description>Medical University of South Carolina</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Myocardial interstitial fluid
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Women and Men
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  18 and 80 years of age

          -  Body mass index &lt;40 kg/m2

          -  Left ventricular ejection fraction &gt; 30%

          -  This study will assess elective coronary artery bypass surgery patients

          -  If diabetic, be under proper control, (fasting glucose &lt;350 mg/dL or recent
             hemoglobin A1c [HgbA1c] &lt;12%) and with no change in glycemic control medications
             within the past 6 months.

          -  Female of child bearing potential with a negative pregnancy test, or post-menopausal
             for at least 2 years

          -  The patient is an appropriate study candidate as determined by the Investigator on
             the basis of medical history and physical examination

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Previous stroke or thrombo-embolic event in the 3 months prior to study entry

          -  Off pump surgery is planned

          -  A previous myocardial infarction within the last 7 days, characterized by a clearly
             defined ST segment elevation (STEMI) or a clinically significant and persistent
             increase in cardiac enzymes (such as troponin) that is accompanied by clear wall
             motion abnormalities

          -  Documented coagulopathy

          -  Hepatic dysfunction as defined by aspartate transaminase (AST) or alanine
             transaminase (ALT) 1.5 times the upper limit of normal

          -  Chronic renal insufficiency as defined by a creatinine &gt;2.5mg/dL or the patient
             required dialysis

          -  Undergoing HIV therapy that affects the enzyme p450 system

          -  Psychiatric or other disorders that compromise the ability to obtain informed consent

          -  Patient is pregnant or breastfeeding

          -  Is taking cyclosporine A, because of drug interaction with sitaxsentan

          -  Severe left ventricular hypertrophy

          -  Other significant cardiac disease

          -  Participation in any investigational device or drug clinical study within 30 days
             prior to study entry

          -  Active Malignancy

          -  Chronic inflammatory disease

          -  Redo Operation

          -  Severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (FEV1&lt;60% predicted)
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Francis Spinale, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Wm. Jennings Bryan Dorn VA Medical Center, Columbia, SC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ralph H. Johnson VA Medical Center, Charleston, SC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29401-5799</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Spinale FG, Koval CN, Deschamps AM, Stroud RE, Ikonomidis JS. Dynamic changes in matrix metalloprotienase activity within the human myocardial interstitium during myocardial arrest and reperfusion. Circulation. 2008 Sep 30;118(14 Suppl):S16-23. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.108.786640.</citation>
    <PMID>18824748</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ford RL, Mains IM, Hilton EJ, Reeves ST, Stroud RE, Crawford FA Jr, Ikonomidis JS, Spinale FG. Endothelin-A receptor inhibition after cardiopulmonary bypass: cytokines and receptor activation. Ann Thorac Surg. 2008 Nov;86(5):1576-83. doi: 10.1016/j.athoracsur.2008.06.076.</citation>
    <PMID>19049753</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Toole JM, Ikonomidis JS, Szeto WY, Zellner JL, Mulcahy J, Deardorff RL, Spinale FG. Selective endothelin-1 receptor type A inhibition in subjects undergoing cardiac surgery with preexisting left ventricular dysfunction: Influence on early postoperative hemodynamics. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2010 Mar;139(3):646-54. doi: 10.1016/j.jtcvs.2009.11.046. Epub 2010 Jan 13.</citation>
    <PMID>20074751</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 5, 2014</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 27, 2008</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
