<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02519764</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to evaluate the impact of a hydration protocol "at thirst" compared to other "not at thirst" hydration protocols on the changes in serum sodium in runners of the Ultra Trail Mont-Blanc (UTMB) in 2015.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Impact of a Hydration Protocol "at Thirst" on Natremia of the Ultra Trail du Mont-Blanc, 2015 Runners</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The secondary objectives of this study are: A. To assess the relationship between hydration protocols and the dropout rate. B. To evaluate the correlation between body weight change before and after the race and serum sodium before and after the race. C. To evaluate the change in serum sodium into major types of conventional hydration protocols. D. To evaluate the incidence of adverse events (cramps, gastrointestinal symptoms, etc ...) depending on the hydration protocol and the serum sodium.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>The subject must have given his/her informed and signed consent The subject must be insured or beneficiary of a health insurance plan The subject is participating in the 2015 MontBlanc Ultra Trail and has no contraindication for ultratrail activities The subject is participating in another study The subject is in an exclusion period determined by a previous study The subject is under judicial protection, under tutorship or curatorship The subject refuses to sign the consent It is impossible to correctly inform the subject The subject is pregnant or breastfeeding The subject will be excluded from the study in case of early drop out (before 15 km of trail).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>volunteer runners who are participating in the 2015 Mont Blanc Ultra Trail</keyword>
	<keyword>hydration protocol</keyword>
	<keyword>natremia</keyword>
	<keyword>Volunteers</keyword>
</DOC>