<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02519530</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Investigators are carrying out a study to assess the immediate and long-term effects of a positive youth development program (the Teen Outreach Program) on high school youth in Florida. This study will answer the following questions: What is the impact of the Teen Outreach Program on sexual activity and positive youth development at the end of the program and 10 months after the program?</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multi-site Evaluation of an Evidence-based Positive Youth Development Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Schools were randomly allocated to either the intervention or the control group. At treatment (intervention) schools, youth participated in TOP in addition to their Health, HOPE, Critical Thinking, Career Research, or Leadership class. At control (non-intervention) schools, youth simply participated in their business-as-usual Health, HOPE, Critical Thinking, Career Research, or Leadership class. Two cohorts of students were recruited for this study, the first cohort joined the study in August 2012 and the second cohort joined the study in August 2013. A survey was given to youth at both treatment and control schools. The paper-and-pencil survey took approximately 30 minutes and asked questions about youth school, grades, peers, health behaviors, and behaviors related to teen pregnancy, including what the participant believes and does in regards to sexual health. The survey was completely confidential and participant names were not linked to survey responses. All survey materials were pre-approved by school administration and the school district office. Participants will be asked to complete the a survey at pre-intervention, post-intervention, and 10-months post-intervention (Cohort 1 only)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Problem Behavior</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Enrolled in a class selected for evaluation Had parental consent Proficient in English Capable of independently taking a paper and pencil survey Not enrolled in a class randomly selected for the evaluation They joined a participating class after the completion of the parental consent process Not sufficiently proficient in English Could not independently take a paper and pencil survey</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>22 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Positive Youth Development</keyword>
	<keyword>Teen Outreach</keyword>
	<keyword>Teen Pregnancy Prevention</keyword>
</DOC>