<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02519439</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A follow-on, two-year open-label extension study of ganaxolone as add-on therapy in adult patients with drug-resistant partial-onset seizures</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Two-year Open-label Extension Study of Ganaxolone in Patients With Drug-resistant Partial-onset Seizures</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a 2-year, open-label continuation for those patients benefiting from ganaxolone treatment after completing Protocol 1042-0603.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Seizures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pregnanolone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who have completed all scheduled clinical study visits in the previous protocol 10420603 and have shown a minimum 35% improvement in mean 28day seizure frequency over the last three 28day periods in study 1042603 as compared to the baseline of study 1042603. Subjects whose daily study drug compliance in Study 10420603 was 90% or greater, and for whom the investigator feels that the subject was compliant with the full dose as prescribed. Able to give informed consent in writing, or have a legally authorized representative able to do so, after being properly informed of the nature and risks of the study and prior to engaging in any studyrelated procedures. Currently being treated and maintained with a stable regimen of 1, 2, or 3 antiepileptic drugs (AED) at a consistent dose for one month prior to study entry. Implanted Vagus Nerve Stimulator (VNS) is permitted and will not count towards the number of concomitant AEDs. Able and willing to maintain an accurate and complete daily written seizure calendar or has a caregiver who is able and willing to maintain an accurate and complete daily written seizure calendar. Able and willing to take drug with food twice daily. Ganaxolone must be administered with food. Sexually active women of childbearing potential (WCBP) must be using a medically acceptable method of birth control and have a negative pregnancy test at Visit 1 and at subsequent visits. Have any medical condition that, in the investigator's judgment, is considered to be clinically significant and could potentially affect subject safety or study outcome Experienced a Serious Adverse Event or a moderate or severe medically important adverse event judged probably or definitely related to openlabel ganaxolone in the previous study, 10420603 Have Alanine transferase (ALT; SGPT) or Aspartate transferase (AST; SGOT) levels &gt; 3 times upper limits of normal (ULN), or total bilirubin &gt;1.5 time ULN during Study 10420603. Have a history of malignancy within the past 2 years, with the exception of basal cell carcinoma. Seizures secondary to illicit drug or alcohol use, infection, neoplasm, demyelinating disease, degenerative neurological disease, or central nervous system (CNS) disease deemed progressive, metabolic illness, or progressive degenerative disease. Have active suicidal plan/intent, or have had active suicidal thoughts in the past 6 months. Have a history of an actual suicide attempt in the last 5 years or more than 1 lifetime actual suicide attempt as classified by the ColumbiaSuicide Severity Rating Scale (CSSRS). Have a history of drug or alcohol abuse within the past 5 years. As with other AEDs, the use of alcohol is not advised. Are currently following or planning to follow a ketogenic diet. Current use of vigabatrin or ezogabine (retigabine; Potiga; Trobalt) is not permitted. Females who are pregnant, currently breastfeeding or planning to become pregnant during the study. Inability/unwillingness to withhold grapefruit and grapefruit juice from diet during the entire clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Partial Onset Seizures</keyword>
	<keyword>complex partial seizures</keyword>
	<keyword>simple partial seizures</keyword>
	<keyword>anticonvulsant</keyword>
	<keyword>ganaxolone</keyword>
	<keyword>neurosteroid</keyword>
	<keyword>Marinus</keyword>
	<keyword>epilepsy</keyword>
</DOC>