<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00873899</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The EVOLVO study is designed to compare the remote defibrillator management to the current standard of care, to assess its ability to treat and triage patients more effectively.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evolution of Management Strategies of Heart Failure Patients With Implantable Defibrillators</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Heart failure patients with implantable defibrillators (ICD) perform frequent clinic visits for routine device monitoring. Moreover, in case of clinical events, such as ICD shocks or alert notifications for changes in cardiac status or safety issues, they often visit the emergency department or the clinic for an unscheduled visit. These planned and unplanned visits create a great burden on healthcare providers. Internet-based remote device interrogation systems, allowing physician's remote access to patients' data, are being proposed for reducing routine and interim visits and for earlier detection and notification of alert conditions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Death</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Death, Sudden, Cardiac</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient with left ventricular systolic dysfunction, left ventricular ejection fraction ≤35%, as documented at the moment of ICD implant; Patient implanted with a wirelesstransmissionenabled Medtronic ICD or CRTD; Patient must be able and willing to replace regularlyscheduled inoffice routine followups with remote followups; Patient must be able to attend all required followup visits at the study center. Patient is less than 18 years of age; Patient is unwilling or unable to sign an informed consent; Patient life expectancy is less than 12 months; Patient is participating in another clinical study that may have an impact on the study endpoints.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Heart Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Implantable defibrillator</keyword>
	<keyword>Remote Monitoring</keyword>
</DOC>