<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02741089</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This monocentric, non-interventional observational registry study was designed in order to obtain data of patients with the indication for a flexible bronchoscopy to control and optimize a guideline conform therapy of these patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bronchoscopy Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Aims of this registry study are documentation of the characteristics of all patients with an indication for a flexible bronchoscopy who are attended at the University Hospital Aachen (UKA) to obtain new knowledge concerning safety and patient comfort using different medications for sedation. Therefore a routine flexible bronchoscopy is carried out, whereat the choice of analgosedation medication is for the investigators decision, independent from the study. Subsequently the following data are collected: - duration of medical examination - medication (e.g. midazolam, fentanyl, propofol, lidocain) - vital signs at the end of the examination - complications Furthermore the patient should be asked concerning the general tolerance for the procedure and different symptoms like emesis, feeling of suffocation, cough and pain (0 = no stress, 100 = intolerable). In addition to that the grade of amnesia and the acceptance for later bronchoscopies should be asked. Analyzing this data will optimize the internal quality control concerning the conducted examination, collect all complications related to the analgosedation and enhance the patients comfort during a flexible bronchoscopy.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Written declaration of consent Patients with the medical indication for a flexible bronchoscopy Patients who are not fulfilling the inclusion criteria or: Pregnant or breastfeeding women Participation in other studies Sponsordependent patients or patients who are working with the sponsor Patients without mental ability or capacity to understand and follow the instructions of the investigator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Analgosedation</keyword>
	<keyword>Internal Quality Assurance</keyword>
</DOC>