<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02741518</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized controlled pilot study to assess the microbiological and clinical impacts of Fecal Microbiota Transplantation (FMT) in patients with obesity. The investigators will prospectively enroll 20 adult patients who are obese (Body Mass Index of 35kg/m2 or higher) after providing written informed consent. The study participants will be randomized 1:1 to either the treatment arm or the placebo arm. The treatment arm will receive an induction FMT with capsules followed by a monthly maintenance dose of oral capsules for 12 weeks total. The placebo group will receive a placebo capsules for induction followed by monthly intake of oral placebo capsules for 12 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fecal Microbiota Transplantation for the Treatment of Obesity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 18 years or older 2. Obesity defined as a BMI of 35kg/m2 or higher 1. Triglycerides &gt; 500 mg/dL 2. Use of antibiotics &lt;8 weeks prior to participation 3. Use of probiotics &lt;4 weeks prior to participation 4. Alcohol use of greater than 20g/daily or suspicion of alcohol abuse and dependence 5. Substance abuse, current 6. LFTS greater then 3x the ULN 7. Cirrhosis. 8. DM type 2 that is insulin dependent, treated with GLP1agonists, or poorly controlled on oral medications (HbA1C &gt; 10%) 9. Use of any weight loss medication or participation in a weight loss study or program such as Weight Watchers 10. History of recent weight change (weight loss or weight gain in the two months preceding trial enrollment). This is defined as a gain or loss of 10 or more pounds in the preceding 2 months 11. Patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding 12. Patients who are unable to give informed consent 14. Patients who have previously undergone FMT 15. Patients who have a confirmed malignancy or cancer 16. Patients who are immunocompromised 17. Participation in a clinical trial in the preceding 30 days or simultaneously during this trial 18. Previous gastric or small intestinal surgery that alters gut anatomy such as fundoplication, gastric resection, gastric bypass, small bowel resection, and ileocectomy 19. Other comorbidities including: systemic lupus, inflammatory bowel disease, or Chronic kidney disease as defined by a GFR &lt;60mL/min/1.73m2 44 20. History of rheumatic heart disease, endocarditis, or valvular disease due to risk of bacteremia 21. Any condition, based on clinical judgment that may make study participation unsafe 22. History of severe food allergies 23. Use of immune modulators including methotrexate, mycophenolate mofetil, tacrolimus, cyclosporine, thalidomide, Interleukin10, or Interleukin11 24.Treatment with infliximab, adalimumab, certolizumab, natalizumab, vedolizumab or thalidomide 25. Congenital or acquired immunodeficiencies</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>FMT</keyword>
</DOC>