<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01521247</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Despite the clear and often stated need, a formal transition program does not exist for asthma patients as they move from pediatric to adult care in Western Canada. This population is not having their health care needs met. The investigators proposed study would evaluate a well structured transition program designed to facilitate continuity of care for this at risk patient population. Primary hypothesis: A pediatric-to-adult asthma transition program will improve the asthma-specific quality of life of young asthma patients in the Calgary area over a 1 year period. Secondary hypothesis: A pediatric-to-adult asthma transition program will improve asthma control, decrease asthma exacerbations, and reduce health care utilization in young asthma patients in the Calgary area over a 1 year period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Implementation of a Pediatric-to-adult Asthma Transition Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>clinical diagnosis of asthma (as confirmed by a pediatric respirologist or pediatrician with asthma expertise, and including evidence of variable airflow obstruction, bronchial hyperresponsiveness, airway inflammation, and/or response to therapy) patients who are known to be nonadherent within the Calgary Regional Pediatric Asthma Clinic (defined as &gt;50% missed appointments over a 2 year period) patients unable to complete pulmonary function testing patients with a history of significant respiratory comorbid conditions (including history of cystic fibrosis, alpha1 antitrypsin deficiency, and lung transplant rhinosinusitis patients will not be excluded) patients unable to provide consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>Transition program</keyword>
	<keyword>Pediatric</keyword>
	<keyword>Adult</keyword>
</DOC>