<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01521312</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Glucose ACCES study will explore the acute and long term (12-week treatment) effects of saxagliptin in patients with impaired glucose tolerance during fasting and after a standardised breakfast. The investigations will be performed on: - glycemic parameters - on cardiovascular parameters</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ACute and Chronic Effects of Saxagliptin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of this pilot study is to compare in patients with impaired glucose tolerance the effects of saxagliptin versus placebo: (i) on glucose metabolism (ii) on vago-sympathetic activity, arterial stiffness and endothelial function. A total of 36 patients will be recruited in the department of Endocrinology-Diabetology-Nutrition of Jean VERDIER hospital, AP-HP, Bondy, France. The measurements will be performed in the morning 1) at the time of randomisation (Acute ACCES study) and 2) 11-14 weeks after the beginning of saxagliptin or placebo (Chronic ACCES study). We will evaluate at fasting and each hour after a standardized breakfast: (i) biological and metabolic parameters. Furthermore, an oral glucose tolerance test will be performed at the end of the study. (ii) by non-invasive devices arterial stiffness (Sphygmocor®), endothelial function (ENDOPAT 2000® ), cutaneous microcirculation (laser doppler Perimed ®.PF 5010) and cardiac autonomic function(task force monitor®).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glucose Intolerance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Saxagliptin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Social security affiliation Persons without TUTORSHIP that can freely agree to participate to the study Age between 18 to 70 years Impaired glucose tolerance diagnosed during the previous month. Exclusion criteria: Pregnancy Breast feeding Diabetes No contraception Body Mass Index &gt; 45 kg/m² Arterial blood pressure &gt; 160/110 mmHg Creatinine clearance &lt; 60 ml/min Severe hepatocellular insufficiency Chronic respiratory disease Anaemia (Hemoglobin &lt; 10 g/dl) Peripheral arterial occlusive disease Heart failure Cardiac arrhythmia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Impaired glucose tolerance</keyword>
	<keyword>Saxagliptin</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular risk integrators</keyword>
	<keyword>Vago-sympathetic activity</keyword>
	<keyword>Arterial stiffness</keyword>
	<keyword>Endothelial function</keyword>
</DOC>