<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01521208</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to show the superiority in survival at hospital admittance and in neurological outcome on hospital discharge of continuous mechanical chest compression using LUCAS device versus manual chest compressions in patients who suffered an out-of-hospital cardiac arrest.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>LUCAS Chest Compressor Versus Manual Chest Compression in Out-of-hospital Sudden Cardiac Arrest. LUCAT Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary goals of the trial are: - To show a survival increase at hospital admittance after out-of-hospital cardiac arrest of patients treated by continuous chest compressions LUCAS device compared with patients treated by manual chest compressions. - To evaluate neurological outcome on hospital discharge, in two centres (Vall d'Hebron Hospital and Josep Trueta Hospital).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Out-of-Hospital Cardiac Arrest</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Death, Sudden, Cardiac</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: between 18 and 80 years , Suffering from NON traumatic or an unexpected SCA, SCA witnessed (seen, heard or monitored), Attended by an advanced support ambulance (served by doctor or nurse) in Barcelona city, or in the Girona or Lleida area Time between alarmcall to SEM 061 and reaching patient is less than 12 minutes. Biological signs of death Age under 18 or over 80 years Trauma caused cardio respiratory arrest (CRA), including hanging Secondary CRA or intoxication Return of spontaneous circulation previous to arrival of SEM's medical team Known pregnancy Inadequate size for LUCAS device Anything in the study that can delay treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Out-of-Hospital cardiac arrest (OHCA)</keyword>
	<keyword>Chest compressions</keyword>
	<keyword>LUCAS device</keyword>
</DOC>