<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="197840">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00515294</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CDC R49-CE000946</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00515294</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Acute and Residual Effects of Caffeinated Beer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Acute and Residual Effects of Beer VS. Caffeinated Beer On Simulated Driving</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Boston University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Brown University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Michigan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Boston University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to develop information about the acute and residual effects of a
      new product being targeted to young adults. Using a double placebo-controlled 2 X 2
      factorial model study design, we will compare the acute and residual effects on driving
      impairment of caffeinated alcohol, non-caffeinated alcohol, caffeinated placebo, and
      non-caffeinated placebo. Under the alcohol conditions, participants will receive sufficient
      alcoholic beverage to attain a blood alcohol concentration (BAC) of .12 g%. Participants
      will be 144 undergraduate and graduate students, and recent college graduates.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Caffeinated alcoholic beverages target young adults with the promise that the caffeine will
      counteract the sedating effects of alcohol and thus let the consumer remain alert and active
      longer, while continuing to drink. It is likely that in the minds of some young people, this
      promise also translates into the idea that mixing caffeine with alcohol allows one to drive
      more safely than would be possible after having consumed an equivalent amount of
      non-caffeinated alcoholic beverage. These are dangerous assumptions because (1) alertness
      may not indicate the absence of impairment under intoxication and (2) next-day impairment
      from the residual effects of heavy drinking may be exacerbated by mixing caffeine and
      alcohol. We will compare the acute and residual effects of caffeinated and non-caffeinated
      beer in terms of a highly relevant outcome - the ability to drive safely.

      The long-term objectives of this program of research are to investigate factors that predict
      or contribute to performance decrements after alcohol ingestion, with a focus on behaviors
      most relevant to public health, such as driving. The primary specific aims of the proposed
      work are:

      AIM 1: To compare the acute effects of caffeinated alcohol, non-caffeinated alcohol,
      caffeinated placebo, and non-caffeinated placebo on driving-related impairment, as measured
      by performance on a driving simulator and the Psychomotor Vigilance Test (PVT), a test of
      sustained attention/reaction time. We hypothesize that caffeinated beverage will result in
      less impaired simulated driving ability and better PVT performance acutely, compared to
      non-caffeinated beverage, but that performance on these measures following both caffeinated
      and non-caffeinated beverage be impaired relative to placebo beverages.

      AIM 2: To compare the residual effects of caffeinated alcohol, non-caffeinated alcohol,
      caffeinated placebo, and non-caffeinated placebo on next-day driving-related impairment, as
      measured by a driving simulator and the PVT. We hypothesize that caffeinated beverage will
      result in greater impairment in next-day simulated driving and attention/reaction time,
      relative to non-caffeinated beverage, and that performance following both caffeinated and
      non-caffeinated alcoholic beverages will be impaired relative to corresponding placebo
      beverages.

      AIM 3: To compare the acute effects of caffeinated alcohol, non-caffeinated alcohol,
      caffeinated placebo, and non-caffeinated placebo on self-rated ability to drive, as measured
      by a self assessment of ability-to-drive questionnaire, and estimate of blood alcohol
      concentration (BAC). We hypothesize that caffeinated alcoholic beverages will result in
      greater confidence in ability to drive and lower estimates of BAC, compared to
      non-caffeinated alcoholic beverages, but that for both alcoholic beverages, confidence in
      driving ability will be lower and estimates of BAC will be greater, relative to placebos.

      AIM 4: To compare the residual effects of caffeinated alcohol, non-caffeinated alcohol,
      caffeinated placebo, and non-caffeinated placebo on self-rated ability to drive. We
      hypothesize that caffeinated alcoholic beverage will result in lower confidence in ability
      to drive and higher estimates of BAC, compared to non-caffeinated alcoholic beverage, but
      that for both alcoholic beverages, confidence in driving ability will be lower and estimates
      of BAC will be greater, relative to placebo.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Simulated Driving Task, Psychomotor Vigilance Test, Profile of Mood States, Subjective Hangover Ratings</measure>
    <time_frame>Acute and Residual Immediate Exposures</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">144</enrollment>
  <condition>Neurobehavioral Manifestations</condition>
  <condition>Drug Related Sleep Disturbance</condition>
  <condition>Alcohol Intoxication</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Caffeinated Alcohol</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Non-Caffeinated Alcohol</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Caffeinated Non-Alcoholic Beer</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Non-Alcoholic, Non-Caffeinated Beer</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Caffeinated Alcoholic Beer</intervention_name>
    <description>Alcoholic Beer plus Caffeine Citrate powder.</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Non-Caffeinated Alcoholic Beer</intervention_name>
    <description>Alcoholic Non-Caffeinated Beer</description>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Caffeinated Non-Alcoholic Beer</intervention_name>
    <description>Non-Alcoholic Beer plus Caffeine Citrate powder.</description>
    <arm_group_label>3</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Non-Caffeinated, Non-Alcoholic Beer</intervention_name>
    <description>Non-Alcoholic Beer</description>
    <arm_group_label>4</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  College students, graduate students, or recent graduates

          -  Between the ages of 21 and 30 years inclusive (as verified by valid drivers license)

          -  Who, if a student, reports good academic standing

          -  Have not been diagnosed with a sleep disorder

          -  Are not daily smokers

          -  At least occasionally in the past month, consume five drinks (for men) or more (four
             or more if female [based on Flannery et al 2002]) during a single drinking episode

          -  Have a valid drivers license, so as to include only people who know how to drive.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Scores of 5 or more on a screening measure for alcoholism (the short version of the
             Michigan Alcohol Screening Test [SMAST])

          -  A history of counseling or treatment for chronic substance abuse by self-report

          -  Daily smoker (to mitigate confounding of caffeine by nicotine withdrawal, or acute
             nicotine administration, smokers will be excluded from participation)

          -  Current use of medications that affect the sleep/wake cycle or daytime alertness or
             that are contraindicated for alcohol

          -  Presence of a health condition that contraindicates alcohol

          -  Diagnosis of a sleep disorder (sleep apnea, narcolepsy, periodic limb movement,
             restless legs syndrome, circadian rhythm disorder, and insomnia)

          -  Use of recreational drugs (e.g., marijuana) while participating in the study

          -  Working overnight shifts

          -  Female and pregnant, nursing, or not using reliable birth control

          -  Participants who have traveled across two or more time zones in the last month will
             be rescheduled for later participation (minimum of 1 month from time-zone travel)

          -  On average consume greater than 4 cups of coffee per day (&gt;400 mg/day)

          -  Participants who report ever getting motion sick during screening or become motion
             sick after practicing on the driving simulator during Session 1.

          -  Weigh more than 230 Lbs.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jonathan Howland, PhD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Boston University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>General Clinical Research Center, Boston Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02118</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>July 20, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 9, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Boston University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jonathan Howland</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Caffeine</keyword>
  <keyword>Alcohol</keyword>
  <keyword>Alcohol Consumption</keyword>
  <keyword>Residual Effects</keyword>
  <keyword>Family History</keyword>
  <keyword>Psychomotor Vigilance Test</keyword>
  <keyword>Driving Simulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Reaction Time</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Dyssomnias</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neurobehavioral Manifestations</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alcoholic Intoxication</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Caffeine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
