<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01156415</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will assess safety and tolerability of 0.5 mg/day and 1 mg/day of sublingual (under the tongue) formulation of agomelatine (AGO178) in patients with Major Depressive Disorder over a 52-week open-label phase. Cohort I is restricted to include patients who have completed a previous Novartis agomelatine (178C) Double-blind study. Cohort II will include de-novo patients (those who did not participate in a previous agomelatine 178C study) and will only be open for a limited time span ranging from approximately June to Sept 2010, at which point this cohort II will be closed to enrollment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-label Long Term (52 Weeks) Safety and Tolerability of Agomelatine Sublingual Tablets in Major Depressive Disorder (MDD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>S 20098</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Inclusion Criteria Cohort I: Documentation of completion of a Novartis AGO178C Doubleblind Study in MDD patients. Male and female adults, 18 through 71 years of age, inclusive (i.e., same age range as for Doubleblind Study, but with upper age limit increased by 1year to accommodate patients whose age increased during the Doubleblind Study). Female patients should continue to use effective contraception as defined in doubleblind study protocol. Key Inclusion criteria Cohort II: Male and female adults, 18 through 70 years of age, inclusive. Diagnosis of MDD, single or recurrent episode, according to DSMIV criteria. Current episode ≥4 weeks. CGISeverity score ≥4 at Screening and Baseline. Key Exclusion Criteria Cohort I: Concomitant use of fluvoxamine. Any significant medical condition that emerged during Doubleblind Phase of a previous study, which may interfere with study participation and/or study assessments as assessed by the investigator. Key Exclusion criteria Cohort II: History of bipolar disorder (I or II), schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder, eating disorder (current or during previous one year), obsessivecompulsive disorder. Any other current Axis I disorder other than MDD which is the focus of treatment. Substance or alcohol abuse in the last 30 days, dependence in the last 6 months. Prior exposure to agomelatine. Female patients of childbearing potential who are not using effective contraception. Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>71 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>agomelatine</keyword>
	<keyword>Major Depressive Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>MDD</keyword>
	<keyword>depression</keyword>
</DOC>