<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="215223">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00283803</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>01-9710-A04</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>EX1006</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00283803</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>To Lengthen the Duration of the Off-Treatment of Intermittent Androgen Suppression</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Effect of Exisulind on the Duration of the &quot;Off-Treatment&quot; Interval on Patients With Biochemical Relapse of Prostate Cancer Who Are Treated With Intermittent Androgen Suppression</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Washington</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>OSI Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Washington</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research study is to determine if an investigational drug called
      Exisulind will extend the &quot;off-treatment&quot; period of patients receiving intermittent androgen
      suppression.

      There is evidence suggesting that alternating between periods of treatment and no treatment
      with androgen suppressants may delay the time to develop androgen-insensitive progression
      and improve overall quality of life. During intermittent androgen suppression (IAS)
      treatments, men receive an LHRH agonist and antiandrogen for a fixed period of time
      (approximately 9 months) and then enter an off-treatment period, whose length will vary,
      depending on the rate of rise in the patient's PSA. Once the PSA reaches an established
      threshold (1 ng/mL in men who have had a prostatectomy or 4 ng/ml in men with an intact
      prostate), androgen suppression will be re-initiated for another 9 months. These cycles of
      on-treatment/off-treatment will be repeated until patient no longer responds to the androgen
      suppression and it is clear that their cancer is progressing. It has been observed that
      off-treatment periods tend to become shorter with each successive cycle of androgen
      suppression, presumably due to the emergence of androgen-independent clones. This study
      proposes to look at exisulind, a pro-apoptotic drug, which may extend the off-treatment
      period in patients receiving IAS.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A study doctor will meet with you and ask you about your medical history, examine you, and
      explain the study. We will draw some blood for tests (about 4-6 tablespoons), including PSA.
      If not already obtained, you will have a bone scan and a CT scan to establish a baseline.

      You will be receiving hormone suppression treatment with monthly injections of an LH-RH
      analog such as Lupron or Zoladex and an antiandrogen such as Eulexin or Casodex as part of
      your standard care for prostate cancer. About 3 months before your next &quot;off-treatment&quot;
      period, you will start 1 Exisulind pill 250 mg (2 x 125mg capsules) by mouth twice a day. It
      is necessary for you to start the Exisulind treatment 3 months prior to your next
      &quot;off-treatment&quot; period so that the medication can build up in your system enough to be
      effective.

      Per our standard follow-up procedures, we will ask you to have blood draws every 2 weeks for
      up to 12 weeks after starting Exisulind to check liver function. Thereafter you will be
      asked to have monthly blood draws, and return to the clinic every 3 months for a physical
      examination, to determine how well you are tolerating the study medication, how your cancer
      is responding to the treatment, and to give you more study medication. You will continue
      taking Exisulind during your &quot;off-treatment&quot; period until your PSA reaches a threshold
      level. PSA threshold is defined by your primary treatment. If you have had your prostate
      removed, the threshold is 1.0 ng/dL. If you have an intact prostate, your threshold is 4
      ng/dL. Once your PSA reaches this level, you will restart your hormone suppression treatment
      as directed by your doctor.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>October 2001</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine whether the addition of exisulind to the treatment of patients who have completed at least ONE cycle of IAS will extend the &quot;off-treatment&quot; cycle.</measure>
    <time_frame>to be determined</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the time to hormone-refractory diseases in the patients who are taking exisulind with IAS</measure>
    <time_frame>to be determined</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Exisulind</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Flutamide</intervention_name>
    <description>250 mg tid</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Leuprolide Acetate</intervention_name>
    <description>7.5 mg q month</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lupron</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exisulind</intervention_name>
    <description>Exisulind 125 mg</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>no other names</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  A willingness and ability to sign an informed consent document;

               -  21 years or of legal age;

          -  Histologically or cytologically documented prostate cancer.

          -  ECOG Performance status score of 0 or 1.

          -  Received at least one cycle of IAS with an LHRH agonist and anti-androgen

          -  Willingness to remain off chronic NSAIDs (with the exception of ibuprofen or
             naproxen), including COX 2 inhibitors and salicylates (e.g., aspirin, mesalamine,
             azodisalicylate, salsalate, sulfasalazine) for duration of the study. Patients on low
             dose aspirin for cardiovascular prevention may be included in the study.

          -  Have not taken sulindac (Clinoril™) on regular basis for any indication for one week
             prior to enrollment and willing to remain off of sulindac for the duration of the
             study.

          -  Patients with prior radiation must be 2 weeks from their last radiation-treatment and
             have recovered from all associated toxicity.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Known hypersensitivity to sulindac (Clinoril™)

          -  ECOG Performance status score &gt; 1;

          -  Patients previously on SWOG 9346 or 9921 trials, or any other trials using IAS for
             which adding exisulind may be confounding.

          -  Patients may not have any evidence of hormone-refractory prostate cancer, i.e. 2
             consecutive rises in PSA on LHRH agonist and anti-androgen

          -  Active peptic ulcer disease;

          -  Use of an investigational medication or device within one month of initiating study
             therapy;

          -  Elevations of serum creatinine to above the upper limit of normal;

          -  Platelet count &lt; 100,000/L; hgb &lt; 9.0 g/dL; absolute neutrophil count &lt; 1500/mm3

          -  Known hepatic, biliary tract, renal or hematologic dysfunction which in the opinion
             of the Investigator or Sponsor are clinically significant or would obscure laboratory
             analyses or are associated with lab abnormalities;

          -  Any condition or any medication that may interfere with the conduct of the study.

          -  Bilirubin &gt; ULN. Patients with elevated indirect bilirubin due to Gilbert's Syndrome
             will be eligible.

          -  AST or ALT &gt;2.5 X ULN
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Celestia Higano, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Washington</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seattle Cancer Care Alliance</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2008</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 20, 2008</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 26, 2006</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Celestia Higano</name_title>
    <organization>University of Washington</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Sulindac sulfone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sulindac</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leuprolide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Flutamide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
