<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01443026</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to compare the effects of a lycopene supplement made from tomatoes to a placebo (a capsule with no active ingredients) in men who have abnormal cells in the prostate, but have not yet had cancer detected. This study will allow us to see if taking lycopene for six months leads to favorable changes in abnormal prostate tissue and in chemicals measured in the blood that go along with a higher risk of developing cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effects of Lycopene on High Risk Prostatic Tissue</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Intraepithelial Neoplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lycopene</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carotenoids</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male Have a history of prostate biopsy indicating HGPIN without cancer within 2 years prior to registration. At least 4 weeks must have elapsed between the last biopsy and the biopsy used for baseline data. Have an AUA symptom score &lt;=25 at time of registration. Refrain from taking lycopene, selenium, vitamin E, or other antioxidant supplements within 1 month of randomization. Participants must agree to refrain from taking nonstudy dietary supplements while on study Refrain from taking exogenous hormones, drugs affecting hormone metabolism, or specified nonprescription substances (e.g. saw palmetto, PCSpes) taken to affect the prostate within 1 month of registration. Patients must also agree to refrain from taking the nonprescription substances while on study Be willing to limit intake of lycopenecontaining foods while on study Have no prior cancer (except basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer) or complete remission for at least 5 years Be ambulatory, capable of selfcare and able to carry out light or sedentary work Have a dietary fat intake of 2348% of calories Participant's physician recommends repeat biopsy 46 months after randomization No repeat biopsy planned Not willing to change diet Have a diagnosis of prostate cancer</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Intraepithelial Prostatic Neoplasia</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostatic neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Male urogenital disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostate</keyword>
</DOC>