<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01087086</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether a dietary pattern based on crononutrition and dietary training, together with dietary and psychological control, can reduce the body weight, improve the oxidative and inflammatory state in subjects with diagnosed metabolic syndrome features and can reduce the prevalence of the Metabolic syndrome in the population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Reduction of the Metabolic Syndrome in Navarra-Spain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The dietary pattern that characterizes the present nutritional intervention study is based on personalized diet, by elaborating tailoring-diets for each subject regarding his energetic needs and assuring a high adherence to the Mediterranean Diet. Moreover, the diet to be performed will be a hyperproteic diet to guarantee a satiety effect and a lower recovery of the lost weight, in accordance with the results derived from the main European study about nutrition (DIOGENES). The glycemic index/load will be also controlled in the study diet. The increase of the antioxidant capacity of the diet will be increased by the intake of fruits, walnuts and virgin olive oil among other antioxidant containing foods. The present initiative, based on the traditional diet, aims to integrate the main results obtained from diverse observational epidemiological studies and interventional studies in the dietary pattern of the present study. At the same time, the study will apply the concept of crononutrition by selecting and distributing the foods thorough the day according the physiological needs of each individual. In addition to the quantitative and qualitative composition of the diet, the study will take into account other important factors such as the behavior habits regarding the food, the frequency of consumption, the size of the eating portions, the distribution of the portions along the day, the feeling of fullness, the eating speed and so on. The aforementioned factors have recently been shown to be related to the gain of weight. Other non dietary factors, such as smoking habits, sedentary life, socio-economic level, will be also controlled in the present study. Moreover, the project will integrate the dietary support together with psychological support due to the fact that the state of mind has been shown to be associated with the MS in some scientific publications.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antioxidants</mesh_term>
	<criteria>3570 years old Both sexes: Male and Female Metabolic Syndrome according to the IDF(2005)criteria: Waist circumference cutoffs (male ≥94 cm or female ≥80 cm) plus any two of the following four factors: 1. Fasting glucose ≥5.55 mmol/L or use of antidiabetic medication 2. Systolic BP ≥130 mm Hg, diastolic BP ≥85 mm Hg, or use of antihypertensive medication 3. Fasting triglycerides ≥1.7 mm/L; and HDLC &lt;1.0 mm/L in men and &lt;1.3 mm/L in women or specific treatment for this lipid abnormality Recent followup of diets designed for weight loss Unstable weight in the past 3 months Alcoholic and drug dependence Hormonal treatment No stable pharmacological treatment Eatingdisordered behaviors Severe physical or mental disability Pregnancy Terminal disease Institutionalization</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metabolic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Oxidative stress</keyword>
	<keyword>Proinflammatory state</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Dyslipidemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Mediterranean diet</keyword>
	<keyword>Glycemic index</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypocaloric diet</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperproteic diet</keyword>
	<keyword>Macronutrient distribution</keyword>
	<keyword>Antioxidant capacity of the diet</keyword>
	<keyword>Crononutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>Dietary and psychological support</keyword>
	<keyword>Waist circumference</keyword>
</DOC>