<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01087424</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate efficacy and safety of R-miniCHOP for elderly patients with diffuse large B-Cell lymphoma (DLBC) Lymphoma aged over 80 years by measuring the overall survival.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mini-CHOP and Rituximab in Patients Aged Over 80 Years</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient with histologically proven CD20+ diffuse large Bcell lymphoma (WHO classification). DLBCL with some small cell infiltration in bone marrow or lymph node may be included. Aged over 80 years. Ann Arbor stage I bulky, II, III or IV Ageadjusted International Prognostic Index equal to 0, 1, 2 and 3. Patient non previously treated. ECOG performance status ≤ 2. With a minimum life expectancy of 3 months. Negative HIV, HBV and HCV serologies test ≤ 4 weeks (except after vaccination). Having previously signed a written informed consent Any other histological type of lymphoma. Any history of treated or nontreated indolent lymphoma. Central nervous system or meningeal involvement by lymphoma. Contraindication to any drug contained in the chemotherapy regimens. Any serious active disease (according to the investigator's decision). Poor renal function (creatinin level&gt;150µmol/l), poor hepatic function (total bilirubin level&gt;30mmol/l, transaminases&gt;2.5 maximum normal level) unless these abnormalities are related to the lymphoma. Poor bone marrow reserve as defined by neutrophils &lt;1.5 G/l or platelets &lt;100 G/l, unless related to bone marrow infiltration. Any history of cancer during the last 5 years with the exception of nonmelanoma skin tumors or stage 0 (in situ) cervical carcinoma. Treatment with any investigational drug within 30 days before planned first cycle of chemotherapy and during the study. Adult patient under tutelage.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>80 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>