<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01087489</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patient comfort during and after eye injections will be compared after two numbing (anesthetic) protocols, an eye preparation utilizing three cotton swabs soaked in 4% lidocaine drops versus a preparation using 3.5% lidocaine hydrochloride ophthalmic gel.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Patient Comfort After Two Anesthetic Protocols for Injections Into the Eye</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary goal of this investigation is to determine the relative comfort of an intravitreal injection (same day and the next day) after a preparation utilizing three cotton swabs soaked in 4% lidocaine versus a preparation using 3.5% lidocaine hydrochloride ophthalmic gel. Based on the available data, the researchers contend that a preparation based on viscous 3.5% ophthalmic lidocaine gel, which coats the surface and remains in contact with the eye longer, may provide greater anesthesia and result in greater patient comfort than the topical 4% lidocaine, which is part of the standard preparation routinely utilized in the ophthalmology department currently. Secondary outcome measure is the intraocular pressure rise after the injection, and the authors will generate prospective data to study whether softening the eye with cotton swabs prior to the injection lowers post-injection pressure spike.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Proxymetacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Has required repeat Ranibizumab injections and has had at least 3 injections prior to recruitment Informed consent Age ≥ 18 years Clinical need for a therapeutic ranibizumab intravitreal injection regardless of the medical indication Able to understand and read English Pregnancy (positive pregnancy test) Mental disability Prisoners Patients with fluctuating or impaired decisionmaking capacity Inability to comply with study or followup procedures Previous reaction to the same drug class</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>discomfort</keyword>
	<keyword>anesthetic drugs</keyword>
	<keyword>topical drug administration</keyword>
	<keyword>injections, intraocular</keyword>
	<keyword>lidocaine</keyword>
	<keyword>intraocular pressure</keyword>
	<keyword>keratopathy</keyword>
</DOC>