<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02409771</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical trial is to evaluate the effectiveness of the PRECIZON Presbyopic.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trial With PRECIZON Presbyopic</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Prospective, open-label, single-arm, multicenter clinical evaluation with a 3 months follow-up. The PRECIZON Presbyopic is a lens intended for implantation in the capsular bag, indicated for optical correction of aphakia in adults whom the crystalline lens has been removed and who desire presbyopia correction. The main objective is to evaluate the ability of the PRECIZON Presbyopic to provide near, intermediate and distance vision in patients undergoing cataract extraction / Clear Lens Exchange (CLE) and intraocular lens implantation. Study results will be used for CE-approval and registration and marketing purposes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cataract</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Presbyopia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Presbyopic Cataract patient or Clear Lens Extraction (CLE) candidate Patients wishes to be spectacle independent for near and far vision Patient lifestyle and outlook fit with multifocal IOL implantation Qualifies for bilateral implantation Patient must have a calculated IOL power within the available diopter range Expected best corrected visual acuity of 0.5 Snellen decimal or better after IOL implantation. No secondary surgical procedure planned during the course of the study Availability, willingness and sufficient cognitive awareness and physical ability to comply with examination procedures throughout the entire duration of the study Patients must provide written informed consent The predicted keratometric postoperative astigmatism (calculated with respect to the surgical induced astigmatism) must be &lt;1.0 D. Ocular disease other than cataract that may predispose for future complications or might confound the outcome of the investigation (e.g. anterior segment pathology, glaucoma, corneal dystrophy, ocular inflammation, pseudoexfoliation syndrome, retinal disorders) Acute or chronic disease or illness or use of medication that could confound the outcome of the study or increase the risk to the subject Endothelial cell count &lt;1500 cells/mm2 Amblyopia Congenital eye abnormalities Previous ocular surgery that might confound the outcome of the investigation or increase risk to patient Concurrent participation or participation during the last 30 days in any other clinical trial Patient must not be pregnant or has another condition with associated fluctuation of hormones that could lead to refractive changes</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>