<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01520233</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Studying samples of tumor tissue from patients with cancer in the laboratory may help doctors learn more about changes that occur in RNA and predict how patients will respond to treatment. It may also help doctors find better ways to treat cancer. PURPOSE: This research trial studies gene expression in predicting outcomes in samples from patients with high-risk neuroblastoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gene Expression in Predicting Outcome in Samples From Patients With High-Risk Neuroblastoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - To test the correlation of a previously published microarray gene expression signature with the gene expression obtained with the nCounter™ Analysis System using RNA isolated from formalin-fixed, paraffin-embedded (FFPE), high-risk neuroblastoma samples. - To construct, test, and validate a novel robust classifier that can be readily integrated into the clinic. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. RNA samples extracted from paraffin-embedded tissue are analyzed for gene signature expression levels by nCounter™ Analysis System and correlated with published microarray expression data. Results are then used to develop a refined gene-expression-profile classifier of ultra high-risk neuroblastoma.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Formalinfixed paraffinembedded tumor sections linked to clinical and outcome data collected from highrisk neuroblastoma patients (n=100) treated at the University of Chicago, St. Jude Children's Research Hospital, Children's Memorial Hospital, or Texas Children's Hospital PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Not specified PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>disseminated neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>localized unresectable neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>regional neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage 4S neuroblastoma</keyword>
</DOC>