<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02351726</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Prospective, non-randomized, multicenter post-approval study to collect long term clinical and echographic data on Mitroflow DL patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mitroflow DL Post Approval Study- North America</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this clinical investigation is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of the Mitroflow DL valve when used to replace diseased or dysfunctional native or prosthetic aortic heart valves. The study will be conducted in a minimum of 15 centers in the United States. Patients will be evaluated at each of the following time intervals:preoperative, at implant, in the early postoperative period, at 1 year (between 11 and 13 months postoperatively), and annually for 8 years. The duration of the study is anticipated to be 8 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Congenital Abnormalities</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aortic Valve Stenosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Valve Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aortic Valve Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Abnormalities</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pathological Conditions, Anatomical</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients is indicated for Mitroflow DL implantation according to the Instructions for Use (IFU). 2. Patient or patient's legal representative is willing to sign the informed consent. 3. Patient's preoperative evaluation indicated the need for native or prosthetic aortic valve replacement 4. Any patient amenable to aortic valve replacement with a biological prosthesis should be enrolled in the study, even in conjuction with valve repair, coronary artery bypass grafting and other procedures 5. Patient is able to return for all followup evaluations for the duration of the study (geographically stable). 1. Patient is contraindicated for Mitroflow DL implantation according to the Instructions for Use. 2. The patient has a preexisting valve prosthesis in the mitral, pulmonary, or tricsupid position. 3. Patient requires a double or triple valve replacement (repair is not considered an exclusion). 4. Patient has active endocarditis or myocarditis. 5. Patient is pregnant or lactating. 6. Patient is participating in a concomitant research study of an investigational product.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>aortic valve replacement</keyword>
	<keyword>aortic stenosis</keyword>
	<keyword>aortic steno-insufficiency</keyword>
</DOC>