<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02351791</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of the study is to investigate the impact that feces mixtures have on the peristomal skin when using a standard adhesive.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Exploratory Study Investigating Human Skin Reaction to Output</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Six types of patches are tested: Patch 1: Standard adhesive with own feces Patch 2: Standard adhesive with own feces mixture Patch 3: Standard adhesive with simulated feces Patch 4: Standard adhesive with simulated feces mixture Patch 5: Standard adhesive with buffer (control) Patch 6: Standard adhesive with buffer feces mixture (control) Each subject is randomized to one of two arms testing three patches on the peristomal skin (patch 1, 3 and 5 or patch 2, 4 and 6). Furthermore, within each arm an attempt will be made to randomize each of the three patches on the peristomal skin to one of three locations surrounding the stoma (upper left, upper right, lower).</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Have given written informed consent Be at least 18 years of age and have full legal capacity Have had an ileostomy for more than one year Have normal to slightly red skin on the area used in the evaluation Has an ileostomy with a diameter up to (≤) 35 mm Have a peristomal area accessible for applied patches (assessed by investigator) Currently receiving or have within the past 2 months received radio and/or chemotherapy Currently receiving or have within the past month received topical steroid treatment in the peristomal skin area or systemic steroid (tablet/injection) treatment Are pregnant or breastfeeding Having dermatological problems in the peristomal or abdominal area (assessed by investigator) Participating in other interventional clinical investigations or have previously participated in this investigation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>