<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00125099</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate whether the HIV vaccine VRC-HIVDNA009-00-VP will be safe in individuals who started antiretroviral therapy during acute HIV-1 infection. The study will also test whether the vaccine can increase the immune system function in these participants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety of and Immune Response to a DNA HIV Vaccine (VRC-HIVDNA009-00-VP) in HIV Infected Individuals With Acute HIV Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART) has greatly improved mortality and morbidity rates associated with HIV and AIDS. However, many HIV-1 infected individuals are unable to access HAART. It is therefore important to develop a safe and effective therapeutic vaccine to improve immune control of viral replication and reduce the need for antiretroviral medication. This study will evaluate the safety and immunogenicity of the HIV-1 DNA vaccine VRC-HIVDNA009-00-VP in treating HIV-1 infected individuals who initiated antiretroviral therapy during acute infection. This study will involve a supervised treatment interruption (STI) in order to determine whether therapeutic vaccination results in improved immune control of viral replication. Participants in this study will be randomly assigned to receive either the therapeutic vaccine or placebo in addition to their regular HAART regimens. During the first part of the study, participants will receive 4 vaccinations at Weeks 0, 4, 8 and 24. All individuals completing the therapeutic vaccination phase (defined as completing at least 3 immunizations, including the Week 24 immunization) will be given the opportunity to participate in the second part of the study and undergo a supervised discontinuation of HAART. At Week 30, these participants will discontinue all antiretroviral treatment and will be closely monitored. Participants will restart HAART if they experience a significant decline in their CD4 count, an increase in their viral loads, or if their physicians recommend they resume HAART. At Week 52, all other participants can restart HAART at the discretion of their primary physician. 21 study visits will occur over a period of 52 weeks. After Week 52, monthly study visits will occur through Week 72. Study visits will last approximately two hours and will include physical exams and blood and urine collection.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Treated acute HIV1 infection (initiated HAART during the acute retroviral syndrome AND were diagnosed by a positive HIV1 viral load and a negative or indeterminate Western blot) Minimum of 6 months of HAART, defined as 2 or more antiretroviral drugs in combination At least three CD4 cell counts over 350 cells/mm3 for a period of 6 months prior to study entry Screening CD4 cell count over 350 cells/mm3 within 30 days prior to study entry HIV1 RNA levels over 50 copies/ml for a period of 6 months prior to study entry Screening HIV1 RNA level less than 50 copies/ml within 30 days prior to study entry Agrees to use acceptable methods of contraception History of serious adverse reactions to vaccines History of CD4 cell count less than 250 cells/mm3, opportunistic infections, or AIDSdefining illnesses. Patients who have had one CD4 count less than 250 cells/mm3 or who have had CD4 counts less than 250 cells/mm3 for not more than 2 weeks during acute infection are not excluded. History of autoimmune disease, immunodeficiency, asthma, diabetes requiring insulin or oral hypoglycemics, thyroid disease, bleeding disorder, active malignancy, viral hepatitis, or asplenia Positive HBV, HCV, or syphilis test Suspected allergy or adverse reaction to any component of the study agent Changes in antiretroviral regimen within 6 months prior to entry due to virologic failure (not including toxicities) Previous participation in STIs Pregnancy or breastfeeding Live attenuated vaccines or investigational research agents within the 30 days prior to study entry Blood products within the 120 days prior to study entry Immunoglobulin within the 60 days prior to study entry Subunit or killed vaccines or allergy treatments with antigen injections within the 14 days prior to study entry Prior experimental HIV vaccines Certain immunosuppressive medications within the 6 months prior to study entry Current TB prophylaxis or therapy Active drug or alcohol use or dependence that, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with adherence to study requirements Serious illness requiring systemic treatment and/or hospitalization. An individual who has either completed therapy OR is clinically stable for at least 14 days prior to study entry is eligible. AntidsDNA antibody greater than the upper limit of normal</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute Infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment Experienced</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment Interruption</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Therapeutic Vaccine</keyword>
</DOC>