<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00125606</DOC>
	<brief_summary>For patients with acute myeloid leukemia (AML), allogeneic hematopoetic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) is one of the most potent treatment options currently available. In order to overcome the high risk of fatal treatment-related complications, reduced intensity and nonmyeloablative conditioning regimens for allogeneic HSCT are currently being explored in various hematological malignancies including AML. At least for allogeneic HSCT in AML, the optimal dose-intensity of preparative regimens for disease control at an acceptable rate of treatment-related lethal complications has not been determined. The investigators, therefore, evaluated reduced intensity myeloablative conditioning with 8 Gy TBI and fludarabine in AML patients considered ineligible for conventional conditioning in a phase 2 trial (data published in BLOOD by Stelljes et al., 2005). The results suggest that with 8 Gy TBI/fludarabine, conditioning related and unrelated donor transplants can be performed in AML patients in first or second complete remission (CR) with a remarkably low 2-year non relapse mortality (NRM) and satisfactory disease control. Based on these data a randomized phase 3 trial for patients with AML in CR≥2 is currently being conducted by the Cooperative German Transplant Study Group comparing TBI 8 Gy/fludarabine to conventionally dosed conditioning with TBI 12 Gy/cyclophosphamide.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 3 Trial for AML Patients in CR2 Comparing 8Gy TBI /Fludarabine to Conditioning With TBI 12Gy/Cyclophosphamide</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with AML in second complete remission HLAidentical related (HLA * A, B, and DR) or HLAcompatible unrelated donor with maximum of one Ag mismatch Ages 1860 years Written informed consent from the patient Written informed consent from the donor No major organ dysfunction Cardiac failure (New York Heart Association [NYHA] grade IIIV) Renal failure (creatinine &gt; 2.0 mg/dl) Hepatic failure (total bilirubin &gt; 3 mg/dl) Severe neurological/psychiatric disorder Previous allogeneic HSCT Contraindications for used drugs HIV infection Noncompliance to processing of personal data according to the protocol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>AML</keyword>
	<keyword>allogeneic HSCT</keyword>
	<keyword>reduced intensity conditioning</keyword>
	<keyword>randomized trail</keyword>
</DOC>