<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00793624</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to assess the long-term efficacy and safety of once daily treatment of BI 1744 CL inhalation solution (5 and 10 mcg) delivered via the Respimat® inhaler, in patients with COPD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of BI 1744 CL in Patients With Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease I</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Olodaterol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Formoterol Fumarate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 1. All patients must have a diagnosis of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and must meet the following spirometric criteria:postbronchodilator FEV1&lt;80% of predicted normal (ECSC) and a postbronchodilator FEV1/FVC &lt;70% at Visit 1 2. Male or female patients, 40 years of age or older 3. Patients must be current or exsmokers with a smoking history of more than 10 pack years: Exclusion criteria: 1. Patients with clinically relevant abnormal baseline haematology, blood chemistry, or urinalysis; all patients with an SGOT &gt;x2 ULN, SGPT &gt;x2 ULN, bilirubin &gt;x2 ULN or creatinine &gt;x2 ULN 2. Patients with a history of asthma and/or total blood eosinophil count greater than 600/mm3 3. Patients with thyrotoxicosis, paroxysmal tachycardia (&gt;100 beats per minute) 4. Patients with a history of myocardial infarction within 1 year of screening visit, unstable or lifethreatening cardiac arrhythmia, hospitalization for heart failure within the past year, known active tuberculosis, a malignancy for which patient has undergone resection, radiation therapy or chemotherapy within last five years, lifethreatening pulmonary obstruction, cystic fibrosis, clinically evident bronchiectasis, significant alcohol or drug abuse 5. Patients who have undergone thoracotomy with pulmonary resection 6. Patients being treated with oral betaadrenergics or oral corticosteroid medication at unstable doses (i.e., less than six weeks on a stable dose) or at doses in excess of the equivalent of 10 mg of prednisone per day or 20 mg every other day. 7. Patients who regularly use daytime oxygen therapy for more than one hour per day. 8. Patients who have completed a pulmonary rehabilitation program in the six weeks prior to the screening visit (Visit 1) or patients who are currently in a pulmonary rehabilitation program 9. Pregnant or nursing women 10. Women of childbearing potential not using two effective methods of birth control (one barrier and one nonbarrier).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>