<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00432692</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine wether a falls prevention program can reduce fall incidence in people with osteoporosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Falls Prevention in Osteoporosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Falling is a major health problem in the elderly causing physical and psychosocial problems. People with osteoporosis are at higher risk for fractures due to falling, because of decreased bone strength. The 'Nijmegen Falls Prevention Program" (NFPP) (Weerdesteyn et al, 2006) has been shown to reduce fall incidence rates by 46% in healthy community-dwelling elderly. This program was adapted in order to meet the specific demands and constraints of people with osteoporosis. The contents of the program are an obstacle course, walking exercises, the practice of fall techniques, adjustment of gait abnormalities, weight bearing exercises and educational sessions. The effectiveness of the program will be evaluated in a randomized clinical trial. Primary outcome measure is fall incidence. Additionally, laboratory assessments of gait and obstacle avoidance will be conducted in conjunction with questionnaires about balance confidence and activity level.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>osteoporosis (DXA Tscore &lt; 2.5 in hip and/or vertebrae) able to walk at least 15 minutes without an helping device 65 years or older community dwelling at least one fall in the prior year severe cardiac, pulmonary or musculoskeletal disorders pathologies associated with increased fall risks (i.e. stroke or Parkinson's disease) use of psychotropic drugs</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>osteoporosis</keyword>
	<keyword>falls</keyword>
	<keyword>prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>incidence</keyword>
	<keyword>obstacle avoidance</keyword>
</DOC>