<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00432406</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is: - To elucidate the immunomodulating properties of anti-TNF-α therapy in patients with psoriatic arthritis (PsA). - To ascertain whether magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is a sensitive tool in measuring early response after therapy with anti-TNF-α in the PsA wrist using the Outcome Measures in Rheumatoid Arthritis Clinical Trials (OMERACT) guidelines for rheumatoid arthritis (RA). - To assess whether the lipid and other cardiovascular risk profiles would improve after anti-TNF-α therapy in patients with PsA.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tumor Necrosis Factors (TNF)-α Blockade for Psoriatic Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study was a 12-week, open-label trial of anti-TNF therapy in 20 consecutive patients (Group 1). Another 20 consecutive patients with active disease whom have met the exclusion criteria, or were unwilling to start anti-TNF therapy for fear of toxicity would be recruited as control patients (Group 2). 20 healthy controls were recruited for comparison of the metabolic risk factors (Group 3). Study visits for groups 1 and 2 were conducted at baseline, weeks 2 and 6, and then week 12.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Psoriatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etanercept</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infliximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 or above PsA with active disease despite treatment with nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug (NSAID) 3 or more swollen and tender joints Inadequate response after 4 weeks of, or intolerance to nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug therapy. Methotrexate (MTX) is allowed during the study only if it has been taken for at least 3 months previously, with the dosage stable for at least 4 weeks prior to the baseline visit. Prednisone ≤ 10 mg/day and/or nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs must have been taken at stable dosage for at least 2 weeks before entering the trial. Informed consent Little or no ability for selfcare Used a DMARD other than methotrexate or received intraarticular, intramuscular, or intravenous corticosteroids in the 4 weeks before screening. Topical vitamin A (Neotigason CR) or D analog preparations (Daivonex CR), and anthralin for psoriasis within 2 weeks of baseline. Concurrent treatment with MTX at dosages &gt; 15 mg/week and/or corticosteroids in a prednisoneequivalent dosage of &gt; 10 mg/day. Prior antiTNF therapy at any time. Infected joint prosthesis during the previous 5 years. Serious infections, such as hepatitis, pneumonia, pyelonephritis in the previous 3 months. Any chronic infectious disease such as renal infection, chest infection with bronchiectasis or sinusitis. Active tuberculosis requiring treatment within the previous 3 years. Opportunistic infections such as herpes zoster within the previous 2 months. Any evidence of active cytomegalovirus; active Pneumocystis carinii; or drugresistant atypical mycobacterial infection. Known hypersensitivity to murine proteins Current signs or symptoms of severe, progressive, or uncontrolled renal, hepatic, haematological, gastrointestinal, endocrine, pulmonary, cardiac, neurological, or cerebral disease. A history of lymphoproliferative disease including lymphoma or signs suggestive of disease, such as lymphadenopathy of unusual size or location (ie, lymph nodes in the posterior triangle of the neck, infraclavicular epitrochlear, or periaortic areas); splenomegaly. Any known malignant disease except basal cell carcinoma currently or in the past 5 years.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Psoriatic Arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>TNF-α</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular risk</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunomodulatory activities</keyword>
</DOC>