<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00432159</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is intended to treat patients with symptomatic degenerative disc disease at one level of the cervical spine. The patients will be randomized to the DISCOVER Artificial Cervical Disc (total disc replacement) or SLIM-LOC™ (cervical fusion) to determine the safety and efficacy at 2 years post operative. Follow-up on patients treated with total disc replacement will be continued to 5 years post operative.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of DISCOVER™ Artificial Cervical Disc and ACDF for Treatment of Cervical DDD (IDE Study)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is designed as a multicenter, prospective, randomized, controlled trial. Subjects will be stratified by the number of levels to be treated then assigned treatment in a randomized 1:1 ratio. Participants in the treatment group will undergo cervical total disc replacement with the DISCOVER Artificial Cervical Disc. Participants in the control group will undergo anterior cervical discectomy and fusion with the SLIM-LOC™ Anterior Cervical Plate System with a cortical or cortico-cancellous allograft spacer. Follow-up visits will occur at 2 weeks, 3 and 6 months and 1, and 2 years for all randomized subjects. Subjects that received the control treatment will complete their required study participation at 2 years post operative and subjects assigned the Discover treatment will complete their participation at 5 years post operative. Follow-up for the Discover treatment group will be via a telephone administered questionnaire at 3, 4 and 5 years post operative.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Intervertebral Disc Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Objective evidence of cervical disc disease in 1 vertebral level between C3C7 defined as (a) shoulder and/or arm pain in a documented radicular distribution resulting from herniated disc or bony osteophytes or (b)myeloradiculopathy resulting from mild spinal cord compression and nerve root impingement Unresponsiveness to documented nonsurgical management for greater than or equal to 6 weeks and/or presentation with progressive symptoms of nerve root or spinal cord compression in the face of continued nonsurgical management Moderate Neck Disability Index (NDI) score Able to give informed consent for study participation Able and willing to return for all followup visits Key Significant cervical degenerative disc disease Prior fusion procedure at any level(s) (C1T1) Marked cervical instability on lateral or flexion/extension radiographs Presence of systemic infection or infection at the surgical site Diagnosis of a condition, or requires postoperative medication(s), which may interfere with bony/soft tissue healing History of alcohol and/or drug abuse Any known allergy to a metal alloy or polyethylene Morbid obesity Any significant general illness (e.g., metastatic cancer, HIV)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cervical</keyword>
	<keyword>spinal</keyword>
	<keyword>arthroplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>disc</keyword>
	<keyword>surgical</keyword>
	<keyword>ACDF</keyword>
	<keyword>DDD</keyword>
</DOC>