<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00892346</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The clinical trial is to evaluate the efficacy of single autologous hematopoietic stem cell transplantation with standard conditioning of melphalan 200 mg/m2 followed by thalidomide maintenance in patients with newly-diagnosed myeloma after receiving 4-6 cycles of induction chemotherapy consisting of vincristin,adriamycin and dexamethasone (VAD) or thalidomide/dexamethasone between 18 to 65 years.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Single Autologous Stem Cell Transplantation Followed by Maintenance Therapy as Front-line Treatment for Myeloma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open label clinical trial to evaluate the efficacy of single autologous hematopoietic stem cell transplantation in newly diagnosed multiple myeloma patients. All patients will receive 4-6 cycles of induction therapy which includes VAD chemotherapy (vincristin, adriamycin and dexamethasone) or thalidomide/dexamethasone. After peripheral hematopoietic stem cell mobilization and apheresis, patients will receive a standard conditioning with melphalan 200mg/m2 followed by thalidomide maintenance therapy at 100-200mg orally daily starting from D+60 till disease progression or untolerable toxicity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Melphalan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thalidomide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Man or woman between age 1865 with newly diagnosed Multiple Myeloma for whom stem cell transplantation is considered appropriate Measurable serum and/or urinary paraprotein European Cooperative Oncology Group performance status 03 Serum bilirubin &lt; 1.5x the upper limit of normal (ULN) Serum alanine transaminase (ALT)/aspartate transaminase values &lt; 2.5 x ULN Subjects (or their legally acceptable representatives) must signed an informed consent document indicating that they understanding the purpose of and procedures required for the study and are willing to participate in the study Exclusion criteria: Woman of child bearing potential Nonsecretory MM Serum creatinine &gt; 400 Micromol/l after initial resuscitation patients with previous Grade 24 peripheral neuropathy Uncontrolled diabetes (if receiving antidiabetic agents, subjects must be on a stable dose for at least 3 months before first dose of study drug Uncontrolled or severe cardiovascular disease including myocardial infarction within 6 months of enrollment, uncontrolled angina, clinically significant pericardial disease, or IIIIV heart failure</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>autologous hematopoietic stem cell transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>maintenance</keyword>
</DOC>