<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01877668</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a 12 month study investigating the effectiveness and safety of tofactinib in treating the signs and symptoms, improving physical function and preserving bone structure in patients with active psoriatic arthritis and had inadequate response to a traditional, non-biologic disease modifying anti-rheumatic drug. Adalimumab is use as a comparator.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy And Safety Of Tofacitinib In Psoriatic Arthritis: Comparator Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Psoriatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tofacitinib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males or females, aged &gt;= 18 years at time of consent. Have a diagnosis of Psoriatic arthritis (PsA) of &gt;= 6 months Meet the Classification Criteria of PsA (CASPAR) at time of screening Must not have been adequately treated with a a traditional nonbiologic disease modifying antirheumatic drug (DMARD). Concurrent treatment with methotrexate, leflunomide, or sulfasalazine allowed and required Must not have taken a biologic Tumour Necrosis Factor Inhibitor Must have 3 or more swollen joints AND 3 or more tender joints Must have active psoriasis skin lesions Have nonplaque forms of psoriasis, eg erythrodermic, guttate or pustular, with the exception of nail psoriasis which is allowed Pregnant or breast feeding, females of childbearing potential not using highly effective contraception New York Heart Association Class III and IV congestive heart failure History of hypersensitivity or infusion reaction to biologic agents Infection with HIV, hepatitis B virus, hepatitis C virus, or other chronic infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>psoriatic arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>radiographic changes</keyword>
	<keyword>active comparator</keyword>
	<keyword>tofacitinib</keyword>
</DOC>