<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02184260</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Clinical efficacy and safety of Metamizole 2 g i.v. versus placebo, as antithermic therapy in the acute phase of ischemic stroke.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Metamizole Versus Placebo as Antithermic Therapy in the Acute Phase of Ischemic Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dipyrone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age over 18 years Hemispherical cerebral infarction with moderate (SSS = 3044 points) or severe (SSS &lt; 30 points) deficit at the time of inclusion. However, only patients with a score between 15 and 44 points on the SSS scale will be included Tympanic temperature between 37 and 38 degrees Celsius. The relationship between tympanic and body temperature is as follows: tympanic temperature = body temperature + 0.3 degrees Celsius Onset of cerebral infarction symptoms within the last 24 hours. When the time of onset of symptoms is unknown (e.g. ictus occurred while sleeping) the last time when the patient was asymptomatic will be considered as time of onset Normal cerebral CT scan or with signs of cerebral infarction Patient's written or orally witnessed informed consent in accordance with local legislation, guidelines of Good Clinical Practice (GCP) and International Conference on Harmonization (ICH)GCP Patients with a history of granulocytopenia, thrombocytopenia or aplastic blood diseases of any etiology. Known hypersensitivity to salicylates, pyrazolones and other nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs). NSAIDinduced bronchial asthma Patients with a history indicating a life expectancy less than 30 days or patients whom the investigator thinks that it will not be possible to follow for entire 30 days Noncooperative Patients with neurological sequelae of a previous stroke Cerebral hemorrhage Pregnancy, lactation Participation in another clinical trial Intake of acetylsalicylic acid (ASA) &gt; 300 mg per day, paracetamol or NSAIDs during the 24 hours prior to administration of the study medication Seizures at the start of the stroke</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>