<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01352286</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to 1) evaluate the safety and tolerability of autologous genetically modified T cells transduced to express the high affinity NY-ESO-1c259 TCR in HLA-A2+ subjects and 2) measure the incidence of GVHD in patients following infusion of TCR modified autologous T cells.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Redirected Auto T Cells for Advanced Myeloma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of autologous genetically modified T cells. Genetic material is transferred into the subject's previously harvested autologous T cells to redirect them to target myeloma cells rather than their usual target. Study subjects must have systemic or multifocal myeloma requiring autologous stem cell transplantation whose disease has relapsed or incompletely responded to prior therapy or have high-risk features. Subjects must also have measureable disease on study entry, as defined by quantifiable or detectable levels of serum or urine paraprotein or elevated serum free light chains with an abnormal ratio.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Myeloma has relapsed, progressed, or failed to respond after at least one prior course of therapy (consisting of at least 2 treatment cycles or months of therapy) Myeloma has responded partially to initial therapy but a complete response (immunofixation negative and normal serum free light chain) has NOT developed after a minimum of 3 cycles or months of initial therapy Myeloma has highrisk features as defined by the presence of one or more cytogenetic abnormalities known to confer a poor outcome even after standard autotransplants: complex karyotype (≥ to 3 abnormalities), t(4;14), t(14;16), del (17) (p13.1), and/or chromosome 13 abnormalities. These patients may be enrolled even while in complete or nearcomplete remission Measurable disease on study entry, as defined by quantifiable or detectable levels of serum or urine paraprotein or elevated serum free light chains with abnormal ratio Patients who are in complete remission at the time of proposed study entry (serum and urine immunofixation consistently negative and normal serum free light chains) are not eligible unless their disease meets the criteria for highrisk as defined in protocol Ages 1880 ECOG performance status 02 (unless due solely to bone pain) Prior to Lenalidomide maintenance phase, all study participants must be registered into the mandatory RevAssist® program, and be willing and able to comply with the requirements of RevAssist® Females subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test and both male and female (of childbearing potential) subjects must agree to use reliable methods of contraception during the study. Lenalidomide treatment phase: able to take aspirin (81 or 325 mg) daily as prophylactic anticoagulation (patients intolerant to ASA may use warfarin or low molecular weight heparin) HLAA201 patients must have confirmed expression of NYESO1 and/or LAGE. HLAA2 patients must have the A201 allele Adequate vital organ function as defined below: Serum creatinine ≤3.0 mg/dl and not on dialysis WBC at least 3000/mm³, platelet count at least 100,000/mm³ SGOT ≤ to 2 x upper limit of normal and bilirubin ≤ to 2.0 mg/dl (unless due to Gilbert's syndrome) Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ≥ 45%. A lower LVEF is permissible if a formal cardiologic evaluation reveals no evidence for clinically significant functional impairment Adequate pulmonary function with mechanical parameters ≥ 40% predicted (FEV1, FVC, TLC, DLCO). Patients who are unable to complete PFTs due to bone pain or fracture must have a high resolution CT scan of the chest and must have acceptable arterial blood gases defined as a room air PO2 greater than 70 mmHg Patients should have recovered from any toxicities related to prior therapy or at least returned to their baseline level of organ function. Patients should be off of glucocorticoids for at least 2 weeks and/or other therapies for at least 1 week prior to enrollment Pregnant or nursing females HIV or HTLV1/2 seropositivity History of myelodysplasia History of chronic active hepatitis or liver cirrhosis (if suspected by laboratory studies, should be confirmed by liver biopsy) Active Hepatitis B (as defined by positive Hepatitis B surface antigen); positive Hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody is NOT an exclusion Prior allogeneic transplant History of severe autoimmune disease requiring steroids or other immunosuppressive treatments Active immune mediated diseases including: connective tissue diseases, uveitis, sarcoidosis, inflammatory bowel disease, multiple sclerosis Evidence or history of other significant cardiac, hepatic, renal, ophthalmologic, psychiatric, or gastrointestinal disease which would likely increase the risks of participating in the study Active bacterial, viral, or fungal infections</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Autologous stem cell transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Received initial treatment previously</keyword>
</DOC>