<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00955448</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Prolapse occurs when pelvic organs drop down and cause a bulging of the tissues. An "anterior wall prolapse" occurs when the front of the vagina loses its support, and the bladder drops down and rotates into the vaginal opening. The bladder can cause a bulge out of the vagina. One of the treatment options available is to repair the anterior wall surgically. The goals of surgery are to return the anatomy to its usual position, ensuring that all the pelvic floor organs (bladder, vagina and rectum) can function properly. The ideal surgical repair would also be long lasting. Two surgical options are routinely performed in Calgary for repair of an anterior compartment prolapse. One option involves fixing the organs back in place using sutures. The other option uses sutures plus a mesh made of small intestine submucosa (SIS) that is already licensed for use in Canada. The SIS mesh is slowly absorbed after it is placed in the pelvic area. The investigators do not know which of these two options is the best surgical procedure. Both may have different advantages that would result in better results. This study is designed to try and find out if one of these procedures is better, and if a larger study may be needed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial of Small Intestine Submucosa (SIS) Mesh for Anterior Repair: A Pilot Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Prolapse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pelvic Organ Prolapse</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women who require surgical correction for anterior compartment prolapse. (Concomitant surgery is permitted.) Point Ba of 0 or greater: that is a positive Ba, indicating that the prolapse is beyond the introitus, not within the vagina. Patient must consent to participate in the study. Having an obliterative procedure (Lefort procedure or colpocleisis). Allergy to graft material. Immunocompromised. Previous anterior compartment repair. Are unable to understand English. Will be unavailable for followup.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anterior pelvic organ prolapse</keyword>
	<keyword>Surgical repair</keyword>
	<keyword>Pelvic floor surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized clinical trial</keyword>
</DOC>