<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00372476</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to investigate the safety and efficacy of the combination of imatinib and vinorelbine in patients with advanced, anthracycline resistant breast cancer</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Imatinib and Vinorelbine in Patients With Advanced Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vinorelbine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vinblastine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Imatinib Mesylate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Histologically documented diagnosis of invasive breast cancer that is locally advanced or metastatic Previous anthracycline containing chemotherapy Presence of a certain protein on the cell surface (ckit (CD117) and /or PDGFreceptor) Preferably tumor samples should be taken within 6 weeks of study entry. Most recent primary tumor tissue has to be available for analysis Acceptable health status (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group [ECOG]performance status 0,1, 2 or 3) Exclusion criteria: (for the secondline therapy) Patient with Grade III/IV cardiac problems (i.e., congestive heart failure, myocardial infarction within 6 months of study) and with severe and/or uncontrolled medical disease (i.e., uncontrolled diabetes, chronic renal disease, or active uncontrolled infection). Patient has a known brain metastasis, chronic liver disease (i.e., chronic active hepatitis, and cirrhosis) and diagnosis of (HIV) infection. Patient received chemotherapy within 4 weeks prior to study entry, unless the disease is rapidly progressing. Patient previously received radiotherapy to ≥ 25 % of the bone marrow and had a major surgery within 2 weeks prior to study entry. Patient received either Vinorelbine or Imatinib in previous treatment regimens Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Tyrosine inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Imatinib</keyword>
</DOC>