<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00372762</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients with NYHA FC II-III heart failure will be randomized in a cross-over fashion to 8 weeks of bumetanide versus furosemide therapy (equipotent dose), to test whether bumetanide therapy has a superior effect on insulin resistance compared to furosemide. Patients will be subject to a frequently sampled intravenous glucose tolerance test (FSIGT) with minimal model (MINMOD) analysis to assess insulin resistance and to a 6-minute walk test (6MWT) to assess functional capacity; patient recruitment and retention success, as well as medication adherence, will also be assessed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bumetanide Versus Furosemide in Heart Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Insulin resistance is common in patients with heart failure (HF) and is associated with a worse functional capacity and more severe symptoms of heart failure. The majority of HF patients take furosemide on at least a daily basis for symptom relief. Bumetanide is a loop diuretic with a similar therapeutic diuretic effect to furosemide. There is evidence from observational and small comparative trials that bumetanide has a significantly less deleterious effect on indirect measures of insulin resistance compared with furosemide. However, a formal comparison between the 2 drugs using rigorous measures of insulin resistance has never been conducted in patients with HF. If bumetanide can be demonstrated to have a similar diuretic and a superior (less deleterious) effect on insulin resistance in patients with HF, the potential exists for bumetanide to have a significantly reduced morbidity in patients with heart failure compared to furosemide. In order to prepare for such a study, the variance of the MINMOD-derived insulin resistance from the FSIGT (26), in this group of patient needs to be determined along with the feasibility of conducting such a study. Functional capacity will be determined by duplicate 6-minute walk tests.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Furosemide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bumetanide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Men and women ≥18 years of age 2. NHYA FC II or III HF AND documented LVEF ≤40% within 6 months prior to study entry 3. Taking 20 mg to 80 mg furosemide orally once or twice per day 4. No changes to cardiac medications for 3 months prior to study entry and no anticipated changes of medications for the duration of the study 5. No changes to oral antidiabetic medications (if applicable) for 3 months prior to study entry, and no anticipated changes for the duration of the study (metformin, sulphonylurea type, glitazone type) 6. Ability to provide written consent 1. Known sensitivity to bumetanide 2. Myocardial infarction, coronary angioplasty, coronary artery bypass surgery, admission for HF or unstable angina within a 3 month period prior to study recruitment 3. Planned coronary intervention within 6 months 4. Patients who are taking insulin 5. Patients with chronic renal (serum creatinine ≥ 200 μmol/L) or hepatic impairment (known cirrhosis or AST or ALT &gt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Insulin resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>heart failure</keyword>
	<keyword>diuretic therapy</keyword>
</DOC>