<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02115334</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Early intervention refers to the provision of early detection, early diagnosis, and early intervention for infants and young children with special needs. The implementation of home programs is very important for children with developmental delay (DD). Therefore, the purposes of this study are to: (1) design the preschool home program activities(PHPA), (2) investigate the immediate efficacy of PHPA for children with DD, (3) investigate the long-term efficacy of PHPA for children with DD.The second year is to investigate the immediate efficacy of PHPA for children with DD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Development and Effectiveness of Home-based Programs for Preschool Children With Developmental Delay</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A total of 36 children with DD, aged 2-6 years, were randomly assigned to the professional-based group (professional therapists delivering the PHPA, total n=13), parents-based group (parents executing the PHPA, n=12) and control group (health education only, n=11). Outcome measures included clinical assessments and subjective questionnaires. The clinical assessments were Comprehensive Developmental Inventory for Infants and Toddlers (CDIIT). The subjective questionnaires were Chinese Child Developmental Inventory (CCDI), Assessment of preschool children's participation (APCP), TN0-AZL Preschool quality of life (TAPQOL) and parent stress index (PSI). Tests were administrated before and after the intervention.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>0 to 6yearsold children clinical diagnosis of DD and other related disorders unstable physiological conditions progression or regression symptoms</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Developmental delay</keyword>
	<keyword>Early Intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Home programs</keyword>
	<keyword>Preschool activities</keyword>
</DOC>