<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01787409</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This partially randomized clinical trial studies cholecalciferol in improving survival in patients with newly diagnosed cancer with vitamin D insufficiency. Vitamin D replacement may improve tumor response and survival and delay time to treatment in patients with cancer who are vitamin D insufficient.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cholecalciferol in Improving Survival in Patients With Newly Diagnosed Cancer With Vitamin D Insufficiency</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine if vitamin D replacement in vitamin D insufficient patients with newly diagnosed untreated diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL) can improve event free survival at 12 months to be equivalent to that of a control population of vitamin D sufficient patients. (Study I) II. To assess the percentage of patients requiring treatment with conventional therapy at 36 in months in vitamin D insufficient patients with early stage chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) being managed with observation who undergo vitamin D replacement. (Study II) SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the effect of vitamin D replacement in vitamin D insufficient patients with newly diagnosed untreated DLBCL on overall survival. (Study I) II. To assess the effect of vitamin D replacement in vitamin D insufficient patients with newly diagnosed untreated DLBCL on event free survival. (Study I) III. To assess the effect of vitamin D replacement in vitamin D insufficient patients with newly diagnosed untreated T cell lymphoma on event free and overall survival. (Study I) IV. To assess the effect of vitamin D replacement in vitamin D insufficient CLL patients on Bio-r response rate and overall response rate. (Study II) V. To assess time to treatment and overall survival in vitamin D insufficient CLL patients who received vitamin D replacement. (Study II) TERTIARY OBJECTIVES: I. To study immune effector cells (lymphocytes, monocytes), serum cytokines, and tumor cells from vitamin D deficient and sufficient patients to learn the effects of vitamin D on both tumor cells and the patient's immune system. (Study I-II) OUTLINE: Vitamin D sufficient patients receive no intervention. Vitamin D insufficient patients receive cholecalciferol orally (PO) once weekly for 12 weeks and then once monthly for a total of 36 months. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Peripheral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large-Cell, Anaplastic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoblastic Lymphadenopathy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Extranodal NK-T-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Enteropathy-Associated T-Cell Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Panniculitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Primary Cutaneous Anaplastic Large Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Newly diagnosed aggressive lymphoma or CLL/small lymphocytic lymphoma (SLL) that meets disease specific criteria below: Study 1 Aggressive lymphoma Newly diagnosed denovo DLBCL or primary mediastinal Bcell lymphoma that will be treated with an anthracyclinecontaining regimen (rituximabcyclophosphamide, doxorubicin hydrochloride, prednisone [RCHOP] or equivalent); patients with composite lymphomas can also be enrolled as long as they have large cell component and will be treated with an anthracycline; in addition, patients with "B cell lymphoma, unclassifiable, with features intermediate between diffuse large B cell lymphoma and Burkitt lymphoma" or posttransplant DLBCL are also eligible as long as they meet other criteria; patients with typical Burkitt lymphoma are not eligible NOTE: patients can be enrolled up through day 1 of cycle 3 of therapy; the patient is permitted to participate in any other therapeutic therapy for their disease as long as it does not concern vitamin D; patients can begin their chemotherapy while awaiting vitamin D results and treatment arm assignment or Newly diagnosed untreated peripheral Tcell nonHodgkin lymphoma (NHL) that will be treated with chemotherapy; NOTE: patients can be enrolled up through day 1 of cycle 3 of therapy; this includes the following disease types: Peripheral T cell lymphoma, unspecified Anaplastic large cell lymphoma (T and null cell type) Extranodal NK/Tcell lymphoma, nasal type Enteropathytype Tcell lymphoma Hepatosplenic Tcell lymphoma Subcutaneous panniculitislike Tcell lymphoma Angioimmunoblastic Tcell lymphoma Anaplastic large cell lymphoma primary cutaneous type and Willing to provide tissue for correlative research purposes Study 2 CLL/SLL Newly diagnosed (&lt; 12 months from preregistration on this study) CLL according to the National Cancer Institute (NCI) criteria or SLL according to the World Health Organization (WHO) criteria; this includes previous documentation of: Biopsyproven small lymphocytic lymphoma Diagnosis of CLL according to NCI working group criteria as evidenced by all of the following: Peripheral blood lymphocyte count of &gt; 5,000/mm^3; if present, prolymphocytes should be &lt; 55% Immunophenotyping consistent with CLL defined as: The predominant population of lymphocytes share both Bcell antigens (cluster of differentiation [CD]19, CD20, or CD23) as well as CD5 in the absence of other panTcell markers (CD3, CD2, etc.) Dim surface immunoglobulin expression Restricted surface kappa or lambda light chain expression Before diagnosing CLL or SLL, mantle cell lymphoma must be excluded by demonstrating a negative fluorescent in situ hybridization (FISH) analysis for t(11;14)(immunoglobulin H [IgH]/cyclin D 1 [CCND1]) on peripheral blood or tissue biopsy or negative immunohistochemical stains for cyclin D1 on involved tissue biopsy Rai stage 0 or 1 Previously untreated Asymptomatic with the plan for observation Life expectancy of at least 24 months Willing to provide tissue for correlative research purposes Both Studies: Capable of swallowing intact study medication capsules Serum calcium &lt; 11 mg/dL; note: patients with hypercalcemia can be enrolled after the calcium is corrected with standard of care treatments Willing to return to enrolling institution for followup (during the active monitoring phase of the study) Note: During the Active Monitoring Phase of a study (i.e., active treatment and observation), participants must be willing to return to the consenting institution for followup Willing to provide blood samples for correlative research purposes Vitamin D level (25 hydroxy D2 + hydroxyl D3) confirmed by central laboratory review</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>