<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02278601</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Epidural analgesia is the gold standard of pain relief for labour pain. Despite this, more than 50% of parturients continue to experience pain leading to suffering and increased caregiver workload. Women who have increased pain tend to have lower successful patient bolus demands when patient controlled epidural analgesia (PCEA) is utilised and have dysfunctional labour requiring obstetric intervention such as Caesarean or instrumental delivery. Labour pain often escalates and worsens as labour progresses requiring an individualized, variable, flexible analgesic regimen. Bolus epidural administrations have been shown to improve uniform spread of local anaesthetics with better pain relief, compared to fixed background infusions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Regimens VAMB, CIPCEA, PCEA</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Our research team developed two novel epidural delivery regimens: computer-integrated PCEA (CIPCEA) (variable flexible background infusion) and variable-frequency automated mandatory bolus (VAMB) focused on individualization of analgesic requirements. This phase 3 double-blinded randomized controlled trial will compare the two novel regimens, and each with conventional PCEA, in reducing breakthrough pain (failure of the regimen to provide adequate pain relief, necessitating unscheduled epidural supplementation) incidence as the primary outcome in nulliparous term women requesting labour epidural analgesia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breakthrough Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Healthy (ASA physical status 1 and 2) nulliparous parturients at term (≥36 weeks gestation); 2. Singleton foetus 3. Early labour (cervical dilation ≤5cm) 4. Request labour epidural analgesia 5. At least 21 years of age 1. parturients with multiple pregnancies 2. noncephalic foetal presentation 3. obstetric (e.g. preeclampsia, premature rupture of amniotic membranes, gestational diabetes on insulin) and uncontrolled medical (e.g. cardiac disease) complications 4. have contraindications to neuraxial blockade or have received parenteral opioids with the last 2 hours.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breakthrough pain</keyword>
</DOC>