<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00700336</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The phase I part of the study is a dose-finding study of escalating doses of CBP501 combined with full-dose cisplatin and pemetrexed in patients with histologically confirmed solid malignancy that is metastatic or unresectable and for which standard curative or palliative measures do not exist or are no longer effective or would otherwise be eligible for cisplatin and pemetrexed as first-line therapy. The maximum tolerated dose (MTD) will be determined based on DLTs occurring during the first treatment cycle. Pharmacokinetics of the triplet combination will be assessed during the phase I part of the trial. The phase II part will evaluate full-dose cisplatin and pemetrexed combined with CBP501 (at the MTD determined in the phase I part) in previously untreated, unresectable malignant pleural mesothelioma patients. Patients will be randomized in a 2 : 1 ratio to pemetrexed, cisplatin and CBP501 (Arm A) or to pemetrexed and cisplatin (Arm B); randomization will be stratified according to histology and performance status.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of CBP501 + Pemetrexed + Cisplatin on MPM (Phase I/II)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Mesothelioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Signed informed consent obtained prior to initiation of any studyspecific procedures 2. Phase I: Histologically confirmed solid malignancy that is metastatic or unresectable and for which standard curative or palliative measures do not exist or are no longer effective or would otherwise be eligible for cisplatin and pemetrexed as firstline therapy Phase II: Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM), not amenable for radical resection, who has not received previous chemotherapy or other systemic treatment 3. Measurable disease according to the modified Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST, see below) 4. Male or female patients aged at least 18 years 5. ECOG Performance Status (PS): 02 6. Previous anticancer treatment must be discontinued at least 3 weeks prior to first dose of study treatment (6 weeks for mitomycin C; 6 weeks for antiandrogen therapy if discontinued prior to treatment initiation, with the exception of 8 weeks for bicalutamide) 7. Life expectancy greater than 3 months 8. Adequate organ function 9. Female patients of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test and be using at least one form of contraception as approved by the Investigator for 4 weeks prior to the study and 4 months after the last dose of study drug. For the purposes of this study, childbearing potential is defined as: "All female patients unless they are postmenopausal for at least one year or are surgically sterile" 10. Male patients must use a form of barrier contraception approved by the investigator during the study and for 4 months after the last dose of study drug 11. Ability to cooperate with the treatment and followup 1. Radiation therapy to more than 30% of the bone marrow prior to entry into the study 2. Phase II only: Mesothelioma originating outside the pleura (e.g.: peritoneum) 3. Absence of measurable lesions 4. The patient has an ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, symptomatic or poorly controlled cardiac arrhythmia, uncontrolled thrombotic or hemorrhagic disorder, or any other serious uncontrolled medical disorders in the opinion of the investigator. 5. Any previous history of another malignancy within 5 years of study entry (other than cured basal cell carcinoma of the skin or cured insitu carcinoma of the cervix) 6. Presence of any significant central nervous system or psychiatric disorder(s) that would hamper the patient's compliance 7. Evidence of peripheral neuropathy &gt; grade 1 according to NCICTCAE Version 3 8. Treatment with any other investigational agent, or participation in another clinical trial within 28 days prior to study entry 9. Pregnant or breastfeeding patients or any patient with childbearing potential not using adequate contraception 10. Known HIV, HBV, HCV infection 11. Presence of CNS metastases</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>malignant pleural mesothelioma</keyword>
	<keyword>solid tumors</keyword>
</DOC>