<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02750397</DOC>
	<brief_summary>HIV-infected (HIV+) individuals who agree to accept and receive a solid organ transplant from an HIV+ deceased donor will be followed to determine the safety and efficacy of this practice. HIV+ individuals who receive a solid organ transplant from HIV-uninfected donors will also be followed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>HIV-to-HIV Transplant at MGH</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an observational study designed to evaluate safety and outcomes of solid organ transplantation in HIV+ recipients of HIV+ deceased donors. This study will evaluate overall survival and graft survival compared to transplantation with an HIV- organ. In addition the study will assess potential complications of organ transplant using HIV+ deceased donors - including but not limited to - HIV superinfection, incidence and severity of graft rejection, recurrence of HIV-associated nephropathy, incidence of bacterial infections, and opportunistic infections.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Participant is able to understand and provide informed consent 2. Participant meets standard listing criteria for transplant. 3. Documented HIV infection (by any licensed ELISA and confirmation by Western Blot, positive HIV ab IFA, or documented history of detectable HIV1 RNA). 4. Participant is ≥ 18 years old. 5. Opportunistic Complications: None or previous history of protocol allowed opportunistic infections or neoplasms with appropriate acute and maintenance therapy and no evidence of active disease. 6. Participant CD4+ Tcell count is &gt;/= 200/μL prior to renal transplant or for liver transplant is &gt;/= 100/μL within 16 weeks prior to transplant and no history of opportunistic infection (OI); or ≥200 μL if history of OI is present. 7. Participant HIV1 RNA &lt; 50 copies/mL (by any FDAapproved assay performed in CLIAapproved laboratory), in the 26 weeks prior to transplant. Nonconsecutive viral "blips" between 50400 copies RNA/mL will be allowed. 8. Antiretroviral therapy: To avoid drug interactions, ritonavir or cobicistatcontaining regimens are not recommended, unless in the opinion of the HIV/Transplant Infectious Disease team there is no alternative regimen expected to control HIV replication. 9. Participant is willing to use PCP, herpes virus and fungal prophylaxis as indicated. 1. Participant has concomitant conditions that, in the judgment of the investigators, would preclude transplantation or immunosuppression. 2. Opportunistic Complication History: Any history of progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy (PML), chronic intestinal cryptosporidiosis of &gt; 1 month duration, or primary CNS lymphoma. 3. Participant has a history of any neoplasm except for the following: resolved kaposi's sarcoma, in situ anogenital carcinoma, adequatelytreated basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, solid tumors (except primary CNS lymphoma) treated with curative therapy and disease free for more than 5 years. History of renal cell carcinoma requires disease free state for 2 years. History of leukemia and diseasefree duration will be per site policy. 4. Participant is pregnant or breastfeeding. Note: Participants who become pregnant posttransplant will continue to be followed in the study and will be managed per clinical practice. Women that become pregnant should not breastfeed.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Liver Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Transplant</keyword>
</DOC>