<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02750761</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a study to assess the pharmacokinetics (PK) of tedizolid phosphate and its active metabolite, tedizolid, and the safety of tedizolid phosphate following administration of a single IV (Part A) or oral suspension (Part B) administration to hospitalized participants ages 6 to &lt;12 years (Groups 1 and 3, respectively), and 2 to &lt;6 years (Groups 2 and 4, respectively).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Oral and Intravenous (IV) Tedizolid Phosphate in Hospitalized Participants, Ages 2 to &lt;12 Years, With Confirmed or Suspected Bacterial Infection (MK-1986-013)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Part A (IV): - Group 1 (Cohort 1 and Cohort 2) (6 to &lt;12 years) - Group 2 (Cohort 1 and Cohort 2) (2 to &lt;6 years) Part B (Oral Suspension): - Group 3 (6 to &lt;12 years) - Group 4 (2 to &lt;6 years) In Cohort 1 of Group 1 (IV) and in Group 3 (oral suspension), participants will receive a single administration of tedizolid phosphate at 5 mg/kg of total body weight. After all participants in Cohort 1 of Group 1 receive study drug, a preliminary analysis of the safety and PK data will be performed and results will be used to confirm 5 mg/kg as the appropriate dose for Cohort 2 of Group 1 and the younger participants, Cohort 1 of Group 2, and subsequently, the dose for Cohort 2 of Group 2. Similarly, the Group 4 dose will be confirmed after data review of Group 3 results. If the preliminary safety and PK analysis suggest a safety signal following a clinical review of adverse events (AEs) or indicate low likelihood of achieving an exposure within 2-fold exposure of adults, the dose will be adjusted in remaining participants.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bacterial Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gram-Positive Bacterial Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Torezolid phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Torezolid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxazolidinones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Receiving prophylaxis for or with a confirmed or suspected infection with Grampositive bacteria and receiving concurrent antibiotic treatment with Grampositive antibacterial activity; Weight &gt;5th percentile and &lt;95th percentile based on age; Stable condition as determined from medical history, physical examination, minimally 5lead ECG, vital signs, and clinical laboratory evaluations; Females must be premenarchal, abstinent, or practicing an effective method of birth control; History of seizures, other than febrile seizures, clinical significant cardiac arrhythmia, cystic fibrosis, moderate or severe renal impairment, or any physical condition that could interfere with the study results; Recent (3 month) history or current infection with viral hepatitis or other significant hepatic disease; History of drug allergy or hypersensitivity to oxazolidinones; Pregnant or breast feeding; Significant blood loss within 60 days prior to study start; Any acute or chronic condition that would limit the participant's ability to complete and/or participate in this clinical study. Treatment with investigational medicinal product within 30 days before the infusion/dose of study drug. Oral administration of methotrexate, topotecan, irinotecan or rosuvastatin, during administration of oral study drug. Administration during the followup period is allowed, as is administration during treatment with IV study drug.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>