<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02750501</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Protocol 0000498 is a multi center, open label study to evaluate the safety, tolerability and fat absorption of sustained Relizorb (immobilized lipase cartridge) use for patients with cystic fibrosis and exocrine pancreatic insufficiency who receive enteral tube feeding.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Absorption and Safety With Sustained Use of Relizorb Evaluation (ASSURE) Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>At study entry (Day -14), blood and urine will be collected at screening to assess baseline plasma and erythrocyte membrane concentrations of docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) and eicosapentaenoic (EPA), plasma concentrations of other long chain fatty acids, fat-soluble vitamins, serum protein and urinary leukotriene concentrations. Body weight and body mass index will be obtained. During an initial 7 day observation period (Day -14 to Day -8), subjects will follow their usual enteral nutrition regimen, including use of pancreatic enzyme replacement therapy (PERT). During the 7 day run in period (Day -7 to Day -1), subjects will use Peptamen 1.5 at their normal volume of administration from 500 mL to 1,000 mL per feeding and follow their normal PERT regimen. On baseline Day 1, subjects will receive Impact Peptide up to a maximum volume of 1,000 mL per feeding for the 90 day treatment period with Relizorb. Blood and urine will be collected to repeat the screening concentration measurements. Standard use of PERT is allowed with daily meals but not permitted with use of Relizorb during enteral feedings. Safety and tolerability will be assessed using a gastrointestinal symptom diary, adverse events and unanticipated adverse device effects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Exocrine Pancreatic Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Confirmed diagnosis of cystic fibrosis with 2 clinical features 2. Documented history of exocrine pancreatic insufficiency 3. Enteral formula use a minimum of 4x/week, using PERT, consuming an unrestricted fat diet, and willing to use Peptamen 1.5 and Impact Peptide 1.5 4. Written informed consent or assent. 1. Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus 2. Signs and symptoms of liver cirrhosis or portal hypertension 3. Lung or liver transplant 4. Active cancer currently receiving cancer treatment 5. Crohn's or celiac disease, infectious gastroenteritis, sprue, lactose intolerance, inflammatory bowel disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>