<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02750813</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the lens fit characteristics, specifically lens centration, of ACUVUE® OASYS® 1-DAY (AO1D) contact lenses and DAILIES TOTAL1® (DT1) contact lenses.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ACUVUE® OASYS® 1-DAY vs DAILIES TOTAL1®</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Refractive Errors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must sign informed consent form; Adapted, current daily disposable soft contact lens wearer who typically wears lenses every day, or at least 5 days per week, 6 hours per day; Symptoms of contact lens discomfort as defined by the Symptomatology (Eligibility) Prescreening questionnaire; Prescription within 1.00 Diopter (D) to 6.00D to be fitted with study contact lenses; Cylinder equal or lower than 0.75D in both eyes; Vision correctable to 20/25 or 0.1 logMAR (Logarithmic minimum angle of resolution) or better in each eye at distance with both study lenses at Visit 1; Can be successfully fitted with both study lenses; Willing to wear lenses every day or at least 5 days per week, 6 hours per day and attend all study visits; Other protocolspecified inclusion criteria may apply. Ocular anterior segment infection, inflammation, abnormality, or active disease that would contraindicate contact lens wear; Use of systemic or ocular medications for which contact lens wear could be contraindicated as determined by the Investigator; Monocular (only 1 eye with functional vision) or fit with only 1 lens; Fitted with monovision; Prior refractive surgery; History of herpetic keratitis, ocular surgery, or irregular cornea; Pregnant or lactating; Use of mechanical eyelid therapy or eyelid scrubs within 14 days before Visit 1 and not willing to discontinue during the study; Participation in any clinical study within 30 days of Visit 1; Current DT1 or AO1D lens wearer; Other protocolspecified exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>