<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01000064</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to evaluate whether Vyvanse, a psychostimulant, can help with attention deficits due to traumatic brain injury (TBI). Vyvanse is currently approved for the treatment of Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity (ADHD). The exact effects this drug may have on attention deficits caused by TBI are not known, but we expect that Vyvanse will be of some help in treating those types of problems as well. The study will utilize functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) methods, as well as neurobehavioral measures, to elucidate neural mechanisms of response.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Traumatic Brain Injury (TBI)-Related Attention Deficits</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Symptoms of inattentiveness, impulsivity, and poor persistence have been observed in both children and adults following traumatic brain injury (TBI). These often are among the most prominent symptoms manifested and may contribute to interference in a variety of other functional domains. Although there has been some use of psychostimulant medication to treat TBI-acquired attention deficits, it remains a relatively uncommon clinical practice. This study, by highlighting mechanisms of action, could serve to promote the appropriate use of this type of treatment for the patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lisdexamfetamine Dimesylate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and females, ages 16 to 45 Closed head injury rated as moderate/severe (based on Glasgow Coma Scale rating, estimated posttraumatic amnesia, etc.) Sustained 6 to 36 months earlier, and considered to be neurologically stable Persistent (&gt; 6 months) problems with focused or sustained attention (+1 SD or worse on Inattention component of ADHD self ratings) corroborated by professional staff (nurses, therapists, etc.) or caregivers. Problems with attention/concentration rated as among most prominent cognitive changes. Accompanying features may include diminished arousal/speed/stamina and/or disinhibited symptoms Penetrating head injury Preinjury history of diagnosed ADHD Other psychiatric conditions such as mania or psychosis. Current posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) symptoms may be present but not so severe as to require pharmacologic treatment. Lifetime history of psychostimulant abuse or dependence. Other (nonpsychostimulant) substance abuse within the past 6 months. Total lifetime drug use will not exceed 5 times each for substances such as amphetamine, methamphetamine, or cocaine. Prior treatment with psychostimulant(s) Tics or other contraindications for psychostimulant use including arteriosclerosis, cardiovascular disease, uncontrolled hypertension or hyperthyroidism, glaucoma, agitation, use of MAO inhibitor within 6 weeks Current treatment with other psychotropic medication(s) within the past 6 weeks Estimated IQ &lt; 80 Sensory and/or motor impairment(s) seriously limiting testing options Other neurological conditions including epilepsy, degenerative disorders, brain tumor, or stroke. Physical conditions affecting arousal, activity level or stamina, including uncontrolled thyroid dysfunction, anemia, autoimmune or metabolic disorders, untreated moderate/severe sleep apnea, etc. Persons for whom MRI scanning is contraindicated, including weight greater than 275 pounds (due to scanner table limitations), severe claustrophobia, implanted electronic medical devices (e.g. pacemaker, cochlear or other inner ear implant, deep brain stimulator), metallic foreign object in eye or rest of the body, history of sheet metal work, aneurysm clips, nonremovable metallic piercings, and dental prosthetics.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Traumatic Brain Injury</keyword>
	<keyword>Attention Deficit</keyword>
	<keyword>TBI</keyword>
</DOC>