<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02965092</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) consists of single chain variable fragment (scFv) and activation domain of T cell, and CAR-modified T cells (CAR-T cells) have the capabilities to recognize tumor associated antigen and kill tumor cells specifically. To a large part of patients with refractory or relapsed B cell malignancies, CAR-T cell adoptive immunotherapy can play a revolutionary effect in the field of cancer treatment. The investigators believe that the cells with CD137 will have a better chance of killing the leukemia cells. In the lab, the investigators constructed a second generation CAR containing CD137. The investigators start Phase I study aimed to relapsed or refractory B cell malignancies. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of CD19 CAR-T cells in patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CD19 Chimeric Antigen Receptor (CAR)-Modified T Cell Therapy in Treating Patients With Acute Lymphocytic Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>CD19 CAR-T has stronger effect of anti-tumor capacity. While people have been able to control the clinical complications now, so conducting CD19 CAR-T clinical trials has a strong demand and value. The investigators constructed a second generation CAR containing CD137.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Pathologically and histologically confirmed CD19 + B cell tumors, the patient is currently no effective treatment options, such as chemotherapy or autologous hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (autoHSCT) / relapse after allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (alloHSCT) treatment; or patients voluntarily choose CD19 CART cells as a first treatment; 2. B cell hematological malignancies include the following three categories: 1) Bcell acute lymphocytic leukemia (BALL); 2) Indolent Bcell lymphoma (CLL, FL, MZL, LPL); 3) Aggressive Bcell lymphoma (DLBCL, BL, MCL); 3. &lt; 60 years old; 4. Expected survival time &gt; 6 months; 5. Female patients around childbearing age, negative pregnancy test before trial, and agreed to take effective contraceptive measures during the trial until the last visit; 6. Voluntarily participate in this experiment and sign informed consent by themself, or legally authorized representative. 1. With a history of epilepsy or other central nervous system diseases; 2. Having graftversushost reaction, requires the use of immunosuppressants; 3. The presence of clinically significant cardiovascular disease, such as uncontrolled or symptomatic arrhythmias, congestive heart failure or myocardial infarction within recent six months, or heart disease with cardiac function in any grade 3 (moderate) or 4 ( severe) (according to the New York Heart Association (NYHA) Functional Classification System); 4. Pregnant or lactating women (safety of this therapy for the unborn child is unknown); 5. Not curable active infection; 6. Patients with active hepatitis B or hepatitis C virus infection; 7. Combined use of systemic steroids within two weeks (except use of inhaled steroid recently or currently); 8. Using product of gene therapy before; 9. Creatinine&gt; 2.5 mg / dl (221.0 umol/L); ALT / AST&gt; 3 X the normal amount; Bilirubin&gt; 2.0 mg / dl (34.2 umol/L); 10. Patients suffering from other uncontrolled diseases, and researchers believe that the patient is not suitable for trial; 11. Patients with HIVinfection; 12. Researchers believe any situation that may increase the risk of patients or interfere with test results.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>