<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02965378</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II trial studies how well FGFR inhibitor AZD4547 (AZD4547) works in treating patients with stage IV squamous cell lung cancer that has come back after previous treatment. This is a sub-study that includes all screened patients positive for the fibroblast growth factor receptor (FGFR) biomarker. FGFR can cause tumor cells to grow more quickly. AZD4547 may decrease the activity of FGFR and may be able to shrink tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lung-MAP: AZD4547 as Second-Line Therapy in Treating Patients With Recurrent Stage IV Squamous Cell Lung Cancer and Positive Biomarker Matches</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To evaluate if there is sufficient evidence to continue to the Phase III component by evaluating the objective response rate (ORR) with AZD4547 in FGFR-positive patients. (Phase II) II. If the study meets the criteria specified in S1400, the study will be amended to include a follow-on randomized Phase III trial. (Phase III) SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To evaluate investigator-assessed progression free survival (IA-PFS) and overall survival (OS) in FGFR-positive patients treated with AZD4547. (Phase II) II. To evaluate the duration of response (DoR) among FGFR positive patients treated with AZD4547 who achieve a complete response (CR) or partial response (PR) (confirmed and unconfirmed) by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1. (Phase II) III. To evaluate the frequency and severity of toxicities associated with AZD4547 in FGFR positive patients. (Phase II) TRANSLATIONAL MEDICINE OBJECTIVES: I. To identify additional predictive tumor/blood biomarkers that may modify response or define resistance to the AZD4547 beyond the chosen biomarker for biomarker-driven sub-studies. II. To identify potential resistance biomarkers at disease progression. III. To establish a tissue/ blood repository from patients with refractory squamous cell carcinoma (SCCA) of the lung. OUTLINE: As of 12/18/2015, patients are assigned to Arm I. ARM I: Patients receive FGFR inhibitor AZD4547 orally (PO) twice daily (BID) on days 1-21. Courses repeat every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. ARM II (CLOSED TO ACCRUAL 12/18/2015): Patients receive docetaxel intravenously (IV) on day 1. Courses repeat every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Upon progression, patients may be eligible to re-register to Arm III. ARM III: Patients in Arm II eligible for re-registration receive FGFR inhibitor AZD4547 PO BID on days 1-21. Courses repeat every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, all patients are followed up every 6 months for the first 2 years and then at the end of the year 3 from date of sub-study/re-registration.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must meet all SCREENING/PRESCREENING and SUBSTUDY REGISTRATION COMMON ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA as specified in S1400: Phase II/III BiomarkerDriven Master Protocol for Previously Treated Squamous Cell Lung Cancer (LungMap) Patients must be assigned to S1400D Patients must not be taking, nor plan to take while on protocol treatment and for 14 days after the last dose of study treatment, drugs, herbal supplements or foods that are known to be strong/moderate cytochrome p450, family 3, subfamily A, polypeptide 4 (CYP3A4) or cytochrome p450, family 2, subfamily D, polypeptide 6 (CYP2D6) substrates Patients must not have received nitrosourea or mitomycin C within 42 days prior to substudy registration Patients must not have had any prior exposure to any agent with FGFR inhibition as its primary pharmacology Patients must not have a mean resting corrected QT interval (QTc) &gt; 450 msec obtained from 3 consecutive electrocardiograms (ECGs) performed within 28 days prior to substudy registration; patients must not have any clinically important abnormalities in rhythm, conduction or morphology of resting ECG (e.g. complete left bundle branch block, third degree heart block); patients must not have any factors that increase the risk of QTc prolongation or risk of arrhythmic events such as heart failure, hypokalemia, congenital long QT syndrome, family history of long QT syndrome or unexplained sudden death under 40 years of age Patients must not be planning to receive any concomitant medication known to prolong QT interval Patients must be able to take oral medications; patient may not have any impairment of gastrointestinal function or gastrointestinal disease that may significantly alter the absorption of AZD4547 (e.g. ulcerative disease, uncontrolled nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, malabsorption syndrome or small bowel resection) Patients must not have a history of hypersensitivity to active or inactive excipients of AZD4547 or drugs with a similar chemical structure or class to AZD4547 Patients must not have any of the following ophthalmological criteria: current evidence or previous history of retinal pigmented epithelium detachment (RPED); previous laser treatment or intraocular injection for treatment of macular degeneration; current evidence or previous history of dry or wet agerelated macular degeneration; current evidence or previous history of retinal vein occlusion (RVO); current evidence or previous history of retinal degenerative diseases (e.g. hereditary); or current evidence or previous history of any other clinically relevant chorioretinal defect Patients must have an eye exam performed within 28 days prior to substudy registration; patients with uncontrolled glaucoma or intraocular pressure &gt;= 21 mm Hg at screening should be referred for ophthalmological management and the condition controlled prior to registration Patients must have albumin, urinalysis, and Troponin I obtained within 7 days prior to substudy registration Patients must have corrected calcium and phosphate &lt; upper limit or normal (ULN) obtained within 28 days prior to substudy registration Patients must have multigated acquisition (MUGA)/echocardiogram performed within 28 days prior to substudy registration Patients must also be offered participation in banking for future use of specimens STEP 2 TO AZD4547 REREGISTRATION: Patients must have progressed on Arm 2 (docetaxel) of this substudy Patients must not have received any prior systemic therapy (systemic chemotherapy, immunotherapy or investigational drug) within 21 days prior to reregistration; patients must have recovered (=&lt; grade 1) from any side effects of prior therapy Patients must have measurable disease documented by computed tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI); the CT from a combined positron emission tomography (PET)/CT may be used to document only nonmeasurable disease unless it is of diagnostic quality; measurable disease must be assessed within 28 days prior to reregistration; pleural effusions, ascites and laboratory parameters are not acceptable as the only evidence of disease; nonmeasurable disease must be assessed within 42 days prior to reregistration; all disease must be assessed and documented on the Baseline Tumor Assessment Form; patients whose only measurable disease is within a previous radiation therapy port must demonstrate clearly progressive disease (in the opinion of the treating investigator) prior to registration Patients must have a CT or MRI scan of the brain to evaluate for central nervous system (CNS) disease within 42 days prior to Step 2 Reregistration; patient must not have leptomeningeal disease, spinal cord compression or brain metastases unless: (1) metastases have been locally treated and have remained clinically controlled and asymptomatic for at least 14 days following treatment prior to reregistration, AND (2) patient has no residual neurological dysfunction and has been off corticosteroids for at least 24 hours prior to reregistration Patients must not be planning to receive any concurrent chemotherapy, immunotherapy, biologic or hormonal therapy for cancer treatment; concurrent use of hormones for noncancerrelated conditions (e.g., insulin for diabetes and hormone replacement therapy) is acceptable Patients must have albumin, urinalysis, and Troponin I obtained within 7 days prior to substudy registration Patients must have corrected calcium and phosphate =&lt; ULN obtained within 28 days prior to substudy registration Patients must have MUGA/echocardiogram performed within 28 days prior to substudy registration Patients must not have any of the following ophthalmological criteria: current evidence or previous history of retinal pigmented epithelium detachment (RPED); previous laser treatment or intraocular injection for treatment of macular degeneration; current evidence or previous history of dry or wet agerelated macular degeneration; current evidence or previous history of retinal vein occlusion (RVO); current evidence or previous history of retinal degenerative diseases (e.g. hereditary); or current evidence or previous history of any other clinically relevant chorioretinal defect; patients must have an eye exam performed within 28 days prior to Step 2 reregistration; patients with uncontrolled glaucoma or intraocular pressure &gt;= 21mm Hg at screening should be referred for ophthalmological management and the condition controlled prior to crossover registration Patients must not be taking, nor plan to take while on protocol treatment and for 14 days after the last dose of study treatment, drugs, herbal supplements or foods that are known to be strong/moderate CYP3A4 or CYP2D6 substrates Patients must not have a mean resting corrected QT interval (QTc) &gt; 450 msec obtained from 3 consecutive electrocardiograms (ECGs); performed within 28 days prior to Step 2 reregistration; patients must not have any clinically important abnormalities in rhythm, conduction or morphology of resting ECG (e.g. complete left bundle branch block, third degree heart block); patients must not have any factors that increase the risk of QTc prolongation or risk of arrhythmic events such as heart failure, hypokalemia, congenital long QT syndrome, family history of long QT syndrome or unexplained sudden death under 40 years of age Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1,500/mcl obtained within 28 days prior to Step 2 reregistration Platelet count &gt;= 100,000 mcl obtained within 28 days prior to Step 2 reregistration Hemoglobin &gt;= 9 g/dL obtained within 28 days prior to Step 2 reregistration Serum bilirubin =&lt; institutional upper limit of normal (IULN); for patients with liver metastases, bilirubin must be =&lt; 5 x IULN within 28 days prior to Step 2 reregistration Either alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; 2 x IULN within 28 days prior to Step 2 reregistration (if both ALT and AST are done, both must be &lt; 2 IULN); for patients with liver metastases, either ALT or AST must be =&lt; 5 x IULN (if both ALT and AST are done, both must be =&lt; 5 x IULN) Patients must have a serum creatinine =&lt; the IULN OR measured or calculated creatinine clearance &gt;= 50 mL/min using the CockroftGault formula Patients must have Zubrod performance status of 01 documented within 28 days prior to Step 2 reregistration Patients must not have any grade III/IV cardiac disease as defined by the New York Heart Association Criteria (i.e., patients with cardiac disease resulting in marked limitation of physical activity or resulting in inability to carry on any physical activity without discomfort), unstable angina pectoris, and myocardial infarction within 6 months, or serious uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmia Patients must not have documented evidence of acute hepatitis or have an active or uncontrolled infection Patients with a known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) seropositivity: 1. Must have undetectable viral load using standard HIV assays in clinical practice; 2. Must have cluster of differentiation (CD)4 count &gt;= 400/mcL; 3. Must not require prophylaxis for any opportunistic infections (i.e., fungal, mycobacterium avium complex [mAC], or pneumocystis pneumonia [PCP] prophylaxis); 4. Must not be newly diagnosed within 12 months prior to reregistration Prestudy history and physical exam must be obtained within 28 days prior to reregistration No other prior malignancy is allowed except for the following: adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, in situ cervical cancer, adequately treated stage I or II cancer from which the patient is currently in complete remission, or any other cancer from which the patient has been disease free for five years Patients must not be pregnant or nursing; women/men of reproductive potential must have agreed to use an effective contraceptive method; a woman is considered to be of "reproductive potential" if she has had menses at any time in the preceding 12 consecutive months; in addition to routine contraceptive methods, "effective contraception" also includes heterosexual celibacy and surgery intended to prevent pregnancy (or with a sideeffect of pregnancy prevention) defined as a hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy or bilateral tubal ligation; however, if at any point a previously celibate patient chooses to become heterosexually active during the time period for use of contraceptive measures outlined in the protocol, he/she is responsible for beginning contraceptive measures As a part of the Oncology Patient Enrollment Network (OPEN) registration process the treating institution's identity is provided in order to ensure that the current (within 365 days) date of institutional review board approval for this study has been entered in the system Patients with impaired decisionmaking capacity are eligible as long as their neurological or psychological condition does not preclude their safe participation in the study (e.g., tracking pill consumption and reporting adverse events to the investigator) Patients must be informed of the investigational nature of this study and must sign and give written informed consent in accordance with institutional and federal guidelines</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>