<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02734433</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1, non-randomized, open-label, multiple dose study of pexidartinib in Asian subjects with advanced solid tumors. The study will be conducted in a dose escalation to assess the safety and tolerability, PK and PD, and preliminary antitumor activity of pexidartinib.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Pexidartinib in Asian Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Age should be ≥ 20 years. Subjects must have a pathologically documented solid tumor that has relapsed from, or is refractory to standard treatment, or for which no standard treatment is available. All associated toxicity from previous cancer therapy must have been resolved (to ≤ Grade 1) prior to administration of pexidartinib. ECOG PS of 0 or 1. Adequate hematologic, hepatic, and renal function tests. Adequate treatment washout period before registration defined as: Major surgery: ≥ 4 weeks (2 weeks for less invasive surgery, such as colostomy) Radiation therapy (eg, whole brain radiotherapy): ≥ 4 weeks (if palliative stereotactic radiation therapy, ≥ 2 weeks) Chemotherapy or immunotherapy (including targeted therapy with antibody or small molecule, retinoid therapy, and hormonal therapy): 4 weeks or 5 halflives of the agent, whichever is shorter (if the regimen has contained nitrosoureas or mitomycin C, ≥ 6 weeks) Other investigational drug therapy: ≥ 4 weeks Refractory nausea and vomiting, malabsorption, external biliary shunt, or significant small bowel resection that would have precluded adequate absorption. Previous use of pexidartinib or any biologic treatment targeting colony stimulating factor 1 (CSF1) or the receptor for colonystimulating factor1 (CSF1R); previous use of oral tyrosine kinase inhibitors, eg, imatinib or nilotinib, is allowed. Clinically active primary central nervous system tumors or brain metastasis, defined as untreated and symptomatic, or requiring therapy with steroids or anticonvulsants to control associated symptoms. Active or chronic infection with hepatitis C or known positive hepatitis B surface. antigen, or known active or chronic infection with human immunodeficiency virus. A screening Fridericia corrected QT interval (QTcF) ≥ 450 ms (men) or ≥ 470 ms (women). A medical history or complications of clinically significant lung disease (eg, interstitial pneumonia, pneumonitis, pulmonary fibrosis, and severe radiation pneumonitis). A history of symptomatic congestive heart failure ([CHF]; New York Heart Association [NYHA] Classes II to IV) or serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring treatment. A history of myocardial infarction or unstable angina within 6 months before enrollment. An uncontrolled infection requiring intravenous injection of antibiotics, antivirals, or antifungals.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Advanced solid tumors</keyword>
	<keyword>asian subjects</keyword>
</DOC>