<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02734940</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators objective is to assess the effectiveness of an opioid sparing multimodal approach for enhancing the recovery in Cardiac Surgical patients. This model would use a combination of intravenous (Dexmedetomidine, Ketamine, Lidocaine) and Spinal (Morphine) drugs.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multimodal Analgesia in Cardiac Surgery (Pilot Study)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cardiac surgery is associated with significant acute pain and a proportion of these patients will develop chronic pain. Opioids are the main stay of analgesia in cardiac surgery because of the safer hemodynamic profile and sedation. However high dose narcotic use is associated with a variety of unwanted side effects prolonging postoperative recovery. There is growing evidence for the effectiveness of multimodal approach utilizing opiate sparing techniques for enhancing patient recovery following surgery. Early extubation has been associated with improved patient outcome and cost effectiveness in cardiac surgery. The investigators objective is to assess the effectiveness of an opioid sparing multimodal approach for enhancing the recovery in Cardiac Surgical patients. This model would use a combination of intravenous (Dexmedetomidine, Ketamine, Lidocaine) and Spinal (Morphine) drugs. All of the above anesthetic drugs have opioid sparing effect in surgical Patients. Dexmedetomidine use has been associated with decreased cardiac arrhythmias and improved neurological outcome in cardiac surgical patients. Ketamine has been linked with attenuation of postoperative cognitive dysfunction after cardiac surgery. Both intravenous lidocaine and spinal morphine have been shown to reduce opioid consumption in the perioperative period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Elective CABGs and/or Valve replacements, ≥ 18 years old Redo cardiac surgery, Acute endocarditis, Circulatory arrest, Emergent cases, Shock, Left Ventricular Assist Device, Transplantation, Transcatheter Aortic Valve Replacement, contraindications for Spinal including coagulopathy and Clopidogrel &lt;7days, psychosis, known allergy to any of the study drugs, Preoperative liver dysfunction (AST/ALT &gt; 2 times normal) and Renal dysfunction (Cr &gt; 2 mg/dL), inability to administer spinal anesthetic, preoperative opioid use, patients who are unable to give their own consent, expected prolonged intubation postoperatively (&gt;12 hrs), prisoners, pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>