<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00822588</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is a prospective, controlled, randomised and assessor blind study that investigate if the need for bank blood transfusion could be reduced in patients, undergoing primary or revision total hip replacement surgery, who receive their own blood back with the medical device Sangvia. A comparison in need for bank blood will be made between patients that either receive their own blood back or not.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison in Need for Bank Blood Between Patients Undergoing Total Hip Surgery That Either Receive Their Own Blood Back or Not</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Provision of informed consent Scheduled for primary or secondary, cemented or noncemented, total hip arthroplasty Classified as ASA Physical Status Classification System class P1, P2 or P3 according to the American Society of Anaesthesiology. Involvement in the planning and conduct of the study (applies to both Astra Tech staff or staff at the study site) Previous enrollment or randomisation of treatment in the present study Expected or confirmed participation in another clinical study, that may interfere with the present study, during the study period Suspected severe noncompliance to protocol as judged by the investigator Current symptoms of haemophilia Current symptoms of hyperkalaemia Current symptoms of systemic infection or local infection in the operation field Current symptoms of impaired renal function including creatinine/clearance levels above the normal reference values History of or presence of malignant disease with propensity for systemic spread during the last 5 years Current or expected use of cytotoxic drugs Current untreated anaemia (e.g. sickle cell anaemia), i.e. Hb concentration &lt; 11 g/dl (7 mmol/l) Use of recombinant erythopoetin Use of aprotinin and/or fibrin sealant Use of other autologous blood transfusion than that with the Sangvia® system (e.g. CellSaver, predonation, acute normovolemic haemodilution etc.) Women of childbearing age Fractures Revision/secondary total hip surgery with expected serious bone grafting</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>