<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00822081</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study compares the efficacy and tolerability/comfort of brimonidine/timolol and dorzolamide/timolol in patients with open-angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension. In an investigator masked randomization process, each subject is allocated to recieve either brimonidine/timolol or dorzolamide/timolol as fixed-combination monotherapy or as an adjuctive to a prostoglandin analogue for a period of 12 weeks. After screening, patient returns at baseline, Month 1, and Month 3 for ophthalmic evaluations.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of the Fixed Combinations of Brimonidine/Timolol and Dorzolamide/Timolol in Subjects With Open-Angle Glaucoma or Ocular Hypertension</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma, Open-Angle</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ocular Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dorzolamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brimonidine Tartrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Timolol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brimonidine Tartrate, Timolol Maleate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Maleic acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female over 18 yrs. Female subjects of childbearing potential must have negative pregnancy test and provide contraception. Subjects must have confirmed diagnosis of primary openangle glaucoma or ocular hypertension in both eyes. Subjects who are or have been insufficiently responsive to IOP reducing monotherapy and use of either study medication is deemed appropriate. Subjects able to complete questionnaires and provide informed consent. Female subjects who are pregnant, planning to become pregnant during study period, breast feeding or not practicing a reliable method of birth control. Subjects wherein the study drugs are containdicated. Subjects who have had introcular surgery with 6 months (3 months for laser). Subjects with known side effects/ allergy or sensitivity to any component of study treatments. Subjects with any uncontrolled systemic disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2009</verification_date>
</DOC>