<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00822016</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to establish a listing (database) of patients diagnosed with lung cancer and treated with best supportive care and standard and investigational chemotherapy regimens, surgery, and radiation therapy at the UNM CRTC and other NMCCA sites. The information will be used to determine the results of various treatments for lung cancer subjects and to find where improvements can be made in safety, effectiveness, supportive care, treatment that eases tumors without curing them, treatments that cure tumors, prevention, and follow-up efforts. The database information will be compared to clinical trial data published in peer-reviewed journals and SEER outcome data. Patients will be acquired both before and after they are treated for lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Observational Study of Best Supportive Care With or Without Surgery, Chemo or Radiotherapy in Pts With Carcinoma of Lung</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Same as above.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Those who are eligible for this treatment protocol will consist of: 1. Patients with histologically diagnosed lung cancer. 2. Patients receiving therapy should have an ECOG/Zubrod/SWOG performance status of &lt;3 at the time of the initiation of therapy. 3. All newly diagnosed patients referred to an NMCC Alliance site will be eligible, as will patients with recurrent disease that are now referred to an NMCCA for their next therapy (such as those who move from out of state, or are referred for protocol therapy), though efforts will be made to obtain records of prior therapy administered elsewhere). Patients not falling under any of the above criteria are not eligible for the study. Withdrawal of the informed consent at any point in the study excludes patient from the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Best Supportive Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Protocol of Standard Practice</keyword>
	<keyword>Carcinoma of the Lung</keyword>
</DOC>