<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01496378</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the feasibility and efficacy of problem-solving skills training (PSST) to reduce distress and increase coping abilities among parents of youth with chronic pain. We hypothesize that parents will complete the PSST intervention and will find it to be an acceptable and satisfactory treatment. We also hypothesize that parents who receive PSST will have less distress and better coping skills than parents who receive standard care, and that children of parents who receive PSST will have better physical and emotional functioning than children of parents who receive standard care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Problem Solving Skills Training For Parent Caregivers of Youth With Chronic Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Chronic pain affects 25-40% of children and adolescents, and results in significantly lower quality of life for these youth. Parents play an important role in how their children cope with chronic pain, and can also experience their own distress related to their child's illness. Parental psychological distress is widely recognized to be associated with poorer child adjustment. However, no interventions have been developed specifically to treat psychological distress in parents of children with chronic pain. Problem-solving skills training (PSST) has been shown to result in significant reductions in parental distress among caregivers of children with other types of chronic illness such as cancer. The purpose of this study is to test the feasibility and preliminary efficacy of PSST for parents of youth with chronic pain.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Headache</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abdominal Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Child age 1017 years Child's pain present for at least 3 months duration Pain occurs at least 1 time per week and interferes with daily functioning Pain is not related to a chronic disease Receiving evaluation or treatment in a pediatric pain clinic Literate in English A serious comorbid chronic condition in the child (e.g., diabetes, arthritis, cancer) NonEnglish speaking Parent has lived with the child for less than one year Parent has active psychosis or suicidal ideation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Abdominal Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Headache</keyword>
	<keyword>Adolescents</keyword>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
	<keyword>Parents</keyword>
	<keyword>Problem-Solving Skills Training</keyword>
</DOC>