<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01705509</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a proof of concept trial using ranolazine, a medication, in patients with known Coronary Artery Disease and reduced left ventricular function, EF &lt; 40%. We propose that ranolazine therapy will result in demonstrative improvements in cardiac function that can be objectively assessed using the parameters measured with CPET. We propose that demonstrative improvement in CPET parameters on ranolazine will translate into improved patient outcomes for this patient population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effects of Ranolazine on CPET Parameters in Ischemic Cardiomyopathy Patients (ERIC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Selected patients will undergo a CPET evaluation. The initial CPET will identify patients with underlying ischemia and serve as a baseline study. Ischemia will be assessed using: 1) peak VO2: measures the peak transport of O2 to the tissues when O2 extraction from the blood is maximal; 2) the anaerobic threshold (AT): measures the sustainable work capacity in units of VO2; 3) the O2-pulse measurements at the AT peak VO2: estimate stroke volume at those levels of exercise; and 4) the relationship of O2 uptake to work rate (ΔVO2/ΔWR): provides information on the ability of the cardiac output to increase. Patients whoseCPET results meet the criteria for ischemia will be started on Ranexa 500mg BID and advanced within one week +/-4 days to 1000mg BID. A second CPET will be performed after 4 weeks +/- 4 days of maximum therapy. CPET results before and after therapy will undergo a statistical comparison. The initial off treatment CPET measurement will serve as the control to assess changes found during therapy. No medication changes or revascularization procedures will occur during the study. If patients require and undergo a medication change or a revascularization procedure, they will be excluded from the study. Patients will be contacted at the completion of week one prior to up titration, then at the end of week two to ensure tolerance and compliance with the 1000mg BID dose. Patients will perform the second CPET study at week four +/- 1 week. The trial medication will be assessed and counted to ensure that patients have taken there allotted pill count for the duration of the study. Patients who are found to be noncompliant of less than 80% will be excluded from the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ranolazine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients &gt; 18 years of age will be enrolled in the trial. Stable patients without hospitalizations, medication changes or cardiac intervention within one month of the study will be enrolled. Patients must be able to complete the CPET protocol and must have demonstrable ischemia on the initial CPET evaluation. Patients must have a documented ejection fraction &lt; 40% a. LV function can be assessed via: i. Echocardiogram ii. MUGA or Nuclear Perfusion Scan iii. Left ventriculogram Patients must be Ranexa naive and without contraindication for Ranexa therapy. QTc&gt;500 msec on resting EKG Hepatic Impairment (ChildPugh class A, B or C) Have received prior treatment with ranolazine Treatment with QT prolonging drugs as class 1A (e.g., quinidine), class III (e.g., sotalol, dofetilide) antiarrhythmics, amiodarone and antipsychotics (e.g., thioridazine, ziprasidone) Treatment with potent or moderately potent CYP3A inhibitors including ketoconazole and other azole antifungals, diltiazem, verapamil, macrolide antibiotics, HIV protease inhibitors or consumption of grapefruit juice or grapefruit juice containing products Have participated in another trial of an investigational device or drug within 30 days of screening Have end stage renal disease requiring dialysis Have any chronic illness likely to effect compliance with the protocol Have second or third degree atrioventricular block in the absence of a functioning ventricular pacemaker Have uncontrolled clinically significant cardiac arrhythmias, or a history of ventricular fibrillation, torsade de pointes, or other lifethreatening ventricular arrhythmias Uncontrolled HTN defined as BP &gt; /= 160/100 mm Hg</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>The Effects of Ranolazine on CPET Parameters in Ischemic</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiomyopathy Patients</keyword>
</DOC>