<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01705288</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Over 600,000 hysterectomies are performed annually in the United States. Despite increasing use of less invasive approaches, the majority of hysterectomies are still performed via traditional laparotomy, which can be associated with generally slower recovery and longer lengths of post-operative hospitalization. Rapid Recovery Protocols (RRP) seek to optimize post-surgical morbidity outcomes by returning a patient to normal physiology as quickly as possible following surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Implementation of a Rapid Recovery Program in Gynecologic Oncology Surgery: A Pilot Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Subjects will be randomly assigned to one of two groups: Rapid recovery protocol (regional anesthesia, pain control options with emphasis on nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDS) over narcotic pain medications, early ambulation, and early enteral feeding) or standard of care (traditional laparatomy and supportive care).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Narcotics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women who are being seen at the Women's Health Center by the Gynecologic Oncology group at the University of Minnesota if planned surgery includes an exploratory laparotomy &lt; 19 years old Pregnant Undergoing a procedure other than laparotomy Scheduled to be discharged the same day of surgery Chronic narcotic pain medication user American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) score of &gt; or = 3 Any condition that would exclude women from undergoing regional anesthesia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>laparotomy</keyword>
	<keyword>hysterectomy</keyword>
</DOC>