<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00126269</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized phase III trial comparing cisplatin with or without gemcitabine in patients with carcinoma of unknown primary and a predicted favorable prognosis. The purpose of this trial is to compare the overall survival rates of patients with carcinoma of unknown primary (CUP) and a predicted favorable prognosis according to the French classification treated with cisplatin with or without gemcitabine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial Comparing Cisplatin With or Without Gemcitabine in Patients With Carcinoma of Unknown Primary</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Unknown Primary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients older than 18 years Evidence of CUP based on histologic examination Negative search for the primary tumor site using recommended guidelines Disease classified as good prognosis according to the French classification criteria: *performance status &gt;2 and *normal serum LDH No prior chemotherapy No previous carcinoma, except basalcell carcinoma of the skin Adequate renal function: measured or calculated creatinine clearance &gt; 60 ml/min Absolute granulocyte count ≥ 1,500/mm3; platelets ≥ 100,000 mm3; bilirubin ≤ 1.5 fold the upper normal value Signed informed consent Patients infected by the Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) CUP belonging to one of the following subgroups: 1) Axillary lymph node of an adenocarcinoma in a woman; 2) Serous adenocarcinoma of the peritoneum in a woman; 3) Undifferentiated carcinoma of the middle line in a young man; 4)Squamouscell carcinoma; 5) Neuroendocrine carcinoma; 6) Bone metastases with elevated serum prostate specific antigen (PSA) in a man Patients who do not fit inclusion criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>Patients with Carcinoma of Unknown Primary and a Predicted Favorable Prognosis</keyword>
</DOC>