<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02790372</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates the effect of using comprehensive geriatric assessment in combination with case conferences on the prevalence of neuropsychiatric symptoms (also known as behavioral and psychological symptoms of dementia) in Norwegian nursing homes</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Case Conferencing in Nursing Homes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Long-term care patients in nursing homes (NH) are characterized by frailty and having multiple health problems and reduced quality of life. Some of these issues relates to the quality of care and do therefore possess a potential for improvement. There is a need for approaches enabling nurses to carry out effective interventions that can promote health related to sustain or improve the nursing home patients health status. Integrating a comprehensive geriatric assessment (CGA) and case conferencing (CC) might be an effective method to individualize care plans in order to improve quality of care. The intervention nursing homes will implement CGA, using the International resident instrument suite for Long Term Care Facilities (InterRai LTCF) and CC. The patients will be included and assessed three times during a 12-month period (control and intervention NHs). In the intervention NHs the results from the CGA will be reviewed in monthly CCs. The CCs are structured and consist of four main steps; evaluating the effects of earlier interventions, defining patients risks or area for improvement, defining the aetiology of the risk or problem, defining interventions and measures for improvement along with an appropriate method for evaluation. The CC group's consensus is basis for the patient's care plan.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neurobehavioral Manifestations</mesh_term>
	<criteria>registered as long term care patient been in the nursing home for more than a month Informed consent from the patient or legal guardians life expectancy less than six months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Nursing homes</keyword>
	<keyword>Norway</keyword>
</DOC>