<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02175602</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the effect of Daclatasvir, Asunaprevir, and BMS-791325 on the pharmacokinetics of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Drug Combination on Pharmacokinetics in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sertraline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citalopram</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Serotonin Uptake Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexetimide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Signed Informed Consent Form a) Signed written informed consent must be obtained from the subjects in accordance with requirements of the study center's IRB or IEC before the initiation of any protocolrequired procedures. 2. Target Population a) Healthy subjects as determined by no clinically significant deviation from normal in medical history, psychiatric history, physical examination findings, vital sign measurements, 12lead ECG measurements, physical measurements, and clinical laboratory test results. 3. Age and Reproductive Status 1. Males and females, ages 25 to 55 years, inclusive. 2. Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must have a negative serum pregnancy test (minimum sensitivity 25 IU/L or equivalent units of HCG) within 24 hours prior to the start of study drug. 3. Women must not be breastfeeding. 1. Any significant acute or chronic medical illness. 2. Current or recent (within 3 months of study drug administration) gastrointestinal disease that could impact upon the absorption of study drug (appendectomies with no complications are allowed at the investigator's discretion). 3. Any major surgery within 4 weeks of study drug administration. 4. Smokers (those who currently smoke, as well as those who have stopped smoking less than 6 months prior to the start of study drug administration). 5. Any other sound medical, psychiatric, and/or social reason as determined by the investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>