<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02855411</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether PF-04958242 is safe and effective in the treatment of cognitive dysfunction in schizophrenia subjects</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study To Evaluate The Safety And Efficacy Of PF-04958242 In Subjects With Cognitive Impairment Associated With Schizophrenia (CIAS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Otherwise healthy male and/or female subjects between the ages of 18 and 50 years, inclusive, with Diagnostic Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, Fifth Edition (DSM5) diagnosis of schizophrenia of at least 2 years duration as confirmed by the M.I.N.I 7.0 for Psychotic Disorders Evidence of stable schizophrenia symptomatology &gt;=3 months (ie, no hospitalizations for schizophrenia, no increase in level of psychiatric care due to worsening of symptoms of schizophrenia). Subjects must be in ongoing maintenance atypical antipsychotic therapy (except clozapine), on a stable treatment regimen for &gt;=2 months prior to Baseline/Day 1, including concomitant psychotropic treatments. Subjects should be on no more than 2 background antipsychotics. Subject must have an identified informant Subject must reside in a stable living situation for at least 12 weeks prior to Screening. Subjects with a current DSM5 diagnosis of schizoaffective disorder in the judgment of the investigator. Subjects with a current DSM5 diagnosis of major depressive episode, manic and hypomanic episode, panic disorder, agoraphobia, social anxiety disorder, obsessivecompulsive disorder, posttraumatic stress disorder, generalized anxiety disorder on the M.I.N.I 7.0 for Psychotic Disorders or in the judgment of the investigator. Subjects with a lifetime DSM5 diagnosis of antisocial personality disorder, anorexia nervosa, bulimia nervosa, bingeeating disorder on the M.I.N.I 7.0 for Psychotic Disorders or in the judgment of the investigator. Subjects who meet the DSM5 diagnosis of moderate or severe psychoactive substance use disorder (excluding nicotine dependence) within 12 months of screening on the M.I.N.I 7.0 for Psychotic Disorders interview and as determined by the investigator. Subjects with significant extrapyramidal symptoms which have not been stabilized with anticholinergics.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>