<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01735071</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is aimed at assessing the efficacy and the safety of the combination of bevacizumab and trabectedin with or without carboplatin in adult women with epithelial ovarian cancer at first recurrence occurred 6-12 months after the end of the last (first or second) platinum-containing regimen. According to the Bryant and Day design the primary endpoints will be the proportion of progression-free patients at 6 months for the efficacy, and the proportion of patients with severe toxicity for the safety at the same time-point.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bevacizumab and Trabectedin +/- Carboplatin in Advanced Ovarian Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Glandular and Epithelial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trabectedin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age≥18years Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 02 Cytological/histological diagnosis of epithelial ovarian cancer Progression free interval between 612 months (calculated from the first day of the last cycle of the previous last platinumbased chemotherapy until the date of progression confirmation through radiologic imaging) One or two previous platinumbased chemotherapy lines Measurable disease according to RECIST version 1.1 Life expectancy ≥ 12 weeks Patients must be able to receive dexamethasone or its equivalent, as a premedication for trabectedin Written informed consents given before the enrolment according to International Conference on Harmonization/ Good Clinical Practice (ICH/GCP). Prior treatment with trabectedin Prior progression while on therapy containing bevacizumab or other vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) pathwaytarget therapy Preexisting grade &gt; 1 sensitive/motor neurologic disorder Current or recent (within 30 days of first study dosing) treatment with another investigational drug Surgery (including open biopsy) within 4 weeks prior to the first planned dose of bevacizumab Current or recent (within 10 days prior to the first study drug dose) use of fulldose oral or parenteral anticoagulant or thrombolytic agent for therapeutic purposes (except for line patency, in which case international normalized ratio (INR) must be maintained below 1.5). Post operative prophylaxis with low molecular weight heparin sc is allowed Inadequate bone marrow function: absolute neutrophil count (ANC): &lt;1.5 x 109/l, or platelet count &lt;100 x 109/l or haemoglobin &lt;9 g/dl. Patients may be transfused to maintain haemoglobin values ≥9 g/dl Inadequate coagulation parameters: activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT) &gt;1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) or INR &gt;1.5 Inadequate liver function, defined as: serum (total) bilirubin &gt; ULN for the institution AST/serum glutamicoxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) or ALT/ serum glutamicpyruvic transaminase (SGPT) &gt;2.5 x ULN Inadequate renal function: serum creatinine &gt;1.5 mg/dL or &gt;132 micromol/L and urine dipstick for proteinuria &gt; or = 2+ and &gt;1g of protein in their 24hour urine collection History or evidence of brain metastases or spinal cord compression Pregnant, breastfeeding women and women of child bearing potential, who do not agree to use a medically acceptable method of contraception through the treatment period and for 6 months after discontinuation of treatment History or evidence of thrombotic or hemorrhagic disorders; including cerebrovascular accident, stroke or transient ischemic attack or subarachnoid haemorrhage within 6 months prior to the first study treatment Uncontrolled hypertension (sustained systolic &gt;150 mmHg and/or diastolic &gt;100 mmHg despite antihypertensive therapy) or clinically significant (i.e. active) cardiovascular disease, including: myocardial infarction or unstable angina within 6 months prior to the first study treatment, New York Heart Association grade II or greater congestive heart failure, serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication History of bowel obstruction, including subocclusive disease, related to the underlying disease and history of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation or intraabdominal abscess. Evidence of rectosigmoid involvement by pelvic examination or bowel involvement on CT scan or clinical symptoms of bowel obstruction Nonhealing wound, ulcer or bone fracture hepatitis C virus (HCV) positivity Other malignancy within the last 5 years, except for adequately treated carcinoma in situ of the cervix or squamous carcinoma of the skin, or adequately controlled limited basal cell skin cancer.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ovarian cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>bevacizumab</keyword>
	<keyword>trabectedin</keyword>
	<keyword>carboplatin</keyword>
	<keyword>randomized trial</keyword>
	<keyword>phase II</keyword>
</DOC>