<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01735305</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Antiplatelet therapy is the cornerstone for the prevention of atherothrombosis in patients with coronary artery disease (CAD). However, the efficacy and safety of antiplatelet therapy are varied due to ethnic and/or individual variability. The aim of the OPT-CAD study was to demonstrate contemporary status and outcomes of antiplatelet therapy in Chinese CAD patients, and to explore predictors of ischemic or bleeding events in such cohort.Patients above 18 years old who were diagnosed as CAD and received antiplatelet therapy were prospectively enrolled in this national wide, non-intervention registry. All medications and laboratory tests were physician discretion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Optimal Antiplatelet Therapy for Chinese Patients With Coronary Artery Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Antiplatelet therapy is the cornerstone for the prevention of atherothrombosis in patients with coronary artery disease (CAD). However, the efficacy and safety of antiplatelet therapy are varied due to ethnic and/or individual variability. The aim of the OPT-CAD study was to demonstrate contemporary status and outcomes of antiplatelet therapy in Chinese CAD patients, and to explore predictors of ischemic or bleeding events in such cohort.Patients above 18 years who were diagnosed as CAD and received antiplatelet therapy were prospectively enrolled in this national wide, non-intervention registry. All medications and laboratory tests were at physician discretion.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 1. Clinical diagnosis of coronary heart disease 2. Age &gt;= 18 years old 3. receiving any antiplatelet agents 4. Informed written consent signed 1. With severe disease and life expectancy for 6 months or less 2. Difficult to attain followup situations judged by researchers (travel, speech or mental disorder, etc.) 3. Taking part in an interventional clinical research</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>antiplatelet therapy</keyword>
</DOC>