<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01258543</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether two osteopathic evaluators with less than 5 years experience will be able to determine the same location and nature of the primary lesion(s) or restriction(s)in patients with chronic non-specific back pain using a global osteopathic evaluation approach.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Osteopathic Evaluation on Patients With Non-specific Back Pain: An Inter-examiner Reliability Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Back pain is one of the leading causes of consultation for rehabilitation. Establishing a diagnosis in the initial patient assessment is essential to choosing a specific treatment plan for that patient, regardless of the type of therapy the patient chooses to pursue. Evidence based medicine is the current gold standard for most manual-therapy professions, and there has been a great deal of research performed in an attempt to give credibility to the one tool that all manual therapy professions share in common: palpation. Few studies have been able to demonstrate an acceptable rate of inter-examiner reliability for palpation. This study will combine a global testing regime, consensus training for evaluators, and access to history of injury with symptomatic subjects to verify the inter-examiner reliability of an osteopathic evaluation on patients with chronic, non-specific low back pain.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and women ages 1860 Must have a history of nonspecific back pain (not due to any known pathology eg. disc herniation or disc degenerative disease) that is currently not irritated and has not been, in the past 8 weeks Must be available for 3 consecutive hour Patients with a known cause for their back pain Patients who have had a flare up of symptoms within the last 8 weeks Patients who are currently undergoing any rehabilitation or who have received manual treatment in the last 8 weeks. Patients who are taking daily medications for pain Pregnant women Major medical conditions: fractures, degenerative arthritis, inflammatory disorders, ankylosing spondylitis, multiple sclerosis, cancer, paralysis stroke or recent concussion history Any other conditions that would prevent the participant from completing the evaluation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Global osteopathic evaluation</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-specific back pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Inter-examiner reliability</keyword>
</DOC>