<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01258192</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of neoadjuvant chemotherapy with nab-paclitaxel plus cisplatin for stage Ⅱ-Ⅲ esophageal squamous cell carcinoma patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy With Nab-paclitaxel Plus Cisplatin for Stage Ⅱ-Ⅲ Esophageal Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A surgical resection is currently the preferred treatment for esophageal cancer if the tumor is considered to be resectable without evidence of distant metastases.A higher percentage of radical resection is reported in studies using neoadjuvant chemotherapy followed by surgery versus surgery alone.The neoadjuvant chemotherapy may improve overall survival. Neoadjuvant chemotherapy with administrations of paclitaxel combined with cisplatin or carboplatin has shown effectively.Nanoparticle albumin-bound (nab)-paclitaxel has better efficacy and practically eliminates the risk of hypersensitivity reactions associated with solvent-based paclitaxel.We try to evaluate the efficacy and safety of neoadjuvant chemotherapy with nab-paclitaxel plus cisplatin for stage Ⅱ-Ⅲ esophageal squamous cell carcinoma patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologic diagnosis of squamous cell carcinoma of esophagus. Preoperative stage ⅡⅢ by endoscopic ultrasound, CT of the chest and abdomen,and esophagogram. Age ranges from 18 to 70 years. Patients must not have received any prior anticancer therapy. Performance status of 0 to 1 Estimated life expectancy of at least 6 months. Tumor can be measured according to RECIST criteria Signed informed consent document on file. Females with childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy Adequate organ function including the following: Bone marrow: Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) greater than or equal 1.5×109/L Platelets greater than or equal 80×109/L Haemoglobin greater than or equal 80g/L Hepatic: total bilirubin less than or equal to 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN), Alanine transaminase (ALT) and aspartate transaminase (AST) less than or equal to 2.5 times ULN Renal: calculated creatinine clearance rate≥60ml/min. test within 7 days prior to study enrollment. Carcinoma at the upper part of esophagus Histologic diagnosis of adenocarcinoma of esophagus. Prior treatment for esophageal cancer. Active infection. Pregnant or breast feeding. History of significant neurological or mental disorder, including seizures or dementia. Prior invasive malignancy in 5 years (except for carcinoma in situ).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>esophageal squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>neoadjuvant chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>albumin-bound paclitaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>cisplatin</keyword>
</DOC>