<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01258712</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase III study to evaluate efficacy and safety of Tocilizumab in patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Tocilizumab in Combination With Methotrexate for Treatment of Moderate to Severe Rheumatoid Arthritis Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients diagnosed with history of moderateto severe rheumatoid arthritis for more than 6 months according to the American College of Rheumatology (ACR) 1987 revised criteria for the classification of RA. Patients who failed to achieve clinical response to treatment of at least 2 DMARDs(disease modifying antirheumatic drug) (including MTX) for at least 12 weeks within 12 months prior to screening, of which MTX must have been at a stable dose of 1020 mg/wk for at least 12 weeks prior to screening. All other DMARDs should be given at standard therapeutic dose. Patients who satisfy swollen joint count (SJC) ≥ 6 (66 joint count) and tender joint count (TJC) ≥ 8 (68 joint count) at screening and baseline. Creactive protein (CRP) level ≥ 1 mg/dl or an erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR) ≥ 28 mm/hour at screening and at baseline. Patients who have received a major surgery including joint surgery 8 weeks prior to the screening or are scheduled to be operated within 6 months after the enrolment. Patients with rheumatoid autoimmune disease other than RA, including but not limited to SLE(system lupus erythematosus), or significant systemic involvement secondary to RA. Patients who belong to the Class IV of the ACR classification criteria for functional status of RA. (ACR Amended Criteria for the Classification of Functional Capacity in Rheumatoid Arthritis; Class IV: Largely or wholly incapacitated with patient bedridden or confined to wheel chair, permitting little or no selfcare). Patients with a history of hypersensitivity to human, humanized or murine monoclonal antibodies or patients with contraindication for them. Patients who currently have or have a history of recurrence of bacterial, viral,fungal, or mycobacterial infections or other infectious diseases; tuberculosis(TB),atypical mycobacterial disease, clinically significant granulomatous disease on chest radiograph, hepatitis B, hepatitis C, or herpes zoster and etc. However, a patient with hand &amp; foot fungal infections can participate.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>