<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01258075</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Colesevelam oral suspension will be studied as treatment of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) to evaluate clinical safety and efficacy in patients aged 10-17 years. The patients may have been treated with Metformin or have had no antidiabetic drug treatment in the previous three months. Study Hypothesis: Colesevelam oral suspension for pediatric subjects with T2DM is safe, well tolerated, and shows improved blood sugar control (as evidenced by a significant change from baseline in hemoglobin A1C [HbA1c]).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Colesevelam Pediatric Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colesevelam Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of type 2 diabetes mellitus, as defined by the American Diabetes Association; Understand study procedures and agree to participate by giving written assent and obtaining written consent from a parent or legal guardian at screening; Males and females aged 10 to 17 years, inclusive, at randomization (randomization must occur before 18th birthday); HbA1c at screening between 7.0% and 10.0%, inclusive; Fasting Cpeptide &gt;0.6 ng/mL; and Antidiabetic treatment at screening: Treatmentnaïve or untreated; OR On metformin monotherapy: Metformin monotherapy has been initiated prior to screening. Fasting plasma glucose &gt;270 mg/dL; Diagnosis of type 1 diabetes; History of more than one episode of ketoacidosis after the initial diagnosis of type 2 diabetes mellitus; Positive autoimmune markers; Creatinine clearance &lt;70 mL/min; Alanine transaminase or aspartate aminotransferase elevation &gt;2.5 X upper limit of normal; Participation in another interventional research study protocol in the past 60 days; Female subjects who are lactating, pregnant, or plan to become pregnant within 1 year of screening; Female subjects who are sexually active and unwilling to use appropriate contraception for the duration of the study; History of bowel obstruction; Other significant organ system illness or condition (including psychiatric or developmental disorder) that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would prevent full participation; Triglycerides &gt;500 mg/dL.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>type 2 diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>blood glucose</keyword>
	<keyword>anti-diabetic</keyword>
	<keyword>bile acid sequestrant</keyword>
	<keyword>colesevelam HCl</keyword>
	<keyword>oral suspension</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatric</keyword>
	<keyword>add-on therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>add-on to metformin</keyword>
	<keyword>metformin</keyword>
	<keyword>adolescent</keyword>
	<keyword>lipid</keyword>
</DOC>