<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01465399</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Immediately following tooth removal, a healing process begins that affects the eventual alveolar bone volume and architecture of the alveolar ridge. Satisfactory and timely healing are essential to obtain ideal functional reconstruction. Traumatic removal of a tooth, or a poor healing response, may lead to excessive bone loss delaying tooth replacement, requiring expensive and time-consuming reconstructive surgeries, or even the inability to be corrected. The Plasma Rich in Growth Factors (PRGF-Endoret) has shown its therapeutic potential effect to minimize the consequences of this aggression, promoting the regeneration of both hard and soft involved tissues.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Plasma Rich in Growth Factors (PRGF-Endoret) in the Regeneration of Post-Extraction Sockets</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Mitogens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>subjects of both genders and ≥ 18 years old Indication of a simple one molar extraction in the mandible. Possibility of observation during the followup period. Unerupted third molars or with horizontal inclination. Severe swelling prior to surgery in the areas designated for extraction. Suffering an alteration or a serious hematologic disease. Be currently undergoing or have received radiotherapy, chemotherapy or immunosuppressive therapy, corticosteroids and/or anticoagulants 30 days prior to inclusion In regular treatment with NSAIDs or other antiinflammatory drugs. History of chronic hepatitis or cirrhosis. Diabetes mellitus with poor metabolic control (glycosylated hemoglobin &gt;9%) Patients undergoing dialysis. Presence of malignant tumors, hemangiomas or angiomas in the extraction area. History of ischemic heart disease in the last year. Pregnancy or planned pregnancy during the study followup period. Metabolic Bone Disease. Patients taking bisphosphonates both orally and intravenously. In general, any inability to participate in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>