<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01465451</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate efficacy and safety of intra-operative chemotherapy with 5-FU for colorectal cancer patients receiving curative resection. The hypothesis is intra-operative intervention might be the best timing for cancer cells killing by cytotoxic agents, when most of residual cancer cells may get a rapid growth after tumor debulking and may become more chemotherapy-sensitive. A three-step procedure is designed for intra-operative chemotherapy with 5-FU of 1500 mg/m2, including step 1 of intraluminal 5-FU injection with 1000 mg/m2 at beginning of resection, step 2 of 200mg/m2 5-FU injection into portal vein system via mesentery vein after tumor removal and finish of bowel reconstruction, and step 3 of 300mg/m2 5-FU left into the abdominal cavity before incision closure. The controlled arm receive curative resection only. All the other treatments will stick to the guidelines.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intra-operative Chemotherapy With 5-FU for Colorectal Cancer Patients Receiving Curative Resection: Efficacy and Safety</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>nil.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>histologically confirmed as adenocarcinoma of colon and rectum age 1875 years eligible for curative surgical resection performance score: ECOG 01 normal blood cells counts: WBC ≥ 4.0×10*9/L，PLT ≥ 100×10*9/L normal blood chemistry test: ALT/AST ≤ 2.5 ULN, TBil ≤ 1.5 ULN, BUN ≤ 1.5 ULN,Cr ≤ 1.5 ULN normal ECG no history of other malignant tumors no concomitant anticancer therapy clinical bowel obstruction anticipated into another clinical trial within three months uncontrolled infection, serious internal medical diseases Pregnant or lactating women mentally abnormal patients patients known allergic to 5FU</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>colorectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>curative resection</keyword>
	<keyword>intra-operative chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>5-fluorouracil</keyword>
	<keyword>chemotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>