<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01854203</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Concurrent cisplatin-based chemotherapy plus radiotherapy increased the risk of treatment-related death and severe acute toxicity. The survival benefit of adding concurrent chemotherapy to intensity modulated radiation in patients with locoregionally advanced nasopharyngeal carcinoma is unclear. Gemcitabine plus cisplatin chemotherapy combine with radiotherapy was effective and well tolerated by patients with locoregionally advanced NPC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination of Cisplatin Plus Gemcitabine Induction Chemotherapy and Intensity-modulated radiotherapyIntensity-modulated Radiotherapy With or Without Concurrent Cisplatin for NPC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to compare gemcitabine plus cisplatin induction chemotherapy combine intensity-modulated radiotherapy with or without concurrent cisplatin in patients with locoregionally advanced nasopharyngeal carcinoma (NPC), in order to reevaluate the value of concurrent cisplatin when 4 cycles induction chemotherapy (gemcitabine+cisplatin) and IMRT is used.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nasopharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with newly histologically confirmed nonkeratinizing (according to World Health Organization (WHO 2005) histologically type). A Karnofsky performance status of at least 80; Tumor staged is according to the 7th American Joint Commission on Cancer edition as Stage III：T12N2M0, T3N02M0 Stage IVa：T4N02M0 Stage IVb：Any T、N3. Adequate marrow: a WBC ≥3.5×109 l1; a platelet count ≥100×109 l1; and hemoglobin levels ≥100 g/l. Normal liver function test: Alanine Aminotransferase (ALT)、Aspartate Aminotransferase (AST) &lt;1.5×upper limit of normal (ULN) concomitant with alkaline phosphatase (ALP) ≤2.5×ULN, and bilirubin ≤ULN. Adequate renal function: a creatinine clearance rate of at least 60 mL/min. Patients must be informed of the investigational nature of this study and give written informed consent. WHO Type keratinizing squamous cell carcinoma. Age &gt;65 years or &lt;18 years. Distant metastasis, Treatment with palliative intent. Pregnancy or lactation. a history of previous radiotherapy in the nasopharyngeal region or previous chemotherapy. history of renal disease, unstable cardiac disease requiring treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cisplatin</keyword>
	<keyword>neoadjuvant chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>intensity-modulated radiation therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>concurrent chemoradiotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>