<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01854567</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study investigates the time to engraftment of a mesenchymal expanded cord blood unit in patients with hematologic malignancies undergoing transplantation with myeloablative conditioning.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>P3 Study of Umbilical Cord Blood Cells Expanded With MPCs for Transplantation in Patients With Hematologic Malignancies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient must have one of the following: Acute myelogenous leukemia (AML) in complete morphological remission at study screening (Complete Remission with Incomplete Platelet Recovery (CRp) acceptable). Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) in complete morphological remission at study screening (Complete Remission with Incomplete Platelet Recovery (CRp) acceptable). NonHodgkin's lymphoma (NHL): High risk subjects with responsive disease after first relapse. High risk includes those with Burkitt's Lymphoma and those with extensive marrow involvement at diagnosisprecluding autologous transplant. Hodgkin's disease: High risk subjects with responsive disease after first relapse. Minimum Karnofsky Scale Subject must weigh at least 20 kg Up to 65 years of age Adequate major organ system function Pregnancy and/or lactating Suitable, 6/6 HLA matched related sibling donor available Previous participation in a stem cell study within last 30 days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cord Blood</keyword>
	<keyword>Stem Cells</keyword>
	<keyword>MPC</keyword>
	<keyword>Mesoblast</keyword>
	<keyword>Expanded</keyword>
	<keyword>AML</keyword>
	<keyword>ALL</keyword>
	<keyword>NHL</keyword>
	<keyword>Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>