<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01854216</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate the repeated dose Pharmacokinetics (PK) of transdermally delivered Rotigotine in Japanese and Caucasian female and male healthy subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Pharmacokinetics, Safety, Tolerability of Repeated Dose Transdermal Rotigotine in Japanese and Caucasian Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>N 0437</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is healthy according to assessments done at eligibility assessment (medical history, physical examination, blood pressure, heart rate, ECG, hematology, clinical chemistry, urinalysis) Subject is of normal bodyweight as determined by a body mass index ranging between 18 to 28 kg/m² Subject is Japanese or Caucasian. Japanese subjects are born in Japan and left Japan not more than 10 years ago. Both parents of the Japanese subjects are 100 % Japanese Subjects (females) without medically adequate contraception or on lactation or pregnant women. Subjects with oral contraception or hormone replacement within 4 weeks prior to eligibility assessment Subject has a history of chronic alcohol or drug abuse Subject has a consumption of more than 20 g of alcohol/day (amount corresponds to 0.5 l of beer/day or 0.25 l of wine/day or 3 glasses (à 2 cl) of liquor/day) Subject has a clinically relevant allergy Subject has a known or suspected drug hypersensitivity in particular, to any component of the trial medication Subject has any clinically significant abnormality in physical examination Subject has a heart rate at rest less than 50 beats per minute (bpm) or more than 100 bpm Subject has systolic blood pressure lower than 100 mmHg or higher than 145 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure higher than 95 mmHg or lower than 60 mmHg Subject has an atopic or eczematous dermatitis and/or an active skin disease or skin tumors Subject has a history of significant skin hypersensitivity to adhesives or other transdermal products or recent unresolved contact dermatitis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Rotigotine</keyword>
	<keyword>Neupro</keyword>
	<keyword>Japanese</keyword>
	<keyword>Caucasian</keyword>
	<keyword>Male</keyword>
	<keyword>Female</keyword>
	<keyword>Single dose</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
</DOC>