<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01854684</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase I trial studies the side effects and best dose of photodynamic therapy during surgery in treating patients with non-small cell lung cancer that can be removed by surgery. Photodynamic therapy uses a drug, such as temoporfin, that becomes active when it is exposed to a certain kind of light. When the drug is active, cancer cells are killed. This may be a better way to treat patients with non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Photodynamic Therapy During Surgery in Treating Patients With Non-small Cell Lung Cancer That Can Be Removed by Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To demonstrate that intraoperative adjuvant regional photodynamic therapy with low-dose temoporfin is safe. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. Initial assessment of efficacy (i.e., 2-year disease free survival). II. To investigate the relationship between signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) levels, measured light dose and the clinical outcome. III. Correlate the serum concentrations of vitamin D metabolites (25-hydroxyvitarnin D3 and 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3) with the presence of lymph node (LN) metastasis at the time of surgical resection. IV. To measure temoporfin uptake in malignant and normal tissue. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study of photodynamic therapy with temoporfin. Patients receive temoporfin intravenously (IV) over no less than 6 minutes and then undergo standard surgical resection with intraoperative photodynamic therapy (PDT). After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 6 months for 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temoporfin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC) Patients with resectable primary NSCLC who are undergoing surgery to resect T3 to T4 lesions OR any patients with clinical NI or N2 disease regardless of Tstage Subjects must have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) scale of 02 Subjects of childbearing potential must agree to use adequate contraceptive methods (e.g., hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry and for 6 months after surgery; should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while she or her partner is participating in this study, she should inform her treating physician immediately The subject or legal representative must understand the investigational nature of this study and sign an Independent Ethics Committee/Institutional Review Board approved written informed consent prior to receiving any study related procedure Must consent to participate in study I 03103: Roswell Park Cancer Institute (RPCI) Data Bank and Biorepository (DBBR) Patients who have had chemotherapy or radiotherapy within 4 weeks (6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin C) prior to entering the study or those who have not recovered from adverse events due to agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier Patients with known brain metastases should be excluded from this clinical trial Patients with porphyria, or with known hypersensitivity to porphyrins or porphyrinlike compounds White blood cell (WBC) &lt; 4,000 Platelet count &lt; 100,000 Total serum bilirubin &gt; 2 mg/dL Serum creatinine &gt; 2 mg/dL Alkaline phosphatase (hepatic) or serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) &gt; 3 times the upper normal limit Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements Pregnant or nursing female subjects Unwilling or unable to follow protocol requirements Any condition which in the Investigator's opinion deems the subject an unsuitable candidate to receive study drug Received an investigational agent within 30 days prior to enrollment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>