<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00884962</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multi-center, open-label, non-controlled Pilot Study. Approximately 24 patients will be assigned to one of 3 treatment groups (8 patients each group). Patients in each group will receive 2, 4, and 6 (3 followed by a retreatment of 3) subsegmental treatments, respectively. All patients will receive treatment in a single lung under conscious sedation or general anesthesia. Patients will be followed for 24 weeks after completion of PLVR treatment(s). Upon completion of 12-week follow-up, all safety and efficacy data will be analyzed to determine an effective treatment dose. Thereafter, Group 1 patients may elect to be retreated at additional sites so that their total dose received is consistent with the effective dose. All study patients will receive standard medical therapy in addition to PLVR.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Dose Ranging Study of the Aeris Polymeric Lung Volume Reduction (PLVR) System in Patients With Advanced Upper Lobe Predominant Emphysema</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Emphysema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Emphysema</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have a diagnosis of advanced upper lobe predominant (ULP) emphysema or advanced disease in the superior lower lobes as defined by FEV1/FVC &lt;70 % predicted, FEV1 of &lt; 50% predicted, TLC &gt; 100% of predicted, and RV &gt; 135% predicted. Patients must have persistent symptoms despite medical therapy and either not be candidates for Lung Volume Reduction Surgery (LVRS) or have elected not to undergo LVRS. Patients must be &gt; 40 years of age, have symptoms despite medical therapy, and have none of the prespecified comorbid conditions that could influence study outcomes or their ability to tolerate bronchoscopy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>emphysema</keyword>
	<keyword>aeris</keyword>
	<keyword>PLVR</keyword>
	<keyword>BLVR</keyword>
	<keyword>germany</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>device</keyword>
	<keyword>breathing</keyword>
</DOC>