<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00884234</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the safety and efficacy of 2 sequential doses of RT001 compared to vehicle control following applications at Baseline (Day 0) and Week 2.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of RT001 to Treat Moderate to Severe Lateral Canthal Lines</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a double-blind, randomized, parallel-group, controlled, repeat dose, single center study to evaluate the safety and efficacy of repeat application of RT001 in at least 30 subjects with moderate to severe lateral canthal lines. Subjects will be randomized to 1 of 2 treatment groups in a 1:1 ratio (RT001 Dose A or vehicle control).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins, Type A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>incobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>abobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>onabotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Female/male ages 30 to 55 2. Bilateral lateral canthal lines rated as moderate or advanced. 3. Willing to refrain from any product that affects skin remodeling or a product that may cause an active dermal response in the treatment area beginning at screening through Week 6. 4. Women of child baring potential must practice and be willing to continue to use an effective method of birth control. 1. Muscle weakness or paralysis in the area receiving treatment. 2. Active skin disease or irritation at treatment areas. 3. Undergone any procedures that may affect the lateral canthal region during the past 12 months prior to screening. 4. Previous treatment with botulinum toxin (any serotype) in the head or neck area within 9 months prior to Baseline (Day 0). 5. Use of topical steroid on either of the treatment areas or use of medications that suppress the immune system 30 days prior to screening and continuing through End of Study (Week 6). 6. Any abnormality on the electrocardiogram (ECG) at screening or any history of clinically significant arrhythmia, unstable angina, myocardial infarction or congestive hear failure.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lateral Canthal Lines</keyword>
	<keyword>Crow's Feet</keyword>
	<keyword>Facial Wrinkles</keyword>
	<keyword>Lateral Canthal Area</keyword>
</DOC>