<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00978029</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to assess the safety and tolerability of a ragweed allergy immunotherapy tablet (AIT) administered sublingually (under-the tongue) in subjects 50 years of age and older with ragweed-induced rhinoconjunctivitis, with or without asthma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of Ragweed Allergy Immunotherapy Tablet in Subjects 50 Years of Age and Older (Study P06081)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Conjunctivitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject must be 50 years of age or older, of either sex, and of any race/ethnicity. Subject must have a clinical history of ragweedinduced allergic rhinoconjunctivitis with or without asthma. Subject must have a positive skin prick test response to Ambrosia artemisiifolia at the Screening Visit Subject must have a forced expiratory volume in 1 second (FEV1) of at least 70% of predicted value at the Screening Visit and at Randomization. A subject's clinical laboratory tests, electrocardiogram (ECG) and vital signs conducted at the Screening Visit must be within normal limits or clinically acceptable to the investigator. Subject with asthma who requires inhaled corticosteroids for the treatment of their asthma during the study period. Subject requiring antiallergy medications during the time period from randomization to study completion. Subject who has received an immunosuppressive treatment within 3 months prior to the Screening Visit (except steroids for allergic and asthma symptoms). Subject with a history of anaphylaxis with cardiorespiratory symptoms. Subject with a history of chronic urticaria or angioedema. Subject with current severe atopic dermatitis. Female subject who is breastfeeding, pregnant, or intending to become pregnant. Subject with a history of allergy, hypersensitivity or intolerance to the ingredients of the investigational medicinal products (IMPs) (except for Ambrosia artemisiifolia), or selfinjectable epinephrine. Subject with a history of selfinjectable epinephrine use.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>immunotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>