<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00978406</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Information about Americans food choices and opinions helps researchers and law makers to develop policies and programs to promote health. For this reason, it is important to be able to collect good quality information about how people think about food. This project will compare different ways of collecting information about food from adults.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>National Cancer Institute Food Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objectives: -To compare different ways of collecting information about food choices and opinions from adults. Eligibility: - Individuals between the ages of 20 and 70, recruited from a database of volunteers who wish to participate in research studies. - Volunteers must have high-speed Internet access. - Individuals who have previously been involved in a research study will be excluded. Design: -Participants will come to a research study center for three consecutive meals (approximately 45 minutes per meal). On the following day, participants will return to the study center for an interview about their food choices and opinions (approximately 45 minutes).</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Eligibility Criteria Individuals between the ages of 20 and 70, recruited from a database of volunteers who wish to participate in research studies. Volunteers must have highspeed Internet access. Individuals who have previously been involved in a research study will be excluded. Subjects will be accrued from a variety of racial and ethnic groups and of varying educational achievement, though these characteristics will not be used to assess eligibility. All subjects will provide informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 25, 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dietary Assessment Methods</keyword>
	<keyword>Measurement of Diet</keyword>
	<keyword>24-Hour Diet Recall</keyword>
	<keyword>Validation</keyword>
	<keyword>Feeding Study</keyword>
</DOC>