<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00994006</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The magnesium food content in the Western world is consistently reducing. Hypomagnesemia is common in hospitalized patients, especially in the elderly with coronary artery disease (CAD) and/or those with chronic heart failure. Hypomagnesemia is associated with increased incidence of diabetes mellitus, metabolic syndrome, mortality rate from coronary artery disease (CAD) and all cause. Magnesium supplementation improves myocardial metabolism, inhibits calcium accumulation and myocardial cell death; it improves vascular tone, peripheral vascular resistance, afterload and cardiac output, reduces cardiac arrhythmias and improves lipid metabolism. Magnesium also reduces vulnerability to oxygen-derived free radicals, improves human endothelial function and inhibits platelet function, including platelet aggregation and adhesion. The data regarding the absorption difference between supplemental magnesium oxide and magnesium citrate in humans is spare.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Absorption of Magnesium Oxide Compared to Citrate in Healthy Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Two oral preparations of magnesium are available in Israel: 1. Magnesium Diasporal (magnesium citrate, elemental magnesium 98.6 mg), PROTINA GMBH, ISMANING, Germany 2. Magnox 520 TM (magnesium oxide, 520 mg elemental magnesium), Naveh Pharma Ltd., Israel. The data regarding the absorption difference between the two supplemental magnesium preparations (magnesium oxide and magnesium citrate) in humans is spare. Primary objective: To find out the absorption of magnesium citrate compared to magnesium oxide in healthy subjects with no apparent heart disease.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Magnesium Oxide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Magnesium citrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citric Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levulinic acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 2070 years 2. Healthy subjects 1. Chest pain 2. Diabetes mellitus 3. Documented coronary artery disease 4. Asthma or any lung disease 5. Chronic diarrhea 6. Chronic renal failure (serum creatinine&gt; 3 mg/dL) 7. Hypo or hyperthyroidism 8. Heart failure 9. On any chronic therapy/medications 10. Malabsorption 11. AV block 12. Pacemaker 13. Any malignancy 14. Obesity &gt; 30 kg/m2 body mass index 15. Smokers 16. Pregnancy 17. Alcohol or drug abuse 18. Any chronic inflammation 19. Refuse to sign inform consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Magnesium</keyword>
	<keyword>nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>platelets</keyword>
	<keyword>aggregation</keyword>
</DOC>