<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00994370</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being done to investigate the influence of giving radiation to the liver on tumors involving the liver. Investigator is specifically looking at this effect on the blood vessels within the tumor. This effect will be measured by studying substances in the blood that the tumors produce and that cause blood vessels to grow. The effects seen on these substances may help design other treatments to improve the results of the radiation used to treat these tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Measurement of Pro-angiogenic Markers in Patients With Hepatic Metastases Undergoing SIRT</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Subjects are invited to participate in this study that have undergone a procedure as their standard of care. This procedure is known as Selective Internal Radiation Therapy (SIRT), a procedure designed for the treatment of cancer in the liver. This includes cancer that has started in the liver as well as cancer that has spread to the liver. The purpose of the study is to collect blood samples to assess for "biological markers," or substances within the blood that may promote cancer growth by causing new blood vessels to form. This study will also use a new method of analyzing medical imaging (CT scan, PET scan) to try and better understand how cancer in the liver forms new blood vessels. SIRT is standard therapy and not part of this study. This study involves blood draws only.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients between the ages of 1885 who have been referred for SIRT as standard of care treatment for hepatocellular carcinoma or colorectal metastases to the liver and qualify for treatment with SIRT Life expectancy of at least 3 months Patients are excluded from participation in this study if they are not undergoing the SIRT procedure</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pro-angiogenic markers</keyword>
	<keyword>SIRT</keyword>
	<keyword>hepatic metastases</keyword>
</DOC>