<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00994149</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Diazoxide is an oral hyperglycemic medication. Diazoxide has been proven effective for treating hypoglycemia in infants and children with some types of persistent hyperinsulinemic hypoglycemia. The mechanism of action results in decreased insulin secretion. One of the causes of hypoglycemia in infants of diabetic mothers occurs due to a transient hyperinsulinemic state postnatally. The investigators have clinical experience and success using diazoxide in their unit for patients with hypoglycemia not adequately managed with intravenous (iv) dextrose and enteral supplementation. In this randomized controlled study the investigators expect that by using diazoxide as the initial treatment for infants of diabetic mothers with asymptomatic hypoglycemia (blood glucose of 2.5 to 2.0mmol/L), the investigators will be able to decrease the number of infants requiring an intravenous by at least thirty percent.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Diazoxide In the Management Of Hypoglycemic Neonates</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypoglycemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infant, Newborn, Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fetal Macrosomia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pregnancy in Diabetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diazoxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Infants of diabetic mothers (IDMs) or infants weighing &gt;90% Hypoglycemia: two consecutive blood glucose measurements &lt;2.6mol/L and &gt;1.9mmol/L in the first twelve hours of life &gt; 36 weeks gestational age Infants with symptomatic hypoglycemia (regardless of value Infants who meet criteria for intravenous dextrose according to the Canadian Pediatric Society (CPS) position statement Infants with contraindications for enteral feeds and/or medications</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Hours</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Infants of Diabetic Mothers</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypoglycemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Diazoxide</keyword>
	<keyword>Large for Gestation Infants</keyword>
</DOC>