<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00994773</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators have shown robust in vitro anti-hepatitis B activity of simvastatin alone and synergistic activity with all four FDA-approved anti-hepatitis B oral drugs tested. The investigators propose phase 1 studies in 48 chronic hepatitis B human carriers who have never been treated before. Doses of drugs will remain at or below FDA-approved dosage levels for cholesterol lowering (simvastatin) or hepatitis B (tenofovir or entecavir). Arm 1 will have simvastatin monotherapy only. Arm 2 will combine simvastatin with tenofovir. Arm 3 will combine simvastatin with entecavir. For maximum safety, the 3 arms and the dose groups in each arm will be filled consecutively and not concurrently. The definition of efficacy for simvastatin alone will be a 1 log drop of hepatitis B virus in 14 days. Efficacy for combination of drugs will require a 2 log drop of hepatitis B virus in 14 days. Numerous safety tests and stop rules are noted in the protocol.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Simvastatin for the Treatment of Chronic Hepatitis B</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Entecavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Simvastatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Hepatitis B positive by HBV DNA within 180 days. 2. Ages 1870. 3. Men and nonpregnant women eligible. 4. Veteran's eligibility or appropriate health insurance. 1. Use of any antiHBV medicine within 30 days. 2. Decompensated cirrhosis as evidenced by esophageal varices, ascites, or encephalopathy. (grade 1 varices without history of bleeding will be allowed, if patient meets Child'sPugh functional classification grade A). 3. A positive urine test for marijuana or alcohol within 2 months of screening.(Allowed to repeat tests on different days, if positive first time in order to become eligible for study. 4. Severe cardiovascular disease (ejection fraction &lt;20%)* or uncontrolled angina. 5. Severe pulmonary disease (FEV1 &lt; 1.0). 6. Chronic renal insufficiency (creatinine clearance &lt;50 ml/min. 7. HIV positive patients.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatitis B</keyword>
	<keyword>simvastatin</keyword>
	<keyword>HBV DNA</keyword>
</DOC>