<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00742846</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective is to compare the clinical outcomes of patients with a clinical diagnosis of Adhesive Capsulitis who receive intra-articular versus subacromial steroid injections. The secondary objective is to verify that steroid injections in combination with physical therapy lead to more favorable outcomes than local anesthetic injections in combination with physical therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Intra-articular Versus Subacromial Steroid Injections on Clinical Outcomes in Adhesive Capsulitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Current treatment for Adhesive Capsulitis involves physical therapy. Steroid injections have not been shown to be as effective alone without the physical therapy. However, there are multiple studies that document the benefit of adding a steroid injection to the physical therapy. After a review of the literature, there are studies that compare different dosages of intra-articular steroid injections,value and site of the injections, and accuracy of clinical injections. There are currently no studies that compare the results after intra-articular versus subacromial injections in combination with physical therapy. This study would help us determine if location of the injection is a major factor in regaining motion. If it is significantly important to be intra-articular with the steroid, than it may be important to send patients for fluoroscopic guided injections routinely rather than risk the chance of not being within the joint.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Periarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rheumatic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bursitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics, Local</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone hexacetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone Acetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone diacetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Meet clinical diagnosis of primary Adhesive Capsulitis Restriction in abduction to less than 130 degrees 50% reduction in external rotation as compared with the contralateral side An intact rotator cuff Between 1875 years of age Previous shoulder capsular surgery History of steroid injection(s) into affected shoulder Inability to provide informed consent Iodinated contrast dye allergy Allergy to lidocaine Other suspected shoulder pathology (i.e., tumor, rotator cuff rupture. infection, arthritis) Known bleeding diathesis Cervical spine pathology History of trauma to the shoulder Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Adhesive Capsulitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Subacromial injection</keyword>
	<keyword>Intraarticular injection</keyword>
</DOC>