<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00742729</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Develop and evaluate in a randomized trial an educational small group intervention to increase colorectal cancer screening among Filipino Americans.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Increasing Colorectal Cancer Screening Among Filipino Americans</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this research study is to increase colorectal cancer (CRC) screening among older Filipino Americans, specifically the use of fecal occult blood tests (FOBTs). We will design a culturally specific intervention, an educational small group discussion with a Filipino health professional. The effect of the intervention will be tested with 620 Filipino Americans. Subjects will be recruited at community-based organizations and churches and invited to join a 1 1/2 hour discussion of health issues with their partner and some of their friends. A third of the subjects will discuss exercise (control group), another third will discuss CRC and receive an FOBT kit, and the remaining third will discuss CRC and will not receive an FOBT kit. Three months after the group session, subjects in the CRC (intervention) groups will receive a letter reminding them to get screened. All subjects will be interviewed before and 6 months after the group sessions to assess CRC screening levels in the three groups. Self-reported CRC screening will be verified by a review of their medical records.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Being: a Filipino American, Member of or affiliated with participating community agencies, between the ages of 50 and 70, Not uptodate with colorectal cancer screening at baseline Being younger than 50 or older than 70 years, Not being a member or not affiliated with participating community agencies, Not being Filipino American or uptodate with colorectal cancer screening at baseline</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Colorectal cancer screening</keyword>
	<keyword>Fecal occult blood test</keyword>
	<keyword>Endoscopies</keyword>
	<keyword>Filipino American immigrants</keyword>
	<keyword>Community based organizations and churches</keyword>
</DOC>