<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00742768</DOC>
	<brief_summary>From previous studies it appeared that menaquinone-7 (MK-7) is the most effective form of vitamin K. The Japanese soya product natto is one of the richest food sources of MK-7. However, the taste of natto is not appreciated by the western society. For this reason the active biological compound is produced as a capsule. Different techniques of encapsulation the vitamin can lead to different absorption profiles with intake. Therefore it is important to study influence of type of encapsulation technique on absorption of menaquinone-7. This study is undertaken to compare absorption of menaquinones between two different encapsulation techniques. Absorption profiles of menaquinone-4 and menaquinone-7 of conventional softgel capsules and newly developed GellpelTM capsules are compared between each other.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Absorption of Vitamin K2</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin K</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin K 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin MK 7</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy men and women between 20 and 30 years old Subjects of normal body weight and height according to BMI &lt; 30 Subjects of Caucasian race Subject has given written consent to take part in the study Subjects with (a history of) metabolic or gastrointestinal disease Subjects presenting chronic degenerative and/or inflammatory disease Subjects receiving corticoϊd treatment Subjects using oral anticoagulants Subject with (a history of) soy allergy Subjects using vitamin K containing multivitamins or vitamin K supplements Subjects with anaemia or subjects who recently donate blood.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>absorption</keyword>
	<keyword>encapsulation</keyword>
	<keyword>menaquinone</keyword>
	<keyword>Bio-availability</keyword>
</DOC>