<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01244282</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will identify a dose of ferumoxytol that can reliably detect changes in blood flow/volume in response to non-drug stimuli. The study will determine whether signal detection for functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) using ferumoxytol is better than that for blood oxygen level-dependent (BOLD) fMRI in response to sensory stimulation. The following procedures will be conducted in each of two study periods: arterial spin labeling (ASL) imaging study with increasing exposure to carbon dioxide (CO2); BOLD fMRI study with sensory stimulation; MRI studies with sensory stimulation in the presence of increasing doses of ferumoxytol; MRI study with increasing exposure to CO2 in the presence of ferumoxytol. There will be a 3-week interval between the two study periods. The study will enroll 8 subjects, but an additional 4 subjects are permitted to enroll to preserve study power.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Two Methodologies for Measuring Blood Flow in the Brain in Response to Non-Drug Stimuli (P08085/MK-0000-180)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Design: Translational Medicine - Imaging Platform Development</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Participant weighs approximately 5575 kg and has a Body Mass Index (BMI) of 1825 kg/m^2 Participant is in good health Participant is a nonsmoker and/or has not used nicotine or nicotinecontaining products for at least 6 months Participant has a contraindication to MRI including cardiac pacemaker, brain aneurysm clip, implanted neurostimulator, insulin pump, cochlear implant, metal slivers in the eyes, or any other MRIincompatible metal implants that cannot be safely removed Participant has a condition that would limit his ability to complete MRI procedures, such as claustrophobia or chronic back pain Participant plans to undergo MRI studies in the 3 months following the poststudy visit Participant has a history of hemochromatosis or other conditions of iron overload or disease of iron metabolism Participant has a known sensitivity to ferumoxytol or ironcontaining products or has a history of severe allergies, anaphylactic reaction, or intolerance to drugs and/or foods Participant has a history of stroke, chronic seizures, or major neurological disorder Participant is unable to refrain from the use of any medication, including prescription and nonprescription drugs or herbal remedies from approximately 2 weeks prior to the first dose of ferumoxytol until the poststudy visit Participant has a history of significant head injury/trauma with loss of consciousness lasting for 15 minutes and one or more of the following: a) recurring seizures resulting from head injury; b) persistent neurological or cognitive sequelae of the injury; c) cognitive rehabilitation following the injury</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>brain imaging</keyword>
</DOC>