<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01298414</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Studying samples of bone marrow from patients with cancer in the laboratory may help doctors identify and learn more about biomarkers related to cancer. PURPOSE: This research study is looking at biomarkers in bone marrow samples from young patients with acute myeloid leukemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Biomarkers in Bone Marrow Samples From Young Patients With Acute Myeloid Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - To study the effect of niche mesenchymal stromal cells (MSC) exposure on microRNAs (miR) expression in pediatric AML at different time points and compare those profiles to the miR profiles at baseline. - To focus on four pediatric AML-specific miRs (miR34a, miR538e, miR193e, and miR198) which show the most significant differential expression after in vivo niche exposure at four months (hematogenous spread). - To determine whether altered miR expression reflects or causes the metastatic invasion pattern of AML. OUTLINE: Bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stromal cell (MSC) samples are implanted subcutaneously in NOD/SCID mice. Cells are then harvested at day 0, 1 month, and 4 months post-implantation. miRNA is isolated and analyzed by Ilumina MicroRNA Expression Profiling single Beadchip. The obtained data is then analyzed by the Illumina Genome Studio Analysis Software.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of acute myeloid leukemia Fresh human bone marrow samples obtained from orthopedic surgery at the Tissue Donation Program of The Feinstein Institute and the Children Oncology Group (COG) Myeloid Disease Biorepository PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Not specified PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>childhood acute myeloid leukemia/other myeloid malignancies</keyword>
</DOC>