<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01364012</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study will evaluate the efficacy and safety of Avastin (bevacizumab) versus placebo in combination with carboplatin/paclitaxel in patients with advanced or recurrent non-squamous non-small cell lung cancer who have not received prior chemotherapy for advanced disease. Patients will be randomized to receive either Avastin 15 mg/kg intravenously or placebo on Day 1 of each 3-week cycle, plus up to 6 cycles of carboplatin/paclitaxel. Anticipated time on study treatment is until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity occurs. After progression, patients in the Avastin-arm may continue to receive Avastin in combination with approved second- and third-line treatment at the discretion of the investigator, up to the third progression.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Avastin (Bevacizumab) Versus Placebo in Combination With Carboplatin/Paclitaxel) in Patients With Advanced or Recurrent Non-Squamous Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Who Have Not Received Previous Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients, &gt;/= 18 years of age Locally advanced (Stage IIIb not amenable for combined modality treatment), metastatic (Stage IV) or recurrent nonsquamous nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC) Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 01 Adequate haematological, renal and liver function Prior chemotherapy or treatment with another systemic anticancer agent for the current stage of the disease (IIIb, IV or recurrent) Mixed nonsmall cell and small cell tumours or mixed adenosquamous carcinomas with a predominant squamous component Evidence of tumour invading major blood vessels on imaging CNS metastases, even if previously treated History of haemoptysis in the 3 months prior to enrollment History or evidence of inherited bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy Uncontrolled hypertension and/or history of hypertensive crisis or hypertensive encephalopathy Clinically significant cardiovascular or vascular disease Malignancies other than NSCLC within 5 years prior to randomization, except for adequately treated carcinoma in situ of the cervix, basal or squamous cell skin cancer, or localized prostate cancer or ductal carcinoma in situ treated surgically with curative intent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>