<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01364324</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effect of gastrectomy on pharmacokinetic profile of first-line anti-tuberculosis drugs in patients with pulmonary tuberculosis (TB).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetics of Anti-tuberculosis Drugs in Gastrectomized Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Gastrectomy is a well-known risk factor for TB. Also, there were some reports about malabsorption of anti-TB drugs in the gastrectomized patients. However, pharmacokinetics of recently used first line anti-TB drugs in the gastrectomized patients have not been well evaluated simultaneously. Therefore, the investigators aim to evaluate the effect of gastrectomy on pharmacokinetic profile of first-line anti-TB drugs in patients with pulmonary TB through this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antitubercular Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age greater than 18 years and less than 80 years 2. pulmonary TB confirmed by microbiologic test such as AFB culture or TB PCR 3. usage of 4 firstline antiTB drugs (Isoniazid(INH) Rifampin(RFP) Ethambutol(EMB), Pyrazinamide(PZA) = HREZ) 1. patients with liver disease (bilirubin ≥ 1.5 mg/d or AST ≥ 2 x normal upper limit) or chronic renal failure (Cr ≥ 2.0 mg/d) who cannot use firstline antiTB drugs 2. patients with AIDS or hypoalbuminemia(albumin &lt; 3.0g/dl)that will influence pharmacokinetics of first line antiTB drugs 3. patients using other drugs that will influence pharmacokinetics of first line antiTB drugs during antiTB treatment (e.g warfarin) 4. patients using anticancer or immunosuppressive agents that will influence the response of pulmonary TB to antiTB drugs 5. discontinuation of firstline antiTB drugs(HREZ)due to side effect or resistance 6. followup loss before completion of antiTB treatment 7. any condition making the patients undergo gastrectomy during antiTB treatment in case of Nongastrectomy group</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>tuberculosis</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>first-line drugs</keyword>
	<keyword>gastrectomy</keyword>
</DOC>