<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01364428</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted in the United States of America (USA). The aim of this trial is to compare the efficacy and safety of two different formulations of insulin degludec (IDeg) in subjects with type 2 diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Two Insulin Degludec Formulations in Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Long-Acting</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 2 diabetes (diagnosed clinically) for minimum 24 weeks prior to randomisation (visit 2) Current treatment with basalonly insulin (no prandial insulin) consisting of either insulin detemir once daily (OD), insulin glargine OD or neutral protamine hagedorn (NPH) insulin OD/twice daily (BID) for at least 12 weeks prior to randomisation (visit 2), in combination with stable doses of OAD(s) (metformin, insulin secretagogue (sulfonylurea or glinide), alphaglucosidase inhibitor, pioglitazone or dipeptidyl peptidase IV (DPPIV) inhibitor in any approved (according to label) dose or combination. Stable OAD doses are defined as unchanged doses for at least 12 weeks prior to randomisation (visit 2) HbA1c (glycosylated haemoglobin) between 7.010.0% (both inclusive) by central laboratory analysis Body mass index (BMI) below or equal to 45 kg/m^2 Ability and willingness to adhere to the protocol including selfmeasured plasma glucose (SMPG) according to the protocol Treatment with rosiglitazone within the last 12 weeks prior to randomisation (visit 2) Treatment with glucagon like peptide1 (GLP1) receptor agonists within the last 12 weeks prior to randomisation (visit 2) Recurrent severe hypoglycaemia (more than one severe hypoglycaemic event during the last 12 months) or hypoglycaemic unawareness as judged by the Investigator (trial physician) Previous participation in this trial. Participation is defined as randomised. Rescreening is allowed once during the recruitment period Known or suspected hypersensitivity to trial products or related products The receipt of any investigational drug within 4 weeks prior to randomisation (visit 2)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>