<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01364857</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Port Wine Stain on a limb can be either isolated or associated with complications (venous or orthopedic impairment, arteriovenous malformations), leading sometimes to complex syndromes (Klippel-Trenaunay syndrome,Parkes-Weber syndrome). Little is known about epidemiology of port wine stains: their evolution during the growth of the child, the frequency of complications, genetic data, and prognostic factors. This prospective french national cohort will help for : description of the evolution of port wine stain and possible complications; prognostic factors for complications ; association with mutations of RASA1 gene; quality of life of these children. It will also help for global appreciation of the management of this disease in France.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>French National Cohort of Children With Port Wine Stain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Prospective national study, including 16 Pediatric and Dermatologic Departments. Methods : each children with a port wine stain on a lower limb will be followed up for 5 years. Collected data : demographic data, clinical features, alterations of RASA1 gene, vascular evaluation by ultrasonographic and orthopedic evaluation by X rays, quality of life with a questionnaire. Inclusion period = 3 years Follow up period = 5 years Population = 150 children</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Port-Wine Stain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemangioma, Capillary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Malformations</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Stem Infarctions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Klippel-Trenaunay-Weber Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sturge-Weber Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>GTPase-Activating Proteins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Child between 2 and 12 years old with a port wine stain on a lower limb ( or two lower limbs) with national health assurance with consent from one parent child with orthopedic impairment with no link with the port wine stain</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>port wine stain of a limb</keyword>
</DOC>