<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02899637</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective is to conduct a study protocol to investigate the effects of repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (rTMS) on sensory and motor performance of individuals with incomplete spinal cord injury (iSCI) . A double-blind randomized sham-controlled trial of patients with iSCI will be conducted.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation in Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Effective rehabilitation programs for individuals with incomplete spinal cord injury (iSCI) are required either in the acute or in the post-acute care. Rehabilitation techniques based on protocols that selectively stimulate specific pathways along the central nervous system have been considered effective in enhancing neurologic recovery thereby improving functional abilities. The rationale relies on the assumption that the stimulation of the corticospinal tract, primary motor cortex, and spinal cord might induce neuronal reorganization of structures that are largely involved in the control of voluntary movements. In this line of reasoning, protocols involving repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) have been found effective in enhancing corticospinal synaptic transmission, attenuating neuropathic pain, improving spasticity and sensorimotor function after iSCI. However, controversial findings have also been reported, as other studies showed unaltered central pain, as well as cortical excitability and sensorimotor function. The lack of consistent results is probably associated with differences in stimulation parameters, number of sessions, site of stimulation, chronicity and levels of injury, and outcome measurements of the previous studies. Thus, it is clear that there are remaining gaps in our knowledge and the development of new studies, preferably prospective fully double-blind placebo-controlled trials, is necessary to complement the current knowledge about the effects of rTMS in patients with iSCI.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have a clinical diagnosis of iSCI with nonprogressive etiology Clinical stability Aged between 1860 years old Score equal to 24 in the MiniMental State Examination No electroencephalography alterations Absence of depression assessed by Hamilton Depression Scale Currently receiving inpatient rehabilitation in Physiotherapy Health Center of University of the State of Paraiba, Brazil. Have metal prosthesis in some part of the body Use cardiac pacemaker Present dementia or neurological disorders which can increase cortical excitability Have psychotic or schizophrenic disorders Take drugs that reduce seizure threshold or spasticity.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-invasive brain stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</keyword>
</DOC>