<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02899390</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Diabetes is a major non communicable chronic diseases in the world. It occupies the fourth or fifth leading cause of death in most high-income countries and there is strong evidence that has epidemic proportions in many developing countries, including Mexico. Like diabetes, prediabetes is associated with obesity and insulin resistance, thus promoting a lifestyle with healthy eating and physical activity can reduce weight and in turn the risk of diabetes. Several studies have shown that it is possible to prevent or delay the development of type 2 diabetes through a lifestyle intervention based on diet and physical activity. The National Diabetes Prevention Program is a study based on the Diabetes Prevention Program conducted in real-world conditions. It is known that the acculturation of some ethnic groups has led to the increase in certain chronic degenerative diseases due to increased associated risk factors. The rural Yaqui tribe has a high prevalence of overweight, obesity, high triglycerides and type 2 diabetes. In addition to the rural Yaqui tribe there is another settlement of this tribe in the city of Hermosillo Sonora. Information on the health of this ethnic group is limited, however, it is known that being seated in an urban setting with an obesogenic lifestyle, which has been shown to have serious health effects in other populations, suggesting a high prevalence chronic non-communicable diseases such as obesity, type 2 diabetes and hypertension at this ethnic group. The present study is a translational research clinical trial to evaluate the effectiveness of the National Diabetes Prevention Program to improve obesity parameters (weight, BMI, waist circumference) and increase physical activity in adults who are at risk of diabetes in the Yaqui tribe established in Hermosillo, Sonora.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Diabetes Prevention Program in Adults of the Yaqui Tribe of Hermosillo, Sonora at Risk of Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The present project wants to know if a diabetes prevention program can reduce the risk of developing diabetes in adults at risk of the Yaqui tribe established in Hermosillo, through the loss of weight and physical activity, all these with an intensive lifestyle intervention program that provide them the benefits of a healthy nutrition and physical activity. The hypothesis is that a lifestyle intervention program addressed to adults in the Yaqui tribe, established in Hermosillo at risk of diabetes can significantly decrease the parameters of obesity in a period of 6 months and increase physical activity in the same time period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prediabetic State</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Being part of the Yaqui tribe established in Hermosillo, Sonora. Age 20 years and less than 65 FINDRISC score of 12 or higher Desire of participate Sign up the consent form Diabetes diagnosis or another chronic disease Have been suffered a myocardial infarction in the last 6 months Cardiovascular disease Be seriously ill Use of medication that alter glucose tolerance Use of medicaments to lost weight Present conditions that affect their participation in the study (use of drugs or inability to exercise</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>