<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02899741</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether omega-3 is effective in the treatment of medically intractable epilepsy as adjunctive therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Omega-3 as Adjunctive Therapy for Medically Intractable Epilepsy: A Prospective Open-label Pilot Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will enroll total 30 patients with medically intractable epilepsy. The patients will be fully assessed on the enrollment, and then seizure frequency will be counted for three months without changing medication. After three months, Omega-3 will be administered for next three months. Seizure frequency, questionnaires evaluating mood and QOL, and adverse events are evaluated at each visit.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Drug Resistant Epilepsy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with medically intractable, focal or generalized, epilepsy: Patients with localizationrelated partial onset or generalized tonic/clonic seizure according to the International League Against Epilepsy (ILAE) can be included. Medically intractable epilepsy means that recurrent seizures occur even though two or more antiepileptic drugs have been used appropriately for over one year. Seizure frequency criteria: three seizures per one month for recent 3 months before enrollment Seizure criteria: simple partial, complex partial, or tonicclonic seizures Subjects with normal cognitive function: patients who can perform normal daily life. If not definite, enrollment will be done with KMMSE score over 27. Poor general medical condition: comorbid with heart, lung, liver diseases Patients who have history of pseudoseizure Antiepileptic drugs has been changed in recent one month. Chronic alcoholic Seizure count cannot be done since seizures occur successively. Allergy to fish High risk of bleeding such as trauma or operation Liver function abnormality Pregnant or lactating women, or women who plans to have children Patients who have participated in the other clinical trial in recent one month</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Medically intractable epilepsy, Omega-3</keyword>
</DOC>