<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02899052</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Phase 2, open-label, dose escalation study to evaluate the safety and efficacy of venetoclax in combination with carfilzomib-dexamethasone (Kd) in participants with relapsed or refractory MM and have received 1 to 3 prior lines of therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Venetoclax in Combination With Carfilzomib and Dexamethasone in Subjects With Relapsed or Refractory Multiple Myeloma (MM)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Eastern Collaborative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance score of less than or equal to 2. Documented relapsed or progressive Multiple Myeloma (MM) on or after any regimen or is refractory to the most recent line of therapy. Received prior treatment with at least 1, but no more than 3, prior lines of therapy for MM. Measurable disease on Screening per International Myeloma Working Group (IMWG) criteria. Meets absolute neutrophil count, platelet count, hemoglobin, liver and kidney function laboratory values within 2 weeks prior to first dose of study drug. Has a preexisting condition that is contraindicated including Nonsecretory or oligosecretory MM Active plasma cell leukemia Waldenström's macroglobulinemia Primary amyloidosis POEMS syndrome (polyneuropathy, organomegaly, endocrinopathy, monoclonal protein, and skin changes) Active hepatitis B or C infection based on screening blood testing Significant cardiovascular disease Major surgery within 4 weeks prior to first dose Acute infections requiring parenteral therapy Peripheral neuropathy ≥ Grade 3 or ≥ Grade 2 with pain within 2 weeks prior to first dose Uncontrolled diabetes or uncontrolled hypertension within 14 days prior to first dose Any other medical condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would adversely affect the subject's participation in the study. History of other active malignancies, including myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS), within the past 3 years prior to study entry Other protocol defined inclusion/exclusion criteria could apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Refractory myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Relapsed myeloma</keyword>
</DOC>