<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02938897</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a 12-week pilot randomized controlled trial to test the feasibility and effectiveness of a home telenutrition weight loss program in men in West Virginia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Telenutrition Weight Loss Study for Men</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a 12-week pilot randomized controlled trial of a home telenutrition weight loss program for men with obesity and at least one additional risk factor for cardiovascular disease. The primary aims are to: 1. To assess the feasibility and acceptability of the male-targeted telenutrition weight loss program in terms of recruitment, retention and satisfaction and 2. To evaluate the effectiveness of the telenutrition program compared to usual care (informational only) with regard to primary and secondary outcome measures at 12 weeks. We hypothesized that men receiving virtual and telephonic support from a registered dietitian nutritionist would have greater weight loss and greater improvements in diet quality than men who were only provided educational materials.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>4070 year old man Body mass index ≥ 30 Living with spouse or companion At least one of the following: hypertension, diabetes, prediabetes, hypercholesterolemia or hypertriglyceridemia A home computer with highspeed internet access A telephone for health coach phone calls Cancer (except skin or prostate), celiac disease, bacterial or viral infections, renal or liver disease (except nonalcoholic fatty liver disease), or condition that prevents fruits and vegetable consumption Major surgery or health event (e.g., stroke, heart attack) in the past six months Taking insulin, antiobesity medications, steroids (e.g., Prednisone), or warfarin (Coumadin) Pacemaker or defibrillator Currently on a weight loss diet or lost &gt; 10 pounds in past six months Consume more than two alcoholic beverages daily</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Telehealth</keyword>
	<keyword>Weight loss</keyword>
	<keyword>Diet quality</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavioral counseling</keyword>
</DOC>