<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02978820</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Scoliosis specific exercises have been shown to improve curve progression but there have been few studies that compare the different exercise approaches in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis (AIS). The objective of this study was to compare the effects of Core stabilization (CS) exercises with Scientific Exercises Approach to Scoliosis (SEAS exercises) in addition to brace wearing in patients with AIS. It is important to compare different exercise methods on different aspects of scoliotic deformity, such as curve progression, angle of trunk rotation, body symmetry, cosmetic trunk deformity, satisfaction with treatment and quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Comparison of Core Stabilization Exercise With Scientific Exercise Approach to Scoliosis in Idiopathic Scoliosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of this study was to investigate whether adolescent with idiopathic scoliosis receiving scoliosis specific exercise approach, such as SEAS exercises, in accordance with the bracing approach for moderate curves would have greater improvement in curve progression, trunk deformity, body symmetry and quality of life than adolescent receiving exercise therapy based on the general core stabilization approach with similar intensity. Thirty female patients with AIS aged 12 to16 years, who have moderate curves (20 to 45 degree) randomly divided into two groups. One group received CS exercise, while other received SEAS exercise for forty-min once weekly for four months. Both groups underwent full-time bracing (23 hours per day) intervention. Outcome was based on Cobb angle, angle of trunk rotation, body symmetry (Posterior Trunk Symmetry Index), cosmetic trunk deformity (Walter Reed Visual Assessment Scale) and quality of life (Scoliosis Research Society - 22 Questionnaire) measured at baseline and after intervention period. Results were analyzed using the paired sample t-test to compare repeated measurements and independent sample t-test to compare the groups.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Scoliosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patients included in the current study were consecutive adolescents with idiopathic scoliosis seen in our department who were referred to receive both brace and exercise treatment conservatively. Additional inclusion criteria included the following: female gender; at least age 12 years; primary curve magnitude between 20 and 45 degrees of Cobb angle; double curve (right thoracicleft lumbar) or single thoracolumbar curve having an apex in the main thoracic region; Risser 23 and no previous treatment. Exclusion criteria for both groups were as follows: evidence of congenital curve; neuromuscular, rheumatologic, renal, cardiovascular, pulmonary or vestibular diseases or surgical correction history.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>scientific exercise approach to scoliosis</keyword>
	<keyword>core stabilization training</keyword>
	<keyword>bracing</keyword>
	<keyword>adolescent idiopathic scoliosis</keyword>
</DOC>