<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02978716</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a study to investigate the potential clinical benefit of trilaciclib (G1T28) in preserving the bone marrow and the immune system, and enhancing chemotherapy antitumor efficacy when administered prior to carboplatin and gemcitabine (GC therapy) for patients with metastatic triple negative breast cancer. The study is open-label and approximately 90 patients will be randomly assigned (1:1:1 fashion) to 1 of the 3 following treatment groups: - Group 1: GC therapy (Days 1 and 8 of 21-day cycles) only (n=30) - Group 2: GC therapy (Days 1 and 8) plus trilaciclib (G1T28) on Days 1 and 8 of 21-day cycles (n=30) - Group 3: GC therapy (Days 2 and 9) plus trilaciclib (G1T28) on Days 1, 2, 8, and 9 of 21-day cycles (n=30) The study will include 3 study phases: Screening Phase, Treatment Phase, and Survival Follow-up Phase. The Treatment Phase begins on the day of first dose with study treatment and completes at the Post-Treatment Visit.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trilaciclib (G1T28), a CDK 4/6 Inhibitor, in Combination With Gemcitabine and Carboplatin in Metastatic Triple Negative Breast Cancer (mTNBC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triple Negative Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed diagnosis of HRnegative, HER2negative (TNBC) breast cancer Available TNBC diagnostic tumor tissue (archived tissue allowed) Measurable disease as defined by RECIST, Version 1.1 ECOG performance status 0 to 1 Adequate organ function Predicted life expectancy of 3 or more months More than 1 prior chemotherapy regimen for locally recurrent or metastatic TNBC Prior treatment of locally recurrent or metastatic breast cancer with gemcitabine, carboplatin, or cisplatin (previous adjuvant/neoadjuvant chemotherapy with carboplatin, cisplatin, or gemcitabine is allowed if ≥ 12 months have elapsed between the date of last adjuvant/neoadjuvant chemotherapy administration and first documented local or distant disease recurrence) Less than 12 months between date of last adjuvant chemotherapy administration (with curative intent) and first documented local or distant disease recurrence. Active uncontrolled/symptomatic CNS metastases, carcinomatous meningitis, or leptomeningeal disease Investigational drug within 30 days of first trilaciclib (G1T28) dose Concurrent radiotherapy, radiotherapy within 14 days of first trilaciclib (G1T28) dose Cytotoxic chemotherapy within 3 weeks of first trilaciclib (G1T28) dose Prior hematopoietic stem cell or bone marrow transplantation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>CDK 4/6 Inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Triple Negative Breast Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>