<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01353625</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of this first human study with CC-115 is to assess the safety and action of a new class of experimental drug (dual DNA-PK and TOR kinase inhibitors) in patients with advanced tumors unresponsive to standard therapies and to determine the appropriate dose and tumor types for later-stage clinical trials. The bioavailability of tablet and capsule formulations under fasting and fed conditions will also be evaluated in some patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Assess Safety and Tolerability of Oral CC-115 for Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors, and Hematologic Malignancies.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Latest amendment clarifies that Chronic Lymophocytic Leukemia (CLL) includes T-cell Prolymphocytic Leukemia (T-PLL). Prior treatment with some drugs targeting mTOR, P13K and related pathways is now permitted.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologicallyconfirmed advanced solid tumor, chronic lymphocytic leukemia, small lymphocytic lymphoma, Tcell prolymphocytic leukemia, NonHodgkin Lymphoma or multiple myeloma Progressed or not tolerated standard therapy, and no further standard therapy is available Archival and screening tumor biopsy Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status: 0 or 1 Adequate organ function Prior cancerdirected modalities or investigational drugs within 4 wks or 5 half lives, whichever is shorter Symptomatic brain metastases (prior treatment and stable metastases are allowed) Acute or chronic renal disease or pancreatitis Diarrhea ≥ Grade 2, impaired gastrointestinal absorption Impaired cardiac function History of diabetes requiring treatment, glucose &gt;126 mg/dL, Glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) ≥6.5% Peripheral neuropathy ≥ Grade 2 Known Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) infection, chronic hepatitis B or C (unless associated with hepatocellular cancer) Pregnant, inadequate contraception, breast feeding Most concurrent second malignancies Part B only: Prior treatment with agents targeting both mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) complexes (dual mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1/2 inhibitors) and/or PI3K/AKT pathways. However, prior treatment with isolated target of rapamycin complex 1 (TORC1) inhibitors (eg., rapalogs) is allowed in both parts of this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neoplasm</keyword>
	<keyword>Malignancy</keyword>
	<keyword>Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiple myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>mTOR kinase inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Castration-resistant prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Hormone-resistant prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Diffuse Large B-cell lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>