<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02954991</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will evaluate the clinical activity of nivolumab in combination with 3 separate investigational agents, glesatinib, sitravatinib, or mocetinostat.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 2 Study of Glesatinib, Sitravatinib or Mocetinostat in Combination With Nivolumab in Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Glesatinib is an orally administered multi-targeted tyrosine kinase inhibitor (TKI) that primarily targets the Axl and Mesenchymal-Epithelial Transition (MET) receptors. Sitravatinib is an orally-available, potent small molecule inhibitor or a closely related spectrum of receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs) including MET, Axl, MERTK, VEGFR family, PDGFR family, KIT, FLT3, Trk family, RET, DDR2 and selected Eph family members. Mocetinostat is an orally administered histone deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitor. Nivolumab is a human IgG monoclonal antibody that binds to the programmed cell death-1(PD-1) receptor and blocks its interaction with programmed cell death ligand-1 (PD-L1) and PD-L2, releasing PD-1 pathway-mediated inhibition of the immune response including anti-tumor immune response. Combining an immunotherapeutic PD-L1 checkpoint inhibitor with an agent that has both immune modulatory and antitumor properties could enhance the antitumor efficacy observed with either agent alone. The study will being with a lead-in dose escalation evaluation of two dose levels of each investigational agent in combination with nivolumab. Following completion of the lead-in dose escalation, enrollment into the Phase 2 study will proceed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mocetinostat</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of nonsmall cell lung cancer. Prior treatment with platinum based doublet and checkpoint inhibitor Adequate bone marrow and organ function Uncontrolled tumor in the brain Unacceptable toxicity with prior checkpoint inhibitor Impaired heart function</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>