<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02954783</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background and purpose: The purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of exercise on intratumoral natural killer (NK)-cell variability in patients with localized prostate cancer undergoing radical prostatectomy. The primary hypothesis is that exercise induces epinephrine-mediated intratumoral natural killer (NK)-cell infiltration in patients with localized prostate cancer, and that the infiltration is greater in patients performing High Intensity Interval Training compared to moderate intensity training. Currently there is a lack of randomized controlled trials examining different types of exercise in patients with localized prostate cancer. Moreover there is a need for studies including biological measurements to allow a full assessment of the effect of exercise on diverse biomarkers and mechanistic pathways, which may influence cancer survival. Subjects: Patients with histologically verified prostate adenocarcinoma scheduled for radical prostatectomy at Urologic Department, Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark. Methods: In this randomized controlled pilot study 30 patients with localized prostate cancer undergoing radical prostatectomy will be included and randomized to either High Intensity Interval Training (HIIT) exercise intervention, Moderate-Intensity Aerobic Exercise and Resistance Training (MI-AT+RT) intervention (standard recommendations) or observational control receiving usual care for a total period of 8 weeks. All patients will undergo assessments at inclusion (baseline) and after 8 weeks (5-7 days prior to surgery,) respectively. Assessments include: anthropometrics; blood pressure; resting hearth rate; cardiorespiratory fitness by cardiopulmonary exercise test (VO2 peak.); body composition by DXA scan; quality of life by self-report questionnaires; oral glucose tolerance test; fasting blood sample measuring cholesterol, triglycerides, insulin, c-peptide, HbA1c, glucose, hormones and inflammatory markers. Also, the investigators will collect blood samples before, during and after an acute exercise bout in order to explore the acute systemic changes in exercise-regulated biomarkers. Biological tissue from tumor (primary prostate biopsies) will be retrieved from the respective local pathological departments and from the perioperative prostate specimen and sent to protocol analyses.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PROstaTe Cancer - Exercise-STudy (PRO-TEST)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of exercise on the variability of intratumoral Natural Killer (NK)-cell infiltration in tumor biopsies taken before and after an exercise intervention in patients randomized to one of three study arms: I) High Intensity Interval Training (N=10) II) Moderate-Intensity Aerobic and Resistance Training (N=10) or III) usual care, prior to radical prostatectomy (N=10). In addition to this the investigators wish to investigate the effect of these different exercise regimens on tumor vessel morphology, modulation of tumor-metabolism, -biology and signaling. Furthermore the aim is to explore the acute response in immune cells, hormones and cytokines in blood samples taken before, during and after a single exercise session in patients in the two exercise intervention arms. Finally the aim is to explore the effect of different pre-operative exercise regimens on physiological (e.g. cardiovascular fitness, body composition, metabolic profile and metabolic inflammatory markers) and psycho-social (e.g. fatigue, emotional well-being, anxiety) endpoints relative to usual care.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pathologically verified localized prostate cancer Eligible for curative radical prostatectomy Any other known malignancy requiring active treatment Performance status &gt; 1 Ongoing treatment with beta blockers, antihistamines, glucocorticoids, NSAIDs (Nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs), DMARDs (Diseasemodifying antirheumatic drugs) Physical disabilities precluding physical testing and/or exercise Inability to read and understand Danish</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Localized</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>Natural killer cells</keyword>
	<keyword>Immune cells</keyword>
</DOC>