<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02421185</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine recommended Phase 2 dose [RP2D]) and the objective response rate of JNJ-42756493 (erdafitinib) in advanced hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) participants with fibroblast growth factor (FGF) 19 amplification.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Safety, Pharmacokinetics, and Pharmacodynamics of JNJ-42756493 (Erdafitinib) in Participants With Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label (all people know the identity of the intervention), multicenter (when more than one hospital or medical school team work on a medical research study), 2 parts (First, dose escalation Phase and second, dose expansion Phase) study to evaluate the safety, pharmacokinetics, pharmacodynamics, and clinical responses of JNJ-42756493 (erdafitinib) in Asian participants with advanced HCC. The duration of study will be approximately 11 months per participant. The study consists of 2 periods: Screening (28 days before study commences on Day 1); Open-label Treatment (dose escalation portion of the trial [Part 1]), participants are enrolled into cohorts at increasing dose levels of JNJ-42756493 (erdafitinib) in 28 day treatment cycles. Part 2, the cohort expansion part of the trial, will further explore the recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) of JNJ-42756493 (erdafitinib) as determined in Part 1; and follow-up Phase (up to 6 months). Blood samples will be collected for evaluation of safety, pharmacokinetics, pharmacodynamics, and predictive biomarkers at pre-dose and post-dose of study treatment. Recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D) for JNJ-42756493 (erdafitinib) will be evaluated primarily. Participants' safety will be monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). (histology or cytology from prior tumor biopsy specimen is acceptable). For Part 1 continuous dosing regimen and Part 2, HCC participants must have fibroblast growth factor (FGF) 19 amplification based on central laboratory results Participant must have advanced disease and meet all the following criteria: Disease progression after previous surgical or localregional therapy, if any; Disease ineligible for surgical or localregional therapy or systemic therapy; Received no more than 1 line of systemic therapy (Participants who are intolerant to previous systemic therapy are allowed.) Cirrhotic status of ChildPugh class A: Participants with ChildPugh class B score of 7 may be considered in Part 2 if no pharmacokinetic (PK) and safety issues are identified in Part 1 from subjects with ChildPugh class A Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status score 0 or 1 Participants with adequate bone marrow, liver, renal function, and electrolytes according to protocoldefined criteria within the 14 days before the first dose of study drug Negative pregnancy test (urine or serum beta human chorionic gonadotropin [beta (b)hCG]) at Screening for women of child bearing potential who are sexually active Received systemic chemotherapy, targeted therapies, definitive radiotherapy, or treatment with an investigational anticancer agent within 2 weeks (in the case of nitrosoureas and mitomycin C, within 6 weeks; in the case of immunotherapy, within 4 weeks) before the first administration of study drug Prior liver transplant Known fibrolamellar HCC or mixed cholangiocarcinoma and HCC Clinically active serious infections greater than (&gt;) Common Terminology Criteria for adverse events (AEs) grade 2 Participants with persistent calcium or phosphate &gt; upper limits of normal (ULN) during screening (within 14 days prior to Day 1 of Cycle 1 up until predose of Cycle 1) and despite medical management of calcium or phosphate levels</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</keyword>
	<keyword>JNJ 42756493</keyword>
	<keyword>a pan-Fibroblast Growth Factor Receptor Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitor</keyword>
</DOC>