<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02565589</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate natural killer (NK) cell activities, circulating cytokine levels and peripheral blood mononuclear cell (PBMC) cytokine production status in critically ill patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hyporesponsiveness of Natural Killer Cells and a Dysfunctional Inflammatory Response in Critically Ill Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Blood samples were collected &lt; 24 hours after admission from 24 intensive care unit (ICU) patients and 24 age-, sex-, and body mass index (BMI)-matched healthy controls. Serum cytokine concentrations and cytokine production by PBMCs and lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-stimulated PBMCs were measured. The ICU group showed lower NK cell activities and an absence of interferon (IFN)-γ than the controls under all conditions. After adjusting for triglycerides, LDL- and HDL-cholesterol, and glucose, the ICU group exhibited lower serum levels of albumin and interleukin (IL)-12 and higher leukocyte count, high sensitivity C-reactive protein (hs-CRP), and IL-6 than the controls. Non-stimulated PBMCs from ICU patients secreted significantly greater amounts of IL-6 and IL-1β than the controls, however, the production of IL-6, tumor necrosis factor (TNF)-α and IL-1β in response to LPS stimulation was significantly lower in the ICU group. Significant reductions in NK cell activities and serum IL-12 levels, an absence of serum IFN-γ, and decreased cytokine production from LPS-stimulated PBMCs may indicate hyporesponsiveness in NK cells and a dysfunctional inflammatory response in the early phase in critically ill patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ICU patients For healthy controls: nondiabetic and nonobese subjects For healthy controls: diabetes; history/presence of significant metabolic disease; pregnancy or breastfeeding; acute or chronic infection; liver disease; kidney disease; gastrointestinal disease; subjects taking any drugs or supplements</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>