<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02860949</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Multimodal local anesthetic infiltration (LAI) provides effective pain control in patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty (TKA). Some surgeons avoid posterior capsular infiltration (PCI) for fear of damaging posterior neurovascular structures. Data are limited on the added benefits of PCI using different combinations of local anesthetic agents. Therefore, the investigator wanted to know the effectiveness of pain control in LAI with and without PCI. Half of participants received LAI with PCI, while the other half received LAI without PCI during total knee arthroplasty.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multimodal Drug Infiltration in Total Knee Arthroplasty: Is Posterior Capsular Infiltration Worth the Risk?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Analgesic agents were bupivacaine, morphine, ketorolac and epinephrine. All patients received spinal anesthesia and patient controlled analgesia (PCA) for 24 hours post surgery. The surgical technique and postoperative medication protocols were identical in both groups. The visual analogue scale (VAS) for pain during activity and at rest, and morphine consumption were recorded at 6, 12, 18 and 24 hours postoperatively. LAI-related side effects, blood loss, length of hospital stay, and VAS for satisfaction were monitored. The reviewer was blinded to treatment groups.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics, Local</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketorolac</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epinephrine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Primary OA of the knee, aged less than 80 years old, and able to understand and comply with the study procedures. Previous drug dependency Inability to undergo a spinal block Allergy to study drugs Renal insufficiency Abnormal liver function History of stroke History of coronary artery disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Local anesthetic infiltration</keyword>
	<keyword>Posterior capsular infiltration</keyword>
	<keyword>Multimodal anesthesia</keyword>
	<keyword>Knee arthroplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain control</keyword>
	<keyword>Osteoarthritis, Knee</keyword>
</DOC>