<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02860078</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Qualitative and quantitatively evaluate the pain control and incidence of adverse effects in patients undergoing corticosteroid infiltration and local anesthetic through sacral epidural puncture with ultrasound assistance or isolated use of fluoroscopy to aid puncture and location of the sacral epidural space. A group will be submitted to epidural corticosteroid infiltration associated with local anesthetic with the use of fluoroscopy for locating the sacral epidural space, which is currently the gold standard for this technique, while in another location group will be held with the use of ultrasound.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Epidural Injection of Corticosteroids Under USG (EICUS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Introduction: Procedures guided by ultrasound (USG) have advantages over traditional techniques (fluoroscopy) with respect to regional anesthesia. Some studies have shown its usefulness as a quick, safe and simple tool for the location of the sacral hiatus and to guide the puncture of the sacral epidural space in patients with chronic low back pain, despite the lack of data with respect to clinical outcomes. OBJECTIVES: Evaluate qualitatively and quantitatively the pain control and incidence of adverse effects in patients undergoing corticosteroid infiltration and local anesthetic through sacral epidural puncture with ultrasound assistance or isolated use of fluoroscopy to aid puncture and location of the sacral epidural space. It will also be evaluated success rate in the first puncture, and the time duration of the procedure in groups. METHODS: It is clinical, analytical, prospective trial, randomized, covered for evaluators. It will include 30 patients with chronic low back pain or pain in the lower limbs resulting in lumbar canal stenosis, refractory to medical treatment. A group will be submitted to epidural corticosteroid infiltration associated with local anesthetic with the use of fluoroscopy for locating the sacral epidural space, which is currently the gold standard for this technique, while in another location group will be held with the use of ultrasound.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Older than 18 years old; Patients who have low back and/or lower extremities due to lumbar spinal stenosis pain outpatients, with regular followup refractory to conservative medical treatment (Verbal Scale of Pain &gt; 3, more three months duration, with no improvement with clinical treatment). Symptoms that characterize a surgical emergency; The presence of sensory or motor deficit (chronic mild motor impairment or mild paresthesia will not be deleted), injury to peripheral nerves, trauma history or recent fracture; Serious medical conditions or decompensated; Infection at the puncture site; Coagulopathy; Contrast allergy history or the medications used in the technique; Pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>epidural</keyword>
	<keyword>ultrasound</keyword>
</DOC>