<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02222844</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The IMPRESS trial aims to see whether the improved results can be achieved for patients with pelvic sigmoid cancers by having an MRI scan prior to surgery so that doctors can make the most appropriate treatment choice. Everyone who agrees to take part will be randomly allocated by one of the research team to either have standard treatment for sigmoid cancer, which involves CT-imaging of chest and abdomen / pelvis before surgery, or to undergo standard treatment, plus an additional MRI scan, before surgery. The additional MRI scan will be the only difference in approach between the two arms of the trial. After all imaging is obtained, patients from both arms will be discussed by the Multidisciplinary Team as usual. An amendment to this study in 2015 allowed for patients with sigmoid cancer who receive an MRI by local indication to be entered into the trial as observational patients, and a new primary endpoint added that compares the rates of high risk features identified between CT and MRI scans for all patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Radical Treatment Through MRI Evaluation of Pelvic Sigmoid Cancers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective of the IMPRESS Trial will be to compare the proportion of patients undergoing any radical treatment in the two arms of the study. Another primary endpoint is to measure the difference in detection of high risk patients when comparing CT and MRI for all patients. Secondary outcomes will measure the proportion of patients who underwent neoadjuvant treatment, quality of surgery including free resection margins, perioperative morbidity and mortality, permanent defunctioning stoma rates, downstaging, quality of life at 1 year, 3 years and 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sigmoid Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All patients with pelvic sigmoid colon (demonstrated on colonoscopy and biopsy) who are eligible for curative treatment (for the purposes of the IMPRESS study, the sigmoid tumour must be over 15cm from the anal verge) Less than 18 years old Unable to consent Consent witheld or withdrawn Unable to have an MRI (e.g. pacemaker, metal implant in major viscera, severe claustrophobia) Allergy or contraindication to Buscopan, small bowel contrast agent or gadolinium (e.g. glaucoma, small or large bowel obstruction, GFR &lt;30) A previous history of colorectal cancer Presence of irresectable distant metastases Severe comorbidities that prevent the application of eventual chemo/radiotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Colorectal Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Colon, Sigmoid</keyword>
	<keyword>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>General Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Postoperative Complications</keyword>
</DOC>