<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02222714</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, pharmacokinetics (PK) and preliminary efficacy of multiple ascending intravenous doses of 3K3A-APC, a Recombinant Variant of Human activated protein C (APC), in in the treatment of acute ischemic stroke following treatment with recombinant tissue plasminogen activator (tPA), mechanical thrombectomy or both.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Evaluation of 3K3A-APC in Ischemic Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multicenter, prospective, randomized, controlled, double-blinded Phase 2 study intended to evaluate the safety, PK and preliminary efficacy of 3K3A-APC following treatment with tPA, mechanical thrombectomy or both in subjects with moderate to severe acute ischemic stroke. Approximately 115 subjects will be randomized, which includes the planned 88 subjects in groups of four to either 3K3A-APC or placebo (in a 3:1 ratio) and the additional placebo subjects who will be enrolled during safety review pauses. This study will utilize a modified version of the continual reassessment method (CRM) in order to establish a maximum tolerated dose (MTD). Eligible subjects will receive 3K3A-APC or placebo every 12 hours for up to 5 doses (approximately 3 days), or until discharge from the hospital, whichever occurs first. Subjects will be monitored for safety evaluations through Day 7 (or discharge, if earlier) and are expected to be seen on Day 7, 14, 30 and 90 for safety and outcome evaluations.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Infarction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Acute ischemic stroke Able to receive IV tPA, mechanical thrombectomy or both National Institutes of Health Stroke Scale (NIHSS) score of ≥ 5 Signed informed consent Mechanical thrombectomy subjects only: onset time to arterial puncture time &lt; 6 hours History of stroke or penetrating head injury within 90 days prior to enrollment History of previous or current diagnosis of intracranial hemorrhage that represents a potential for rehemorrhage if subjected to thrombolytic therapy or mechanical thrombectomy Moyamoya disease, cerebral arteriovenous malformation (AVM), known unsecured aneurysm requiring intervention during the acute study period Presence of other neurological or nonneurological comorbidities that may lead, independently of the current stroke, to further deterioration in the subject's neurological status during the trial period Presence of premorbid neurological deficits and functional limitations assessed by a retrospective Modified Rankin Scale (mRS) score of ≥ 2 Mechanical thrombectomy subjects only: baseline noncontrast CT scan revealing a large core occlusion as defined by local protocol Prolonged prothrombin time (PT) or aPTT Severe hypertension or hypotension Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt;35 mL/min Blood glucose concentration &lt; 50 mg/dL Prior exposure to any exogenous form of APC</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>ischemic stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>APC</keyword>
	<keyword>3K3A</keyword>
	<keyword>3K3A-APC</keyword>
	<keyword>activated protein C</keyword>
	<keyword>RHAPSODY</keyword>
</DOC>