<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01840904</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate subjective sleep quality and fatigue during and after Acute uncomplicated diverticulitis assessed by questionnaires and a sleep-diary. The investigators hypothesis is that subjective sleep and fatigue are correlated with the inflammatory activities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Subjective Sleep and Fatigue During and After Acute Diverticulitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>An increasing number of experimental studies have showed that inflammation can induce disturbances in sleep architecture, mediated by cytokines. some studies showed that cytokines also induce daytime fatigue. In this study the investigators aim to describe the patient experiences of sleep and fatigue during the acute inflammation and the recovery, and the investigators seek to exam the correlation of fatigue with Polysomnography-measured night sleep and cytokine levels in plasma. Following methods will be applied - Other: Karolinska Sleepiness Scale - Other: Physical Fatigue Scale - Other: Visual Analog Scale and 10 point-scales to measure fatigue, general well-being, subjective sleep and pain - Other: Sleep-diary - Device: Polysomnograph - Embla Titanium (Natus Medical Incorporated, USA) - Procedure: Plasma cytokines (IL-2, IL-6 and TNF-alfa(tumor necrosis factor)) - Procedure: Plasma CRP(C reactive protein) and leukocytes - Device: Wrist-Actigraph - Octagonal Basic Motionlogger, Ambulatory monitoring Inc, New York, USA</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diverticulitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>CTverified diverticulitis patients managed by antibiotic treatment at Herlev Hospital Pain and fever occurred less than 72 hours prior to the admission ASA (American Society of Anesthesiologists) score I to III Surgical intervention needed Complicated diverticulitis Complications in relation to diverticulitis Pain and fever occurred more than 72 hours prior to the admission In anticoagulant treatment and heart rate control treatment Known Autoimmune disease Known medically treated sleepdisorder (insomnia, restless legs etc.) and sleep apnea Shiftwork or jetlag Daily use of opioid, psychopharmaca, opioids or anxiolytics (including Hypnotics) Known psychiatry conditions in treatment with psychopharmaca Daily alcohol intake of more than 5 units or drug abuse Missing written consent Diabetes Mellitus Predicted bad compliance Pregnant or breastfeeding Urine or fecal incontinence Severe kidney disease Current cancer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>