<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01601041</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this prospective study is to investigate the association between the amount of residual urine and asymptomatic bacterial prostate infection with the occurrence of recurrent (&gt;2 /year) symptomatic urinary tract infections in patients suffering from chronic (&gt; 1 year) spinal cord injury (SCI) and neurogenic lower urinary tract dysfunction performing intermittent catheterization. The following hypotheses will be tested: 1. The amount of residual urine after intermittent catheterization is significantly greater in SCI patients suffering from frequent (&gt;2 /year) urinary tract infections compared to those without. 2. The incidence of asymptomatic bacterial prostate infections is significantly higher in SCI patients suffering from frequent (&gt;2 /year) urinary tract infections compared to those without.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Role of Residual Urine and Asymptomatic Prostatitis in the Development of Urinary Tract Infections in Spinal Cord Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To investigate the association between the amount of residual urine and asymptomatic bacterial prostate infection with the occurrence of recurrent (&gt;2 /year) symptomatic urinary tract infections in patients suffering from chronic (&gt; 1 year) spinal cord injury (SCI) and neurogenic lower urinary tract dysfunction performing intermittent catheterization, patients perform self-catheterization twice (before and after urodynamic testing. After each catheterization, residual urine is assessed by ultrasound. Prior to urodynamic testing, prostate massage is performed, bacterial cultures of the fluid and the urine are initiated and the results of these cultures will be analysed .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Tract Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>male patients with chronic (&gt; 1 year) spinal cord injury bladder management by intermittent catheterization symptomatic urinary tract infection prostate pathology immunodeficiency antibiotic therapy missing informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Urinary Tract Infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Bacteriuria</keyword>
	<keyword>Pyuria</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Intermittent Catheterization</keyword>
	<keyword>Spinal Cord Injuries</keyword>
	<keyword>Residual Urine</keyword>
</DOC>