<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01481831</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of single and repeated doses of palonosetron hydrochloride in preventing nausea and vomiting caused by moderate and highly emetogenic chemotherapy in patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Palonosetron Hydrochloride in the Prevention of Nausea and Vomiting</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Group I (Highly Emetogenic Chemotherapy): Patients that accepted chemotherapy including Cisplatin≥50mg/m2, Carmustine&gt;250mg/m2, Cyclophosphamide&gt;1500mg/m2, Dacarbazine&gt;60mg/m2, Doxorubicin&gt;60mg/m2, Epirubicin&gt;90mg/m2, IFO≥10g/m2 or AC program. Group II (Moderately Emetogenic Chemotherapy): Patients that accepted chemotherapy including any dose of Carboplatin, Daunorubicin, Oaliplatin, Irinotecan, or Doxorubicin&lt;60mg/m2(not include liposomal doxorubicin), Epirubicin≤90mg/m2, Carmustine≤250mg/m2, Methotrexate≥250mg/m2, Cyclophosphamide≤1500mg/m2, Arabinoside&gt;200mg/m2, IFO&lt;10g/m2, Cisplatin≥50mg/m2. Total subjects: 1000, single dose of palonosetron group of 500 patients, repeated doses of palonosetron group of 500 patients. According to the study subjects receiving highly emetogenic chemotherapy or moderately emetogenic chemotherapy, subjects are stratified randomize.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Nausea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Palonosetron</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emetics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients candidates to a chemotherapy treatment, with histologically or cytologically confirmed malignant disease; 2. The concrete chemotherapy plan does not limited, group I (Highly Emetogenic Chemotherapy), group II (Moderately Emetogenic Chemotherapy); 3. Male or female aged 1875 years, ECOG≤2, estimates survival time≥3 months; 4. WBC≥3.0×109/L, ANC≥1.5×109/L, PLT≥80×109/L, total bilirubin≤1.5×ULN(Normal value upper limit), AST and ALT≤2.5×ULN(With transferability liver cancer≤5×ULN), Cr and BUN≤1.5×ULN, electrolyte and electrocardiogram are normal, conforms to the chemotherapy adaptation; 5. Patients have been apart from the previous chemotherapy to finish above 2 weeks (including 2 weeks); 6. Patients that voluntarily sign the consent form. 1. Pregnancy, or patients during breast feeding; 2. Patients have accepted any radiotherapy during the experimental period; 3. Gastric outlet or intestinal obstruction; 4. Patients have serious heart diseases, liver kidney diseases, or metabolism function disorder; 5. Patients have epilepsy, or have been used psychotropic drug and calm drug; 6. Received any drugs with potential antiemetic efficacy, or experienced any vomiting, nausea or retching in the 24 hours prior to chemotherapy; 7. Patients with transferability brain tumor, have vomiting caused by skull high pressure, or can not speak sickness situation and adverse reactions by self; 8. Patients have known hypersensitivity to 5HT3 antagonists; 9. Patients have chemotherapy contraindications; 10. Patients are participating, or have participated in other Clinical studies of new drugs within 2 weeks.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>