<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="50993">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02442349</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D5160C00017</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02442349</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase II Single Arm Study of AZD9291 to Treat NSCLC Patients in Asia Pacific</brief_title>
  <acronym>AURA17</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase II, Open Label, Single-arm Study to Assess the Safety and Efficacy of AZD9291 in Asia Pacific Patients With Locally Advanced/Metastatic Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Whose Disease Has Progressed With Previous Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitor Therapy and Whose Tumours Harbour a T790M Mutation Within the Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor Gene</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AstraZeneca</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A Phase II, Open Label, Single-arm Study to Assess the Safety and Efficacy of AZD9291 in
      Asia Pacific Patients with Locally Advanced/Metastatic Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer whose
      Disease has Progressed with Previous Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor Tyrosine Kinase
      Inhibitor Therapy and whose Tumours harbour a T790M mutation within the Epidermal Growth
      Factor Receptor Gene
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase II, open label, single arm study assessing the safety and efficacy of
      AZD9291 (80 mg, orally, once daily) in Asia Pacific patients with a confirmed diagnosis of
      Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor (EGFR) sensitising mutation positive (ie, G719X, exon 19
      deletion, L858R, L861Q) and T790M mutation positive (hereafter referred to as EGFRm+ and
      T790M+) un-resectable, locally advanced or metastatic NSCLC (Stage IIIB-IV), who have
      progressed on an Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitor(EGFR-TKI),
      either as first line treatment or following one line of EGFR-TKI and one line of platinum
      containing doublet chemotherapy. Patients must agree to provide a biopsy for central
      confirmation of T790M mutation status following confirmed disease progression on the most
      recent treatment regimen. The primary objective of the study is to assess the efficacy of
      AZD9291 by assessment of Objective Response Rate according to RECIST 1.1 by an Independent
      Central Review.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR according to RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline and every 6 weeks from time of first dose until objective disease progression, for an average of approximately 12 months.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the efficacy of AZD9291 by assessment of Objective Response Rate (ORR) by Independent Central Review (ICR).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PFS according to RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline and every 6 weeks from time of first dose until objective disease progression, for an average of approximately 12 months.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the efficacy of AZD9291 regarding Progression Free Survival.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Reported Outcomes by EORTC QLQ-C30 questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Questionnaires completed at baseline, every 6 weeks relative to first dose, discontinuation and during the progression and survival follow-up periods for approximately 2 years.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the impact of AZD9291 on patients' disease-related symptoms and health related quality of life (HRQoL).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose to end of study or date of death from any cause, whichever comes first, assessed every 6 weeks up to approximately 60 months.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the efficacy of AZD9291 regarding overall survival.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>DoR according to RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline and every 6 weeks from time first dose until date of progression, for an average of approximately 12 months.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the efficacy of AZD9291 regarding During of response (DoR).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>DCR according to RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline and every 6 weeks from time first dose until date of progression, for an average of approximately 12 months.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the efficacy of AZD9291 regarding Disease Control Rate (DCR).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tumour shrinkage according to RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline and every 6 weeks from time of first dose until date of progression, for an average of approximately 12 months.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the efficacy of AZD9291 regarding tumour shrinkage.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Reported Outcomes by EORTC QLQ LC13 questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Questionnaires completed at baseline, weekly for the first 3 weeks, then every 3 weeks (relative to first dose), discontinuation and during the progression and survival follow-up periods for approximately 2 years.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the impact of AZD9291 on patients' disease-related symptoms and health related quality of life (HRQoL).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability profile of AZD9291.</measure>
    <time_frame>Adverse events will be collected from baseline until 28 days after the last dose, expected average 12 months.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess by number and severity of adverse events as recorded on the case report form, clinical chemistry, haematology, urinalysis, vital signs, physical examination, weight, ECG and WHO Performance Status.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">319</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AZD9291</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Once daily tablet 80 mg</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AZD9291</intervention_name>
    <description>Once daily tablet 80 mg</description>
    <arm_group_label>AZD9291</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Aged at least 18 years. Patient from Asia Pacific will be enrolled only.

          -  Locally advanced or metastatic NSCLC, not amenable to curative surgery or
             radiotherapy.

          -  Radiological documentation of disease progression on the last treatment administered
             prior to enrolling in the study: following 1st line EGFR TKI treatment but who have
             not received further treatment OR following prior therapy with an EGFR TKI and a
             platinum-based doublet chemotherapy. Patients may have also received additional lines
             of treatment.

          -  Documented EGFR mutation (at any time since the initial diagnosis of NSCLC) known to
             be associated with EGFR TKI sensitivity (including G719X, exon 19 deletion, L858R,
             L861Q).

          -  Patients must have central confirmation of tumour T790M mutation positive status from
             a biopsy sample taken after confirmation of disease progression on the most recent
             treatment regimen.

          -  World Health Organisation (WHO) performance status 0-1 with no deterioration over the
             previous 2 weeks and a minimum life expectancy of 12 weeks.

          -  At least one lesion, not previously irradiated and not chosen for biopsy during the
             study screening period, that can be accurately measured at baseline as ≥10mm in the
             longest diameter (except lymph nodes which must have short axis ≥15mm) with
             computerised tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) which is suitable
             for accurate repeated measurements.

          -  Females of child-bearing potential using contraception and must have a negative
             pregnancy test.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Treatment with an EGFR-TKI (eg, erlotinib, gefitinib, icotinib or afatinib) within 8
             days or approximately 5x half-life of study entry; any cytotoxic chemotherapy,
             investigational agents or other anticancer drugs within 14 days of study entry;
             previous treatment with AZD9291 or a 3rd generation EGFR TKIs; Major surgery within 4
             weeks of study entry; radiotherapy treatment to more than 30% of the bone marrow or
             with a wide field of radiation within 4 weeks of study entry; currently receiving
             treatment with potent inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4.

          -  Any unresolved toxicities from prior therapy.

          -  Unstable spinal cord compression or brain metastases.

          -  Severe or uncontrolled systemic diseases, including uncontrolled hypertension and
             active bleeding diatheses or infection.

          -  Refractory nausea and vomiting, chronic gastrointestinal diseases or bowel resection.

          -  Cardiac disease.

          -  Past medical history of interstitial lung disease, drug-induced interstitial lung
             disease, radiation pneumonitis which required steroid treatment, or any evidence of
             clinically active interstitial lung disease.

          -  Inadequate bone marrow reserve or organ function.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kogarah</city>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nedlands</city>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Woolloongabba</city>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Changchun</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chengdu</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chongqing</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chongqin</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fuzhou</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Haikou</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hangzhou</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Harbin</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ji Nan</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nanjing</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shanghai</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wuhan</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Xi'an</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zhengzhou</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Goyang-si</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seongnam-si</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>China</country>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>September 13, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 11, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Phase II, Open Label, Single-arm study, Safety and Efficacy of AZD9291, Asia Pacific, NSCLC with T790M mutation within the Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor Gene</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Osimertinib</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mitogens</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
