<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02548078</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety and reactogenicity of a single IM dose of the ChAd3 EBO-Z vaccine, overall and in children aged 1 to 5, 6 to 12, and 13 to 17 years, separately Considering the risk of exposure to Ebola and the potential (based on animal data) for the investigational ChAd3-EBO-Z vaccine to afford at least partial protection, all children in the study will receive the investigational ChAd3 EBO-Z vaccine. The children in the Group EBO-Z/ MENACWY-TT will receive the investigational ChAd3-EBO-Z vaccine at Day 0 of the study, whereas the children in the Group MENACWY-TT/ EBO-Z will receive Nimenrix at Day 0 (as a control). At Month 6, the children in the Group MENACWY-TT/ EBO-Z will receive the investigational ChAd3-EBO-Z vaccine (provided that no safety concerns are raised), whereas the children in the Group EBO-Z/ MENACWY-TT will receive Nimenrix..</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety and Immunogenicity of a Candidate Ebola Vaccine in Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject's parent(s)/ legally acceptable representative(s) (LAR[s]) who, in the opinion of the Investigator, can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol (e.g. availability for Diary Card completion, return for followup visits, availability for clinical followup throughout the study period). Written/ thumb printed informed consent obtained from the subject' parent(s)/ LAR[s] prior to performing any study specific procedure. In addition, written/ thumb printed informed assent should be obtained if appropriate (from all subjects aged 13 to 17 years and from younger subjects as per local requirements). A male or female child aged 1 to 17 years inclusive at the time of Screening. Subjects with a negative RDT test for Malaria within 30 days prior to randomisation into the study. OR Subjects with a positive RDT test for Malaria who completed antimalarial treatment at least 5 days prior to randomisation into the study. Healthy subjects as per Investigator judgement, as established by medical history, clinical examination and haematology/ biochemistry laboratory parameters screening before entering into the study. Female subjects of nonchildbearing potential may be enrolled in the study. Nonchildbearing potential is defined as premenarche or ovariectomy. Female subjects of childbearing potential may be enrolled in the study, if the subject: has practiced adequate contraception for 30 days prior to the Day 0 visit, and has a negative pregnancy test at the Day 0 visit, and has agreed to continue adequate contraception until 30 days after the Month 6 visit Child in care. Use of any investigational or nonregistered product (drug or vaccine) other than the study vaccine during the period starting 30 days before the Day 0 visit, or planned use during the study period. Previous vaccination with an investigational EBOV or Marburg vaccine, or previous vaccination with a chimpanzee adenoviral vectored investigational vaccine. Known prior EBOV or SUDV disease. Travel to country affected by the EBOV epidemic or direct contact with person with EVD within 21 days prior to the Day 0 visit. History of any reaction or hypersensitivity (such as anaphylaxis, urticaria (hives), respiratory difficulty, angioedema, or abdominal pain) likely to be exacerbated by any component of the study vaccine. Planned administration/ administration of a vaccine not foreseen by the study protocol in the period starting 30 days before and ending 30 days after each vaccination visit. Acute or chronic illness determined by medical history, clinical examination and laboratory screening tests including, but not limited to: Clinically significant immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition (e.g. clinical acquired immune deficiency syndrome [AIDS]). Major congenital defects. Malnutrition (defined as weight for age Zscore less than 3, or other clinical signs of malnutrition). Any clinically significant haematological or biochemical laboratory abnormality. Pregnant female. Any condition that in the Investigator's opinion may potentially compromise subject safety or interfere with subject assessment or compliance.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Protection against Ebola Zaire virus</keyword>
</DOC>