<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00214721</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objective: The purpose of this study is to demonstrate: -the non-inferiority of an experimental peritoneal dialysis solution compared to a current solution for the management of end stage renal disease (ESRD) in peritoneal dialysis patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of an Experimental Solution for Peritoneal Dialysis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dialysis Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who have given written informed consent after the nature of the study has been explained. Patients who are at least 18 years of age. Patients who have been treated with CAPD using specific solutions for at least 60 days before the baseline visit. Patients who have received antibiotics for the treatment of an episode of peritonitis within 30 days before the screening visit. Patients who have had acute or chronic exitsite or tunnel infection in the past 14 days, counted from the last day of infection to the screening visit. Patients who have other serious diseases, such as active, or if previously treated, residual malignancy or systemic infection. Patients who have had a major illness or injury requiring hospitalisation within 30 days before the baseline visit. Patients who have severe malnutrition (serum albumin &lt; 25 g/l by bromocresol green method). Patients who are participating in another study that requires Ethics Committee approval. Noninterventional studies are permitted. Patients who have received an investigational product within 30 days preceding the screening visit. Patients who are pregnant or lactating. (NB: Female patients of childbearing potential must have a negative urine or serum pregnancy test at the time of the screening and will be required to use a medically acceptable means of contraception during their participation in this study). Patients who have a significant psychiatric disorder or mental disability that could interfere with his/her ability to provide informed consent and/or comply with protocol procedures.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2007</verification_date>
</DOC>