<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00364273</DOC>
	<brief_summary>GSK159802 is a potent, inhaled, long acting selective beta-2-receptor agonist (LABA), which is being developed for once daily treatment of asthma and COPD as part of a combination product with a once daily inhaled corticosteroid and also as a standalone product for the treatment of COPD. Stimulation of the beta-2-agonist in the lung mainly relaxes bronchial smooth muscle cells which results in bronchodilation. Unwanted systemic side effects related with beta-2-agonist treatment such as tachycardia, tremor, hyperglycemia and hypokalemia are limited by local administration and also tend to show tachyphylaxis. The LABAs that are currently available (e.g., salmeterol, formoterol) require twice-daily administration, given their duration of action. Therefore, there is significant opportunity for a once-daily inhaled medication to improve patient compliance and overall disease management by providing sustained, 24-hour bronchodilation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>GSK159802 In Healthy Male Subjects And Asthmatics</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Body mass index within the range 18.529.9 (kg/m2) Current nonsmokers who have not used any tobacco products in the 6month period preceding the screening visit and have a pack history of &lt; 10 pack years. Additional criteria for Cohorts 2 and 3 only (Asthmatic Patients): Subjects with a documented history of mild to moderate asthma, with the exclusion of other significant pulmonary disease Subjects with clinically stable asthma within the 4 weeks preceding the screening visit and with a screening prebronchodilator FEV1 greater than 60% and less than 90% predicted. During the screening visit, subjects must demonstrate the presence of reversible airway disease, defined as an increase in FEV1 of &gt; or equal to 12.0% over baseline and an absolute change of &gt; or equal to 300 mL within 30 minutes following 400 mcg salbutamol. Exclusion criteria: Any clinically relevant abnormality Subjects who have a screening haemoglobin values &lt; 11 g/dL The subject has participated in a clinical study with a New Chemical Entity (NCE) within the past 112 days or a clinical study with any other drug during the previous 84 days Subjects with known hypersensitivity to salmeterol or salbutamol or any ingredients in their preparations.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma</keyword>
</DOC>