<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00364143</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether IHL-305 (irinotecan liposome injection) is safe and effective in the treatment of advanced solid tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of IHL-305 (Irinotecan Liposome Injection) to Treat Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase I dose-escalation study of intravenous administration of IHL-305 in patients with advanced solid tumors. Patients will receive IHL-305 as an intravenous infusion over 60 minutes on Day 1 followed by a 27-day observation period for a total of 28 days (4 weeks) per cycle. Two patient populations will be evaluated separately; patients with UGT1A1*28 genotype homozygous wild-type (wt/wt) and heterozygous (wt/*28) variants as one group, and patients with UGT1A1*28 homozygous variant (*28/*28) as another group.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Histologically confirmed malignant solid tumor and not a candidate for known regimens or protocol treatments of higher efficacy or priority 2. Failed conventional therapy for their cancer or have a malignancy for which a conventional therapy does not exist 3. Recovered from all acute adverse effects of prior therapies, excluding alopecia (hair loss) 4. ECOG performance status of 0, 1, or 2 5. 18 years of age or older 6. Normal organ and bone marrow function as defined by: absolute neutrophil count greater than or equal to 1,500 cells/microliter platelets greater than or equal to 100,000 cells/microliter total bilirubin within normal institutional limits AST (SGOT)/ALT (SGPT) less than or equal to 2.5 x institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) or less than or equal to 5.0 x ULN in patients with liver metastases plasma creatinine less than or equal to 1.5 x institutional ULN OR creatinine clearance greater than or equal to 60 mL/min/1.73 m2 for patients with creatinine levels above institutional normal 7. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document 1. Previously treated with irinotecan, or had chemotherapy or radiotherapy within 4 weeks (6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin C) prior to entering the study, or not recovered from adverse effects due to agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier 2. Receiving any other investigational agent 3. Known brain metastases 4. History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical composition to IHL305 5. Concurrent serious infections (i.e., requiring an intravenous antibiotic) 6. Pregnant women or women of childbearing potential and not using methods to avoid pregnancy; a negative pregnancy test (urine or serum) must be documented at baseline for women of childbearing potential; no breastfeeding while on study. 7. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, unstable angina pectoris, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements 8. Significant cardiac disease including heart failure that meets New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III and IV definitions; history of myocardial infarction within one year of study entry; uncontrolled dysrhythmias; or poorly controlled angina. 9. History of serious ventricular arrhythmia (ventricular tachycardia [VT] or ventricular fibrillation [VF], greater than or equal to 3 beats in a row); QTc greater than or equal to 450 msec for men and 470 msec for women; or left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) less than or equal to 40% by multigated acquisition scan (MUGA).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Advanced Solid Tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>Oncology</keyword>
</DOC>