<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03085615</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The FEDOX trial is a prospective randomized clinical trial exploring oxidative stress as a mechanism of harm to explain the negative outcomes found in feeding trials that achieved caloric exposure commensurate with the nationally recommended guidelines. Due to its impact on energy metabolism, we will also explore low T3 syndrome's relationship to this mechanism. Finally, we will explore circadian patterns of diurnal/nocturnal TSH fluctuation as a potential biomarker to indicate this mechanism of harm has subsided. This 7-day prospective randomized clinical trial is designed to address the following specific aims (SA) in ICU patients (n=40) who have been recently diagnosed with acute respiratory distress syndrome. SA1) Determine whether provision of enteral nutrition (EN) at 100% of levels in Nationally Recommended Guidelines NRG (25-30 kcals/kg, 100%NRG) early in critical illness increases reactive oxygen species (ROS) production compared to EN at 40% of NRG levels (10-12 kcals/kg, 40%NRG). Subjects will be fasted overnight and randomized to receive either 100% NRG or 40%NRG for 7 days. Plasma F2-isoprostanes will be measured daily and compared between groups through repeated measures analysis. SA2) Determine if EN at 100%NRG interrupts the critical illness induced low T3 syndrome and subsequently further increases the ROS production compared to 40%NRG. Serum thyroid parameters (T3, T4, rT3, TSH) with be measured daily and compared between groups as above. Mediation analysis will be used to determine the proportion of the effect of nutrition group on F2-isoprostane production explained by each thyroid parameter. SA3) Determine if the return of diurnal/noctural fluctuations in TSH is associated with decreased nutrition-induced ROS production. Plasma TSH will be measured twice per day at 0300 and 1800hrs to determine TSH fluctuation. The interaction effect between TSH fluctuation and nutrition group on F2-isoprostane production will be assessed through repeated measures analysis. This study provides vital mechanistic insight into the impact of feeding on oxidative stress during the first week of critical illness, represents an important first step in determining the safest timing and dosage of nutrition support, and sets the foundation for future larger clinical trials on these topics.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Feeding the Critically Ill During Phases of Altered Redox Status</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Euthyroid Sick Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients (&gt;18 years) admitted to RUMC MICU who are diagnosed of ARDS, and who are able to receive EN will be eligible for participation. Patients will be excluded if the are transferred with ARDS from another ICU, are pregnant, have documented neurologic disease prior to admission that interferes with the capacity to give informed consent or do not require EN for their nutritional care.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>