<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03085550</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Conventional management of diabetic ulcers is associated with slow healing, high costs and repeated trips to clinic. Stem cells contained in fat grafts can differentiate into pro-healing cells and release growth factors with evidence suggesting a benefit in wound healing. Platelet-rich-plasma (PRP), an autologous blood-product, demonstrates pro-healing properties through releasing pro-healing factors and regulating angiogenesis. When used combination there is evidence of additional wound healing benefits. The aim is to investigate the rate of wound healing in diabetic ulcers when treated with conventional dressings, fat grafting alone and fat+PRP combination. The secondary aims will be to understand the mechanism of the healing process, the health related quality of life and patient satisfaction and the cost implications. The study is a single-blinded randomised controlled trial of 30 patients with three parallel treatment arms. Each patient will be followed up for 12 weeks and the rate and degree of wound healing will be assessed. Wound biopsies will be taken at Day 0, week 1 and week 4 and will undergo subsequent histological analysis to evaluate the mechanism of healing. The study is expected to last two years from recruitment of the first patient and will be conducted at Royal Free Hospital and UCL Division of Surgery and Interventional Science. The combination of fat+PRP may provide diabetic patients the option of a single treatment with improved healing, shorter followup and a reduced cost burden. Validation of the mechanism of healing through histological analysis will confirm clinical findings and help guide future research.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Platelet Rich Plasma and Autologous Fat Graft for Diabetic Ulcer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Foot Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Foot</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female; Age 1890 at the time of consent; Diabetic foot ulcer (DFU) measuring more than 0.5cm x 0.5cm and less than 10cm x 10cm; Wound with clean, healthy granulating bed, with minimal adherent slough; Patient understands and is willing to participate and can comply with weekly visits and followup regime. Wound with active infection; Patients with underlying vascular insufficiency (ABPI&lt;7.0); Uncontrolled Diabetes Mellitus, as measured by an HbA1c &gt; 10%; Presence of one or more medical conditions, including renal, hepatic, haematologic, active autoimmune or immune diseases that, would make the subject an inappropriate candidate for this ulcer healing study; Patient not fit for surgery (ASA classification &gt; 4).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>diabetic foot ulcer</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>fat grafting</keyword>
	<keyword>platelet rich plasma</keyword>
	<keyword>wound healing</keyword>
</DOC>