<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00152737</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The whole study is divided in 4 parallel protocols. The first protocol estimates the reliability of the technique through test-retest recordings. The second protocol aims to prove that exercise Tcpo2 is efficient to estimate the benefit of proximal revascularisation on proximal and distal ischemia in patients suffering stage two lower extremity arterial disease. The third protocol aims at estimating with exercise tcpo2 the eventual apparison of proximal ischemia after aorto-bi-femoral bypasses. The last protocol is a transversal study of patients with aorto-bi-femoral bypasses aiming to analyse the presence of proximal and distal symptoms and ischemia. The hypothesis for protocol 2 is that TcpO2 at exercise is significantly improved after surgery at the aortic and primary iliac artery. The hypothesis for protocols 3 and 4 relates on the hypothesis that a significant number of patients benefiting aorto-bi-femoral bypass suffer isolated proximal pain/ischemia after surgery. Amendement to the project has been recently validated to study the neurologic and bone complication of chronic vascular ischemia</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Objective Evaluation of Proximal Ischemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients included are submitted to: San Diego Claudication Questionnaire before and during the treadmill test Treadmill test(s) through the Strandness procedure (2MPh 10% slope) Transcutaneous oxygen pressure recording before during and after exercise Ankle and brachial pressure measurements. Neurologic investigation with Quantitative sensory Testing (QST) and neurophysiological tests for patients included in the sub-group analysing neurologic complication Whole body densitometry for patients included in the sub-group analysing osteo-articular complications</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intermittent Claudication</mesh_term>
	<criteria>protocol 1 3 stage 2 claudication Protocols 2 &amp; 3 : Indication for surgery protocol 4 : Patent aorto bio femoral bypass for more than 4 months Ability to perform a treadmill test Stage 4 LEAD Aortic aneurysm Acute coronary syndrom claudication of documented non vascular origin (for protocols 13 only)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Intermittent Claudication</keyword>
	<keyword>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Blood Gas Monitoring, Transcutaneous</keyword>
	<keyword>Surgery</keyword>
</DOC>