<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02193282</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized phase III trial studies how well erlotinib hydrochloride compared to placebo works in treating patients with stage IB-IIIA non-small cell lung cancer that has been completely removed by surgery. Erlotinib hydrochloride may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Erlotinib Hydrochloride in Treating Patients With Stage IB-IIIA Non-small Cell Lung Cancer That Has Been Completely Removed by Surgery (An ALCHEMIST Treatment Trial)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess whether adjuvant therapy with erlotinib (erlotinib hydrochloride) will result in improved overall survival (OS) over placebo for patients with completely resected stage IB (&gt;= 4 cm)-IIIA epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) mutant non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) (confirmed centrally) following complete resection and standard post-operative therapy. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess whether adjuvant therapy with erlotinib will result in improved disease free survival (DFS) over placebo for patients with completely resected stage IB (&gt;= 4 cm)-IIIA EGFR mutant NSCLC (confirmed centrally) following complete resection and standard post-operative therapy, both overall and within the stage subgroups: IB and II/IIIA. II. To evaluate the safety profile of erlotinib in the adjuvant setting. III. To assess whether adjuvant therapy with erlotinib will result in improved DFS rate at 2 years, and OS rate at 5 and 10 years over placebo for patients with completely resected stage IB (&gt;= 4 cm)-IIIA EGFR mutant NSCLC (confirmed centrally) following complete resection and standard post-operative therapy, both overall and within the stage subgroups: IB and II/IIIA. IV. To assess the primary and secondary objectives in all randomized patients, regardless of central confirmation of the EGFR mutant status. OUTLINE: Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. ARM I: Patients receive erlotinib hydrochloride orally (PO) once daily (QD) on days 1-21. Treatment repeats every 21 days for up to 2 years in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. ARM II: Patients receive placebo PO QD on days 1-21. Treatment repeats every 21 days for up to 2 years in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 6 months for 4 years and then yearly for 6 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Previously registered to A151216, with the result of lung cancer harboring an EGFR exon 19 deletion or L858R mutation; the testing must have been performed by one of the following criteria: 1. Patient registered to A151216 and the assessment performed centrally by the protocol specified laboratory 2. By a local Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments (CLIA) certified laboratory; the report must indicate the result as well as the CLIA number of the laboratory that performed the assay; these patients will also have been registered to A151216, but can be enrolled on A081105 regardless of the central lab results Patients with known resistant mutations in the EGFR tyrosinekinase (TK) domain (T790M) are not eligible Patients that are both EGFR mutant and anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK) rearrangements will be registered to A081105 Completely resected stage IB (&gt;= 4 cm), II or IIIA nonsquamous NSCLC with negative margins Complete recovery from surgery and standard postoperative therapy (if required); patients must be completely recovered from surgery at the time of randomization; the minimum time requirement between date of surgery and randomization must be at least 28 days, the maximum time requirement between surgery and randomization must be 90 days if no adjuvant chemotherapy was administered, 240 days if adjuvant chemotherapy was administered, and 300 days if adjuvant chemotherapy and radiation therapy was administered Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 01 No prior or concurrent malignancies within 5 years, except nonmelanoma skin carcinoma and in situ carcinomas Nonpregnant and nonlactating No history of cornea abnormalities Granulocytes &gt;= 1,500/ul Platelets &gt;= 100,000/ul Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) Serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN Serum creatinine =&lt; 1.5 x ULN</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>