<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00453726</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate variation of BNP in non invasive mechanical ventilated patients with severe acute respiratory failure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Brain Natriuretic Peptide (BNP) Levels in Patients in Non Invasive Mechanical Ventilation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of the study is to evaluate in patients with severe acute respiratory failure requiring non invasive mechanical ventilation BNP levels at admission and during the following 24 hours during non invasive mechanical ventilation (Non Invasive Positive Pressure Ventilation or Continuous positive airway pressure). Because in patients affected by acute respiratory failure it is often difficult to distinguish if the disease precipitating the respiratory failure is a cardiac disease or a lung disease, aim of the present study is to evaluate the discriminating role that BNP could have in this group of patients; evaluation will be completed, once obtained clinical stabilisation, with an echocardiography and respiratory functional test.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Valve Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Severe respiratory distress (use of respiratory accessory muscles); Respiratory rate &gt; 25 per minute; Respiratory acidosis (pH &lt; 7.35 and PaCO2 &gt; 45 mmHg); PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 250 Age &lt; 18 years; Facial deformities; Pneumothorax; Shock or systolic arterial pressure below 90 mmHg with amine infusion; Lifethreatening arrhythmias; Need for immediate endotracheal intubation (PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 100 with FiO2 100%, respiratory rate &lt; 10, GCS &lt; 8); Lack of cooperation from the patient; Recent esophagealgastric surgery; Inability to clear secretions; Drugs that may interfere with BNP secretion; Severe obesity; Hepatic cirrhosis with ascitis; Endocrine disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Natriuretic peptide brain</keyword>
	<keyword>Continuous positive airway pressure</keyword>
	<keyword>Intermittent positive pressure breathing</keyword>
	<keyword>Respiratory insufficiency</keyword>
</DOC>