<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00453180</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether treatment with oral N-acetylcysteine (NAC) will improve behavior problems often associated with autism spectrum disorders.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Oral N-Acetylcysteine in Children With Autism Spectrum Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Autism is increasingly being recognized as a common disorder with enormous public health significance. The core symptoms of autism include severe deficits in social relatedness and communication, and interfering repetitive behavior. No medications have been shown to consistently improve any of these symptoms. The central hypothesis of this study is that NAC will improve behavioral manifestations of autism which may include core or associated symptoms. We plan to test our hypothesis and complete the objectives of this project by pursuing the following specific aims: - Evaluate the efficacy of oral NAC in a 12-week, double-blind, placebo-controlled study involving 32 children and adolescents with autism spectrum disorders. - Evaluate the safety and tolerability of oral NAC in 32 children and adolescents with autism spectrum disorders.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Child Development Disorders, Pervasive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Asperger Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Developmental Disabilities</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acetylcysteine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>N-monoacetylcystine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 4 to 12 years. Diagnosis of autistic disorder, Asperger's disorder, or PDD NOS. If taking concomitant psychotropic medications, the medication must be at a constant dose for 60 days with no dose changes planned for the duration of the trial. Able to swallow capsules. Presence of any medical condition that significantly increases risk or hampers assessment (e.g., unstable hypertension or cardiac disease, unstable asthma, kidney disease, unstable seizure disorder, pregnancy or any other medical condition as determined by the investigator). Weight &lt; 15 kg. Subjects taking concomitant medications or supplements known for their glutamatergic effects (e.g., dextromethorphan, Dcycloserine, amantadine, memantine, lamotrigine, riluzole) or antioxidant properties (high dose vitamin supplements, DMG, TMG, many alternative treatments) within 30 days of the baseline visit with the exception of short term use of dextromethorphan as needed as a cough suppressant. The use of this medicine must be stopped at least 7 days prior to the baseline visit. Regular multivitamins will be allowed. Subjects taking daily acetaminophen or nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs within 30 days of the baseline visit. Profound mental retardation as evidenced by a mental age below 18 months. Subjects taking concomitant medications with the potential for pharmacokinetic or pharmacodynamic drugdrug interactions (e.g., carbamazepine) within 30 days of the baseline visit. Subjects who are likely to experience significant changes in their ongoing psychosocial or medical treatments for autism over the course of the trial (e.g., initiation of new behavioral therapy, initiation of new medication or alternative treatment [e.g., chelation]). Minor changes in ongoing treatment (e.g., missed therapy sessions due to holiday/vacation; planned break in therapy due to school holidays) will not be considered significant. History of prior treatment with NAC. Evidence of hypersensitivity/allergy to NAC. Presence of certain neurodevelopmental disorders such as Fragile X Syndrome, Tuberous Sclerosis, or other neurological disorders known to be associated with autism or autistic features. Diagnosis of Rett's disorder, childhood disintegrative disorder, schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, another psychotic disorder, or substance abuse disorder.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Autistic Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Asperger's</keyword>
	<keyword>PDD NOS</keyword>
	<keyword>Pervasive Developmental Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Autism</keyword>
	<keyword>N-acetylcysteine</keyword>
	<keyword>acetylcysteine</keyword>
	<keyword>NAC</keyword>
	<keyword>antioxidant</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>core symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>Autism Spectrum Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Asperger's Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Pervasive Developmental Disorder Not Otherwise Specified</keyword>
	<keyword>Pervasive Developmental Disorders</keyword>
</DOC>