<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00453869</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The prevalence of chronic hepatopathies is high in jail. However, the medical care of these hepatopathies is few developed. This study is an observational, an epidemiologic (screening and prevalence of fibrosing hepatopathies) and an evaluating study for a better taking care of these hepatopathies in jail. The aims of the study will be to evaluate the diagnostic performance of the FibroMeter score in the screening of the hepatic fibrosis in persons with multiple risk factors for liver fibrosis (alcoholism, intravenous drug users, tattoo, and virological status) with FibroScan速 as gold standard; to evaluate the feasibility of these different screening tools for chronic hepatopathies in jail and to evaluate the prevalence of the fibrosing hepatopathies with clinically significant fibrosis and theirs risk factors, alcohol and hepatitis B and hepatitis C viruses in population from Angers jail.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Screening of Fibrosing and/or Viral Chronic Hepatopathies in Jail</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary outcome: Screening of clinically significant fibrosis with FibroMeter blood score. Screening for hepatitis B and hepatitis C viruses. Secondary outcome: Clinically significant fibrosis confirmed with FibroScan速. The means for this study are a clinical questionnaire, a virological screening, a blood score for liver fibrosis: FibroMeter according to cause of the fibrosis and FibroScan速 is referent and independent examination. The expected results from this study are the knowledge of the prevalence of hepatopathies with hepatic fibrosis will be able to justify, possibly, a screening politic of them. This study will permit to evaluate the feasibility of noninvasive screening of the liver fibrosis in the goal to suppress the liver biopsy in a population having numerous drawbacks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Person over 18, All new inmates, for less than one month, in Angers jail, To have a written informed consent. No consent obtained from person, Detention inferior to one month, Person under 18.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Liver fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis B virus and C virus</keyword>
	<keyword>FibroMeter</keyword>
	<keyword>FibroScan速</keyword>
</DOC>