<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01952236</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study seeks to develop and then perform a controlled efficacy Randomized Controlled Trial assessing tobacco abstinence of a best-practices Web-based smoking cessation intervention combined with a Mobile intervention. Study participants are randomized to one of two conditions: a Web Only intervention and the Web+Mobile intervention. The hypothesis is that the Web+Mobile approach will yield greater efficacy than the Web Only condition.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Web and Mobile Smoking Cessation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary aims of this project are to: 1. Use an iterative formative development process to create two separate Web-based smoking cessation programs (Web+Mobile, Web Only). 2. Compare the efficacy of the two smoking cessation programs in terms of tobacco abstinence. The investigators hypothesize that the Web+Mobile condition will be significantly more efficacious in terms of tobacco abstinence than the Web Only condition. 3. Evaluate program usage/participant engagement, treatment acceptability, and consumer satisfaction. The investigators hypothesize that both conditions will be acceptable and that the Web+Mobile condition will have significantly greater usage and higher consumer satisfaction than the Web Only condition. 4. Evaluate and compare the intervention cost and incremental cost-effectiveness (cost per-participant and cost per-quit) of each of the two experimental conditions. The secondary aims of this proposal are to: 1. Evaluate the differences between conditions on ancillary tobacco outcomes. The investigators hypothesize that the participants assigned to the Web+Mobile condition who continue to smoke will nonetheless report a greater decline in the smoking rate and more quit attempts. 2. Evaluate predictors and condition moderators of tobacco abstinence. The investigators will conduct exploratory analyses of the association of treatment outcomes to participant characteristics (e.g., baseline smoking rate, nicotine dependence level, partner's tobacco use, prior quitting attempts, prior use of pharmacological adjuncts, and other demographic factors). 3. Evaluate putative mechanisms of change. The investigators will test whether change in the putative mechanisms of change (i.e., self-efficacy, program use, use of pharmacological adjuncts) mediate the association between the intervention condition and 3-month sustained abstinence from the 3 month to 6 month assessments.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>≥ 18 years of age Cigarettes are primary tobacco of use Smoke ≥ 10 cigs/day for the previous 6 months Want to quit in next 30 days Use a smartphone and willing to potentially receive/send up to 70 text messages over the duration of the program Access the Internet daily Have a valid personal email address Be a U.S. citizen Current or recent (past 30day) use of a smoking cessation product or treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Smoking</keyword>
	<keyword>Quit</keyword>
	<keyword>Tobacco</keyword>
	<keyword>Abstinence</keyword>
	<keyword>Adult</keyword>
	<keyword>Text Messaging</keyword>
	<keyword>Web-based</keyword>
	<keyword>Mobile phone</keyword>
	<keyword>smartphone</keyword>
	<keyword>internet</keyword>
	<keyword>web</keyword>
</DOC>