<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01952743</DOC>
	<brief_summary>We propose a pilot study to assess safety and benefit of renal artery ablation at the time of planned atrial fibrillation ablation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Renal Denervation Therapy in Hypertensive Patients Undergoing A-Fib Ablation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Symptomatic atrial fibrillation (AF) refractory to anti-arrhythmic drugs is commonly treated with ablation therapy. Pulmonary vein isolation along with additional substrate medication is commonly performed during ablation procedures is associated with 60-80% success rate for maintenance of sinus rhythm. After AF ablation hypertension (HTN) is a strong predictor for recurrence of atrial fibrillation. Drug resistant hypertension can be effectively treated with catheter based renal denervation therapy. Our primary hypothesis is concomitant renal denervation therapy along with AF ablation is associated with improvement in success rates of AF ablation along with adequate control of blood pressure. The specific objectives of this study are to prospectively compare success rates, time to AF recurrence, AF burden and blood pressure controls in patients randomized to concomitant renal denervation arm when compared to patients with AF ablation alone.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Paroxysmal and Persistent Atrial Fibrillation refractory eligible for AF ablation as per HRS/ECAS/EHRA consensus statement.[23] Paroxysmal AF is defined as two or more episodes of AF lasting less than 7 days in duration during the last 6 months before enrollment. Persistent AF is defined as AF lasting more than 7 days or requiring cardioversion for termination. 2. Hypertension (&gt;140/80 mm Hg) on treatment with at least 1 hypertensive medication. 3. GFR &gt;60ml/dl using Cockcroft Gault equation 1. Secondary causes of hypertension 2. Severe renal artery stenosis or dual renal arteries 3. Congestive heart failure with NYHA class III or IV status 4. EF&lt; 35% 5. LA Diameter &gt;6 cm 6. Previous AF ablation 7. Previous renal artery stent or angioplasty 8. Severe contrast allergy 9. Inability to give informed consent 10. Solitary kidney</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Atrial Fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal Denervation</keyword>
</DOC>