<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01181284</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension(PAH) suffer from chronic shortness of breath, and have impaired survival related to progressive right ventricular failure. Abnormal vasoreactivity to nitric oxide(NO) plays a role in the pathophysiology of PAH. Phosphodiesterase Type 5 Inhibitor (PDE5 inhibitors) sildenafil have been shown to be beneficial in PAH, but extent of benefit is variable.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Modulating Effects of Lisinopril on Sildenafil Activity in Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension(PAH)( MELISSA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The broad aim of this investigation is to determine whether the modulating effect of angiotensin converting enzyme inhibition on vascular smooth muscle responsiveness to the nitric oxide pathway that we have observed in an animal model of Congestive Heart Failure(CHF) can be exploited in humans with PAH. Furthermore, we have identified a group of genes TAO kinase I, IL-10, Rho kinase, Raf1, bile acid coenzyme A and Fmr1 that are modulated by long-acting angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitor (ACEI) in our animal model, and therefore may also be modulated by ACEI in patients with PAH</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Familial Primary Pulmonary Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lisinopril</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sildenafil Citrate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1875 World Health Organization (WHO) Group I PAH with prior documentation of peripheral vascular resistance (PVR) &gt; 3 WU and wedge(PCW) 16 or less. WHO Functional Class IIII 6 minute walk distance 150575 meters Women of child bearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test and be using effective contraception Receiving therapy with phosphodiesterase5 inhibitor for PAH (sildenafil or tadalafil) for at least 3 months and with stable dose for at least 30 days If already receiving therapy with endothelin receptor antagonists must have been on therapy for at least 3 months and on stable dose for at least 30 days Allergy or intolerance to captopril or other angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors Systemic systolic blood pressure less than 100 mm Hg Therapy with prostanoids (iloprost, treprostinil, epoprostenol) within preceding 3 months Pregnant or breast feeding Creatinine &gt; 2.0 mg/dl Potassium &gt; 5.0 meq/dl Unable to provide informed consent TLC or VC &lt;60% predicted Untreated obstructive sleep apnea LVEF &lt; 40% Hb &lt; 10 mg/dL</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension (PAH)</keyword>
</DOC>