<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01987037</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to describe the feasibility of the passation of the assessment battery of psychomotor functions tests (NP-MOT) in children aged 4 to 11 years with a diagnosis of autism spectrum disorder: number and type of evaluable events, number and type of tests with a deficit compared to the standard results.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neuropsychomotor Functions in Children With Autism Spectrum Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After informed consent obtention, the children will be submitted to the different tests of the battery to evaluate the psychomotor functions. The results will be compared with other data collected from the routine practise : socio-demographic data, medical and developmental antecedents,psychological tests (KABC II, Rey test, London Tower test, ...), psychomotor evaluation (MABC, evaluation of manual praxis, visual abilities, Frostig test), understanding data (N-EEL test), neuropediatric examination, clinical assessment (ADI-R, CARS). The use of this battery allows this fine discriminative assessment of the psychomotor functions involved in the movement. Exploring each function will allow to take into account qualitative and quantitative aspects of the movement in every aspects, and this is not applied in the routine care until now. Calibration for each event can explore each function independently of each other, and will provide information to determine any specific developmental characteristics improve care.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Child Development Disorders, Pervasive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>informed consent from the parents or the legal representative age 4 to 11 autism spectrum disorder diagnosis according to the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, fourth edition text revised bad understanding of the french language motor disability from lesion or accidental origin, proved genetic or neurologic disease deafness, blindness parents with administrative or judiciary protection, and without health insurance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>autism spectrum disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>neuropsychomotor assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>NP-MOT</keyword>
	<keyword>motor skills</keyword>
	<keyword>gross motor</keyword>
</DOC>