<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01987908</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sickle cell disease (SCD) is a genetic blood disorder characterized by the presence of sickle-shaped red blood cells. In the U.S. and the U.K. this occurs primarily in persons of African origin. There is only one drug (hydroxyurea) approved to manage SCD, but it is not fully efficacious and can produce medically significant side effects. Aes-103 is being evaluated as a novel agent for the long term management of SCD. By directly reducing the sickling process, Aes-103 has a different mechanism of action than hydoxyurea. The active ingredient in Aes-103 is 5-hydroxymethyl furfural, a naturally occurring small molecule that is chemically related to glucose. This study will evaluate the safety and pharmacokinetic profile of two dosing regimens of Aes-103 for up to 28 days in up to 50 adult subjects with stable SCD compared with subjects receiving placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Different Dose Regimens of Aes-103 Given for 28 Days to Subjects With Stable Sickle Cell Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will evaluate evaluate in subjects with stable SCD the safety, pharmacokinetic profile, clinical pharmacology actions and clinical activities of two dosing regimens of Aes-103 (1000 mg four times daily in Cohort A and a higher or lower dose given once daily or up to four times daily in Cohort B) given for up to 28 days in adult subjects with stable SCD compared with subjects receiving placebo.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female, aged 1860 years old, inclusive Diagnosis of SCD (hemoglobin SS) without hospitalization for pain crises or any other reason in the 14 days before enrollment Have normal organ function as defined by direct bilirubin &lt;1.1 mg/dL (19 μmol/L), alanine transaminase (serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase) ≤120 IU/L, and Creatinine ≤1.3 mg/dL (115 μmol/L) Have at least one of the following baseline values: hemoglobin level of &lt;10 g/dL, numerical pain rating scale (NPRS) score of ≥ 4, or 6minute walk distance (6MWD) of &lt;500 m If female, be nonpregnant and nonbreastfeeding and be surgically sterile or using an acceptable method of contraception throughout the study and for 3 months after the last dose of study medication Have completed an outpatient screening visit consisting of medical history, physical examination, 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG), vital signs, hematology and chemistry tests, urinalysis, urine drug screen, urine or serum pregnancy test (females), hemoglobin electrophoresis, hepatitis B and C screening, and HIV serology Be able to understand and have provided written informed consent including signature on an informed consent form approved by an institutional review board or independent ethics committee Have provided written authorization for use and disclosure of protected health information Agree to abide by the study schedule and to return for the required assessments Have been hospitalized in the 14 days before enrollment, for any reason Have evidence of clinically significant cardiovascular, respiratory, renal, hepatic, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, hematological, neurological, psychiatric, or other disease that may interfere with the objectives of the study or the safety of the subject, or have been hospitalized in the past 6 months as a result of these conditions (for SCDrelated morbidity, a minimum of 14 days from the last hospitalization is required)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
	<keyword>6 minute walk test</keyword>
	<keyword>5-HMF</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Analgesic use</keyword>
	<keyword>Sickle cell disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Aes-103</keyword>
	<keyword>SpO2</keyword>
	<keyword>Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemoglobin</keyword>
</DOC>