<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00831311</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: - To demonstrate that the immune response of the DTaP-IPV-Hep B-PRP~T is non-inferior for all valences to those of the association of PENTAXIM™ and ENGERIX B® PEDIATRICO one month after a three-dose primary series. Secondary Objectives: - To describe in each group the immunogenicity parameters one month after the three-dose primary series. - To describe safety profile after each vaccination in both groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of DTaP-IPV-Hep B-PRP~T Combined Vaccine Compared With PENTAXIM™ and ENGERIX B® PEDIATRICO in Argentinean Infants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Whooping Cough</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tetanus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diphtheria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Poliomyelitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria : Infant of either gender, aged 50 to 70 days inclusive Mother is negative for HBsAg Born at full term of pregnancy (≥37 weeks) and with a birth weight ≥2.5 kg Written informed consent form signed by at least one parent or by another legal representative and an independent witness Parent/legal representative able to attend scheduled visits and to comply with the trial procedures during the entire duration of the trial. Exclusion Criteria : Axillary temperature ≥37.1°C on the day of inclusion Current or planned enrolment in another clinical trial during the clinical trial period Known mother's history of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) infection Known immunodeficiency (congenital or acquired) or induced by immunosuppressive therapy such as anticancer chemotherapy or radiation therapy since birth, or systemic corticosteroids in the last 4 weeks (≥0.5 mg per kilogram and per day equivalent prednisolone and lasting more than 7 days) Receipt of bloodderived products since birth Acute symptoms or severe chronic illness (e.g. cardiac, renal insufficiency, diabetes, auto immune disorders, congenital defect) that may interfere with conduct or completion of trial Occurrence of seizures since birth Hypersensitivity to any of the vaccine components Coagulopathy contraindicating intramuscular injection History of (documented) clinical or serological/microbiological confirmed infection due to pertussis, tetanus, diphtheria, polio, Haemophilus influenzae type b (Hib) or hepatitis B (HB) diseases History of vaccination against pertussis, tetanus, diphtheria, polio, Hib or HB infections Vaccination within the last 4 weeks.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Days</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Days</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diphtheria</keyword>
	<keyword>Tetanus</keyword>
	<keyword>Pertussis</keyword>
	<keyword>Whooping cough</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis B</keyword>
	<keyword>Poliomyelitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Haemophilus influenzae type b</keyword>
</DOC>