<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00303550</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is now completed</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Intravenous (I.V.) Iclaprim Versus Linezolid in Complicated Skin and Skin Structure Infections [cSSSI] (ASSIST-2)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary Objective: The primary objective of this study is to compare the clinical cure rates of iclaprim and linezolid at the test of cure (TOC) visit (7 to 14 days after the end of treatment). Secondary Objectives: The secondary objectives of this study are to compare iclaprim with linezolid regarding: - Clinical efficacy at the end of study medication treatment; - Time to resolution of systemic and local signs and symptoms of complicated skin and skin structure infection (cSSSI); - Clinical outcome in the microbiologically evaluable (ME) population; - Bacteriologic outcome in the ME population; - Bacteriologic eradication rates of Baseline (BL) pathogens; - Clinical outcome in the modified intent-to-treat (MITT) population; - Bacteriologic outcome in the MITT population; - Baseline in vitro susceptibility of isolated pathogens in the ME population; and - Safety and tolerability of iclaprim treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Skin Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Skin Diseases, Bacterial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Linezolid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iclaprim</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of an infection consistent with complicated skin and skin structure infection due to a gram positive pathogen. Known or suspected hypersensitivity to any study medication or other related antiinfective medication Any known or suspected condition or concurrent treatment contraindicated by the prescribing information Previous enrollment in this study Treatment with any investigational drug within 30 days before enrollment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>skin infection</keyword>
	<keyword>complicated skin infection</keyword>
	<keyword>skin structure infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Complicated Skin and Skin Structure Infection</keyword>
</DOC>