<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00303251</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is an open-label, dose-escalating study to delineate the safety, pharmacokinetics (PK), and pharmacodynamics (PD) of TKI258. Pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics will be performed on all subjects. The eligible subject population consists of subjects who have been diagnosed with locally advanced or metastatic melanoma that is refractory to standard therapy or for which no curative standard therapy exists.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety of TKI258 in Advanced/Metastatic Melanoma Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed diagnosis of locally advanced or metastatic melanoma (American Joint Committee on Cancer [AJCC] stage IIIB, IIIC or IV) that is refractory to standard therapy or for which no curative standard therapy exists. Measurable disease Must be eighteen years of age or older Must meet baseline laboratory requirements ECOG performance status 0 or 1 Adults of reproductive potential must agree to use effective contraception or be sterile Concurrent therapy with any other investigational agent Uncontrolled central nervous system metastases Impaired cardiac function or clinically significant cardiac disease Received chemotherapy, targeted therapy or monoclonal antibody therapy ≤4 weeks biological therapy or immunotherapy (therapeutic or diagnostic) ≤2 weeks an investigational agent (therapeutic or diagnostic) ≤4 weeks prior to starting study drug or has not recovered from side effects of such therapy Received any hematopoietic colonystimulating factor (e.g., GCSF, GMCSF) ≤ 2 weeks prior to starting study drug. Erythropoietin is allowed. Has undergone major surgery ≤ 2 weeks prior to starting study drug or has not recovered from side effects of such surgery. Malabsorption syndrome or uncontrolled gastrointestinal symptoms such as nausea, diarrhea, vomiting Pregnant or breast feeding women History of another primary malignancy that is currently clinically significant or currently requires active intervention. Chronic anticoagulation therapy with full strength aspirin, Coumadin, or heparin. History of thromboembolic or cerebrovascular events within the last 12 months. History of rectal bleeding, bloody vomit, or spitting up blood within the last 3 months. Known diagnosis of HIV infection (HIV testing is not mandatory) Use of ketoconazole, erythromycin, carbamazepine, phenobarbital, phenytoin, rifampin, St. John's wort and quinidine is prohibited. Other severe, acute, or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory abnormality that may increase the risk associated with study participation or studydrug administration or may interfere with the interpretation of study results and, in the judgment of the investigator, make the patient inappropriate for this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Locally Advanced or Metastatic Melanoma</keyword>
</DOC>