<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00473057</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a open label study to assess the safety of autologous bone marrow transplantation in patients with a ischemic stroke in the middle cerebral artery territory within 90 days from symptoms onset.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Autologous Stem Cell Transplantation for Patients With Ischemic Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objective: The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and feasibility of intra-arterial and intravenous injection of autologous bone marrow mononuclear cells in patients in the acute and sub-acute phase (&gt; 3 and &lt; 90 days after symptoms onset) of ischemic cerebral infarct in the middle cerebral artery territory. Methods: 15 patients with cerebral infarct within the middle cerebral artery territory will be enrolled in this prospective, nonrandomized, open-labeled study. Up to 10 patients will receive up to 500x 10 6 autologous bone marrow cells injected intra-arterially into the middle cerebral artery through percutaneous approach. The procedure is monitored by Transcranial Doppler (TCD) and electroencephalogram (EEG). Other 5 patients will receive up to 500x 10 6 autologous bone marrow cells injected intravenously. Changes in neurological deficits and improvements in functions will be evaluated at baseline and at regular intervals during follow-up ( 4 months). EEG and neuroimaging exams will be performed at baseline and at regular intervals during the follow-up period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infarction, Middle Cerebral Artery</mesh_term>
	<criteria>clinical diagnosis of ischemic stroke lasting for more than 3 hours and less than 90 days from symptoms onset neuroimages exams showing ischemic cerebral infarct in the middle cerebral artery territory age between 18 and 75 years old NIHSS between 4 and 20 spontaneous recanalization of the middle cerebral artery documented by TCD or MRI signed informed consent difficult in obtaining vascular access for percutaneous procedures vascular impossibility to reach the middle cerebral artery through percutaneous approach severe carotid stenosis( &gt;70%, by Doppler) related to the severe stroke neurological worsening (&gt;4 points in the NIHSS ) due to edema or intracerebral hemorrhage primary hematological disease neurodegenerative disorder previous stroke with mRS &gt; 2 intracardiac thrombosis autoimune disorders osteopathies that could increase the risk of bone marrow harvesting procedure thrombophilias liver failure chronic renal failure (creatinine &gt; 2mg/ml) life support dependence lacunar stroke pregnancy history of neoplasia or other comorbidity that could impact patient's shortterm survival any condition that in the judgment of the investigator would place the patient under undue risk</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>acute stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>middle cerebral artery</keyword>
	<keyword>autologous transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>bone marrow cells</keyword>
	<keyword>stem cells</keyword>
	<keyword>cell therapy</keyword>
</DOC>