<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00887887</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to test whether the presence of polymorphisms in genes encoding substances of the innate immune response in patients undergoing partial hepatic resection because of benign or malignant hepatobiliary disease is related to a higher incidence of infectious complications, post-resectional liver failure or mortality.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Association Between Gene Polymorphisms and Infectious Complications After Liver Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Partial hepatic resection is a feasible and relatively safe procedure for selected patients with benign or malignant hepatobiliary disease. Liver failure after partial hepatic resection, so-called post-resectional liver failure (PLF), is a dreaded complication with high mortality rates. Patients suffering from PLF experience significantly more clinically significant infections (CSI) when compared with patients without PLF. The liver plays an important role in the body's innate immune defense. Recently, polymorphisms in genes encoding key molecules in the innate immune response (e.g. nuclear factor kappa-B) have shown to be associated with a greater risk of CSI. The presence of these polymorphisms combined with partial hepatic resection might render patients susceptible to the development of CSI, PLF and early mortality after liver resection.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age &gt;18 years benign or malignant liver disease requiring partial hepatic resection inability to give informed consent liver disease judged irresectable after intraoperative evaluation use of immunosuppressive drugs resection &lt; 1 segment unable to comply with followup</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>liver surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>gene polymorphisms</keyword>
	<keyword>innate immune response</keyword>
	<keyword>infectious complications</keyword>
	<keyword>post-resectional liver failure</keyword>
	<keyword>mortality</keyword>
</DOC>