<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01129297</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Type 2 diabetes and obesity are both multifactorial diseases resulting from gene-environment interactions. However, this interaction, as well as the specific effect of each polymorphism, remains poorly understood. We now proposed a prospective cohort study to improve our understanding of the influence of phenotypic characteristics on gene expression in tissues involved in glucose and/or lipid metabolism by collecting different biological samples.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Biological Atlas of Severe Obesity (Biological Tissue Collection)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Type 2 diabetes (T2D) is a disease commonly associated with obesity, which is an important risk factor for this condition. More than 80% of the diabetic subjects are obese. By analogy with the metabolic syndrome, the close association between obesity and T2D justifies the recognition of a new disease entity named by the neologism "diabesity". This study will examine the contribution of different genetic variants on "diabesity" development, by integrating multiple genomics approaches (linkage analysis on whole genome, transcriptomics and bioinformatics) and analysis of biological pathways in relevant animals models and humans.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucose Intolerance</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age between 18 and 65 years Indication of abdominal surgery requiring a laparotomy or laparoscopy for bariatric surgery, cholecystectomy, or parietal surgical Phenotype corresponding to one of the following four cases : 1. Body Mass Index ≥ 35 kg/m2 and diabetes defined by a fasting blood glucose ≥ 7 mmol/l and/or ≥ to 11.1 mmol/l, 120 minutes after ingestion of glucose (hyperglycemia caused by oral route) 2. Body Mass Index ≥ 35 kg/m2 with intolerance glucose defined by a fasting blood glucose&gt; 6 mmol/L and &lt;7 mmol/l and/or&gt; 7.8 mmol/l and &lt;11.1 mmol/l , 120 minutes after ingestion of glucose (hyperglycemia caused by oral route) 3. Body Mass Index ≥ 35 kg/m2 without diabetes defined by a blood glucose ≤ 6 mmol/L and / or ≤ 7.8 mmol/l, 120 minutes after ingestion of glucose (hyperglycemia caused by oral route) 4. Body Mass Index &lt;27 kg/m2 without diabetes defined by a blood glucose ≤ 6 mmol/L and / or ≤ 7.8 mmol/l, 120 minutes after ingestion of glucose (hyperglycemia caused by oral route) 5)27 &lt;Body Mass Index &lt;35 kg/m2 without diabetes defined by a blood glucose ≤ 6 mmol/L and / or ≤ 7.8 mmol/l, 120 minutes after ingestion of glucose (hyperglycemia caused by oral route) unable to receive clear information refusal to sign the consent form pathology associated judged by the surgeon, may increase the risk of adverse events related to sampling tissue</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>genetic expression</keyword>
	<keyword>collection of samples</keyword>
</DOC>