<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01292629</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this multi-center clinical trail is to determine the safety and efficacy of the iSert 251 for the correction of aphakia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of the Hoya Surgical Optics (HSO) iSert 251 Posterior Chamber Aspheric Aphakic Intraocular Lens to Historical / Literature Controls.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study evaluated the safety and effectiveness of the Hoya Surgical Optics iSert Model 251 IOL following primary implantation for the visual correction of aphakia in adults in whom the cataractous lens has been removed by phacoemulsification. Results from this prospective, multicenter clinical trial will be used to support a PMA supplement for the iSert® 251 IOL.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cataract</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aphakia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have been diagnosed with cataract for which phacoemulsification extraction and posterior chamber IOL implantation is indicated Have clear intraocular media Have potential Best Corrected Visual Acuity of 20/40 or better Have preoperative Best SpectacleCorrected visual acuity of 20/40 or worse Have ocular pathology or abnormalities that do or are expected to reduce best corrected visual acuity in the operative eye during the study period Are monocular Have current ocular infection Are taking systemic steroids or other antimetabolites Have previous retinal detachment in the operative eye or expect to require retinal laser treatment during the course of the study Eligibility criteria not complete. Contact Hoya Surgical Optics, Inc. for more information.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>intraocular lens</keyword>
	<keyword>IOL</keyword>
	<keyword>cataract</keyword>
	<keyword>Hoya</keyword>
	<keyword>surgical</keyword>
	<keyword>optics</keyword>
	<keyword>ocular</keyword>
	<keyword>visual acuity</keyword>
</DOC>