<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01292824</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase I pilot study to determine the safety and preliminary efficacy of a novel hepatitis C virus (HCV) entry inhibitor (ITX 5061) in patients with HCV infection undergoing liver transplantation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Study of Hepatitis C Virus Entry Inhibitor (ITX 5061) in Liver Transplant Recipients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection is common and treatment options at present are limited. Recurrence of HCV infection after liver transplantation is inevitable and disease progression is rapid when compared with disease in the non-transplanted liver. Studies of ITX 5061 in vitro have shown it to be a potent inhibitor of HCV entry into hepatocytes, through blocking the interaction of the virus with scavenger receptor BI suggesting it may reduce graft re-infection rates after liver transplant. There are no studies of treatments to block host receptors for HCV and the investigators hypothesize that ITX 5061 will modulate HCV kinetics in the early phase post liver transplant.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Extracts</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years old, ≤ 65 years old Plasma HCV RNA positive at time of listing for liver transplantation Accepted for liver transplantation for any of: Endstage liver disease due to HCV infection Endstage liver disease due to HCV infection and alcohol related liver disease (ALD) HCC due to HCV Refusal or inability to give informed consent Viral coinfection with either hepatitis B virus (HBV) or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) Pregnancy or breastfeeding Women, of childbearing potential, who are not willing to practice effective contraception Men, sexually active with women of childbearing potential, who are not willing to practice effective contraception Any situation that in the Investigator's opinion may interfere with optimal study participation Participation in any clinical study of an investigational agent within 30 days of recruitment Transplantation with a donor organ from a HCV positive individual</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C virus</keyword>
	<keyword>Entry</keyword>
	<keyword>Scavenger receptor-BI</keyword>
	<keyword>High density lipoprotein</keyword>
	<keyword>Liver transplantation</keyword>
</DOC>