<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01292083</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial studies azacitidine in treating patients with triple negative stage I-IV invasive breast cancer that can be removed by surgery. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as azacitidine, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Azacitidine in Treating Patients With Triple Negative Stage I-IV Invasive Breast Cancer That Can Be Removed By Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To evaluate the ability of deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) methylation inhibition using 5-azacitidine to induce expression of the estrogen receptor (ER) and progesterone receptor (PR) genes in solid human triple negative invasive breast cancer. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the effect of systemic 5-azacitidine therapy on the expression of other methylated genes in triple negative invasive breast cancer using an Illumina GoldenGate array. OUTLINE: Patients receive azacitidine intravenously (IV) over 10-40 minutes 5 days a week for 2 weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients undergo definitive breast surgery within 12 days of the last dose of azacitidine.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triple Negative Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Azacitidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Resectable tumor measuring 2 cm or more Histologically documented triple negative invasive breast cancer characterized by 0% Immunohistochemistry (IHC) nuclear staining for ERalpha, 0% IHC nuclear staining for PRalpha, and no amplification of HER2/neu by fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH); standard IHC assays for ER and PR use antibodies to ERalpha and PRalpha and PRbeta Southwest Oncology Group (SWOG) performance status of less than or equal to 1 Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1500/μL Hemoglobin (Hgb) &gt;= 9 g/dL Platelets &gt;= 100,000/uL Aspartate aminotransferase (AST)/serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT)/serum glutamic pyruvate transaminase (SGPT) =&lt; 2.5 x upper limit normal (ULN) or =&lt; 5.0 x ULN in patients with liver metastases Creatinine =&lt; 2.0 mg/dL Or Calculated Creatinine Clearance &gt;= 50 ml/min Albumin &gt;= 3 g/dL Potassium &gt;= lower limit normal (LLN) Phosphorous &gt;= LLN Calcium &gt;= LLN Magnesium &gt; LLN Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test performed within 7 days prior to start of treatment Accessible for treatment and followup Written informed consent prior to study entry HER2/neu amplification by FISH Concurrent neoadjuvant treatment with chemotherapy, endocrine therapy, or radiotherapy Known hypersensitivity to azacitidine or mannitol Preexisting hepatic impairment or renal impairment Intent to receive additional neoadjuvant therapy prior to surgery Concurrent use of an histone deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitor or hydralazine Known diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection Major surgery &lt; 4 weeks prior to starting study drug Pregnant or breastfeeding or female of reproductive potential not using an effective method of birth control Other concurrent severe, uncontrolled infection or intercurrent illness, including but not limited to ongoing or active infection or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements Prior antiestrogens (selective estrogen receptor modulator [SERM] or aromatase inhibitors) within 6 months of study entry Underlying medical, psychiatric or social conditions that would preclude patient from receiving treatment</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>