<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00751803</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this trial is to assess the safety, tolerability, and efficacy of three doses of BI 44370 TA in the treatment of patients with an acute migraine attack and headache pain of moderate or severe intensity, compared to placebo and an active comparator.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>BI 44370 TA in Acute Migraine Attack</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Migraine Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eletriptan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult migraine patients with or without aura, diagnosed according to the ICH. Established migraine diagnosis greater than or equal to 1 year. Age at first migraine onset latest at 50 years of age. Medical history of migraine with headache of moderate to severe intensity and migraine frequency of 28 times/ month. Patient has provided written informed consent in accordance with ICHGCP and local legislation. History of hemiplegic, ophthalmoplegic or basilar migraine, or cluster headache. History of treatmentresistant migraine attacks. Other pain syndromes possibly interfering with study assessment or use of any pain medication &gt; 10 days / month. Use of migraine and other restricted medication, or other restrictions as per protocol. Pregnancy or breastfeeding. Female of childbearing potential who do not use contraception. Clinically significant cardiovascular, peripheral vascular, hepatic, respiratory, haematological, gastrointestinal, renal, metabolic, immunological, hormonal, neurological and psychiatric disorders. Patients in whom unrecognised coronary artery disease is likely, or who are at risk of coronary artery disease indicated by the presence of risk factors. Persistent liver enzyme elevation such as ALT, AST or AP &gt; 2x ULN. Known history of HIV, or history of cancer within the last 5 years. DSMIVdefinedhistory of substance abuse or dependence within the past 6 months, excluding nicotine and caffeine, but including alcohol or benzodiazepines.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>