<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01274741</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if an integrated, cognitive-behavioral model of psychotherapy is effective in the treatment of individuals with posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) and substance use disorder (SUD) compared to a known evidence-based model for PTSD/SUD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Treatment for Posttraumatic Stress Disorder and Substance Use</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This project is designed to evaluate a new model of psychotherapy that was developed for individuals with PTSD and SUD. The new model helps them to explore the past as a step in their recovery process. It has major public health relevance in that it is a low-cost, flexible model designed for all trauma and substance abuse types, both genders, and all clinical settings. It has particular relevance for VA in that many veterans suffer from PTSD and SUD. The new model has demonstrated positive results in two pilot studies. If the results of the current study are positive, a larger study could be done for the next stage of scientific testing.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Meet Diagnostic and Statistical Manual (DSMIV) criteria for current PTSD and current substance use disorder Have used a substance in the 60 days prior to intake Outpatient Plan to stay in Boston for the next 6 months If on psychiatric medication, are on a stable regimen for at least 4 weeks prior to participation in the study Have a stable mailing address and live nearby enough to come to VA Boston for treatment Able to sign informed consent Willing to participate in all assessments and urine testing Willing to provide a release of information for study staff to contact treaters as needed for clinical concerns Any current acute medical condition that would either interfere with the patient's ability to attend treatment, or would be of such severity as to affect the patient's psychological functioning Current bipolar I disorder, schizophrenia or other psychotic disorders, mental retardation, or organic mental disorder Any obvious clinical sign that the patient is not sufficiently stable to participate in the treatment, or notification by the patient's primary providers that participation would be contraindicated Dangerousness that would present a threat to staff or patients (e.g., history of assault within the past 6 months) The patient is mandated to treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Posttraumatic stress disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Substance use disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized trial</keyword>
</DOC>