<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01274923</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims to evaluate the effect of shockwave therapy on erectile dysfunction on patients responding to PDE5i therapy in a sham controlled randomized double blind manner.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Double Blind Placebo Controlled Study on the Effect of Extracorporal Shock Wave Therapy on Erectile Dysfunction in PDE5i Responders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study aims to evaluate the effect of a 12-session low intensity shockwave therapy protocol for patients with erectile dysfunction. On screening patients will undergo evaluation by thorough medical history and by questionnaires for evaluation of sexual function. A one-month active treatment with PDE5i will be provided followed by re-evaluation using the same questionnaires. Then another one-month period without PDE5i medication (washout period ) will be done and finally on the following visit evaluation will include the same questionnaires and if fit for inclusion- additional objective evaluation of endothelial function using the Flow mediated dilatation technique and penile blood flow measurement by doppler ultrasound of the Penis will be performed. At the end of this screening pahse the first shock wave session will be performed. Altogether 12 treatment sessions will be performed - 6 treatments twice a week followed by a 3 week no-treatment interval and again 6 treatments twice a week. Follow-up which will include the same evaluation as in the first treatment visit will be performed one month after end of treatment</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Erectile Dysfunction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ED of more than 6 months Rigidity score ≥ 3 under PDE5i therapy SHIM ≤21 under PDE5i therapy Non hormonal, neurological or psychological pathology Stable heterosexual relationship for more than 3 months Prior prostatectomy surgery Any unstable medical, psychiatric, spinal cord injury and penile anatomical abnormalities Clinically significant chronic hematological disease Antiandrogens, oral or injectable androgens Radiotherapy in pelvic region</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Erectile dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Low Intensity Shock Wave</keyword>
</DOC>