<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01274065</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There is no common rule as to how a drug will affect patients. This is due to the effect specific DNA sequences of genes have on drug response, by the effect they have on how medications are metabolized. The primary objective of this research is to optimize medication therapy and to reduce the number of medications used, specifically medications for people with developmental disabilities and co-occuring psychiatric illnesses.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Developing an Interdisciplinary Pharmacogenomic Treatment Approach to Reduce Medication Burden and Improve Outcomes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary goal of this study is to develop a process for utilizing pharmacogenomic analysis as a strategy to improve the quality of life, safety, decrease medication burden, and enhance the effectiveness of medications in people with psychiatric illnesses and developmental disabilities. Ultimately, this inter-disciplinary service could be developed into a standard screening and consultation tool for healthcare providers to utilize when determining the most appropriate medication for their patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Developmental Disabilities</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Current resident of the South Dakota Developmental Center (SDDC) Currently taking a high number of medications per month Eligibility of the subjects will be determined by the treatment team which consists of 34 of the following individuals: treating psychologist, behavior therapist, case manager, supervisors, counselors, dietitians, physician assistants, occupational therapists, and physical therapists To be determined by the research staff</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>psychiatry</keyword>
	<keyword>psychiatric illness</keyword>
	<keyword>developmental disability</keyword>
	<keyword>mental health</keyword>
	<keyword>medication burden</keyword>
</DOC>