<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01946217</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot research trial studies factors affecting patient participation in Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS) Malignancy Clinical Trials Consortium clinical trials. Determining how patients makes decisions about participating in a clinical trial may help doctors plan clinical trials in which more patients are willing to participate and are satisfied with their decision to participate.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Factors Affecting Patient Participation in AIDS Malignancy Clinical Trials Consortium Clinical Trials</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To identify participant-level factors affecting recruitment of potentially eligible participants in AIDS Malignancy Clinical Trials Consortium (AMC) studies at core and affiliated sites. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To describe the socio-demographic characteristics for participation and non-participation in AMC clinical trials among all approached volunteers across AMC sites. II. To characterize socio-demographic characteristics with motivation and decision making among those who consented to participate in an AMC trial. III. To identify the perceived barriers associated with clinical trial participation among those who did not consent to participate in an AMC clinical trial. IV. To better understand how potential study volunteers learn about AMC clinical trials and by what means are they referred to a particular study. OUTLINE: Participants complete the Improving Participation in AMC Clinical Trials (IMPACTS) survey comprising questions about socio-demographic information and clinical trial participation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precancerous Conditions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HIVinfected participants Cancer or anal dysplasia diagnosis Offered informed consent on an AMC interventional clinical trial Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document Inability to provide informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>