<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01946932</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a steering group approved substudy to the Target Temperature Management trial (TTM, ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT01020916). TTM compares the effect of two strictly controlled temperature regimes for survivors of out-of-hospital cardiac arrest. The primary aim of this sub-study is to compare the amount of cognitive impairment in cardiac arrest survivors treated with 33 degrees and 36 degrees and with a matched group of control patients with myocardial infarction. Our secondary aims are: - To investigate the impact of cognitive impairment on our patients' ability to participate in society and their health related quality of life. - To investigate the relationship between our patients cognitive impairments and their relatives/informants health related quality of life and feelings of burden. - To test the hypothesis that the simple cognitive screening battery used in the TTM main trial is sensitive enough to detect all patients with significant cognitive disability.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cognitive Impairment Following Cardiac Arrest and Target Temperature Management</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Out-of-Hospital Cardiac Arrest</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 years or older OutofHospital Cardiac Arrest (OHCA)of presumed cardiac cause Unconsciousness after sustained return of spontaneous circulation (ROSC) Exclusion Criteria at time for inclusion in the TTM study: Known bleeding diathesis Suspected or confirmed acute intracranial bleeding Suspected or confirmed stroke Unwitnessed asystole Known limitations in therapy and Do Not Resuscitateorder Known disease making 180 days survival unlikely Known prearrest status Cerebral Performance Category (CPC)3 or 4 Temperature &lt;30°on admission 4 hours (240 minutes) from ROSC to screening Systolic blood pressure &lt;80 mm Hg in spite of fluid loading/vasopressor and/or inotropic medication/intra aortic balloon pump Inhospital cardiac arrest OHCA of presumed noncardiac arrest cause Additional Exclusion criteria for the substudy: Disability to speak the site language well enough to complete tests without interpreter Controls should never have suffered a cardiac arrest</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Induced hypothermia</keyword>
	<keyword>Mild induced hypothermia</keyword>
	<keyword>Resuscitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Therapeutic hypothermia</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurological function</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognition</keyword>
</DOC>