<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00870415</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Breast-conserving surgery is a less invasive type of surgery for breast cancer and may have fewer side effects and improve recovery. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying different breast-conserving surgery techniques in treating women with breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Breast-Conserving Surgery Techniques in Treating Women With Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Evaluate the percentage of histologically healthy margins maintained during resection in women with breast cancer. Secondary - Evaluate local recurrence at 5 years. - Evaluate aesthetic results. - Evaluate quality of life using the QLQC30 and BR23 questionnaires. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients undergo oncoplastic conservative surgery according to defined modalities across the various centers. Quality of life is assessed periodically. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 6 months for 2 years and then for at least 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Meets 1 of the following criteria: Diagnosis of intraductal breast cancer requiring a wide local resection Diagnosis of infiltrating ductal breast cancer within range Diagnosis of invasive breast cancer that has not responded well to neoadjuvant treatment No multicentric tumor No gigantomastia Hormone receptor status not specified PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Menopausal status not specified No patients subject to a measure of legal protection or unable to express consent No patients deprived of liberty by judicial or administrative decision or hospitalized without patient consent Not pregnant or nursing PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: No prior radiotherapy to the diseased breast No prior adjuvant treatment No concurrent participation in another clinical research study</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IA breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IB breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIA breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIC breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>ductal breast carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>invasive ductal breast carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>