<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00870285</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Ustekinumab, an IL-12/23 antibody has been approved in the E.C. and U.S.A. for the treatment of moderate to severe psoriasis. The aim of this study is to determine in a randomized half-side comparison whether additional narrowband UVB-311nm phototherapy accelerates and improves the clearance of skin lesions in Ustekinumab-treated patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ustekinumab Plus UVB-311nm in Psoriasis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with moderate to severe psoriasis who receive standard treatment with Ustekinumab (45 mg at week 0, 4, and every 12 weeks) are exposed to UVB-311nm phototherapy on a randomized body half (left or right; head exempt) 3 x per week for six weeks and/or until complete response (defined as reduction in PASI to &lt; 3). PASI score, patient visual analogue score (VAS) for therapeutic response, and patient VAS for severity of skin lesions is assessed weekly; and at follow-up visits at month 3, 6, and 12. Paired Wilcoxon testing for differences in PASI and patient VAS scores is done; Fischer exact test is applied to determine differences in complete remission, PASI reduction &gt; 90%, &gt; 75% and/or 50% between body sites.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ustekinumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt; 18 years Psoriasis patients who receive treatment with Ustekinumab Age below 18 years Pregnancy or lactation History of malignant melanoma History of invasive squamous cell carcinoma of the skin Dysplastic melanocytic nevus syndrome Antinuclear antibodies (dsDNA, Ro/SSA, La/SSB) Autoimmune disorders such as Lupus erythematosus or Dermatomyositis Photosensitive diseases such as porphyria, chronic actinic dermatitis, Xeroderma pigmentosum, basal cell nevus syndrome, and others General poor health status</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Biologic</keyword>
	<keyword>Ustekinumab</keyword>
	<keyword>UVB-311nm narrowband</keyword>
	<keyword>phototherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>half-side comparison</keyword>
</DOC>