<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00944957</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Efavirenz causes neuropsychiatric side effects and sleep disturbance, including vivid dreams, dizziness, and abnormal tiredness. These symptoms are frequent during the first weeks of treatment, with subsequent attenuation but may not completely resolve even years after efavirenz initiation. The investigators plan a four week, randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind study. In group 1, efavirenz will be replaced with efavirenz placebo plus raltegravir, in group 2, efavirenz would be continued, and raltegravir placebo given in addition. After two weeks, patients in group 1 would switch to the regimen of group 2, and vice versa. The primary endpoint of the trial will be patient preference. Sleep quality, daytime sleepiness, and anxiety will also be investigated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Patient Preference, Sleep Quality, and Anxiety/Depression: A Comparison of Raltegravir and Efavirenz</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Efavirenz</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Raltegravir Potassium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients &gt; 18 years Signing the study consent form and agree to change ART regimen Stable HAART including EFV since at least 3 months HIVRNA below 50 copies for at least 3 months No major psychiatric disease (psychosis, severe depression) diagnosed before the initiation of EFV Mentally incompetent patients Pregnancy or lactation Women of childbearing potential must use one or two reliable contraceptive methods during the trial, from day 1 to the end of week 12. Acceptable methods include the birth control pill, IUD, condoms with spermicides. Nonacceptable methods include (nonexhaustive list): Withdrawal, calendar (Onigo method), or spermicides alone. Concomitant renal or hepatic disease: Creatinine above 150 micromol/L Transaminases above 5 times upper normal limit Prothrombin (Quick) value below 50%</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Raltegravir</keyword>
	<keyword>efavirenz</keyword>
	<keyword>anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>depression</keyword>
	<keyword>sleep quality</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>NNRTI</keyword>
	<keyword>Tritherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>compliance</keyword>
	<keyword>stocrin</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment experienced</keyword>
</DOC>