<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00944034</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This extension study V72P12E1 will investigate the safety, tolerability and immunogenicity of a fourth (booster) dose of rMenB+OMV NZ at 12, 18 and 24 months of age in subjects previously primed with rMenB+OMV NZ according to two different three-dose immunization schedules in infancy (2, 4 and 6 or 2, 3 and 4 months of age in the parent study V72P12). The study will also explore the bactericidal antibody persistence at 12, 18 and 24 months of age, following the two different immunization schedules, in order to identify the optimal timing for boosting. Two catch-up rMenB+OMV NZ doses will be given to unprimed, naïve toddlers at 12 (subjects enrolled in the control group of V72P12), 18 and 24 months of age (two new cohort of subjects enrolled). These subjects will generate data for assessing the safety and immunogenicity of a two-dose catch-up regimen at these ages, but will also serve as controls for a descriptive comparison of antibody persistence and booster responses for the other groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Tolerability and Immunogenicity of Meningococcal B Recombinant Vaccine Administered as Booster Dose at 12, 18 or 24 Months of Age in Toddlers (12-24 Months) Primed With a Three-Dose Immunization Series as Infants in Study V72P12</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Meningitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Meningococcal Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Meningitis, Meningococcal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Followon participants of V72P12: Healthy toddlers who completed Study V72P12, aged: 12 months or older Groups 1a, 2a, 3a, 4 18 months (0/ +29 days window) Groups 1b, 2b, 3b 24 months (0/ +29 days window) Groups 1c, 2c, 3c Naive subjects newly enrolled: Group 5: healthy 18monthold toddlers (0/ +29 days window) Group 6: healthy 24monthold toddlers (0/ +29 days window) History of any meningococcal B vaccine administration (only for groups 5 and 6); Previous ascertained or suspected disease caused by N. meningitidis; History of severe allergic reaction after previous vaccinations or hypersensitivity to any vaccine component; Significant acute or chronic infection within the previous 7 days or axillary temperature major or equal to 38 degrees within the previous day Antibiotics within 6 days prior to enrollment; Any serious chronic or progressive disease; Known or suspected impairment or alteration of the immune system; Receipt of blood, blood products and/or plasma derivatives or any parenteral immunoglobulin preparation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Meningococcal meningitis</keyword>
	<keyword>prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>vaccination</keyword>
	<keyword>toddler</keyword>
</DOC>