<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02671019</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this trial is to compare the effectiveness and costs of a five-module Internet-based treatment program (including therapist support) for harmful alcohol use with the effectiveness and cost of the same treatment content delivered face-to-face in specialized addiction treatment. The hypotheses to be tested through this trial are that: 1. The Internet-based treatment program (including therapist support) is as effective (reducing alcohol consumption) as the same treatment content delivered face-to-face in specialized addiction treatment. 2. The Internet-based treatment program (including therapist support) is associated with lower cost per treated individual in relation to the achieved effects (in terms of reduced alcohol consumption) compared with the same treatment content delivered face-to-face in specialized addiction treatment. The design is a two-armed randomized controlled trial, and outcomes are measured in terms of changes in alcohol consumption, problematic alcohol use as well as alcohol dependence, depression, anxiety, quality of life and costs for the treatments. A minimum of 350 participants will be recruited and randomized into two groups: Intervention group 1: All participants in this group will have access to the five-module Internet-based treatment program for harmful alcohol use and have access to a therapist with training in psychotherapy (CBT) who assists and counsels the participant throughout the program. Intervention group 2: All participants in this group will attend five face-to-face treatment sessions in specialized addiction treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness and Costs of Internet-based Treatment for Harmful Alcohol Use and Face-to-face Treatment in Addiction Care</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alcohol Drinking</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years or older 16 points on Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test or at least 3 criteria on the International Classification of Diseases (ICD10) for Alcohol Dependence Resident in Stockholm County Lack of understanding of the Swedish language. Doctor's assessment that there is a risk for severe withdrawal symptoms, risk for suicide or mental illness requiring separate care. Doctor's assessment that there is a need for medication for alcohol dependence.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>