<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01690858</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to assess the role of complement dysregulation and its impact on antiangiogenic factors (soluble Flt1 and endoglin) in patients with foetal losses.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicentric Prospective Study of Genetic and Physiopathology Concerning Dysregulation of Complement During Repeated Fetal Abortions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Females with medical history of repeated foetal losses will have blood sampling to perform analyses. If pregnant, blood sampling will be performed at different times throughout the pregnancy. Controls will be females without medical history of repeated foetal losses. They will also have blood sampling to perform analyses. If pregnant, blood sampling will be performed at different times throughout the pregnancy. Blood analyses will focus on : - mutations in genes coding for molecules that modulate complement activity - serum levels of sFlt1 and endoglin and their link to complement activation</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Complement System Proteins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for females with repeated fetal losses: Age&gt; 18 Female affiliated to French health insurance (Social Security), Informed consent form signed Patient with history of at least three foetal losses without any cause found (chromosomal abnormalities, uterine malformations, endocrine disorders, etc.) Exclusion criteria for females with repeated fetal losses : Patient not fulfilling inclusion criteria Age &gt; 40 Female unable to understand benefits and risks of protocol Female with history of repeated foetal losses of infectious or endocrine origin. Inclusion criteria for females without repeated fetal losses: Age&gt; 18 Female affiliated to the French health insurance (Social Security) Informed consent form signed Female without history of repeated foetal losses Exclusion criteria for females without repeated fetal losses: Patient not fulfilling inclusion criteria Female with age above 40 Female unable to understand benefits and risks of protocol</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Foetal loss</keyword>
	<keyword>complement</keyword>
	<keyword>antiangiogenic factors</keyword>
	<keyword>Repeated fetal losses</keyword>
</DOC>