<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01442935</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective is to compare resection rates (R0 or R1) for hepatic metastases in the experimental arm (tri chemotherapy plus targeted therapy) versus the control arm (bi chemotherapy plus targeted therapy); in both arms the targeted therapy is selected according to K-Ras status of the patient's tumor. The secondary objectives are to evaluate the objective response rate (CR and PR) after 4 cycles of treatment, according the RECIST V1.1 evaluation scale. - the rate of complete remission (CR) at 6 months after the last study treatment (hepatic surgery or last chemotherapy cycle). - the specific rates of resection R0, R1, R2. - the complete pathological response Rate, - the relapse-free survival rate in (R0 or R1) resected patients, - the response duration in non-resected patients, - the toxicity according to CTC AE V4 scale except for the neurotoxicity that will be evaluated with the Levi scale, - the post operative complications using the DINDO classification, - the progression-free survival (PFS) and overall survival (OS). The objectives of the biological study are: - to evaluate tumor-related predictive factors such as somatic mutations (KRAS, BRAF, TP53) and genetic amplification related factors (EGFR), - to evaluate patient-related predictive factors in connection with genetic polymorphisms (Fc gamma and VEGF receptors), - to evaluate ADCC activity via immunohistochemistry in order to analyze the lympho free and progression-free survival, - to study circulating of tumor cells as prognostic factor for metastatic colorectal cancer, non- resectable at presentation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chemotherapies Associated With Targeted Therapies on the Resection Rate of Hepatic Metastases</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leucovorin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levoleucovorin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically proven colorectal adenocarcinoma, Primary tumor of the colon or rectum, resectable or resected at least 3 weeks before randomization or 4 weeks before the beginning of the study treatment, Metastatic disease with synchronous or metachronous (&gt; 3 months after diagnosis of the primary tumor) hepatic metastasis, Nonresectable (with respect to curative intent) hepatic metastasis at presentation. This criterion must be validated by both a surgeon and a radiologist during the RCP (Multidisciplinary cancer case presentation committee) patient's evaluation meeting (either technically nonresectable metastases (absolute contraindication): i.e. impossibility to resect all metastases in a single operation while preserving at least 30% of healthy liver tissues and/or impossibility to preserve the portal vein and hepatic artery homolateral to the liver or a portal pedicle, or due to oncological nonresectability (relative contraindication): presence of &gt; 5 nodules and bilateral invasion), Hepatic metastases, without spread to other sites except in case of ≤ 3 resectable pulmonary metastases of diameter &lt; 2 cm, detected by thoracic scanner, KRas status determined before randomization, Measurable disease according to the RECIST V1.1 criteria, No prior treatment of the hepatic metastases, Previous 5FU +/ oxaliplatinbased adjuvant chemotherapy administered after colorectal tumor resection is authorized if complete more than 1 year before, Age ≥ 18 &amp; ≤ 75 years Performance status : ECOG 0 or 1, Life expectancy ≥ 3 months, Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dl, Polynuclear neutrophiles ≥ 1500/mm3, Platelets ≥ 100 000 mm3, Creatinemia ≤ 135 µmol/l (1,35 mg/dl) Total bilirubin ≤ 1.25 times the Upper Limit of Normal (ULN). Hepatic enzymes ASAT and ALAT &lt; 5 x ULN, Negative pregnancy test for women of childbearing age, Information given to the patient and signed informed consent, Public Health insurance coverage. Non metastatic and/or non measurable disease according to the RECIST v1.1 criteria. Nonresectable primary tumor (e.g.: T4 tumors) or incomplete resection R2. History of intestinal inflammatory disease. Specific contraindication to any of the study treatments. Patient who have previously received antiEGFr (e.g., cetuximab) or antiVEGF monoclonal antibody treatment (e.g., bevacizumab) or treatment with irinotecan. History of cancer considered as not cured. Stroke/CVA or pulmonary embolism within 6 months before inclusion. Significant concomitant disease such as: coagulopathy, respiratory or cardiac congestive insufficiency, nonmedically controlled/unstable angina pectoris, myocardial infarction within 6 months prior to study entry, arterial hypertension and uncontrolled arrhythmia, severe infections. Clinical neuropathy, grade ≥1. Patient already included in another therapeutic trial using an experimental molecule. Pregnant women or women who might become pregnant during the study or lactating women. Men or women who can procreate and who do not abide with the use of a contraceptive means. Persons kept in detention or incapable of giving consent Patient unwilling or unable to comply with the medical followup required by the trial because of geographic social or psychological reasons.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Adenocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-resectable hepatic metastases</keyword>
	<keyword>First-line treatment</keyword>
</DOC>