<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01684410</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This was a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose escalation study to assess the safety and tolerability of 100 mg and 200 mg of inhaled Alpha-1 HC administered once a day for three weeks in subjects aged 18 years and older with cystic fibrosis (CF). The treatment duration in this study was intended to provide multi-dose safety information prior to proceeding to longer durations of exposure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Tolerability Trial of Inhaled Alpha1-Proteinase Inhibitor (Human), Hydrophobic Chromatography Process (Alpha-1 HC) in Subjects With Cystic Fibrosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alpha 1-Antitrypsin Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alpha 1-Antitrypsin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Protein C Inhibitor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Protease Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 years or older. Documentation of CF diagnosis. Have a prebronchodilator FEV1 ≥ 40% of predicted at Visit 1 and have a Visit 2 preinvestigational product FEV1 that is ≥ 40% of predicted and within ± 15% of the Visit 1 result. Deemed by the Investigator to be a suitable candidate for serial collection of expectorated sputum. Had a pulmonary exacerbation during the 4 weeks before screening (Visit 1) which required the initiation of new antibiotic treatment Have a pulmonary exacerbation during the screening period (between Visit 1 and Visit 2) which requires the initiation of new antibiotic treatment FEV1 &lt; 0.59 liters at the screening visit Respiratory insufficiency with continuous supplemental oxygen therapy, or carbon dioxide retention Elevated aspartate transaminase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) that is ≥ 3 times the upper limit of normal for age and gender Smoking during the past 6 months Lung surgery during the past 2 years Positive culture for Burkholderia cepacia or mycobacterium during the past two years. Active allergic bronchopulmonary aspergillosis Pretreatment sputum collection at Visit 1 or Visit 2 (Randomization) characterized by problems such as inadequate sputum volume or quality. Known selective Immunoglobulin A (IgA) deficiency with known antibody against IgA (antiIgA antibody). History of anaphylaxis or severe systemic response to any plasmaderived alpha1proteinase inhibitor preparation or other blood product(s), or to polysorbates. Use of chronic oral steroids during the study. Note: Inhaled corticosteroids that had been administered for at least 4 weeks prior to Visit 1 were permissible during the study. Use of chronic, high dose ibuprofen therapy within 3 weeks of screening and at anytime during the study. Chronic maintenance therapy with systemic antibiotics within 3 weeks of screening and through last dose of investigational product. Use of leukotriene synthesis inhibitor (zileuton) or leukotriene receptor antagonists (montelukast, zafirlukast) within 3 weeks of screening and at anytime during the study. Use of roflumilast within 3 weeks of screening and at any time during the study. Initiation of a new chronic medication or dosage change of a chronic medication for treatment of cystic fibrosis (example: Kalydeco™ [ivacaftor]) within 3 weeks of screening (Visit 1).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cystic Fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Alpha1-proteinase inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Alpha1-antitrypsin</keyword>
</DOC>