<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02277899</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine communication content and strategies in primary care that predict improvement in weight status among overweight school-age children.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Primary Care, Communication, and Improving Children's Health</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We will test whether 1) pediatrician-patient communication regarding overweight status, behavior/risk-factor counseling, and the frequency and time to next follow-up visit, compared with either no communication or incomplete communication (communicating only high weight status without behavior/risk-factor counseling or a follow-up visit) will predict improvement in weight status at one year follow-up, and 2) during pediatrician-patient communication regarding weight and weight management, higher patient-centeredness will predict improvement in weight status at one year follow-up. The communication content identified will generate new information about the most effective content and style of pediatrician-patient communication that predict weight-status improvement. Because we prospectively will examine clinical practice elements in the one-year interval between well-child visits, acknowledging that communication regarding high weight status may initiate assessment of risk factors for heart disease (such as high cholesterol and blood sugar), more frequent follow-up visits, or prompt a nutrition referral, we will generate novel information about the most effective clinical practices and follow-up interval and frequency that predict weight-status improvement in overweight children. We also will examine if the content and style of communication are related to improvements in diet and lifestyle behaviors at one-year follow-up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Schedule a wellchild visit with a participating pediatrician Agree to return in one year for the followup wellchild visit Overweight 612 years old Have a working telephone and/or email address Child/parent willing to provide assent/consent Unstable illness (such as uncontrolled asthma) Developmental condition (such as trisomy 21) Planning to move/leave practice within two years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>childhood obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>overweight</keyword>
	<keyword>communication</keyword>
	<keyword>primary care</keyword>
	<keyword>weight management</keyword>
	<keyword>communication methods</keyword>
	<keyword>patient-centered communication</keyword>
</DOC>