<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02890030</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The patients enrolled on this new study will serve as an appropriate comparison group consisting of patients with the diagnosis of germ cell testicular cancer who were cured with surgical resection and did not receive cisplatin-based chemotherapy with a group of patients from another study who did receive cisplatin-based chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Platinum Study Comparison Group</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary Objective To compare the prevalence of ototoxicity and neurotoxicity in GCT cancer survivors who only had surgery to a similar population from The Platinum Study (RSRB45410/1305011509) who received cisplatin-based combination chemotherapy. Secondary Objective To compare the prevalence of obesity, hypertension, and use of antidepressants/anxiolytics in GCT cancer survivors who only had surgery to a similar population from The Platinum Study who received cisplatin-based combination chemotherapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Testicular Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis or confirmation of diagnosis of a histologically or serologically confirmed testicular germ cell tumor (GCT) or GCT at another anatomic location Age at GCT diagnosis: 55 years of age or younger Males, 18 years of age or older at time of study consent Subject is able to provide consent Subject is able to speak and read English Treatment consisted of surgery only (i.e., orchiectomy and/or retroperitoneal lymph node dissection [RPLND]) for either initial testicular germ cell tumor (GCT) or subsequent testicular cancer Subject completed surgery &gt; 1 year ago Subject is currently undergoing active followup at IU Subject did not require any subsequent chemotherapy, salvage chemotherapy treatment or bone marrow transplant. Subject had no prior chemotherapy of any kind Patients with prior chemotherapy (whether for GCT or any other cancer)</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cisplatin-based therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Ototoxicity</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurotoxicity</keyword>
</DOC>