<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02890927</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the evaluation study is to determine if geriatric co-management is superior to standard of care in preventing functional decline in older patients admitted for acute heart disease or Transcatheter Aortic Valve Implementation (TAVI) to the cardiology units of the University Hospitals Leuven.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Geriatric-CO-mAnagement for Cardiology Patients in the Hospital</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study aims to implement and evaluate a geriatric co-management intervention in older patients admitted for acute heart disease or Transcatheter Aortic Valve Implementation (TAVI) to the cardiology units of the University Hospitals Leuven. The study uses a mixed-methods methodology aiming to 1) assess the feasibility and evaluate the effectiveness of geriatric co-management, 2) describe the experiences of intervention participants, and 3) perform a process evaluation. We will first consecutively recruit patients on the cardiology units to measure the standard of care in the control group. The geriatric co-management intervention will then be implemented and piloted on the participating units. Once fully implemented, we will consecutively recruit patients for the intervention group who will receive the geriatric co-management intervention.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Delirium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients will be included if they: Are admitted for nonsurgical treatment of an acute heart problem (patients may be admitted through the emergency department or the cardiology outpatient services for any heart related acute disease) OR if they are admitted for Transcatheter Aortic Valve Implantation (TAVI); Are aged 75 years or older; Have an expected length of stay of three days or longer; Have an expected life expectancy of six months or longer; Are Dutch speaking and testable; Give informed consent or proxyinformed consent; Patients will be excluded if they: Are admitted from another hospital unit or other hospital; Have been admitted to the intensive care unit for three days or longer;</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>75 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Geriatric Nursing</keyword>
	<keyword>Geriatric co-management</keyword>
	<keyword>Geriatric team</keyword>
</DOC>