<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02890368</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicenter, open-label, phase 1 study that is being done to test intratumoral injections of TTI-621 in subjects that have relapsed and refractory percutaneously accessible solid tumors or mycosis fungoides. The study will be performed in two different parts. Part 1 is the Dose Escalation phase and Part 2 is the Dose Expansion phase. The purpose of this study is to characterize the safety profile of TTI-621 and to determine the optimal dose and delivery schedule of TTI-621.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial of Intratumoral Injections of TTI-621 in Subjects With Relapsed and Refractory Solid Tumors and Mycosis Fungoides</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multicenter, open-label, phase 1 study that is being done to test intratumoral injections of TTI-621 in patients that have relapsed and refractory percutaneously accessible solid tumors or mycosis fungoides. The study will be performed in two different parts: Dose Escalation and Dose Expansion. During the escalation part of the study, TTI-621 will be studied at 3 different dose levels and at different dosing frequencies to characterize safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD). During the expansion part of the study, TTI-621 will be studied in an expanded group of patients at the dose and frequency which had acceptable level of side effects during the escalation part of the study. The expansion phase will further define safety and characterize efficacy. The purpose of this study is to characterize the safety profile of TTI-621 and to determine the optimal dose and delivery schedule of TTI-621.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycoses</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycosis Fungoides</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Merkel Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically documented, injectable cancer lesion (limited to solid tumors and mycosis fungoides) Adequate renal function Adequate coagulation function Adequate hepatic function Disease that has progressed on standard therapy or for whom there is no other therapy option available Central nervous system involvement Significant cardiovascular disease Active autoimmune disease Active hepatitis B or C or a history of HIV infection Uncontrolled infection History of hemolytic anemia or bleeding diathesis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>CD47</keyword>
	<keyword>SIRPa</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Checkpoint inhibitor</keyword>
</DOC>