<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02489383</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The treatment of asthma is based in clinical control. However, previous studies have been shown that patients that participate of the programs of regular or aerobic continuous exercise training (CT) presented improvements in the physical conditioning, and quality life, as well as decreased the levels of anxiety and depression, reduced the oxide nitric exhaled and leukocyte migration at the airways and reduced the airway hyperresponsiveness. The regular exercise also is important part in the rehabilitation of other lung disease as well as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). Additionally, others studies have been shown the effects of high intensity interval training (IT) in the pulmonary rehabilitation of COPD patients, that after performed IT presented reduction of dyspnea, and increase the physical capacity. In this sense, the impact of IT in the asthmatic patients at the present moment is poorly studied, and necessity of the more investigation to prove the efficiency of this training model for asthma patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison Between Continuous Versus Interval Exercise Training in Asthmatic Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The present study will compare the impact of IT and CT in patients with moderate or severe asthma, and investigate what is the most efficient and increases the physical capacity, and quality of life and reduces the inflammatory mediators. Sixty asthmatic adults will be randomly assigned into two groups: CT (Continuous training) or IT (Interval training). CT will have treatment 2x week, 40 min./session, 60-75% of maximum heart rate intensity and IT also 2x week, 40 min./session, 80-140% of the maximum load intensity, both performed in ergometer cycle by 24 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Asthma moderate and severe Asthma will diagnosed (Global Initiative for Asthma GINA) Body Mass Index (BMI) &lt; 35kg/m2 Medical Treatment for at least 6 months Clinically stable (i.e., no exacerbation or medication changes for at least 30 days) Cardiovascular, musculoskeletal or other different chronic lung diseases Active cancer Pregnant Smokers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>59 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>Continuous Exercise Training</keyword>
	<keyword>interval Exercise Training</keyword>
	<keyword>Clinical Control</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammation</keyword>
</DOC>