<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02489409</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Endostatin has been widely applied for the clinical treatment of partial primary and metastatic solid tumors. Endostatin combined with chemotherapy has achieved favorable progression in the treatment of non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). However, the research about the efficacy of Endostatin on breast cancer has just started. Breast cancer is a highly-differentiated solid tumor, indicating that it is also an indicator for Endostatin therapy. Additionally, after chemo- and radiotherapy, the primary nidi of patients with advanced breast cancer may also lead to rapid development of tumors in other locations. So Endostatin combined with chemotherapy can also improve the prognosis of patients with recurrent metastatic breast cancer, but there is rare any report at home and abroad. To further explore the above research, this study designed a randomized, opened and controlled clinical study to observe the clinical efficacy of EndostarTM Injection combined with GP/NP/GX/NX in the treatment of recurrent metastatic breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Recombinant Human Endostatin (EndostarTM) Injection in Treatment of Recurrent Metastatic Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vinorelbine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vinblastine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endostatins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: 18～70 years old; Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) score: 0～1 score; All patients were diagnosed as recurrent metastatic breast cancer retreatment by histopathology and computed tomography (CT) examination; The measurable nidus≥1: Patients whose nidus diameter ≥ 20 mm by normal CT or magnetic resonance image (MRI) scanning, and ≥ 10 mm by spiral CT scanning; Patients whose blood routine, hepatorenal function, electrolyte and cardiac function were basically normal without dysfunction of primary organs. White blood cell count (WBC) ≥4.0×109/L, neutrophile granulocyte count ≥1.5×109/L, platelet (PLT) count ≥100×109/L, hemoglobin (HGB) ≥95 g/L, serum bilirubin (BIL) ≤1.5fold upper limit of normal value, alanine transaminase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤2fold upper limit of normal value, and serum creatinine (Scr) ≤1.5mg/dl; The expected survival time ＞3 months; Patients who could understand this study status and had signed the informed consent forms. Patients who had history of allergic responses to biological agents; Patients who were receiving other antitumor therapies; Patients without measureable nidus; Others, including one of the following conditions: patients with uncontrolled central nervous system (CNS) metastatic nidi, with dysfunction of important organs and severe cardiac diseases (congestive heart failure, uncontrollable arrhythmia, and angina pectoris, valvular heart disease, myocardial infarction and refractory hypertension that required longterm drug administration), with chronic infectious wound and with history of uncontrollable psychosis, and women in pregnant or lactation period.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>