<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01549899</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to directly compare 6 sessions of in-person and Internet administered Cognitive-Behavior Therapy for Insomnia (CBTi) to a Minimal Contact control (MC), within an active duty military population to determine the comparative benefits of these interventions on improvement in sleep as well as domains strongly related to insomnia such as depression, substance abuse, and PTSD symptoms. A total of 189 military personnel with chronic insomnia, aged 18-65, will be recruited and randomized to receive 6-sessions (over 6 weeks) of CBTi (n=77), ICBTi (n=35), or a MC control (n=77) condition. The investigators will compare these three groups on subjective and objective measures of sleep. The CBTi and MC control groups will be compared on other variables of interest (e.g., depression, substance abuse, and PTSD symptoms) and predictors of outcomes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparing Internet and In-Person Brief Cognitive Behavioral Therapy of Insomnia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronic Insomnia as defined by Research Diagnostic Criteria (RDC) criteria41 Complaint of &gt; 3 months (chronic insomnia) of disturbed sleep &gt;3 nights/week (severe insomnia) as defined by at least one of the following as assessed by sleep diaries: Sleep Onset Latency of &gt;30 min (initial insomnia) and/or Wake After SleepOnset of &gt;30 min (middle insomnia) and/or Early Morning Awakening of &gt;30 min before the desired wakeup time (late insomnia) and Sleep Efficiency &lt; 85% Active Duty military member stationed at Fort Hood as assessed by selfreport. History of having deployed in support of OIF or OEF as assessed by selfreport. • Stable on psychotropic and/or hypnotic medications for at least one month as assessed by selfreport and review of medical record.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Insomnia</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavioral</keyword>
	<keyword>Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Internet</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Substance Use</keyword>
	<keyword>Post-Tramatic Stress Disorder</keyword>
</DOC>