<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00305006</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A randomized control trial of constraint-induced movement therapy and bimanual training. The protocols have been developed at Columbia University to be child friendly and draws upon our experience since 1998 with constraint-induced movement therapy in children with cerebral palsy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Constraint-induced Movement Therapy (CIMT) and Bimanual Training (HABIT) in Children With Hemiplegic Cerebral Palsy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A randomized control trial to test the efficacy of constraint-induced movement therapy and a new treatment involving bimanual (Hand-Arm Bimanual Intensive Therapy (HABIT). The protocols have been developed at Columbia University to be child friendly and draws upon our experience since 1998 with constraint-induced movement therapy in children with cerebral palsy. The interventions are performed in a 15 day day-camp setting with several children and at least one therapist per child. The aim is to promote the use of and improve the coordination of movement of both hands together. PARTICIPATION IS FREE. Please check out our website for more information: http://www.tc.edu/centers/cit/</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Paralysis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Palsy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemiplegia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1) willingness to agree to intervention and testing procedures and travel to the University for participation and testing. 1) health problems not associated with CP, 2) uncontrollable seizures, 3) visual problems that would interfere with carrying out the intervention or testing, 4) botulinum toxin therapy in the upper extremity musculature during the last six months or who wish to receive it within the period of study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>14 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>cerebral palsy</keyword>
	<keyword>constraint-induced therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>constraint-induced movement therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>CP</keyword>
	<keyword>hemiplegia</keyword>
	<keyword>hand</keyword>
	<keyword>forced use</keyword>
	<keyword>motor control</keyword>
	<keyword>children</keyword>
	<keyword>HABIT</keyword>
	<keyword>Hand-arm bimanual intensive therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Bilateral training</keyword>
	<keyword>Bimanual training</keyword>
	<keyword>functional therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>physical therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>occupational therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>intensive</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatric</keyword>
	<keyword>development</keyword>
	<keyword>upper extremity</keyword>
	<keyword>hemiplegic</keyword>
</DOC>