<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01786928</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether resistance exercise are effective in combating the decline in muscle strength during an exacerbation of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Role of Resistance Exercise in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease Exacerbation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Acute exacerbations are common in patients with COPD and cause specific signs and symptoms, such as increased dyspnea, productive cough with altered sputum, and fever. With disease progression, exacerbations are frequent and have a negative impact on health related quality of life and pulmonary function as well as increase mortality. More severe exacerbations require hospitalization resulting in enormous health expenditures, severely reducing daily life activities and declining peripheral muscle strength that can be only partially reversed after 3 months. Despite many features have been pointed out as responsible for the decrease in muscle strength during hospitalization, physical inactivity seems the most important. Resistance training is an interesting therapeutic option to prevent and/or reverse muscular dysfunction due to immobilised in healthy subjects and stable COPD patients because induces hypertrophy of type II fibers, increases muscle strength and exercise tolerance. In addition, provokes lower dyspnea perception during effort compared with other exercise training. Despite these benefits for stable COPD, the impact of a resistance exercise program during hospitalization remains poorly known.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients hospitalized for exacerbation of COPD patients presenting change in mental status (confusion, lethargy or coma) persistence or worsening in hypoxemia (PaO2&lt;40mmHg) and/or respiratory acidosis (pH&lt;7.25) despite oxygen supplementation or use of noninvasive ventilation hemodynamic instability requiring vasoactive drugs patients transferred to ICU hospitalization lower than 5 days diseases that prevented the exercises</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</keyword>
	<keyword>exacerbation</keyword>
	<keyword>resistance training</keyword>
	<keyword>muscle force</keyword>
</DOC>