<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01786512</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objectives of this study are (i) to select an oral modified release (MR) formulation and dose of omecamtiv mecarbil for chronic twice daily (BID) dosing in subjects with HF and left ventricular systolic dysfunction and (ii) to characterize its pharmacokinetics (PK) over 20 weeks of treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>COSMIC-HF - Chronic Oral Study of Myosin Activation to Increase Contractility in Heart Failure.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Omecamtiv mecarbil (AMG 423, CK-1827452) is a novel small molecule that increases cardiac contractility by selectively and directly activating the enzymatic domain of cardiac myosin heavy chain, the force-generating motor protein of the cardiac sarcomere. This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, multicenter, phase 2 study, consisting of a dose escalation phase to select 1 of 3 omecamtiv mecarbil oral formulations in 2 dose escalation cohorts, followed by an expansion phase to evaluate 20 weeks of administration of the selected omecamtiv mecarbil formulation at 2 target dose levels, compared with placebo.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ventricular Dysfunction, Left</mesh_term>
	<criteria>History of chronic HF, defined as requiring treatment for HF for a minimum of 4 weeks prior to screening Treated with stable, optimal pharmacological therapy for ≥ 4 weeks History of left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ≤ 40% Elevated Nterminal fragment BNP (NTproBNP) Exclusion criteria: Severe uncorrected valvular heart disease Hospitalization within 30 days prior to enrollment Hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy, active myocarditis, constrictive pericarditis, or clinically significant congenital heart disease Acute Myocardial Infarction, Unstable angina or persistent angina at rest within 30 days prior to randomization Systolic BP &gt; 160 mmHg or &lt; 90 mmHg or diastolic BP &gt; 90 mmHg TBL ≥ 2x ULN; AST or ALT ≥ 3x ULN Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt; 30 mL/min/1.73m2</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Omecamtiv mecarbil</keyword>
	<keyword>AMG 423</keyword>
	<keyword>Double-blind</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized</keyword>
	<keyword>Placebo-controlled</keyword>
	<keyword>Oral forumlation</keyword>
	<keyword>CK-1827452</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac myosin activator</keyword>
</DOC>