<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01883258</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study objectives are: 1. To compare cardiovascular function in type 2 diabetes patients vs. healthy controls. 2. To compare the effect of 8 weeks of aerobic interval training versus continuous moderate exercise on cardiovascular function in adults with type 2 diabetes. 3. To examine the mechanisms underlying the exercise-related changes in cardiovascular function. The investigators hypothesize that compared to continuous moderate intensity exercise training, interval training will be more effective in improving cardiovascular function in adults with type 2 diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Aerobic Interval Training on Cardiovascular Function in Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cardiovascular function will be measured at baseline in adults with type 2 diabetes and in age-matched healthy controls. Research volunteers with type 2 diabetes who meet the inclusion criteria will be randomized to the aerobic interval training group, continuous moderate exercise group or non-exercise control group. At the end of the 8-week randomized control exercise intervention, baseline measures will be repeated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria for type 2 diabetes : Diagnosis of type 2 diabetes Sedentary or minimally physically active for at least the prior 1 year Able to give consent Inclusion criteria for healthy control group: Sedentary or minimally physically active for at least the prior 1 year Able to give consent History of diabetic proliferative retinopathy, autonomic or peripheral neuropathy History of any relevant cardiovascular diseases (myocardial infarction, angina pectoris, history of coronary artery bypass surgery or angioplasty, congestive heart failure, or arrhythmia) Hypertension (≥160 mmHg systolic or ≥100 mmHg diastolic) History of renal impairment History of gout or hyperuricemia History of hepatic disease or infection with hepatitis B, C History of seizures, or other relevant ongoing or recurrent illness Recent (within 3 months) or recurrent hospitalizations Use of tobacco products &gt;5 % weight change in the prior 6 months. Current intake of medications that may affect study results Premenopausal women taking oral contraceptives and postmenopausal women taking hormone replacement therapy. Pregnancy (positive urine pregnancy test) or lactation For the healthy control group, history of diabetes.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>