<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02019901</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose: To compare a nurse-led clinic including person-centered care and tight control with "care as usual" in patients with rheumatoid arthritis (RA) and moderate/ high disease activity. Project description: Study population: Patients with RA, 18-80 yrs old, with moderate/ high Disease Activity Score of 28 joints (DAS28 &gt; 3.8) and disease duration &gt; 2 yrs in a 6-month randomized controlled study with a 6 month open follow-up. Intervention group (N=60): Nurse-led visits every 6th week, with structured person-centered care and evaluation of disease activity. If disease remission is not reached, pharmacological treatment including both short-term (intra-articular and oral steroids) and long-term alterations (DMARDs and biologics) is modified according to a predefined algorithm. The control group (N=60) is treated according to "care as usual" with visits to physician every 6th month. Outcome measures: Primary outcome measure is change in Diseases Activity Score (DAS). Secondary outcomes are quality of life, self-efficacy, disability, emotional well-being, pain, fatigue, sleep and satisfaction.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>GotNet Study, The Gothenburg Nurse-led Tight Control Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>≥18 and &lt;80 years of age Signed and dated informed consent form before the start of any specific protocol procedures Fulfill the 1987 ACR criteria or the 2010 ACR/EULAR criteria for RA with disease duration of &gt;2 years Moderate to high disease activity (DAS28 &gt;3.8) ≥2 swollen joints Diagnosis of any other inflammatory arthritis History of chronic infection, recent serious or lifethreatening infection within 6 months Concurrent malignancy, a history of malignancy or current or recent history of severe, progressive, and/or uncontrolled renal, hepatic, hematological, gastrointestinal, endocrine, pulmonary, cardiac, neurological or cerebral disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Rheumatoid arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>Person-centered care</keyword>
	<keyword>Tight control</keyword>
</DOC>