<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02503423</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label, dose-escalation Phase 1/2 study to assess the safety of ASTX660, determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD), recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D), and recommended dosing regimen, and to obtain preliminary efficacy, pharmacokinetic (PK), and target engagement data, in subjects with advanced solid tumors or lymphoma for whom standard life-prolonging measures are not available.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 1-2 Study of ASTX660 in Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors and Lymphomas</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>ASTX660 is a synthetic small molecule dual antagonist of cellular inhibitor of apoptosis protein (cIAP) 1 and X-linked inhibitor of apoptosis protein (XIAP) that has been shown to have potent proapoptotic and tumor growth inhibitory activity in nonclinical models. ASTX660 has not been previously evaluated in human subjects. The Phase 1 portion of the study will determine the MTD, RP2D, and recommended dosing regimen. The Phase 2 portion will evaluate activity in selected tumor types. Subjects will continue to receive their assigned treatment throughout the study until the occurrence of disease progression, death, or unacceptable treatment-related toxicity, or until the study is closed by the sponsor. Tolerability and safety of study treatment will be evaluated throughout the study by collection of clinical and laboratory data. In Phase 2, antitumor response will be assessed according to standard Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST v1.1) using computed tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scans or assessed using another reliable method of disease evaluation appropriate for the tumor type.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects with histologically or cytologically confirmed advanced solid tumors or lymphoma and for whom standard lifeprolonging measures are not available. In the Phase 2 portion of the protocol only, subjects must have measurable disease according to RECIST v1.1, or evaluable disease that can be reliably and consistently followed. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (performance status): 0 to 2 Acceptable organ function Hypersensitivity to ASTX660, excipients of the drug product, or other components of the study treatment regimen Uncontrolled medical disease(s) or active, uncontrolled infections Lifethreatening illness or significant organ system dysfunction A history of, or at risk for, cardiac disease Known history of HIV, or hepatitis B (HBV) or C (HCV) Grade 2 or greater neuropathy Known brain metastases unless stable or previously treated Known significant mental illness Prior anticancer treatments or therapies within specified time windows prior to first dose of study treatment (ASTX660) Pregnant or nursing an infant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>