<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02503605</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Biosimilar drug marketing of recombinant FSH for the treatment of infertility is another step in simplifying fertility treatments, making them easier to manage and more accessible to patients. Taking in mind these arguments ,the study is proposed for determining equivalence in terms of biological effectiveness of an ovarian stimulation protocol with biosimilar recombinant FSH stimulation protocol vs. urinary FSH in oocyte donation program.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Biosimilar Versus Urinary Gonadotropins</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Biosimilar products are drugs "like" biotechnological origin to other innovative biological medicines and that can be marketed once the patent has expired. These drugs are intended to achieve the same therapeutic benefit as biological medicinal resembles. Because of the similarity in both the active substance in the formulation, it is intended to demonstrate the equivalence between the biosimilar medicine of recombinant FSH and FSH of urinary origin in terms of fitness. The investigators' main objective is to perform a non-inferiority trial of biosimilar recombinant FSH product compared to a conventional ovarian stimulation protocol with urinary FSH in relation to the number of oocytes retrieved and the number of metaphase II oocytes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Follicle Stimulating Hormone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients aged 1835 years who meet the criteria for entry into the oocyte donor program and that are going to undergo controlled ovarian stimulation Patient with a basal antral count&gt; 20 follicles in total or &lt;6 antral follicles per ovary Patients with comorbidities that, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with the treatment of ovarian stimulation The presence of ovarian cysts that judgment of the investigator would interfere with the stimulation or may pose a risk to the donor BMI &lt;18 kg / m2 BMI&gt; 30 kg / m2 Severe hypersensitivity to drugs with similar structure</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Biosimilar</keyword>
	<keyword>ovarian stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>oocyte donor</keyword>
</DOC>