<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02758366</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The standard therapy of glioblastoma (GBM) consists of gross total resection followed by focal irradiation to the tumor bed with concomitant and adjuvant temozolomide (TMZ). The association of valproic acid and TMZ during radiotherapy improves survival of GBM. Preclinical studies suggested that doxorubicin had a strong antineoplastic activity against human gliomas. Moreover, some studies showed that the continuous infusion of anthracyclines in patients with solid tumor ensured a better safety profile compared with bolus administration. Based on these findings, the purpose of this study is to evaluate safety and efficacy of prolonged administration of doxorubicin in combination with radiotherapy, temozolomide and valproic acid in pediatric and adult patients with newly diagnosed GBM and diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma (DIPG).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prolonged Exposure to Doxorubicin in Patients With Glioblastoma Multiforme and Diffuse Intrinsic Pontine Glioma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Valproic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and females patients, aged &gt;3 years and &lt; 30 years; Histologically confirmed newly diagnosed GBM and MRI T2scans confirmed DIPG; Patients undergone either surgery or biopsy only; No prior chemotherapy and/or radiotherapy; Life expectancy ≥ 4 weeks; Karnofsky/Lansky ≥ 40 %; Written informed consent obtained from the patient/parents or legal representative; Adequate hematological function (leucocyte ≥ 2.0 x 10^9/l Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dl platelet ≥ 50 x 10^9 /l); Adequate liver function (total bilirubin ≤ 2.5 x ULN ALT/AST ≤ 5.0 x ULN); Adequate renal function (serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN); Adherence to trial treatment and compliance with the protocol Any disease or condition that contraindicates the use of the study drug (es. serious mental retardation, brain palsy, congenital syndrome, cardiomyopathy) Prior anticancer therapy Pregnancy or breastfeeding Non adequate contraception</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>glioblastoma multiforme</keyword>
	<keyword>high grade glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>DIPG</keyword>
	<keyword>doxorubicin</keyword>
	<keyword>temozolomide</keyword>
	<keyword>malignant glioma</keyword>
</DOC>