<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01440374</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a worldwide, three-part (Part 1: open-label, Part 2: randomized, double-blind, Part 3: extension), multi-center study to evaluate the effect of eltrombopag in subjects with myelodysplastic syndromes (MDS) or acute myeloid leukemia (AML) who have thrombocytopenia due to bone marrow insufficiency from their underlying disease or prior chemotherapy. This objective will be assessed by a composite primary endpoint that consists of the following: the proportion of ≥Grade 3 hemorrhagic adverse events, or platelet counts &lt;10 Gi/L, or platelet transfusions. Patients with MDS or AML and Grade 4 thrombocytopenia due to bone marrow insufficiency from their underlying disease or prior chemotherapy will be enrolled in the study. No low or intermediate-1 risk MDS subjects will be enrolled in the study. Subjects must have had at least one of the following during the 4 weeks prior to enrolment: platelet count &lt;10 Gi/L, platelet transfusion, or symptomatic hemorrhagic event. Supportive standard of care (SOC), including hydroxyurea, will be allowed as indicated by local practice throughout the study. The study will have 3 sequential parts. Subjects who are enrolled in Part 1 (open-label) cannot be enrolled in Part 2 of the study (randomized, double-blind); however, subjects who complete the treatment period for Part 1 or Part 2 (8 and 12 weeks, respectively) will continue in Part 3 (extension) if the investigator determines that the subject is receiving clinical benefit on treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Three-part Study of Eltrombopag in Thrombocytopenic Subjects With Myelodysplastic Syndromes or Acute Myeloid Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thrombocytopenia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult subjects (18 years of age or older) with MDS or AML (bone marrow blasts ≤50%) with thrombocytopenia due to bone marrow insufficiency from the disease or prior treatment. Subjects with transient thrombocytopenia due to active treatment with disease modifying agents or chemotherapy (except for hydroxyurea) are excluded Subjects must have Grade 4 thrombocytopenia (platelet counts &lt;25 Gi/L) due to bone marrow insufficiency (or Grade 4 thrombocytopenia, but platelet count greater than or equal to 25 Gi/L due to platelet transfusion). In addition, subjects must have had at least one of the following during the 4 week screening period: platelet transfusion, or symptomatic bleeding or platelet count &lt;10 Gi/L. Subjects whose thrombocytopenia below 10 Gi/L is due to causes other than bone marrow insufficiency (e.g., fever, infection, autoimmune disease) are not eligible. Subjects must have platelet count, bleeding and platelet transfusion data available over a period of at least 4 weeks prior to randomization. Prior systemic treatment for malignancy, with the exception of hydroxyurea, ﻿must have been discontinued prior to entry into the study: at least 4 weeks before Day 1 for the following: chemotherapy, demethylating agents (azacitidine or decitabine), lenalidomide, thalidomide, clofarabine and IL11(oprelvekin); at least 8 weeks before Day 1 for antithymocyte/antilymphocyte globulin. Subjects with a prior stem cell transplant (SCT) must have relapsed after the SCT. Subjects must be stable and, in the opinion of the investigator, be expected to complete a 12 week treatment period. ECOG Status 02. Subject must be able to understand and comply with protocol requirements and instructions. Subject has signed and dated an informed consent form. Adequate baseline organ function defined by the criteria below: total bilirubin ≤ 1.5xULN except for Gilbert's syndrome or cases clearly not indicative of inadequate liver function (i.e. elevation of indirect (hemolytic) bilirubin in the absence of ALT abnormality), ALT ≤ 3xULN, creatinine ≤ 2.5xULN Women must be either of nonchild bearing potential or women with childbearing potential and men with reproductive potential must be willing to practice acceptable methods of birth control during the study Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 7 days prior to the first dose of study treatment. In France, a subject will be eligible for inclusion in this study only if either affiliated to, or a beneficiary of, a social security category. Subjects with MDS and an IPSS of low or intermediate1 risk at screening. Subjects with a diagnosis of acute promyelocytic or megakaryocytic leukemia or AML secondary to a myeloproliferative neoplasm. History of treatment with romiplostim or other TPOR agonists. Subjects with a QTc &gt;480 msec (QTc &gt;510 msec for subjects with Bundle Branch Block). Leukocytosis ≥25,000/uL on Day 1 of treatment with study medication. Subjects with known thrombophilic risk factors. Exception: Subjects for whom the potential benefits of participating in the study outweigh the potential risks of thromboembolic events, as determined by the investigator. Female subjects who are nursing or pregnant (positive serum or urine βhuman chorionic gonadotropin [βhCG] pregnancy test) at screening or predose on Day 1. Current alcohol or drug abuse. Treatment with an investigational drug within 30 days or 5 halflives (whichever is longer) preceding the first dose of study medication. Active and uncontrolled infections (e.g. sepsis, hepatitis B, hepatitis C). Subjects infected with Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV). Subjects with liver cirrhosis (as determined by the investigator). Subjects receiving or planned to receive any prohibited medication. Have a known immediate or delayed hypersensitivity reaction or idiosyncrasy to drugs chemically related to eltrombopag or excipient (microcrystalline cellulose, mannitol, polyvinylpyrrolidone, sodium starch glycolate, magnesium stearate, hypromellose, titanium dioxide, polyethylene glycol 400 and polysorbate 80) that contraindicates the subjects' participation. In France, subjects who have participated in any study using an investigational drug during the previous 30 days.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>110 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>