<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01440946</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the study is to evaluate the safety of Recombinant Human Coagulation Factor IX Fc Fusion Protein (rFIXFc) in previously treated pediatric subjects with hemophilia B. Secondary objectives of this study in this study population are as follows: to evaluate the efficacy of rFIXFc for prevention and treatment of bleeding episodes; to evaluate and assess the pharmacokinetics (PK) of rFIXFc; to evaluate rFIXFc consumption for prevention and treatment of bleeding episodes</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Recombinant Coagulation Factor IX Fc Fusion Protein, BIIB029, in Previously Treated Pediatric Participants With Hemophilia B</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>At the Baseline visit (28 ± 7 days prior to Day 1), participants receive a single IV injection of prestudy FIX over 10 (±5) minutes in the clinic under medical supervision at a dose of 50 IU/kg. A washout period with no FIX treatment is required prior to administration of prestudy FIX and prior to rFIXFc. A PK assessment is done with prestudy FIX and also done with rFIXFc on Day 1. After completing the PK assessments, participants begin weekly prophylactic treatment with rFIXFc for approximately 50 weeks, to obtain 50 EDs. One ED is defined as a 24-hour period in which a participant received 1 or more doses of rFIXFc, with the time of the first injection of rFIXFc defined as the start of the ED.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulin Fc Fragments</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Severe hemophilia B defined as ≤ 2 IU/dl (≤ 2%) endogenous FIX Male &lt; 12 years and weight ≥ 13 kg History of at least 50 documented prior exposure days to FIX No history of, or currently detectable, inhibitor Key Other coagulation disorders in addition to Hemophilia B History of anaphylaxis associated with any FIX or IV immunoglobulin administration NOTE: Other protocol defined Inclusion/ Exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>