<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01780805</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study involves completion of questionnaires, computer-based cognitive tasks and an alcohol drinking session. Participation in this study consists of an initial, in-person screening appointment, 4 brief daily appointments at the research office, an alcohol drinking session at a local bar and a follow-up appointment 1-3 days after the alcohol drinking session. Participants who are found to be eligible in the screening phase will then complete a daily appointment for 4 days out of a 5-day period (i.e., there will be 1 day out of the 5 on which they will not attend an appointment). Each appointment will last 20 minutes, on average and consist of a questionnaire and computer-based cognitive task. On the day of the fourth appointment, participants will complete an alcohol drinking session. The alcohol drinking session begins at 4pm and lasts until at least midnight. Participants in this study will be young adults between the ages of 21-25, who regularly drink alcohol and are not currently seeking treatment for alcohol use. Seventy-two participants will complete this study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Second Young Adult Naturalistic Alcohol Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alcohol Drinking</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Be between the ages of 2125. Be able to read English and complete study evaluations. Drink alcohol on a regular basis No participant may: Be seeking treatment for alcohol or other addictive behaviors or have been in inpatient or intensive outpatient treatment within the past 12 months. Provide two positive breath alcohol concentration (BAC) readings (i.e., &gt; 0.00%) at any of the following times: inperson screening, a presession screening, or at the outset of an alcohol selfadministration session. After participants blow their first positive BAC, they will be allowed to reschedule and participate at another time, however if they blow a second positive BAC, they will be excluded from this study and offered referrals for alcohol treatment. Have positive urine screen results at the inperson screening or presession screening on the day of an alcohol selfadministration session for opiates, cocaine, phencyclidine, amphetamines, methamphetamine, barbiturates, methadone or benzodiazepines. A woman who is pregnant, nursing, or refuses to use a reliable method of birth control. Fail to perform at a normative level at screening on any of the four cognitive and psychomotor tasks administered in this study. Participants must perform within two standard deviations of the mean from the samples in relevant prior studies Perform computer tasks initially administered at baseline in either a random or inordinately slow fashion A body mass index lower than 18.5 or greater than 35.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>