<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01780012</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Osteoporosis is a disease characterized by reduced bone mass and increased skeletal fragility, predisposing to an increased fracture risk. The presence of a low trauma fracture is a powerful predictor of future fractures and about 50% of patients with a fragility fracture will suffer a subsequent fracture in the next 10 years (Center Jacqueline R, 2007). Osteoporotic fractures are associated with an increased morbidity and mortality but also high financial costs. However, less than 20% of patients presenting a low trauma fracture receive an appropriate post-fracture osteoporosis management (Little and Eccles, 2010). The hypothesis of a lack of information and an under assessment of consequences by both patients and physicians has been raised to explain this gap between recommended care and usual practices. The aim of the PREVOST program is to assess the efficiency of patient-centered osteoporosis prevention program, after a fragility fracture of the upper limb, to improve post-fracture management of osteoporosis (ie BMD test and / or osteoporosis treatment) in women over 50 years old. This open randomized controlled trial aims to compare the BMD or osteoporosis treatment prescription rate at 6 months after inclusion between two groups: "intervention" receiving information on fracture and osteoporosis (oral and written), phone call reminders and written information to give to their family physician, and "control" receiving usual care without information.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of an Osteoporosis Prevention Strategy in Women With Osteoporotic Fracture of the Upper Limb</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporotic Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women aged over 50 years with a fragility fracture of wrist or humerus that occurred in the past 6 months treated in an emergency department or orthopedic department who signed the consent form no signed consent previous history of femoral neck fracture polytrauma or accident patients under osteoporosis treatment patients who performed a BMD test in the past 6 months patients with severe renal impairment, hyperthyroidism, bone primary or secondary malignancy. legal disability difficulty in understanding French psychiatric disorder</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>osteoporosis</keyword>
	<keyword>fragility fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>secondary prevention</keyword>
</DOC>