<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01060514</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the highest dose of Vinorelbine and Pazopanib that can be given together without causing severe side effects. Also, this study will evaluate what effects (good and bad) that the treatment has on patients and their cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pazopanib + Vinorelbine in Non Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC) and Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study involves an investigational drug called pazopanib in combination with the chemotherapy drug vinorelbine. An investigational drug is a drug that has not been approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for use in the United States. Vinorelbine has been FDA approved to treat patients with NSCLC and breast cancer. Pazopanib is a vascular endothelial growth factor inhibitor, which means it may prevent the tumor from growing its own blood vessels thereby interfering with the growth of the tumor. Participants in this study will be assigned to one of three groups with each group receiving a higher dose of vinorelbine and pazopanib than the previous group. Vinorelbine will be given through a needle in the vein on days 1 and 8 of each 21 day study treatment cycle. Pazopanib is a pill which will be taken by mouth every day during the 21 day study treatment cycle.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vinorelbine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vinblastine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt; 18 years Patients must have diagnosis of breast cancer or non small cell lung cancer Patients must have evaluable disease Women of childbearing potential and sexually active males must commit to the use of effective contraception while on study. Patients must have given signed, informed consent prior to registration on study. Patients must not be pregnant and/or lactating. Patients must not be receiving any other investigational agents. No prior exposure to vinorelbine or other VEGF inhibitors as treatment for metastatic disease Patients must not have received prior therapy (including radiation, surgery, and/or chemotherapy) within 30 days History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition to pazopanib or vinorelbine. Patients cannot have received more than 2 prior chemotherapy regimens for lung cancer or 3 prior chemotherapy regimens for breast cancer. This criterion can be discussed further with the study doctor. Must not have uncontrolled illness including, but not limited to: ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmic, psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>