<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01294241</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare intra-individually the efficacy and tolerance of Sericare® versus standard treatment in accelerating the epithelialization of skin lesions of patients with Epidermolysis bullosa hereditaria.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Case Series Documentation of Patients With Epidermolysis Bullosa</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The design of the trial is a case-series documentation of each individual patient involved in the trial, and an assessment of the treatment for each patient without the need for comparison and statistical analysis of different groups of patients. A comparison of the Sericare® treated Epidermolysis Bullosa (EB) wounds with the untreated part of the same wound will enable independent experts to assess the outcome of the treatment. Objective methods will be applied to evaluate the wound healing progress, i.e., the grade of epithelialization of the wound.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Epidermolysis Bullosa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients aged 195 years who have provided written informed consent. In case of minor patients, written informed consent of parents or legal representatives is available. EB Patients with at least one skin lesion between 10 and 200 cm2. prepared and comply with all trial requirements, including the following: Application of Sericare on one half of the wound at every change of wound dressing; Regular clinic visits during the treatment period and followup period (14 days for disease with recent wounds or 28 days for disease with delayed wound healing after the start of the treatment). Negative pregnancy test of women of childbearing potential performed within 7 days prior to the start of treatment. Women of childbearing potential must agree to use an effective method of contraception (PearlIndex &lt; 1, e.g. hormonal contraception including the combined oral contraceptive pill, the transdermal patch, and the contraceptive vaginal ring, intrauterine devices or sterilization) during treatment and for at least 6 months thereafter. Men of procreative capacity must agree to use an effective method of contraception during treatment and for at least 6 months thereafter. received treatment with systemic steroids during the last 30 days; uncontrolled diabetes or diabetic ulcers; diseases or conditions that could, in the opinion of the investigator, interfere with the assessment of safety, tolerance or efficacy; a skin disorder that is chronic or currently active and which the Investigator considers will adversely affect the healing of the recent wounds or involves the areas to be examined in this caseseries documentation; a history of clinically significant hypersensitivity to the trial medication or surgical dressings to be used in this caseseries documentation; known multiple allergic disorders; taking, or have taken, any investigational drugs within 3 months prior to the screening visit; undergoing investigations or changes in management for an existing medical condition; not likely to complete the caseseries documentation for whatever reason.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>95 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Epidermolysis bullosa</keyword>
	<keyword>Wound healing</keyword>
	<keyword>Epithelialization</keyword>
</DOC>