<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00492661</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this trial is to investigate whether a combined dietary and exercise intervention, added to standard care, reduces the expected frequency of insulin resistance in renal (kidney) transplant recipients on tacrolimus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pilot Trial to Evaluate the Effect of Diet and Exercise in Renal Transplant Recipients on Tacrolimus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label (all people know the identity of the intervention), prospective (study following participants forward in time), single-arm, multi-center (conducted in more than 1 center), interventional pilot study of the effects of a combined dietary and exercise intervention on glucose metabolism. The duration of this study will be 6 months and will include following visits: Baseline, Week 4, Week 12, and Week 24. Dietary compliance will be evaluated with a 3-day food record and during weekly telephone conversations and face-to-face visits with a dietician. Exercise compliance will be measured using an exercise log presented to the co-ordinator at the end of each month. Primarily, participants with insulin resistance will be assessed by Homeostasis Model Assessment-Insulin Resistance (HOMA-IR) of greater than 1 at 6 months. Participants' safety and tolerability will be monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants who has sufficiently recovered from surgery to tolerate an intensive exercise evaluation Participants who have received a livingdonor or cadaveric (from dead donor) renal transplant Participants who has been initiated tacrolimus as firstline immunosuppressive agent Participants who has given informed consent forms Participants with significant disease or disability that prevents taking part in a diet or exercise regime (e.g. cardiac instability, including unstable angina [chest pain due to decreased oxygen being supplied to the heart] and/or other unstable disease, severe cognitive [mental functioning] impairment) Participants with significant postsurgical complications that prevent participation in the exercise component of the study (e.g. wound dehiscence [pathologic process consisting of a partial or complete disruption of the layers of a surgical wound] or infection) Participants with contraindications to maximal exercise testing or highintensity progressive resistance training (e.g. proliferative diabetic or hypertensive retinopathy, unrepaired aneurysm, critical aortic stenosis, recurrent symptomatic hernias, New York Heart Association (NYHA) classIV congestive heart failure) Participants with nonambulatory (mobility) status Participants who require ongoing systemic immunosuppressive therapy for an indication other than renal transplant and this therapy is higher than that required for their kidney disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tacrolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>Prograf</keyword>
	<keyword>PRIDE</keyword>
</DOC>