<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01893788</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to determine which treatment will be more effective to reduce left ventricular mass in hypertensive patients with left ventricular hypertrophy comparing aliskiren and eplerenone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Eplerenone and Aliskiren Research Targeting Hypertensive Patients With Left Ventricular Hypertrophy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertrophy, Left Ventricular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eplerenone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spironolactone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female ≧ 20 years of age Clinical diagnosis of hypertension Patients who are able to provide written informed consent 1. History of congestive heart failure, myocardial infarction, or coronary revascularization in the recent 6 months. 2. Planned to taking percutaneous coronary intervention and coronary artery bypass graft 3. Severe hypertension (≧ 180/110 mmHg) or secondary hypertension or malignant hypertension. 4. History of stroke, cerebral hemorrhage, subarachnoid hemorrhage, transient ischemic attack in the recent 6 months 5. Severe valvular heart disease or atrial fibrillation 6. Congenital heart disease 7. Severe heart failure (NYHA functional class Ⅳ) 8. Current treatment with aliskiren or eplerenone or diuretics 9. Taking potassium preparation or potassiumsparing diuretic 10. Estimated GFR ≦ 30ml/min/1.73m２ at screening or current treatment with hemodialysis 11. Potassium &gt; 5.0mEq/L at screening 12. Diabetes mellitus with microalbuminuria or albuminuria 13. Impairment of liver function (liver failure, liver cirrhosis) 14. Pregnant woman or possibly pregnant woman 15. History of malignant tumor include hematological neoplasm 16. Current treatment with itraconazole, cyclosporin, ritonavir or nelfinavir 17. Prior treatment with, hypersensitivity to, intolerance of or contraindication to aliskiren and/or eplerenone 18. Current participation in another clinical trial 19. Serious noncardiovascular disease severely limiting life expectancy 20. Contraindication to MRI</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>left ventricular hypertrophy</keyword>
	<keyword>renin angiotensin system</keyword>
	<keyword>aldosterone</keyword>
	<keyword>aliskiren</keyword>
	<keyword>eplerenone</keyword>
	<keyword>P3NP</keyword>
</DOC>