<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01893840</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A study to assess the effect of negative pulsating pressure therapy on patients with impaired blood flow to the leg caused by arterial disease, to see if the FlowOx device will increase the blood flow to the leg in these patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect on Blood Flow Using the FlowOx™ Device in Patients With Reduced Peripheral Circulation in the Lower Leg</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arterial Occlusive Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written Informed Consent Age 3090 years Affected foot/shoe sise less than 46 (approximate foot length less than 29.5 cm) Patients with Peripheral Arterial Occlusive Disease (PAOD) grade 2,3 or 4, i.e.: 1. Clinically verified grade 2, i.e. Intermittent Claudication: AncleBrachial Index (ABI)less than 0.9 or Toe brachial Index (TBI) less than 0.7 or Ultrasound and/or CT/Magnetic Resonance (MR) angiography suggesting stenosis(es)and/or occlusion(s) 2. Clinically verified grade 3, i.e. Critical Limb Ischemia (CLI): ABI less than 0.4 or Toe pressure less than 30 mmHg Rest pain since at least 2 weeks or Use of analgesics for rest pain for at least 2 weeks or Ultrasound and/or CT/Magnetic Resonance (MR) angiography suggesting stenosis(es)and/or occlusion(s) 3. Clinically verified grade 4, i.e. CLI: Ischemic ulcers or gangrene/tissue loss ABI less than 0.4 Toe pressure less than 30 mmHg Rest pain since at least 2 weeks or Use of analgesics for rest pain for at least 2 weeks or Ultrasound and/or CT/MR angiography suggesting stenosis(es)and/or occlusion(s) Grade 1 PAOD Incapable of consenting voluntarily Fewer higher than 39 degrees Centigrade Severe Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) Severe heart disease such as unstable angina, severe heart failure and severe valve failure Severe Polyneurophathy Verified Osteomyelitis other than in the Phanlanx Currently treated for cancer and With a life expectancy of less than 2 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>