<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01385709</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to determine whether blood levels of lithium or sertraline are affected by different phases of the menstrual cycle and whether there is an effect on psychiatric symptoms. Subjects are seen for two visits: one visit during the luteal phase and one visit during the follicular phase of the menstrual cycle. On each visit, they will fill out a depression, anxiety and mania rating scale. Also at each visit a 20mL blood sample will be drawn to measure progesterone level and either a lithium or sertraline level, depending on which medication the patient takes. The primary hypothesis in this study is that blood levels of lithium and sertraline will be significantly lower in women during the luteal phase of the menstrual cycle than during the follicular phase. Examination will also be made of whether symptoms will increase in severity during the luteal phase as compared to the follicular phase. The investigators expect a negative linear association between symptom severity and blood level, i.e. expect symptom severity to worsen as blood levels of lithium or sertraline decrease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Influence of the Menstrual Cycle on Lithium and Sertraline Blood Levels</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Behavior</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Panic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mood Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phobic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Genetic Diseases, X-Linked</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dysthymic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Premenstrual Dysphoric Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclothymic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lithium Carbonate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sertraline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1840 year old female women currently taking Lithium or Sertraline currently pregnant or breastfeeding concurrent use of any form of hormonal birth control, including oral contraceptive pills, Norplant or Depoprovera hepatic or renal disease irregular menstrual cycles.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lithium</keyword>
	<keyword>Sertraline</keyword>
</DOC>