<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02744768</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims at exploring the activity of a frontline approach based on dasatinib plus steroids administration as induction treatment, followed by the infusion of Blinatumomab, in adult Ph+ ALL.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>D-ALBA Frontline Sequential Dasatinib and Blinatumomab in Adult Philadelphia Positive Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Blinatumomab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dasatinib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Bispecific</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Newly diagnosed adult Bprecursor Ph+ ALL patients. Age greater or equal to18 years, Signed written informed consent according to ICH/EU/GCP and national local laws. ECOG Performance Status 0 or 1 and/or WHO performance status less or equal to 2. Renal and hepatic function as defined below: AST (GOT), ALT (GPT), and AP &lt;2 x upper limit of normal (ULN). Total bilirubin &lt;1.5 x ULN. Creatinine clearance equal or greater than 50 mL/min. Pancreatic function as defined below: Serum amylase less or equal to 1.5 x ULN Serum lipase less or equal to1.5 x ULN. Normal cardiac function. Negative HIV test, negative HBV DNA and HCV RNA. Negative pregnancy test in women of childbearing potential. Bone marrow specimen from primary diagnosis available. History of or current relevant CNS pathology (current ≥grade 2 epilepsy, seizure, paresis, aphasia, clinically relevant apoplexia, severe brain injuries, dementia, Parkinson's disease, organic brain syndrome, psychosis). Impaired cardiac function, including any one of the following: LVEF &lt;45% as determined by MUGA scan or echocardiogram. Complete left bundle branch block. Use of a cardiac pacemaker. ST depression of &gt;1mm in 2 or more leads and/or T wave inversions in 2 or more contiguous leads. Congenital long QT syndrome. History of or presence of significant ventricular or atrial arrhythmia. Clinically significant resting bradycardia (&lt;50 beats per minute). QTc &gt;450 msec on screening ECG (using the QTcF formula). Right bundle branch block plus left anterior hemiblock, bifascicular block. Myocardial infarction within 3 months prior to starting Dasatinib. Angina pectoris. Other clinically significant heart disease (e.g., congestive heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, history of labile hypertension, or history of poor compliance with an antihypertensive regimen). Impairment of gastrointestinal (GI) function or GI disease that may significantly alter the absorption of Dasatinib (e.g., ulcerative diseases, uncontrolled nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, malabsorption syndrome, or small bowel resection). History of or current autoimmune disease. Systemic cancer chemotherapy within 2 weeks prior to study. Known hypersensitivity to immunoglobulins or to any other component of the study drug formulation. Active malignancy other than ALL with the exception of basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, or carcinoma "in situ" of the cervix. Active infection, any other concurrent disease or medical conditions that are deemed to interfere with the conduct of the study as judged by the investigator. Nursing women or women of childbearing potential not willing to use an effective form of contraception during participation in the study and at least 3 months thereafter or male patients not willing to ensure effective contraception during participation in the study and at least three months thereafter.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia, adult, dasatinib, blinatumomab</keyword>
</DOC>