<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02744287</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this protocol, patients with non-resectable pancreatic cancer will have autologous T cells collected via apheresis and genetically modified using a retrovirus to express the anti-PSCA Chimeric Antigen Receptor (CAR). The T cells will be reinfused according to a dose-finding schedule after the subject has been identified as having adequate lymphopenia to provide for homeostatic expansion of the adoptively transferred, engineered T cell therapeutic product.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prostate Stem Cell Antigen (PSCA)-Specific CAR T Cells In Subjects With Non-Resectable Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase I, single center, open-label, non-randomized, feasibility, safety and dose-finding study. The purpose of the clinical trial is to determine the safety of the administration of the anti-PSCA CAR T cells (BPX-601) in subjects with non-resectable pancreatic adenocarcinoma, followed by the evaluation of the safety of the rimiducid infusion after BPX-601 administration, and the persistence of the CAR-T cells over time after a single rimiducid infusion.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the pancreas with nonresectable disease. Subjects with mixed histology may be included if the predominant component is adenocarcinoma. Tumor with positive PSCA expression. Failed standard therapy (chemotherapy or surgery) or investigational therapy for non resectable disease, or have documented refusal of standard treatments. Tumor must be evaluable by CT scan (or MRI, if subject is allergic to CT contrast media). Age ≥ 18 years. If a female subject is of childbearing potential, she must have a negative serum pregnancy test documented prior to administration of BPX601. If sexually active, the subject must agree to use contraception considered adequate and appropriate by the Investigator for 3 months after administration of BPX601. Life expectancy &gt;12 weeks. Signed informed consent. Performance status: Karnofsky score &gt; 60%. Subjects must have adequate venous access for apheresis or agree to use of central line for apheresis collection. Subject has adequate organ function as measured by: 1. Cardiac: left ventricular ejection fraction at rest must be ≥ lower limit of institutional normal. 2. Hematologic: i) White Blood Cell (WBC) ≥ 2,000/μl, ii) Absolute Neutrophil Count (ANC) ≥ 1,000/μl, iii) Platelets ≥ 50 x 10^3/μl, iv) Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL. 3. Hepatic: direct bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal, or aspartate aminotransferase (AST)/alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤ 2.5 x upper limit of normal. 4. Renal: creatinine ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal. 5. Pulmonary: forced expiratory volume (FEV) 1, forced vital capacity (FVC), diffusing capacity of lung for carbon monoxide (DLCO) ≥ 50% predicted (corrected for hemoglobin). Subjects with islet cell neoplasms. Participation in any investigational drug study &lt; 28 days prior to BPX601 infusion. Chemotherapy or immunotherapy &lt; 2 weeks prior to BPX601, other than salvage/lymphodepletion chemotherapy. Active autoimmune disease requiring immunosuppressive therapy &lt; 4 weeks prior to screening. Treatment with systemic high dose prednisone of ≥ 0.5mg/kg/day or its equivalents and within 7 halflives of the prescribed corticosteroid prior to the date of leukapheresis for BPX601 infusion. Uncontrolled bacterial, viral or fungal infection, or any medical condition determined by the Investigator to be a risk for enrolling on the protocol. Known HIV, hepatitis B virus (HBV),hepatitis C virus (HCV) positivity or subject not meeting the selection criteria as defined for the Foundation for the Accreditation of Cell Therapy (FACT) and American Association of Blood Banks (AABB). Positive serum or urine β human chorionic gonadotropin (HCG) test or breastfeeding. Fertile men or women unwilling to use effective forms of birth control or abstinence for 3 months after BPX601 administration. Bovine product allergy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non Resectable Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>BPX-601</keyword>
	<keyword>AP1903</keyword>
	<keyword>CAR T</keyword>
	<keyword>PSCA-CAR</keyword>
</DOC>