<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02255760</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose escalation study evaluating the safety and tolerability of a single ascending IV dose of MEDI3902 in healthy adult subjects 18 to 60 years of age.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 1 Randomized Double-blind Placebo Controlled Study to Evaluate Safety and PK of MEDI3902 in Healthy Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 1, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose escalation study evaluating the safety and tolerability of a single ascending IV dose of MEDI3902 in healthy adult subjects 18 to 60 years of age. Approximately 40 subjects will be enrolled across 4 fixed dose cohorts at 1 study site. This study will last approximately 90 days, constituting a screening period of up to 28 days, 1 day of investigational product administration, and a 60 day safety follow up period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 18 through 60 years at the time of screening 2. Written informed consent 3. Weight ≥ 45 kg and ≤ 110 kg at screening 4. Healthy by medical history, physical examination, and baseline safety laboratory studies 5. Systolic blood pressure (BP) &lt; 140 mm Hg and diastolic BP &lt; 90 mm Hg at screening 6. Electrocardiogram (ECG) without clinically significant abnormalities at screening 7. Able to complete the followup period through Day 61 as required by the protocol 1. Acute (timelimited) illness, including fever 99.5F, on day prior to or day of planned dosing 2. Any drug therapy within 7 days prior to Day 1 (except contraceptives or a single use of acetaminophen, aspirin, antihistamine, or combination overthecounter (OTC) product that contains acetaminophen with an antihistamine, or OTC nonsteroidal anti inflammatory agent at a dose equal to or lower than that recommended on the package). Vitamins and other nutritional supplements that are not newly introduced, ie, have been taken for at least 30 days prior to enrollment, are not exclusionary 3. Blood drawn in excess of a total of 450 mL (1 unit) for any reason within 2 months prior to screening 4. Receipt of immunoglobulin or blood products within 6 months prior to screening 5. Receipt of any investigational product in the preceding 90 days or expected receipt of investigational product during the period of study followup, or concurrent participation in another interventional study Receipt of any vaccine within 7 days prior to investigational product dosing or planned receipt within 61 days after investigational product dosing except for influenza vaccine administered at least 28 days after dosing 6. Previous receipt of a mAb 7. Immunodeficiency due to illness, including human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, or due to drugs, including any course of glucocorticoid therapy exceeding 2 weeks of prednisone or equivalent at a dose of 20 mg daily or every other day within 6 months prior to screening. HIV testing must be negative at screening 8. History of allergic disease or reactions likely to be exacerbated by any component of the investigational product 9. Either history of active infection with hepatitis B or C 10. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST), alanine aminotransferase (ALT), or serum creatinine above the upper limit of normal (ULN) or hemoglobin, white blood cell count, or platelet count below the lower limit of normal at screening and in the predose blood sample 11. Pregnant or nursing mother 13. History of alcohol or drug abuse within the past 2 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>MEDI3902, Safety, Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
</DOC>