<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02255552</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to provide confirmatory evidence of efficacy of eteplirsen (AVI-4658) in Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD) patients that are amenable to skipping exon 51. Additional objectives include evaluation of safety, biomarkers and the long-term effects of eteplirsen up to 96 weeks, followed by a safety extension (not to exceed 48 weeks). Sites are currently being initiated into the study. Initiation of approximately 39 planned sites in the United States is expected to be completed by June 2016. The initiated sites can be found in the "Contacts and Locations" section of this posting in addition to a listing of the city and states of sites the investigators are working to initiate. This information will be updated on a rolling basis as additional sites are initiated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Confirmatory Study of Eteplirsen in DMD Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label, multi-center, 96-week study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of eteplirsen in patients with genotypically confirmed Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD) with genetic deletions amenable to exon 51 skipping (treated group), with a concurrent control arm of DMD patients not amenable to exon 51 skipping (untreated group). Following primary efficacy endpoints at week 48, dosing will continue to week 96 to evaluate the long term effects of eteplirsen. Patients in the treated group will receive once weekly intravenous (IV) infusions of 30 mg/kg Eteplirsen. Patients in the untreated group will not receive treatment. Clinical efficacy will be assessed at regularly scheduled study visits, including functional tests such as the six minute walk test. Patients in the treated group will undergo a muscle biopsy at Baseline and a second muscle biopsy over the course of the study. Patients in the untreated group will not undergo muscle biopsy. Safety, including adverse event monitoring and routine laboratory assessments, will be continuously monitored for all patients. The sponsor is working to initiate approximately 39 sites across the United States. Sites will vary in the following functions: 1. Local Site (N=39) - Enrolls patients and is the primary contact point for their patients. Sites will perform all protocol activities (including dosing and laboratory assessments), except for functional assessments and biopsies. 2. Hub Site (N=14) - Performs functional (physical) assessments at specified times per protocol. 3. Surgical Site (N=2) - Performs muscle biopsies for the Treated group.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Muscular Dystrophies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Muscular Dystrophy, Duchenne</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male 716 years old Diagnosed with DMD, genotypically confirmed Stable dose of corticosteroids for at least 24 weeks Have intact right and left alternative upper muscle groups Mean 6MWT greater than 300m (primary analysis on 300 to 450 meters) Stable pulmonary and cardiac function: predicted FVC equal to or greater than 50% and LVEF of greater than 50% Previous treatment with drisapersen or any other RNA antisense agent or any gene therapy within the last 6 months Participation in any other DMD interventional clinical study within 12 weeks Major surgery within 3 months Presence of other clinically significant illness Major change in the physical therapy regime within 3 months Other inclusion/exclusion criteria apply.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>DMD, Duchenne, Eteplirsen, dystrophy, dystrophin, exon 51</keyword>
</DOC>