<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02255422</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Mitochondrial myopathies are a multisystemic group of disorders that are characterized by a wide range of biochemical and genetic mitochondrial defects and variable modes of inheritance. Currently there are no effective treatments for this disease. Despite the heterogeneous myopathy phenotypes, a unifying feature of mitochondrial myopathies is that the pathogenic mtDNA mutations and/or nuclear mutations of the electron transport chain invariably lead to dysfunctional mitochondrial respiration. This reduction in mitochondrial respiration leads to a reduced ability to produce cellular adenosine triphosphate (ATP), often resulting in muscle weakness, exercise intolerance, and fatigue in patients with mitochondrial myopathies. RTA 408 is a potent activator of Nrf2 and inhibitor of NF κB (nuclear factor kappa-light-chain-enhancer of activated B cells), and thus induces an antioxidant and anti-inflammatory phenotype. Several lines of evidence suggest that Nrf2 activation can increase mitochondrial respiration and biogenesis. Collectively, available data suggest that the ability of RTA 408 to activate Nrf2 and induce its target genes could potentially improve muscle function, oxidative phosphorylation, antioxidant capacity, and mitochondrial biogenesis in patients with mitochondrial myopathies. Part 1: The first part of this study will be a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, dose-escalation study to evaluate the safety of omaveloxolone (RTA 408) at various doses in patients with mitochondrial myopathies. Part 2: The second part of this study is a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, parallel study to evaluate the safety, efficacy, and pharmacodynamics of up to 2 dose levels of omaveloxolone (RTA 408) in patients with mitochondrial myopathies. Eligible patients in Part 2 will be randomized 1:1:1 to receive omaveloxolone (RTA 408) (at one of 2 doses chosen from Part 1), or placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>RTA 408 Capsules in Patients With Mitochondrial Myopathy - MOTOR</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Muscular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitochondrial Myopathies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Have mitochondrial myopathy as evidenced by the following 2 criteria (must meet both): 1. Have a history of exercise intolerance with or without weakness and/or progressive exercise intolerance (in which modest exercise typically provokes heaviness, weakness, aching of active muscles, or tachycardia) 2. Have a known primary mitochondrial DNA mutation or a nuclear DNA defect that is associated with reduced activity of at least 1 mitochondrially encoded respiratory chain complex 2. Be male or female and ≥18 years of age and ≤75 years of age 3. Have no changes to exercise regimen within 30 days prior to Study Day 1 and be willing to remain on the same exercise regimen during the 16week study period 4. Have the ability to complete maximal exercise testing 5. Have a peak workload during maximal exercise testing of ≤ 1.5 W/kg 6. Be able to swallow capsules 1. Have uncontrolled diabetes (HbA1c &gt;11.0%) 2. Have Btype natriuretic peptide level &gt;200 pg/mL 3. Have a history of clinically significant leftsided heart disease and/or clinically significant cardiac disease 4. Have known active fungal, bacterial, and/or viral infection, including human immunodeficiency virus or hepatitis virus (B or C) 5. Have known or suspected active drug or alcohol abuse 6. Have clinically significant abnormalities of clinical hematology or biochemistry, including but not limited to elevations greater than 1.5 times the upper limit of normal of aspartate aminotransferase, alanine aminotransferase, or creatinine 7. Have any abnormal laboratory test value or serious preexisting medical condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would put the patient at risk by study enrollment 8. Have taken any of the following drugs within 7 days prior to Study Day 1 or plan to take any of these drugs during the time of study participation: 1. Sensitive substrates for cytochrome P450 2C8 or 3A4 (e.g., repaglinide, midazolam, sildenafil) 2. Substrates for pglycoprotein transporter (e.g., ambrisentan, digoxin) 9. Have participated in any other interventional clinical study within 30 days prior to Study Day 1 10. Have a cognitive impairment that may preclude ability to comply with study procedures</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>omaveloxolone</keyword>
	<keyword>RTA 408 capsules</keyword>
	<keyword>mitochondrial myopathies</keyword>
</DOC>