<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02952209</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to assess the effects of Alveolar Ridge Preservation (ARP) after tooth extraction compared to extraction alone in the posterior maxilla. The results of this study will demonstrate if the use of ARP reduces alveolar ridge resorption at 6 months post extraction in the posterior maxilla region.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Alveolar Ridge Preservation After Tooth Extraction in the Posterior Maxilla</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Fifteen subjects requiring extraction of one posterior tooth in the right maxilla and one posterior tooth in the left maxilla will be considered for enrollment. Subjects who meet the inclusion and exclusion criteria will be randomized to receive alveolar ridge preservation on one side of the maxilla and only an extraction on the other side of the maxilla. Extraction of the failing teeth will be performed atraumatically; a mucoperiosteal flap will not be employed. After removal of the tooth, the alveolus will be meticulously debrided and cleaned. In the test site, the socket will be filled with xenograft and a collagen membrane. In the control site, no graft material or collagen membrane will be used. Clinical measurements, standardized peri-apical radiographs and Cone Beam Computed Tomography scans will be performed immediately following tooth extractions (visit 2) and 6 months (visit 4) after extractions. Subjects will be examined over the course of 6 months. Investigators will be trained prior to participating in the study. Training will be undertaken during a site initiation visit and will include a detailed description of all study procedures including treatment methods, and measurement methods to obtain study endpoints.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Subjects must voluntarily sign the informed consent form. 2. Subjects must be male or female who are at least 2070 years of age. 3. Subjects must be able and willing to follow study procedures and instructions. 4. Presence of one posterior tooth in the right maxilla and one posterior tooth in the left maxilla that require extraction (ADA tooth positions 24 and 1315). The same type of tooth should be in booth side, either two molars or two premolars. 5. Teeth extractions of one posterior tooth in the right maxilla and one posterior tooth in the left maxilla must be completed successfully (ADA tooth positions 24 and 1315). 6. If present, teeth adjacent to the teeth slated for extraction must be healthy. Healthy teeth are defined as asymptomatic teeth without periapical lesions. 1. Female subjects who are pregnant or lactating, or who intend to become pregnant during the study period following entrance into the study. 2. Subjects who have failed to maintain good plaque control. 3. Subjects with any systemic condition such as uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, cancer, HIV, disorders that compromise wound healing, chronic high dose steroid therapy, intravenous and oral bisphosphonate therapy, bone metabolic diseases, history of irradiation of the head and neck area, or any other immunosuppressive therapy that would contraindicate oral surgical treatment. 4. Subjects who report allergy or hypersensitivity to any of the products (collagen membrane and ABBM) used throughout the study. 5. Presence of ≥3 mm of vertical loss of the buccal bone in relation to the palatal wall. 6. Subjects with untreated periodontitis. 7. Presence of acute dentoalveolar infections in the teeth slated for extraction. 8. Subjects who are heavy smokers (defined as &gt;10 cigarettes per day or &gt;1 cigar per day) or chew tobacco, including within 3 months prior to enrollment. 9. Subjects with conditions or circumstances, in the opinion of the investigator, which would prevent completion of study participation or interfere with analysis of study results, such as history of non compliance or unreliability</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alveolar Ridge Preservation</keyword>
	<keyword>Xenograft bone graft</keyword>
	<keyword>Collagen membrane</keyword>
</DOC>