<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02952885</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Acromegaly is a rare, chronic, and debilitating disease, usually caused by a benign tumor on the pituitary gland, which leads to excessive production of growth hormone (GH). GH excess in turn causes overproduction of another hormone called insulin-like growth factor-1 (IGF-1). IGF-1 levels are currently the most widely accepted measure of disease activity. In Canada, medical therapy with a type of medicine called "somatostatin analogues" (SSA), such as octreotide and lanreotide, is recommended for treatment of acromegaly. However, studies have shown that a significant number of patients who take SSA medications alone remain with elevated levels of IGF-1 in their blood. Another medication that is used to treat acromegaly is pegvisomant (PEGV), and the investigators plan to study whether strict control of IGF-1, by adding or optimizing the use of PEGV, results in a significant health benefits to patients who still have modestly high levels of IGF-1 in their blood.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Strict IGF-1 Control in Acromegaly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Acromegaly</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients (at least 18 years old) with confirmed acromegaly who have been on a stable dose of SSA monotherapy, or combination therapy with suboptimal dose of pegvisomant for at least 6 months and whose IGFI levels are persistently but modestly (1.0 ULN&lt; [IGF1 serum level] &gt; 1.3 ULN) elevated will be included. Visual field loss or optic chiasmal compression or pituitary tumors within 3 mm from the chiasm will not be included Cranial nerve palsies or intracranial hypertension requiring tumour decompression surgery Clinically significant hepatic disease and/or elevated liver enzymes (ALT, AST &gt; 3 x ULN) Patients who have received pituitary surgery within one year prior to screening visit Patients who have received radiation therapy within one year prior to screening visit History of hypersensitivity to any components of Pegvisomant Inability to fully comprehend the nature of the study or cooperate with study procedures Pregnant / lactating women and subjects refusing to use adequate contraception to prevent pregnancy during the study. Subjects unwilling or unable to selfadminister medication on a daily basis Known or suspected alcohol / drug abuse Severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory abnormality that could increase the risk associated with trial participation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>