<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02952768</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Ultrasound is a frequently used diagnostic tool in the emergency department and suggested to have a role during resuscitation. The aims of this study were to develop a novel, resuscitative ultrasound-circulation-airway-breathing (US-C-A-B) protocol, to implement a short curriculum and to assess the feasibility. The US-C-A-B protocol was built in an advanced life support-compliant manner. It involved a 3-part assessment: (1) C: subxiphoid 4-chamber view of the heart; (2) A: tracheal ultrasound; and (3) B: bilateral lung sliding. It could be used for direct confirmation for the C-A-B and searching the possible cause of cardiac arrest. A half-day curriculum was designed, and comprised of one-hour didactics and 3-hour small-group hand-on training. Assessments were performed, including a written test, the US image acquisition and a satisfaction survey. From August 1, 2014 to March 31, 2016, the multi-center emergency physicians who attended the US-C-A-B curricula were enrolled prospectively.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Novel US-C-A-B Protocol: Curriculum Implementation and Evaluation of Proficiency</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Ultrasound is a frequently used diagnostic tool in the emergency department and suggested to have a role during resuscitation. The aims of this study were to develop a novel, resuscitative ultrasound-circulation-airway-breathing (US-C-A-B) protocol, to implement a short curriculum and to assess the feasibility. The US-C-A-B protocol was built in an advanced life support-compliant manner. It involved a 3-part assessment: (1) C: subxiphoid 4-chamber view of the heart; (2) A: tracheal ultrasound; and (3) B: bilateral lung sliding. It could be used for direct confirmation for the C-A-B and searching the possible cause of</detailed_description>
	<criteria>The enrolled participants were emergency physicians of the National Taiwan University Hospital (NTUH), the FarEastern Memorial Hospital (FEMH) and the ChangKung Memorial Hospital (CKMH), three teaching hospitals in Taiwan. Not emergency physicians.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>