<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02952430</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients aged over 65 comprise more than half the emergency general surgical workload, however, available risk-prediction tools for such patients are extrapolated from younger cohorts. Research suggests that high pre-operative frailty scores correlate with increased post-operative mortality and morbidity. Validated frailty assessments may help identify high risk older emergency surgical patients, facilitating decision-making and informing patient choice. We propose the first prospective UK observational study assessing frailty as an independent predictor of outcome in the older surgical patient undergoing emergency laparotomy. Prospective data collection of patients over 65 undergoing emergency laparotomy will be performed in 20 NHS Trusts. Pre-operative frailty scores will be evaluated using the Rockwood Frailty Scale. Primary outcome measure is 30-day mortality. Secondary outcome measures are post-operative complications, altered independence status and length of stay. Results will be disseminated at national/international surgical meetings and published in a peer-reviewed journal.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Emergency Laparotomy and Frailty Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The ELF steering committee will run this project as part of the North West Research Collaborative(NWRC), consisting of surgical trainees with a successful record of publishing credible research and establishing clinical trials. Following ethical approval, data will be collected from NHS Trusts throughout the UK. Trained leads will facilitate data collection adhering to a study protocol and local clinical governance. Patients over 65 undergoing emergency laparotomy will be identified prospectively over 3 months. Demographics, time to surgical intervention, length of stay(LOS), pre- and post-admission independence, intermediate care stay, Clavien-Dindo post-operative complications, 30-day mortality and 30-day re-admission data will be collected on a secure database. Pre-operative frailty will be assessed using the Rockwood Frailty Scale. 500 patients are required for a statistically significant difference in primary outcome (30 day mortality). Secondary outcome measures are complications, change in independence status and LOS. Outcomes will be analysed to compare the impact of frailty.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients aged 65 years and older Admitted to emergency surgical departments Requiring an emergency laparotomy Patients less than 65 years old</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>