<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02952326</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Comparing the postoperative flare ups and pain after adding the XP Endo Finisher to the final irrigation protocol on necrotic mandibular premolars.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparing Between XP Endo Finisher and Conventional Irrigation Method On Post-Operative Flare Ups In Necrotic Teeth</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>patients are randomized into 2 groups after meeting the eligibility criteria, 1. Each patient will be given pain scale chart in order to record his /her pain level before any intervention. 2. The tooth is anesthetized, accessed and mechanical instrumentation to be made 3 A) For the experimental group: The canals will be thoroughly irrigated using 3ml syringe of 2.5% Sodium hypochlorite between every subsequent instrument. XP Endo finisher is used after the last instrument in preparation B) For the control group : The canals will be thoroughly irrigated using 3ml syringe of 2.5% Sodium hypochlorite between every subsequent instrument. 4) Obturation is done and postoperative instructions are given to the patient</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Necrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dental Pulp Necrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sodium Hypochlorite</mesh_term>
	<criteria>i. Age between 1850 years old. ii. Males or Females. iii. mandibular Premolars Asymptomatic. Nonvital response of pulp tissue (negative response). With or without periapical radiolucency. i. Patients allergic to penicillin. ii. Pregnant females. iii. Patients having significant systemic disorder. iv. If antibiotics have been administrated during the past two weeks preoperatively. v. Patients having bruxism or clenching. vi. Teeth that have : Vital pulp tissues. Association with swelling Acute periapical abscess Periodontally affected teeth No possible restorability Previous endodontic treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>