<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02389049</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to study DNA sequencings for mutations in a research genetic test panel of genes (which contains all 32 known and/or published genes associated with PCD). The study aims to show that about 70% of PCD patients have biallelic mutations in one of these genes. This project will enroll patients who have already had a clinical evaluation, and have clinical features consistent with PCD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Genetics of Primary Ciliary Dyskinesia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators have established a Consortium of 9 geographically-dispersed clinical research sites to study rare disease of the airways, including Primary Ciliary Dyskinesia (PCD). PCD is a genetic disorder with defective mucociliary clearance (MCC), sinus and pulmonary disease with chronic infection, and organs located on the wrong side of the body in about 50% of patients (Kartagener Syndrome). Lung disease occurs early in children with PCD, but establishing a diagnosis remains a major challenge, based on the traditional approaches of using electron microscopy and/or ciliary waveform analysis to define abnormalities of ciliary ultrastructure and/or function. For this study, blood or buccal samples for DNA will be collected and genetic testing in patients with known or suspected PCD will be performed. This study can include term neonates with respiratory distress of unknown etiology and features of PCD, particular laterality defects (situs inversus or heterotaxy). The key hypothesis for this study is that a genetic test panel of 32 genes will confirm a diagnosis in most patients with PCD.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dyskinesias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ciliary Motility Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kartagener Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Any patient who has ≥ 2 clinical features (+/ lab) characteristic of PCD, including: Neonatal respiratory distress after term (or nearterm) birth and/or laterality defect ( situs inversus or heterotaxy) and/or daily wet cough before 6 months of age and/or middle ear disease and/or chronic nasal congestion before 6 months of age and/or bronchiectasis and/or male infertility due to sperm tail dysfunction and/or low nasal nitric oxide levels (&lt;77 nanoliters/minute) and/or defective ciliary ultrastructure Known diagnosis of cystic fibrosis with classic clinical presentation and elevated sweat chloride levels and/or two known diseasecausing Cystic Fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator (CFTR) mutations, or documented primary or acquired immunodeficiency. Known explanation for bronchiectasis (and other clinical features), such as α1antitrypsin deficiency (ZZ or ZS), inflammatory bowel disease or rheumatoid arthritis. Any patient who is unwilling or unable to provide consent or to comply with the testing required in this protocol A participant should not be in the study if they have not had a standard clinical evaluation to address other potential causes of chronic otosino pulmonary disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Primary Ciliary Dyskinesia</keyword>
	<keyword>Kartagener Syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>