<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02389153</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main focus of the pilot study is to evaluate the feasability and effectiveness of a collaborative care intervention for patients suffering from a coronary heart disease (CHD) with insufficient controlled health related risk factors in their lifestyle. The design of the study is a wait list control design. 30 patients will receive treatment immediately after submission, the other 30 after 6 months. An interdisciplinary team, including a care manager for each patient, will offer an individualized treatment plan, based on shared decision making for each patient to reduce risk factors and improve quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Feasability of Collaborative Care in the Secondary Prevention of Coronary Heart Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The following assumptions will be evaluated: 1. The collaborative care concept is feasable in the context of the german health care system and leads to greater patient satisfaction 2. The team-based intervention leads to a decrease of cardiovascular risk factors of patients in the intervention group compared to participants in the waitlist condition 3. The collaborative care intervention leads to an improvement of quality of life as well as mental well being of participants in the intervention group compared to participants of the waitlist condition</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>both sexes coronary heart disease (angiographically oder clinically approved) sufficient knowledge of the german language at least one not sufficient controlled risk factor : Diabetes mellitus (HbA1c&gt;7,5%), smoking, lack of physical activity (less than 60 minutes of light physical exercise per week), heightened stress level (PSS4 &gt;5), arterial hypertension (blood pressure despite medication repeatedly heightened &gt;140/90 or in a 24hour measurement &gt;135/85 mmHg), hypercholesteremia (LDL &gt;130 mg/dl) written informed consent to participate no existence of an medically approved coronary heart disease insufficient knowledge of the german language and ulterior disabilities to complete the questionnaires or to understand the education about the Intervention existence of a psychosis drug dependency (except tobacco) dementia severe episode of Depression current suicidal tendency cardiac insufficiency NYHA 4 missing informed consent malign tumor (unless curative treated and without relapse) acute coronary syndrome or cardiosurgery within the last 3 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>secondary prevention coronary heart disease</keyword>
	<keyword>myocardial infarction</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiovascular risk factors</keyword>
	<keyword>collaborative care</keyword>
	<keyword>quality of life</keyword>
	<keyword>patients´ satisfaction with treatment</keyword>
</DOC>