<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00977340</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether a change in the content of nightmares is necessary at all in the treatment of chronic nightmares or if a single confrontation with their content is sufficient to reduce nightmare frequency significantly.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study on the Psychotherapeutic Treatment of Chronic Nightmares</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The inclusion and exclusion criteria are assessed during a telephone interview. If the participants meet the criteria, they are randomly assigned to two intervention groups or an active control group. In the first session the participants who suffer from chronic nightmares are interviewed using the Structured Clinical Interview for DSM-IV (SCID-I and -II) to determine the clinical diagnosis; in addition, they are given questionnaires and record sheets to obtain baseline data. They are asked to record their nightmares in a "dream diary" up until the next session four weeks later. At that session they learn one of three interventions to reduce nightmares. The first group receives imagery rehearsal treatment in which participants learn to consciously alter the contents of their nightmares and then to visualize the new set of images. The second group is subjected to confrontation treatment in which they are instructed to confront their nightmares until habituation. The third group, the psychotherapeutic placebo group, just learn an imagination technique, without reference to their nightmares. At the end of the intervention session all participants receive written instructions on how to perform the learned method at home. They must also record their dreams up until the next session. That session and the last one are used for data acquisition. At these sessions, the participants are asked to fill in the questionnaires given to them at the beginning of the treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Psychotropic Drugs</mesh_term>
	<criteria>nightmare frequency of at least one night per week for six month duration stable medication if currently in psychotherapy: no treatment of nightmares Informed consent Life time clinical diagnosis of schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder or bipolar disorder according to DSMIV Body mass index &lt; 17 Initiation of nightmares after taking pharmaceuticals Clinical diagnosis of alcohol or drug addiction according to DSMIV Mental retardation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic nightmare sufferers</keyword>
	<keyword>nightmares</keyword>
	<keyword>Imagery Rehearsal Therapy IRT</keyword>
	<keyword>sleep disturbance</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment of nightmares</keyword>
	<keyword>confrontation</keyword>
	<keyword>People who suffer of chronic nightmares</keyword>
</DOC>