<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03005054</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The proposed study is designed as a phase II open-label, controlled, randomized, multicenter, dose-escalation study of the safety, tolerability, and efficacy of a single or multiple applications of StrataGraft skin tissue as an alternative to autografting in promoting the healing of excised full-thickness complex skin defects resulting from acute traumatic skin loss. The proposed study population will include patients with up to 49% Total Body Surface Area (TBSA) complex skin defects including a full-thickness component. The study has been designed to focus on the evaluation of safety and tolerability of prolonged exposure to increasing amounts of a single or multiple applications of StrataGraft skin tissue, while also assessing the potential for StrataGraft tissue to promote healing of the full-thickness component of these complex skin defects as an alternative to donor site harvesting and autografting. Targeted enrollment for this study is up to 20 subjects with complex skin defects due to acute traumatic skin loss which require surgical excision and autografting. Subjects will be sequentially enrolled in two cohorts of increasing treatment area receiving StrataGraft skin tissue.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>StrataGraft® Skin Tissue as an Alternative to Autografting Full-thickness Complex Skin Defects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Men and women aged 1865 years, inclusive 2. Written informed consent 3. Sufficient healthy skin identified and reserved as a donor site in the event that the StrataGraft treatment site requires autografting 4. Complex skin defects of up to 49% TBSA requiring excision and autografting Total skin defect may consist of more than one wound area 5. Fullthickness complex skin defects requiring excision and autografting 6. Study treatment sites on the torso and limbs may be up to 200 cm2 in cohort 1 and 400 cm2 in cohort 2 7. For thermal burns only, first excision and grafting of treatment sites 1. Pregnant women and prisoners 2. Subjects receiving systemic immunosuppressive therapy 3. Subjects with a known history of malignancy 4. Preadmission insulindependent diabetic subjects 5. Subjects with concurrent conditions that in the opinion of the investigator may compromise subject safety or study objectives 6. Expected survival of less than three months 7. Participation in the treatment group of an interventional study within the 90 days prior to enrollment 8. Chronic wounds 9. The face, head, neck, hands, feet, buttocks, perineum, and area over joints 10. Treatment sites with exposed tendon or bony prominences 11. Chemical and electrical burns 12. Treatment sites adjacent to unexcised eschar 13. Clinical suspicion of infection at the anticipated treatment sites</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>