<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03005496</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a randomized controlled trial which compares the effect of zinc, beta-carotene, and Vitamin D3 supplementation in pregnant women which has preterm birth. The measured outcome is zinc, vitamin A, and 25(OH)D level in serum and placenta, MyD88, TRIF, NFκB, and IL-1β levels in placenta.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Zinc, β-carotene, and Vitamin D3 in Preterm Delivery Through Placental MyD88, TRIF, NFkB, and IL-1β</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The research will be held in Cipto Mangunkusumo General and Budi Kemuliaan Hospital. Each participant of each group will be given the medication of preterm birth hospital protocol, which includes nifedipine 4x10 mg as tocolytic agent, dexamethasone 2x6 mg intravenous for 2 days which aims to support lung maturation, and antibiotic. Then, the blood sample is obtained for zinc, vitamin A and 25(OH)D levels examination. Randomly, subjects will be divided into 2 groups which are group whose given the oral zinc 50 mg/day, oral beta-carotene 25,000 IU and oral vitamin D3 50,000 IU/week supplementation, and group who is not given the intervention. Each participant will be observed until delivery. After delivery, level of zinc, vitamin A, and 25(OH)D in serum and placenta will be measured, as well as level of MyD88, TRIF, NFκB, and IL-1β in placenta.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Beta Carotene</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nifedipine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carotenoids</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pregnant women who has preterm birth in 2834 weeks gestational age Multiple pregnancy Drug allergy Intra Uterine Growth Retardation (IUGR) is detected Congenital malformation in fetus was found Preterm Premature Rupture of Membrane (PPROM) Maternal complication such as gestational hypertension, preeclampsia, gestational diabetes mellitus, heart disease, infection, and autoimmune disease</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>