<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02592187</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: Mild Cognitive Impairment (MCI) is a risk factor for dementia and represents a critical window of opportunity to intervene and alter the trajectory of both cognitive and functional decline. Emerging life-logging technologies has shown a tremendous potential to increase autobiographical memory. Objective: The main goal of the present study is to develop a Cognitive Training program (CT) for MCI based on life-logging captured by a Wearable Camera (WeC) recording specific autobiographical episodes for stimulating posteriorly episodic memory. The challenge is to create an application to manage this large collection of images, which can be easily retrieved as events by users in a therapeutic context as a multimodal cognitive stimulation. The investigators will conduct the first pilot Randomized Controlled Trial (RCT) evaluating the effectiveness of the life-logging re-experiencing program immediately and 3-month follow-up period. Methodology: The Design is a single blind RCT of CT based on life-logging tools. 30 adults with MCI, after completion of two weeks image collection by a WeC, will be randomly allocated (1:1) into experimental or control group. Once acquire episodic individual's videos, all participants will attend 1-hour individual training sessions 2 times per week for 14 weeks. Main outcomes measures will be cognitive, functional, emotional and quality of life measures, as well as biochemical measures (BDNF). Expected results: The investigators expect the outcomes to provide preliminary evidence that autobiographical experimentation CT programs can positively impact cognitive functioning and may represent an effective strategy to improve memory and functionality in those who begun to experience cognitive decline.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Cognitive Training Tool Based on Life-logging in Mild Cognitive Impairment (ReMemory-MCI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<criteria>6590 years of age Meet definition criteria for MCI (Petersen, 2004) Be receiving CT at least three month in Day Hospital during three months or more; c) having memory complaint, usually verified by an informant Memory performance and those in one or more other cognitive modality (i.e. attention or executive domain) below the normative data The cutoff scores for abnormality in memory 1,5 below the mean score for the corresponding age and education group Having normal general cognitive functioning as determined by a MiniMental State Examination (MMSE) score &gt; o = 24 Having Global clinical dementia rating scale score of 0.5 Granted written informed consent accepting to participate in the study Neurological, psychiatric or medical disorders Intellectual deficiency (Premorbid Intellectual Quotient (IQ) Vocabulary less 85) Moderate or severe depression as determined by a score &gt;11 (moderate depression) or 19 (severe depression) on the Geriatric Depression Scale (GDSYesavage) Relevant hearing, vision, motor or language deficits Less than 4 years of education e) acquisition of Catalonian or Spanish languages after 15 years old Living alone Recent participation in cognitive stimulation/training procedure different from the received at the Day Hospitals.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Life-logging</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive Training</keyword>
	<keyword>Mild Cognitive Impairment</keyword>
	<keyword>Memory</keyword>
	<keyword>Information and communications technology (ICT) in healthcare</keyword>
	<keyword>Portable camera</keyword>
</DOC>