<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01420627</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, efficacy, and pharmacokinetics of EZN-2279 in patients with ADA-deficient combined immunodeficiency currently being treated with Adagen.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>EZN-2279 in Patients With ADA-SCID</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Severe Combined Immunodeficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Agammaglobulinemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosis of ADAdeficient combined immunodeficiency 2. Stable clinical status while receiving therapy with Adagen®. Patients previously receiving gene therapy or undergoing hematopoietic stem cell transplantation who still require Adagen® treatment are eligible. The dose of Adagen® must be stable for at least 3 months prior to study entry. 3. Have both during the Adagen® Leadin phase of the study: 1. Trough plasma ADA activity &gt;15 μmol/h/mL while receiving Adagen® 2. Total erythrocyte dAXP ≤0.02 μmol/mL from a trough blood sample 4. Patients or parent/guardian must be capable of understanding the protocol requirements and risks and providing written informed assent/consent 1. Autoimmunity requiring immunosuppressive treatment 2. Patients with neutralizing antiAdagen® antibodies at screening evaluation. 3. Severe thrombocytopenia (platelet count &lt;50 x 109/L) 4. Current participation in other therapeutic protocols for ADAdeficient combined immunodeficiency 5. Current or prior participation in another clinical study with an investigational agent and/or use of an investigational drug in the 30 days before study entry. 6. Known planned participation in a genetherapy study for the planned duration of this study 7. Any condition that, in the opinion of the PI or SigmaTau, makes the patient unsuitable for the study 8. Inability or unwillingness to administer Adagen® or EZN2279 on a one time per week regimen 9. Inability to comply with the study protocol 10. Female patients who are pregnant or lactating 11. Female patients who are breastfeeding 12. Female subjects of childbearing potential who are not using an FDA approved birth control method</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>