<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01155583</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as azacitidine and dexamethasone, work in different ways to stop the growth of cancer cells either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Biological therapies, such as lenalidomide, may stimulate the immune system in different ways and stop cancer cells from growing. Giving azacitidine together with lenalidomide and dexamethasone may kill more cancer cells. PURPOSE: This phase I/II trial is studying the side effects and best dose of azacitidine when given together with lenalidomide and low-dose dexamethasone in treating patients with relapsed or refractory multiple myeloma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Low-Dose Azacitidine, Lenalidomide, and Low-Dose Dexamethasone in Relapsed or Refractory Multiple Myeloma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: Define the highest tolerated low dose (HTLD) and safety of azacitidine given at low but increasing doses up to 50mg/m2 twice a week concurrently with GFR-adjusted lenalidomide and low dose dexamethasone in patients with relapsed or refractory multiple myeloma. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: - Response according to international response criteria (≥PR) and clinical benefit response (≥minor response according to adapted EBMT criteria) - Correlate response with plasma activity of the azacitidine inactivating enzyme cytidine deaminase (CDA) - Progression-free survival and overall survival - Peripheral blood hematopoietic progenitor (CD34+) yield and time to neutrophil and platelet recovery in patients undergoing autologous stem cell transplantation - Promoter demethylation and gene reactivation in myeloma cells and hematopoietic progenitors treated at the HTLD / HTLD-CKD level after cycle 1 - Changes in global gene expression in myeloma cells treated at the HTLD / HTLD-CKD level after cycle 1 OUTLINE: This is a phase I, dose-escalation study of azacitidine followed by a phase II study. Patients receive azacitidine subcutaneously once or twice weekly and oral dexamethasone once weekly starting on day 1. Patients also receive oral lenalidomide once daily on days 1-21. Treatment repeats every 28 days for 6 courses. Patients then continue to receive lenalidomide as maintenance therapy. Treatment continues in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 3 months for 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenalidomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thalidomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Azacitidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Understand and voluntarily sign an informed consent form Able to adhere to the study visit schedule and other protocol requirements Refractory or relapsed multiple myeloma Measurable disease defined as at least one of the following: Serum mspike ≥ 1g/dL, urine mspike ≥ 200mg/24hrs, serum free light chains ≥ 100mg/L (provided the kappa/lambda ratio is abnormal), or bone marrow plasma cells ≥ 30% Previous therapy with IMiD™ compounds (thalidomide, lenalidomide, pomalidomide), proteasome inhibitors (bortezomib, carfilzomib), and corticosteroids must be discontinued at least 14 days before entry onto this study. Previous cytotoxic chemotherapy (e.g. alkylating chemotherapy, anthracyclines, and vinca alkaloids), radiation therapy to the pelvis, and any experimental therapy other than carfilzomib or pomalidomide must have been discontinued at least 28 days prior to entry onto this study. ECOG performance status of ≤ 2 at study entry. Laboratory test results within these ranges: Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500 /mm³ Platelet count ≥ 75,000/mm³ Calculated creatinine clearance (CockroftGault) ≥ 30ml/min. Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN Serum glutamicoxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) (aspartate aminotransferase [AST]) and serum glutamicpyruvic transaminase (SGPT) (alanine aminotransferase [ALT]) levels ≤2 x ULN All study participants must be registered into the mandatory RevAssist® program, and be willing and able to comply with the requirements of RevAssist®. Females of childbearing potential (FCBP)must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test with a sensitivity of at least 50 mIU/mL within 10 14 days prior to and again within 24 hours of prescribing lenalidomide (prescriptions must be filled within 7 days) and must either commit to continued abstinence from heterosexual intercourse or begin TWO acceptable methods of birth control, one highly effective method and one additional effective method AT THE SAME TIME, at least 28 days before she starts taking lenalidomide. FCBP must also agree to ongoing pregnancy testing. Men must agree to use a latex condom during sexual contact with a FCBP even if they have had a successful vasectomy. Able to take aspirin (81 or 325 mg) daily as prophylactic anticoagulation (patients intolerant to ASA may use warfarin or low molecular weight heparin) if no additional risk factor for VTE other than myeloma diagnosis according to IMW guidelines Able to take low molecular weight heparin or warfarin if ≥ 1 additional risk factor for VTE according to IMW guidelines Any serious medical condition, laboratory abnormality, or psychiatric illness that would prevent the subject from signing the informed consent form Pregnant or breast feeding females (Lactating females must agree not to breast feed while taking lenalidomide or azacitidine) Any condition, including the presence of laboratory abnormalities, which places the subject at unacceptable risk if he/she were to participate in the study or confounds the ability to interpret data from the study Use of any experimental drug or therapy other than carfilzomib and pomalidomide within 28 days of treatment start on this protocol. Neuropathy &gt; Grade 2 Known hypersensitivity to thalidomide, lenalidomide, azacitidine, or mannitol The development of erythema nodosum if characterized by a desquamating rash while taking thalidomide or lenalidomide drugs Concurrent use of other anticancer agents or treatments, concurrent radiation to the pelvis. Palliative radiation to areas outside the pelvis is allowed Previous inability to tolerate fulldose lenalidomide, adjusted to creatinine clearance (CrCl) according to CockroftGault at the time of previous lenalidomide treatment (25mg day 121 every 28 days if CrCl &gt; 60ml/min, 10mg lenalidomide d121 every 28 days if CrCl &lt; 60mL/min but &gt; 30mL/min, lenalidomide 15mg every 48 h d121 every 28 days if CrCl &lt; 30mL/min but not requiring dialysis, lenalidomide 5mg daily, day 121 every 28 days if CrCl &lt; 30mL/min and requiring dialysis).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>