<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01155362</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the study is to estimate the treatment effect of 3 different doses of PDA001 versus placebo in subjects with moderate-to-severe Crohn's Disease. The secondary objective of the study is to assess the safety and tolerability of PDA001 versus placebo in the above-mentioned patient population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Multi-Center Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of Intravenous Infusion of Human Placenta-Derived Cells (PDA001) for the Treatment of Adults With Moderate-to-Severe Crohn's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Males and females ages 1875 years 2. Understand and voluntarily sign an informed consent 3. Able to adhere to the study visit schedule and other protocol requirements 4. Minimum weight of 50 kg 5. A female of childbearing potential (FCBP)† must have a negative urine pregnancy test at screening (Visit 1) and immediately prior to all doses of IP. In addition, sexually active FCBP must agree to use two of the adequate forms of contraception methods for the duration of the study and the followup period. A FCBP must agree to have pregnancy tests at least every 4 weeks during the study. Males (including those who have had a vasectomy) must agree to use barrier contraception (latex condoms) when engaging in reproductive sexual activity with FCBP for the duration of the study and the followup period. 6. Subject must have inflammatory CD 6 months prior to treatment and have confirmation of ongoing disease activity by colonoscopy or (other method) at screening 7. Subject must have a CDAI score &gt; 220 and &lt; 450 as assessed between Visit 1 and Visit 2 8. The Subject must have failed, i.e., had an inadequate response or lost response (recurrence of symptoms) to an agent, or documented intolerance to an agent at any time 1. Any significant medical condition, laboratory abnormality, or psychiatric illness that would prevent the subject from participating in the study 2. Any condition including the presence of laboratory abnormalities, which places the subject at unacceptable risk if he/she were to participate in the study A female of childbearing potential is a sexually mature woman who: 1. has not undergone a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy 2. has not been naturally postmenopausal for at least 24 consecutive months (i.e., has had menses at any time in the preceding 24 consecutive months).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Human Placenta-Derived Cells for the Treatment of Moderate-to-Severe Crohn's Disease</keyword>
</DOC>