<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02427412</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A randomized, prospective, placebo-controlled study which aims to evaluate the effect of combined intraarticular and intravenous Tranexamic acid on total blood loss following unilateral knee replacement versus only intravenous tranexamic acid.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Intraarticular Tranexamic Acid to Reduction of Total Blood Loss Following Knee-Arthroplasty</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Intravenous (IV) Tranexamic acid is already well-established and well-documented regarding significant effect on reducing blood loss following knee replacement. A few studies more shown a similar effect of intraarticular (IA) injected Tranexamic acid into the knee joint at the end of surgery for knee replacement. In this study investigators therefore investigate the possible combined effect of added intraarticular tranexamic acid to conventional intravenous Tranexamic acid.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Postoperative Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Exsanguination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tranexamic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>&gt; 18 years old Unilateral knee replacement Must be able to give oral and written consent General Anesthetized Allergic to Tranexamic acid In treatment with the following anticoagulants: Adenosine diphosphate receptor inhibitors or vitamin K antagonist within in the last 5 days. Factor Xa inhibitor and thrombin inhibitor. Use of oral anticonceptive. Reduced kidney function (Screatinine &gt; 120 micromol/L) Medicine or alcohol abuse Females with menstruation within the last 12 mounts. Any kind of cancer disease Rheumatoid arthritis Have participated in a clinical trial within the last 30 days.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tranexamic Acid</keyword>
	<keyword>Knee Arthroplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Blood loss</keyword>
	<keyword>Blood transfusion</keyword>
	<keyword>Thrombolic complication</keyword>
	<keyword>Total blood loss 24 h after ended surgery.</keyword>
	<keyword>Total blood loss 2 days after ended surgery.</keyword>
</DOC>