<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02427061</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sexual violence (SV) and adolescent relationship abuse (ARA) are prevalent among adolescents and associated with poor health. Global health organizations highlight engaging men and boys in preventing violence against women as a potentially impactful public health strategy. This study aims to test, via a two arm cluster randomized controlled trial, a "gender transformative" SV/ARA perpetration prevention program among African American adolescent males ages 13-19 (target is high school age) implemented in a community-based setting. "Gender transformative" refers to a theory- and evidence-based approach to alter gender norms that foster SV/ARA while promoting bystander intervention (i.e., giving boys skills to interrupt abusive behaviors they witness among peers) to reduce SV/ARA perpetration. As the acceptance of SV and involvement in unhealthy sexual behaviors are associated with SV/ARA perpetration, this program integrates analysis of social norms that condone violence against women, sexual health promotion, and skills in bystander intervention -- an approach that has been implemented in multiple non-U.S. settings among young adult males with reductions in violence, development of more equitable gender attitudes, and less risky sexual behaviors. This will be the first test of such a gender transformative program among adolescent males in the U.S. Via a 2-arm cluster-randomized trial in youth-serving agencies (16 clusters, N=840 adolescent males ages 14-19), this study will assess the effectiveness of "Manhood 2.0" (proposed name for this gender transformative program) compared to a job skills curriculum. Three months after the end of the program (Time 2), compared to controls, youth will demonstrate increased positive bystander intervention behaviors (secondary outcome). Intermediate outcomes are: condom use self-efficacy; contraception use attitudes; recognition of abusive behaviors; gender-equitable attitudes; and intentions to intervene with peers. Nine months after intervention completion (Time 3), youth will report less perpetration of SV and ARA toward females (Primary Outcome) compared to controls. This study will provide urgently needed information about the effectiveness of a gender transformative program that combines healthy sexuality skills, gender norms change, and bystander skills to interrupt peers' disrespectful and harmful behaviors to reduce SV/ARA perpetration among adolescent males.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Engendering Healthy Masculinities to Prevent Sexual Violence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: adolescent males ages 1319 recruited from youthserving agencies in the Pittsburgh region able to provide their own assent English speaking Exclusion criteria: adolescent males younger than 13 years old or older than 19 years old not able to provide their own assent non English speaking</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>