<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01983644</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Endovascular therapy is increasingly used for patients with moderate-to-severe acute ischemic stroke.This study will compare the efficacy and safety of RECO(a novel, self-expanding stent retriever) with Solitaire FR within 8 hours of stroke onset caused by the large vessel occlusion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>RECO Flow Restoration Device Versus Solitaire FR With the Intention for Thrombectomy Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>RECO is a novel, self-expanding stent retriever, designed to yield rapid flow restoration in acute cerebral ischaemia. The proposed study is a multicenter, randomized, prospective, parallel-group, open-label clinical trial with a blinded outcome, to test the RECO(a novel, self-expanding stent retriever), as compared with Solitaire FR stent retriever.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. age (1880 years) 2. acute ischemic stroke 3. within 8 hours after symptom onset 4. a largevessel confirmed by CTA/MRA (eg, internal carotid, middle cerebral M1 and/or M2 segments) 5. NIHSS(≥8 and ≤24) 6. patients or their legally authorised representatives provided signed, informed consent. 1. CT or MRI evidence of intracranial haemorrhage/tumor 2. major ischaemic infarction (acute ischaemic change in more than a third of the middle cerebral artery territory) 3. NIHSS(≥25 and ≤7) 4. severe sustained hypertension (systolic blood pressure &gt;185 mm Hg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;110 mm Hg) 5. baseline glucose concentrations of less than 2·7 mmol/L or higher than 21.6 mmol/L 6. known haemorrhagic diathesis, coagulation factor deficiency, or oral anticoagulant therapy with an international normalised ratio of more than 1.7 7. treatment with heparin within 48 h with a partial thromboplastin time more than two times the laboratory normal, baseline platelet count of less than 100×10^9/L 8. history of severe allergy (worse than rash) to contrast medium or nitinol 9. pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>acute ischemic stroke,endovascular recanalization</keyword>
	<keyword>mechanical thrombectomy</keyword>
</DOC>