<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01983462</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to test the effects of: 1) blocking sympathetic nerve activity with a drug called clonidine, and 2) by blocking a kidney protein called renin, and on blood vessel function and muscle nerve activity in adults who are obese and have high blood pressure. Years 1 and 2: The 1st cohort of subjects will consist of 69 healthy young men and women age 18-79 years who are obese, defined as a body mass index &gt; or = to 30 kg/m2, who have untreated systolic hypertension (systolic blood pressure &gt; or = to 130 - &lt;180 mmHg- average of at least 3 measurements 2 min apart after 10 min seated resting position). These 69 subjects will then be randomized to 3 treatment arms: clonidine (0.1 mg/day), hydrochlorothiazide (25 mg/day) or placebo for 4 weeks in years 1 and 2. All tablets will be encapsulated by to look identical. Subjects will randomly (1:1:1) receive one of the following combinations in a double-blind, placebo-controlled design: 1. Oral clonidine (0.1 mg twice/day) 2. Oral hydrochlorothiazide (12.5 mg twice/day) 3. Oral placebo In addition to 69 healthy young men and women, we will also enroll 15 obese adults with 'normal/optimal' systolic blood pressure (&lt;120mmHg) who will undergo baseline testing only (Visits 1, 2 and 3). Years 3 and 4: A 2nd cohort of subjects (n=42) will be randomized to aliskiren (150 mg/day), hydrochlorothiazide (25 mg/day) or placebo for 4 weeks. All tablets will be encapsulated to look identical. Subjects will receive one of the following in a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled design: 1. Oral Aliskiren(150 mg/day- once per day) 2. Oral Hydrochlorothiazide (12.5 mg twice/day) 3. Oral placebo</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vascular Dysfunction in Human Obesity Hypertension</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prehypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clonidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrochlorothiazide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Willing and able to provide written, signed informed consent after the nature of the study has been explained, and prior to any researchrelated procedures. Systolic blood pressure &gt;/= 130 mmHg and &lt;180 mmHg Age is &gt; or = 18 and &lt; or = 79 years of age Weight stable (+/ 5 lbs) for the previous 3 months Healthy, as determined by health history questionnaire, blood chemistries, 12lead ECG Blood chemistries indicative of normal renal (creatinine &lt;2.0 mg/dl), liver (&lt;3 times upper limit for ALT, AST), and thyroid function (TSH between 0.4 5.0 mU/L) If currently receiving treatment with or taking any of the following supplements, be willing and able to discontinue taking them for 2 weeks prior and throughout the treatment period: Vitamin C, E or other multivitamins containing vitamin C or E; or omega3 fatty acids. No history of cardiovascular disease (e.g., heart attack, stroke, heart failure, valvular heart disease, cardiomyopathy), Type 1 or Type 2 diabetes, or peripheral arterial disease Nonsmokers, defined as no history of smoking or no smoking for at least the past 1 year Normal resting 12lead ECG (no evidence of myocardial infarction, left ventricular hypertrophy, leftbundle branch block, 2nd or 3rd degree AV block, atrial fibrillation/flutter) Systolic blood pressure &gt;/=180 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;110 mmHg History of cardiovascular disease such as heart angioplasty/stent or bypass surgery, myocardial infarction, stroke, heart failure with or without left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;40%, cardiomyopathy, valvular heart disease, cardiomyopathy, heart transplantation, Type 2 and Type 1 diabetes Smoking or history of smoking within past one year History of gastric ulcers, bleeding disorders, dyspepsia, severe gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD), or metabolic acidosis History of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) Abnormal resting 12lead ECG (e.g., evidence of myocardial infarction, left ventricular hypertrophy, leftbundle branch block, 2nd or 3rd degree AV block, atrial fibrillation/flutter) Serious neurologic disorders including seizures History of renal failure, dialysis or kidney transplant Serum creatinine &gt; 2.0 mg/dL, or hepatic enzyme (ALT/AST) concentrations &gt; 3 times the upper limit of normal History of HIV infection, hepatic cirrhosis, other preexisting liver disease, or positive HIV, Hepatitis B or C test at screening. Use of any investigational product or investigational medical device within 30 days prior to screening, or requirement for any investigational agent prior to completion of all scheduled study assessments. History of recent chicken pox, shingles or influenza (ie., risk of Reye's syndrome) Recent flulike symptoms within the past 2 weeks Pregnant or breastfeeding at screening, or planning to become pregnant (self or partner) at any time during the study. A urinary pregnancy test will be done on all females. If test is positive, the subject will be excluded. Women with history of hormone replacement therapy within the past 6 months History of rheumatoid arthritis, Grave's disease, systemic lupus erythematosis, and Wegener's granulomatosis; Taking lipid lowering (e.g., statins, niacin), glycemic control (e.g. metformin, insulin), anticoagulation, antiseizure, antidepression or antipsychotic agents History of comorbid condition that would limit life expectancy to &lt; 6 months. Taking chronic nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDS) such as aspirin, indomethacin, naproxen, acetaminophen (Tylenol), ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin) and not able or willing to go off of for 2 weeks prior and during the study Taking cox2 inhibitors (Celebrex, Vioxx, etc) or allopurinol (Zyloprim, Lopurin, Allopurin) Taking blood thinners such as coumadin (Warfarin), enoxaparin (Lovenox); clopidogrel (Plavix); dipyridamole (Persantine); heparin; Taking diabetic medications (Metformin, glyburide, insulin, etc.), thiazolidinediones (Avandia, Rezulin, Actos); Taking steroids or biologics : corticosteroids (prednisone); methotrexate, infliximab (Remicade), etanercept (Enbrel); anakinra; Taking thyroid medications such as levothyroxine (Levoxyl, Synthroid, Levoxyl, Unithroid); Levodopa; Taking Phosphodiesterase (PDE) 5 inhibitors (e.g., Viagra速, Cialis速, Levitra速, or Revatio速); PDE 3 inhibitors (e.g., cilostazol, milrinone, or vesnarinone); lithium May participate if no use of the following medications in the 48 hours prior to experimental visits: naproxen (Aleve), acetaminophen (Tylenol), ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin), other any nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDS) Vulnerable populations (prisoners, etc.) Any condition that, in the view of the PI, places the subject at high risk of poor treatment compliance or of not completing the study. History of alcohol abuse or &gt;10 alcoholic units per week (1 unit= 1 beer, 1 glass of wine, 1 mixed cocktail containing 1 oz alcohol) On weight loss drugs (e.g., Xenical (orlistat), Meridia (sibutramine), Acutrim (phenylpropanolamine), or similar overthecounter medications) within 3 months of screening Any surgery within 30 days of screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prehypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Obese</keyword>
	<keyword>Sympathetic Nervous System</keyword>
	<keyword>renin-angiotensin system</keyword>
	<keyword>Endothelial function</keyword>
</DOC>