<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02230046</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the bioequivalence (equivalence of pharmacokinetic parameters) of 2 abiraterone acetate coated tablet formulations with respect to the current commercial abiraterone acetate uncoated tablet formulation under fasted (without eating or drinking) conditions in healthy male participants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bioequivalence Study of Abiraterone Acetate Coated and Uncoated Tablet Formulations in Healthy Male Participants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 1, randomized (study medication assigned to participants by chance), open-label (all people know the identity of the intervention), single-center, single-dose and 3-way Crossover (the same medications provided to all participants but in different sequence) pivotal study to determine the bioequivalence of 2 abiraterone acetate coated tablet formulations with respect to the current commercial abiraterone acetate uncoated tablet formulation. Approximately 102 healthy male participants will participate in this study. Participants will be randomly assigned to 1 of 6 treatment sequences. The study will consist of 3 parts: Screening Phase (within 21 days before the first study drug administration of the first period), an open-label treatment Phase consisting of 3 single-dose treatment periods (45 days) and follow-up Phase (5 to 7 days after the last study procedure). The total study duration for each participant will be from 45 days to a maximum of 61 days. Participants will receive a single oral 1000 milligram (mg) dose of abiraterone acetate under fasted conditions either as Treatment A (current commercial formulation, uncoated), Treatment B (current commercial formulation, coated) or Treatment C (new composition, coated). Bioequivalence will be primarily evaluated by pharmacokinetic parameters. Participants' safety will be monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Abiraterone Acetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>If sexually active, participants must always use a condom during the study and for 1 week after last intake of study drug. If sexually active with a pregnant woman or woman of childbearing potential, participants must agree to abstain from intercourse during the study and for 1 week after last intake of study drug. Participants should not donate sperm during the study and for 1 week after receiving the last dose of study drug Body mass index (BMI; weight [kilogram(kg)]/height^2 [meter square (m^2)]) between 18.5 and 30.0 kg/m^2, (inclusive), and body weight not less than 50 kg Blood pressure (after the participants is supine for 5 minutes) between 90 and 140 millimeter of mercury (mmHg) systolic, inclusive, and no higher than 90 mmHg diastolic at Screening A 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG) consistent with normal cardiac conduction and function at Screening as specified in the protocol Nonsmoker, no history of smoking or use of nicotinecontaining substances within the previous 2 months, as determined by medical history or participant's verbal report History of or current clinically significant medical illness including (but not limited to) cardiac arrhythmias or other cardiac disease, hematologic disease, coagulation disorders (including any abnormal bleeding or blood dyscrasias), lipid abnormalities, significant pulmonary disease, including bronchospastic respiratory disease, diabetes mellitus, renal or hepatic insufficiency, thyroid disease, neurologic or psychiatric disease, infection, or any other illness that the investigator considers should exclude the participants or that could interfere with the interpretation of the study results Clinically significant abnormal values for hematology or clinical chemistry at Screening Presence of sexual dysfunction (abnormal libido, erectile dysfunction, etc.) or any medical condition that would affect sexual function Use of any prescription or nonprescription medication (including vitamins and herbal supplements), except for acetaminophen, within 14 days before the first dose of the study drug is scheduled through study completion History of, or a reason to believe a participants has a history of drug or alcohol abuse within the past 5 years</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Healthy,</keyword>
	<keyword>Abiraterone Acetate,</keyword>
	<keyword>Bioequivalence.</keyword>
</DOC>