<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02230722</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators propose to develop a novel intervention that targets the system (Collaborative Care), PCP (computerized decision support for opioid therapy) and veteran (CM-delivered MI) to reduce problematic prescription opioid use and encourage non-opioid pain management alternatives.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Opioid Safety in Veterans Using Collaborative Care and Decision Support</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators will develop and test the acceptability, feasibility, and preliminary efficacy of a Collaborative Care intervention in which one of two Care Managers delivering both interventions will assist primary care providers (PCPs) by using Motivational Interviewing to communicate computer-based ATHENA-OT (opioid therapy) decision support guidelines to veterans with chronic pain. Specifically, after honing the intervention, the investigators will conduct a pilot randomized controlled trial of Collaborative Care/Motivational Interviewing in 100 veterans (ages 18 and older) with chronic pain in primary care who are prescribed opioid pain medications and exhibit at least one "high-risk" opioid use behavior (e.g. obtaining early opioid refills, etc.). Using ATHENA-OT decision support, PCPs will make guideline-concordant recommendations to all enrolled study patients and initiate a Pain Care Plan. Veterans randomized to Collaborative Care, will have one MI session with their assigned study Care Manager followed by 3 Care Manager-delivered telephone MI/monitoring sessions; patients randomized to the Attention Control arm will have one brief session with their assigned Care Manager, followed by 3 Care Manager-delivered neutral telephone sessions</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Analgesics, Opioid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Current Male or Female patient at San Francisco VA Medical Center or affiliated VA clinics Must be older than 18 years Chronic musculoskeletal pain of at least 6 months duration and Prescribed one or more opioid pain medication for more than three months and Evidence of being a highrisk opioid user as determined by PI, electronic medical record, and study measures NonEnglish speakers Plans to relocate within 6 months; not able to come to San Francisco VA Medical Center for three inperson visits Cancer or other terminal illness involving palliative care with opioid medications Serious or untreated mental illness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>opioids</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic pain</keyword>
	<keyword>collaborative care</keyword>
</DOC>