<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00429169</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary study comparing effectiveness for suicidal ideation and/or behavior of two antidepressant medications in depressed patients who have attempted suicide or are currently experiencing suicidal thoughts has been completed. A secondary study component using functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) to investigate different medication effects on reward processing in the same sample is ongoing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Paroxetine/Bupropion in Suicide Attempters/Ideators With Major Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Major depressive disorder (MDD) is a common and serious psychiatric illness. It is among the leading causes of disability and is the psychiatric disorder most often associated with suicide. The treatment of MDD with antidepressant medication remains largely trial and error. Little empirical evidence exists to guide the treatment of MDD when suicide risk is a major factor. Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) are a type of antidepressant medication that works by increasing the amount of serotonin, a natural substance in the brain that helps maintain mental balance. The study compared the effectiveness of paroxetine, an SSRI, versus bupropion, a non-SSRI, on suicidal ideation and/or behavior in depressed patients with a past suicide attempt and/or current suicidal thoughts. Results of the completed primary study have been published (Grunebaum MF et al. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2012 Feb;37(3):697-706). In the ongoing secondary neuro-imaging component of the study, Participants are randomly assigned to either paroxetine or bupropion treatment for 8 weeks with fMRI scans involving a reward processing task at baseline and Week 8. Weekly study visits include interviews with a psychologist, self-report scales, and medication monitoring. All participants will then be offered 4 additional months of open clinical treatment. If original medication assignments prove to be ineffective, participants will have the option to switch to another medication. After completing the study, participants will be referred for ongoing treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Suicide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paroxetine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupropion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Currently suffering from a major depressive episode (unipolar only) History of a past suicide attempt or score greater than 2 on the Hamilton Depression Rating Scale (HDRS) item #3 (suicide) at inperson screening interview. Patients with suicidal plan or intent will only be enrolled as inpatients if independent inpatient treatment team agrees. Patients 60 years of age and older must score at least 25 on MMSE at screening. Patients 60 years of age and older must have a normal ECG within the past year. Any of the following conditions: bipolar disorder; current psychotic symptoms; bulimia or anorexia that is current or within the past year, or current purging at least twice a week for three months; already taking selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) or bupropion for other indications (such as anxiety disorders) Primary disorder is an anxiety disorder (e.g., panic disorder, general anxiety disorder, obsessive compulsive disorder, social anxiety disorder), with secondary depression Drug or alcohol dependence within 6 months prior to study entry (current drug or alcohol abuse may be permitted if study officials determine that the abuse is of lesser importance than the major depressive episode) Systolic blood pressure greater than or equal to 140 mm Hg or diastolic blood pressure greater than or equal to 90 mm Hg Significant active physical illness, particularly those that may affect the brain or serotonergic system (e.g., blood dyscrasias lymphomas, hypersplenism, endocrinopathies, kidney failure, severe chronic obstructive lung disease, autonomic neuropathies, active malignancy) Active medical problems Requires antipsychotic medication History of hypomania or mania while taking antidepressants Any condition that may make the use of an SSRI or bupropion medically inadvisable Currently using Zyban Failure to respond to adequate trials of three SSRIs, paroxetine, or bupropion within 2 years prior to study entry (failure to respond to therapeutic trial defined as at least 2/3 maximal daily dose [PDR] for at least 6 weeks) Pregnant, breastfeeding, or plans to become pregnant during the course of study participation Currently on effective treatment, requires adjunctive antipsychotic or mood stabilizing medication, or is unlikely to respond to single agent treatment for depression Patients with ferrous metal implants in their bodies, or a history of claustrophobia that precludes MRI, will be excluded. Patients assessed as being unlikely to tolerate the maximum 2week delay to start of treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Major Depressive Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>MDD</keyword>
</DOC>