<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00429871</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The combination of docetaxel+epirubicin is highly effective and well tolerated as first line treatment in patients with metastatic breast cancer (MBC). Capecitabine is an active drug in women with MBC pretreated with taxane and anthracycline. Docetaxel increases the intracellular levels of thymidilate phosphorylase and thus is synergistic with capecitabine. The combination of docetaxel plus capecitabine is highly active and superior to docetaxel monotherapy in women with MBC pretreated with an anthracycline</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized Phase III Trial With Docetaxel Plus Epirubicine Versus Docetaxel Plus Capecitabine for Metastatic Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This trial will compare the efficacy of docetaxel plus epirubicin versus docetaxel plus capecitabine combinations as first line treatment in women with MBC</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epirubicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed metastatic breast adenocarcinoma. No previous chemotherapy treatment for metastatic disease. No previous anthracycline treatment except as adjuvant therapy at least one year before. Age 1975 years old Presence of measurable disease Performance status 02 (WHO) Adequate cardiac function (LVEF &gt;50%) without a recent (within 6 months) history of myocardial infraction and/or unstable or uncontrolled angina. Adequate bone marrow(absolute neutrophil count &gt;1500/mm3, platelet count &gt;100.000/mm3, hemoglobin &gt;10gr/mm3), liver (bilirubin &lt;1.5 times upper limit of normal and SGOT/SGPT &lt;2 times upper limit of normal) and renal function (creatinine &lt;2mg/dl). No previous radiotherapy to more than 25% of marrowcontaining bones. Written informed consent Active brain metastases. Psychiatric illness or social situation that would preclude study compliance Other concurrent uncontrolled illness. Other invasive malignancy within the past 5 years except of nonmelanoma skin cancer. Positive pregnancy for premenopausal women. Concurrent antineoplastic treatment e.g. hormonal therapy</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic breast cancer;</keyword>
	<keyword>First line chemotherapy;</keyword>
	<keyword>Docetaxel;</keyword>
	<keyword>Epirubicin;</keyword>
	<keyword>Capecitabine</keyword>
</DOC>