<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02875405</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if preforming a posterior left pericardiotomy prevents atrial fibrillation after cardiac surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prevention of AtriaL Fibrillation After Cardiac Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Post-operative atrial fibrillation (POAF) is a common complication of cardiac surgery which is observed in 30-40% of patients. POAF may cause stroke, systemic embolism or cardiac failure and Its detection mandates for additional treatment with variable combinations of drugs to control cardiac rate or rhythm, anticoagulation, and electrical cardioversion, with their side effects and complications. As a result, POAF prolongs hospital stay and increases the costs of hospitalization. Several strategies aimed at reducing the incidence of POAF have been investigated, including beta-blockers, amiodarone, and statins, with unsatisfactory results. Posterior left pericardiotomy has been associated with a reduction in the incidence of POAF in a few studies. However, these studies are flawed by methodological limitations in terms of sample size, inclusion/exclusion criteria, randomization procedure, and suboptimal electrocardiographic monitoring strategies. Moreover, posterior left pericardiotomy requires additional operative time and is associated with procedure-specific complications. As a result, current evidence on posterior pericardiectomy failed to translate into changes in clinical practice and the incidence of POAF remains high.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>all consecutive patients admitted to the department of cardiothoracic surgery of the NYPHWCMC will be screened for enrollment. preoperative nonsinus rhythm history of previous atrial arrhythmia of any type reoperations mitral or tricuspid valve disease surgery of the descending thoracic or thoracoabdominal aorta need for hypothermic circulatory arrest off pump operation urgent/emergent presentation disease of the left pleura or previous left thoracotomy chest deformity</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>postoperative</keyword>
	<keyword>pericardiotomy</keyword>
	<keyword>prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiac surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>left</keyword>
	<keyword>posterior</keyword>
</DOC>