<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="120600">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01532817</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BC-US-06</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01532817</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Relief of Acute Bronchoconstriction/Asthma Using the Non-Invasive AlphaCore Device</brief_title>
  <official_title>Non-Invasive Neurostimulation of the Vagus Nerve With the AlphaCore™ Device, for the Relief of Acute Bronchoconstriction Due to Asthma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>ElectroCore LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>ElectroCore LLC</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this pilot study is to collect preliminary clinical data related to the
      safety and preliminary clinical benefits of non-invasive vagal nerve stimulation with the
      AlphaCore™ device for the relief of acute bronchoconstriction due to asthma.

      Up to 30 subjects who meet all inclusion/exclusion criteria and consent to participate in
      the study may be enrolled at up to 5 investigational (study) sites. The study sites are
      clinic settings capable of treating any potential complications of bronchoconstriction, an
      acute exacerbation of asthma, and any emergencies associated with use of the investigational
      device.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety- type and occurrence of adverse events, including device-related, serious or unanticipated</measure>
    <time_frame>From time subject signs the consent through the 1-week follow-up visit</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Bronchoconstriction</condition>
  <condition>Asthma</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The AlphaCore Device</intervention_name>
    <description>A single 90 second stimulation to the vagus nerve on the right side of the neck</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA: VISIT 1

          1. Is able to give written Informed Consent.

          2. Is between the ages of 18 and 65 years, male or female.

          3. Has a known history of mild to moderate asthma for at least 1 year as defined by GINA
             Guidelines.

          4. Is using a short acting beta-agonist for relief/rescue of asthma..

          5. At Visit 1, demonstrates current or historical (within 1 year) FEV1 reversibility of
             at least 12% (and 200ml) or greater within 15-30 minutes following administration of
             4 inhalations of albuterol.

        EXCLUSION CRITERIA: VISIT 1

          1. Has a history of lung cancer, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), or other
             co-morbidity associated with irreversible narrowing of the airways.

          2. Has an abscess or other infection or lesion (including lymphadenopathy) at the
             AlphaCore™ treatment site.

          3. Has known or suspected moderate to severe atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease,
             carotid artery disease (e.g. bruits or history of TIA or CVA) or congestive heart
             failure (CHF).

          4. Has suspected or confirmed sepsis.

          5. Has a clinically significant irregular heart rate or rhythm.

          6. Has experienced recent clinically significant changes in blood pressure, has
             uncontrolled high blood pressure, or is presently receiving pressors to maintain
             blood pressure.

          7. Is currently implanted with an electrical and/or neurostimulator device, including
             but not limited to cardiac pacemaker, defibrillator, vagal neurostimulator, deep
             brain stimulator, spinal stimulator, bone growth stimulator, or cochlear implant.

          8. Has a history of carotid endarterectomy or vascular neck surgery on the right side.

          9. Has been implanted with metal cervical spine hardware.

         10. Has a recent or repeated history of syncope.

         11. Has a recent or repeated history of seizures.

         12. Is pregnant or nursing, or of childbearing years and is unwilling to use an accepted
             form of birth control.

         13. Is participating in any other therapeutic clinical investigation or has participated
             in a clinical trial in the preceding 30 days.

         14. Belongs to a vulnerable population or has any condition such that his or her ability
             to provide informed consent, comply with follow-up requirements, or provide
             self-assessments is compromised (e.g., homeless, developmentally disabled, prisoner).

         15. Is a relative of or an employee of the Investigator or the clinical study site.

        INCLUSION CRITERIA: VISIT 2

          1. No changes have occurred in the patient's health or status relative to the original
             inclusion and exclusion criteria and the patient continues to be eligible for
             participation in the study.

          2. Either (i) develops subjective symptoms of asthma (wheezing, shortness of breath,
             cough) for which the patient would normally self-medicate with a short acting beta
             agonist, and/or (ii) documents a drop of 20% from screening PEF scores as recorded in
             their patient diary.

          3. At Visit 2, FEV1 is the same or lower than the screening FEV1 previously measured at
             visit 1 or the PEF is the same or lower than the screening previously measured at
             Visit 1.

        EXCLUSION CRITERIA: VISIT 2

          1. The patient self-administered a short-acting beta agonist within 6 hours prior to
             onset of asthma symptoms.

          2. The patient induced an asthma exacerbation by withholding their pre-treatment
             medication used for exercise-induced bronchoconstriction (EIB).

          3. Has signs and symptoms of asthma instability at Visit 2:

               -  Lung Function: FEV1 &lt; 50 % predicted.

               -  Signs and symptoms of extreme respiratory distress at rest.

               -  Rapid deterioration in respiratory status (sudden change in respiratory rate,
                  decrease in oxygen saturation, change in consciousness, etc.).
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Allergy and Asthma</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CRI</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vital Prospects Clinical Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tulsa</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 25, 2012</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 10, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
