<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00611728</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objectives To determine maxi tolerated dose &amp; dose limiting toxicity of SU011248 + Irinotecan in recurrent MG pts not on EIAEDs To characterize safety &amp; tolerability of SU011248 + Irinotecan among pts w recurrent MG Secondary Objectives To evaluate pharmacokinetic profile of SU011248 &amp; Irinotecan when co-administered in pts w MG To evaluate anti-tumor activity of SU011248 + Irinotecan</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ph I SU011248 + Irinotecan in Treatment of Pts w MG</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary interest for combining SU011248 w irinotecan in malignant glioma pts derives from dramatic anti-tumor activity recently demonstrated among RMG pts treated w humanized anti-VEGF monoclonal antibody, bevacizumab, when combined w irinotecan. 63 percent radiographic response rate was observed following treatment w regimen every other wk, &amp; median progression-free survival was 23wks. Similar enhancement of chemo activity by VEGF-directed therapy w bev has been previously demonstrated for colorectal &amp; lung cancer pts. SU011248 is being evaluated in current regimen because it may exert more potent anti-angiogenic effect than bev among MG pts due to its ability to inhibit PDGFR-mediated pericyte stabilization in tumor neovasculature. Current proposed ph I study is designed to determine MTD &amp; DLT of SU011248 when combo w irinotecan for pts w RMG. Both SU01148 &amp; irinotecan are known to be metabolized by CYP3A4 cytochrome system. Current study will limit enrollment to pts who are not on CYP3A4-enzyme inducing anti-epileptic drugs.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sunitinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pts confirmed GBM, GS, AA, AO &amp; AOA w recurrent disease following standard therapy consisting of at least external beam XRT &amp; temo chemo Pts not had tumor biopsy &lt;1 week/surgical resection &lt;2 weeks prior to starting study drug Pts should be on nonincreasing dose of steroids &gt;7 days prior to obtaining baseline GdMRI of brain Age &gt;18yrs KPS &gt;70 ANC &gt;1.5 x 10 9/L Hgb &gt;9 g/dL Platelets &gt;100 x 10 9/L AST/SGOT &amp; ALT/SGPT &lt;2.5 x ULN Serum bilirubin &lt;1.5 x ULN Serum CA &lt;12 mg/dL Serum creatinine &lt;1.5 x ULN/measured 24hr CrCl&gt;50mL/min/1.73m^2 Pt has ability to understand &amp; provide signed informed consent that fulfills IRB guidelines Prior gr3/&gt;toxicity/failure to CPT11 therapy Prior Sunitinib malate therapy Concurrent administration of EIAEDs Major surgery &lt;2 weeks of enrollment History of impaired cardiac function Other clinically significant cardiac diseases Uncontrolled diabetes Active/uncontrolled infection requiring intravenous antibiotics Impairment of GI function/GI disease that may significantly alter absorption of Sunitinib malate Sutent Acute/chronic liver/renal disease Cerebrovascular accident/transient ischemic attack &lt;6mths of study enrollment Pulmonary embolism &lt;6mths of study enrollment Preexisting thyroid abnormality w thyroid function that can not be maintained in normal range w medication Pts taking warfarin sodium Pts have received chemo ≤4wks to starting study drug unless they have fully recovered from all anticipated side effects of such therapy Pts have received immunotherapy ≤2wks to starting study drug/have not recovered from side effects of such therapy Pts have received investigational drugs ≤2wks to starting study drug unless they have fully recovered from all anticipated side effects of such therapy Pts have received XRT ≤4wks to starting study drug unless they have fully recovered from all anticipated side effects of such therapy Pts have undergone major nonCNS surgery ≤2wks to starting study drug/pts who have not recovered from side effects of such therapy Cardiac pacemaker Ferromagnetic metal implants other than those approved as safe for use in MR scanners Claustrophobia Obesity Female pts who are pregnant/breast feeding/adults of reproductive potential not employing effective method of birth control Known diagnosis of HIV History of another primary malignancy that is currently clinically significant/currently requiring active intervention Pts unwilling to/unable to comply w protocol Existing intratumoral hemorrhage Concurrent participation in another clinical trial except for supportive care/nontreatment trials Other severe acute/chronic medical/psychiatric condition/lab abnormality that may increase risk associated w study participation/study drug administration/ may interfere w interpretation of study results, &amp; in judgment of investigator would make subject inappropriate for entry into this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>CPT 11</keyword>
	<keyword>Sutent</keyword>
	<keyword>Sunitinib</keyword>
	<keyword>Sunitinib malate</keyword>
	<keyword>Malignant Glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>GBM</keyword>
	<keyword>Irinotecan</keyword>
	<keyword>Camptosar</keyword>
	<keyword>Anaplastic astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Anaplastic oligodendroglioma</keyword>
	<keyword>Anaplastic oligoastrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>SU011248</keyword>
	<keyword>Brain tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>Recurrent malignant glioma</keyword>
</DOC>