<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01356030</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The two most commonly used methods to biopsy suspected pancreaticobiliary masses are (1) endoscopic ultrasound guided fine-needle aspiration (EUS-FNA) and (2) cytology brush biopsies obtained during endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography (ERCP). At most centers, the specific method used depends on the availability of the technology and local expertise. Although it is believed that EUS-FNA is more accurate than ERCP brushings, there have been no head-to-head comparisons. The investigators' hypothesis is that EUS-FNA is superior to ERCP in obtaining tissue biopsies of pancreaticobiliary tumors, and the investigators aim to directly compare the two techniques.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Endoscopic Ultrasound Versus Endoscopic Retrograde Cholangiopancreatography (ERCP) Tissue Sampling for the Diagnosis of Suspected Pancreatico-Biliary Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with pancreaticobiliary tumors usually present with painless jaundice due to bile duct obstruction. The standard clinical evaluation may include EUS and/or ERCP. At centers where EUS is available (like CPMC), it is usually used first as it is generally considered a better tool for tumor detection, staging, and performing biopsies (FNA). ERCP is then performed, if needed, to place a stent and relieve jaundice. As EUS is a relatively newer technology that has not widely disseminated, other centers use ERCP as the 1st modality to evaluate suspected malignant pancreaticobiliary obstruction. The role of ERCP in this setting is to not only place a stent to relieve jaundice, but to additionally obtain cytology brushings for tissue diagnosis. Several studies have reported high sensitivity of EUS-FNA for detecting pancreaticobiliary cancers that are causing bile duct obstruction and jaundice (80-90%). The sensitivity for ERCP brushings and biopsies to detect the same types of tumors is reportedly lower (30-80%), but there have been no direct comparisons of these techniques. Few centers use both technologies (EUS and ERCP) for patient care, or often perform EUS and ERCP at separate sessions. At CPMC, the investigators routinely perform EUS and ERCP together for patients needing these procedures. Thus the investigators are in a unique position to directly compare EUS-FNA to ERCP brushings for tissue diagnosis of suspected pancreaticobiliary tumors. The proposed study will be the 1st direct comparison of EUS-FNA to ERCP tissue sampling for patients with suspected pancreaticobiliary cancers. Study results will highlight the best approach to obtain a biopsy diagnosis of pancreatic and biliary tract cancers.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Jaundice</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholestasis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients age &gt;18 years that are scheduled for EUS and possible ERCP for the evaluation of jaundice from suspected pancreaticobiliary tumors. Patients that do not provide consent for EUS and ERCP (for standard clinical reasons) Patients that do not require ERCP based on EUS findings (e.g. no mass seen, mass is not causing jaundice Patients in whom an additional 5 minutes of procedure time may increase the procedural/sedation risks: pregnant patients patients with severe medical comorbidities (ASA class 4 or 5) Patients with significant bleeding risk precluding endoscopic tissue sampling INR &gt; 1.4 or Prothrombin time &gt; 5 sec more than control Platelet count &lt; 50,000</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>