<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01356602</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study assessed the safety and efficacy of canakinumab pre-filled syringes in comparison to triamcinolone acetonide 40 mg and canakinumab lyophilizate in patients that have frequent flares of acute gouty arthritis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Canakinumab Prefilled Syringes in Frequently Flaring Acute Gouty Arthritis Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Gouty</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone hexacetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone Acetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone diacetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 3 or more gout flares within last year Contraindication, intolerance or lack of efficacy for NSAIDs and/or colchicine Body mass index of less than or equal to 45 kg/m2 Exclusion criteria: Use of the following therapies (within varying protocol defined timeframes): corticosteroids, narcotics, topical ice/cold packs, chronic opiate treatment, NSAIDs (such as aspirin), colchicine. Hemodialysis Live vaccine within 3 months before first dose Donation or loss of 400 mL or more within 3 months before first dose Gout brought on by other factors such as chemotherapy, lead, transplant, etc. Presence of other acute inflammatory arthritis such as Rheumatoid Arthritis Any conditions or significant medical problems that puts the patient at an unacceptable immunological risk to receive this type of therapy such as HIV, Hepatitis, Tuberculosis and other infections/conditions Significant cardiovascular conditions such as uncontrolled hypertension Significant medical diseases such as uncontrolled diabetes, thyroid disease History of malignancy of any organ system within the past 5 years Women who are pregnant or nursing Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gout</keyword>
	<keyword>arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>gout flare</keyword>
	<keyword>acute gout</keyword>
	<keyword>gouty</keyword>
	<keyword>rheumatic disease</keyword>
	<keyword>uric acid</keyword>
</DOC>