<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00899132</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Studying samples of tumor tissue from patients with cancer in the laboratory may help doctors learn more about changes that occur in DNA and identify biomarkers related to cancer. PURPOSE: This research study is evaluating a tumor marker for testicular cancer, skin cancer, small intestine cancer, and pancreatic cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Studying a Tumor Marker for Testicular Cancer, Skin Cancer, Small Intestine Cancer, and Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - To identify TAB3 transcript/protein as a molecular marker of cancer, specifically testicular, skin, small intestine, and pancreatic cancer. - To characterize TAB3 and its signaling networks that are involved in tumorigenesis. OUTLINE: Tumor tissue samples from paraffin-embedded tissue blocks are analyzed for TAB3 transcript and protein expression using in situ hybridization and immunostaining with TAB3 cRNA probe and antibody. Antibodies against the proteins involved in the NFkB signaling pathway (e.g., p65, TAK1, MyD88, and Akt) are used in the immunostaining assays.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Germ Cell and Embryonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Skin Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testicular Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intestinal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Duodenal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ileal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Jejunal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Paraffin tissue blocks from surgical pathology cancer cases, specifically testicular, skin, small intestine, and pancreatic cancer, available PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Not specified PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>skin cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>small intestine cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreatic cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>malignant testicular germ cell tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>testicular teratoma</keyword>
</DOC>