<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2519">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03074097</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB0000871240</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03074097</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Epidural Analgesia Vs Rectus Sheath Block: Postoperative Analgesia and Proinflammatory Cytokines</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Epidural Analgesia Versus Rectus Sheath Block on Postoperative Pain and Proinflammatory Cytokines in Patients Undergoing Malignant Urological Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Good quality of postoperative analgesia would lead to attenuate or prevent the adverse
      effects on the common functions of the immune system. We compared the effect of epidural
      analgesia versus rectus sheath block on postoperative pain and proinflammatory cytokines
      following malignant urological surgery.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study groups: 60 patients were included in the study divided into two groups of 30 patients
      each as follow.

      Epidural group: Lumbar epidural catheter (L3-4) was inserted in each patient before
      induction of general anesthesia. After induction of general anesthesia 5ml of plain
      bupivacaine 0.25% plus 5ml normal saline (10 ml bupivacaine 0.125%) was injected through the
      epidural catheter, then continuous epidural infusion of 25 ml plain bupivacaine 0.25% plus
      25 ml normal saline (50 ml bupivacaine 0.125%) at a rate of 3-5 ml/hour for 24hours
      postoperative.

      Rectus sheath group: Each patient received bilateral single shot ultrasound guided rectus
      sheath block under complete aseptic condition in a dose of 30 ml of plain bupivacaine 0.25%
      in each side immediately after induction of general anesthesia.

      Anesthetic technique: Standard monitoring by pulse oximetry, ECG, and non-invasive arterial
      pressure was performed. General anaesthesia was induced with sleeping dose of propofol (2 to
      4 mg/kg) IV; fentanyl 1 mcg/kg IV; atracurium 0.5 mg/kg. Subsequently, the trachea was
      intubated and general anesthesia was continued with atracurium 0.015 mg/kg/min IVI and
      isoflurane, initially at 1 MAC, and then titrated to clinical end points. The lungs were
      mechanically ventilated at tidal volumes less than 6 mL/kg, and at respiratory rates
      (12-14/minute to maintain end-tidal carbon dioxide (ETCO2) concentration between 30-40 mmHg,
      with a positive end-expiratory pressure (PEEP) of 5mmHg and an inspired oxygen fraction
      (FIO2) of 0.6. At the beginning of the skin closure, anesthesia was discontinued and
      tracheal extubation performed once the patient was awake after reversal of neuromuscular
      blocking agent.

      Data collection:

      Evaluation of postoperative pain intensity by Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) pain score (0 =
      no pain, 10=the worst pain imaginable): NRS evaluation was evaluated during rest and during
      cough (by asking the patient to cough) at the following postoperative period, 1hour (T1),
      2hour (T2), 4hour (T4), 6hour (T6), 12hour (T12), 18hour (T18) and 24hours (T24). All the
      patients, in both groups, will receive paracetamol 1000 mg/6hour IVI. When VAS &gt; 4 morphine
      0.1 mg/kg will be given slowly IV as rescue analgesia with a maximum three doses in 24 hours
      with 8 hours interval.

      Measurement of proinflammatory cytokines (TNF-α and IL-6): Two samples (preoperative and
      24hour postoperative) of 5 mL venous blood were drawn in plan tubes under sterile conditions
      from each patient. Serum was rapidly centrifugated and quickly frozen at −70°C and stored
      until processed. Serum TNF-α and IL-6 levels were measured by enzyme-linked immunosorbent
      assay (ELISA) technique using commercially available kit from (KOMA BIOTECH, KOREA)
      according to the manufacturer instructions.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 5, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 28, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 1, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>No masking</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Numerical Rating Scale (NRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours postoperative</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of postoperative pain intensity by Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) pain score (0 = no pain, 10=the worst pain imaginable): NRS evaluation was evaluated during rest and during cough (by asking the patient to cough).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>tumour necrosis alpha</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours postoperative</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of serum proinflammatory cytokines</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>interleukin 6</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours postoperative</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of serum proinflammatory cytokines</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Postoperative Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Epidural analgesia</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Lumbar epidural catheter (L3-4) was inserted in each patient before induction of general anesthesia. After induction of general anesthesia 10 ml bupivacaine 0.125% was injected through the epidural catheter, then continuous epidural infusion of 50 ml bupivacaine 0.125% at a rate of 3-5 ml/hour for 24hours postoperative.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Rectus Sheath</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Each patient received bilateral single shot ultrasound guided rectus sheath block under complete aseptic condition in a dose of 30 ml of bupivacaine 0.25% in each side immediately after induction of general anesthesia.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bupivacaine 0.125%</intervention_name>
    <description>Before induction of general anesthesia. Lumber epidural Catherine was inserted,Bupivacaine 0.125% epidural infusion started.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Epidural analgesia</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Plain marcaine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bupivacaine 0.25%</intervention_name>
    <description>After induction of general anesthesia, bilateral Ultrasound-guided Rectus Sheath Block was done by bupivacaine 0.25%</description>
    <arm_group_label>Rectus Sheath</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Plain marcaine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  ASA I-III, undergoing malignant urological surgery (cancer urinary bladder and cancer
             prostate) through midline abdominal incision under general anesthesia.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Contraindications to epidural analgesia or rectus sheath block as patient refusal,
             coagulopathy, local infection and allergy to bupivacaine. Planned transverse or
             oblique incision approach, extensive existing midline abdominal scarring or
             pre-existing chronic abdominal pain.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Waleed S Farrag</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assuit university</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assiut university faculty of medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hong JY, Lim KT. Effect of preemptive epidural analgesia on cytokine response and postoperative pain in laparoscopic radical hysterectomy for cervical cancer. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2008 Jan-Feb;33(1):44-51.</citation>
    <PMID>18155056</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 3, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 27, 2017</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Abdelrady S Ibrahim, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant professor of anesthesia and ICU</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
