<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01597388</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess safety and tolerability of AZD2014 when given in combination with Fulvestrant.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>AZD2014 and Fulvestrant in Patients With ER+ Advanced Metastatic Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Phase I, Open-label, Multicentre, Study to Assess the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Preliminary Efficacy of AZD2014 Administered Orally in Combination with Intramuscular (IM) Fulvestrant to Patients with Estrogen Receptor Positive (ER+) Advanced, Metastatic Breast Cancer.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fulvestrant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estrogens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Provision of signed and dated written informed consent prior to any study specific procedures, sampling analysis Aged at least 18 At least one lesion (measurable and/or nonmeasurable) that can be accurately assessed at baseline by computerised tomography (CT) magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) or plain Xray and is suitable for repeated assessment Histological or cytological confirmation of an ER+ advanced metastatic breast cancer tumour that is eligible for treatment with fulvestrant Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1 Patients must have evidence of nonchildbearing potential. Prior chemotherapy, biological therapy, radiation therapy, androgens, thalidomide, immunotherapy, other anticancer agents, and any investigational agents within 14 days of starting study treatment (not including palliative radiotherapy at focal sites) Major surgery within 4 weeks prior to entry to the study (excluding placement of vascular access), or minor surgery within 2 weeks of entry into the study. Patients with severe cardiac condition of ischemia, impaired ventricular function and arrhythmias, evidence of severe or uncontrolled systemic or current unstable or uncompensated respiratory or cardiac conditions. Patients with diabetes type 1 or uncontrolled type II (HbA1c &gt; 8% assessed locally)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Estrogen receptor positive</keyword>
	<keyword>Advanced metastatic breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Estrogen receptor positive advanced metastatic breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>