<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00467857</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if there is a qualitative reduction in microbial skin flora post-surgery compared to pre-surgery when a cyanoacrylate based microbial sealant is used in combination with a surgical skin preparation solution.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Combination of a Cyanoacrylate and Surgical Solutions in Reducing Skin Flora Contamination</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The CDC states that there are two sources of surgical site infection (SSI) pathogens- endogenous and exogenous. The endogenous flora of the patient's skin, mucous membranes, or hollow viscera are the source of pathogens for most SSIs. In addition to the known sources of SSI pathogen, there are also known risk factors for SSI. The risk factors for SSIs may be patient-related, or related to the preoperative, intra-operative, and post-operative surgical treatment and care of the patient. Many known risk factors that contribute to SSIs include, but are not limited to age, nutritional status, co-morbidities, length of pre-operative stay, duration of operation, preoperative skin prep, and surgical techniques. In addition, there are certain surgical procedures in which the risks for developing SSI are greater than other surgical procedures. While there are various pre-operative and post-operative techniques or approaches to prevent these infections in patients undergoing surgeries, such as pre-operative skin care techniques, appropriate use of antibiotic prophylaxis, and the use of other post-operative anti-microbial methods, by immobilizing the patient's endogenous skin flora, an opportunity exists to reduce the rate of skin flora contamination which leads to wound contamination.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Scheduled for an elective Coronary Artery Bypass Graft (CABG) surgical procedure with median sternotomy utilizing either the saphenous vein and/or radial artery as one of the graft sites within 28 days of the screening date, as documented by a Cardiothoracic Surgeon who is the Principal Investigator or subinvestigator. This includes subjects who are also receiving internal mammary artery grafts in addition to saphenous vein and/or radial artery grafts. The skin near or around the proposed incision sites should be intact. Known sensitivity or allergy to cyanoacrylate, isopropyl alcohol, iodine or iodinecontaining products or tape allergies. Female subjects that are nursing or actively lactating. Abnormal skin condition adjacent to or at the surgical incision sites. Hair removal at the surgical sites prior to entrance to the operating suite. Use of antimicrobial impregnated incise drapes (i.e. Ioban®). Hospital stay of &gt;14 days immediately prior to scheduled CABG surgery. Use of chemotherapy agents, within 30 days prior to Visit 1 screening. Scheduled for additional chemotherapy for the duration of the study. Known positive Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) with a CD4 count &lt; 350 mm3. If HIV status is not known, the subject is not excluded. Currently taking antibiotics for an infection (within 30 days prior to Visit 1). Has had therapeutic radiation to the chest within 30 days of visit 1. This does not include subjects who receive chest xrays. Preoperatively scheduled to have concomitant procedures with coronary artery bypass graft procedure. Scheduled to receive only one incision (a median sternotomy) without a planned saphenous vein graft and/or a radial artery graft donor site. Renal dialysis currently or within 30 days of visit 1. Morbid Obesity (Subjects with a Body Mass Index (BMI) &gt; 37). Neutropenia (absolute neutrophil count &lt;1000/mm3). Preoperatively on an intraaortic balloon pump or mechanical assist device. Has received an experimental drug or used an experimental medical device within 30 days prior to Visit 1. Employees of the investigator or study center with direct involvement in the proposed study or other studies under the direction of that investigator or study center. Any condition, which in the opinion of the investigator would exclude the subject from the study. Patients on steroid use for more than 1 week within 30 days of visit 1. Patients on immunosuppressive therapy within 30 days of visit 1. Depilatory creams with containing antibiotics.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>cyanoacrylates</keyword>
	<keyword>microbial sealants</keyword>
	<keyword>skin flora contamination</keyword>
	<keyword>surgery</keyword>
</DOC>