<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00467389</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the safety of intravenous cocaine in subjects receiving oral donepezil.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of Donepezil for Treatment of Cocaine Dependence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, double-blind, double-dummy, placebo controlled, inpatient, single-center, parallel group evaluation of the potential for oral donepezil to attenuate cocaine-induced craving. Non-treatment-seeking cocaine-experienced volunteers will receive baseline treatment with intravenous cocaine (30Mg). Forty-two subjects that tolerate baseline cocaine infusions will then receive two subsequent intravenous doses of cocaine during double-blind treatment with oral placebo or 5 mg daily of donepezil. Each dose of cocaine will be preceded or followed by administration of intravenous placebo (saline) in a random order.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cocaine-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Donepezil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholinesterase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cocaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Nontreatment seeking, experienced cocaine users, who have used cocaine by smoking or intravenous injection within the four weeks prior to screening, and must supply a cocainepositive urine obtained within four weeks of entry into the study. Shows signs of psychostimulant toxicity, or has a history of a medical adverse reaction to cocaine or other psychostimulants, including loss of consciousness, chest pain, cardiac ischemia, or seizure. Has a current psychiatric disorder other than drug abuse or dependence or dementia. Meets the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental DisordersIV criteria for dependence to opiates, benzodiazepines, alcohol, or other sedativehypnotics. Has received opiatesubstitution therapy (methadone or buprenorphine) within two months prior to enrollment. Has current or past history of seizure disorder, including alcohol or psychostimulant related seizures, or family history of seizure disorder. Has a diagnosis of adult asthma, or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, including a history of acute asthma within the past two years, and those with current or recent (with the past two years) treatment with an inhaled or oral betaadrenergic agonist. Has had head trauma that resulted in neurological sequelae. Has an unstable medical condition, which, in the judgement of investigators, would make participation hazardous.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acetylcholine</keyword>
	<keyword>Acetylcholinesterase</keyword>
	<keyword>Butyrylcholinesterase</keyword>
	<keyword>Cholinesterase Inhibitor</keyword>
</DOC>