<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02796625</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators will use non-invasive recordings of brain activity to measure pain as a proxy to self-report. Participants will undergo testing for about 3 hours on two separate days. The testing will involve experiencing painful heat.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Alpha as a Predictive Biomarker</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Neurophysiological investigations of pain have suggested that electroencephalograph (EEG) measures of peak alpha frequency might provide a means of pain assessment. In healthy subjects, increased peak alpha frequency is strongly correlated with pain self-reports after exposure to acute noxious heat. Conversely, chronic pain patients compared to healthy control display decreased peak alpha frequencies higher in alpha power. Measures of peak alpha frequency also show a negative relationship with disease duration, suggesting that peak alpha frequency may not only index ongoing pain but also disease progression. The overall aim is to determine the predictive accuracy, reliability, and specificity of EEG alpha activity in acute pain and a model of neuropathic pain in healthy subjects.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Able to speak, read, and write English Between 21 and 44 years of age Able to understand and willing to comply with all study procedures and is available for the duration of the study Free of an acute or chronic pain condition Not history of psychiatric or neurologic condition Unable to undergo EEG, assessed on an individual basis History of unstable major psychiatric disorder (selfreport) History of chronic pain (selfreport) More than 14 alcoholic drinks per week on average (selfreport) Active [within 6 months] substance or alcohol abuse (selfreport and urine toxicology) Use of opioids (selfreport and urine toxicology) History of major depressive disorder (selfreport) Pregnant or Lactating (women only), based on (selfreport and urine test) Anything that, in the opinion of the investigator, would place the subject at increased risk or preclude the subject's full compliance with or completion of the study Uncontrolled (systolic blood pressure &gt; 175 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;105 mmHg) or unstable hypertension</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>44 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>EEG</keyword>
	<keyword>healthy subjects</keyword>
</DOC>