<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00749177</DOC>
	<brief_summary>1. Purpose 1. Provide a culturally sensitive and supportive treatment environment for children, youth and families in the aboriginal community experiencing stress, anxiety and depression. 2. Gain insight into understanding of the role of Traditional Healing options provided by Aboriginal Healers and Helpers in the management of stress, anxiety and depression. 3. Encourage Aboriginal and First Nation clients to seek treatment earlier from a culturally supportive system. 2. Hypothesis This will be a descriptive hypothesis generating research project, however it is anticipated that members of the Aboriginal community experiencing stress, anxiety and depression may experience improved care and outcomes if their treatment includes traditional healing methods. A number of measures of subject and treatment characteristics, stress, anxiety and depression will provide the foundation for triangulation of outcomes in order to describe the impact of the various treatment options (standard care, Traditional Healing, combined standard care and Traditional Healing).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Blending Two Worlds: Traditional Aboriginal Healing Strategies for Depression and Anxiety</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Aboriginal clients, including first nation youth, may not be confident or comfortable with the standard treatments offered by the current Mental Health environment. Incorporating traditional aboriginal healing methods such as dream work, energy healing, healing circles, pipe ceremonies, self care, smudging, sweat lodge and traditional learning into standard practice will provide a culturally sensitive and supportive environment for children, youth and families experiencing stress, anxiety and depression. It is believed that Aboriginal and First Nation clients that access treatment options consistent with cultural beliefs will be encouraged to seek treatment earlier and will experience improved care and outcomes. In addition, the improved understanding of the role of traditional healing methods provided by Aboriginal Healers and Helpers in the management of these disorders will help clinicians incorporate these practices in the management of anxiety and depression</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>children and adolescents (less than 18 years of age)and families with anxiety and/or depression attending the Surrey North Child and Youth Mental Health Team. Subjects with severe anxiety or depression requiring intervention (i.e. hospitalization) or have a past or present history of suicide attempt. Subjects with special needs including medical contraindications (i.e. medical conditions including pregnancy), brain injury, developmental disability or fetal alcohol syndrome). Those subjects unwilling or unable to participate in a Traditional Healing options.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>traditional healing</keyword>
	<keyword>anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>depression</keyword>
	<keyword>aboriginal</keyword>
	<keyword>children</keyword>
	<keyword>youth</keyword>
</DOC>