<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00243204</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This Phase 3 study will compare the efficacy of talabostat plus docetaxel to docetaxel plus placebo in patients with Stage IIIB/IV NSCLC who have failed a platinum-based chemotherapy regimen.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Talabostat + Docetaxel Versus Docetaxel in Stage IIIB/IV Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC) After Failure of Platinum-Based Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Men or women age 18 years or older Histologically or cytologically confirmed NSCLC Recurrent, locally advanced or metastatic, inoperable NSCLC (Stage IIIB/IV) Patients with Stage IIIB NSCLC must have a cytologically documented pleural effusion Failed or relapsed after receiving a platinumcontaining chemotherapy regimen as firstline therapy for advanced NSCLC Measurable disease on computerized tomography (CT) scan ECOG Performance Status of 0 or 1 Expected survival ≥12 weeks Provide written informed consent EXCLUSION CRITERIA: More than 2 prior chemotherapy regimens Clinically significant laboratory abnormalities, specifically: Total bilirubin ≥ institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) Serum alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≥1.5 x ULN concomitant with alkaline phosphatase &gt;2.5 x ULN Serum creatinine ≥2.0mg/dL Absolute neutrophil count &lt;1500/μL or platelets &lt;100,000/μL Untreated or symptomatic brain metastases Any malignancy within the 5 years immediately prior to the first dose of study medication with the exception of basal cell or nonmetastatic squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, and carcinoma insitu of the cervix A history of severe hypersensitivity to drugs formulated with polysorbate 80 Any comorbidity or condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with the assessments and procedures of this protocol Patients who are within 28 days of chemotherapy, radiation therapy, immunotherapy, or other investigational medication for NSCLC. Pregnancy or lactation. Women of childbearing potential and nonvasectomized men must agree to use a barrier method of contraception.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Stage IIIb/IV non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
	<keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>