<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00243841</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the maximum tolerated dose of limited fractions of large dose radiation in an effort to achieve a biologically potent cancer therapy in selected patients with primary hepatocellular carcinoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose Escalation Study for Primary Hepatocellular Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Despite recent advances in early detection and diagnosis, only 30-40% of patients with hepatocellular carcinoma may benefit from radical therapies. Liver transplantation offers the best chance for cure. Surgical resection has been the only other potentially curative option, but the majority of patients are not candidates for resection. This reflects the usual comorbidity of severe underlying liver disease that either precludes surgery or makes the surgical approach extremely dangerous.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Evaluation by the Surgery and/or Liver Transplant Team has been performed and the patient is not considered a candidate for either "standard" therapy to target area (upper abdomen) Adequate liver function defined as: total bilirubin &lt; 3mg/dl, albumin &gt; 2.5 g/dl normal PT/PTT unless on anticoagulants mild elevation of liver enzymes acceptable (must be less than three times upper limit of normal) Adequate renal function (creatinine &lt; 1.8 mg/dl or creatinine clearance ≥ 50 ml/min) Adequate bone marrow reserve: ANC count ≥ 1500 mm3 Platelets ≥ 50,000/mm3 Hemoglobin &gt; 9 g/dL NOTE: Lab values must be obtained within 2 weeks prior to being registered for protocol therapy. No history of systemic lupus erythematous, rheumatoid arthritis, systemic sclerosis or scleroderma No chemotherapy within 14 days before radiotherapy (chemotherapy may cause transient hepatitis with hepatomegaly) No subsequent chemotherapy planned within 2 weeks of radiotherapy No active liver infection No acute Hepatitis. Definition of active disease: Hepatitis A: Acute hepatitis determined by presence of AntiHAV IgM Hepatitis B: 1. HBsAg (HB surface Antigen): present in patients with acute and chronic hepatitis 2. HBV DNA present in patients with active viral replication in amounts greater than 100,000 copies 3. HBeAg is present in wild type HBV infection and suggests active replication 4. AntiHBs: Antibody against HBsAg appears after HBV infections and confers immunity 5. AntiHBcIgM: Antibody against HBcAg, fraction IgM, present in acute infection and often could be detected during periods of high viral replication in chronic disease 6. AntiHBcIgG: is present in chronic disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>