<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01643213</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate patient preference of the Boston Scientific Corporation (BSC) commercially approved spinal cord stimulation (SCS) systems with the Observational Mechanical Gateway (OMG) in patients who failed non-BSC SCS trial therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized Study of Failed SCS Trials Comparing Outcomes Using the Observational Mechanical Gateway (OMG) Connector</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Spinal cord stimulation (SCS) is an established therapy for the treatment of chronic pain of the trunk and/or limbs. Standard practice includes a screening trial, typically lasting from 3 days to 7 days or more, for both the physician and the patient to evaluate whether SCS therapy is appropriate for permanent implantation. Screening trial success (hereafter referred to as a trial) is often considered predictive of long-term success of the therapy, although that has never been definitively demonstrated. Boston Scientific Corporation (BSC) developed the Observational Mechanical Gateway (OMG) connectors to allow patients who previously underwent an SCS trial using Medtronic or St Jude Medical leads, operating room cables (OR-cables), and external trial stimulators (ETSs), to be able to connect to BSC commercially approved Spinal Cord Stimulation (SCS) trial systems to evaluate the BSC SCS therapy in the physician office setting prior to removal of the non-BSC leads.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Chronic intractable pain of the trunk and/or lower extremities History of trunk and/or lower extremity pain lasting at least 6 months Study candidate completed a spinal cord stimulation (SCS) trial of a FDAapproved nonBoston Scientific Corporation (nonBSC) system, exclusively for the treatment of chronic intractable pain of the trunk and/or lower extremities, that will not proceed to permanent implantation due to unsatisfactory treatment or in the physician's opinion received suboptimal results Currently implanted with FDAapproved nonBSC SCS lead(s) exclusively in the thoracolumbar epidural space that are temporarily anchored for nonsurgical removal at the termination of the screening trial period and which are approved for use with either the Observational Mechanical Gateway (OMG) A or OMGM, per the OMG directions for use Key Primary source of pain is cancerrelated, pelvic, visceral or angina Investigatorsuspected gross lead migration during the nonBSC trial period which may preclude the study candidate from receiving adequate SCS therapy Study candidate reports &lt;10% paresthesia coverage of overall pain while running the preferred stimulation settings on the nonBSC SCS system at the end of the nonBSC SCS screening trial period Study candidate unwilling to tolerate implantation with an SCS system</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>