<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01643460</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to track outcomes and complications of patients at IUMC referred by physicians for EUS-guided pancreatic cyst ablation. This information is essential in order to disseminate future published information to physicians about this technique. A database will be created to track these patients undergoing an already scheduled/planned procedure. Phone calls at selected intervals will be made following the procedure to track any complications that occur</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Endoscopic Ultrasound (EUS)-Guided Ablation of Pancreatic Cysts</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Pancreatic cysts represent a wide spectrum of lesions. Many cysts are uniformly benign (pseudocysts) or have negligible malignant potential (serous cystadenomas). However, others represent premalignant (i.e. intraductal papillary mucinous neoplasms (IPMNs) or mucinous cystadenomas [MCN]), or malignant (i.e. invasive IPMNs or mucinous cystadenocarcinomas) tumors. Management of pancreatic cysts is challenging but surgery is generally recommended for cysts that are symptomatic, premalignant (except possibly branch duct IPMNs) or demonstrate malignancy by imaging features and/or biopsy. However, even in experienced hospitals, surgical resection or enucleation of pancreatic cystic tumors is associated with significant perioperative morbidity and mortality rates of 20-40% and up to 2%, respectively.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cysts</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Cyst</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystadenoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystadenoma, Mucinous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients referred between January 2009 and February 2016 to EUS at IUMC for pancreatic cyst ablation and with no contraindications for anticipated safe and successful performance of the procedure. 2. Patient at least 18 years of age. 1. Investigator deems cyst does not meet safety or need for cyst ablation. 2. Subject not competent to sign consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Intraductal papillary mucinous neoplasms (IPMNs)</keyword>
	<keyword>Mucinous cystadenomas [MCN])</keyword>
	<keyword>Invasive IPMNs or mucinous cystadenocarcinomas) tumors</keyword>
</DOC>