<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03065296</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This project will encompass an evaluation of the educational value of having evidence based home exercise protocols available for family medicine residents in regard to the prescription of home exercise treatment for common musculoskeletal conditions. Investigators will be evaluating resident knowledge on home exercise prescription as well as their level of comfort in educating their patients before and after a series of didactic sessions and implementation of exercise protocols.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Standardized Home Exercise Prescription Education</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study aims to fill the gap in this area of the literature pertaining to home exercise prescription. The justification of this study's scientific merit comes from the lack of literature and the need for research in this area. There have been multiple studies that have shown different exercise modality treatments for common musculoskeletal (MSK) complaints significantly improve both disability and overall quality of life. Despite the evidence of the short and long term effectiveness of exercise based therapies, there is a general lack of confidence of residents in prescribing and teaching patients rehab exercises.Additionally, many of the patients seen in the University of Florida (UF) Family medicine residency program cannot afford or do not have time to attend physical therapist led rehab sessions. This makes physician led education and the ability of prescribing exercise based treatments for musculoskeletal (MSK) complaints a very important component of patient care.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Resident of the Family Medicine Department at the University of Florida.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>education</keyword>
	<keyword>medical residents</keyword>
	<keyword>knowledge</keyword>
	<keyword>confidence</keyword>
	<keyword>skills assessment</keyword>
</DOC>