<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01256450</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether buprenorphine hydrochloride (HCl) buccal film is effective and safe in the treatment of chronic low back pain (CLBP).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Study of Buprenorphine HCl Buccal Film in Subjects With Low Back Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an enriched enrollment, randomized withdrawal study with an open label, dose-titration period followed by a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled treatment period of 12 weeks. During the double-blind treatment period, this study will evaluate the effectiveness of buprenorphine HCl buccal film versus placebo buccal film in treating CLBP in subjects. Buprenorphine HCl buccal film is an oral transmucosal form of the opioid analgesic, buprenorphine hydrochloride, intended for application to the buccal mucosa. Buprenorphine is a synthetic opioid that is classified as a partial µ-receptor agonist and a Schedule III controlled substance in the United States.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Buprenorphine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or nonpregnant and nonnursing female aged 18 or older History of moderate to severe chronic low back pain for ≥3 months with a pain intensity ≥5 [11 point numerical rating scale] reported at the openlabel titration period Day 0/1 visit following a washout period (opioids, nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs [NSAIDs], and muscle relaxants) of approximately 12 to 24 hours Currently taking ≤60 mg oral morphine/day or equianalgesic dose of another opioid (including opioid naïve) for 1 week or longer Stable health, as determined by the Investigator, on the basis of medical history, physical examination, and screening laboratory results so as to comply with all study procedures Female subjects of childbearing potential must be using a recognized effective method of birth control Written informed consent obtained at Screening, prior to any procedure being performed Reflex sympathetic dystrophy or causalgia (complex regional pain syndrome), acute spinal cord compression, cauda equina compression, acute nerve root compression, meningitis, and discitis Surgical procedure for back pain within 2 months prior to screening or nerve/plexus block within 4 weeks of screening Hypokalemia or clinically unstable cardiac disease, including: unstable atrial fibrillation, symptomatic bradycardia, unstable congestive heart failure, or active myocardial ischemia Corrected QT (QTc) interval of &gt;450 milliseconds on the 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG) History of long QT syndrome, or an immediate family member with this condition Diagnosis of moderate to severe hepatic impairment. History of severe emesis with opioids Clinically significant sleep apnea</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>buccal soluble film</keyword>
	<keyword>enriched enrollment</keyword>
	<keyword>randomized withdrawal</keyword>
</DOC>