<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01256242</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study Purpose: To evaluate the safety and performance of Augment Rotator Cuff as a primary surgical treatment for full thickness rotator cuff tears. The hypothesis is that Augment Rotator Cuff will be easy to deliver as an inter-positional graft placed between the rotator cuff tendon and the humeral head providing further enhanced tendon to bone healing without adding any additional safety risk to the patient. Study Rationale: To evaluate the safety and performance Augment™ Rotator Cuff in surgical intervention of a torn rotator cuff and to obtain preliminary data to support the rationale for a subsequent pivotal clinical trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Study of Augment Rotator Cuff for Surgical Treatment of Full Thickness Rotator Cuff Tears</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>The subject has a repairable rotator cuff tear with an estimated full thickness size of ≥ 2 cm to &lt; 5 cm confirmed with diagnostic MRI in AP or ML dimension The subject is independent, ambulatory, and can comply with all postoperative evaluations and visits The subject is at least twenty one (21) years of age and considered to be skeletally mature. The subject has undergone previous rotator cuff repair surgery to the affected shoulder The subject has a partial thickness rotator cuff tear The subject requires a concomitant subscapularis repair The subject requires a concomitant labral repair The subject has an irreparable rotator cuff tear The subject has an allergy to yeastderived products or a known bovine collagen allergy The subject has implanted metallic devices (cardiac pacemakers, insulin pumps, and nerve stimulators), medically implanted clips or other electronically, magnetically or mechanically activated implants that would contraindicate undergoing an MRI scan of the shoulder The subject has tested positive or has been treated for a malignancy in the past or is suspected of having a malignancy or is currently undergoing radiation or chemotherapy treatment for a malignancy anywhere in the body, whether adjacent to or distant from the proposed Augment Rotator Cuff implantation site The subject's condition represents a worker's compensation case The subject is currently involved in a healthrelated litigation procedure The subject is pregnant or able to become pregnant but not practicing a medicallyaccepted form of birth control, and/or intending to become pregnant during this study period</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>tendon</keyword>
	<keyword>shoulder</keyword>
	<keyword>rotator cuff</keyword>
	<keyword>Glenohumeral</keyword>
</DOC>