<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="60146">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02322970</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>impr14</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02322970</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Invasive Versus Non Invasive Measurement of Intracranial Pressure in Brain Injury Trial (IMPRESSIT)</brief_title>
  <acronym>IMPRESSIT</acronym>
  <official_title>Invasive Versus Non Invasive Measurement of Intracranial Pressure in Brain Injury Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Università degli Studi di Brescia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Università degli Studi di Brescia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Investigators aim to assess sensitivity and specificity of transcranial doppler in
      determining intracranial hypertension in all patients admitted to intensive care unit for
      brain injury and needing Intracranial Pressure (ICP) monitoring (according to international
      guidelines). Non invasive ICP measurement through the use of transcranial doppler will be
      carried out before and after standard invasive ICP monitoring placement; a head computed
      tomography (CT) scan will also be performed before and after interventions.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      As part of intensive treatment of brain injury, intracranial pressure (ICP) should be
      controlled when the cerebral perfusion pressure (CPP) falls below 60-70 millimeters of
      mercury (mmHg) (depending on the cause of injury) and/or the ICP is greater than 20 mmHg.
      Intracranial hypertension (ICHP) occurs in approximately 40% of all patients with severe
      traumatic brain injury and is not infrequent in patients with non traumatic brain injury,
      such as subarachnoid hemorrhage (SAH), spontaneous intracerebral hemorrhage (SICH), and
      ischemic stroke (IS), and the presence of ICHP and inadequate CPP has been correlated to
      poor outcome. Therefore, measures to monitor ICP and CPP should be instituted as soon as
      possible in patients with severe brain injury. Currently, available methods for ICP
      monitoring include epidural, subdural, subarachnoid, parenchymal, and ventricular locations.
      Historically, ventricular ICP catheter has been used as the reference standard and the
      preferred technique when possible. It is the most accurate, and reliable method of
      monitoring ICP. Subarachnoid, subdural, and epidural monitors are less accurate.
      Unfortunately, all of the described methods are invasive, associated with a complication
      rate and are not inexpensive. For this reason, new methods have been developed in order to
      measure ICP non invasively. One of which uses Transcranial Doppler (TCD): by using a
      low-frequency-pulsed Doppler of 2 Mega Hertz (MHz) over the acoustic window regions—where
      the skull bone is thin—or at the foramen magnum, it is possible to measure flow velocities
      in the basal cerebral arteries. Many formulas have been described to correlate Flow
      Velocities and ICP: in our study, we use the method introduced and tested by Schmidt et Al.
      in 2000. Those authors observed a relationship among mean arterial blood pressure (ABP)
      diastolic flow velocity (FVd) and mean flow velocity (FVm) in the middle cerebral artery
      (MCA) that led them to find a formula able to yield CPP (estimated CPP: ABP x FVd / FVm +
      14); once CPP is estimated, ICPtcd is easily calculated (ICP= ABP- CPP). The first aim of
      our study is to evaluate the sensitivity and specificity of ICPtcd, compared to invasive ICP
      measurement, in order to exclude elevated ICP in patients with acute brain injury such as
      epidural hematomas (EDH), subdural hematomas (SDH), subarachnoid hemorrhage (SAH),
      intraparenchymal hemorrhage (IPH), ischaemic strokes (IS), traumatic brain injury (TBI); the
      secondary outcome is the correlation of ICPtcd to ischemia on brain CT scan and to Glasgow
      outcome scale (GOS) at discharge and at three months. Inclusion criteria are: acute brain
      injury, patients requiring invasive ICP monitoring and Age &gt; 18 yrs; exclusion criteria are:
      inaccessible ultrasound window and patients who receive craniotomy before ICP probe
      placement. The sample size is about 250 patients. All patients included will have evaluation
      of non-invasive ICP monitoring through use of TCD (ICPtcd), and at least three TCD
      Measurements will be performed and correlated with non-invasive ICP. The timing for the TCD
      measurements and correlations will be as follows:

        -  1° measurement: will be performed before, and as close as possible, to ICP monitoring
           probe placement.

        -  2° measurement. Immediately following ICP monitoring probe placement;

        -  3° measurement: after ICP management optimization.

      A CT scan must be performed before the first measurement and after the third one. All
      patients will receive standard clinical treatment according to the international guidelines
      for the treatment of various types of brain injury.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Receiver operator curve (ROC) curve for non invasive ICP evaluated by transcranial doppler</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation coefficient between non invasive ICP and Glasgow Outcome Scale (GOS) at discharge and at three months</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">250</enrollment>
  <condition>Intracranial Hypertension</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intracranial Pressure monitoring</arm_group_label>
    <description>Invasive Intracranial Pressure monitoring will be compared to non invasive intracranial monitoring ( through use of transcranial Doppler ).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>transcranial Doppler</intervention_name>
    <description>Comparison of non invasive intracranial pressure (through use of transcranial Doppler ) vs invasive monitoring (through insertion of intracerebral catheters) with the purpose of comparing these two techniques in terms of specificity and sensitivity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intracranial Pressure monitoring</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients with brain injury, at risk of developing intracranial hypertension, requiring
        invasive intracranial pressure monitoring.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Brain injury (All patients with brain injury, at risk of developing intracranial
             hypertension, requiring invasive intracranial pressure monitoring. );

          -  Patients requiring invasive ICP monitoring;

          -  Age &gt; 18 yrs.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  inaccessible ultrasound window;

          -  decompressive craniotomy before ICP placement.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Frank A Rasulo, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Neuro-Intensive Care, Spedali Civili Accademic Hospital, University of Brescia, Italy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Frank A Rasulo, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+390303995</phone>
    <phone_ext>841</phone_ext>
    <email>frank.rasulo@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Spedali Civili, Neuro Critical Care Unit.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brescia</city>
        <zip>25100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Frank Rasulo</last_name>
      <email>frank.rasulo@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>December 3, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>November 10, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Università degli Studi di Brescia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Frank Rasulo</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>NEURO CRITICAL CARE UNIT'S CHIEF</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>intracranial hypertension</keyword>
  <keyword>tcd</keyword>
  <keyword>non invasive</keyword>
  <keyword>ICP</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Intracranial Hypertension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
