<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00704496</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The hypothesis is that pseudoephedrine, a sympathomimetic amine commonly used as a decongestant, will decrease nasal congestion leading to increased patency of the nose and a decrease in nighttime sleep fragmentation in individuals with year round perennial allergic rhinitis (PAR). This decrease in sleep fragmentation will reduce daytime somnolence and fatigue.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Pseudoephedrine on Rhinitis and Sleep</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pseudoephedrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ephedrine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 18 to 65. 2. History of allergic rhinitis. 3. The ability to be placed on placebo without significant compromise in the quality of life. 4. General good health. 5. Ability to comply with the protocol and sign an informed consent. 6. Have daytime sleepiness by history. 7. Have poor sleep by history. 8. Have fatigue by history. 9. Have a skin test or RAST test to a perennial allergen (indoor mold, dog, cat, mite) with correlating symptoms. 1. Age fewer than 18 or over 65 years. 2. A history of sleep apnea. 3. Atopic diseases other than allergic rhinitis, such as atopic dermatitis or asthma. 4. Nonallergic rhinitis. 5. Hypertension 6. Diabetes Mellitus 7. Inability to tolerate pseudoephedrine 8. Significant other diseases as determined by the investigator. 9. Use of a research medication within 30 days. 10. Use of a nasal steroid or topical antihistamine or decongestant within 30 days. 11. Use of betablockers, antidepressants, oral decongestants, oral steroids, or H2blockers. 12. Excessive use of alcohol or drug abuse. 13. Inability to stop medication use during runin period. 14. Use of an oral antihistamine within 1 week of enrollment. 15. Failed to have benefit when pseudoephedrine was used for rhinitis or asthma in the past</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sleep, Pseudoephedrine</keyword>
</DOC>