<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01368406</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aims of this study were to evaluate the efficacy of an intervention for weight gain management for patients from schizophrenia spectrum compared to treatment as usual (TAU), and to evaluate the effects of this program on metabolic profile, symptoms and quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lifestyle Intervention for Weight Gain Management for Patients With Schizophrenia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study took place on four institutions: Schizophrenia Program (PROESQ- Universidade Federal de São Paulo), Schizophrenia Program of Institute of Psychiatry PROJESQ (Universidade de São Paulo), CAISM (Centro de Atenção Integrada à Saúde Mental) from Irmandade Santa Casa de Misericórdia de São Paulo, and CAPS Luiz da Rocha Cerqueira, all in the city of São Paulo. Participants were randomly assigned to an intervention group or a standard care group using table of randomization from web site www.randomization.com. The patients' weights were recorded monthly. All patients were weighed in the morning, on the same scale, without shoes, with the individuals wearing light clothes. Waist was considered at the level of the navel. Measures were collected by the same investigator in all assessments. Body mass index (BMI) was calculated as the weight in kilograms divided by the square of the height in meters. The investigators recorded sociodemographic data, clinical data and physical exam (weight, height, BMI, waist circumference and blood pressure). Patients were diagnosed as having schizophrenia by the SCID-P (REF). Severity of the disease was assessed using PANSS, Calgary Depression Scale, CGI-S and CGI-I. GAF, ILSS-BR, and he following self-rated scales: WHOQoL-BREF, Rosenberg self-esteem scale, IPAQ, DINE and Fagerstrom were used to evaluate functionality (GAF), independent living skills (ILSS-BR), quality of life (WHOQoL-BREF), self esteem (Rosenberg self-esteem scale), physical activity (IPAQ- short version), fat and fibers ingestion (DINE), and smoking (Fagerstrom). Raters were kept blind for patient's treatment condition. Fasting glucose, total cholesterol, HDL, LDL, triglycerides, insulin, and HOMA-IR index were assessed at baseline, and 3 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Gain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Eligible patients were between 18 and 65 years of age, were on an antipsychotic medication, were asymptomatic (PANSS ≤ 60), had outpatient status and a DSMIV diagnosis of schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder or other psychosis, and presented some interest on themes of program. a history of diabetes mellitus, eating disorders (anorexia and bulimia), drug or alcohol abuse, and an acute psychotic state in need of intensive management. There was no use of medication for weight control for the subjects during the intervention and followup period.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>weight gain</keyword>
	<keyword>intervention</keyword>
</DOC>