<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01368341</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Tick borne diseases are increasing in Norway. Lyme borreliosis is the most common infection. Erythema migrans is mainly diagnosed and treated in general practice. There is disagreement about what antibiotic treatment that should be given. An RCT with the three most common antibiotics used, will support data for revision of national guidelines.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparing 3 Antibiotic Regimes for Erythema Migrans in General Practice</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Comparison of phenoxymethylpenicillin, doxycycline and amoxicillin for Erythema migrans in Norwegian general practice. Every patient receives 14 days of antibiotic treatment. There are blood samples for measurement of Borrelia antibody level at day 1, 14 and 90 and questionnaires on subjective health complaints (SHC) at day 1, 90 and 360. Side symptoms and side effects are registered. For volunteers there is an additional PCR-analysis on punch biopsy from the EM for subgrouping of the Borrelia bacteria. TBE-antibodies are measured on day 14. Antibody levels and SHC-scores are compared to healthy blood donors.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Erythema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erythema Chronicum Migrans</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glossitis, Benign Migratory</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lyme Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxycycline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amoxicillin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Penicillin V</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of Erythema migrans Over the age of 18 Signing an concent form after information in writing Allergic to any of the three drugs in the study Under the age of 18 Pregnancy Dementia or known drug abuse Antibiotic treatment last 14 days Concommitant Chemotherapy or immunomodulating therapy Concommitant use of medicine with potential interaction (defined in protocol)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Antibiotics</keyword>
	<keyword>General Practice</keyword>
	<keyword>Erythema migrans</keyword>
	<keyword>Borrelia</keyword>
	<keyword>Ticks</keyword>
</DOC>