<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="69474">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02201381</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Metabolic Cancer 001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02201381</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of the Safety, Tolerability and Efficacy of Metabolic Combination Treatments on Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>METRICS</acronym>
  <official_title>Prospective Observational Study of the Safety, Tolerability and Efficacy of Metabolic Combination of Existing Medicines on Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Health Clinics Limited</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Health Clinics Limited</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the effectiveness of a regimen of selected
      metabolic treatments for patients with cancer in a real world setting and to conduct
      exploratory analysis on the relationship between the degree of response and changes in
      biochemical markers (such as glucose and lipid levels).
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a real world study since this gives the best opportunity to properly examine the
      effect of multi-drug regimens in representative populations. Including a standard of care
      arm is inappropriate, in a population in which that standard of care has already been shown
      to be ineffective or intolerable.

      Patients will be sent to the study clinic directly by their Health Care Professionals
      (&quot;HCP's&quot;) .

      The study will consist of a pre-screening visit to determine eligibility for inclusion into
      the study, an initiation visit and then a follow up visit every three months thereafter. If
      required, unscheduled visits may take place. Day 0 (baseline) for each patient will be the
      initiation visit when study treatment is started.

      Prior to conducting any study-related procedures, subjects will provide written informed
      consent, eligibility will be assessed, a medical history and past medical records will be
      taken and vital signs will be measured. These records will include the stage of their
      disease, response to previous cancer therapy, their prior and current medications and any
      specific regimen they are currently on for their cancer. If prior medical records do not
      contain sufficient information to determine a baseline for the patient, additional blood
      tests and scans will be undertaken as appropriate.

      Patients will be monitored quarterly thereafter when blood tests (e.g. safety parameters,
      glucose, cholesterol, immune response and cancer markers where applicable) and scans (where
      applicable) will be taken.

      Patients will complete a quality of life questionnaire at baseline and then every 3 months.
      This will comprise the generic EQ-5D instrument and a disease- specific questionnaire (FACT
      or European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Quality of Life Questionnaire
      [EORTC-QLQ]).

      All patients will be on the same drug regimen (see below) at the same doses throughout the
      study. All patients will be followed up until they choose to leave the study, or death.

      Data from all patients recruited to the study will be analysed using an Intention-to-treat
      (ITT) philosophy, so data will be included in the primary analysis irrespective of whether
      the dose regimen was followed throughout the study. If appropriate, and numbers allow,
      analysis will also be conducted on the Per Protocol population, comprising those patients
      who adhere to the regimen as prescribed.

      Survival analysis methods will be used to estimate the PFS associated with the study regimen
      for each type of cancer. Estimates of PFS will be presented for various time points (to be
      specified) with associated confidence intervals. These estimates will be interpreted in the
      light of data obtained from the literature, and from eliciting expert opinion. Bayesian
      methods may be used where appropriate.

      Overall survival will be investigated in a similar way.

      The pattern of response to the regimen on quality of life will be investigated using
      repeated measures, mixed models analysis of variance to derive estimates of the change in
      EQ-VAS and utility scores derived from the EQ-5D at key time points. The data may also be
      used to calculate Quality-adjusted Life Years (QALYs) for use in health economic evaluation.
      Similar methods will be used for the disease-specific instrument. The estimated changes will
      be interpreted in the light of published data on meaningful changes in these variables.
      Separate estimates will be produced for each type of cancer if appropriate. Data will be
      shown in graphs.

      Tumour response, where applicable, will be summarised in tables and graphs. Estimates of
      response rates will be presented for each cancer type with confidence intervals.

      The relationship between changes in biochemistry values (glucose, lipids) and efficacy
      outcomes (Progression Free Survival (PFS), Overall Survival (OS) and HRQoL) will be
      investigated graphically, or using other methods as appropriate.

      Further exploratory analysis to investigate the effects of other factors such as age ,
      ethnic backgrounds , cancer stage, and response to prior therapy, will also be conducted in
      order to try and characterise the profile of patients most likely to benefit from the study
      regimen.

      The characteristics of patients on the regimen and those who do not stay on the regimen, for
      whatever reason, will be summarised to see whether there is any observed bias. If
      appropriate, methods will be used to adjust for any observed bias, for example using
      propensity scores. OS can then be assessed adjusted for this to try and mitigate for any
      possible risk of bias which can occur in uncontrolled studies. Furthermore, by enrolling all
      eligible patients over a specified time frame, it is hoped that the risk of bias should be
      further reduced. In addition, a large number of patients are expected to participate in the
      study.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Pending discussions with regulatory and ethics bodies
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>October 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>5 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Patients will continue to be monitored for as long as possible thereafter in order to provide data on overall survival.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Health related quality of life (HRQoL)assessment using Patient Reported Outcome Measures (PROMS). It is intended to use both generic (EQ-5D) and disease specific instruments (FACT-G or EORTC-QLQ)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Tumour Response</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Changes to tumour size and type will be measured where applicable as well as any blood markers for tumours if available</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood Glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events reported by the subject or their HCP.
Quarterly assessment of routine laboratory tests</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cholesterol Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Total cholesterol LDL Levels HDL Levels LDL/HDL Ratios</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2000</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Quality of Life</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Metabolic Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with all types of metastatic cancers and for those whom standard of care treatment options are not available
Atorvastatin 80mg once daily Metformin up to 1000mg once a day, increased to twice a day if tolerated after 2 weeks Doxycycline 100mg a day for 1 month alternated with Mebendazole 100mg once a day (after Doxycycline) for 1 month</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood Serum Tissue
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All Cancer Patients with metastatic disease
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Male or female 18-85 years old meeting one or more of the following criteria:

               -  Metastatic disease

               -  Unable to tolerate standard of care

               -  Standard of care ineffective

               -  Standard of care side effects unacceptable

               -  Standard of care declined by patient

               -  Patient fail inclusion criteria for other cancer clinical trials

          -  Able to understand study requirements, agree to its provisions and to give written
             informed consent

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Major organ failure, renal, lung and liver failure

          -  Ilium, colon or stomach part or full removal

          -  Mentally incapacitated

          -  Has known or suspected problem with alcohol or drug abuse

          -  Is direct employee of the study site
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Justin Stebbing, MD MA PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Care Oncology Clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Angus Dalgleish, MD FRACP</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Care Oncology Clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Care Oncology Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>W1G 9PP</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>September 27, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 22, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer Treatments</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer Palliative Care</keyword>
  <keyword>Metabolic</keyword>
  <keyword>Metabolism</keyword>
  <keyword>Existing Medicines</keyword>
  <keyword>Licensed Medicines</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
  <keyword>Real World</keyword>
  <keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Triple Negative Breast Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Colon Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Prostrate Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Brain Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Ovarian Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>AML</keyword>
  <keyword>CML</keyword>
  <keyword>Leukemea</keyword>
  <keyword>Metformin</keyword>
  <keyword>Statins</keyword>
  <keyword>Mebendazole</keyword>
  <keyword>Doxycycline</keyword>
  <keyword>Ibuprofen</keyword>
  <keyword>Metastatic</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Doxycycline</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mebendazole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
