<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02484248</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a double-blind, placebo -controlled, cross-over trial of ketotifen in children ages 8 through 17 inclusive that have a diagnosis of Functional Dyspepsia and have had continued pain despite acid reduction therapy in combination with montelukast. This study is 147 days for subjects responsive to the ketotifen and 63 days for those who are not. The study includes scheduled visits including a physical, blood draws, and questionaires.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial of Ketotifen in Children and Adolescents</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary aim is to assess the symptomatic response to ketotifen as compared to placebo in children and adolescents with functional dyspepsia in association with duodenal eosinophilia who have previously had worsening, no clinical change, or only a partial response to acid-reduction therapy in combination with montelukast. Secondary aims include: 1) assessing the impact of ketotifen as compared to placebo on quality of life; 2) assessing the impact of ketotifen as compared to placebo on state and trait anxiety; 3) assessing whether baseline trait anxiety is predictive of clinical response to ketotifen; 4) assessing whether functional dyspepsia subtype is predictive of response to ketotifen, 5) assessing the sustainability of response to ketotifen in initial responders, and 6) assessing the pharmacokinetics of ketotifen in this patient population.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dyspepsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ketotifen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. between the ages of 8 and 17 years, inclusive 2. abdominal pain of at least 8 weeks duration and fulfilling symptombased criteria for functional dyspepsia(5); 3. previous endoscopy with biopsies demonstrating &gt;20 eosinophils/high powered field on duodenal mucosal biopsies; 4. previous treatment with acidreduction therapy and montelukast with a level 3 (as defined below)or lesser response; 5. evidence of written parental permission (consent) and subject assent; 6. Negative pregnancy screening for females of child bearing potential. 1. previous treatment with ketotifen; 2. treatment with corticosteroids or oral cromolyn sodium in the four weeks prior to enrollment; 3. any prior history of diabetes mellitus, cancer, chronic cardiac disease, respiratory disease, or renal disease requiring routine medical care; 4. Pregnant/planning to become pregnant; 5. Postmenarche females unwilling to use highlyefficacious contraception to prevent pregnancy; 6. Epilepsy or history of seizures; 7. Liver disease or elevation of liver enzymes; 8. Use of oral hypoglycemic medications, antipsychotics, benzodiazepines, tricyclic antidepressants, barbiturates, or opioids; 9. Allergy to ketotifen or other products in capsule 10. Refusal of Urine pregnancy test in postmenarchal females.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>