<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02945735</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether giving gaze-contingent feedback is an effective attention modification procedure, helping in the treatment of Major Depressive Disorder (MDD)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gaze Contingent Feedback in Major Depressive Disorder (MDD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study examines giving depressive participants gaze-contingent feedback as a novel attention training procedure. Half of the participants will receive contingent feedback while the other half would receive non-contingent "placebo" feedback.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A signed consent form Men and women between the ages of 18 and 65. Meeting a current diagnosis of Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) according to the DSMIV MDD as the primary diagnosis: In cases of comorbidity, MDD will be deemed as the most distressing and clinically significant condition among the comorbid disorders Stable pharmacotherapy: Participants receiving a pharmacological treatment who are taking a stable medication for at least 3 months before the beginning of the procedure. Psychotic episode in the past or the present time. Comorbidity with any neurological disorder (i.e., epilepsy, brain injury). Another psychotherapeutic treatment during the study. Usage of neuroleptic medication. Change in medication status during the study. Substantial usage of drugs or alcohol in the present time. Poor judgment capacity (i.e., children under 18 and special populations). High Risk of Suicide.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>depression</keyword>
	<keyword>cognitive bias modification</keyword>
	<keyword>MDD</keyword>
	<keyword>major depressive disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>attention bias modification treatment</keyword>
</DOC>