<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02945488</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objectives are to: 1) Assess the independent and synergistic efficacy of exercise and nutrition interventions to manage major symptomatic concerns of inflammatory bowel diseases (IBD), 2) Assess the independent and synergistic efficacy of exercise and nutrition to mitigate inflammation in IBD, and 3) Assess the feasibility of such an intervention in preconception women with IBD. The investigators hypothesize that the combination of anti-inflammatory exercise and nutritional interventions will have a synergistic effect on managing major symptomatic concerns associated with IBD, reducing inflammation, and improving fertility status in preconception women with IBD, as compared to either intervention independently.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Exercise and Nutrition in IBD &amp; Preconception</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Potential participants will be recruited from the Preconception and Pregnancy Clinic recently established within the Saskatchewan Multidisciplinary Inflammatory Bowel Disease Clinic [MDIBDC]. Eligible participants will be randomized [stratified] to one of four groups: 1) Exercise and dietary plan, 2) Exercise and no dietary plan, 3) Stretching [placebo exercise] and dietary plan, 4) Stretching and no dietary plan. Participants will be assessed at baseline, midway [3 months], and post-intervention [6 months] for indications of disease activity, quality of life, fertility status, and bone health.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Intestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female Confirmed diagnosis of Inflammatory Bowel Disease Childbearing age Currently following a Mediterranean diet Currently performing resistance training on a regular basis (within the past 6 months) Failed Physical Activity Readiness QuestionnairePlus (PARQ+). Past ileal pouch anal anastomosis Unstable or uncontrolled cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic, renal, gastrointestinal, or other medical disorder that, in the opinion of the investigator, would confound the study results or compromise subject safety</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>