<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02945072</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to investigate long-lasting or later behavioral changes in children in the context of different anesthesia techniques (Inhalation anesthesia vs. TIVA)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Study of Behavior Problems in Children After Different Anesthesia Methods</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The process of surgery and anaesthesia can be an extremely frightening and stressful event for a child, and is frequently followed by negative postoperative behavioural changes. This Event could be associated with poor postoperative outcome and long term behavior problems like anxiety, eating or sleeping disorders. The aim of this study is to investigate long-lasting or later behavioral changes in children in the context of different anesthesia techniques (Inhalation anesthesia vs. TIVA). After anesthesia initiation, anesthesia maintenance should be done with sevoflurane or Tiva. The effect of behavioral changes in children in the context of anesthesia techniques should be evaluate by post hospitalisation behavior questionaire at first, second and fourth week. Early postoperative problems like postoperative nausea and vomiting, pain level, pain therapy and postoperative awareness should be evaluate too.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Problem Behavior</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sevoflurane</mesh_term>
	<criteria>elective Operation operation in general anesthesia in combination with regional anesthesia Age 210 years ASA classification 1 or 2 (without severe basic disease or disability) Lack of Consensus general anesthesia during the last 3 months before or 4 weeks after the procedure PONV prophylaxis with droperidol severe known growth factor mental preexisting conditions and behavioral abnormalities contraindications for one of the used study medications insufficient regional anesthesia secondary intervention within of the 4week followup</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Child Behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>Problem Behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>postoperative behaviour problems</keyword>
</DOC>