<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02983084</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this randomized clinical trial (RCT) is to compare traditional CuNiTi archwires and a recently marketed multiforce version of the same material for the initial alignment and leveling of dental arches, as well as the expression of EARR in adult orthodontic patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Orthodontic Archwire Comparison Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized clinical trial utilizing multiforce and CuNiTi orthodontic archwires to align and level dental arches and compare their results. A three group double blind parallel single site study at IUSD will be used. Patients that meet the inclusion and exclusion criteria will be recruited from the IUSD orthodontic clinic. The subjects will be randomly assigned to one of the three groups by the study statistician. Subjects, examiners providing subject treatment, and examiners measuring study outcomes will be blinded to treatment assignment. Study population indicates a sample size of 105 subjects, each group containing 35 clinical subjects. Patients will be treated with Ormco Titanium Orthos fixed appliances and defined archwire sequence according to a clinical protocol. During the six-month study period, subjects will be seen approximately every 4 (four) weeks for regular standard of care appointments that will include archwire monitoring, photography and questionnaire completions. Final study records will be taken at the end of the study period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malocclusion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult &gt;18yrs of age Amenable to treatment with metal brackets Crowding of 38mm in one or both arches (nonextraction treatment) Overbite &gt;3mm Read and speak English without a translator Individuals in good general health at the discretion of the investigator(s) Medical/Dental History (Hx): Documented metabolic disorder(s) Nickel allergy Bisphosphonate treatment Amelogenesis, dentinogenesis or osteogenesis imperfect Active caries or periodontal disease Root resorption (moderate to severe) Patients who are pregnant or breast feeding or plan to be pregnant during the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Orthodontic wires</keyword>
	<keyword>Root resorption</keyword>
</DOC>