<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02099617</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of the SENIOR study is to establish the efficacy and safety of the everolimus eluting stent with a biodegradable abluminal polymer (SYNERGY II) associated with a short dual antiplatelet therapy (DAPT) in patients ≥75 years old, suffering from stable angina, silent ischemia (1 month DAPT) or acute coronary syndromes (6 months DAPT) related to significant coronary artery disease and requiring percutaneous coronary intervention. The primary end point is to demonstrate that SYNERGY II in patients ≥75 years old is associated with a lower rate of the composite rate of major cardiovascular and cerebrovascular events (all-cause death, myocardial infarction, stroke, ischemia-driven target lesion revascularization) and a similar risk of stent thrombosis than bare metal stent at one year.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of New Generation Drug Eluting Stents Associated With an Ultra Short Duration of Dual Antiplatelet Therapy. Design of the Short Duration of Dual antiplatElet Therapy With SyNergy II Stent in Patients Older Than 75 Years Undergoing Percutaneous Coronary Revascularization.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angina, Stable</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1 Patient is ≥ 75 years old 2 One or more significant coronary artery stenosis is/are present (defined as ≥70% by visual assessment or ≥50% with Fractional Flow Reserve &lt;0.80) or a left main coronary stenosis ≥50% by visual assessment) suitable for PCI with one of the following present: a Silent ischemia, stressinduced myocardial ischemia ≥ 10% of myocardium in a asymptomatic patient or stressinduced myocardial ischemia &lt; 10% of myocardium AND FFR (Fractional Flow Reserve) ≤0.80 or b Stable angina, in a patient with objective ischemia despite optimal medical therapy or c acute coronary syndrome including: unstable angina, non ST and ST elevation myocardial infarction. 3 All patients must also sign informed consent as per local law and comply with all study process during follow up for at least one year. 1 The subject is not eligible for randomization if ANY of the following is present: 2 Indication for myocardial revascularization by coronary artery bypass grafting, 3 Subjects unable to tolerate, obtain or comply with dual antiplatelet therapy for at least one month (stable angina or silent ischemia) or at least six month (acute coronary syndrome), 4 Subjects requiring additional surgery (cardiac or noncardiac) within one month, 5 Non cardiac comorbidities with life expectancy less than 1 year, 6 Prior hemorrhagic stroke, 7 Known allergy to aspirin or P2Y12 inhibitors, 8 At least one contra indication to ALL the authorized P2Y12 inhibitors at the requested dose (in case of contra indication to only one of two of the P2Y12 inhibitors, the investigators are allowed to use the P2Y12 inhibitors for which no allergy is known). 9 Silent ischemia &lt;10% of the myocardium with FFR ≥0.80. 10 Participation in another clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>75 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>