<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02099058</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1/1b open-label study evaluating the safety, pharmacokinetics (PK), and preliminary efficacy of ABBV-399 in subjects with advanced solid tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 1/1b Study With ABBV-399, an Antibody Drug Conjugate, in Subjects With Advanced Solid Cancer Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subject must have advanced solid tumor that is not amenable to surgical resection or other approved therapeutic options that have demonstrated clinical benefit but based on evidence gathered in this study or from external sources, the Sponsor in consultation with the Investigators, may decide to limit to specific tumor types. 2. Subject has an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 to 2. 3. Subject must have measurable disease per Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1. 4. Subject has one archived diagnostic formalinfixed paraffin embedded (FFPE) tumor tissue confirmed available for analyses. 5. Subject has adequate bone marrow, renal, and hepatic function. 6. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test within 14 days prior to initiation of treatment. 7. Subjects in the combination therapy arms must be eligible to receive erlotinib, cetuximab, bevacizumab or nivolumab per most current prescribing information, or at the discretion of the Investigator. 1. Subject has received anticancer therapy including chemotherapy, radiation therapy, immunotherapy, biologic, or any investigational therapy within a period of 21 days or herbal therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of ABBV399. 2. Subject has known uncontrolled metastases to the central nervous system (CNS). Subjects with brain metastases are eligible provided they have shown clinical and radiographic stable disease for at least 4 weeks after definitive therapy and have not used steroids for at least 4 weeks prior to first dose of ABBV399. 3. Subject has unresolved adverse events &gt;= Grade 2 from prior anticancer therapy, except for alopecia or anemia. 4. Subject has had major surgery within 21 days prior to the first dose of ABBV399. 5. Subject has a clinically significant uncontrolled condition(s). 6. Subject has history of major immunologic reaction to any Immunoglobulin G (IgG) containing agent. 7. Subjects enrolled on the combination therapy phase must satisfy the above exclusion criteria and also the following: Subjects may not receive ABBV399 in combination with erlotinib, cetuximab, bevacizumab or nivolumab if they have any medical condition which in the opinion of the Investigator places the subject at an unacceptably high risk for toxicities from the combination. i. Subjects may not receive cetuximab if they have Kras mutation. ii. Subjects may not receive bevacizumab if they have squamous Nonsmallcell lung carcinoma (NSCLC).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Advanced Solid Tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>Neoplasm</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>