<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02060539</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To obtain subjective and objective feedback on the clinical performance of Biofinity lenses after at least two weeks daily wear in existing contact lens wearers compared with their habitual lenses.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicenter Dispensing Study of Biofinity Lenses in Extended Range</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hyperopia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Has had an oculovisual examination in the last two years Is at least 18 years of age and has full legal capacity to volunteer Has read and understood the information consent letter Is willing and able to follow instructions and maintain the appointment schedule Is correctable to a visual acuity of 20/50 or better (in at least one eye) with their habitual vision correction Currently wears soft contact lenses They should require contact lens powers between 12.00 and 20.00D or between +8.00 and +15.00D Has clear corneas and no active ocular disease Demonstrates an acceptable fit with the study lenses. Has any systemic disease affecting ocular health Is taking medication, such as antihistamine eye drops, oral and ophthalmic betaadrenergic blockers (e.g. Propanolol, Timolol), anticholinergics, and any prescribed or overthecounter eye medication, except artificial tears or eye lubricants Have any active ocular disease and/or infection that would contraindicate contact lens wear. Active ocular disease is defined as infection or inflammation which requires therapeutic treatment. Mild (i.e. not considered clinically relevant) lid abnormalities (blepharitis, meibomian gland dysfunction, papillae), corneal and conjunctival staining and dry eye are not considered active ocular disease. Neovascularization and corneal scars are the result of previous hypoxia, infection or inflammation and are therefore not active. Has worn gas permeable contact lenses within the last month. Is aphakic Has undergone corneal refractive surgery. Is participating in any other type of clinical research study Female who is currently pregnant or is breastfeeding.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>