<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02155374</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objective: to determine which regimen results in best glycemic control and safety profile, expressed as glucose values within target range and occurrence of hypoglycemia. Secondary objective is to compare patient satisfaction, clinical outcomes and toxicity. Study design: Randomized open label cross-over study Study population: Patients ≥ 18 years, who developed glucocorticoid induced hyperglycemia requiring initiation or adjustment of antihyperglycemic agents in a previous chemotherapy cycle. Patient should have ≥2 cycles of chemotherapy scheduled, with 3-10 consecutive days of ≥12,5mg prednisone-equivalent glucocorticoid and a wash-out period of 4-38 days between each cycle. Intervention: subjects will be treated by insulin regimen A and B in random order during two consecutive cycles of chemotherapy. A) intermediate acting insulin 0.01 IU / mg prednisone-equivalent / kg body weight once daily subcutaneous B) Short-acting insulin according to sliding scale regimen, dose adjusted to current grade of hyperglycemia. Main study parameters: Difference in fraction of blood glucose measurements (BGM) within target range and occurrence of hypoglycemia. Nature and extent of the burden and risks associated with participation, benefit and group relatedness: Both study treatments are just a slight variation in regular care for glucocorticoid induced hyperglycemia. Glycemic control is likely to improve due to treatments and increased counselling. All subjects will receive both treatment regimens. The burden consists of 16-32 extra BGMs over 2 x 4-10 days, wearing the glucose sensor, 1 venipuncture (if HbA1c and creatinin are not determined in routine laboratory within 3 months before start), and 1 randomization visit to the outpatient clinic. Potential risk is the occurrence of hypoglycemia, as is present in any insulin therapy. The investigators account for this risk by giving subjects dietary advice and education how to prevent, recognize and treat hypoglycemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Glucose Control for Glucocorticoid Induced Hyperglycemia During Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hyperglycemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Short-Acting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucocorticoids</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years Written informed consent Glucocorticoid induced hyperglycemia in previous cycle of chemotherapy that required therapy initiation or adjustment Duration of glucocorticoid cycles 310 consecutive days and 438 glucocorticoidfree days between 2 cycles Prednisoneequivalent dose of ≥ 12,5mg At least 2 more cycles of chemotherapy to receive History of hypounawareness Continuous tube or parental feeding Continuous (maintenance) systemic glucocorticoid therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Glucocorticoid induced hyperglycemia, insulin, chemotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>