<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02155842</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether endurance exercise of either high or moderate intensity can reverse structural and functional changes of the heart in patients with diastolic heart failure, and to investigate which type of exercise is best in terms of aerobe capacity and quality of life. The investigators expect that high intensity endurance exercise is superior to moderate intensity endurance exercise.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Exercise Training in Treating Diastolic Heart Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a prospective randomized controlled intervention study comparing two active arms. Eligible patients are being sampled consecutively by cardiologists, and randomized to either high or moderate intensity endurance exercise. Endpoints are measured at baseline, 4 weeks and 7 months. The intervention is considered safe, and the study has been approved by the Regional Ethics Committee (REK-midt). This project has been financially supported by the Norwegian ExtraFoundation for Health and Rehabilitation through EXTRA funds.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ventricular Dysfunction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure, Diastolic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ventricular Dysfunction, Left</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Sedentary lifestyle Normal systolic function left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt; 50% New York Heart Association (NYHA) class II or III Diastolic dysfunction (E/é &lt; 15 or E/é 815 and Nterminal proBNP &gt; 220pg/ml) Medically stable the last 4 weeks Written informed consent Other causes of dyspnea than diastolic heart failure Personal preferences or characteristics prohibiting the person from attending inpatient cardiac rehabilitation Not able to perform physical exercise</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>exercise therapy</keyword>
</DOC>