<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02172001</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the study is to evaluate and compare the effect of iron isomaltoside 1000 to placebo in its ability to increase haemoglobin (Hb) in subjects with IDA when oral iron preparations are ineffective or cannot be used.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomized, Double-blind, Comparative Study of Intravenous Iron Isomaltoside 1000 (Monofer®) Against Placebo</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>IDA is highly prevalent in subjects and can have a substantial medical and quality of life (QoL) burden on the subjects and the treatment of these subjects includes replenishing lost iron. Oral iron administration is often used in the clinical practice at many clinics; however, oral iron may not be tolerated by all subjects. Hence, there is a need for an alternative iron treatment in subjects, who do not tolerate oral iron. This study is planned to compare the efficacy and safety of iron isomaltoside 1000 with placebo in subjects with IDA and who are intolerant or unresponsive to oral iron therapy..</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Iron-Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deficiency Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ferric Compounds</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Men or women ≥ 18 years having IDA caused by different aetiologies* such as abnormal uterine bleeding, gastrointestinal diseases (e.g. inflammatory bowel disease), cancer, preoperative anaemia (e.g. orthopaedic surgery), and other conditions leading to IDA and with a documented history of intolerance or unresponsiveness to oral iron therapy** for at least one month*** prior to study enrolment 2. Hb &lt; 11 g/dL 3. TSAT &lt; 20 % 4. Sferritin &lt; 100 ng/mL 5. Willingness to participate and signing the informed consent form (ICF) 1. Hb &lt; 6 g/dL 2. Anaemia predominantly caused by factors other than IDA (e.g. anaemia with untreated vitamin B12 or folate deficiency, haemolytic anaemia) 3. Iron overload or disturbances in utilisation of iron (e.g. haemochromatosis and haemosiderosis) 4. Decompensated liver cirrhosis or active hepatitis (ALAT &gt; 3 times upper limit of normal) 5. Active acute or chronic infections (assessed by clinical judgement supplied with white blood cells (WBC) and Creactive protein (CRP)) 6. Body weight &lt; 50 kg 7. Pregnant or nursing women. In order to avoid pregnancy, women of childbearing potential have to use adequate contraception (e.g. intrauterine devices, hormonal contraceptives, or double barrier method) during the whole study period and 7 days after the last dosing 8. History of multiple allergies 9. Known hypersensitivity to parenteral iron or any excipients in the investigational drug products 10. Erythropoietin treatment within 8 weeks prior to the screening visit 11. Other intravenous (IV) iron treatment or blood transfusion within 4 weeks prior to the screening visit 12. Participation in any other interventional clinical study within 3 months prior to the screening 13. Any other medical condition that, in the opinion of Investigator, may cause the subject to be unsuitable for the completion of the study or place the subject at potential risk from being in the study, e.g. uncontrolled hypertension, unstable ischemic heart disease, or uncontrolled diabetes mellitus</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>IDA</keyword>
	<keyword>Iron deficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>iron deficiency anemia and who are intolerant or unresponsive to oral iron therapy</keyword>
</DOC>