<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02172976</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this multicenter study, patients with resectable pancreatic carcinoma will be treated with (a) surgery followed by 6 cycles gemcitabine or (b) 6 cycles FOLFIRINOX followed by surgery followed by 6 cycles FOLFIRINOX. The overall survival between both therapies will be compared as well as other parameters.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized Multicenter Phase II/III Study With Adjuvant Gemcitabine Versus Neoadjuvant / Adjuvant FOLFIRINOX for Resectable Pancreas Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase II/III randomized multicenter study. Patients with resectable pancreatic carcinoma will be randomized in Arm A (surgery plus adjuvant gemcitabine, 6 cycles) or Arm B (6 cycles FOLFIRINOX neoadjuvant, 6 cycles FOLFIRINOX adjuvant). Primary endpoint is the overall survival, secondary endpoints are progression-free survival, perioperative morbidity and mortality, rate of R0 resections, tolerability and feasibility of neoadjuvant FOLFIRINOX and others.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Histologically confirmed ductal adenocarcinoma of the pankreas. For histological confirmation, max. 3 tests are allowed. If no confirmation of carcinoma is possible, the patient can not be included into the study. 2. Radiological confirmation of a locally limited curativ resectable (primarily resectale or borderline situation) pankreas carcinoma without distant metastases. 3. no prior pancreas resection 4. no prior cytostatic chemotherapy 5. Bilirubin &lt; 1,6 mg/dl 6. female and male patients &gt; 18 years using contraception 7. ECOG ≤ 1 8. medical resectability 9. granulocytes &gt; 1.500/µl 10. thrombocytes &gt; 100.000/µl 11. hemoglobin ≥ 8,0 g/dl 12. serumcreatinine ≤ 1.5x of normal value or CreatinineClearance &gt; 50 ml/min 13. written informed consent 1. Endocrine and acinar pancreas carcinoma 2. locally advanced inoperable stages: nonresectable infiltration of V. porta or longway infiltration of A. mesenterica superior or infiltration of Truncus coeliacus. 3. distant metastases 4. Relapse 5. prior radiotherapy of measurable lesions 6. peritonealcarcinosis 7. malignant secondary disease, dated back &lt; 5 years (exeption: insitucarcinoma of the cervix, adequately treated skin basal cell carcinoma) 8. contraindication for operative resection 9. ECOG ≥ 2 10. severe liver dysfunction (AST/ALT&gt;3,5xULN, AP&gt;6xULN, Bilirubin&gt;1,5xULN) 11. Transhepatic drainage 12. active CHD (symptoms present), cardiomyopathy or heart insufficiency stage IIIIV according to NYHA and EF &lt; 45% 13. severe nonsurgical accompanying diseases or acute infection 14. chronic diarrhea 15. chronic inflammable gastrointestinal disease 16. peripheral polyneuropathy &gt; NCI grade II 17. pregnancy or lactation 18. hypersensibility or contraindication for Gemcitabine, Oxaliplatin, Natriumfolinate, Irinotecan or 5Fluorouracil 19. participation in another interventional trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>pancreas cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>neoadjuvant chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Folfirinox</keyword>
	<keyword>gemcitabine</keyword>
</DOC>