<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02172599</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to examine the contribution of sit-stand workstations to total daily physical activity in a multi-component office-based 12 month intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Take A Stand for Workplace Health: A Sit-stand Workstation Project Evaluation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study adopts a randomised control trial design and is mixed methods (qualitative and quantitative). The outcome data from the trial is quantitative. Alongside this a qualitative process evaluation will be conducted to inform the intervention, explain trial results and understand the intervention implementation and context (Cathain et al. 2014). Two worksites will participate in this study, in line with COCHRANE recommendations for randomised control trials.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Must be a fulltime employee on a fixed term contract for at least 18 months at one of the two worksites involved in the study (Macmillan Cancer Support, Public Health England) Must engage in primarily deskbased work Must have their own desk (i.e. does not hot desk) Must be primarily office based (i.e. not working from home) Must have no plans to leave the organisation for an extended period (e.g. holiday &gt; 4 weeks or secondment) or finitely before the anticipated study end date (January 2016) Have engaged in standingbased desk work in the month prior to the start of the study Have been advised against standing by a health professional; or be unable to stand Work for the Macmillan Support Line</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>sit-stand workstation</keyword>
	<keyword>workplace</keyword>
	<keyword>multi-component intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>randomised control trial design</keyword>
	<keyword>physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>sitting</keyword>
	<keyword>sedentary behaviour</keyword>
	<keyword>process evaluation</keyword>
	<keyword>health</keyword>
</DOC>