<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02161562</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial will assess the efficacy of optimized re-treatment therapy with omalizumab (150mg or 300mg) after relapse, in patients with Chronic Spontaneous Urticaria who were clinically well-controlled following their first course of treatment with omalizumab (150mg or 300mg). Will also assess the benefit of uptitrating to 300mg dose those patients who are not well-controlled following their first course of treatment with omalizumab 150mg.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>OPTIMA: Efficacy of Optimized Re-treatment and Step-up Therapy With Omalizumab in Chronic Spontaneous Urticaria (CSU) Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Urticaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Omalizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men or women at least 18 years of age at time of screening. Having a diagnosis of CSU and the presence of symptoms for ≥6 months prior to the screening visit. Presence of itch and hives for ≥6 consecutive weeks at any time prior to the screening visit despite concurrent use of nonsedating H1antihistamine treatment Patient must have been on an approved dose of nonsedating H1antihistamine for CSU, and no other concomitant CSU treatment, for at least the 7 consecutive days immediately prior to the randomization visit and must document current use on the day of the randomization visit. Patients having a clearly defined underlying etiology for chronic urticaria other than CSU including the following urticarias: acute, solar, cholinergic, heat, cold, aquagenic, delayed pressure or contact Patients with other skin disease associated with itch that could interfere with study outcomes and/or compromise the safety of the patient Patients with evidence of parasitic infection Patients with a history of malignancy of any organ system (other than localized basal cell carcinoma of the skin), treated or untreated, within the past 5 years, regardless of whether there is evidence of local recurrence or metastases. Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women, Women of childbearing potential, unless they are using effective methods of contraception during dosing of study treatment. Patients who are unable or unwilling to comply with study procedures, attend scheduled study visits, complete questionnaires and daily diaries, or who may otherwise be unable to comply with the study requirements. Other eligibility criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>chronic spontaneous urticaria, CSU, chronic idiopathic urticaria, CIU, hives, angioedema, itch</keyword>
</DOC>