<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02161484</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to evaluate the analgesic efficacy of adding a single shot parasacral (sciatic) nerve block to a continuous lumbar plexus block in patients undergoing total hip replacement.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Continuous Lumbar Plexus Block With and Without Parasacral Block in Patients Undergoing Total Hip Replacement</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This prospective study is intended to assess the efficacy of placing a parasacral (sciatic) nerve block in addition to a lumbar plexus block for postoperative analgesia following total hip arthroplasty. Although the placement of a lumbar plexus block alone has become accepted as the standard of care at UPMC for postoperative analgesia following total hip arthroplasty, the addition of a parasacral (sciatic) nerve block may provide the advantage of blocking the superior gluteal nerve and nerve to the quadratus femoris which both supply small articular sensory branches to the posterior hip capsule.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Hip</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics, Local</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subject has signed and dated an Informed Consent Form. 2. Subject is classified as a ASA (American Society of Anesthesiologists) status IIII 3. Subject is age 18 75 years old. 4. Subject is having primary total hip arthroplasty 5. No contraindication to peripheral nerve catheter ( local infection or hypocoagulable state) 6. Patient willing to receive spinal anesthesia as operative anesthesia 7. No known drug allergies to study medications 8. Patients not expected to receive therapeutic anticoagulation in the postoperative period. 1. Subject inability to provide adequate informed consent. 2. Age younger than 18 years or older than 75 years 3. Any contraindication to the placement of lumbar plexus catheter, including local infection, hypocoagulable state. 4. ASA (American Society of Anesthesiologists) physical status of IV or greater 5. Any chronic painful conditions 6. Preoperative opioid use 7. Coagulation abnormalities or patients who are expected to be on therapeutic anticoagulants postoperatively</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Peripheral Nerve Block</keyword>
	<keyword>Total Hip Replacement</keyword>
</DOC>