<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01901211</DOC>
	<brief_summary>As children with cerebral palsy (CP) become teenagers, they experience a decrease in their physical function and mobility. Decreased mobility leads to increased social isolation for the teens and impacts negatively on their quality of life. This loss of function is multifactorial, but poor physical fitness and muscle weakness secondary to disuse are significant contributors. Exercise video games are a novel approach to engage youth in physical exercise and social interaction with their peers. The objective of this study is to evaluate the impact of an exercise video gaming intervention to improve physical fitness and social wellbeing. Our over-arching research questions are whether "exergames" can provide health benefits (improved physical fitness) and improved social wellbeing in youth with CP.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physical and Social Benefits of Multi-Player Interactive Computer Play Games in Youth With Cerebral Palsy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objectives of this study are to evaluate the impact of exergaming on cardiovascular fitness and social wellbeing related to friends/peers in youths with CP. The secondary objectives of the study will be to evaluate the impact of the exergaming intervention on additional components of physical fitness including anaerobic fitness, and muscle strength. In addition, the effect of the exergaming intervention on overall health-related quality of life (HRQL), self-esteem and motor participation will also be measured. Finally, the effectiveness of a technique for balancing performance in multiplayer exergames will be evaluated. The objectives will be investigated using a randomized crossover study design.Outcomes will be measured a total of four times: at study entry and after the first ten-week period (either comparison or intervention), at the end of a six-week washout period, then again after second period (either intervention or comparison). Outcomes will be assessed by physiotherapists and research staff members who will be blinded to the condition of the participants.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Paralysis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Palsy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of CP and GMFCS level III Between 9 and 18 years of age inclusive Ability to operate a handheld videogame controller Highspeed internet in the home Able to commit for the entire study duration Orthopedic surgery in the preceding six months Exerciseinduced asthma Any underlying heart condition Seizure disorder Visual, auditory or cognitive disabilities that will interfere with game play</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>9 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cerebral palsy</keyword>
	<keyword>Interactive computer play</keyword>
	<keyword>Multi-player gaming</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
</DOC>