<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01219075</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Chemoprevention is the use of certain drugs to keep cancer from forming. The use of soy isoflavones supplements may prevent or treat early stage breast cancer. PURPOSE: This clinical trial studies soy isoflavones supplementation in treating women at high risk for or with breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Soy Isoflavones Supplementation in Treating Women at High Risk For or With Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess whether magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) volume (equivalent to 3-dimensional mammographic density) is reduced in high-risk women or those with invasive breast cancer or DCIS who are supplemented daily with soy (5p mg total isoflavones as aglycone) compared to placebo (microcrystalline cellulose) tablets for 1 year.II. To assess whether cell proliferation and apoptosis, as measured by Ki67 and caspase 3 staining, respectively, of breast epithelial cells is altered with soy treatment.SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess whether other intermediate molecular markers including estrogen receptor alpha (ER alpha) and ER beta differ between women supplemented with soy vs placebo. OUTLINE: Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms.ARM I: Patients receive oral soy isoflavones supplement once daily for12 months in the absence of disease progression.ARM II: Patients receive oral placebo once daily for 12 months in the absence of disease progression.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma in Situ</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ductal, Breast</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Intraductal, Noninfiltrating</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Lobular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phytoestrogens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women at high risk for breast cancer, defined as any of the following groups: Five year Gail risk &gt; 1.7% Known BRCA1/BRCA2 mutation carrier Family history consistent with hereditary breast cancer Prior biopsy exhibiting atypical hyperplasia or lobular carcinoma in situ (LCIS) History of invasive breast cancer or ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) and have completed standard therapy including tamoxifen/aromatase inhibitor or will not be treated with tamoxifen/aromatase inhibitor Signed Informed Consent Metastatic breast cancer Undergoing treatment (chemotherapy, radiation, or SERMs) Pregnancy or breastfeeding, or planning to become pregnant within one year prior to study entry Regular soy consumers (i.e., &lt; once per week of soy food, soy supplements or other products) Known food allergies such as to soy or nuts Not willing to avoid soy foods/supplements during study period Current users of exogenous hormones or oral contraceptive or planning to use exogenous hormones during the duration of the study Cannot stop taking aspirin or NSAIDs within a week of breast biopsy Active participant in other ongoing trials</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>