<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01219088</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Falls are a common problem in elderly patients resulting fractured femur, which require early operation. Adequate postoperative pain control will provide good recovery. The investigators will compare the efficacy of postoperative pain control among intrathecal morphine, femoral nerve block, and periarticular infiltration with bupivacaine in patients undergone intramedullary hip screw under spinal anesthesia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intrathecal Morphine,Femoral Nerve Block,Periarticular Bupivacaine Infiltration for Pain After Intramedullary Hip Screw</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study methods : Every patients without any exclusion criteria will be performed spinal anesthesia by 0.5% heavy bupivacaine then divided into 4 groups 1. Controlled group : spinal anesthesia alone 2. Femoral nerve block by 20 mL of 0.25% bupivacaine before spinal anesthesia 3. Spinal anesthesia plus 0.1 mg morphine intrathecally 4. Spinal anesthesia plus periarticular infiltration with 20 mL of 0.25% bupivacaine All patients will receive postoperative intravenous patient controlled analgesia (IV PCA) morphine for 48 hours. Data collection 1. Demographic data 2. Pain score : preoperative, 3 hours postoperative in the 1st six hours, 12 hours postoperative by visual analog scoring system (VASS) 3. Patient global assessment and patient satisfactory VASS at 24 and 48 hours postoperative 4. The amount of morphine at 24 and 48 hours postoperative and the time of the 1st dose</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Femoral Neck Fractures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1890 years old good consciousness, well cooperated, can use PCA machine ASA class 13 no contraindication of spinal anesthesia accept for spinal anesthesia body weight &gt; 30 kg BMI 2035 kg/m2 no history of researchdrug allergy previous history of hip surgery (the same side) pathological fractured such as severe infection, bone cancer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>