<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01028027</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of loteprednol etabonate [LE] and tobramycin ophthalmic suspension versus tobramycin and dexamethasone ophthalmic suspension in the treatment of ocular inflammation associated with blepharokeratoconjunctivitis (BKC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Loteprednol and Tobramycin Versus Tobramycin and Dexamethasone, in the Treatment of Blepharokeratoconjunctivitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Conjunctivitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Blepharitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Keratitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tobramycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Loteprednol Etabonate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must have a clinical diagnosis of BKC in at least one eye Subjects must be willing to discontinue contact lens use for the duration of the study Subjects who are able and willing to comply with all treatment and follow up/study procedures. Subjects participating in any drug or device clinical investigation within 30 days prior to entry into this study and/or during the period of study participation. Subjects who have any uncontrolled systemic disease or debilitating disease. Subjects who have a known hypersensitivity to the study drugs or their components (including benzalkonium chloride) or contraindications to tobramycin or ocular corticosteroids. Subjects who use any topical or systemic ophthalmic medications listed as disallowed in the study protocol, within the specified time frame prior to Visit 1. Subjects who have a disease or conditions which the Investigator determines could interfere with the safety and efficacy evaluations of the study drug. Subjects having ocular surgery (including laser surgery) in either eye within the past three months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Blepharokeratoconjunctivitis</keyword>
</DOC>