<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01028014</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Lower urinary tract symptoms such as urinary leakage and overactive bladder affect millions of American women. Women may develop these problems because the innervation of the muscles of the bladder and urethra are injured. Most research on treating these problems has focused on the abnormalities of the bladder muscle, but newer studies have shown abnormalities in the innervation and muscle function of the urethra. Women with these symptoms may benefit from treatment with medications to improve their urethral function. However, to truly understand what types of medications will help women with these symptoms, the investigators wish to study how these medications affect innervation and muscle function in healthy women who do not have lower urinary tract symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Medication Effects on Periurethral Sensation,Urethral Sphincter Activity and Pressure Flow Parameters</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Women without urinary incontinence or bladder symptoms (healthy controls)will undergo urethral testing prior to randomization to one of 5 medications or placebo. Participants will take an oral medication for 2 weeks and then return for repeat testing.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tamsulosin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Solifenacin Succinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ephedrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Imipramine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amitriptyline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pseudoephedrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclobenzaprine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy Females only Ages 1951 and up including premenopausal older women who have had a normal menstrual cycle for the prior 3 months Able to take oral medication for 2 weeks For women of child bearing potential,willing to use an approved method of birth control during the study Urinary Incontinence or other bladder symptoms Known neurologic disease that may impair urethral tone or sensation Currently taking a class of medication that is being tested (alphaantagonists, anticholinergics, sympathomimetics, tricyclic antidepressants, or skeletal muscle relaxants) History of QTc prolongation or cardiac arrhythmia Pregnant, breastfeeding, or are less than 6 months postpartum Known hypersensitivity to or other contraindications to taking any of the study medications</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>51 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>