<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01028807</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose: To determine the safety and efficacy of early enteral feeding after distal (ileum-colon) elective bowel anastomoses in children. Methods: Controlled randomized trial including all pediatric patients with distal elective bowel anastomosis, excluding non-elective and high risk patients. VARIABLES: Demographic characteristics, operative time, anastomosis placement, Follow up: Tolerability variables: beginning peristalsis, beginning bowel movement, time to full diet intake, post-operative stay. Safety variables: mild and persistent vomiting, persistent abdominal distention, wound infection or dehiscence as well as anastomotic leak or dehiscence, reoperation and death. At the end of surgery were randomized to: 1. Experimental group(EG): Early feeding group, after a 24 hours fasting period, with good abdominal conditions (once the post operative ileus had solved), oral fluids and diet was started. 2. Control group (CG): obligatory 5-day fasting. Once the regular diet was tolerated, the patients were discharged. Statistics: Descriptive statistics for global description. Student's t test for quantitative variables and Chi square test for qualitative variables, a p-value less than 0.05 was considered statistically significant.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Early Feeding vs 5-day Fasting After Distal Elective Bowel Anastomoses in Children. A Randomized Controlled Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>All patients between the ages of 1 month to 18 years old that required elective laparotomy with a distal elective bowel anastomosis (ileum and colon). Proximal and non elective anastomosis High risk groups: Newborns Upper gastrointestinal tract anastomosis (esophagus, gastric, duodenal or jejunal) Biliousdigestive or rectal anastomosis Immunosuppressed patients Gastrostomy or any pre anastomotic derivation Multiple anastomoses Chronic intestinal obstruction Patients who did not complete the minimum POP follow up of one month.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Early feeding</keyword>
	<keyword>Bowel anastomosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
</DOC>