<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01028586</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Parkinson's disease is a major neurodegenerative disorder in which there is a progressive loss of nigrostriatal dopaminergic neurons. The understanding that PD is a syndrome of dopamine (DA) deficiency led to the introduction in the clinical practice of L-dopa, a precursor of DA that crosses the blood brain barrier, and also to the use of selective inhibitors of MAO B, the major DA metabolising enzyme in man. This is a double-blind, placebo-controlled, extension trial, parallel-group, randomised, multi-centre, multi national, Phase III trial, comparing two doses of safinamide (50 and 100 mg p.o. q.a.m.) versus placebo as add-on therapy to a stable dose of a single dopamine agonist in subjects with early idiopathic Parkinson's Disease. The principal objective is to evaluate the time to first intervention, as some previous data suggested that safinamide may delay the need for further dopaminergic supplementation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>MOTION, Safinamide in Early Idiopathic Parkinson's Disease (IPD), as add-on to Dopamine Agonist (Extension of Trial 27918)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dopamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dopamine Agonists</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. The subject completed 24 weeks of Trial 27918. 2. The subject successfully completed all trial requirements in Trial 27918. 3. If female, they must be either post menopausal for at least 2 years, surgically sterilized or have undergone hysterectomy or, if of child bearing potential they must be willing to avoid pregnancy by using an adequate method of contraception as defined in the protocol for four weeks prior to, during and four weeks after the last dose of trial medication. For the purposes of this trial, women of childbearing potential are defined as: "All female subjects after puberty unless they are postmenopausal for at least two years, are surgically sterile or are sexually inactive". 4. Subject is willing and able to participate in the trial and has provided written, informed consent 1. If female, the subject is pregnant or lactating. 2. The subject experienced a clinically significant adverse effect during trial 27918 that could put the subject at risk according to the investigator's opinion. 3. The subject has shown clinically significant deterioration during participation in Trial 27918. 4. Motor deterioration during trial 27918 that required upward titration of existing antiparkinsonian medication or the initiation of an additional antiparkinsonian medication. 5. The investigator deems it is not in the subject's best interest to participate to trial 27938 6. Signs and symptoms suggestive of transmissible spongiform encephalopathy, or family members who suffer(ed) from such.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>