<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02751580</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot clinical trial studies how well telehealth works in patients during post radiation therapy visits. A telehealth virtual office visit can be performed from the patient's home or workplace, decreasing time spent traveling to visit site, time spent in waiting room, and cost to patient. Studying telehealth may improve quality of life in patients during post radiation therapy visit.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Telehealth in Improving Quality of Life in Patients During Post Radiation Therapy Visits</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To examine feasibility of conducting a trial comparing a telehealth visit and an in person office visit. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To examine patient satisfaction, patient assessment of physician communication during a telehealth visit. II. To examine patient distrust in the healthcare system following a telehealth visit. III. To examine physician ability to perform a patient assessment during a telehealth visit. IV. To examine physician perceptions of telehealth visits. V. To examine monetary and time cost to patients for telehealth visit. VI. To calculate clinic savings derived from telehealth visits. OUTLINE: Patients undergo their first post-treatment visit as a virtual telehealth visit using the JeffConnect application.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients currently undergoing or planned to start radiation treatment with curative, adjuvant or palliative intent Karnofsky performance status (KPS) score &gt;= 60 Patients must be capable to read and speak English and provide study specific informed consent prior to study entry Patients must have access to a computer or smartphone and internet connection at home on which they would be willing to do a telehealth study Pennsylvania residents KPS &lt; 60% No access to a computer, smartphone or internet Unable to read and/or speak English Decisionally impaired patients Patients not residing in Pennsylvania</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>