<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02751112</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a proof of concept that will assess the Predictor's kit performances. The test will be performed by several technicians, in immunological laboratories of several sites in France. In this study, "couples" of donor / recipient in the frame of a graft of CSH will be included.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of a Kit for the Prediction of the Risk of Graft Versus Host Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Hematopoietic Stem Cell (HSC) graft is the only curative treatment for lots of hematologic diseases, malignant or not, particularly leukemias. The acute Graft versus Host (aGvH) reaction is the most frequent complication, and could concern until 50% of recipients. It is mainly linked to immune characteristics of the donor which will act versus the graft recipient. There is a huge need of a technology that could predict the risk of aGvH, especially in order to select a donor in case of several possibilities, in order to reduce morbidity and mortality of graft. The Predictor' kit allows to predict acute and severe forms of Graft versus Host disease before the graft of peripheral hematological stem cells, by the assesment of iNKT cells expansion.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Graft vs Host Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Main inclusion Criteria for Donors : Being a relative of the recipient patient, OR being registered on the National Registry of the volunteers for bone marrow donation Being candidate for a donation of Hematologic Stem Cells with a HLA compatibility 10/10 Main inclusion Criteria for Recipient : Being candidate for a donation of Hematologic Stem Cells with the following criteria: HLA compatibility 10/10 with the donor Suffering from malignant or nonmalignant hemopathy in first remission Myeloablative or reducted intensity conditioning Classic scheme of immunosuppression decreasing Main exclusion Criteria: Participation to a therapeutical protocol in the 30 last days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>