<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02751502</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Twenty pediatric patients aged 5-17 years with Acquired Brain Injuries (ABI) will be randomized to receive either a bimanual-to-unimanual device home training program (10 subjects) or a conventional non-device home training program (10 subjects) for a period of 6 weeks. The specific aims of this proposal are to: Aim 1: Introduce home-based targeted upper limb training in children with hemiplegia from ABI (Acquired Brain Injuries) using a bimanual-to-unimanual training approach It is hypothesized that child-friendly home-based upper limb bimanual-to-unimanual training will lead to greater compliance and improved motor outcome on the Fugl Myer Scale compared to a conventional home training program. Aim 2: Improve the understanding of the pattern of recovery of isolated joint movements in the pediatric population with hemiplegia following ABI. It is hypothesized that individuals receiving device-based bimanual-to-unimanual training will show improvement in active range of motion across upper limb joints compared with a conventional home training program.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Home Based Adaptive Arm Training for Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemiplegia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Acquired Brain Injury at least 3 months prior to enrollment. Unilateral hemiparesis History of compliance with home exercise programs in the past. Any social or medical problem that precludes compliance with the protocol Comorbid seizure disorder or other neurological disease Treatment with botulinum toxin or intrathecal baclofen in the 3 months preceding enrollment Implanted neuromodulatory or electronic device or other complicating illness Lack of capacity to consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
	<keyword>Pediatrics</keyword>
	<keyword>Arm</keyword>
	<keyword>Upper limb</keyword>
	<keyword>bimanual training</keyword>
	<keyword>physical training</keyword>
</DOC>