<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02751385</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Investigate the effect of multiple oral doses of nintedanib on the single dose kinetics of a combination of ethinylestradiol and levonorgestrel (Microgynon®)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Investigation of the Effect of Nintedanib on the Pharmacokinetics of a Combination of Ethinylestradiol and Levonorgestrel in Patients With Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Purpose:</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nintedanib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levonorgestrel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethinyl estradiol, levonorgestrel drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethinyl Estradiol-Norgestrel Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethinyl Estradiol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Female patients 18 years or older at screening Female patient is postmenopausal or surgically sterilised Patient with locally advanced, metastatic or locally recurrent nonsmall cell lung cancer with histology of adenocarcinoma Nintedanib (Vargatef®) is planned to be prescribed in accordance with the marketing authorisation (SmPC) Signed and dated written informed consent in accordance with Good Clinical Practice (GCP) and local legislation prior to admission to the trial Exclusion criteria: Any contraindication to nintedanib (Vargatef®), ethinylestradiol or levonorgestrel (Microgynon®), as specified in the respective labels Use of hormone containing contraceptives (including vaginal and intrauterine devices and including hormone replacement therapy) within 30 days prior to first administration of Microgynon® Systemic use of drugs known to induce (e.g. rifampicin, St. John's Wort, carbamazepine) or to inhibit (e.g. azole antimycotics, macrolides) CYP3A4 within 7 days prior to first trial drug administration until last PKsampling in the trial. Exception: allowed is the intake of corticosteroids as docetaxel (pre)medication History of major thrombotic or clinically relevant major bleeding event in the past 6 months Persistence of clinically relevant therapy related toxicities (i.e. &gt; Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events [CTCAE] grade 2) from previous chemotherapy and/or radiotherapy Treatment with other investigational drugs or treatment in another clinical trial within the past four weeks before start of therapy or concomitantly with this trial Gastrointestinal disorders or abnormalities that would interfere with absorption of the trial drugs Major surgery (major according to the investigator's assessment) performed within 4 weeks prior to first treatment within the trial and without complete wound healing Patients who must or wish to continue the intake of restricted medications or any drug considered likely to interfere with the safe conduct of the trial Patients unable to comply with the protocol Previous enrolment in this trial</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>