<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02751333</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Esophageal stents are commonly used for benign esophageal pathology, especially strictures or esophageal mucosal defects such as leaks, fistulae, or perforations. The major limiting factor to stent placement is the high migration rate of the stent. Investigators are trying to prospectively evaluate the efficacy of endostitch in preventing stent migration in benign esophageal disease in comparison with standard, fully covered self-expanding metal stents (FCSEMS) placement without fixation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Esophageal Stent Migration With Endoscopic Suture Fixation Compared to Standard Deployment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The use of removable, fully covered self-expanding metal stents (FCSEMS) in the management of benign esophageal pathology has been increasingly applied in recent years. Several studies have shown promising results with its application in esophageal perforation, fistula, or leak, and refractory benign strictures. However, the major limiting factor to successful treatment with FCSEMS in this setting is the substantial migration rates. Different strategies has been used to secure esophageal stents but to little success. Several tertiary institutions including investigators have adopted the use of endostitch (ES) with the OverStitchTM system (Apollo Endosurgery, Austin, Texas) as the preferred method for stent fixation. Animal ex-vivo studies have confirmed the greater anchoring ability and tensile strength with this method when compared to esophageal stenting alone or with through the endoscope clip fixation while retrospective series have shown promising results with lower rates of stent migration when compared to conventional stent insertion. However, although the use of endostitch stent fixation has been used in several centers in the United-States with strong retrospective data (including investigators data), no prospective randomized controlled trial have confirmed its effectiveness in preventing stent migration.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fistula</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Constriction, Pathologic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Stenosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Fistula</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Perforation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adult patients age 18 years and older 2. Patients with esophageal refractory benign strictures (peptic, anastomotic, caustic, radiation, and idiopathic) where a 14 mm luminal diameter cannot be achieved over 2 dilation sessions at 13week intervals. 3. Patients with esophageal leak, perforation, or fistula referred for endoscopic stenting 4. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document 1. Pediatric patients age under 18 years 2. Pregnant or breastfeeding patients 3. Patients with malignant esophageal lesions, primary or metastatic, requiring endoscopic stenting (all females of child bearing age will undergo urine pregnancy testing as per standard1 preprocedural testing) 4. Benign strictures not having had two attempts at endoscopic dilation 5. Uncorrectable coagulopathy defined by partial thromboplastin time (PTT) greater than 50 sec, or international normalized ratio (INR) greater than 1.5 6. Uncorrectable thrombocytopenia with platelet count less than 50, 000</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Esophageal stricture</keyword>
	<keyword>Esophageal leak</keyword>
	<keyword>Esophageal perforation</keyword>
	<keyword>Esophageal fistula</keyword>
	<keyword>Endostitch</keyword>
	<keyword>Esophageal stent</keyword>
</DOC>