<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02836925</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a non-randomized, a single arm, phase II multicentre study of sofosbuvir plus ledipasvir ± ribavirin (genotype 1, 3 and 4) or sofosbuvir + ribavirin (genotype 2) for patients with hepatitis C virus-associated indolent B-cell lymphomas (HCV-RNA positive).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sofosbuvir+Ledipasvir ±Ribavirin and Sofosbuvir+Ribavirin for Pts With Indolent Bcell Lymphoma Associated With HCV Infection Treatment With Sofosbuvir Plus Ledipasvir ± Ribavirin(G1, 3 and 4) and Sofosbuvir+Ribavirin(G2) for Pts With Hepatitis C Virus Associated Indolent B-cell Lymphomas</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study includes an antiviral treatment with interferon-free regimen followed by lymphoma restaging; following the end of antiviral treatment patients will be evaluated for sustained virological response and safety parameters every 3 months for 1 year and then every 6 months for 2 years. ORR and vital status will be also evaluated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sofosbuvir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ledipasvir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ledipasvir, sofosbuvir drug combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age &gt;18 years 2. Indolent B cell lymphoma including: marginal zone lymphoma (nodal, extranodal, splenic and disseminated), lymphoplasmacytic lymphoma, small lymphocytic lymphoma, follicular lymphoma grade 1 and 2, CD5‐negative B‐cell lymphoma NOS 3. HCV‐RNA positivity 4. Assessable HCV genotype 5. No previous therapy for the lymphoma 6. Measurable disease after diagnostic biopsy (longest axis ≥1.5 cm for nodal and ≥1 cm for extranodal lesions) and/or evaluable disease (quantifiable BM infiltrate and ≥5 x 109/l clonal Bcell in peripheral blood in case of exclusive BM/leukemic disease in CD5negative Bcell lymphoma NOS) 7. No need of immediate lymphoma treatment defined as absence of all the following criteria: systemic symptoms, bulky nodal or extranodal mass (&gt;7 cm), symptomatic splenomegaly, progressive leukemic phase, serous effusions 8. Performance status &lt;2 according to ECOG scale 9. Adequate hematological counts: ANC &gt;1 x 109/L, hemoglobin &gt;9 g/dl (transfusion independent), platelet count &gt; 50 x 109/L (transfusion independent) 10. No central nervous system (CNS) disease (meningeal and/or brain involvement by lymphoma) 11. Adequate kidney function (creatinine clearance ≥ 45 ml/min) 12. Cardiac ejection fraction ≥45% (echocardiography or MUGA scan) 13. Normal lung function 14. Non peripheral neuropathy or active neurological non neoplastic disease of CNS 15. Non major surgical intervention prior 3 months to enrolment if not due to lymphoma and/or no other disease life‐threatening that can compromise chemotherapy treatment 16. Disease free of prior malignancies other than lymphoma for &gt;3 years with exception of currently treated squamous cell and basal cell carcinoma of the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix or breast 17. Life expectancy &gt; 6 months 18. No psychiatric illness that precludes understanding concepts of the trial or signing informed consent 19. Written informed consent 20. Women must be: postmenopausal for at least 1 year (must not have had a natural menses for at least 12 months) surgically sterile (have had a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy, tubal ligation, or otherwise be incapable of pregnancy), completely abstinent (at the discretion of the investigator/per local regulations) (periodic abstinence from intercourse is not permitted) or if sexually active, be practicing a highly effective method of birth control (eg, prescription oral contraceptives, contraceptive injections, contraceptive patch, intrauterine device, double‐barrier method (eg: condoms, diaphragm, or cervical cap, with spermicidal foam, cream, or gel, male partner sterilization) as local regulations permit, before entry, and must agree to continue to use the same method of contraception throughout the study. They must also be prepared to continue birth control measures for at least 6 months after terminating treatment. 21. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine beta‐human chorionic gonadotropin (betahCG) pregnancy test at screening 22. Men must agree to use an acceptable method of contraception (for themselves or female partners as listed above) for the duration of the study. Men must agree to use a double barrier method of birth control and to not donate sperm during the study and for 1 month after receiving the last dose of study drug if not taking ribavirin of for 6 months after receiving the last dose of study drug if taking ribavirin. 1. Diagnosis of lymphoblastic lymphoma, Burkitt lymphoma, diffuse large Bcell lymphoma, mantle cell lymphoma, follicular lymphoma grade 3, primary mediastinal Bcell lymphoma 2. Previous antiHCV treatment with sustained virological response 3. Diagnosis of cirrhosis (histological or Stiffness &gt;12 KpA) 4. CNS disease (meningeal and/or brain involvement by lymphoma) 5. History of clinically relevant liver or renal insufficiency; significant cardiac, vascular, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, endocrine, neurologic, rheumatologic, hematologic, psychiatric, or metabolic disturbances 6. Uncontrolled diabetes (if receiving antidiabetic agents, subjects must be on a stable dose for at least 3 months before first dose of study drug) 7. Concomitant therapy with amiodarone 8. Uncontrolled or severe cardiovascular disease including myocardial infarction within six months of enrollment, New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class III or IV heart failure, uncontrolled angina, 9. Cardiac ejection fraction &lt;45% (MUGA scan or echocardiography). 10. Creatinine clearance &lt;45 ml/min 11. Presence of major neurological disorders 12. HIV positivity, HBV positivity (HbsAg+ or HBVDNA+) with the exception of HBcAb+, HbsAg, HBsAb+/ patients with HBVDNA negativity 13. Ongoing systemic bacterial, fungal or viral infections at the time of initiation of study treatment (defined as requiring therapeutic dosing of an antimicrobial, antifungal or antiviral agent) 14. Major surgical intervention prior 3 months to enrollment if not due to lymphoma and/or other 15. Prior malignancies other than lymphoma in the last 3 years with exception of currently treated squamous cell and basal cell carcinoma of the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix or breast 16. Life expectancy &lt;6 months 17. Any other coexisting medical or psychological condition that would preclude participation in the study or compromise ability to give informed consent. 18. If female, the patient is pregnant or breastfeeding.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>hepatitis C</keyword>
	<keyword>NHL</keyword>
	<keyword>Indolent B-cell lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>