<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02042690</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The survival of adult patients with standard-risk acute lymphoblastic leukemia(ALL) need to improve. We want to compare the efficacy of haplo-identical hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) with chemotherapy for adult(age:18-39 years old) ALL patients in first phase of complete remission (CR1)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Haplo-identical HSCT Versus Chemotherapy for Adult Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Although the high complete remission rate (80%-90%) can be achieved, the long-term survival rate of standard-risk adult patients with acute lymphoblastic leukemia(ALL) is only 25%-55% when they receive chemotherapy alone. The survival rate can be further improved uo to 50%-75% when they receive HLA-matched HSCT However, the chance of finding a HLA-matched donor is low, especially in China. Alternative donor such as halpo-identical related donor might be an choice. Our retrospective analysis showed about 59% overall survival could be achieved when standard-risk adult ALL patients received halpo-identical HSCT.Therefore, we start this randomization controlled trial to compare the efficacy of haplo-identical HSCT with chemotherapy for adult(age:18-39 years old) ALL patients in CR1.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>6-Mercaptopurine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epirubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>acute lymphoblastic leukemia 1839 years old in first complete remission Adequate hepatic function defined as: total bilirubin ≤2.0 times the institutional upper limit of normal (ULN); alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase(AST) ≤2.5 times the institutional ULN Adequate renal function defined as creatinine ≤3 times the institutional ULN No uncontrollable infection Performance Status(PS)score 02(WHO) Subjects able to provide written informed consent having HLAmatched donor highrisk ALL: (1)Ph+ALL (2)Hypodiploidy (3)t(v;11q23) (4) complex karyotype（≥5 chromosome abnormalities）（5）high white blood cell (WBC) count (BALL≥30×109/L;TALL ≥100×109/L). pregnancy Loss of ability to freely provide consent due to psychiatric or physical illness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>39 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>hematopoietic stem cell transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>chemotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>