<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01124149</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study was designed to evaluate if subjects who achieve complete remission after 8 weeks of acute therapy with MMX mesalamine/mesalazine 4.8g/day given QD have better long-term outcomes and remain in remission longer compared with subjects who demonstrate only partial remission after acute therapy with MMX mesalamine/mesalazine 4.8g/day given QD. Therefore, subjects who achieve either complete or partial remission will enter into a 12-month maintenance phase, during which they will receive MMX mesalamine/mesalazine 2.4g/day given QD. Remission status for the 2 groups will be evaluated and compared at the end of this 12-month maintenance period. The data obtained from this study will provide scientifically meaningful information to demonstrate that achieving complete remission (clinical and endoscopic remission) is important for a better long-term prognosis, or that the current paradigm of symptomatic treatment is appropriate.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ability to Maintain or Achieve Clinical and Endoscopic Remission With MMX Mesalamine Once Daily in Adults With Ulcerative Colitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mesalamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adults aged 18 or older 2. Male, or nonpregnant, nonlactating female who agrees to comply with any applicable contraceptive requirements of the protocol 3. Diagnosis of active mild to moderate UC (acute flare or newly diagnosed) 4. Stable maintenance therapy of 5ASA less than or equal to 3.2 g/day (excluding MMX mesalamine/mesalazine), if 5ASA is being taken at the onset of acute flare. 1. Severe UC 2. Acute flare with onset greater than &gt;6 weeks prior to baseline while on maintenance therapy. There is no limit to the onset of flare prior to baseline if the flare is untreated. 3. Acute flare while on maintenance MMX mesalamine/mesalazine (Lialda, Mezavant, Mezavant XL, Mezavant LP) 4. Unsuccessfully treated current acute flare using steroids or 5ASA doses &gt;3.2 g/day 5. Acute flare on a 5ASA maintenance therapy of &gt;3.2 g/day 6. Systemic or rectal steroids use within the 4 weeks prior to screening or immunosuppressants within the last 6 weeks prior to screening 7. History of biologic (antiTNF agent) use 8. Antibiotic use or repeated use (&gt;3 consecutive days of use at doses above the prescribed overthecounter dose) of any antiinflammatory drugs, including nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs such as aspirin, COX2 inhibitors or ibuprofen, within 7 days prior to screening. However, prophylactic use of a stable dose of aspirin up to 325mg/day for cardiac disease is permitted 9. Current or recurrent disease, other than UC, that could affect the colon, the action, absorption, or disposition of the IMP, or clinical or laboratory assessments</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>