<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00513786</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose of this study is to determine the effectiveness of the drug combination carboplatin, paclitaxel, and bevacizumab(Avastin) in patients with advanced stage endometrial carcinoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Carboplatin/Paclitaxel/Bevacizumab in the Treatment of Advanced Stage Endometrial Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to test the effectiveness, safety, and tolerability of the drug combination carboplatin, paclitaxel, and bevacizumab(Avastin) in patients with advanced stage endometrial carcinoma. This is a phase II,open label,single center study. Patients will receive carboplatin, paclitaxel, and bevacizumab in an outpatient center by intravenous administration. The primary objectives is to study the progression free survival at 24 months after initiation of treatment and to determine the toxicity profile of the drug combinations. The secondary objectives are to estimate the overall survival and tumor response for this group of patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Advanced Stage Endometrial Cancer (Stage 3 or 4) Any Histology including clear cell, and serous papillary carcinomas surgery must have had hysterectomy and bilateral salpingooophorectomy chemotherapy initiated 12 weeks after surgery sign informed consent Adequate Endorgan function GOG (Gynecologic Oncology Group)Performance Status 0,1,2 Patients must be 18 years or older Patients may have received radiation for the treatment of endometrial cancer. Patients may have measurable or nonmeasurable disease. Patient with concomitant malignancy other than nonmelanoma skin cancer Patients with prior malignancy who have been disease free for 5 years. Patients with serious uncontrolled infection, angina or serious peripheral neuropathy. Patients whose circumstances will not permit study completion or adequate follow up Patients who have received prior cytotoxic chemotherapy for treatment of endometrial cancer including chemotherapy used for radiation sensitization.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Endometrial Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Advanced Stage Endometrial Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Stage 3 or 4 endometrial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>gyn cancer</keyword>
</DOC>