<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02562768</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This two-part study will evaluate how safe LY3154207 is and the effects it has on the body. Part A will include healthy participants. Each participant will receive daily doses of LY3154207 or placebo for 14 days. Part A will last approximately 4 weeks including a 17 day stay in the clinical research unit (CRU) and follow-up. Part B is contingent on the results of Part A. Part B will include participants with Parkinson's disease. Each participant will receive daily doses of LY3154207 or placebo for 14 days. Part B will last approximately 4 weeks including a 17 day stay in the CRU and follow-up. Both Part A and Part B will require screening within 30 days prior to the start of the study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of LY3154207 in Healthy Participants and Participants With Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Part A: Overtly healthy males or females, as determined by medical history and physical examination Female participants not of childbearing potential Part B: Have a clinical diagnosis of idiopathic Parkinson's disease for at least 1 year and on stable medication for at least 4 weeks Part A and B Are reliable and willing to make themselves available for the duration of the study and are willing to follow study procedures Have given written informed consent Have a body mass index (BMI) of 18.0 to 29.9 kilograms per square meter (kg/m²) Have participated, in the last 30 days, in a clinical trial involving an investigational product Have a significant history of or current cardiovascular, respiratory, hepatic, renal, gastrointestinal, endocrine, hematological or neurological disorders capable of significantly altering the absorption, metabolism or elimination of drugs; or constituting a risk when taking the study medication; or interfering with the interpretation of study data</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>