<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02696603</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to understand variation in the symptoms of Parkinson disease. This study uses an iPhone app to record these symptoms through questionnaires and sensors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mobile Parkinson Observatory for Worldwide, Evidence-based Research (mPower)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Living with Parkinson disease means coping with symptoms that change every day. Yet these changes are not tracked frequently enough. Most people with Parkinson disease see a clinician only once or twice a year. This study measures changes in Parkinson disease symptoms in real time using an app. The app remotely monitors Parkinson disease symptoms using surveys and the sensors on mobile devices. This study may contribute to increasing our understanding of the variability in Parkinson disease symptoms. This knowledge could be used to improve quality of life for people living with Parkinson disease.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Movement Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neurodegenerative Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Parkinsonian Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Basal Ganglia Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 18 years 2. Have a personal (i.e., not shared) iPhone (4s or newer running iOS 8.0 or later) 3. Be able to read and understand an official language of the country of participation 4. Be able to provide informed consent (i.e., pass assessment quiz) 5. Be willing to follow study procedures 1. Age 17 years or younger 2. Not a resident of the of a country where the app is approved for use 3. Not have a personal (i.e., not shared) iPhone (4s or newer running iOS 8.0 or later) 4. Not be able to read and understand an official language of the country of participation 5. Not be able to give informed consent 6. Not be willing to follow study procedures</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Health app research</keyword>
	<keyword>mHealth research</keyword>
	<keyword>Mobile health research</keyword>
	<keyword>Mobile application health research</keyword>
</DOC>