<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02696538</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to investigate how useful three balance tests are in predicting fall risk in the individual with traumatic brain injury (TBI). These tests are the Functional Gait Assessment (FGA), the Berg Balance Scale (BBS), and the mini-Balance Evaluation Systems Test (mini-BESTest).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparative Utility of Clinical Balance Measures in Traumatic Brain Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of the proposed study is to investigate the reliability and predictive validity of three balance measures, the Berg Balance Scale (BBS), the Functional Gait Assessment (FGA) and the mini-Balance Evaluation Systems Test (mini-BESTest), among individuals with history of traumatic brain injury. Participants will complete a health history questionnaire and six-month fall history. When available, fall history will be corroborated with a family member that resides with the participant. Participants will complete the Montreal Cognitive Assessment. Each participant will then participate in a 45-minute evaluation using the three performance-based outcome measures, with order randomized, with two blinded assessors. Six and 12 month follow-up of number of falls will occur via telephone. Statistical analysis with investigate the inter-rater reliability, predictive validity of fall risk and to determine cut off scores for fallers vs. non fallers in the population.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>community dwelling medically stable able to stand at least one minute unsupported (with/without assistive device) able to ambulate 20 feet (with/without assistance or assistive device) able to follow one step instructions or visual demonstrations. presence of partial or nonweight bearing on a lower extremity</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fall risk</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehabiliation</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Functional Gait Assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>mini-Balance Evaluation Systems Test</keyword>
	<keyword>Berg Balance Scale</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychometric properties</keyword>
	<keyword>Validity</keyword>
	<keyword>Inter-rater reliability</keyword>
	<keyword>Montreal Cognitive Assessment</keyword>
</DOC>