<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02696837</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In prospective, safety-control study; children undergoing laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair using PIRS (Percutaneous Internal Ring Suturing) method will be randomly assigned into four groups. Gr 1: Endotracheal intubation and muscle relaxant, Gr 2: Endotracheal Intubation without muscle relaxant, Gr 3: Proseal Laryngeal Mask Airway without muscle relaxant, Gr 4: Proseal Laryngeal Mask Airway with subparalytic does muscle relaxant. Apart from standard monitorization, all patients' intragastric pressures will also be monitored. Patients' age at presentation, gender, time of surgery, time of anesthesia, intragastric pressure, intraabdominal pressure, intraoperative findings and complications will be noted and compared between groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pediatric Inguinal Hernia Repair: Are Muscle Relaxants Necessary? Endotracheal Intubation vs Laryngeal Mask Airway</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this prospective, safety-control study; children undergoing laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair using PIRS (Percutaneous Internal Ring Suturing) method will be randomly assigned into four groups. Gr 1: Endotracheal intubation and muscle relaxant, Gr 2: Endotracheal Intubation without muscle relaxant, Gr 3: Proseal Laryngeal Mask Airway without muscle relaxant, Gr 4: Proseal Laryngeal Mask Airway with subparalytic does muscle relaxant. Apart from standard monitorization, all patients' intragastric pressures will also be monitored. Patients' age at presentation, gender, time of surgery, time of anesthesia, intragastric pressure, intraabdominal pressure, intraoperative findings and complications will be noted and compared between groups.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hernia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hernia, Inguinal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Muscle Hypotonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rocuronium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children aged 018 years Diagnosed with inguinal hernia or communicating hydrocele Due to undergo laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair Previous abdominal surgery Comorbidities that will effect surgical time, time under anesthesia, intragastric pressure and abdominal pressure</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>