<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02338674</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic hepatitis B patients with normal ALT are not subjective to the therapeutic indication in EASL Clinical Practice Guidelines. However, growing consensus on long-term risk of HBV infection with normal ALT are reached as more solid evidences are accumulated. Moreover, a large proportion of hepatitis B patients with normal ALT are at child-bearing age. Concerns about the impact of HBV on fetal and neonatal health become a psychological burden for them. Therefore, it is necessary to explore a regimen that can generate a rapid virological response, and a promising e antigen conversion rate, and safeguard the fetus. The pre-clinical study at our center found that the group had a rapid decrease of HBV DNA and a low recurrence rate after discontinuation of antiviral therapy with combined tenofovir and telbivudine (LdT + TDF) treatment. The current study is to use tenofovir and telbivudine jointly in immune-tolerant patients with chronic hepatitis B, and observe seroconversion rates, DNA decrease, the proportion of drug resistance, and relapse rate after treatment, as well as adverse effects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TDF and LdT in HBV Patients With Normal ALT</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Telbivudine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female, aged 1845 years old with artificial reproductive needs Liver function (ALT) &lt;2ULN or &gt;2ULN (the latter is included in the control group) HBVDNA&gt; 10e+5, &lt;10e+10 HBVeAg +/ History&gt; 0.5 years Cirrhosis Combined with other liver diseases such as autoimmune liver disease, alcoholic liver disease, fatty liver Liver or other parts of malignancies Bilirubin&gt; 17.1 GGT&gt; 2ULN Liver transplant patients combined HCV, HDV, HIV infection A history of antiHBV drug resistance History of habitual abortion previous fetal malformation history CRP&gt; 3.0ng / ml Uncontrolled hypertension Proteinuria or Calculated creatinine clearance &lt; 70 mL/min Heart failure or acute coronary syndrome Coagulopathy Drug or alcohol addiction Hyperlipidemia LDL&gt; 4.6 or TG&gt; 2.0 Alphafetoprotein &gt; 50 ng/mL Received interferon (pegylated or not) therapy within 6 months of the screening visit Evidence of hepatocellular carcinoma Received solid organ or bone marrow transplantation Was currently receiving therapy with immunomodulators (eg, corticosteroids, etc.), investigational agents, nephrotoxic agents, or agents Known hypersensitivity to the study drugs, the metabolites, or formulation excipients</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>