<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01022047</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the efficacy of the study product Noex in the treatment of allergic rhinitis by means of the Nasal Index Score (NIS) after 4 weeks of treatment with the drug.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Non-inferiority, Open-label, Multicenter and Randomized Clinical Trial About the Treatment of Mild to Moderate Persistent Allergic Rhinitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary objective: To assess the efficacy of the study product Noex in the treatment of allergic rhinitis by means of the Nasal Index Score (NIS) after 4 weeks of treatment with the drug. Secondary objectives: To determine the total NIS scale score after 12 weeks of treatment and the scores of the same scale individually for the symptoms of nasal obstruction, coryza, sneezing and nasal pruritus after 4 and 12 weeks of treatment, as well as to assess the safety of the study product according to the presence of adverse events. Some eligibility criteria: - NIS scale score &gt; 4 points at the randomization visit - Patients with persistent mild to moderate AR, according to the ARIA criteria with indication for use budesonide;</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Budesonide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Sign the informed consent form or in case of patients younger than 18 years, the legal responsible must sign the consent; ≥ 12 years old; NIS scale score &gt; 4 points at the randomization visit Patients with persistent mild to moderate AR, according to the ARIA criteria (see Appendix B), with indication for use budesonide; Positive skin test for at least one relevant airborne agent; AR symptoms for at least 2 years; May undergo a washout period of at least 2 weeks (without using any oral, nasal or inhalant corticosteroid agent; see 6.4). Patients with persistent severe allergic rhinitis; Patients with severe comorbidities (at the investigator's opinion); Patients with moderate to severe persistent asthma; Clinical history of infection of the airways 30 days before the study entry; Patients with structural changes causing nasal obstruction, such as pronounced nasal septum deviation, nasal polyps or any other type of nasal malformation; Pregnant women and patients planning to become pregnant during the study period or breastfeeding women; Patients in need of other drugs to treat the allergic rhinitis, such as antiimmunoglobulin E, allergenspecific immunotherapy, antileukotrienes, systemic vasoconstrictors, oral corticosteroids and other inhalant corticosteroids. Patients using allergenspecific immunotherapy during the last year, as well as using antileukotrienes and antiimmunoglobulin E during the last month, or even patients using inhalant or oral corticosteroids after V0 will not be enrolled in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>