<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01531634</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The field of psychiatric rehabilitation focuses on creating a personal narrative and developing coping strategies and environmental supports. The concept of recovery is person-centered and emphasizes the person's ability to change and to live meaningful life. The strengths approach has a central role in the recovery concept, emphasizing the person's abilities and potential. A preserved cognitive ability can be a significant strength in the recovery process. Research had shown growing support for the use of cognitive-behavioral approaches as the most effective therapy for people with borderline personality disorder, using structured interventions. A central focus in cognitive therapy is the change of maladaptive schemes. The dynamic-cognitive intervention (DCI) is based on the understanding of structural cognitive modifiability and suggests the use of mediated learning in order to enhance sense of competence and develop better psychological coping skills. The present study will focus on women diagnosed with borderline personality disorder, with normative cognitive ability seen as a strength as opposed to their emotional ability. This study will examine the effects of a Dynamic Cognitive Intervention on recovery measures and on symptoms severity. The study will include 30 women aged 18-45 years. Participants will be randomly assigned to an intervention group and a control group. All participants will be assessed before and after intervention using Recovery Assessment Scale, Hope Scale and The Brief Symptom Inventory. The intervention designed for this study is based on the principles of the Dynamic Cognitive Intervention. The intervention tools that will be used include: a. Instrumental Enrichment tools. b. life events analysis. c. Stories, lyrics and movie clips. d. Worksheets. The intervention encompasses 12 sessions of 1.5 hours, with a routine structure. The results are expected to contribute to the understanding of the impact of a dynamic cognitive intervention in women diagnosed with borderline personality disorder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Promoting Recovery Processes in Women With Borderline Personality Disorder Using a Dynamic Cognitive Intervention</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Personality Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Borderline Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women Age 18 45 Borderline Personality Disorder, by DSMV Current Acute Depressive Episode Current Psychotic Episode Less Than 12 school years Non Compliance with therapy Dual diagnosis</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Borderline Personality Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Women</keyword>
	<keyword>Dynamic Cognitive Intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Recovery</keyword>
	<keyword>Hope Scale</keyword>
</DOC>