<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02794857</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates NP001 in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) and evidence of systemic inflammation. Half of participants will receive NP001 and the other half will receive placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of NP001 in Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) and Systemic Inflammation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of NP001 in subjects with ALS and evidence of elevated systemic inflammation. Subjects will be allocated (1:1) to NP001 and placebo. Drug or placebo will be given intravenously.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Motor Neuron Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Diagnosis of clinically possible, clinically probable (with or without laboratory support), or clinically definite ALS (using the revised El Escorial Criteria) Forced vital capacity greater than or equal to 65% of that predicted for age and height Onset of ALSrelated weakness less than 3 years prior to first dose of study drug Plasma high sensitivity Creactive protein (hsCRP) concentration of greater than or equal to 0.113 mg/dL at prescreening/screening Stable dose (greater than 30 days) of riluzole if undergoing treatment with this agent For females: Not be of childbearing potential or agree to use adequate birth control during the study Key Life expectancy of less than 6 months Tracheotomy or be using ventilatory assistance, including Bilevel Positive Airway Pressure (BiPAP) or Continuous Positive Airway Pressure (CPAP) Active pulmonary disease Gastrostomy Stem cell therapy Immune modulator therapy or participation in studies of other agents within 12 weeks of prescreening/screening Unstable medical condition other than ALS</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>ALS</keyword>
	<keyword>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Motor Neuron Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Central Nervous System Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Nervous System Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurodegenerative Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuromuscular Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>C-Reactive Protein</keyword>
</DOC>