<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02794831</DOC>
	<brief_summary>- NSAIDs are widely consumed, and some are currently available for self-medication with indications 'Pain and Fever' (Cavalié, National Agency for Drug Safety (ANSM), 2014) - There is no recommendation to limit their use in bacterial infections except for chicken pox in children. - To date, no study has highlighted the aggravating role of exposure to NSAIDs on bacterial infections in adults, based on the usual septic severity Levy's score (SSS), and mortality, but it delays adequate antibiotics (Legras, Critical Care, 2009) - Community-acquired bacterial infections in adults exposed to NSAIDs are serious by their spread (multiple locations), and suppurative character requiring frequent use of invasive procedures such as surgery or drainage. The SSS does not reflect the seriousness of these infections. They are frequently associated with use of ibuprofen (63.4%), and self-medication practices (65.5%). The main hypothesis is that NSAIDs exposure is associated with a specific severity of community-acquired bacterial infection, marked by dissemination, suppurative complications or even invasive procedures requirement. Our objectives are also to: - Describe what NSAID use terms are associated to the risk of serious bacterial infections: molecule, dosage, duration of exposure, access (prescription or self-medication), associated drugs. - To determine what type (s) (s) of bacterial infection is worsened by exposure to NSAIDs. - To determine if other risk factors contribute to severity of bacterial community acquired infection - To describe hospital costs associated to such severity of bacterial infection</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Exposure to NSAIDs (Non Steroidal Anti-Inflammatory Drugs) and Severity of Community-acquired Bacterial Infections</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bacterial Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient : adult patient hospitalized in managed care organization (MCO) in one of the study centers for severe community bacterial infection, infected with more than one site, and / or abscess collection, and / or a percutaneous drainage of the infection, and / or septic surgery Control: Patient hospitalized in the same center (different service or not), during the week or months of the inclusion of cases for infection without abscess or invasive procedure, only one infected site Hematologic or solid neoplasia undergoing chemotherapy, longterm corticosteroid, chronic exposure to NSAIDs, ongoing treatment with methotrexate or monoclonal antibody (antitumor necrosis factor (antTNF) particular), chronic buffy neutropenia, surgical site infections, catheter infections, disorders of consciousness or cognitive neuroagainstindicating the administration of the drug exposure questionnaire adults under guardianship, minor, no insurance disease, patients already included in a biomedical research with taking medication blind.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>NSAIDs</keyword>
	<keyword>Bacterial Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Severity</keyword>
	<keyword>Self Medication</keyword>
</DOC>