<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00025454</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. PURPOSE: Phase I trial to study the effectiveness of R115777 in treating patients who have advanced solid tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>R115777 in Treating Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the maximum tolerated dose of R115777 in patients with advanced malignant solid tumors. - Assess the toxicity of this drug in these patients. - Determine, preliminarily, the efficacy of this drug in these patients. - Determine the potential predictors of response in patients treated with drug. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter, dose-escalation study. Patients receive oral R115777 twice daily on weeks 1 and 3. Treatment repeats every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Cohorts of 3-6 patients receive escalating doses of R115777 until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose preceding that at which at least 2 of 3 or 2 of 6 patients experience dose-limiting toxicity. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A minimum of 20 patients will be accrued for this study within 12 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tipifarnib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed malignant tumors deemed to be incurable or refractory to therapy Advanced, recurrent, or metastatic disease Previously treated with at least 1 chemotherapy regimen Brain metastases allowed if asymptomatic and controlled (e.g., after prior surgical resection or radiotherapy/radiosurgery) and not on steroids or anticonvulsants PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: Karnofsky 60100% Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: WBC at least 3,500/mm3 Absolute granulocyte count at least 1,500/mm3 Platelet count at least 75,000/mm3 Hepatic: Bilirubin no greater than 2.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) SGOT no greater than 2.5 times ULN Renal: Creatinine clearance at least 60 mL/min OR Creatinine no greater than 1.6 mg/dL Other: Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 3 months after study PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: No concurrent biologic therapy Chemotherapy: See Disease Characteristics At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy (6 weeks for mitomycin or nitrosourea) Endocrine therapy: See Disease Characteristics No concurrent hormonal therapy Radiotherapy: See Disease Characteristics At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy and recovered No prior radiotherapy to a field containing a measurable target lesion unless there is evidence of progression or a new lesion is present No concurrent radiotherapy to measurable lesions Surgery: See Disease Characteristics At least 3 weeks since prior major surgery and recovered Other: At least 2 weeks since prior proton pump inhibitors (e.g., omeprazole) Concurrent H2 blockers (e.g., cimetidine or related drugs) or antacids are allowed if there is an interval of at least 2 hours between H2 blocker/antacid intake and R115777 dosing</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>unspecified adult solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
</DOC>