<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03055247</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase II exploratory study conducted to evaluate the safety and efficacy of the combination of Ibuprofen, G-CSF and Plerixafor as stem cell mobilization regimen in patients affected by X-CGD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination of Ibuprofen, G-CSF and Plerixafor as Stem Cells Mobilization Regimen in Patients Affected by X-CGD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We designed a mobilization trial with the aim of collecting a sufficient number of HSPC in X-CGD patients; it is well known that this procedure is challenging for these patients, potentially due to functional defects induced by their chronic inflammatory state. The combination of G-CSF and Plerixafor is considered state of the art for HSPC harvest in gene therapy trials; we considered to add a non-steroidal inflammatory drug to increase HSPC mobilization and reduce inflammation that could have a role in altering HSPC content. If this trial confirms the synergistic effect of the three drugs under investigation, such a regimen will be considered for a HSPC mobilization in future gene therapy trial for X-CGD patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Granulomatous Disease, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Granuloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>JM 3100</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ibuprofen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Genetic diagnosis of XCGD 1845 years of age Karnofsky Index &gt; 80 % Adequate cardiac, renal, hepatic and pulmonary function. Negative thrombophilic screen and negative history for previous thrombotic events Written informed consent Previous Bone Marrow Transplantation or previous Gene Therapy. Use of other investigational agents within 4 weeks prior to study enrolment (within 6 weeks if use of longacting agents). Ongoing IFNγ treatment (within 4 weeks). Symptomatic inflammatory bowel disease. Symptomatic viral, bacterial, or fungal infection within 6 weeks of eligibility Neoplasia (except local skin cancer) or history of "familial" cancer Myelodysplasia or other serious hematological disorder History of uncontrolled seizures and deep venous thrombosis Other systemic disease judged as incompatible with the procedure Positivity for HIV and/or HCV RNA and/or HbsAg and/or HBV DNA Active alcohol or substance abuse within 6 months of the study. Contraindications to IBU, GCSF, Plerixafor or Pantoprazole administration</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic granulomatous disease X-linked</keyword>
	<keyword>Ibuprofen</keyword>
	<keyword>Mobilization regimen</keyword>
	<keyword>Gene Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>