<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00905645</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Safety and effectiveness of the Silimed Gel-Filled Mammary Implant as indicated for primary augmentation, primary reconstruction, and/or revision of the female breast.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sientra Sponsored Silimed Gel-Filled Breast Implant Core Clinical Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Subjects are admitted into the study only if all of the following eligibility is true: Female Age limitation specific to the indication: Primary Augmentation: Must be 18 years or older Primary Reconstruction: No age limit Revision: If original surgery was primary reconstruction, then no age limit. If original surgery was primary augmentation, then must be 18 years or older. Adequate tissue available to cover implant(s) Willingness to follow study requirements (informed consent form, followup visits) Candidate for primary augmentation, primary reconstruction, or revision Exclusion Criteria Subjects are not eligible if any of the following criteria exist: Advanced fibrocystic disease, considered to be premalignant without mastectomy Inadequate or unsuitable tissue Active infection in the body at the time of surgery Pregnant or lactating Medical condition that might result in unduly high surgical risk and/or significant postoperative complications, in the judgment of the Investigator Use of drugs, including any drug that would interfere with blood clotting, that might result in high risk and/or significant postoperative complications Demonstrated psychological characteristics that are unrealistic or unreasonable given the risks involved with the surgical procedure Determination by physical examination that the subject does have any connective tissue/autoimmune disorder Existing carcinoma of the breast without accompanying mastectomy MRI scan is prohibited because of implanted metal device, claustrophobia, or other condition.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast Augmentation</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Reconstruction</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Revision</keyword>
	<keyword>Silicone breast implants</keyword>
</DOC>