<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01395342</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Introduction: Hypertensive disorders during pregnancy are an important issue in global public health. It is current the leading cause of maternal mortality in Brazil. Objective: To assess the effect of physical exercise using stationary bicycle through blood pressure and heart rate measurements, incidence of pre-eclampsia and quality of life survey in pregnant women with chronic high blood pressure, previous preeclampsia pregnancies or both factors associated comparing to a group with no intervention. Verify the type of births, maternal and perinatal outcomes in both groups. Methodology: This randomized clinical trial enrolled pregnant women presenting chronic hih blood pressure, previous pre-eclampsia experience or both. Women from 12 to 20 gestational weeks were selected from the prenatal outpatient clinic and randomly allocated to the study or non-interventional group. Women at the study group performed physical exercise using stationary bicycle (horizontal bench model) during 20 minutes, once a week. The heart rate was maintained at 20% above resting heart rate and up to 140 bpm. Blood pressure and heart rate measurements were evaluated before and after exercise. The non-intervention group followed regular prenatal routine with weekly returns for heart rate and blood pressure measurements. Both groups fulfilled the quality of life survey (SF-36 questionnaire) at three times: between 12 and 20 weeks; 28 and 32 weeks and 36 and 41 weeks of gestation. After that data of parturition will be analyzed to compare the incidence of pre-eclampsia, types of birth, maternal and perinatal outcomes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of Physical Exercise Using Stationary Bicycle for Pregnant Women With Risk for Preeclampsia Development</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Significance was assumed as p&lt;.5%.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension, Pregnancy-Induced</mesh_term>
	<criteria>pregnant with 12 to 20 weeks gestational have chronic blood pressure, previous preeclampsia or both able to perform a exercise multiple pregnancy Systemic lupus erythematosus heart disease neurological disease renal failure persistent vaginal bleeding isthmiccervical insufficiency</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pregnant women</keyword>
	<keyword>Pre-eclampsia</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypertension, Pregnancy-Induced</keyword>
	<keyword>Parturition</keyword>
</DOC>