<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01395472</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to determine the effects of an acute session of physical exercise on cognitive functioning and humor of traumatic brain injury patients and to investigate whether different cognitive responses can be achieved with different intensities of exercise (moderate and vigorous). The investigators hypothesize that while moderate intensity physical exercise may be beneficial to cognitive functioning, vigorous intensity may be detrimental to TBI patients, as physical fatigue may impair alertness and other higher cognitive functions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Influence of Physical Exercise on Cognitive Functioning of Traumatic Brain Injury Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>It is well known the benefits of physical exercise to cognitive functioning, which have been demonstrated in animal studies and in those with healthy humans or with individuals with some type of pathology. Nevertheless, there are few studies investigating the effects of acute physical exercise on cognitive functions of people with traumatic brain injury, even though they frequently have impairments in several cognitive domains due to their brain damage. The effect of two intensities of physical exercise (moderate and exhaustive) in attention, processing speed, memory, executive control and decision making will be investigated in patients with TBI. For that matter, their performance will be compared to non-brain injured subjects submitted to the same protocol and to TBI patients submitted to a stretching session. Each subject will be submitted to a neuropsychological evaluation before and after the physical exercise in order to determine if there is an improvement in cognitive performance post-exercise.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Craniocerebral Trauma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trauma, Nervous System</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with TBI eligible for participation in this research study must meet the following inclusion criteria: diagnose of moderate to severe TBI be at least sixmonths postinjury have a neurologist that allowed to enroll into the study be able to take part in a cycloergometerprotocol, attested by the laboratory (CEPE) physician brain injury must have occurred in adult life provided written informed consent for participation</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>TBI</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute physical exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive functions</keyword>
	<keyword>Mood</keyword>
</DOC>