<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01806103</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine if physician education coupled with audit and feedback of antibiotic prescribing can improve antibiotic prescribing by primary care clinicians.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Antimicrobial Stewardship for Primary Care Pediatricians</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Using a large, diverse pediatric primary care network sharing a comprehensive electronic health record (EHR), a cluster-randomized trial will be performed to determine the effectiveness of an outpatient antimicrobial stewardship bundle, including treatment guidelines coupled with audit and feedback of physician prescribing, to curb inappropriate antibiotic prescribing for respiratory tract infections. Aim 1: To determine the impact of an outpatient antimicrobial stewardship bundle within a pediatric primary care network on antibiotic prescribing for conditions for which antibiotics are not indicated. Hypothesis: Antimicrobial stewardship will decrease rates of antibiotic prescribing for conditions for which antibiotics are not indicated. Aim 2: To determine the impact of an outpatient antimicrobial stewardship bundle within a pediatric primary care network on broad-spectrum antibiotic prescribing for conditions for which narrow-spectrum antibiotics are indicated. Hypothesis: Antimicrobial stewardship will decrease the rate of broad-spectrum antibiotic prescribing for conditions for which narrow-spectrum antibiotics are indicated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sinusitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharyngitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibiotics, Antitubercular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Infective Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Primary care pediatric practices within the CHOP Care Network Academic primary care pediatric practices within the CHOP Care Network Providers entering a practice after the start of the intervention Providers with less than 25 antibiotic prescriptions in the 6 months prior to the start of the intervention</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>antimicrobial stewardship program</keyword>
	<keyword>inappropriate prescribing of antibiotics</keyword>
	<keyword>physician prescribing</keyword>
	<keyword>antibiotic prescribing for respiratory tract infections</keyword>
	<keyword>respiratory tract infections</keyword>
</DOC>