<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01890421</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Subjects being evaluated for suspected or known Coronary artery Disease (CAD) based on signs and/or symptoms, will be invited to participate in the study. The duration for a subject in the study may range from 2 days to 4-6 weeks. One to four visits to the study doctor will be required. This study will investigate the diagnostic results of gadobutrol-enhanced Cardiac Magnetic Resonance Imaging (CMRI) images regarding the detection (sensitivity) and exclusion (specificity ) of coronary artery disease utilizing a uniform image acquisition software. The CMR images will be tested either against the results from routine clinical Coronary Angiography (CA) or those from Computed Tomography Angiography (CTA), which is used as the standard of reference. The CA/CTA may have been performed up to 4 weeks prior to enrollment or be scheduled up to 4/6 weeks after the study. CMRI and CA/CTA images will be collected for an independent image review (blinded read).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gadobutrol/Gadavist-enhanced Cardiac Magnetic Resonance Imaging (CMRI) to Detect Coronary Artery Disease (CAD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subjects aged ≥18 years Subjects with suspected or known CAD based on signs and/or (typical or atypical) chest pain who have routine CA without intervention or CTA within 4 weeks around gadobutrolenhanced CMRI Willingness to undergo stress/rest CMRI and to follow directions and complete all study procedures Women of childbearing potential (e.g. age &lt; 60y, no history of surgical sterilization or hysterectomy): use of contraception and a negative pregnancy test Suspected clinical instability or unpredictability of the clinical course during the study period Contraindication to the cardiac MRI examination (e.g. inability to hold breath; severe claustrophobia, metallic devices such as pace makers) History of severe allergic or anaphylactoid reaction to any allergen including drugs and contrast agents according to the investigator's assessment / judgment Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) value &lt;30 mL/min/1.73 m2 derived from a serum / blood creatinine result within 2 weeks prior to gadobutrol injection. Any subject on hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis is excluded from enrollment. Acute renal insufficiency Coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) Acute myocardial infarction (&lt; 14 days prior to inclusion), unstable angina / acute coronary syndrome, severe congestive heart failure Irregular heart rhythm Condition that precludes the safe administration of pharmacological stressor according to the respective approved label such as sinus node disease, 2nd or 3rd degree atrioventricular block, obstructive lung disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Myocardial Perfusion Imaging</keyword>
</DOC>