<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02802085</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Voluntary Post-Marketing Clinical Follow-up (PMCF) as part of the post marketing surveillance plan for the product under investigation. For this PMCF only CE-marked medical devices have been used and will be used within their intended purpose and no additional invasive or other stressful examinations have been or are to be carried out (acc. to MPG §23b).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>VEGA Prospective Kiel</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This non-interventional clinical study (NIS) is conducted to clinically confirm the safety and performance of the Aesculap® VEGA System® PS components under routine conditions. The VEGA System® PS is an established TKA design, and there is a long-lasting experience in the use of PS components in particular; thus a NIS is thought to be sufficient to give the required confirmation. For this NIS only CE-marked medical devices have been used and will be used within their intended purpose and no additional invasive or other stressful examinations have been and are to be carried out (acc. to MPG §23b). This voluntary NIS is part of the post-marketing surveillance for the product under investigation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient has received primary TKA at the study site five to six years ago using the product under investigation because of the following severe knee joint conditions that could not be treated through other therapies: degenerative osteoarthritis, rheumatoid arthritis, posttraumatic arthritis, symptomatic knee instability, knee stiffness or deformation of the knee joint Age at the time of surgery ≥ 18 years Patient signed informed consent Age younger than 18 years at the time of surgery Any prior joint replacement at the index knee Patient did not sign informed consent All cases not listed under indications (according to IfU) All cases showing any contraindication (according to IfU)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Total Knee Arthroplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Total Knee Replacement</keyword>
	<keyword>TKA</keyword>
	<keyword>TKR</keyword>
	<keyword>Stiffness of Knee</keyword>
	<keyword>Deformity</keyword>
	<keyword>Knee Joint</keyword>
	<keyword>Instability</keyword>
	<keyword>Post-traumatic</keyword>
	<keyword>Arthrosis</keyword>
</DOC>