<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02289287</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Stroke is defined as a sudden vascular accident that causes brain damage and neurological impairment. Literature shows that a stroke has a negative effect on participation. Self-Management (SM) is defined as health promotion and education programs used mostly for people with chronic diseases, which aim at helping patients to maintain a feeling of wellness. The primary aim of this study is to assess the effectiveness of a group-based SM program for post-stroke patients in a community setting, and its contribution to improving participation, compared to standard care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of a Self-Management Group-Intervention on Participation in Post-Stroke Patients.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>At enrollment eligible patients will be randomized to Intervention + Standard Care or Standard Care group. Within 3 weeks after enrollment all participants will undergo baseline assessment using a predefined set of scales and questionnaires (intervention group will additionally undergo a semi-structured interview). The group-intervention (SM program) will begin after enrollment of at least 4 participants to the intervention group, and within no longer than 5 weeks since enrollment. The intervention will include 12 weekly sessions, each session 2.5 hour long, and will be based on well-known SM interventions that were found effective for stroke patients in the U.S. Standard care will include 'one-on-one' sessions in each paramedical discipline as given regularly in this setting (average of 15-20 sessions per patient). Follow-up measures will be performed within a week after the end of the intervention, and 6 months thereafter, in order to examine long term effectiveness. Outcome measures are questionnaires; change will be assessed by the difference in total score between T1 |(pre-intervention), T2 (post-intervention) and T3 (after 6 months)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Cerebrovascular accident diagnosed 318 months before enrollment. Treated at th Neurologic Rehabilitation Center of Clalit Health Services in Kiryat Byalik, Israel. Living in the community (in their homes). Are capable of basic communication in Hebrew. Moderatesevere stroke (National Institutes of Health Stroke Scale (NIHSS) score ≤ 16). ModerateSevere Cognitive impairment (Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MOCA) total score ≤ 16). Inability to provide informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Self-Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Group Processes</keyword>
</DOC>