<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02289742</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the pre lens tear film characteristics of DAILIES® Aqua Comfort Plus® Multifocal (DACP MF) and Toric (DACP Toric) compared to DAILIES® Aqua Comfort Plus® Sphere (DACP) daily disposable contact lenses over 12 hours of lens wear.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tear Film Evaluation of Dailies® AquaComfort Plus® Multifocal and Toric</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Two population groups (presbyopes and astigmats) will be enrolled in the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Refractive Errors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must sign an informed consent document; Adapted, current soft contact lens wearer with either: 1. A spectacle add between +0.50 and +2.50 (inclusive) [Presbyopes group] 2. A spherical correction of an astigmatism up to 20% of the amount of the sphere [Astigmats group]; Contact lens prescription in the power range specified in the protocol; Vision correctable to 0.2 logMAR (logarithmic minimal angle for resolution) or better in each eye at distance with prestudy lenses or manifest refraction at Visit 1; Willing to wear study lenses up to 12 hours and attend all study visits; Can be successfully fitted with study lenses; Other protocolspecified inclusion criteria may apply. Any ocular anterior segment infection, inflammation, abnormality, or active disease that would contraindicate contact lens wear; Use of systemic or ocular medications for which contact lens wear could be contraindicated as determined by the investigator; Use of artificial tears and rewetting drops during the study; Monocular (only 1 eye with functional vision) or fit with only 1 lens; Any abnormal ocular condition observed during the Visit 1 slitlamp examination; History of herpetic keratitis, ocular surgery, or irregular cornea; Pregnant or lactating; Unstable tear film with a NIKBUT value below 8 seconds in either eye without lenses; Participation in any clinical study within 30 days of Visit 1; Other protocolspecified exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dailies AquaComfort Plus® Multifocal (DACP MF)</keyword>
	<keyword>Dailies AquaComfort Plus® Toric (DACP Toric)</keyword>
	<keyword>tear film stability</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-Invasive Keratograph Break-Up Time (NIK-BUT)</keyword>
</DOC>