<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00288353</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary goal of this study is to examine the triglyceride/HDL ratio and the ischemic EKG changes in patients with schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder or bipolar disorder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Estimating and Reducing the Cardiovascular Risk of Patients With Schizophrenia Drugs From Lipid Measures and Ischemic Electrocardiographic Changes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary goal of this study is to examine the triglyceride/HDL ratio and the ischemic EKG changes in patients with schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder or bipolar disorder. The secondary goal is to identify those subjects in the top tertile for the highest risk of IHD as defined by TG/HDL ratios (&gt;&gt;3.5) and ischemic EKG changes with and without clinical ischemia, e.g. angina and to see if these risk factors can be reduced or reversed by a change of antipsychotic medication, dietary counseling, enrollment into available exercise groups, etc.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ziprasidone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aripiprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria To be eligible, a patient must : Be male or female, between 1865. Have a diagnosis of schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder or bipolar disorder according to DSMIV criteria Have TG/HDL ratios (&gt;&gt;3.5) and ischemic EKG changes with and without clinical ischemia, e.g. angina Be treated for a minimum of six months with one of six oral antipsychotic medications: clozapine, haloperidol, olanzapine, quetiapine, risperidone and ziprasidone Be willing to change current antipsychotic medication to that chosen by the principal investigator Have a history of compliance with the above medication Be Medicaid eligible or maintain insurance covering requested lab procedures Be able to provide written informed consent. Exclusion criteria A patient will be considered ineligible if he/she: Has a diagnosis other than schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder or bipolar disorder with psychotic features according to DSMIV criteria. Has a history of noncompliance with prescribed psychiatric medications Has a TG/HDL ratio &lt; 3.5 on current medication Is uninsured or is unable to selfpay potential costs of required lab procedures not covered by insurance. Is unable to provide written informed consent. (Females only) Is pregnant, lactating or plans to become pregnant during study participation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>schizoaffective disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>bipolar disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolic syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>