<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02773121</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this research study is to examine whether an intervention to increase physical activity using a body-worn sensor affects cognitive (thinking) processes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physical Activity and Cognition Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The overall duration of participation in this research study is approximately 4 months. During this time, three study visits will be required. The first visit is for informed consent and screening, the second visit is for baseline fitness and cognitive testing, and the third visit is for follow-up fitness and cognitive testing after a 12-week physical activity monitoring program. Participants will be randomized to one of two study arms, a physical activity monitoring arm and a flexibility and balance arm. Both study arms involve wearing a physical activity sensor and monitoring physical activity for a duration of 12 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Nonsmoking Age between 5585 years Sedentary status (physically inactive; not participating in at least 30 minutes of moderate intensity physical activity on at least three days per week for at least three months) Generally healthy men and women Living in the greater Boston area Available for the 4 month duration of the study NativeEnglish speaking or fluent in English (must have attended elementary school and higher in English) Poor vision that cannot be corrected with glasses or contact lenses Presence of an acute infection Diagnosis of kidney failure Diagnosis of liver disease Diagnosis of thyrotoxicosis/hyperthyroidism Diagnosis of cancer Past or present conditions that affect cognitive functioning: 1. learning disability 2. neurological disorders or conditions (movement disorder, history of head trauma or stroke, epilepsy, etc.) 3. psychiatric disorders or conditions (depression, anxiety disorder, etc.) Past or present conditions that are counter indicators for participation in cardiorespiratory fitness assessment and moderateintensity physical activity: 1. heart conditions (e.g. heart attack, arrhythmias, etc.) 2. circulatory conditions (e.g. uncontrolled hypertension, leg claudication, high cholesterol, etc.) 3. respiratory conditions (e.g., asthma or lung conditions, such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, acute bronchitis, acute common cold, lung cancer, pneumonia, etc.) 4. current musculoskeletal impairments (e.g. fractures, hemiplegia, chronic joint pain, arthritis, osteoporosis, not able to walk comfortably without assistance, etc.) 5. diagnosis of electrolyte disorder or abnormality 6. presence of diabetes mellitus Obesity Prescription medication or other drugs that treat heart, lung, or circulatory conditions (e.g. beta blockers, bronchodilators, etc.) Prescription medication or other drugs that affect chemicals in the brain (e.g. antidepressants, anxiolytics, etc.) Implanted medical devices, such as a pacemaker or defibrillator Unavailable for the approx. 4month duration of the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cognition</keyword>
	<keyword>Learning</keyword>
	<keyword>Memory</keyword>
	<keyword>Executive Function</keyword>
	<keyword>Attention</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuropsychological Tests</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical Activity</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical Fitness</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Resistance Training</keyword>
	<keyword>Walking</keyword>
	<keyword>Muscle Stretching Exercises</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise Test</keyword>
	<keyword>Balance</keyword>
	<keyword>Flexibility</keyword>
	<keyword>Body Composition</keyword>
</DOC>