<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01460446</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical, prospective, randomized, multi-center study determined if the use of an insulin bolus advisor improves glycemic control as measured by a change in HbA1c in patients failing multiple daily injection/intensified conventional therapy (MDI/ICT).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ACCU-CHEK® Aviva Expert Study: Does Use of a Bolus Advisor Improve Glycemic Control in Patients Not Achieving Optimal Control Using Multiple Daily Injections (MDI)?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Eligible participants were randomized to 24 weeks multiple daily injection therapy using either the Accu-Chek® Aviva Expert blood glucose meter with an integrated bolus advisor or the Accu-Chek® Aviva Nano blood glucose meter and manual bolus calculation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must be 18 years of age or older. Diagnosed with Type 1 or Type 2 diabetes. Recent HbA1c &gt; 7.5% (measured within the last 6 weeks at local laboratory). On multiple daily injection (MDI) therapy for at least 6 months consisting of 12 injections per day of longacting basal insulin (Lantus® or Detemir®) and at least 2 injections per day of regular or rapidacting analog insulin for meal coverage. Subject adjusts meal insulin doses based on carbohydrate content of meals. Subject with Type 2 diabetes may be on stable metformin therapy (therapy unchanged during 3 months prior to study). Subject has been in Investigator's practice for at least 3 months but may have been seen by another physician in the practice. Subject has completed carbohydrate (CHO) training within the last 2 years. Subject is on a therapy regimen that conflicts with the study: Neutral protamine Hagedorn (NPH) or premixed insulin; oral antidiabetic agents, with the exception of metformin; injectable antidiabetic agents other than longacting insulin and rapidacting insulin analogs or regular insulin (eg, fixed dose therapy); use of sliding scale insulin therapy that determines insulin dosages based exclusively on specific blood glucose (bG) results. Subject has participated in another interventional trial within 6 weeks prior to study. Subject has been diagnosed with any clinically significant infectious disease or major organ system disease, such as gastroparesis or renal disease (at Investigator's discretion). Subject has used systemic oral or inhaled steroids for more than 7 days within the last 3 months. Subject is on chemotherapy or radiation therapy (selfreported). Subject is pregnant or lactating or is currently planning a pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>