<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01460966</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Attenuated plaque ≥ 5mm by intravascular ultrasound(IVUS) was reported to be high risk for distal embolism in Acute coronary syndrome(ACS). The purpose of this study is to assess the effect of thrombus aspiration catheter and distal protection device (filter wire; Filtrap™) in the aforementioned subgroup of patients at high risk for distal embolism.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of Distal Protection Device in Patients at High Risk for Distal Embolism in Acute Coronary Syndrome (ACS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Embolism</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who were diagnosed as ACS and meet the following criteria. Patients with acute myocardial infarction or unstable angina within 2 months from onset. Patients who have severe coronary stenosis which require PCI and in whom attenuated plaque ≥ 5mm (longitudinally) by IVUS before PCI is observed prior to balloon dilatation and stent deployment. Patients who need balloon expansion (including small diameter balloon) for IVUS catheter crossing. Patients who were resuscitated after dead on arrival Graft lesion or instent restenosis lesion Patients on dialysis or renal failure (Cr&gt;1.5mg/dl). Left main trunk lesion Target vessel size is &lt;2.5mm or &gt;5mm Ineligible for PCI Lactating and (possibly) pregnant woman or having possibility of pregnant Patients who are considered ineligible by the attending physician</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Distal protection device</keyword>
	<keyword>Thrombus aspiration</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute Coronary Syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>