<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01116921</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this research is to compare the need for intubation and mechanical ventilation in the first seven days of life for infants with respiratory distress syndrome (RDS) on nasal continuous positive airway pressure (nCPAP) who receive surfactant via a Laryngeal Mask Airway (LMA) with those who are maintained on nCPAP and do not receive surfactant.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Laryngeal Mask Airway (LMA) for Surfactant Administration in Neonates</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Secondary outcomes were total number of hours on mechanical ventilation, CPAP and supplemental oxygen during the first 7 days of life and for the entire hospitalization. Other secondary outcomes were number of surfactant doses, incidence of pulmonary air leak, survival until discharge, chronic lung disease (defined as need for oxygen at 36 weeks PMA), oxygen requirement at discharge, severe intraventricular hemorrhage (Grade 3/4), and periventricular leukomalacia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Surfactants</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Gestational age at time of enrollment 28 0/7 to 35 6/7 weeks postmenstrual age Age less than or equal to 36 hours old On nCPAP 6 with supplemental oxygen requirement (Fi02 greater than or equal to 30%) for greater than or equal to 30 minutes (to maintain Sa02 between 8892%) Chest radiograph and clinical presentation consistent with respiratory distress syndrome (tachypnea, retractions, nasal flaring, and/or grunting Prior mechanical ventilation or surfactant administration Major congenital anomaly Abnormality of the airway Respiratory distress secondary to an etiology other than respiratory distress syndrome (pneumothorax, meconium aspiration syndrome, pneumonia, hypoxicischemic encephalopathy) Apgar score &lt; 5 at 5 minutes of age</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>36 Hours</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>laryngeal mask airway</keyword>
	<keyword>surfactant</keyword>
	<keyword>respiratory distress syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>neonate</keyword>
</DOC>