<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01116401</DOC>
	<brief_summary>We plan to enroll 60 healthy, non-pregnant premenopausal women age 18-45 who do not have hot flashes (in order to have 30 women complete all study procedures) in a trial investigating the impact of hot flashes developed in response to an injection of a GnRH agonist, leuprolide (brand name: Lupron) on sleep disruption and mood. This study is designed to mimic the menopause transition. Based on previous studies, we expect that 2/3 of the women will develop hot flashes, naturally dividing participants into two groups: + hot flashes and no hot flashes. We will collect data on sleep disruption and mood changes to compare differences between the + hot flashes group and the group of women who do not develop hot flashes on leuprolide. Specific Aim 1: To determine the effects of hot flashes on sleep using a model of induced hot flashes in pre-menopausal women. Hypothesis 1a: Hot flashes worsen objectively measured sleep Hypothesis 1b: Exposure to hot flashes leads to the perception of poor sleep quality Specific Aim 2: To identify the relative effects of hot flashes and sleep disruption on mood using a model of induced hot flashes in premenopausal women. Hypothesis 2a: Objectively measured sleep disturbance has a greater effect than hot flashes on mood Hypothesis 2b: Perception of poor sleep correlates with negative mood Exploratory Aim: To establish the feasibility of identifying specific genetic polymorphisms for genes involved in the estrogen pathway and the development of hot flashes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Hot Flashes on Sleep and Mood Disturbance</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hot Flashes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leuprolide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deslorelin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women 1845 years old Premenopausal, defined as regular monthly menstrual cycles (every 2535days) for the past 6 months and corroborated by a midluteal phase progesterone of &gt; 3 ng/ml Willingness to use barrier methods of contraception during study and after completion of study until menses resume Good general health with normal hemoglobin, prolactin, TSH, liver function tests (SGOT, SGPT, bilirubin) and renal function tests (BUN, creatinine, alkaline phosphatase) Pregnancy, as determined by serum HCG at screening visit and immediately preceding (day before or day of) GnRH agonist administration, or currently breastfeeding. Hot flushes, as determined subjectively (7day hot flash diary) and objectively (24hour skinconductance monitoring Midluteal phase progesterone &lt;3ng/mL Clinically significant abnormalities in screening blood tests. BMI &gt; 35 kg/m2 Previously diagnosed osteoporosis or osteopenia Clinically significant depressive symptoms (MontgomeryAsberg Depression Rating Scale (MADRS) score &gt; 10) Psychiatric illness, as defined by clinical interview and the MiniInternational Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI). Sleep apnea or periodic limb movement of sleep (PLMS) either diagnosed previously or on a screening polysomnography (PSG) study. Contraindication, hypersensitivity, or previous allergic reaction to GnRH agonists Current or recent (one month) use of centrally active medications (antidepressants, anxiolytics, hypnotics, or the anticonvulsant gabapentin. Current or recent (3 months) use of systemic hormone medications Night shift workers Current or recent (one month) overthecounter (OTC) medications that may affect hot flashes, sleep, or mood (eg diphenhydramine, St. John's Wort, Black Cohosh, and other phytoestrogen supplements) Abnormal vaginal bleeding History of any medical diseases that may put subject at risk when treated with study medication. These include a history of thromboembolism or cardiovascular disease, congestive heart failure or other conditions requiring sodium restriction, spinal cord compression, metastatic vertebral lesions, memory disorders, urinary tract obstruction or history of liver, kidney, pulmonary, or metabolic disease that may put subject at risk when treated with study medication.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hot Flashes</keyword>
	<keyword>Sleep disturbance</keyword>
	<keyword>Lupron</keyword>
	<keyword>Menopause</keyword>
</DOC>