<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02578342</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to investigate the response on cognitive testing of healthy persons compared to adults with or without medication against ADHD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Brain Activity in Adults With ADHD During Neuropsychological Tasks</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) is one of the most prevalent psychiatric disorders in children and adolescents. It is characterized by inattentive, hyperactive, impulsive behaviour and neuropsychological deficits. In 40-60% of cases emerge in childhood and persists into adulthood. The aim of the study is to investigate the response on cognitive testing of healthy persons compared to adults with or without medication against ADHD. As a secondary endpoint a more robust diagnosing method combining advanced imaging methods with neuropsychological evaluation is tested. Neuropsychological testing, functional MRI and spectroscopy will be performed. Statistical analysis will assess differences in the functional magnetic resonance imaging, spectroscopy and neuropsychological evaluation results between three groups: 1) group of healthy volunteers, 2) participants with ADHD with medication and 3) participants with ADHD without medication.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participant is between 2055 years old Participant is not pregnant Participant is not able to consent him/herself Suspected or proven pregnancy Nursing Neurological diseases that could interfere with a diagnosis of ADHD Psychiatric comorbidity under treatment Previous history of psychiatric medication Substance abuse Intelligence quotient&lt;75 Claustrophobia Electrical simulator nerve or bone Implanted medication infusion pump Cerebral aneurysm clips Unstable medical condition</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>