<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02127281</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the efficacy of a negative pressure wound therapy (NPWT) system after revision total knee and hip arthroplasty in patients at high risk for infection. It is hypothesized that the use of NPWT system (i.e., Prevena) in high risk patients prevents wound complications and decreases reoperation rates.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Wound Management With Negative Pressure Dressing Versus Standard Dressing After Revision Arthroplasty.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>One of the primary causes of un-planned readmission following lower extremity arthroplasty procedures is infection. Continuous wound drainage poses a serious risk for infection and is often initially treated with absorbent dressings and/or oral antibiotics. Comorbidities such as obesity, diabetes and tobacco abuse predisposes to wound complications and therefore infection after these procedures. NPWT has proven to be effective for postoperative drainage and decreases the risk for infection or further reoperation. This prospective randomized trial will involve 160 patients at high risk for infection undergoing revision total knee or hip arthroplasty; 80 patients will be randomly selected to be treated with the NPWT system (Prevena) and randomly selected to be treated with the current standard of care wound dressing (control group). Patients will be enrolled at a single site of the Cleveland Clinic Health System (Main Campus).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Joint Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prosthesis-Related Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Scheduled revision Total Hip or Knee Arthroplasty Procedure Presence of one of the following: body mass index (BMI) greater than 35, use of blood thinners other than acetylsalicylic acid (ASA) after surgery, peripheral vascular disease, depression, diabetes mellitus, current tobacco use, history of prior infection, current use of immunomodulators or steroids, current history of cancer or hematological malignancy, rheumatoid arthritis, renal failure or dialysis, malnutrition, liver disease, transplant status, or HIV. Patient lives &gt;100 miles from hospital Patient is &lt; 18 years old Silver allergy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Revision total knee arthroplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Revision total hip arthroplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Negative pressure wound therapy system (NPWT)</keyword>
	<keyword>Drainage</keyword>
</DOC>