<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02127528</DOC>
	<brief_summary>this study aims to verify the adequacy of doses of antibiotics prescribed in clinical practice for the treatment of ventilated acquired pneumonia (VAP) in the intensive care unit (ICU) with the pharmacodynamic efficacy criteria considered relevant literature. The impact of these pharmacodynamic parameters on the clinical and microbiological VAP will be evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Empiric Antibiotic Therapy for Ventilator-acquired Pneumonia With Gram-negative Bacilli in Intensive Care</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia, Ventilator-Associated</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Use of mechanical ventilation for more than 48 hours 2. Clinical suspicion of ventilationacquired pneumonia (VAP) defined by new radiological persisting infiltrate (or ARDS) AND one of the following features: purulent tracheal aspirates OR temperature ≥ 38.3°C OR leukocytosis&gt; 10 giga/L 3. High risk of multidrugresistant bacteria, defined as either at least 6 days of mechanical ventilation OR antibiotic treatment in the previous 15 days 4. Implementation of a prior distal respiratory sample for microbiological diagnosis by bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) OR distal sampling by protected catheter (PDP) 5. Age ≥ 18 years 6. Implementing a medical examination 7. Obtain the written consent of the patient, one of its relatives or trusted person previously designated or emergency clause. 1. Pregnant woman 2. Expected death within 72 hours of diagnosis of VAP patient 3. Dialysis 4. No affiliation to a social security scheme (beneficiary or legal) 5. Contraindication to one of classes of molecules used antibiotics (βlactam / Fluoroquinolones / Aminoglycosides), contained in the Summary of Product Characteristics for authorization on the market.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>