<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02127541</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Insulinoma: Insulinoma are rare, small insulin secreting neuroendocrine tumors. The only curative approach is the surgical excision. The preoperative detection remains a challenge. A non-invasive, highly sensitive tool in localizing the insulinomas would be appreciated in the preoperative work-up of these patients. To this aim Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor (GLP-1R) imaging (Single Photon Emission Computer Tomography co-registered with a CT; SPECT/CT) could be a convenient tool. The possibly more sensitive approach of targeting GLP-1R using Positron emission tomography (PET/CT) methodology has not been investigated in patients so far. Beta cell mass (BCM): The in vivo determination of BCM is currently impossible due to the lack of a reliable tool. Quantitative assessment of BCM in vivo is of enormous interest for patients with type 1 (T1D) and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2D) in order to evaluate pathophysiological mechanisms of T1D and T2D and potential therapeutical interventions aiming at the prevention of autoimmune beta cell destruction (i.e. in T1D before clinical diagnosis or after islets transplantation) or preservation of BCM in T2D. Radionuclide-based methodology (GLP-1R imaging using) radioligands that directly target beta cells appears particularly promising.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>New Imaging Procedure for the Localisation of Insulinoma and Transplanted Islet Cells</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypoglycemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Exenatide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Biochemically proven endogenous hyperinsulinaemic hypoglycaemia in the fasting state with neuroglycopenic symptoms or autologous Islet Cell transplantation in the forearm Conventional imaging (CT,MRI or EUS) not older than 2 months Signed written consent Age above 18 years Kidney failure (creatinine &gt; 140micromol/l) Known allergies against Exendin4 (Byetta or Bydureon) Pregnancy Breastfeeding Medication with Byetta or Bydureon Evidence for malignancy (extrapancreatic tumor manifestations)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Localisation of Insulinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>beta-cell imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>exendin-4</keyword>
	<keyword>68Ga-DOTA-exendin-4 PET/CT</keyword>
	<keyword>111In-DOTA-exendin-4 SPECT/CT</keyword>
</DOC>