<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01174550</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A prospective multicenter imaging study for evaluation of chest pain. Objective is to determine whether an initial non-invasive anatomic imaging strategy with coronary CT angiography (CTA) will improve clinical outcomes in subjects with symptoms concerning for coronary artery disease relative to an initial functional testing strategy (usual care). Study hypothesis: initial anatomic testing strategy will provide information that will result in superior long-term health outcomes as compared to an initial functional testing strategy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PROspective Multicenter Imaging Study for Evaluation of Chest Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Pragmatic randomized trial of clinical effectiveness of diagnostic testing strategies for coronary artery disease (CAD), to be performed in outpatient settings including acute and primary care and cardiology offices. Qualifying patients presenting with new or worsening symptoms suspicious for clinically significant CAD who require diagnostic testing and have not been previously evaluated will be randomized to an initial strategy of either anatomic or functional testing. All subsequent decisions regarding additional testing, medications and/or procedures will be at the discretion of the responsible clinical care team Within the functional testing arm, the subject's care team will select the specific test to be performed (exercise electrocardiogram (ECG), stress nuclear, or stress echocardiogram (echo)) consistent with 'usual care' in that practice setting. The subject's care team will be provided with 'Information sheets' summarizing current standards for test interpretation and preventive care, but specific medical treatment will not be mandated by the trial.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Chest Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>new or worsening chest pain suspicious for clinically significant coronary artery disease (CAD) no prior evaluation for this episode of symptoms planned noninvasive testing for diagnosis men age ≥55 years men age ≥45 years with increased probability of coronary artery disease (CAD) due to either (A. Diabetes Mellitus (DM) requiring medical treatment OR Peripheral Arterial Disease (PAD) defined as documented &gt;50% peripheral arterial stenosis treated medically or invasively OR cerebrovascular disease (stroke, documented &gt; 50% carotid stenosis treated medically or invasively) OR B. At least one of the following cardiovascular risk factors: 1Ongoing tobacco use, 2Hypertension, 3Abnormal ankle brachial index (ABI) defined as less than &lt;0.9, 4Dyslipidemia women age ≥65 years women age ≥50 years with increased probability of coronary artery disease (CAD) due to either (A. Diabetes Mellitus (DM) requiring medical treatment OR Peripheral Arterial Disease (PAD) defined as documented &gt;50% peripheral arterial stenosis treated medically or invasively OR cerebrovascular disease (stroke, documented &gt; 50% carotid stenosis treated medically or invasively) OR B. At least one of the following cardiovascular risk factors: 1Ongoing tobacco use, 2Hypertension, 3Abnormal ankle brachial index (ABI) defined as less than &lt;0.9, 4Dyslipidemia Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL within the past 90 days Negative urine/serum pregnancy test for female subjects of childbearing potential Diagnosed or suspected acute coronary syndrome (ACS) requiring hospitalization or urgent or emergent testing; Elevated troponin or creatine kinasemyocardial band (CKMB) Hemodynamically or clinically unstable condition systolic blood pressure (BP) &lt; 90 mmHg, atrial or ventricular arrhythmias, or persistent resting chest pain felt to be ischemic despite adequate therapy) Known coronary artery disease (CAD) with prior Myocardial infarction (MI), percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI), coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) or any angiographic evidence of coronary artery disease (CAD) ≥50% lesion in a major epicardial vessel Any invasive coronary angiography or noninvasive anatomic or functional cardiovascular (CV) test for detection of coronary artery disease (CAD), including coronary tomographic angiography (CTA) and exercise electrocardiogram (ECG), within the previous twelve (12) months Known significant congenital, valvular (&gt; moderate) or cardiomyopathic process (hypertrophic cardiomyopathy or reduced systolic left ventricular function (LVEF) ≤ 40%)) which could explain cardiac symptoms Contraindication to undergoing a coronary tomographic angiography (CTA), including but not limited to: a. Allergy to iodinated contrast agent, b. Unable to receive beta blockers unless heart rate &lt; 65 beats per minute, c. Pregnancy Life expectancy &lt; 2 years Unable to provide written informed consent or participate in longterm followup</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>chest pain</keyword>
	<keyword>coronary artery disease</keyword>
	<keyword>CAD</keyword>
</DOC>