<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01174485</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Liposuction is the most popular aesthetic surgery in Brasil and worldwide. Evidence showing that adipose tissue is a metabolically active tissue led to the suggestion that liposuction could be a viable method for the improvement of metabolic profile through the immediate loss of adipose tissue. Studies about the effects of liposuction on metabolic profile are conflicting. A few studies report the improvement of insulin sensitivity, inflammatory markers and lipid profile, others observe no changes and a few report the worsening of metabolic profile. In addition, animal studies show a compensatory growth of intact adipose tissue in response to lipectomy. Physical exercise improves insulin sensitivity, lipid profile, inflammatory balance, adipose tissue distribution and increases or preserves free fat mass. Therefore, liposuction and physical exercise seem to act on similar tissues of the body. To the investigators knowledge, there are no studies about the associated effects of liposuction and exercise in humans. However, one can suggest that exercise training associated with liposuction could: [1] attenuate or block the possible fat recovery or compensatory growth; [2] block or reverse the possible harmful effects of liposuction; or [3] exert an additive or synergistic effect to the possible beneficial effects induced by liposuction on metabolic and hormonal profile and inflammatory balance.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Liposuction and Exercise Training on Metabolism, Lipid Profile and Adiposity in Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>20 to 35year old healthy subjects with a BMI of 22 to 28 Kg/m2; Nonsmokers; Present stable body weight for 6 months (without variations exceeding 4 kg); Be in use contraceptive pill for at least 6 months; Health problems that impede surgery or exercise training; Be in chronic use of antibiotics or antiinflammatory medication.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>36 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Liposuction</keyword>
	<keyword>exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolism</keyword>
	<keyword>adiposity</keyword>
</DOC>