<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01174784</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective, multi-center, non-randomized study of the Wildcat Catheter to cross a single femoropopliteal chronic total occlusion (CTO). Safety and efficacy will be evaluated during the index procedure through 30-day follow-up.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chronic Total Occlusion Crossing With the Wildcat Catheter</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patient is willing and able to provide informed consent. 2. Patient is willing and able to comply with the study protocol. 3. Patient is &gt; 18 years old. 4. Patient has peripheral arterial disease requiring revascularization as evidenced by contrast, CT or MR angiography. 5. Patient has an occluded femoropopliteal artery that is 99100% stenosed and is ≥ 1 cm and ≤ 30 cm in length by visual estimate. 6. Target femoropopliteal vessel is ≥ 3.0 mm in diameter. 7. Patient has Rutherford Classification of 25. 1. Patient has a known sensitivity or allergy to contrast materials that cannot be adequately pretreated. 2. Patient has a known sensitivity or allergy to antiplatelet medications. 3. Patient is pregnant or lactating. 4. Patient has a coexisting disease or medical condition contraindicating percutaneous intervention. 5. Target vessel is severely calcified as evidenced by angiography. 6. Target lesion is in a bypass graft. 7. Target lesion is in a stent (i.e., instent restenosis). 8. Patient has had a procedure on the target limb within 7 days. 9. Patient has had a procedure on the target limb within the past 30 days and is unstable. 10. Patient is simultaneously participating in an investigational device or drug study. 11. Patient has a planned surgical or interventional procedure within 30 days after the study procedure.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Total Occlusions</keyword>
	<keyword>Superficial Femoral Artery</keyword>
	<keyword>Popliteal Artery</keyword>
</DOC>