<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2089">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03079687</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D0816R00014</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03079687</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Expanded Access Program for Olaparib Tablets as Maintenance Therapy in Patients With Ovarian, Fallopian Tube or Primary Peritoneal Cancer.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multiple Patient Expanded Access Program for Olaparib Tablets for the Maintenance Treatment Following Response (Complete Response or Partial Response) to Platinum-based Chemotherapy in Patients With Platinum-sensitive Relapsed High-grade Epithelial Ovarian, Fallopian Tube or Primary Peritoneal Cancer.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Parexel</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AstraZeneca</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, single-arm, international, multicenter Multiple Patient Expanded
      Access Program (MPEAP). The program is designed to provide treatment access to olaparib
      tablets for patients with platinum-sensitive relapsed high-grade epithelial ovarian,
      fallopian tube or primary peritoneal cancer without other treatment options or eligible for
      an olaparib clinical trials.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Multiple Patient Expanded Access Program is designed to provide treatment access to
      olaparib tablets for patients with platinum-sensitive relapsed high-grade epithelial
      ovarian, fallopian tube or primary peritoneal cancer who are in response (complete response
      or partial response) following platinum-based chemotherapy. The dose of olaparib tablets is
      300 mg (two 150 mg tablets) taken twice daily, equivalent to a total daily dose of 600 mg.
      The 100 mg tablet is available for dose reduction. Treatment may continue until disease
      progression, unacceptable toxicity or withdrawal of patient consent. The program will
      collect observational data only.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Available</overall_status>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Expanded Access</study_type>
  <expanded_access_info>
    <expanded_access_type_treatment>Yes</expanded_access_type_treatment>
  </expanded_access_info>
  <condition>Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Olaparib tablets</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive olaparib tablets 300mg (two 150mg tablets) twice daily.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria

        For inclusion in the program patients must fulfill the following criteria:

          -  Provision of informed consent prior to any program specific procedures

          -  Female patients ≥ 18 years of age and has platinum-sensitive relapsed high grade
             epithelial ovarian, primary peritoneal or fallopian tube cancer

          -  Patient is in response (complete response or partial response) following
             platinum-based chemotherapy.

          -  Patients must have normal organ and bone marrow function measured within 28 days
             prior to administration of program treatment.

          -  Postmenopausal or evidence of non-childbearing status for women of childbearing
             potential.

        Exclusion criteria:

        Patients should not enter the program if any of the following exclusion criteria are
        fulfilled:

          -  Patients with a known hypersensitivity to olaparib or any of the excipients of the
             product.

          -  Concomitant use of known strong CYP3A inhibitors or moderate CYP3A inhibitors.

          -  Concomitant use of known strong or moderate CYP3A inducers. The required washout
             period prior to starting olaparib is 5 weeks for enzalutamide or phenobarbital and 3
             weeks for other agents.

          -  Patient with moderate or severe hepatic impairment.

          -  Breast feeding women.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>AstraZeneca Clinical Study Information Center</last_name>
    <phone>1-877-240-9479</phone>
    <email>information.center@astrazeneca.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>PAREXEL (For enrollment purpose only) PAREXEL (For enrollment purpose only)</last_name>
    <email>olaparib@parexel.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 8, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 8, 2017</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ovarian cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>gynaecological cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>platinum-sensitive disease</keyword>
  <keyword>platinum-sensitive relapsed</keyword>
  <keyword>Olaparib</keyword>
  <keyword>Ovarian Neoplasms</keyword>
  <keyword>Neoplasms</keyword>
  <keyword>Ovarian Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>fallopean tube cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>primary peritoneal cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>epithelial ovarian cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>PARP inhibitors</keyword>
  <keyword>Poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase inhibitors.</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Olaparib</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Poly(ADP-ribose) Polymerase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
