<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2110">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03079414</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>108939</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03079414</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Role of Electrophysiology Testing in Survivors of Unexplained Cardiac Arrest</brief_title>
  <acronym>EPS ARREST</acronym>
  <official_title>The Role of Electrophysiology Testing in Survivors of Unexplained Cardiac Arrest</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Western University, Canada</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Academic Medical Organization of Southwestern Ontario</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Western University, Canada</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Sudden cardiac death (SCD) remains a major cause of mortality within developed nations
      despite aggressive efforts to reduce its societal burden. Despite extensive clinical and
      genetic investigations, a subgroup of cardiac arrests remain unexplained, highlighting the
      potential contribution of additional cardiac conditions that may not be identified with
      contemporary diagnostic algorithms. The EPS ARREST study aims to evaluate the role of
      invasive electrophysiology study within this patient population.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The majority of cases of SCD in older individuals occur secondary to coronary and structural
      heart disease, while genetic channelopathies and cardiomyopathies are prominent contributors
      in young adults. Among individuals that suffer aborted cardiac arrests in the absence of
      overt coronary and structural heart disease, diagnostic algorithms that screen for cardiac
      channelopathies and more subtle forms of structural heart disease have been established.
      Despite the extensive investigations currently utilized, a significant proportion of aborted
      cardiac arrests remain unexplained.

      Although invasive electrophysiology studies are a cornerstone for diagnosis and management
      of arrhythmia disorders, they are not invariably included in the workup of cases of
      unexplained aborted cardiac arrest. This is largely driven by initial studies suggesting
      that the diagnostic yield in this context is low, however these investigations often used
      invasive electrophysiology studies indiscriminately in all cases of aborted cardiac arrest.
      Since these earlier studies, our insight and approach to SCD has evolved and it has become
      clear that the majority of patients do not require an invasive electrophysiology study for
      diagnosis. However an invasive electrophysiology study may still have an important role
      among these individuals when the initial workup is negative. Notably, arrhythmias that
      require invasive electrophysiology for diagnosis, including bundle branch reentrant
      ventricular tachycardia and supraventricular tachycardias associated with hemodynamic
      collapse, have been identified as arrhythmic culprits in this patient population.

      The goal of the EPS ARREST study is to evaluate the diagnostic yield of a standardized
      invasive electrophysiology study among survivors of SCD when initial investigations fail to
      identify an underlying etiology.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Arrhythmic culprit for aborted cardiac arrest</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed immediately upon testing</time_frame>
    <description>Identification of an arrhythmic culprit for aborted cardiac arrest using an invasive electrophysiology study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of bundle branch reentrant ventricular tachycardia</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed immediately upon testing</time_frame>
    <description>Prevalence of bundle branch reentrant ventricular tachycardia among survivors of unexplained cardiac arrest.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of supraventricular tachycardia associated with hemodynamic collapse</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed immediately upon testing</time_frame>
    <description>Prevalence of inducible supraventricular tachycardia during invasive electrophysiology study among survivors of unexplained cardiac arrest.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Sudden Cardiac Death</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Unexplained Aborted Cardiac Arrest</arm_group_label>
    <description>Survivors of sudden cardiac death with no identifiable etiology following initial diagnostic workup.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Invasive Electrophysiology Study</intervention_name>
    <description>Invasive electrophysiology studies will be performed using four catheters placed in the right ventricular apex, the coronary sinus, the His bundle region, and the high right atrium. Standard induction protocols for supraventricular and ventricular arrhythmias will be utilized in the absence and presence of isoproterenol. Long-short ventricular extra-stimuli will also be delivered to screen for bundle branch reentrant ventricular tachycardia. The study is considered observational as the participating sites perform electrophysiology studies in this patient population as part of standard clinical care.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Unexplained Aborted Cardiac Arrest</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      DNA will be collected on patients identified to possess bundle branch reentrant ventricular
      tachycardia on invasive electrophysiology study.
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Survivors of unexplained sudden cardiac death for whom an underlying etiology remains
        unclear following a standard diagnostic workup.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Unexplained cardiac arrest requiring cardioversion or defibrillation

          2. Willing and able to sign informed consent

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Coronary artery disease (stenosis &gt; 50%) and clinical findings consistent with an
             ischemic arrest

          2. Reduced left ventricular function (left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 50%) on
             echocardiogram or cardiac MRI.

          3. Persistent resting QTc &gt; 460 msec for males and 480 msec for females

          4. Resting QTc &lt; 350 msec

          5. Type I Brugada ECG with &gt;/= 2 mm ST elevation in V1 and/or V2 (Spontaneous or
             Drug-Induced)

          6. Polymorphic or bidirectional ventricular tachycardia observed with exertion on
             exercise treadmill testing

          7. Clinical, electrocardiographic, and/or imaging findings consistent with a diagnosis
             of arrhythmogenic right ventricular cardiomyopathy

          8. Myocarditis

          9. Reversible cause of cardiac arrest such as marked hypokalemia (&lt;2.8 mmol/l) or drug
             overdose sufficient in severity without other cause to explain the cardiac arrest.

         10. Bileaflet mitral valve prolapse

         11. Documented ventricular fibrillation initiated by a short-coupled premature
             ventricular contraction
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jason D Roberts, MD MAS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Western University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andrew D Krahn, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of British Columbia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Melvin M Scheinman, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, San Francisco</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jason D Roberts, MD MAS</last_name>
    <phone>(519) 663-3746</phone>
    <phone_ext>34526</phone_ext>
    <email>jason.roberts@lhsc.on.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCSF Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94143-0124</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Melvin M Scheinman, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>London Health Sciences Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>N6A 5A5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jason D Roberts, MD MAS</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Krahn AD, Healey JS, Chauhan V, Birnie DH, Simpson CS, Champagne J, Gardner M, Sanatani S, Exner DV, Klein GJ, Yee R, Skanes AC, Gula LJ, Gollob MH. Systematic assessment of patients with unexplained cardiac arrest: Cardiac Arrest Survivors With Preserved Ejection Fraction Registry (CASPER). Circulation. 2009 Jul 28;120(4):278-85. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.109.853143. Epub 2009 Jul 13. Erratum in: Circulation. 2010 Jun 29;121(25):e460.</citation>
    <PMID>19597050</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wang YS, Scheinman MM, Chien WW, Cohen TJ, Lesh MD, Griffin JC. Patients with supraventricular tachycardia presenting with aborted sudden death: incidence, mechanism and long-term follow-up. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1991 Dec;18(7):1711-9.</citation>
    <PMID>1960318</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 8, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 2, 2017</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Sudden Cardiac Death</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiac Arrhythmia</keyword>
  <keyword>Electrophysiology Study</keyword>
  <keyword>Genetics</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Death</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Death, Sudden, Cardiac</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>There is no current plan to share IPD with other researchers.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
