<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01407809</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Idiopathic Intracranial Hypertension (IIH) is a disease that affects mainly young people, and is associated with headache and loss of vision. The medical and surgical management of IIH is problematic and many patients are not treated effectively. Some cases of IIH are associated with severe stenosis of the large veins of the brain and various researchers have recently reported significant improvement in patients with IIH after the narrow veins of the brain were treated with a stent. Our project aims to evaluate the safety and long-term efficacy of venous sinus stenting in patients with severe IIH refractory to medical management.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Venous Sinus Stenting for Idiopathic Intracranial Hypertension Refractory to Medical Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intracranial Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pseudotumor Cerebri</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA 1. Age &gt; 18 years 2. Established diagnosis of Idiopathic Intracranial Hypertension according to the criteria of the 2004 International Classification of Headache Disorders (Table 3). 3. Visual field loss: One of criteria A, B or C must be fulfilled. A. Severe visual function loss, defined as grades 4 and 5 on the Humphrey Visual Field Analyzer SITA Standard 242 Test grading scale (Table 4) at initial presentation. B. Moderate visual function loss, defined as grade 3 on the Humphrey Visual Field Analyzer SITA Standard 242 Test grading scale (Table 4) at presentation and failure of treatment with acetazolamide (Diamox) given at efficient dose (2g/d or maximum tolerated dose) or Topiramate (Topamax) given at efficient dose (maximum 150mg daily). Failure is defined by the absence of visual function improvement after 1 month of treatment and/or medication intolerance. C. Mild visual function loss, defined as grades 0,1 or 2 on the Humphrey Visual Field Analyzer SITA Standard 242 Test grading scale (Table 4) at presentation and a worsening to moderate or greater visual function loss, defined as grades 35, after 1 month of treatment and/or medication intolerance. 4. Magnetic Resonance Venography (MRV) or Computed Tomography Venography (CTV) demonstrating bilateral transverse sinus stenosis or unilateral transverse sinus stenosis with contralateral transverse sinus hypoplasia or atresia. At least one of the stenoses must cause ≥ 50% reduction of the sinus lumen diameter. 5. Signed informed consent obtained from the patient.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>