<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01407276</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a 2-part study in participants with renal impairment and matched healthy participants to investigate the effect of impaired renal function on the plasma and urine levels of omarigliptin (MK-3102) after taking a single 3 mg dose by mouth.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Omarigliptin (MK-3102) in Participants With Impaired Renal Function (MK-3102-009)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In Part I, three panels of 6 participants each will be enrolled with varying degrees of renal disease (mild, moderate, or severe renal impairment) based on their estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR). Each of these panels will be matched with a corresponding panel of equal number of healthy, age-, race-, BMI- and gender-matched control participants. All panels will receive a single oral dose of 3-mg omarigliptin, followed by plasma sampling and urine collection. In Part II, 6 participants with end stage renal disease (ESRD) requiring hemodialysis will receive a single 3-mg oral dose of omarigliptin immediately following hemodialysis (HD) (Period 1) and 2 hours prior to HD (Period 2).There will be approximately 1 month between Period 1 and Period 2. A corresponding panel of equal number, healthy matched control subjects (age, race, BMI, gender) will also receive a single 3 mg dose by mouth. Omarigliptin dose administration will be followed by plasma sampling for both panels.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Impaired Renal Function Subjects: Females of reproductive potential must have a negative pregnancy test and agree to use 2 methods of birth control Diagnosis of renal insufficiency based on estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) calculated using the Modification of Diet in Renal Disease (MDRD) equation Healthy Subjects: Females of reproductive potential must have a negative pregnancy test and agree to use 2 methods of birth control; In general good health Impaired Renal Function Subjects: Is mentally or legally incapacitated Has rapidly fluctuating renal function or has demonstrated or suspected renal artery stenosis History of significant endocrine (other than Type 2 diabetes), gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, hematological, immunological, respiratory, or genitourinary diseases History of stroke, chronic seizures or major neurological disease Uncontrolled Type 2 diabetes or history of Type 1 diabetes or ketoacidosis History of cancer (Some exceptions apply) Regular user of barbiturates or sleep aides Consumes excessive amounts of alcohol (more than 2 drinks/day) Consumes excessive amounts of caffeinated beverages (more than 6/day) Has had major surgery or has lost or donated 1 unit of blood within 4 weeks Has a history of significant multiple and/or severe allergies Current or history of illicit drug abuse Nursing mothers Healthy Subjects: Is mentally or legally incapacitated; Has a history of stroke, chronic seizures, or major neurological disorder Renal impairment History of clinically significant endocrine, gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, hematological, immunological, respiratory, or genitourinary diseases Hypoglycemia, glucose intolerance, Type 1 or Type 2 diabetes, or ketoacidosis History of cancer (Some exceptions apply) Regular user of barbiturates or sleep aides Consumes excessive amounts of alcohol (more than 2 drinks/day) Consumes excessive amounts of caffeinated beverages (more than 6/day) Has had major surgery or has lost or donated 1 unit of blood within 4 weeks Has a history of significant multiple and/or severe allergies Current or history of illicit drug abuse Nursing mothers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>