<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01407562</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open label, dose escalation study to determine the safety and tolerability and maximum tolerated dose of pazopanib combined with weekly paclitaxel and carboplatin in patients with advanced solid tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Pazopanib, Paclitaxel, and Carboplatin in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open label, dose escalation study to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of pazopanib combined with weekly paclitaxel and carboplatin in patients with advanced solid tumors. There will be a dose expansion cohort of thirty patients to assess detailed pharmacokinetics and to assess any signal of activity in patients with solid tumors and in a portion who have breast cancer that is triple negative (ER-negative, PR-negative, and HER2-negative).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed diagnosis of a solid malignancy with advanced disease that has relapsed, that is refractory to standard therapies, or for which there is not standard therapy, or for which the patient opts not to receive standard therapy. At the recommended phase II dose level, triplenegative breast cancer defined as ERnegative, PRnegative, and HER2negative, will be enrolled and another 10 patients with a solid malignancy who would benefit from a paclitaxel and carboplatinbased regimen, will also be enrolled. Male or female ≥ 18 years of age Able to swallow and retain oral medications Major surgery within last 28 days or cytotoxic chemotherapy, biologic therapy, investigational agents, or radiotherapy within last 21 days. Patients who have completed therapy with mitomycin C or nitrosurea will have to wait 42 days. More than 3 prior lines of cytotoxic chemotherapy for metastatic disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>