<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01828827</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1, single-center, randomized, balanced, single-dose, two-treatment, two-period, two-sequence, crossover, open-label study to evaluate the effect of food on the pharmacokinetics of PA-824. This study was designed to understand the possible effects of a high-calorie, high-fat meal on PA-824 absorption and pharmacokinetics. The hypothesis to be tested in this study is that the rate and extent of absorption of PA-824, as measured by Tmax, Cmax, AUC(0-t), and AUC(0 inf), are the same after a high-calorie, high-fat meal as compared with after a minimum 10-hour fast.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Food Effect Study on the Bioavailability and PK of PA-824 Tablets in Healthy Adult Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Have the ability to understand the requirements of the study, have provided written informed consent (as evidenced by signature on an informed consent document approved by an IRB), and agree to abide by the study restrictions. 2. Be healthy nontobacco/nicotine using (6month minimum) adult subjects, 19 to 50 years of age, inclusive. 3. Be medically healthy subjects with clinically insignificant Screening results (among laboratory profiles, medical histories, ECGs, or physical exam), as deemed by the Principal Investigator. 4. Have a body mass index of 18 to 29. 5. Have negative urine test results for alcohol and drugs of abuse such as amphetamines, cannabinoids, and cocaine metabolites at both Screening and Checkin. 6. Agree to follow the requirements set forth in the protocol regarding pregnancy controls and donation of sperm, blood, or blood components. 1. Any clinically significant (as deemed by the Principal Investigator) history, acute illness (resolved within 4 weeks of screening), or presence of cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic, renal, hematologic, gastrointestinal (including eating disorders), endocrine, metabolic, immunologic, dermatologic, neurologic, psychological, or psychiatric disease. 2. Any serum creatinine or BUN measure beyond the upper limit of the normal range at Screening or Checkin. Individual values may be discussed with the Sponsor Medical Monitor. 3. Positive Screening test for HCV, HBV, or HIV. 4. History of peptic ulcer disease, gastritis, esophagitis, or gastroesophageal reflux disease. 5. History of any cardiac abnormality (as deemed by the Principal Investigator). 6. History of hypokalemia or hypomagnesemia. 7. History of prolonged QT interval. 8. Family history of LongQT Syndrome or sudden death without a preceding diagnosis of a condition that could be causative of sudden death (such as known coronary artery disease or CHF or terminal cancer) 9. Resting pulse rate &lt; 40 or &gt; 100 bpm at Screening. 10. At either Screening or the predose read before the first dose, a QTcB (Bazett's correction) &gt;430 msec, calculated from the average of triplicate reads collected at one sitting. 11. At either Screening or the predose read before the first dose, a QTcF (Fridericia's correction) &gt;430 msec, calculated from the average of triplicate reads collected at one sitting. 12. History or presence of alcoholism or drug abuse within the past 2 years (as deemed by the Principal Investigator). 13. Use of alcohol within 72 hours prior to dosing. 14. Significant history of drug and/or food allergies (as deemed by the Principal Investigator). 15. For women, lactation. 16. For women, positive test for serum HCG at Screening or Checkin. 17. Use of any systemic or topical prescription medication within 14 days prior to dosing or during the study, except hormonal contraceptives in women. 18. Use of any systemic or overthecounter medication including vitamins, herbal preparations, antacids, cough and cold remedies, etc., within 7 days prior to dosing or during the study. 19. Use of any drugs or substances within 30 days prior to dosing known to be strong inhibitors or inducers of cytochrome P450 enzymes (including xenobiotics, quinidine, tyramine, ketoconazole, testosterone, quinine, gestodene, metyrapone, phenelzine, doxorubicin, troleandomycin, cyclobenzaprine, erythromycin, cocaine, furafylline, cimetidine, dextromethorphan, etc.) or known to prolong the QT interval (including amiodarone, bepridil chloroquine, chlorpromazine, cisapride, clarithromycin, disopyramide dofetilide, domperidone, droperidol, erythromycin, halofantrine, haloperidol, ibutilide, levomethadyl, mesoridazine, methadone, pentamidine, pimozide, procainamide, quinidine, sotalol, sparfloxacin, thioridazine, etc.). 20. Use of any therapeutic agents known to alter any major organ function (e.g., barbiturates, opiates, phenothiazines, cimetidine, etc.) within 30 days prior to dosing. 21. Consumption of products containing grapefruit within 10 days prior to dosing. 22. Any special dietary changes during the 30 days prior to dosing, as deemed by the Principal Investigator in consultation with the Sponsor Medical Monitor. 23. Any strenuous exercise within 7 days of Checkin, as deemed by the Principal Investigator in consultation with the Sponsor Medical Monitor. 24. Donation of whole blood or significant loss of blood within 56 days prior to dosing. 25. Plasma donation within 7 days prior to dosing. 26. Participation in another interventional clinical trial within 30 days prior to dosing. 27. Hemoglobin &lt; 12.0 g/dL. 28. Previous use of PA824. 29. Any other factor which suggests to the Principal Investigator that the subject should not participate in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>tuberculosis</keyword>
	<keyword>PK</keyword>
	<keyword>PA-824</keyword>
	<keyword>food effect,</keyword>
	<keyword>bioavailability</keyword>
	<keyword>pretomanid</keyword>
	<keyword>CL-003</keyword>
</DOC>