<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01828671</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Tortillas are a staple food in several cultures and are widely used to make tacos, burritos, and enchiladas. These foods are gaining a significant segment of the North American fast food and restaurant industry. From a health point of view, the addition of soy flour into corn tortillas will improve the nutritional profile of the tortillas and the presence of soy protein, dietary fibre and bioactive components has the potential to yield other health benefits. It is hypothesized that the addition of soy flour to corn tortillas will lower the glycemic index which could benefit those individuals with type 2 diabetes. The purpose of this research is to investigate whether different levels of soy flour in corn tortillas influences the glycemic response.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Examine the Glycemic Response of Corn and Soy Tortillas in Healthy Individuals</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Soybeans are an important crop in Canada, with approximately 10% of soybean production in Manitoba. Soybeans are grown primarily for their oil. The press cake that remains following oil extraction is a good source of protein and contains bioactive ingredients such as the isoflavones. The press cake can be ground into a flour (soy flour) and used in food products. For example, a finely ground flour can be used in infant formulas as well as for meat and dairy substitutes. This research is examining other applications of soy flour in food products such as corn tortillas. Tortillas are a staple food in several cultures and are widely used to make tacos, burritos, and enchiladas. These foods are gaining a significant segment of the North American fast food and restaurant industry. From a health point of view, the addition of soy flour into corn tortillas will improve the nutritional profile of the tortillas and the presence of soy protein, dietary fibre and bioactive components has the potential to yield other health benefits. It is hypothesized that the addition of soy flour to corn tortillas will lower the glycemic index. The glycemic index describes the potential of a food to increase blood glucose post-prandially in relation to the same amount of available carbohydrate in a glucose solution. Consumption of low glycemic index foods helps to achieve better glycemic control in individuals with type 2 diabetes. Recent meta-analyses are reporting that consumption of high glycemic index foods is associated with higher risk of coronary heart disease and breast cancer in women. The purpose of this research is to investigate whether different levels of soy flour in corn tortillas influences the glycemic response. This information will form the basis of developing food products for glycemic management in type 2 diabetes and for reducing risk of other chronic diseases. This single site, double-blind, randomized, controlled study designed to examine the glycemic response to corn and soy tortillas in healthy individuals will recruit 10 eligible volunteers into the study who will visit the research clinic on 6 separate visits for the glycemic testing. At each visit, one of the following products will be consumed: i) 296 mls (~1 cup) of oral glucose solution; ii) 296 mls (~1 cup) of oral glucose solution for a duplicate assessment as per standard glycemic index testing protocols; iii) corn tortillas; iv) corn tortillas with a low amount of soy flour; v) corn tortillas with a moderate amount of soy flour; or vi) corn tortillas made with a higher amount of soy flour.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female, greater or equal to 18 and less than or equal to 40 years of age; Normal blood lipid profile (total cholesterol, LDLcholesterol, HDL cholesterol, triglycerides) and glycated hemoglobin &lt;6%; Body mass index (BMI) of 20 to 30; Stable regime for the past 3 months if taking vitamin and mineral/dietary/herbal supplements; Agree not to eat soybeans (edamame) or soybased foods, or consume soy or isoflavone supplements while participating in this study; Willing to comply with the protocol requirements; Willing to provide informed consent. Allergies to corn or soy flour or to corn or soy products; Presence of a clinically diagnosed disease affecting the circulatory, respiratory, immune, skeletal, urinary, muscular, endocrine, digestive, nervous or reproductive system that requires medical treatment; Taking any prescribed medication (with the exception of birth control) within the last 3 months, or taking supplements which affect glycemic control within the last 3 months; Cigarette/cigar smoking, current or within the last 6 months; Current (within the last 30 days) bacterial, viral or fungal infection, or taking overthecounter medication within the past 72 h; Pregnancy or lactation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Soy</keyword>
	<keyword>Corn</keyword>
	<keyword>Flour</keyword>
	<keyword>Tortilla</keyword>
	<keyword>Glycemic</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucose,</keyword>
	<keyword>glycemic index</keyword>
</DOC>