<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01316731</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Rationale: Proteins released from muscle during and shortly after exercise, often referred to as myokines, may be central to our understanding of the cross-talk during and after exercise between skeletal muscles and other organs, in particular the liver. So far only a few myokines are identified (e.g. IL-6, IL-8, IL-15, TNF-alpha). Taking into account the role of these several known myokines in developing insulin resistance, revealing new putative myokines might provide valuable information and a direction for future research on the pathogenesis and treatment of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Objective: The objective of the present study is to identify novel myokines, expression of which is altered in skeletal muscle after a single bout of exercise. Study design: experimental study. Study population: Ten healthy, male subjects between 40 and 60 years of age and BMI &lt; 30 kg/m2, will participate in this study. Intervention: A single exercise bout that consists of one hour one-legged cycling on a adapted recumbent cycle ergometer at a submaximal rate. The non-exercising leg will serve as control for the exercising leg. Main study outcomes: Main study outcomes include upregulation of genes in skeletal muscle after exercise (with a focus on genes encoding myokines) and changes of blood plasma levels of selected proteins after exercise.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>MyoGene: Effects of Acute Exercise on (Myokine) Gene Expression in Human Skeletal Muscle</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Age 4060 years Male gender BMI &lt; 30 kg/m2 Exercising regularly (&gt; 2 times a week, &gt; 3 hour in total per week) Unstable body weight (weight gain or loss &gt; 3 kg in the past three months) Following, or have recently followed a (weightloss) diet Donated or intended to donate blood 2 months before until two months after the study Medical condition that can interfere with the study outcome (i.e. cardiovascular disease, pulmonary disease) Systolic blood pressure &gt;160 mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure &gt;100 mmHg Use of medications known to interfere with gene expression in the muscles (i.e. statins, fenofibrate). Use of antithrombotic therapy (marcoumar, sintromitis). Diagnosed diabetes mellitus type 1 or 2. Drugs or alcohol abuse ( &gt; 3 glasses of alcoholic beverages a day). (Chronic) injuries of the locomotor system that can interfere with the intervention Participated in another study within the last six months</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>