<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01672281</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In endurance sports competitions such as cycling, an athlete's capacity to sustain submaximum power (i.e. endurance capacity) strongly influences overall race performance. Endurance capacity can be increased by both long, continuous endurance exercise at moderate oxygen consumption, and high-intensity (at or above peak oxygen consumption) interval training. However, it has also been shown that resistance exercise, if performed in addition to endurance exercise, can further enhance endurance capacity. The investigators have recently described a novel training method, which is based on combined vibration and resistance training and superimposed vascular occlusion. Based on the investigators previous results showing that this type of training leads to marked increases in endurance capacity in previously untrained young women, the investigators aim at investigating whether the method is also effective in increasing endurance capacity in highly endurance-trained young men, and whether the method leads to bigger improvements relative to resistance exercise alone. Besides the functional outcomes the investigators are also interested in the specificity of the cellular adaptations with respect to the two trainings methods.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>vibroX-training in Endurance Trained Men</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: male no fever / no common cold at the beginning of the study at least 4 endurance training sessions prior to beginning of study age 1835y nonsmoker no cardiological / orthopedic problems no pacemaker fulfills health questionnaire's requirements Exclusion criteria: female fever / common cold at beginning of study untrained condition (less than 4 endurance training sessions prior to the beginning of the study) age under 18 oder above 35y smoker cardiovascular or orthopedic problems cardiac pacemaker does not fulfill health questionnaire's requirements</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>