<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01672086</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The active surveillance post-approval study of the Stelkast Surpass Acetabular System is a retrospective, multi-center, single-arm study intended to collect data on the survivorship and long-term safety and effectiveness of the device.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Active Surveillance Post-Approval Atudy of the Stelkast Surpass Acetabular System</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This active surveillance study is intended to evaluate the survivorship and long-term safety and effectiveness of the Stelkast Surpass Acetabular System. Neither the patient nor the surgeon are blinded to treatment. The study will compare the Surpass' survivorship to the survivorship observed in a historical control group established by a meta-analysis. The evaluation will be conducted for a period of ten years. These evaluations will be recorded through onsite visits and/or mailings sent to physicians requesting deidentified patient-level data for subjects implanted with the Surpass system.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Calcium Carbonate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Primary hip arthroplasty Skeletal maturity Noninflammatory degenerative joint disease such as osteoarthritis, avascular necrosis, congenital hip dysplasia, and traumatic arthritis The Stelkast Surpass Acetabular System is contraindicated in patients with the following conditions: Overt or latent infection in or around the hip joint, insufficient bone stock to allow appropriate insertion and fixation of the prosthesis, insufficient soft tissue integrity to provide adequate stability, muscle laxity or inadequate soft tissue for proper function and healing, mental or neuromuscular disorders that do not allow control of the affected joint, revision hip arthroplasty, inflammatory hip joint disease, and neuropathic hip joint disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>