<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01042964</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary objective: To evaluate safety and tolerability, adverse events (AEs), vital signs, ECG, bleeding time, evaluation of antibody titer and safety laboratory tests Secondary objectives: To evaluate the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics (platelet aggregation)of six ascending single intravenous doses of PR-15 in healthy volunteers</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Pharmacokinetic and -Dynamic Study of PR-15, an Inhibitor of Platelet Adhesion</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary objective: To evaluate safety and tolerability by using adverse events (AEs), vital signs including blood pressure/pulse rate (BP/PR), electrocardiographic examinations (12 lead ECG), bleeding time, evaluation of antibody titer and safety laboratory tests (biochemistry, hematology, coagulation, urinalysis) Secondary objectives: To evaluate the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics (collagen-induced platelet aggregation)of six ascending single intravenous doses of PR-15 in healthy, male volunteers</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tissue Adhesions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy, male Caucasians between 18 and 45 years of age. Normotensive subjects (systolic BP &lt; 140 mmHg and diastolic BP &lt;90 mmHg; Body weight of 70 to 90 kg (BMI 20 25. Negative results in HIV antibody, HBs antigen (HBsAg) and HCV tests; Signed Informed Consent Form. Normal coagulation function (aPTT between 24 and 35 seconds, PT between 70 and 130%, INR between 0.85 and 1.15. Subjects who are taking or have taken any prescription medication within the last 14 days or any nonprescription medication, especially, antiplatelet drugs, within the last seven days prior to the administration of trial medication on Day 1. Intake of any investigational drug within three months prior to the administration of study medication on Day 1. Concomitant use of any other medication including overthecounter preparations. History of hypersensitivity, contraindication or serious adverse reaction to inhibitors of platelet aggregation or hypersensitivity to related drugs (crossallergy) or to any of the excipients in the study drug. A history or clinical evidence of any cardiac, cardio or cerebrovascular, hepatic, renal, pulmonary, endocrine, neurological, infectious, gastrointestinal, haematological, oncological or psychiatric disease or emotional problems or any other clinically relevant condition, physical finding, ECG or laboratory test abnormality, which in the opinion of the investigator would pose a significant risk for the subject, invalidate the Informed Consent or limit the ability of the subject to comply with study requirements or interfere otherwise with the conduct of the study. Any laboratory value outside the normal laboratory reference range at Screening and before randomization, unless approved by the investigator. Subjects known to have experienced elevated liver enzyme values will also be excluded. History of alcohol and/or drug abuse (verified by drug screening). Blood loss of 450 ml or more during the last three months before Screening. Subjects who smoke more than 5 cigarettes per day and/or are unable to abstain from smoking during the entire inhouse period. Subjects who were previously enrolled in this trial or who have received PR15 in a previous trial. Subjects who have participated in other clinical trials in the last 3 months.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>platelet adhesion and aggregation</keyword>
	<keyword>acute coronary syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>myocardial infarction</keyword>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>inhibition of platelet adhesion to plaques</keyword>
	<keyword>collagen-induced platelet aggregation</keyword>
</DOC>