<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00731393</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the present study is to assess the reactogenicity and immunogenicity of a thiomersal-free influenza vaccine. For comparison, a group of subjects is administered the standard formulation of Influsplit SSW® 2003/2004.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immuno &amp; Reacto of TF Trivalent Influenza Split Vaccine 2003/04 or of Std Formulation Influsplit SSW®/Fluarix™ 2003/04</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects whose parents/guardians the investigator believes can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol Male or female children over 6 months of age at the time of vaccination, but who are not yet 6 years old. All children included in the study must never have been given a prophylactic influenza inoculation. Written consent to vaccination must be available from both parents or only the single parent after the parents/guardians have been briefed on the study in an understandable language. Use of study or unlicensed medication or administration of a vaccine other than the study vaccine within 30 days preceding vaccination and/or during the study period until 30 days after administration of the second vaccine dose. Acute disease at the beginning of the study Acute clinically significant changes in the lungs, cardiovascular system, liver or kidney function, identified by physical examination or laboratory tests. Known allergic reactions that might have been caused by one or more components of the vaccine. Administration of immunoglobulins and/or other blood products within 3 months before the beginning of the study or planned administration during the study period.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Thiomersal-free influenza split vaccine 2003/2004</keyword>
	<keyword>Influsplit SSW®/Fluarix™ 2003/2004</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza</keyword>
</DOC>