<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02905669</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Impedance planimetry using Endoscopic Functional Lumen Imaging Probe (EndoFLIP) device is a promising diagnostic tool to assess esophageal, esophago-gastric junction and pylorus function. It allows the measurement of esophageal and pylorus distensibility as well as contractile activity in response to distension. Examination is useful performed under sedation. General anesthesia might affect distensibility values. The aim of this study is to normal values for esophageal, esophago-gastric junction and pylorus distensibility in controls during an upper gastro-intestinal endoscopy performed under general anesthesia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Normal Values for Esophageal and Pyloric Impedance Planimetry Under General Anesthesia (NormaFLIP)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject older than 18 years and younger than 80 years Subject referred for upper gastrointestinal endoscopy under general anesthesia for anemia, intestinal metaplasia in the stomach, Helicobacter pylori screening, or submucosal dissection Subject with health insurance Written informed consent Patient younger than 18 years or older than 80 years Pregnancy or breast feeding Previous history of esophagogastric surgery or vagotomy Previous history of Parkinson disease or diabetes mellitus Contraindication to upper gastrointestinal endoscopy Esophageal varices Esophageal diameter smaller than 5 mm Contraindication to general anesthesia Hiatal hernia greater than 3 cm on endoscopy Esophageal or gastric cancer otherwise than superficial lesion with indication of submucosal dissection Typical symptoms (heartburn, regurgitation) of gastroesophageal reflux disease and/or gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD)Q score greater or equal to 8 Nausea, vomiting or epigastric pain Dysphagia with Sydney score greater ou equal to 50 Incapability to give consent No written informed consent Participation to another study at the same time</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>distensibility</keyword>
	<keyword>impedance planimetry</keyword>
	<keyword>esophagus</keyword>
	<keyword>esophago-gastric junction</keyword>
	<keyword>pylorus</keyword>
</DOC>