<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02905383</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to investigate the effect of a multi-component exercise program on physical function, physical activity and health-related quality of life (HRQOL) in older people recently discharged from hospital. The intervention consists of 32 group-based exercise sessions, performed twice a week. In addition the participants in the intervention group will be encouraged to perform an exercise program on their own, at least once weekly. The participants in the control group will be encouraged to exercise on their own, according to the World Health Organization (WHO) recommendations on physical activity for adults aged 65 and above.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Exercise on Physical Function and Health in Older People After Discharge From Hospital</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Older people who have been hospitalized often experience loss of function, increased risk of falls and reduced health-related quality of life (HRQOL) in the post-discharge period. The reason for this is the cumulative effect of illness, bedrest during hospital stay and inactivity after discharge. Previous research indicates that exercise therapy should be an integrated part of the post-hospital treatment to prevent or postpone this functional decline and improve HRQOL. Therefore, the investigators will conduct a randomized controlled trial to investigate the effect of a multi-component exercise program consisting of high intensity exercises on physical function, physical activity and HRQOL among older people living at home after discharge from hospital after treatment of an acute medical event.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chest Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemic Attack, Transient</mesh_term>
	<criteria>70 years or older, live in their own home, consent to participate in the program three times a week (twice a week outside their home), manage to walk with or without assistive device, and assessed by a doctor as able to tolerate the intervention. Severe cognitive impairment (MiniMental State Examination (MMSE) score less than 20), have an expected lifespan less than one year, exercise more than twice a week, and score above nine points on the Short Physical Performance Battery.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>70 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>