<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01134393</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The general aim of this trial to determine the efficacy as measured by the percentage of patients reaching blood pressure goal at the end of the treatment period at 12 weeks. In-clinic blood pressures, home blood pressures and safety will be carefully monitored.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TElmisartan and AMlodipine Single Pill sTudy With Patients Not on Goal With Mono rAas Therapy-switch</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Design:</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Telmisartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amlodipine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 1. Ability to provide written informed consent in accordance with Good Clinical Practice and local legislation 2. Age 18 years or older 3. Patients with uncontrolled hypertension as defined SBP &gt; 140 mmHg and SBP &gt; 130 mmHg in patients with diabetes or renal impairment or DBP &gt; 90 mmHg and DBP &gt;80 mmHg in patients with diabetes or renal impairment after at least an 6 weeks of stable treatment with antihypertensive medication defined as treatment with the clinically recommended dose of a single RAAS blocking agent (Angiotensin Converting Enzym inhibition, AII Receptor Blocker and Direct Renin Inhibitor) at entering the trial. Renal impairment is defined as a creatinine &gt;133µmol/l (1.5mg/dl) in male patients and a creatinine &gt;124µmol/l (1.3mg/dl) in female patients or a creatinine clearance between 3060 ml/min Exclusion criteria: 1. Premenopausal women who are not surgically sterile; or are nursing or pregnant; or are not practising acceptable means of birth control or do not plan to continue using acceptable means of birth control throughout the study and do not agree to submit to pregnancy testing during participation in the trial. Acceptable methods of birth control include the transdermal patch, oral, implantable or injectable contraceptives, sexual abstinence and vasectomised partner. 2. Known or suspected secondary hypertension (e.g., renal artery stenosis or phaeochromocytoma). 3. Mean inclinic seated cuff Systolic BP &gt;180 mmHg and SBP &gt;160 mmHg in patients with diabetes or renal impairment or Diastolic BP &gt;110 mmHg and DBP &gt;100 mmHg in patients with diabetes or renal impairment. Renal impairment is defined as a creatinine &gt;133µmol/l (1.5mg/dl) in male patients and a creatinine &gt;124µmol/l (1.3mg/dl) in female patients or a creatinine clearance between 3060 ml/min. 4. Renal dysfunction as defined by the following laboratory parameters: Serum creatinine &gt;3.0 mg/dl (or &gt;265 ¿mol/L) and/or known creatinine clearance of &lt;30 ml/min and/or clinical markers of severe renal impairment. 5. Bilateral renal artery stenosis, renal artery stenosis in a solitary kidney, postrenal transplant patients or patients with only one kidney. 6. Clinically relevant hypokalaemia or hyperkalaemia (i.e., &lt;3.5 or &gt;5.5 mEq/L). 7. Uncorrected sodium or volume depletion. 8. Primary aldosteronism. 9. Hereditary fructose intolerance. 10. Congestive heart failure New York Heart Association functional class Congestive Heart Failure IIIIV (Refer to Appendix 10.1). 11. Clinically significant ventricular tachycardia, atrial fibrillation, atrial flutter or other clinically relevant cardiac arrhythmias as determined by the Investigator. 12. Biliary obstructive disorders (e.g., cholestasis) or hepatic insufficiency (defined as elevated levels of &gt;2x bilirubin or &gt;2x transaminases values). (Refer to Appendix 10.3) 13. Patients who have previously experienced symptoms characteristic of angioedema during treatment with ACE inhibitors or angiotensinII receptor antagonists. 14. History of drug or alcohol dependency within six months prior to signing the informed consent form. 15. Any investigational drug therapy within one month of signing the informed consent. 16. Known hypersensitivity to any component of the trial drugs (telmisartan or amlodipine). 17. History of noncompliance or inability to comply with prescribed medications or protocol procedures. 18. Any other clinical condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, would not allow safe completion of the protocol and safe administration of the trial medication.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>