<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01134016</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A phase I study to determine the maximum tolerable dose (MTD) and to evaluate pharmacokinetic, safety/tolerability and efficacy profiles of antroquinonol (Hocena®) in non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) subjects refractory to conventional treatment modalities</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Determine MTD and to Evaluate pk, Safety/Tolerability and Efficacy Profiles of Hocena® in NSCLC Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>1. Antroquinonol, a novel cyclohexenone compound, is a purified compound from extract of Antrodia camphorata. 2. The pharmacological effects of antroquinonol were postulated to exert its antitumorigenesis effects through interactions to primary targets of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)/Akt/mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK). 3. In vivo study in NOD/SCID mice with A549 subcutaneous xenografts consistently showed tumor growth suppression after 2 weeks of oral 30 and 60 mg/kg antroquinonol treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ubiquinone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age ≥ 20 years. 2. Diagnosed stage III/IV NSCLC. The grading is determined according to the TumorNodeMetastasis (TNM) staging system for lung cancer. 3. Patients with histologically or cytologically proven primary NSCLC with adenocarcinoma or mixed cell type with adenocarcinoma, who have failed on standard treatments. 4. With progressive tumor after two lines of chemotherapy (including one platinumbased) and 1 EGFRtargeted therapy if patient is identified with EGFR mutation or his/her EGFR mutation status is unknown OR having refused further currently approved treatment modalities. 5. Life expectancy ≥ 3 months. 6. Within 1 week of planned first study treatment day, adequate hematopoietic functions are presented: Total white blood cell (WBC) ≥ 3500 cells/mm3 Hemoglobin (Hb) ≥ 9.0 g/dL Platelets ≥ 100,000 cells/mm3 Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1500 /mm3 7. Within 1 week of planned first study treatment day, adequate hepatic and renal functions are presented: Total bilirubin ≤2.0 mg/dLGOLANTA20090911, Amendment 4/v. 1.0/ 13 October 2010 AST ≤ 3 × upper limit of normal (ULN); patients with liver metastasis: AST ≤ 5 × ULN ALT ≤ 3 × ULN; patients with liver metastasis: ALT ≤ 5 × ULN Creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL 8. Must have recovered from toxicities of previous anticancer treatments to grade 1 NCICTC or better, except for alopecia. 9. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance score ≤ 2. 10. Female patient with childbearing potential confirmed of not being pregnant at the screening; and informed that effective contraception must be used during the entire treatment period of this study and for 6 months after exiting from the study. 11. Given signed and dated written informed consent form. 1. Primary major surgery &lt; 4 weeks prior to the planned first study treatment day. 2. Lactating, pregnant or plans to be become pregnant. 3. Except for alopecia, recovered from any previous treatments to a grade 1 or less prior to the planned first study treatment day. 4. With active systemic infections, active and clinically significant cardiac diseases, active gastrointestinal ulcers, or medical conditions that may significantly affect adequate absorption of investigational product. 5. Within 5 years, prior history of malignancy other than NSCLC, except cervical carcinoma in situ and basal or squamous cell skin carcinoma. 6. Known allergic to antroquinonol or its formulation excipients. 7. Within 14 days of planned first study treatment day, exposed to any drug(s) known to be significant CYP2C19, 3A4, 2C8, and 2E1, inhibitor or activator. 8. With conditions judged by the investigator as unsuitable for the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
</DOC>