<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02254772</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase I/II trial studies the side effects and best dose of ipilimumab in combination with toll-like receptor 9 (TLR9) agonist SD-101 and radiation therapy in treating patients with low-grade B-cell lymphoma that has returned. Monoclonal antibodies, such as ipilimumab, may block cancer growth in different ways by targeting certain cells. Biological therapies, such as TLR9 agonist SD-101, use substances made from living organisms that may stimulate or suppress the immune system in different ways and stop cancer cells from growing. Radiation therapy uses high energy x-rays to kill cancer cells and shrink tumors. Giving ipilimumab in combination with TLR9 agonist SD-101 and radiation therapy may be a better treatment for B-cell lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TLR9 Agonist SD-101, Ipilimumab, and Radiation Therapy in Treating Patients With Low-Grade Recurrent B-cell Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the safety and tolerability of increasing dose levels of intratumoral injections of ipilimumab and a fixed dose of intratumoral injection of SD-101 (TLR9 agonist SD-101) combined with local radiation in patients with low-grade B-cell lymphoma. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the local and systemic anti-tumor effects of intratumoral injection of ipilimumab and intratumoral injections of SD-101 combined with local radiation in patients with low-grade B-cell lymphoma. II. To evaluate tumor-specific humoral and cellular immune responses. OUTLINE: This is a phase I, dose-escalation study of ipilimumab followed by a phase II study. Patients receive TLR9 agonist SD-101 via intratumoral injection on days 1, 2, 8, 15, and 22; ipilimumab via intratumoral injection on day 1; and undergo radiation therapy on days 1 and 2. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at weeks 6, 8, 10, 12, and 24, and then every 3-6 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Follicular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell, Marginal Zone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Biopsy confirmed lowgrade Bcell lymphoma, specifically, follicular grade 1 or 2, or 3A marginal zone or small lymphocytic lymphoma; patients must have relapsed from or are refractory to prior therapy Patients must have at least one site of disease that is accessible for intratumoral injection of SD101 and of ipilimumab (diameter &gt;= 10mm), percutaneously Tumor specimens must be available for immunological studies either from a previous biopsy or a new biopsy obtained before the initiation of the study Patients must have measurable disease other than the injection site or biopsy site Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1 (corresponds to Karnofsky performance status [KPS of &gt;= 70) White blood cell count (WBC): &gt;= 2000/µL (~2 x 10^9/L) Absolute neutrophil count (ANC): &gt;= 1000/µL (~0.5 x 10^9/L) Platelets: &gt;= 75 x 10^3/µL (~75 x 10^9/L) Hemoglobin: &gt;= 8 g/dL (may be transfused) Creatinine: =&lt; 2.0 x upper limit of normal (ULN) Aspartate aminotransferase (AST)/alanine aminotransferase (ALT): =&lt; 2.5 x ULN for subjects without liver metastasis; =&lt; 5 times for liver metastases Bilirubin: =&lt; 2.0 x ULN (except for subjects with Gilbert's Syndrome, who must have a total bilirubin of less than 3.0 mg/dL) No active or chronic infection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), Hepatitis B, or Hepatitis C Must be at least 4 weeks since treatment with standard or investigational chemotherapy, biochemotherapy, surgery, radiation, cytokine therapy, and 8 weeks since any monoclonal antibodies or immunotherapy, and recovered from any clinically significant toxicity experienced during treatment Patients of reproductive potential must agree to use an effective (&gt; 90% reliability) form of contraception during the study and for 6 months following the last study drug administration Women of reproductive potential must have negative urine pregnancy test Life expectancy greater than 4 months Able to comply with the treatment schedule Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document Preexisting autoimmune or antibody mediated disease including: systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, multiple sclerosis, Sjogren's syndrome, autoimmune thrombocytopenia, Addison's disease, but excluding the presence of autoantibodies without clinical autoimmune disease History of inflammatory bowel disease (e.g., Crohn's disease or ulcerative colitis), celiac disease, or other chronic gastrointestinal conditions associated with diarrhea, or current acute colitis of any origin History of diverticulitis (even a single episode) or evidence of diverticulitis at baseline, including evidence limited to computed tomography (CT) scan only; note: diverticulosis is not an exclusion criterion per se Severe psoriasis Active thyroiditis History of uveitis Known history of HIV; patients with Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (AIDS) are excluded Patients with active infection or with a fever &gt; 38.5 degrees C within three days prior to the first scheduled treatment Central nervous system (CNS) lymphoma Prior malignancy (active within 5 years of screening) except basal cell or completely excised noninvasive squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, or in situ squamous cell carcinoma of the cervix History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar composition to SD101 or ipilimumab (anticytotoxic Tlymphocyteassociated protein 4 [CTLA4] antibodies) Current anticoagulant therapy (acetylsalicylic acid [ASA] =&lt; 325 mg per day allowed) Treatment with an immunosuppressive regimen of corticosteroids or other immunosuppressive medication (e.g., methotrexate, rapamycin) within 30 days of study treatment; note: patients with adrenal insufficiency may take up to 5 mg of prednisone or equivalent daily; topical and inhaled corticosteroids in standard doses are allowed Significant cardiovascular disease (i.e. New York Heart Association [NYHA] class 3 congestive heart failure; myocardial infarction with the past 6 months; unstable angina; coronary angioplasty with the past 6 months; uncontrolled atrial or ventricular cardiac arrhythmias) Pregnant or lactating Any other medical history, including laboratory results, deemed by the investigator to be likely to interfere with their participation in the study, or to interfere with the interpretation of the results</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>