<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02254876</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Painful Shoulder Syndrome is a frequent complication after stroke occurring in between 5% and 84% of patients, often having a strong impact on their well-being and resulting in delays achieving rehabilitative objectives. The aim of the study is to demonstrate the effectiveness of Neuromuscular Taping in a population of post-stroke hemiplegic patients suffering from painful shoulder syndrome with respect to pain, spasticity and range of motion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of NeuroMuscular Taping on Painful Hemiplegic Shoulder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will use two groups according to the methodology of Randomized Controlled Trials. Both components of the two groups were treated by four rehabilitation sessions defined as "standard". This involves joint health and passive mobility for the glenohumeral and scapulothoracic joints for a period of about 45 minutes each. The patients of the sample group underwent the application of the NeuroMuscular Taping (NMT) before each rehabilitative session. The control group was addressed exclusively to the "standard" treatment. The sessions were spaced apart about five days to ensure the optimum adhesion of NMT. The results were evaluated by administering rating scales for pain (VAS) and spasticity (Modified Ashworth Scale). The ROM was evaluated using the manual goniometer. The outcomes (Pain, Spasticity, ROM) were assessed at base line, before and after each treatment session and at 1 month follow up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemiplegia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Right or left hemiplegia resulting from an ischemic or hemorrhagic stroke Painful Shoulder Syndrome, with pain at rest and during functional movement of the shoulder girdle Spasticity with an Ashworth score greater than or equal to 1. Flaccidity Thermoalgesic sensitivity deficits Previous surgery to the shoulder Cognitive impairment Taking antiinflammatory drugs and/or muscle relaxants during the course of the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemiplegia</keyword>
	<keyword>Painful shoulder Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>NeuroMuscolar Taping</keyword>
</DOC>