<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01377922</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Phase 3 study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of Amifampridine Phosphate in patients with Lambert-Eaton Myasthenic Syndrome (LEMS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 3 Study of Amifampridine Phosphate in Patients With Lambert Eaton Myasthenic Syndrome (LEMS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This multicenter, double-blind, placebo-controlled, randomized (1:1) discontinuation study is a 4 part study designed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of multiple dose administration of amifampridine phosphate in patients with LEMS.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lambert-Eaton Myasthenic Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>3,4-diaminopyridine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Individuals eligible to participate in this study must meet all of the following inclusion criteria: ≥18 years of age Confirmed diagnosis of LEMS Normal respiratory function Normal swallowing function If receiving peripherally acting cholinesterase inhibitors a stable dose is required for at least 7 days prior to Screening. If receiving oral immunosuppressants a stable dose is required for at least 90 days prior to Screening. Negative pregnancy test for females of childbearing potential If sexually active, willing to use 2 acceptable methods of contraception Willing to perform all study procedures as physically possible. Willing and able to provide written informed consent after the nature of the study has been explained and prior to the start of any researchrelated procedures. Individuals who meet any of the following exclusion criteria are not eligible to participate in the study: History of epilepsy or seizure. Known active brain metastasis. Use of Fampridine (4aminopyridine), and any form of 3,4diaminopyridine other than the IP provided, such as amifampridine base or Firdapse, during the study. Use of medications known to lower the epileptic threshold within 7 days or 5 halflives. Use of medications which inhibit neuromuscular junction function within 7 days or 5 halflives. Use of IVIG, plasmapheresis (plasma exchange), or immunoadsorption within 90 days Use of guanidine hydrochloride within 7 days Use of rituximab within 12 months History of drug allergy to any pyridinecontaining substances or any amifampridine phosphate excipient(s). Use of any other investigational productwithin 30 days Treatment with a concomitant medication that prolongs the QT/QTc interval within 7 days or 5 halflives. Treatment with sultopride (4aminoN[(1ethylpyrrolidin2yl)methyl]5ethylsulfonyl2methoxybenzamide) within 7 days. An abnormal electrocardiogram (ECG). Documented history of arrhythmias. History of additional risk factors for torsade de pointes. Breastfeeding or pregnant or planning to become pregnant (self or partner) at any time during the study. Likely or expected to require treatment for cancer within 3 months (90 days) after entering. History of severe renal impairment or evidence of severe renal impairment Any condition that places the patient at high risk of poor treatment compliance or of not completing the study. History of uncontrolled asthma.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>