<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01377597</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to provide efficacy and safety data of 3 consecutive monthly intravitreal injections with 0.5 mg ranibizumab in Japanese patients with visual impairment due to macular edema secondary to retinal vein occlusion (BRVO or CRVO) to support the applicability of the phase III study results of BRAVO and CRUISE in this indication, in the Japanese ethnic patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Ranibizumab in Japanese Patients With Retinal Vein Occlusion</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Retinal Vein Occlusion</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vision Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Japanese patients diagnosed with visual impairment exclusively due to macular edema secondary to either branch retinal vein occlusion (BRVO) or central retinal vein occlusion (CRVO) Diagnosis within 12 months prior to Visit 1 Bestcorrected visual acuity (BCVA): CRVO: BCVA score ≥24 and ≤73 letters ETDRS (approx. Snellen equivalent of 20/320 and 20/40) at Visit 1 and 2 BRVO: BCVA score ≥19 and ≤73 letters ETDRS (approx. Snellen equivalent of 20/400 and 20/40) at Visit 1 and 2 Pregnant or nursing women History of stroke Uncontrolled blood pressure Active ocular infection or intraocular inflammation in either eye Uncontrolled glaucoma in either eye Neovascularization of the iris or neovascular glaucoma in either eye Prior episode of RVO more than 12 months prior to Visit 1 in the study eye Use of any systemic antiVEGF drugs within 6 months prior to Visit 2 Prior treatment with any antiangiogenic drugs within 3 months prior to Visit 2 in either eye Prior panretinal laser photocoagulation within 3 months prior to Visit 2 in the study eye Prior focal/grid laser photocoagulation within 4 months prior to Visit 2 in the study eye Use of intra/periocular corticosteroids within 3 months prior to Visit 1 in the study eye Use of any intraocular corticosteroid implants in the study eye Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>retinal vein occlusion</keyword>
	<keyword>branch retinal vein occlusion</keyword>
	<keyword>central retinal vein occlusion</keyword>
	<keyword>visual impairment</keyword>
	<keyword>macular edema</keyword>
	<keyword>ranibizumab</keyword>
</DOC>