<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01377519</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a pilot randomized, blinded, placebo-controlled trial of a noninvasive, FDA approved treatment for uterine fibroids called MR Guided Focused Ultrasound (MRgFUS). Our hypothesis is that MRgFUS provides superior relief of fibroid symptoms compared with the placebo, a sham MRgFUS treatment. The investigators will recruit 20 premenopausal women with symptomatic uterine fibroids to participate in the trial. Participants will be randomly assigned in a 2:1 ratio to the active treatment arm (MRgFUS) versus the sham MRgFUS treatment. Participants will remain blinded to their group assignment for 3 months. After 3 months, participants will be told their treatment group and those assigned to the sham group will be offered complimentary MRgFUS if they desire it. Women will be excluded if they are inappropriate candidates for a 3 month delay in fibroid treatment, such as those with significant anemia. The investigators will assess the change from baseline to 1 and 3 months after treatment in fibroid symptoms, quality of life, fibroid volume measured by MRI, and hematocrit.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Magnetic Resonance Guided Focused Ultrasound for Uterine Fibroids</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leiomyoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myofibroma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age&gt;18 years Premenopausal Symptomatic fibroids Fibroids accessible for focused ultrasound treatment Exclusion criteria: Desires future fertility Current pregnancy Hematocrit &lt;30% Emergency room visit in last 3 months for fibroid symptoms History of venous thromboembolism Fibroids that are: &gt;10cm, nonenhancing with contrast Adenomyosis Contraindications to undergoing MRI Unexplained menstrual irregularity</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fibroids</keyword>
	<keyword>Uterine</keyword>
	<keyword>Focused Ultrasound</keyword>
	<keyword>Magnetic Resonance focused ultrasound</keyword>
	<keyword>HIFU</keyword>
	<keyword>NOninvasive</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment</keyword>
</DOC>