<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00418262</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Determine if atomoxetine is safe and well tolerated by children with fetal alcohol syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-Label Study of the Long Term Tolerability and Safety of Atomoxetine in Children With FASD and ADD/ADHD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Abnormalities of attention, function, and activity level in children exposed to alcohol in utero share similarities and differences to children who do not have alcohol exposure. Previous psychological studies have examined either core attention deficit hyperactivity (ADHD) symptoms of hyperactivity, inattention, and impulsivity or hypothesized neuropsychological differences in children with fetal alcohol syndrome (FAS) and ADHD. Atomoxetine Hydrochloride is a non-stimulant medication used to treat ADHD. This study will determine if atomoxetine HCL significantly reduces symptoms of ADD/ADHD in children with fetal alcohol exposure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atomoxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient must have been between the ages of 4 and 11 years at the time of entry into the double blind study. Patients must meet diagnostic criteria for FASD. Patient must, at entry into doubleblind study, have met DSMIV criteria for ADHD, any subtype. And must have an ADHDRSIV score of &gt; or + 90% for age and gender on either subtest or total score for children above 5 years of age. Patients will continue atomoxetine/placebo until entry nto this study. History and physical exam must reveal no clinically significant abnormalities that would preclude safe participation in the study. Patients must be able to swallow capsules. Patients must be of a sufficient mental age (3 yrs) to participate in the study. Patients and parents must be able to communicate effectively with the investigator and coordinator and be judged reliable to keep appointments and participate in data collection. Teacher must agree to cooperate with the study. Have received an investigational medication other than atomoxetine in the previous 30 days. Have significant current medical conditions that could be exacerbated or compromised by atomoxetine. Have used MAOIs within one month prior to visit 1. Patients with hypertension. Patients with a previous diagnosis of bipolar disorder, psychosis, or autism spectrum disorder. Patients taking anticonvulsants for seizure control. Patients taking another psychotropic medication or health food supplements purported to have central nervous system activity within 5 halflives of visit 1. Patients with Tourette Disorder or any other neurological condition that would interfere with their ability to receive treatment or comply with monitoring. Pubertal girls.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>fetal alcohol syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>attention deficit disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>attention deficit disorder with hyperactivity</keyword>
	<keyword>ADD</keyword>
	<keyword>FAS</keyword>
	<keyword>FASD</keyword>
	<keyword>ADHD</keyword>
</DOC>