<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00418314</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to demonstrate that frequent atrio-ventricular (AV/PV) and inter-ventricular (V-V) delay optimization using QuickOpt in patients with cardiac resynchronization therapy device results in improved clinical response over standard of care (i.e. empiric programming or one-time optimization using any non-intracardiac electrogram optimization methods).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>FREEDOM - A Frequent Optimization Study Using the QuickOpt Method</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>- This is a prospective, double-blinded, multicenter, randomized study - Patient could be enrolled up to 2 weeks post CRT-D implant and are followed for 12 months post implant with follow-up visits at 3, 6, 9 and 12 months - Patients will be randomized at enrollment to either Group 1 ("QuickOpt Group") or Group 2 ("Control Group"). - Group 1 - The patient's device is programmed to sequential biventricular pacing mode with AV/PV and VV delays optimized using QuickOpt. For Group 1 patients, optimization using QuickOpt is performed at enrollment, 3 month, 6 month, 9 month, 12 month and at any unscheduled follow-up visits. - Group 2 - The patient's device is programmed to either simultaneous or sequential BiV pacing mode as per physician's discretion. The AV/PV and inter-ventricular (VV) delays could be programmed empirically or optimized using any non-IEGM based method as per sites standard of care. However, the Group 2 patients can be optimized only once within the first 4 weeks post implant. Any AV/PV and VV delay optimizations performed after 4 weeks post implant in Group 2 patients will be considered protocol deviations.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arrhythmias, Cardiac</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient meets current CRTD indications and be implanted with a St. Jude Medical (SJM) CRT¬D device with VV timing and a compatible lead system. Patient has the ability to complete a 6minute hall walk with the only limiting factor to be fatigue or shortness of breath. Patient has the ability to independently comprehend and complete a QOL questionnaire. Patient has an epicardial ventricular lead system. Patient has the ability to walk ≥ 450 meters in 6 minutes Patient has limited intrinsic atrial activity (≤ 40 bpm). Patient has persistent or permanent atrial fibrillation (AF). Patient has a 2° or 3° heart block. Patient's life expectancy is less than 1 year. Patient is pregnant. Patient is on IV inotropic agents.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>