<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01814111</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate whether renal sympathetic denervation is safe and effective in patients with hypertension and paroxysmal atrial fibrillation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Renal Sympathetic Denervation in Patients With Hypertension and Paroxysmal Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Atrial fibrillation (AF) is one of the most common cardiac arrhythmia, complications of AF such as stroke, thromboembolism and heart failure will bring high disable rate and mortality , which will be serious influence on people's health and aggrandize medical financial burden, however, treatment for AF is not ideal. The affection of traditional antiarrhythmia drugs is not enough good, due to extra-heart bad reaction and potential arrhythmogenic substrate function restricted; rate control strategy applied quite abroad, however, anticoagulated medicine were not applied enough, Radiofrequency catheter ablation of AF has developed rapidly in recent years, But it's station is also disputed and its success rate is low and recrudescence is very high. meanwhile, serious complications will be caused. So far, hypertension is the most risk factor of AF. Long-term hypertension will change left-ventricle structure, through variability of pressure loading and capacity loading, damage diastolic function of left-ventricle. Increase of diastolic pressure in left-ventricle and atrial pressure will gradually result in atrial enlargement and fibrosis, so it will cause atrial fibrillation, repeating paroxysm or slow maintaining. Investigation indicated anti-hypertension therapy can decrease occurrence ratio and reoccurrence ratio of AF. Recently, many clinical researches have verified that renal sympathetic denervation acquired exact and sustained hypotension effect, In addition, Renal sympathetic denervation can reduce left ventricular hypertrophy, improve glucose metabolization and obstructive sleep, meanwhile, it reduce the level of nonepinephrine for both partial and whole-body. While left ventricle hypertrophy, left atrium enlarge，epinephrine over release itself and breath sleep obstacle are the independent dangerous factors of emerging AF. So ,we design this randomized parallel control multi center clinical study to demonstrate that renal sympathetic denervation is a safe and effective treatment for patients with hypertension and paroxysmal atrial fibrillation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Individual is ≥ 18 and ≤ 75 years of age. 2. More than half a year for definite hypertension. 3. AF is a common superventricular arrhythmia that is characterized by chaotic contraction of the atrium. An electrocardiogram (EGG) recording is necessary to diagnose AF. At least 30 seconds on a rhythm strip in an EGG record and at least 1 AF outbreak which was recorded by EGG and Holter in half a year. 4. Paroxysmal AF Individual ,Paroxysmal AF is defined as recurrent AF (≧2 episodes) that terminates spontaneously within 7 days. Episodes of AF of ≤ 48 hours' duration that are terminated with electrical or pharmacologic cardioversion should also be classified as paroxysmal AF episodes. 5. Individual eligible conditions through renal artery CTA inspection, such as undoubled renal artery on one side, renal artery length≧2cm, diameter≧4mm, and distortion at incept sect. 6. Agree to attend clinic experiment and sign written informed consent. 1. Persistent AF Individual, Persistent AF is defined as continuous AF that is sustained beyond seven days. Episodes of AF in which a decision is made to electrically or pharmacologically cardiovert the patient after _≧48 hours of AF, but prior to 7 days, should also be classified as persistent AF episodes. 2. Individual with Severely enlarged left atria≥ 55 mm 3. Individual who reversibility mostly generated AF, such as abnormal hypothyroid or structural heart diseases 4. Individual has experienced renal artery stenosis ，or A history of prior renal artery intervention including balloon angioplasty or stenting. or ineligible conditions through renal artery CTA inspection, such as double renal artery on one side, renal artery length≤2cm, diameter≤4mm, and distortion at incept sect. 5. Individual has experienced a definite acute coronary syndrome in recent 3 months, or a cerebrovascular accident and alimentary canal bleeding within 3 months 6. Individual has experienced sick sinus syndrome 7. Pregnant Women or planning to be Pregnant Women, psychopathy Individual, individual who is sensitive to visualization, individual who can not cooperate with followup visit, or individual who researcher think it unsuitable to be included in this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Atrial Fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>Arrhythmias, Cardiac</keyword>
	<keyword>Heart Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular Diseases</keyword>
</DOC>