<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01899157</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A prospective cross-sectional study evaluates nutritional status and its relationship to the related factors in Thai HIV-infected patients who attending in out patient clinic.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nutritional Status Among na誰ve HIV Infected Patients and HIV Infected Patients Receiving Highly Active Antiretroviral Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A prospective cross-sectional study evaluates nutritional status and its relationship to the related factors in Thai HIV-infected patients who attending in out patient clinic at The Thai Red Cross AIDS Research Centre, Bamrasnaradura Infectious Disease Institute, Surat Thani hospital, Khonkaen hospital, Sanpathong hospital and the Queen Savang Vadhana Hospital at Sri Racha . General Objective: To determine nutritional status among Thai People Living with HIV (PLHIV). Specific Objective: 1. To assess nutritional problems including undernutrition, overnutrition and others such as lipodystrophy, dyslipidemia, hyperglycemia, cardiovascular disease, etc. among na誰ve HIV-infected patients and HIV-infected patients undergoing HARRT by using ABCDEF approach: Anthropometric, Biochemical, Clinical, Dietary, Exercise and Family assessment. 2. To describe the relationship between the nutritional status and HIV disease staging and other related factors among na誰ve HIV-infected patients and HIV-infected patients undergoing HARRT. 3. To describe the prevalence of CVD and its relationship to cardiac risk factors 4. To validate the community screening tool developed by the Thai Nutrition Taskforce in HIV (TNT-HIV) by assessing the correlation of this tool and nutritional status.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HIV positive 18 years of age or older Receiving ongoing care as part of the anonymous clinic, TRCARC, the antiretroviral therapy clinics at Bamrasnaradura Infectious Disease Institute, Surat Thani hospital, Khonkaen hospital, Sanpathong hospital and the Queen Savang Vadhana Hospital at Sri Racha. Either na誰ve HIVinfected patients and HIVinfected patients undergoing HARRT HIV negative Patient who had active AIDSrelated disorders within three months before participate the study Patients who are pregnant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Nutritional status</keyword>
	<keyword>Nutritional situation</keyword>
</DOC>