<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02260063</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the bioequivalence of two galenic formulations for epinastine (Flurinol®): syrup and 20 mg tablets</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Relative Bioavailability of Epinastine Syrup Compared to Tablets in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Epinastine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>male and female, nonsmoker and nonalcohol user, healthy volunteers, of 21 45 years of age. To be eligible, women must not be pregnant or lactating and they must not be taking hormone contraceptives Volunteers must not have a history of liver or renal disease or a history of psychiatric disorder. Volunteers will be submitted to the biochemical tests listed below, the results of which must be within expected normal values: complete blood count, erythrosedimentation rate, GOT (glutamate oxalacetate transaminase) GPT (glutamate pyruvate transaminase), blood creatinine, glycemia, uremia, blood cholesterol, pregnancy test. HIV test (with prior written consent), serum tests for Chagas disease, hepatic b and syphilis, complete urinalysis, ECG (electrocardiogram) and chest xray Volunteers must have discontinued all pharmacological treatment at least two weeks before entering this trial informed written consent, signed prior to the start of this trial Volunteers requiring any kind of pharmacological treatment or having some known addiction Volunteers having participated in any other clinical trial during the four preceding weeks Volunteers who must start a treatment incompatible with this trial during its course Volunteers who do not comply with the fasting requirements established in the trial or who do not comply with trial requirements such as avoiding intake of coffee, tea, cola soft drinks, etc. for 24 hours prior to the start of the trial History of allergy or intolerance to Epinastine Uncooperative volunteers Previous participation in this trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>