<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02807623</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical investigation is to evaluate the efficacy and immunologic effects of a non-pharmacological exercise intervention (pushups) compared to an oral NSAID (ibuprofen) and an oral placebo to decrease local injection site inflammation symptoms of delayed pain, erythema, and edema and any impact on serologic antibody immune response after influenza vaccine receipt.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Do NSAIDS or Executing Exercise Decrease Local Erythema, Site Swelling &amp; Pain After INoculation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will evaluate the efficacy and immunologic effects of a non-pharmacological exercise intervention (pushups) compared to an oral NSAID (ibuprofen) and a blinded oral placebo to decrease local injection site inflammation symptoms of delayed pain, erythema, and edema and any impact on serologic antibody immune response after influenza vaccine receipt. A healthy military cohort will be randomly assigned to either perform pushups consistent with their army physical fitness score, or to take a blinded oral medication which will be an NSAID (ibuprofen) or an oral placebo. The study will require three visits for assessment: on the day of vaccine receipt, 48-72 hours later and 21 -28 days later. The assessment visits will include injection site inspection, an injection site photograph, completion of symptom diaries and a validated pain scale and a laboratory blood specimen at the first and third visit to measure antibody level changes. The exercise participants will also be required to provide 1-2 fingerstick blood samples to evaluate for lactate, which is a byproduct of anaerobic exercise to measure if level of exercise effort achieved anaerobic metabolism. The study will evaluate if either of the interventions impacted perceived delayed pain, physical signs of inflammation or antibody response as measured by serology.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Erythema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ibuprofen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must: 1. Be Active Duty Service Members. 2. at least 18 years of age or older. 3. Be requiring and eligible for inactivated influenza vaccine receipt. 4. Be willing and able to complete the study protocol requirements. 5. Have a current Womack Army Medical Center Flu Screening Form with medical clearance to receive the influenza vaccination. Must Not: 1. Have already received influenza vaccine for this season. 2. Have received any type of vaccine in the previous 72 hours. 3. Be on a medical profile resulting in current profile exemption from Physical Training of Upper 2 or Upper 3. (Upper extremity injury or illness) 4. Have preexisting symptoms of injury or infection or other local symptoms that would interfere with site assessment. 5. Be pregnant. 6. Have a history of allergy, intolerance, stomach bleeding or other medical exclusion for ibuprofen. 7. Have a history of stroke or coronary artery disease, such as uncontrolled high blood pressure or abnormal heart beat. 8. Has taken any topical or oral pain medications from the following medication classes in the past 24 hours prior to the start of the study: oral acetaminophen, opioids, tramadol, nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug (NSAID) or acetylsalicylic acid (ASA) or topical pain relievers or counterirritants of menthol, methyl salicylate, camphor menthols, and capsaicins. 9. Have any chronic or acute illness or treatment causing immunological suppression such as current oral steroid therapy, malignancy or chemotherapy or lung disease. (not including controlled asthma) 10. Currently participating in any other study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>