<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02807077</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1 open label, single dose, 5 parallel-group study in which a single 400 mg dose of pacritinib will be administered orally to patients with renal impairment (mild, moderate, severe, and patients with ESRD requiring hemodialysis) and sex-, age- and weight-matched healthy subjects.Patients with ESRD will receive a single 400 mg dose of pacritinib during 2 different treatment periods: Dialysis and Inter-Dialysis. The primary objective of the study is to evaluate the pharmacokinetics and safety of pacritinib in renal impairment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>To Determine PK of Pacritinib in Patients With Mild, Moderate, and Severe Renal Impairment and ESRD Compared to Healthy Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Groups 1, 2, and 3 will consist of 8 patients each with mild, moderate, or severe renal disease, respectively, based on their estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR, calculated by the Modification of Diet in Renal Disease [MDRD] study equation). Each of these patients will receive a single 400 mg dose of pacritinib. Group 4 will consist of 8 patients with ESRD requiring hemodialysis who have been on a stable dialysis regimen for at least 6 months. In this cohort only, patients will participate in 2 treatment periods, Dialysis and Inter-Dialysis, separated by a 14-day period between pacritinib administration. In the Dialysis Treatment Period, a single 400 mg dose of pacritinib will be administered 4 hours prior to each patient's normally scheduled hemodialysis. In the Inter-Dialysis Treatment Period, a single 400 mg dose of pacritinib will be administered immediately after the end of the patient's normally scheduled hemodialysis session. Group 5 will consist of 8 healthy subjects enrolled to match the sex-, age-, and weight of the patients with mild, moderate, and severe renal impairment and patients with ESRD enrolled in the study. Healthy subjects will be administered a single 400 mg dose of pacritinib.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Primary Myelofibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All Study Participants 1. Male and/or female participants aged 18 to 85 years (inclusive) 2. Male, nonfertile female or female of childbearing potential using a medically approved birth control method Females must be nonpregnant and nonlactating, and females not of childbearing potential must be postmenopausal for at least 1 year or surgically sterile (e.g., tubal ligation, hysterectomy) for at least 90 days, or agree to use contraception from the time of signing the informed consent or 10 days prior to Checkin (Day 1) until 30 days after Study Completion. One of the following forms of contraception must be used from the time of signing the informed consent or 10 days prior to Checkin (Day 1) until 14 days after the final dose administration: nonhormonal intrauterine device (IUD) with spermicide; female condom with spermicide; contraceptive sponge with spermicide; intravaginal system (e.g.,NuvaRing®); diaphragm with spermicide; cervical cap with spermicide; male sexual partner who agrees to use a male condom with spermicide; sterile sexual partner; or abstinence. Oral, implantable, transdermal, or injectable contraceptives may not be used from the time of signing the informed consent or 10 days prior to Checkin (Day 1) until 14 days after the final dose administration. For all females, the pregnancy test result must be negative at Screening and Checkin (Day 1) Males will be sterile, or completely abstain from sexual intercourse, or agree to use, from Checkin (Day 1) until 90 days following Study Completion/ET, one of the following approved methods of contraception: male condom with spermicide; sterile sexual partner; or use by female sexual partner of an IUD with spermicide; a female condom with spermicide; a contraceptive sponge with spermicide; an intravaginal system; a diaphragm with spermicide; a cervical cap with spermicide; or oral, implantable, transdermal, or injectable contraceptives. Participants will refrain from sperm donation from Checkin (Day 1) until 90 days following Study Completion 3. Body mass index (BMI) 1833kg/m2 (inclusive) at Screening 4. Negative test for selected drugs of abuse (including alcohol) at Screening and at Checkin (Day 1) for Groups 13 and 5. Negative test for selected drugs of abuse (including alcohol) is only required at Screening in Group 4 5. Negative hepatitis panel (including hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg] and hepatitis C virus antibody [anti HCV]) and negative human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antibody screens 6. Able to communicate well with the investigator, to understand and comply with the requirements of the study. Understand and sign the written informed consent. Legal authorized representatives are not permitted Patients with Renal Impairment Only In addition to the inclusion criteria specified for "All Study Participants" above, patients with renal impairment must meet the following criteria: 7. Have stable renal disease without evidence of progressive renal disease (i.e. no known significant change of eGFR for 12 weeks) mild renal impairment: eGFR 6089 mL/min/1.73 m2 moderate renal impairment: eGFR 3059 mL/min/1.73 m2 severe renal impairment: CrCl from eGFR 1529 mL/min/1.73 m2 ESRD: requiring dialysis and have been on a stable dialysis regimen for at least 6 months Renal function will be determined from Screening serum creatinine value using the MDRD Study equation 8. Vital signs (after 5 minutes resting measured in the supine position) within the following ranges as guidance for the Investigator: oral body temperature between 35.037.8 °C systolic blood pressure, 95180 mm Hg diastolic blood pressure, 5595 mm Hg pulse rate, 5095 bpm Blood pressure and pulse will be taken again in a standing position. After 3 minutes standing, there shall be no more than a 20 mm Hg drop in systolic or 10 mm Hg drop in diastolic blood pressure associated with symptomatic postural hypotension Healthy Subjects Only In addition to the inclusion criteria specified for "All Study Participants" above, healthy subjects must meet the following criteria: 9. No history or clinical manifestation of clinically significant cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic, renal, hematologic, gastrointestinal (e.g., celiac disease, peptic ulcer, gastro esophageal reflux, inflammatory bowel disease), metabolic, allergic, dermatological, neurological, or psychiatric disorder (as determined by the Investigator; appendectomy and cholecystectomy are not considered to be clinically significant disease) 10. Normal renal function, eGFR ≥90 mL/min/1.73m2 (determined by Screening serum creatinine using the MDRD Study equation) 11. Matched with all enrolled patients with renal impairment for age classes in the 025, 2650, 5175, and 76100 percentiles of age distribution 12. Matched with all enrolled patients with renal impairment for weight (BMI) classes in the 025, 2650, 5175, and 76100 percentiles of BMI distribution 13. Matched according to the sex distribution of all enrolled patients with renal impairment 14. Vital signs (after 5 minutes resting measured in the supine position) within the following ranges as guidance for the Investigator: oral body temperature between 35.037.5 °C systolic blood pressure, 90160 mm Hg diastolic blood pressure, 50100 mm Hg pulse rate, 4590 bpm Blood pressure and pulse will be taken again in a standing position. After 3 minutes standing, there shall be no more than a 20 mm Hg drop in systolic or 10 mm Hg drop in diastolic blood pressure associated with symptomatic postural hypotension All Study Participants Participants meeting any of the following criteria will be excluded from entry into or continuation in the study unless sponsor approval is obtained: 1. Pregnant or lactating female 2. Renal transplant at any time 3. Liver cirrhosis or a positive Hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) or Hepatitis C antibody test result 4. History of immunodeficiency diseases, including a positive HIV antibody test result 5. Acute renal failure 6. History of chronic or recurrent urinary tract infection active within the past 30 days 7. History of pelvic irradiation within the past 30 days 8. Alcohol related hepatic disease 9. History of malignancy except the following: cancers determined to be cured or in remission for ≥5 years, curatively resected basal cell or squamous cell skin cancers, cervical cancer in situ, or resected colonic polyps 10. Any of the following within the past 6 months: myocardial infarction (MI) (if the Screening ECG reveals patterns consistent with a MI and the date of the event cannot be determined, then the subject can enter the study at the discretion of the Investigator and/or local medical monitor, with sponsor's permission) coronary artery bypass surgery or percutaneous coronary intervention unstable angina or stroke 11. Past medical history of clinically significant ECG abnormalities, presence of an abnormal ECG (which in the Investigator's opinion is clinically significant), QTcF&gt;450 msec, or has concomitant conditions that increase risk for QTc interval prolongation (e.g., heart failure, hypokalemia [defined as serum potassium &lt;3.0mEq/L that is persistent and refractory to correction], or family history of long QT interval syndrome) 12. History of significant hypersensitivity, intolerance, or allergy to any drug compound, food, or other substance, unless approved by the Investigator 13. Any medical or surgical conditions that might significantly interfere with the gastrointestinal absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of the investigational drug. This includes any history of a significant disease of the gastrointestinal tract, pancreas, liver, kidneys, and/or bloodforming organs. It does not include appendectomy, cholecystectomy, hernia repair, or underlying renal disease or abnormalities that occur as a direct result of renal disease in the renal impairment patients or abnormalities that occur as a direct result of renal disease 14. History of drug or alcohol abuse within the last 6 months, or evidence of recent drug or alcohol abuse as indicated by laboratory assays conducted during screening or baseline evaluations 15. Heavy use of tobacco or nicotinecontaining products within 6 months prior to Checkin (Day 1) and during the entire study, defined as urinary cotinine &gt; 150 ng/mL 16. Consumption of alcohol or caffeinecontaining foods and beverages for 72 hours prior to screening and during the entire study 17. Consumption of grapefruitcontaining foods and beverages or other potent cytochrome P450 (CYP)3A4 inhibitors or inducers for 7 days prior to Checkin (Day 1) and during the entire study 18. Participation in any other investigational study drug trial in which receipt of an investigational study drug occurred within 5 halflives or 30 days prior to Checkin (Day 1), whichever is longer, and during the entire study 19. Use of oral, implantable, injectable, or transdermal contraceptives within 10 days prior to Checkin (Day 1) or from the time of signing the informed consent (females only) until 14 days after the final dose administration 20. Use of any overthecounter, nonprescription medications, vitamins, or minerals (except as prescribed by a physician), within 14 days prior to Checkin (Day 1) and during the entire study 21. Use of phytotherapeutic/herbal/plantderived preparations within 14 days prior to Checkin (Day 1) of and during the entire study 22. Use of potent inducers of CYP3A4 within 30 days of Checkin (Day 1) 23. Use of potent inhibitors of CYP3A4 within 15 days of Checkin (Day 1) 24. Poor peripheral venous access 25. Donation or loss of 400 mL or more of blood or plasma within 8 weeks prior to Checkin (Day 1) and through entire study 26. Receipt of blood products within 2 months prior to Checkin (Day 1) 27. Any diarrhea or vomiting during the Screening period or at Checkin (Day 1) 28. Any acute or chronic condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would limit the subject's ability to complete and/or participate in this clinical study 29. Any of the following concomitant medications within 30 days of Checkin (Day 1) (unless cited otherwise below): potassiumsparing diuretics e.g. spironolactone, triamterene, amiloride (within 14 days of Checkin) class Ia, Ib and Ic or III antiarrhythmics probenecid any medication that is contraindicated in moderate or severe renally impaired population any drug with a known and frequent toxicity to a major organ system within 3 months of Screening (i.e., cytostatic drugs) 30. Any of the following (repeated and confirmed) laboratory abnormalities at Screening or Checkin: Clinically significant (as judged by the Investigator in consultation with the Sponsor) laboratory abnormalities except elevated blood urea nitrogen (BUN), elevated serum creatinine, hyperglycemia, and/or glycosuria Alanine aminotransferase (ALT)&gt;1.5xULN Aspartate aminotransferase (AST)&gt;1.5xULN Total bilirubin &gt;1.3x ULN (unless due to Gilbert's Syndrome) Hemoglobin &lt; 8 g/dL Laboratory testing may be repeated once prior to dosing (to rule out any possible laboratory error) 31. Planned surgery during the study period 32. Subjects who are deemed vulnerable by way of imprisonment, remand or detention Patients with Renal Impairment Only In addition to the exclusion criteria specified for "All Subjects" above, any patient with renal impairment who meets the following criteria will be excluded from entry into the study: 33. Any condition that would compromise patients' safety during study participation 34. Participants in Groups 13: Difficulty voiding or urinary tract obstruction at Checkin or undergoing any method of dialysis (hemodialysis, peritoneal dialysis) 35. Screening physical exam or ECG finding considered of clinical significance by the Investigator, or a laboratory evaluation outside of the normal reference range with the exception of values that are related to renal impairment 36. Any significant acute or chronic disease (except renal impairment) which is unstable or can interfere with the objectives of the study 37. Any change in stable dose regimens, either overthecounter or prescription, for chronic medical conditions (e.g. diabetes, dyslipidemia, renal impairment) within 4 weeks preceding dosing Healthy Subjects Only In addition to the exclusion criteria specified for "All Study Participants" above, any healthy subject who meets the following criteria will be excluded from entry into the study: 38. Any screening or baseline physical exam, EKG, or laboratories outside the normal range and deemed clinically significant by the Investigator. Results deemed not clinically significant by the Investigator in consultation with the Sponsor are allowable. 39. Use of any prescription medications and/or products within 14 days prior to Checkin (Day 1) and during the entire study 40. History of renal impairment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Healthy subjects</keyword>
</DOC>