<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02807181</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will evaluate the benefit of applying Selective Internal Radiation Therapy (SIRT) using SIR-Spheres Y-90 resin microspheres prior to receiving systemic chemotherapy treatment (cisplatin-gemcitabine, or CIS-GEM) in patients with unresectable intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma. Half of the patients will be randomized to CIS-GEM chemotherapy plus SIRT, and half of the patients will be randomized to CIS-GEM alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SIRT Followed by CIS-GEM Chemotherapy Versus CIS-GEM Chemotherapy Alone as 1st Line Treatment of Patients With Unresectable Intrahepatic Cholangiocarcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This clinical study is a prospective, multicenter, randomized, controlled study evaluating SIR-Spheres Y-90 resin microspheres followed by cisplatin-gemcitabine (CIS-GEM) chemotherapy vs. CIS-GEM chemotherapy alone as first-line treatment of patients with unresectable intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma. Randomized patients will be followed until death, withdrawal of consent, or until end of study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cholangiocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Willing, able and mentally competent to provide written informed consent. Aged 18 years or older. Histologically or cytologically confirmed unresectable and nonablatable intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma. Liveronly or liver predominant intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma. Patient are permitted to have locoregional lymph node involvement defined as: portal LN &lt;/= to 2 cm and/or para aortic LN &lt;/= to 1.5 cm in longest diameter, and/or up to 2 indeterminate lung lesions &lt; 1 cm if these lung lesions are positron emission tomography (PET) negative. Chemotherapy naïve. Adjuvant chemotherapy is not permitted. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 or 1. Adequate hematological function defined as: Hemoglobin &gt;/= 10g/dL White Blood Cell count (WBC) &gt;/= 3.0 x 10^9/L Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;/= 1.5 x 10^9/L Platelet count &gt;/= 100,000/mm^3 Adequate liver function defined as: Total bilirubin &lt;/= 30 umol/L (1.75 mg/dL) Albumin &gt;/= 30 g/L Adequate renal function defined as: Serum urea and serum creatinine &lt; 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) Creatinine clearance &gt;/= 45 ml/min (calculated with CockcroftGault Equation) Life expectancy of at least 3 months without any active treatment Female patients must either be postmenopausal, sterile (surgically or radiation or chemicallyinduced), or if sexually active use an acceptable method of contraception during the study. Male patients must be surgically sterile or if sexually active must use an acceptable method of contraception during the study. Considered suitable to receive either regimen in the clinical judgement of the treating investigator. Patients with only nonmeasurable lesions in the liver according to RECIST criteria Incomplete recovery from previous liver surgery, e.g. unresolved biliary tree obstruction or biliary sepsis or inadequate liver function Biliary stent in situ Main trunk Portal Vein Thrombosis (PVT) Ascites, even if controlled with diuretics. (A minor perihepatic rim of ascites detected at imaging is acceptable). Mixed hepatocellular carcinoma intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma (HCCICC) disease History of prior malignancy. Exceptions include insitu carcinoma of the cervix treated by conebiopsy/resection, nonmetastatic basal and/or squamous cell carcinomas of the skin, recurrent intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma post local treatment or any early stage (stage 1) malignancy adequately resected with curative intent at least 5 years prior to study entry Suspicion of any bone metastasis/metastases or central nervous system metastasis/metastases on clinical or imaging examination. Prior internal or external radiation delivered to the liver. Pregnancy; breast feeding. Participation within 28 days prior to randomization, in an active part of another clinical study that would compromise any of the endpoints of the study. Evidence of ongoing active infection that may affect treatment feasibility or outcome. Prior Whipple's procedure.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>