<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00171574</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Title: Antiproteinuric effect of valsartan, lisinopril and valsartan versus lisinopril in non-diabetic and diabetic renal disease: a randomized (3:3:1), double blind, parallel group, controlled trial, 5 months follow-up. Objective: To evaluate the antiproteinuric effect of high doses of valsartan vs combo treatment in no-diabetic and diabetic patients. Hypothesis: Combo treatment reduces microalbuminuria, proteinuria and the albumin/creatinin ratio more than monotherapies. Design: Multicentric, randomized, double blind, parallel group, active controlled. Dose / regimen Valsartan 320 vs Lisinopril 40 vs Valsartan/lisinopril 160/20</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Antiproteinuric Effect of Valsartan and Lisinopril</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Nephropathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lisinopril</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Valsartan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female outpatients aged 1870 years, 2. Chronic nephropathy, as defined by a serum creatinine concentration of &gt; 3 mg/dL or calculated glomerular filtration rate of &gt; 30 mL/min/1.73 m2. 3. Persistent proteinuria, as defined by urinary protein excretion exceeding 1g/24 h. (for a minimum of three months ). 4. Normotensive and hypertensive patients not adequately controlled with or without treatment (controlled: &lt;125/75 mmHg). 5. Written informed consent to participate in the study prior to any study procedures. Exclusion Criteria Immediate need for renal replacement therapy. Treatment resistant oedema. Need for treatment with corticosteroids, nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs, or immunosuppressive drugs. Proteinuria greater than 10g /24h and/or hypoalbuminaemia less than 28g/L. Renovascular hypertension Malignant hypertension MI, cerebrovascular accident within last year, severe peripheral vascular disease, CHF, chronic hepatic disease. Angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors and angiotensin II receptors blockers within one month prior to randomization. A serum creatinine concentration &gt;265 ümol/L Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>valsartan</keyword>
	<keyword>lisinopril</keyword>
	<keyword>antiproteinuric</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetic nephropathy</keyword>
</DOC>