<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00171925</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Multiple myeloma is a disease of B-lymphocytes producing malignant plasma cells. Malignant plasma cells induce osteolytic lesions, which is characteristic for progression of multiple myeloma. It is the aim of this study to investigate whether zoledronic acid has an influence on the progression of multiple myeloma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Therapy With Zoledronic Acid in Patients With Multiple Myeloma Stage I</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zoledronic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diphosphonates</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Evidence of myeloma according to the criteria of the British Columbia Cancer Agency (for the diagnosis, 2 of the 3 criteria must be met): Evidence of paraprotein in the serum or urine Bone marrow infiltration with plasma cells which represent more than 10% of the nucleated cells Radiologically, at least one osteolytic lesion Asymptomatic patients with Stage I (Durie and Salmon) multiple myeloma Exclusion criteria: Patients with more than one osteolytic lesion on conventional skeletal radiography Previous treatment with bisphosphonates bilirubin &gt; 2.5 mg/dl Abnormal renal function as evidenced by: A calculated creatinine clearance &lt; 30 ml/minute. Creatinine clearance (CrCl) is calculated using the CockcroftGault formula: CrCl= [140age(years)] x weight(kg)/[72xserumcreatinine(mg/dL)] X {0.85 for female patients} Patients with other malignant diseases or severe concomitant diseases Potentially fertile patients who are not using a reliable and appropriate method of contraception Pregnancy or breastfeeding Participation in another clinical study with an investigational drug within 12 weeks of study entry Current active dental problems including infection of the teeth or jawbone (maxilla or mandibular); dental or fixture trauma, or a current or prior diagnosis of osteonecrosis of the jaw (ONJ), of exposed bone in the mouth, or of slow healing after dental procedures. Recent (within 6 weeks) or planned dental or jaw surgery (e.g.. extraction, implants) Other protocoldefined inclusion and exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Stage I</keyword>
	<keyword>Zoledronic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>Progression</keyword>
</DOC>