<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00171340</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Post-menopausal breast cancer patients will receive letrozole 2.5 mg daily for the treatment of breast cancer and will be randomized to a treatment group to receive either upfront zoledronic acid 4 mg IV 15-minute infusion every 6 months or delayed start zoledronic acid 4 mg IV 15-minute infusion every 6 months. Delayed start zoledronic acid will be initiated when either the Bone Mineral Density T-score is below -2 Standard Deviations at either the lumbar spine or hip or any clinical fracture unrelated to trauma or an asymptomatic fracture discovered at the month 36 scheduled visit. Letrozole 2.5 mg will be given daily for 5 years.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Zoledronic Acid in the Prevention of Cancer Treatment Related Bone Loss in Postmenopausal Women Receiving Letrozole for Breast Cancer.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bone Diseases, Metabolic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zoledronic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diphosphonates</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Letrozole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Stage IIIIa breast cancer Postmenopausal or recently postmenopausal Recent surgery for breast cancer Estrogen Receptor positive and/or progesterone receptor positive hormone receptor status No prior treatment with letrozole Other protocoldefined inclusion criteria may apply. Metastatic disease Invasive bilateral disease Clinical or radiological evidence of existing fracture in spine or hip Prior treatment with IV bisphosphonates in the past 12 months Current treatment with oral bisphosphonates ( must be discontinued within 3 weeks of baseline evaluation) Use of Tibolone within 6 months Prior use of parathyroid hormone for more than 1 week Previous or concomitant malignancy Abnormal renal function History of disease effecting bone metabolism Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bone Loss</keyword>
	<keyword>Osteopenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>letrozole</keyword>
	<keyword>zoledronic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>postmenopausal</keyword>
</DOC>