<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00584987</DOC>
	<brief_summary>We hypothesize that once daily use of oxymetazoline will not cause significant rhinitis medicamentosa and that the combination of fluticasone furoate plus oxymetazoline leads to faster relief of nasal congestion secondary to perennial allergic rhinitis than the use of fluticasone furoate alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intranasal Steroids and Oxymetazoline in Allergic Rhinitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We performed a 6-week, 4-group, parallel, randomized, double-blind, double-dummy, clinical trial in 60 patients with perennial allergic rhinitis. After an initial screening with an allergy questionnaire and skin puncture testing to confirm an allergic response to a perennial allergen (cat, dog, dust mite, indoor mold), qualified individuals were randomized into 1 of 4 treatment groups. The 4 groups received the following treatments: placebo, OXY (0.05%, 2 puffs in each nostril every evening), FF nasal spray (110 mg per day), and FF nasal spray plus OXY (FF/OXY). All participants received 2 nasal sprays at night, with 1 spray containing FF or its placebo, the other oxymetazoline or its placebo. The nasal sprays were labeled with participant code numbers, and the investigator assigned participants in a sequential randomized fashion to a study code number in blocks of 4. Dropouts were replaced until 60 subjects were randomized. Replacement subjects were assigned the next sequential treatment. Thus, the number of subjects in each group was not exactly 15. Eligible participants completed the Rhinitis Quality of Life Questionnaire (RQLQ) and underwent measurement of nasal volume by acoustic rhinometry before starting the study. Participants were instructed to keep a diary of daily symptoms, nasal peak inspiratory flow (NPIF) meter readings, and medication use during the study; no rescue medications were allowed. The severity of sneezing, rhinorrhea, nasal congestion, and other symptoms was recorded in the morning (reflective of symptoms overnight) and evening (reflective of daytime symptoms) on a 0 to 3 scale. Intake of the study medication was performed once daily, at night, after recording of symptoms and NPIF values. Subjects returned to the nasal laboratory every 2 weeks for a total of 4 weeks for review of the symptom diaries, replacement of medications, performance of acoustic rhinometry, and completion of the RQLQ. After the fourth week, participants stopped treatment, returned medication, and continued with the clinical trial for 2 additional weeks. During this time, they maintained symptom diaries and NPIF measurements twice daily. At the end of the 2-week period, participants returned to the nasal laboratory to perform a final acoustic rhinometry, complete an RQLQ survey, and return the diaries.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxymetazoline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phenylephrine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Males and females between 18 and 55 years of age. 2. History of perennial allergic rhinitis. 3. Positive skin test to dust mite, dog, cat or indoor mold antigen. 4. And a combined nasal morning and evening score of ≥4 for nasal congestion in the day preceding entry 1. Physical signs or symptoms suggestive of renal, hepatic or cardiovascular disease. 2. Pregnant or lactating women. 3. Subjects treated with systemic steroids during the previous 30 days. 4. Subjects treated with topical (inhaled, intranasal or intraocular) steroids, Nasalcrom or Opticrom during the previous 30 days. 5. Subjects treated with oral antihistamine/decongestants during the previous seven days. 6. Subjects treated with topical (intranasal or intraocular) antihistamine/decongestants during the previous 3 days. 7. Subjects treated with immunotherapy and are escalating their dose. 8. Subjects on chronic antiasthma medications. 9. Subjects with polyps in the nose or a significantly displaced septum. 10. Upper respiratory infection within 14 days of study start.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>