<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00187278</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of the study is to evaluate if patients with a standard indication for permanent ventricular pacing, left ventricular ejection fraction without limit, or any QRS duration will profit from the prevention of ventricular desynchronisation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Biopace Study: Biventricular Pacing for Atrioventricular Block to Prevent Cardiac Desynchronization</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will be performed as a controlled, single-blind, international, multicenter, prospective, randomized, parallel group design. In order to pragmatically examine the effectiveness of biventricular pacing in patients with an indication for ventricular pacing, the study group with biventricular pacing is compared to a control group with standard pacemakers which only allow univentricular (right ventricular) stimulation, as it has been the standard outside of clinical studies until so far.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ventricular Dysfunction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrioventricular Block</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Presence of an indication for ventricular pacing according to the actual guidelines for the implantation of cardiac pacemakers and a need for frequent (or even permanent) ventricular pacing for: Permanent 3rd degree atrioventricular (AV)block or Intermittent 3rd degree AVblock in combination with 1st degree AVblock with a pQinterval ≥ 220 ms or 2nd degree AVblock type Mobitz II in combination with 1st degree AVblock with a pQinterval ≥ 220 ms or 2nd degree AVblock type Mobitz I (if indicated) in combination with 1st degree AVblock with a pQinterval ≥ 220 ms or 1st degree AVblock with a pQinterval ≥ 220 ms and indication for ventricular pacing (includes indication for ventricular pacing based on long HV interval measured during invasive electrophysiological testing) or Sicksinussyndrome with symptomatic sinus bradycardia or sinus arrest as primary indication for device implantation in combination with long 1st degree AVblock with a pQinterval ≥ 220 ms or Chronic (permanent) atrial fibrillation (flutter or tachycardia) with a spontaneous heart (ventricular) rate at rest ≤ 60/min or Chronic (permanent) atrial fibrillation (flutter or tachycardia) with a spontaneous heart (ventricular) rate at rest ≤ 75/min, if initiation or increase of pharmacological treatment with a relevant heart rate lowering effect (negative chronotropic effect) is planned for the time after pacemaker implantation (i.e. ßblockers for heart failure and rate control) Patients scheduled for AV node ablation Any QRS duration and morphology Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) without limit as measured by echocardiography (in at least one plane, either 4 or 2chamber or apical long axis view) Signed written informed consent of the patient or a firstdegree relative for study participation after informing the patient/relative about the risks and the aim of the study Willingness and ability to comply with the prescribed followup tests and schedule of evaluations. Absence of an implanted ventricular pacing device (patients with atrial pacemakers and new need for ventricular pacing may be included) Implanted Cardioverter Defibrillator or consideration for implantation of an ICD due to arrhythmia indication. However, ICD implant for primary prevention of sudden cardiac death in patients with LVEF ≤ 35 % (in accordance with the actual guidelines for the implantation of arrhythmia devices[LVEF &lt; 30%] and in accordance with the results of the SCDHeft study [LVEF &lt; 35%) will be allowed. Implanted ventricular pacing device Status 1 for cardiac transplantation and likelihood to receive transplantation within 2 years (these patients would not be expected to fulfill the followup requirements as outlined in this protocol) Evidence of acute left ventricular dysfunction and high probability for its reversibility (e.g. acute myocarditis, tachycardiomyopathy) Implanted prosthetic tricuspid valve Severe musculoskeletal disorder(s) Age below 18 years Current or planned pregnancy in the next 6 months Current or recent (within the past 30 days) participation in any other clinical investigation Life expectancy of less than 6 months Patient's inability to independently comprehend and complete the Quality of Life (QoL) questionnaire</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Standard pacing indication</keyword>
</DOC>