<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00187200</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate the benefit of interventricular (V-V) delay optimization in reducing the non-responder rate in patients with cardiac resynchronization defibrillator (CRT-D) devices. The primary endpoint of this study is CRT responder rate. For patients enrolled with new CRT-D systems, patients are considered non-responders if BOTH of the following requirements are fulfilled: - &lt; 10% improvement in 6-minute hall walk, and - no class improvement or worsening in New York Heart Association (NYHA) scale. For those receiving CRT-D devices as replacements of older CRT-D systems, patients are considered non-responders if BOTH of the following requirements are fulfilled: - &gt; 1 heart failure (HF) related hospitalization, and - no class improvement or worsening in NYHA scale.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Response of Cardiac Resynchronization Therapy Optimization With Ventricle to Ventricle Timing in Heart Failure Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Methods - This is a prospective, randomized (simultaneous biventricular (BiV) pacing vs. sequential BiV pacing) study. - Any patient that receives an FDA approved St. Jude Medical (SJM) CRT-D with V-V timing is eligible for enrollment. - At 3 months post enrollment (or at implant for CRT-D replacements), patients screened as non-responders are randomized to either simultaneous or sequential BiV pacing. Patients requiring a replacement CRT-D device that are identified as non-responders to CRT are enrolled at the screening/randomization visit. - Patients are followed for a period of 6 months post randomization: - Enrollment (1 week pre CRT-D implant to &lt; 2 weeks post CRT-D implant) - Screening/Randomization Visit (3 months post enrollment) - Follow-up Visit (6 months post randomization) - Total # of centers - 80 centers - Sample size - 800 patients screened for CRT non-responders</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient has a standard indication for a CRTD. Patient has the ability to complete a 6minute hall walk with the only limiting factor to be fatigue or shortness of breath. Patient is geographically stable and willing to comply with the required followup schedule. Prior to 1 month of randomization, patient's HF medications are maintained stable and remain stable throughout the study. Patients requiring a CRTD replacement must comply with BOTH of the following: &gt; 1 HF related hospitalization No class improvement or worsening in NYHA scale Patient's life expectancy is less than 12 months. Patient has had cardiac surgery within 6 months of enrollment. Patient has an epicardial ventricular lead system. Patient is less than 18 years old. Patient is pregnant.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>