<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01712724</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Both aerobic training (AT) and resistance/strength training (RT) have the potential to improve recovery after stroke. Research conducted in chronic disease and healthy populations suggest that AT and RT "combination therapy" may produce synergistic and superior effects along cognition and mobility domains, when compared to AT alone. However, the effects of a combined training approach (AT+RT) compared to AT alone has not been investigated in people post-stroke.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Combined Resistance and Aerobic Training vs Aerobic Training on Cognition and Mobility Following Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients referred to Toronto Rehabilitation Institute's Risk Factor Modification and Exercise Program following Stroke (TRI-REPS) will be randomized to either AT+RT or AT alone. Mobility (6 minute walk test), and cognition (Vascular Cognitive Impairment Harmonization Standards) will be measured pre- post 6 months of exercise. Secondary measures will include body composition, and biochemical changes. This project will help to determine an exercise treatment strategy that will guide best practice guidelines aimed at promoting mobility and brain health in people post-stroke.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of stroke (ischemic or hemorrhagic) Ability to walk at least 100 m independently with or without an assistive device with no severe limitations due to pain Living in the community at least 3 months post stroke (no upper limit) Strokerelated motor impairment score of 36 on the ChedokeMcMaster Stroke Assessment scale of the leg and/or foot Ability to provide informed consent Unstable angina or orthostatic blood pressure decrease of &gt; 20 mmHg Resting hypertension (SBP &gt; 160 mm Hg or DBP &gt; 100 mm Hg) Diabetes related or other eye/vision complications (severe proliferative retinopathy) Cardiovascular morbidities which would limit exercise tolerance (e.g. heart failure, hypertrophic cardiomyopathy, horizontal or downsloping STsegment depression &gt; 2 mm, symptomatic aortic stenosis, complex arrhythmias) Musculoskeletal impairments which would preclude safe participation in exercise Cognitive and/or behavioral issues that would significantly limit participation in exercise testing and training, prior unrelated neurological disorders or psychiatric illness Severe communicative aphasia or comprehensive aphasia (as noted in clinical reports) Patients with anxiety disorder, claustrophobia, or pacemaker implantation will be excluded from brain imaging and perfusion measures Exposure to a similar or identical neuropsychological battery within &lt;6 months Currently smoking</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>exercise therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
</DOC>