<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01712425</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The HIVconsv gene was constructed by assembling the 14 most conserved regions of the HIV-1 proteome into one chimaeric protein. This gene has been inserted into 2 leading non-replicating vaccine vectors: an attenuated chimpanzee adenovirus serotype 63 (ChAdV63) and a modified vaccinia virus Ankara (MVA) to construct the ChAdV63.HIVconsv and MVA.HIVconsv HIV-1 candidate vaccines. The present study is named ChAd-MVA.HIVconsv-BCN01 and it is a phase I, multicenter primary/booster therapeutic vaccination study to evaluate the safety and immunogenicity of ChAdV63.HIVcons and MVA.HIVconsv HIV-1 vaccines, delivered intramuscularly according to a 0-8 weeks or a 0-24 weeks schedule to recently HIV-1 infected individuals with early viral suppression 6 months after initiation of Tenofovir/Emtricitabine plus Raltegravir.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Immunogenicity of ChAdV63.HIVconsv and MVA.HIVconsv Candidate HIV-1 Vaccines in Recently HIV-1 Infected Individuals</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>It is a Phase I, multicenter primary/booster therapeutic vaccination study to evaluate the safety and immunogenicity of ChAdV63.HIVcons and MVA.HIVconsv HIV-1 vaccines, delivered intramuscularly according to a 0-8 weeks or a 0-24 weeks schedule to recently HIV-1 infected individuals with early viral suppression 6 months after initiation of Tenofovir/Emtricitabine plus Raltegravir. 24 patients who meet all eligibility criteria will be enrolled, first 10 individuals will be assigned in the 0-24 week prime/boost regimen (ARM A). The next 10 volunteers will be assigned in the 0-8 week prime/boost regimen (ARM B).Four additional volunteers will be included as 'back-up' and assigned 2 in ARM A and 2 in ARM B to cover a possible 10% of patients who drop-off during the follow-up. Purpose of staging of 2 study arms is just to shorten overall study duration (from screening of first volunteer to 6 months after last immunisation of last volunteer). Lastly, 24 patients who also meet all eligibility criteria will be enrolled as controls, will also initiate promptly antiretroviral treatment with Tenofovir/Emtricitabine plus Raltegravir but will not receive the investigational vaccines. Control patients will consecutively be assigned to the 0-24w control arm (ARM C 'long control') or 0-8w control arm (ARM D 'short control') until 12 patients per arm are reached. The purpose of the control arms is to have a study population to compare the viral reservoir decay kinetics in the absence of vaccination.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female, aged 1860 years 2. Confirmed HIV1 seropositive documented in the past 6 months (by acute antiretroviral syndrome, p24 antigenemia and/or ELISA seroconversion) 3. Willing and able to give written informed consent for participation in the study 4. Willing and able to adhere to an effective HAART regimen for the duration of the study 5. Cluster of differentiation 4 (CD4)+ T cell count &gt; 350 cells/ml at screening and at the preceding clinic visit 6. No new AIDSdefining diagnosis or progression of HIVrelated disease. 7. Haematological and biochemical laboratory parameters as follows: Haemoglobin &gt; 10g/dl, Platelets &gt; 100.000/dl, alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤ 2.5 x ULN, Creatinine ≤ 1.3 x upper limit of normal (ULN) 8. Serology: negative for hepatitis B surface antigen OR HbsAg positive with Hepatitis B Virus (HBV)DNA &lt; 1000 copies/ml; negative for hepatitis C antibodies OR confirmed clearance of Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) infection (spontaneous or following treatment); negative syphilis serology or documented adequate treatment of syphilis if positive enzimeimmunoassay (EIA) Immonoglobulin G (IgG) or Treponema pallidum hemagglutination assay (TPHA) 9. Available for follow up for duration of study (screening + 72 weeks) and willing to comply with the protocol requirements 10. Women of childbearing age must not be pregnant, not be planning a pregnancy or breastfeeding. Sexually active women must be willing to use an approved method of contraception from screening until 4 months after the second immunisation. Sexually active men in heterosexual relationships must be willing to use an approved method of contraception with their partners from screening until 4 months after the second immunisation. 1. Confirmed HIV2 seropositive 2. Positive pregnancy test 3. Presence of Nucleos(t)ide Reverse Transcriptase Inhibitors (NRTI) mutation in the screening genotype 4. Participation in another clinical trial within 12 weeks of study entry 5. History of autoimmune disease other than HIVrelated autoimmune disease. 6. History or clinical manifestations of any physical or psychiatric disorder which could impair the subject's ability to complete the study 7. History of anaphylaxis or severe adverse reaction to vaccines 8. Previous immunisation with any experimental immunogens 9. Receipt of blood products within 6 months of study entry 10. Treatment for cancer or lymphoproliferative disease within 1 year of study entry 11. Receipt of vaccines other than Hepatitis B vaccine within 2 weeks of study entry or planned receipt within 2 weeks of vaccination 12. Any other prior therapy which, in the opinion of the investigators, would make the individual unsuitable for the study or influence the results of the study 13. Current or recent use (within last 3 months) of interferon or systemic corticosteroids or other immunosuppressive agents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>recently HIV-1 infected individuals</keyword>
</DOC>