<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02069184</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Post-operative pain management after C-section is an important topic as the number of elective c-sections increases each year. Pain is managed either by giving opioids or by using non-opioids. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of IV Acetaminophen in pain relief and its impact in the usage of post-operative opioid requirements and opioid associated complications. The hypothesis is that four doses of IV Acetaminophen in conjunction with intrathecal or epidural morphine given to the patients after c-section will reduce post-operative opioid requirements and opioid associated complications.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>IV Acetaminophen for Acute Post Operative Pain in C-Section Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Most of the opioids used are centrally acting drugs like morphine or its derivatives. The most common adverse reactions related to systemic administration of opioids are sedation, itching, constipation and less commonly, respiratory depression. One of the other management strategies for the pain control is the use of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDS). Frequent use of NSAIDS is also associated with complications, such as gastric ulcer and platelet dysfunction. When compared to other non-NSAIDS, IV acetaminophen is a relatively safer drug with quicker onset of action. In an earlier conducted study, the onset of action of analgesia for a bolus dose of IV acetaminophen is 3 minutes. IV acetaminophen is FDA approved for management of mild to moderate pain. An adverse reaction associated with the prolonged usage of IV acetaminophen is hepatic injury. The most common adverse events encountered during previous clinical trials were nausea, vomiting, headache and insomnia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acetaminophen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Elective full term CS patients Age 18 and above ASA IIII Allergic reaction to IV acetaminophen Not able to understand and sign the research consent Pregnancy induced hypertension or preeclampsia patients Planned intensive care admission patients Patients with severe hepatic impairment or active liver diseases (Two fold increase in any of the liver enzymes) Patients with serum creatinine&gt;2mg/dl For nursing mothers, any evidence of hepatic dysfunction of the new born</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>opioid usage requirements</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>IV acetaminophen</keyword>
	<keyword>opioid usage</keyword>
	<keyword>c-section</keyword>
</DOC>