<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02069535</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is an open, national, multi-centre trial. The main objective of this trial is to assess the tolerability of the up-dosing phase of AVANZ® Cupressus arizonica by measurement of related Adverse Events.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Open Trial to Assess the Tolerability of AVANZ® Cupressus Immunotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The main objective of this trial is to assess the tolerability of the up-dosing phase of AVANZ® Cupressus arizonica, the measurement rate is the frequency of patients with investigational medicinal product (IMP)-related adverse events (AEs) will be the primary endpoint.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Conjunctivitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A documented clinically relevant history of Cupressus arizonica pollen induced allergic rhinoconjunctivitis with or without asthma for at least one year prior to trial entry. Positive Skin Prick Test (SPT) response to Cupressus arizonica pollen (wheal diameter ≥ 3 mm) History of severe asthma exacerbation or emergency room visit or admission for asthma in the previous 12 months. Previous treatment with immunotherapy with Cupressus arizonica pollen extract within the last 5 years (initiation of subcutaneous immunotherapy is acceptable if treatment has been discontinued before reaching maintenance dose; for SLIT 3 months in the last 5 years is accepted). Ongoing treatment with any allergenspecific immunotherapy product. A history of anaphylaxis with cardiorespiratory symptoms (immunotherapy, exerciseinduced, food allergy, drugs or an idiopathic reaction). A systemic disease affecting the immune system (e.g. insulindependent diabetes, autoimmune disease, immune complex disease, or immune deficiency disease whether acquired or not).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cupressus arizonica</keyword>
</DOC>