<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02069600</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Rationale: Almost all the information the investigators have about the effect of continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP) in patients with obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) comes from randomized clinical trials including only middle-aged patients. Little is know, however, about the effect of CPAP in elderly people with OSA. Objective: To assess the effect of CPAP treatment in elderly patients with severe OSA on clinical, quality-of-life and neurocognitive spheres. Methods and Measurements: Open-label, randomized, multicenter clinical trial of parallel groups with blinded end-point design conducted in 12 Spanish teaching hospitals on a consecutive clinical cohort of elderly (≥ 70 years) patients with confirmed severe OSA (IAH≥ 30) receiving CPAP or no therapy while maintaining their usual control for three months. CPAP titration was performed by an auto CPAP device. A good adherence was set as at least 4 hours/day of CPAP use. Primary endpoint was the measurement of quality of life by the Quebec Sleep questionnaire, which includes diurnal and nocturnal symptoms, hypersomnolence, and social and emotional dimensions. Secondary endpoints include different sleep-related symptoms, presence of anxiety or depression, office blood pressure figures and some neurocognitive tests. Patients were invited to a clinical visit on three occasions to quantify the adherence to CPAP. Intention-to-treat analysis was performed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of CPAP Treatment in Elderly: Randomized Clinical Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Not needed</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients were initially eligible for participation in the study if they were aged at least 70 years, had an apneahypopnea index (AHI) ≥30 and had signed the informed consent to participate Current use of CPAP treatment, central sleep apnea (defined as at least 50% of respiratory events having a pattern of apnea or hypopnea without respiratory effort), respiratory failure (defined as diurnal oxygen saturation below 90%), severe heart failure (NYHA IIIIV), a cardiovascular event in the month prior to the inclusion in the study or disabling hypersomnia requiring urgent treatment (defined as an Epworth Sleepiness Scale ≥ 18).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>70 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>CPAP</keyword>
	<keyword>clinical trial</keyword>
	<keyword>obstructive sleep apnea</keyword>
</DOC>