<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02195895</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if a year of alendronate treatment will maintain or increase bone mass density (BMD) compared to baseline BMD values in people with chronic SCI. This study will also investigate 1) if alendronate therapy will increase bone strength in people with chronic SCI, 2) the safety of alendronate, and 3) the effects of alendronate on serum markers of bone metabolism.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Alendronate on Bone in People With Chronic Spinal Cord Injury Previously Treated With Teriparatide</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This extension study will enroll individuals who have completed treatment in the parent protocol "Effect of Teriparatide, Vibration and the Combination on Bone Mass and Bone Architecture in Chronic Spinal Cord Injury" or in the teriparatide extension protocol. This study will allow those individuals who previously received teriparatide to be treated for a year with alendronate to maintain any bone they may have gained and to possibly increase bone mass further. Termination of teriparatide is followed by bone loss if anti-resorptive therapy is not initiated, so this approach is optimal for continued treatment of the current group of participants.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alendronate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Teriparatide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bone Density Conservation Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium Carbonate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Prior enrollment in protocol "Effect of Teriparatide, Vibration and the Combination on Bone Mass and Bone Architecture in Chronic Spinal Cord Injury", (NCT ID # NCT01225055). Women of childbearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry, for the duration of study participation, and for 90 days following completion of therapy. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent. Individual with renal insufficiency (calculated creatinine clearance &lt; 30 ml/min). Individuals who are not able to sit or stand upright for at least 30 minutes after taking their medication. Individuals with poor dental hygiene. Individuals with esophageal abnormalities. Individuals who are not able to tolerate alendronate treatment. Individuals who will not be able to return for all study visits. Patients may not be receiving any other investigational agents. Other medical conditions that in the opinion of the investigator would preclude the subject from completing the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Teriparatide</keyword>
	<keyword>Alendronate</keyword>
	<keyword>Alendronic Acid</keyword>
	<keyword>Osteoporosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Loss</keyword>
	<keyword>Spinal Cord Injury</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic Bone Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Musculoskeletal Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Spinal Cord Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Central Nervous System Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Nervous System Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Nervous System</keyword>
	<keyword>Wounds and Injuries</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Density Conservation Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Physiological Effects of Drugs</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacologic Actions</keyword>
</DOC>