<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00335907</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research is being done to see if a protocol (a set of orders that determine how much and how quickly a drug/fluid is given) for fluid and drugs used to increase blood pressure (vasopressors) will work better then general clinical practices to improve outcomes in patients with septic shock.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Protocol-driven Hemodynamic Support for Patients With Septic Shock</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Septic shock is low blood pressure caused by an infection. Sepsis is the most common cause of death in non-cardiac intensive care units, and septic shock is the most severe form of sepsis. Treatment for septic shock includes giving antibiotics, intravenous fluids, and medications to raise the blood pressure (vasopressors). We would like to see if a protocol-driven management strategy for septic shock can shorten time on vasopressors and limit the number of side effects. We have constructed a protocol that will allow the nurse at the bedside, in conjunction with the physician's orders, to adjust the amount of fluids and medications that raise the blood pressure (vasopressors).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Shock</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sepsis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Toxemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Shock, Septic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vasoconstrictor Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ACCP/SCCM sepsis criteria Need for institution of vasopressors after adequate volume resuscitation Age&lt; 18 On vasopressors for &gt; 24 hours prior to ICU admission Other cause for shock ( cardiac tamponade, massive pulmonary embolus, cardiogenic shock) Physicians and family not committed to aggressive medical therapy ( a patient will not be excluded if he/she would receive all care except for attempts at resuscitation from cardiac arrest)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Clinical trial</keyword>
	<keyword>Controlled clinical trial</keyword>
	<keyword>Shock, Septic</keyword>
</DOC>