<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00335153</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study will be to provide further evidence of the long-term safety and tolerability of levodopa-carbidopa intestinal gel (Duodopa®) over 12-months in participants with advanced Parkinson's disease (PD) and severe motor fluctuations.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Levodopa-Carbidopa Intestinal Gel Open-Label Study in Advanced Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study was composed of a screening period followed by 3 sequential on-treatment periods, as follows: - Screening Period (up to 28 days): determination of eligibility and discontinuation of antiparkinsonian disease medications other than levodopa-carbidopa immediate release (LC-oral) prior to nasojejunal (NJ) tube placement. - NJ Test Period (2 to 14 days): first hospitalization period, Baseline assessments, placement of NJ tube, and optimization of levodopa-carbidopa intestinal gel (LCIG) treatment via NJ tube and infusion pump (participant was hospitalized for NJ tube placement but hospitalization was not required for entire duration of LCIG treatment optimization). - PEG-J Period (2 to 14 days): second hospitalization period; placement of PEG-J tube; further optimization of LCIG treatment. - Post PEG-J Long-Term Treatment Period (Day 28 to Day 378): LCIG administration via a permanent PEG-J tube and infusion pump, with dosage adjusted according to clinical condition.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carbidopa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carbidopa, levodopa drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levodopa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Idiopathic Parkinson's disease (PD) according to United Kingdom Parkinson's Disease Society (UKPDS) Brain Bank Criteria Levodoparesponsive with severe motor fluctuations Recognizable off and on state (motor fluctuations) confirmed by diary Diagnosis is unclear or a suspicion of other parkinsonian syndromes exists such as secondary parkinsonism Undergone surgery for the treatment of PD Contraindications to levodopa (such as narrow angle glaucoma)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>severe motor fluctuations</keyword>
	<keyword>levodopa</keyword>
	<keyword>levodopa/carbidopa intestinal gel</keyword>
	<keyword>efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>dyskinesia</keyword>
	<keyword>Parkinson's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>carbidopa</keyword>
	<keyword>DUOPA</keyword>
</DOC>