<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00713401</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Assess the tolerability and safety of a rapid bolus of tecadenoson at different dose levels when given alone and in combination with a beta-blocker (esmolol) in patients with atrial fibrillation to control rapid heart rate. Explore the pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic effects when given alone and in combination with beta-blocker (esmolol).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of Tecadenoson to Treat Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esmolol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tecadenoson</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenosine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have a diagnosis of atrial fibrillation in need of treatment for rate control Be able and willing to abstain from any antiarrhythmics, including atrioventricular (AV) nodal blocking agents (except for esmolol per protocol), from no later than 8:00 p.m. on the day prior to dosing until completion of the last dose period assessment Be able and willing to abstain from xanthine or chocolatecontaining foods, beverages, and medications Females must be postmenopausal or sterilized; or if of childbearing potential, must not be breastfeeding and must have a negative pregnancy test at screening and no intention of becoming pregnant during the course of the study. Males and females must be using adequate contraception during the study. Have a known accessory pathway Have active myocardial ischemia or recent acute coronary syndrome Have acute or overt heart failure, bradycardia, heart block greater than first degree, or cardiogenic shock Have allergies or contraindications to treatment with esmolol or aminophylline, or any of their constituents Have a supine cuff systolic blood pressure &lt; 90 mm Hg Be undergoing treatment with theophylline/aminophylline preparations, Trental® (pentoxifylline), or carbamazepine Have asthma or other reactive airways disease currently ontreatment Have a history of an active or chronic pancreatic disease or clinically significant increased levels of serum amylase or lipase</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>