<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00612742</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, adaptive design, multi-center study of the long-term cardiovascular and breast safety of LibiGel in the treatment of HSDD in postmenopausal women with at least two points of cardiovascular risk and clinical diagnosis of Hypoactive Sexual Desire Disorder (HSDD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of LibiGel® for Treatment of Hypoactive Sexual Desire Disorder in Postmenopausal Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypokinesia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sexual Dysfunctions, Psychological</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone enanthate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone undecanoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone 17 beta-cypionate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methyltestosterone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Postmenopausal female subjects at least 50 years of age with at least two points of cardiovascular risk with a clinical diagnosis of HSDD. Subjects must not require treatment with antiandrogens, highdose oral or injectable corticosteroids, tamoxifen or other selective estrogen receptor modulators, have used androgen therapy within 2 months of randomization, have a history of estrogendependent neoplasia or any gynecologic cancer, have a history of cancer of any kind in the past 10 years prior to randomization, have a history of malignant melanoma or a history of invasive cancer at any time, have a screening mammogram with any finding that requires follow up within 6 months of randomization, have a history of myocardial infarction, coronary revascularization or stroke within 12 months of randomization, have any medical condition associated with predicted survival of less than 3 years in the judgment of the Investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular event</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Testosterone</keyword>
	<keyword>Menopause</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypoactive Sexual Desire Disorder</keyword>
</DOC>