<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01535781</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The effect of Tranexamic acid on blood loss, hemoglobin and transfusions in patients with pertrochanteric hip fractures. Tranexamic acid is a well known drug used in many types of surgery. The investigators wish to investigate if the use of tranexamic acid can reduce the peri- and post-operative blood loss in patients who undergo surgery with a short intramedullary nail, for a pertrochanteric hip fracture. An interim analysis was planned when reaching 60 inclusions. The interim analysis was conducted only on the primary outcome (TBL). A difference in TBL of no less than 500 ml was considered a reason to halt the study. The 0.001 level was chosen as a simple approach to this interim analysis from the Haybittle-Peto boundary</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Effect of Tranexamic Acid Administered to Patients With Hip Fractures. Can Blood Loss be Reduced?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Studies have shown that hip fractures have a hidden blood loss besides the recorded perioperative blood loss. Patients who are osteosynthesised with an intramedullary nail have been shown to have the largest hidden blood loss. Postoperative anaemia is associated with a higher morbidity and mortality. We wish to investigate the possibility of reducing this hidden blood loss, with the use of a well known drug (tranexamic acid) that is widely used to reduce blood loss in other forms of surgery and in multitraumatized patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tranexamic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients planned to undergo osteosynthesis with short intramedullary nail for a pertrochanteric hip fracture. ASA score 3, 2 or 1 Allergy for tranexamic acid Clinical signs of acute thromboembolic event Renal function impairment (Screatinin&gt;120micromol/l) Active thrombotic disease or DIC Kvitamin antagonist treatment Malignancy Pathological fracture Previously operated in same hip BW &gt; 100kg</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>pertrochanteric fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>tranexamic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>postoperative blood loss</keyword>
	<keyword>blood loss</keyword>
	<keyword>hidden blood loss</keyword>
	<keyword>blood transfusions</keyword>
</DOC>