<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02685098</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients undergoing semi-elective below knee amputation from complications associated with atherosclerotic limb ischemia will received intra-muscular injections of allogeneic Mesenchymal Stromal Cells in the leg above and below the point of amputation to prevent ischemic wound complications after surgery and decrease the incidence of conversion from below knee to above knee amputation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical and Histological Analysis of Mesenchymal Stem Cells in Amputation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase I single center open label trial study that will enroll sixteen patients requiring semi-elective below knee amputation (BKA) within a 30 day period for non-infectious complications related to critical limb ischemia (CLI). After enrollment patients will be randomized to BKA at 3,7,14, or 21 days after MSC administration. The investigational treatment uses allogeneic bone marrow derived mesenchymal stem cells at the point of care. Allogeneic MSCs will be injected in the thigh muscles and the gastrocnemius muscle of sixteen patients undergoing BKA. Through a review of treatment related adverse events over 6 months we will test the hypothesis that allogeneic MSCs do not result in significant cardiovascular, respiratory, or infectious treatment related adverse events. Through an exploratory investigation we will assess the efficacy of MSCs in promoting freedom from gangrene, conversion to AKA, and death after BKA.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arteriosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arterial Occlusive Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pathologic Processes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Be ≥ 40 and ≤80 years of age. 2. Patients requiring below knee amputation, as determined by an independent vascular specialist, for rest pain, nonsuppurative gangrene, or ulceration due to limb ischemia. 3. Resting Ankle Brachial Index &lt; 0.55 or TBI &lt; 0.40. 4. Ulceration or gangrene distal to malleoli (to allow adequate length of ATM for 4 injections 4 cm. apart ) 5. BKA can safely be performed up to 30 days after screening, as determined by an independent vascular or orthopedic surgeon. 6. Females of childbearing potential must be willing to use one form of birth control for the duration of the study. Female participants must undergo a blood or urine pregnancy test at screening. 1. Evidence of infection. Suppurative gangrene: purulence emanating from gangrenous areas, with or without compression. Spreading cellulitis: proximal progression of erythema from wound within 24 hours. Systemic manifestations of infection: WBC &gt; 11.5k (with antibiotic therapy &gt; 24 hours), increasing oxygen requirements or pulmonary failure, pressor support , change in creatinine &gt; 50% from baseline 2. Patients who are pregnant, planning to become pregnant in the next 12 months, or lactating. 3. Venous stasis disease or lymphedema. 4. An HbA1C level &gt;10% 5. Significant hepatic dysfunction (ALT or AST greater than 2 times normal). 6. eGFR &lt;30mL/min 7. CHF hospitalization within the last 1 month prior to enrollment.* 8. Acute coronary syndrome in the last 1 month prior to enrollment.* 9. HIV positive, active HBV or HCV. 10. History of cancer within the last 5 years, except basal cell skin carcinoma 11. Any bleeding diathesis defined as an INR ≥ 2.0 (off anticoagulation therapy) or history of platelet count less than 70,000 or hemophilia. 12. Inability to provide written informed consent due to cognitive or language barriers (interpreter permitted). 13. Concurrent enrollment in another clinical investigative trial. 14. Any condition requiring immunosuppressant medications (e.g., for treatment of organ transplants, psoriasis, Crohn's disease, alopecia areata).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Stem cells</keyword>
	<keyword>MSCs</keyword>
	<keyword>Mesenchymal</keyword>
	<keyword>Amputation</keyword>
	<keyword>BKA</keyword>
	<keyword>below knee amputation</keyword>
	<keyword>CHAMP</keyword>
</DOC>