<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02685995</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Randomized two-arm study examining 90 day primary patency of two FDA-approved tunneled dialysis catheters.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>VectorFlow Tunneled Dialysis Catheter (TDC) Versus Palindrome TDC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The VectorFlow tunneled dialysis catheter is a novel symmetrical tip design tunneled dialysis catheter which in pre-clinical testing and retrospective review has improved flow and patency compared to other dialysis catheter designs. This study will compare 90 day patency rates of newly inserted VF catheters to the Palindrome catheter both of which are FDA approved devices and will inserted as standard of care. The Palindrome catheter has been selected as the comparison device because it is also a symmetrical tip catheter design and prior studies by the manufacturer of this device suggests it has a lower occlusion rate and better flow compared to other catheter designs.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>End stage renal disease or acute renal failure requiring hemodialysis through a tunneled dialysis catheter Age &gt;18, Age &lt;80 Capable of giving informed consent Coagulopathy defined as international normalized ration (INR) &gt;2 which cannot be corrected with fresh frozen plasma Platelet count &lt;50,000/microliter, which cannot be corrected with platelet transfusion Active skin infections at site of TDC insertion Presence of bacteremia or infected AVG/AVF within 7 days prior to enrollment Neutropenia defined as absolute neutrophil count less then 1,700/microliter Known central venous stenosis Occlusion of bilateral external and internal jugular veins or bilateral brachiocephalic veins or stenosis of the superior vena cava Functioning surgical HD access (ie AVG/AVF) or AVG/AVF which is expected to be functional within 90 days of enrollment Inability to provide informed consent Pregnant or nursing women In the event a physician does not feel that either catheter would be appropriate for a subject, the subject will not be eligible to participate</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>