<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01329744</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study examines the effects of recombinant insulin like growth factor - I on body composition, glucose homeostasis, and lipids, in adults with HIV infection and signs of metabolic disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of IGF-I in HIV Metabolic Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The main objectives of this study are the following: 1. Determine the effect of recombinant human insulin like growth factor-I (rhIGF-I) (generic: mecasermin) on subcutaneous adiposity in patients with HIV lipodystrophy syndrome. 2. Determine the effects of rhIGF-I on glucose homeostasis and lipids in patients with HIV lipodystrophy. 3. Determine the effects of rhIGF-I on apoptosis, mitochondria, and inflammation, in adipose tissue obtained from patients with HIV lipodystrophy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lipodystrophy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HIV positive with undetectable viral load No change in antiretrovirals for 3 months Evidence of lipoatrophy in the limbs, and face or gluteal area Dyslipidemia defined as: Fasting triglycerides &gt; 200 OR HDL cholesterol &lt; 40 mg/dL Abnormal glucose homeostasis defined as: Fasting hyperinsulinemia &gt; 20 uU/mL OR Fasting glucose 100125 mg/dL, inclusive Two consecutive viral &gt;75 or &gt; 50 copies/mL using the tests listed above Presence of AIDS wasting Change in antiretroviral medication (not dose) in the prior 3 months Coronary artery disease, cerebrovascular, or peripheral arterial disease Diabetes mellitus Adrenal insufficiency, hypoglycemia, thyroid disease, or other endocrine disorder that is untreated Malignancy Eating disorder Pregnancy (urine pregnancy test is required of all females) Previous liposuction or bariatric surgery Other systemic conditions or other disorders at the discretion of the investigators Current use of systemic glucocorticoids, or other agent affecting body weight or glucose homeostasis or other drug at the discretion of the investigators Use of interferon within the past six months Use of insulin, insulin secretagogue, thiazolidinedione, or metformin in the prior 3 months Initiation or dose adjustment, within the prior 3 months, of any of the following drugs or drug classes: fibrate, cholesterol binding resin, statin, niacin, or omega 3 fatty acid (fish oil). Use of uridine, growth hormone, IGFI, and growth hormone releasing factor analogues</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV lipodystrophy</keyword>
</DOC>