<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00062270</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Radiation therapy uses high-energy x-rays to damage tumor cells. Biological therapies such as gefitinib may interfere with the growth of the tumor cells and slow the growth of the tumor. Combining chemotherapy and radiation therapy with gefitinib before surgery may shrink the tumor so that it can be removed during surgery. PURPOSE: Phase I/II trial to compare the effectiveness of neoadjuvant chemoradiotherapy with or without gefitinib in treating patients who are undergoing surgery for stage III non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neoadjuvant Chemoradiotherapy With or Without Gefitinib in Treating Patients With Stage IIIA or Stage IIIB Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Phase I: - Determine the tolerability and toxicity of gefitinib in combination with chest radiotherapy in patients with stage IIIA or stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer. Phase II: - Compare the pathologic response (complete response and rate of downstaging) in patients treated with neoadjuvant chemoradiotherapy with vs without gefitinib. - Compare the feasibility and toxicity profile of these regimens in these patients. - Compare the resection rates, time to progression, and overall survival of patients treated with these regimens. - Correlate the percent decline in the fludeoxyglucose F 18 standardized uptake value as measured by position emission tomography with pathologic response at resection, time to progression, and overall survival in patients treated with these regimens. OUTLINE: - Phase I: This is an open-label, nonrandomized study. - Induction: Patients receive cisplatin IV over 60 minutes on day 1 and gemcitabine IV over 30 minutes on days 1 and 8. Treatment repeats every 3 weeks for a total of 2 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. - Consolidation: Within 3-4 weeks after the completion of induction therapy, patients undergo radiotherapy once daily 5 days a week for 5 weeks and receive oral gefitinib once daily concurrently. A cohort of 3-6 patients receives consolidation chemoradiotherapy. If 2 of 6 patients experience dose-limiting toxicity, gefitinib is deleted from consolidation therapy in phase II arm II. - Surgery: Patients without disease progression after consolidation therapy undergo thoracotomy within 3-5 weeks after consolidation. - Maintenance: Beginning 2-4 weeks after surgery, patients receive oral gefitinib once daily for 6 months in the absence of disease progression. - Phase II: This is a randomized study. Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. - Arm I: Patients receive induction and consolidation therapy (with the exception of gefitinib) as in phase I. Patients also receive docetaxel IV over 60 minutes concurrently with radiotherapy during consolidation. Patients undergo surgery as in phase I. - Arm II: Patients receive therapy (including gefitinib) as in phase I. Patients also receive docetaxel IV over 60 minutes concurrently with radiotherapy during consolidation. Patients are followed every 6-8 weeks for the first 12 months and then every 4-6 months thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 43-80 patients (3-6 patients for phase I and 40-74 patients [20-37 per treatment arm] for phase II) will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gefitinib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed nonsmall cell lung cancer Stage IIIA (T13, N2) Positive (pathological) ipsilateral mediastinal node Selective stage IIIB meeting all of the following criteria: No pleural/pericardial effusion or superior vena cava syndrome T4 due to invasion of carina, trachea, or mediastinal structures Mediastinal N3 nodes (without supraclavicular or cervical adenopathy) Proof of N2 or N3 status requires surgical staging of the mediastinum (mediastinoscopy, mediastinotomy, or exploration) Expression of epidermal growth factor receptor (at least 1+) by immunohistochemistry Measurable disease by contrast CT scan allowed No bronchoalveolar cell carcinoma No prior diagnosis of lung cancer PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 19 and over Performance status ECOG 01 (02 if albumin is at least 0.85 times lower limit of normal and weight loss within 3 months before diagnosis is no greater than 10%) Life expectancy Not specified Hematopoietic Absolute neutrophil count at least 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count at least 150,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin at least 10 g/dL Hepatic Bilirubin normal AST and ALT no greater than 2.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) Alkaline phosphatase no greater than 2 times ULN Alkaline phosphatase between 1.52 times ULN requires a negative bone scan for metastatic bone disease Renal Creatinine no greater than 1.4 mg/dL OR Creatinine clearance at least 60 mL/min Cardiac No myocardial infarction within the past 3 months No active angina No unstable heart rhythms No congestive heart failure Pulmonary Postresection predicted FEV_1% greater than 35% Predicted FEV_1% is defined as FEV_1% times percent perfusion to uninvolved lung from quantitative lung V/Q scan report Other Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for at least 6 weeks after study treatment No other uncontrolled medical illness No other malignancy within the past 5 years except basal cell skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix No grade 2 or greater peripheral neuropathy No concurrent ocular inflammation or infection No prior severe hypersensitivity reaction to docetaxel or other drugs formulated with polysorbate 80 No known severe hypersensitivity reaction to gefitinib or any of its excipients No prior severe allergic reaction to platinumcontaining compounds or mannitol PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy No concurrent growth factors (e.g., filgrastim [GCSF] or sargramostim [GMCSF]) during chemotherapy Chemotherapy No prior chemotherapy for lung cancer Endocrine therapy Not specified Radiotherapy No prior radiotherapy for lung cancer Surgery Recovered from prior major surgery No concurrent ophthalmic surgery Other More than 30 days since prior unapproved or investigational drugs No concurrent use of the following drugs: Phenytoin Carbamazepine Barbiturates Rifampin Phenobarbital Hypericum perforatum (St. John's Wort) Warfarin No concurrent retinoids</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>