<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00062608</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aims are to evaluate: (1) the effectiveness of written self-disclosure (WSD) on health status of youth ages 12-18 with functional recurrent abdominal pain (RAP); (2) whether effectiveness of WSD is similar for younger (12-14) and older (15-18) youth with functional RAP; and (3) the feasibility and acceptability of WSD when extended to the pediatric health care setting.We will implement a randomized, controlled trial (RCT) designed to compare health status in 140 youths (ages 12-18) with functional RAP assigned either to standard medical care (SMC) or WSD provided in the health care setting in addition to SMC. Health status will be measured at Baseline and 3- and 6-months thereafter. Primary measures of health status are symptom severity and episode frequency, consistent with the definition of RAP. Secondary measures of health are functional health, psychological distress, health-related quality of life, and health care utilization. Total use and diagnostic tests will index health care utilization, collected for the 6-mos prior to and following Baseline. Mixed model ANOVA or MANOVA will be used to test directional hypotheses corresponding to the specific aims.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Written Self-disclosure for Youth Abdominal Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Abdominal Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ages 1218. Diagnosis of RAP by the examining pediatric gastroenterologist using Apley's (1975) criteria: (a) 3 episodes of abdominal pain, (b) severe enough to interrupt activities and occurring, (c) over a period of at least 3 months, (d) without an identifiable organic cause (If an organic cause is identified during participation in protocol, then participant is withdrawn from database prior to analysis). Free of a known chronic health condition. Physical and mental ability to complete the procedures, as judged by Dr. MadanSwain. Consents to complete the protocol over the next 6 months. Parent(s) consents to participate and agrees to support the youth in completing the protocol. Access to a phone on the days writing sessions are to be completed at home.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Abdominal</keyword>
</DOC>