<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02251275</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to evaluate and describe the long term safety of tolvaptan in patients with autosomal dominant polycystic kidney disease (ADPKD</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-label Trial to Evaluate the Long Term Safety of Titrated Immediate-release Tolvaptan in Subjects With Autosomal Dominant Polycystic Kidney Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This trial is a phase 3b to evaluate and describe the long-term safety of tolvaptan treatment in ADPKD patients with CKD (chronic kidney disease). Eligible Subjects will enter the trial from Trial 156-08-271 or other Tolvaptan interventional trials. Renal function will be assessed during screening by using historical laboratory values for serum creatinine levels to calculate the estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR). General safety endpoints will be assessed and also relevant safety endpoints for the trial as Serum transaminase elevations in frequency &amp; Serum sodium excursions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polycystic Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polycystic Kidney, Autosomal Dominant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tolvaptan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male and female subjects ≥ 18 years with confirmed diagnosis of ADPKD (during participation in prior tolvaptan trials) who have Completed and transferred from the doubleblind Trial 15613210 (12month period including post treatment followup, regardless of whether this was ontreatment or offtreatment), or Completed Trial 15608271 or a prior tolvaptan trial, or Interrupted or discontinued treatment in a prior tolvaptan ADPKD trial other than Trial 15613210. Subjects may be enrolled with the medical monitor approval, and additional close monitoring may be required at the beginning of the study 2. Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) ≥ 20 mL/min/1.73m2 within 45 days of the baseline visit. Subjects who have an eGFR between 15 and 19 mL/min/1.73m2 may be enrolled with medical monitor approval 3. Diagnosis of ADPKD by modified PeiRavine criteria Need for chronic diuretic use Hepatic impairment based on liver function assessments other than that expected for ADPKD with cystic liver disease Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) who do not agree to practice 2 different methods of birth control or remain abstinent during the trial and for 30 days after the last dose of IMP Women who are breastfeeding and/or who have a positive pregnancy test result prior to receiving IMP. Subjects with contraindications to required trial assessments (contraindications to optional assessments, eg, MRI are not a limitation). Subjects who in the opinion of the Investigator or the Medical Monitor, have a medical history or medical finding inconsistent with safety or trial compliance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Autosomal Dominant Polycystic Kidney Disease</keyword>
</DOC>