<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00962780</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will evaluate the safety, tolerability and immunogenicity of a 13-valent pneumococcal conjugate vaccine (13vPnC) in HIV-infected subjects 6 years of age or older who have not been previously immunized with a pneumococcal vaccine. All subjects will receive 3 doses of 13vPnC and 1 dose of 23-valent pneumococcal polysaccharide vaccine (23vPS), with each dose given approximately 1 month apart.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Immunogenicity of 13-Valent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine (13vPnC) in HIV-Infected Subjects 6 Years of Age or Older Who Are Naive to Pneumococcal Vaccine</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumococcal Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heptavalent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)infected subjects aged 6 years or older Viral load &lt; 50,000 copies/mL and CD4+ T cell count &gt;= 200/uL within 6 months before study vaccination Receiving stable highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART) or not currently receiving any antiretroviral therapy No previous vaccination with a pneumococcal vaccine Subject or parent/legal guardian able to complete an electronic diary Acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) at time of enrollment Current illicit substance and/or alcohol abuse History of active chronic viral hepatitis Previous anaphylactic reaction to a vaccine or vaccinerelated component Serious chronic disorders including metastatic malignancy and endstage renal disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>13-valent pneumococcal conjugate vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>23-valent pneumococcal polysaccharide vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>human immunodeficiency virus</keyword>
</DOC>