<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00402883</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see if this combination of chemotherapy plus radiation therapy and immunotherapy (with bevacizumab) expands treatment options for patients with non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chemotherapy, Radiotherapy and Bevacizumab in Patients With Unresectable Stage III Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The patients on this study will receive treatment in 3 stages of therapy. The first stage is Induction Therapy. This therapy is 7 weeks long. Patients will receive bevacizumab followed by pemetrexed followed by carboplatin all by vein once a week in weeks 1 and 4. During Induction patients will also receive radiation therapy daily, Monday through Friday, for 7 weeks (weeks 1-7). This is followed by 2 weeks of rest. During this rest period patients will have scans done to see how their disease has responded to treatment. The next stage of treatment is Consolidation Therapy. This stage is 10 weeks long. Patients will receive bevacizumab followed by pemetrexed followed by carboplatin all by vein once a week in weeks 10, 13 and 16. This is followed by 3 weeks rest. During week 19 patients will have scans to see how their disease has responded to treatment. The last stage of treatment is Maintenance Therapy. Patients will receive bevacizumab alone by vein every 3 weeks. Treatment will be given every three weeks for up to 9 treatments. (week 45)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin B 12</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxocobalamin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin B Complex</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinically confirmed nonsmall cell lung cancer stage IIIA and selected stage IIIB Measurable or evaluable disease Be up and about and able to care for self Adequate kidney, liver and bone marrow function No prior treatment for this disease Must be able to give written informed consent Must be able to take folic acid, vitamin B12 and dexamethasone as described in the protocol Age 18 years or older Stage IV or IIIB patients with pleural or pericardial effusions Stage IIIB disease with contralateral mediastinal nodes greater than 4cm Squamous cell predominant tumors Pregnant or lactating women Patients with active infections History of another cancer within the last 5 years with the exception of skin cancer or cervical carcinoma in situ History of stroke, transient ischemic attacks, or acute MI within the past 6 months or any other serious cardiovascular disease Symptoms of peripheral vascular disease History of neurological disease Recent history of blood in the sputum or vomitus Nonhealing wounds, ulcer or long bone fractures History of bleeding problems or coagulation problems History of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation or intraabdominal abscess within 6 months History of uncontrolled hypertension Chronic use of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory medication not allowed on this study Please note: There are additional inclusion/exclusion criteria. The study center will determine if you meet all of the criteria. If you do not qualify for the trial, study personnel will explain the reasons. If you do qualify, study personnel will explain the trial in detail and answer any questions you may have. You can then decide if you wish to participate.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>