<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02050100</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study goal is to collect blood samples from individuals at risk for lung cancer in order to identify protein markers for diagnosis of lung cancer in the Chinese population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Biomarkers for Diagnosis of Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults ≥ 18 years of age Patients referred to pulmonologists, oncologists, or thoracic surgeons for diagnosis of suspicious pulmonary nodules as either lung cancer or benign and undergoing bronchoscopic biopsy Patients will be enrolled if the result of the bronchoscopic biopsy is a diagnosis of NSCLC or benign pulmonary nodule Cases: Patients with untreated nonsmall cell lung cancer, i.e. primary lung adenocarcinoma or squamous cell carcinoma of early Computed tomography or XRay is available and shows a suspicious pulmonary nodule A biopsy or surgical resection to clarify the nature of the lung nodule is available (NSCLC or benign, including histological diagnosis) in both groups Controls: Patients must be available for a 6 month followup to confirm benign diagnosis A serum and plasma sample was collected prior to any treatment of the lung nodule beyond biopsy No other cancer diagnosis in the last 5 years excluding nonmelanoma skin cancer Patients must be fully informed of the investigational nature of the procedure and sign an informed consent. Prior treatment for lung cancer by chemotherapy or surgery (excluding biopsy) Patients with benign nodules who are not able or willing to have a 6month followup visit to confirm benign diagnosis Diagnosis or treatment of other cancer in the last 5 years excluding nonmelanoma skin cancer. In the judgment of the clinical investigator, patients who are likely to be non compliant or uncooperative during the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>primary lung adenocarcinoma Stages I, II, IIIA, IIIB</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell carcinoma Stages I, II, IIIA, IIIB</keyword>
	<keyword>benign non-calcified pulmonary nodules</keyword>
	<keyword>early detection</keyword>
</DOC>