<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00346424</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to compare the safety and effectiveness of alfimeprase to a placebo in restoring function of occluded central catheters.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of Alfimeprase in Subjects With Occluded Central Catheters</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary Outcomes: The ability to withdraw at least 3 ml of blood and infuse more at least 5 mL of sterile saline through the occluded catheter lumen at 15 minutes after receiving initial instillation of study drug. Secondary Outcomes: The ability to withdraw at least 3 mL of blood and infuse at least 5 mL of sterile saline through the occluded catheter lumen at 30 minutes following a single instillation of study drug and at 30 minutes following a second instillation of study drug if patency is not restored within 30 minutes of the first instillation. Safety: - Adverse events - Major bleeding events - Change in laboratory values.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must give written informed consent Unable to withdraw 3 mL of blood from a central venous access device Hemodynamically stable Available for followup assessments Inability to infuse at least 2 mL of saline through the catheter Catheter placed less than 48 hours prior to detection of occlusion Catheter used for hemodialysis of pheresis Less than 18 years of age Evidence of mechanical or nonthrombotic occlusion Receipt of any thrombolytic agent within 24 hours of randomization In the opinion of the investigator, subject is at "high risk" for bleeding events of embolic complications, or has a condition for which bleeding constitutes a significant hazard Increased risk for drug extravasation Pregnant, lactating, or actively menstruating women and women of childbearing potential who are not using adequate contraceptive precautions (e.g. intrauterine device, oral contraceptives, barrier methods, or other contraception deemed adequate by the investigator) Known righttoleft cardiac shunt, patent foramen ovale, or atrial/ventricular septal defect Participation in any other study of an investigational device, medication, biologic, or other agent within 30 days before enrollment and until the 30day follow up visit Any other subject feature that in the opinion of the investigator should preclude study participation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>occluded central catheter</keyword>
	<keyword>central venous access devices dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>withdrawal occlusion</keyword>
	<keyword>Thrombosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Venous thrombosis</keyword>
</DOC>