<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00346567</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to find short course alternatives to single dose (sd)nevirapine for the prevention of mother-to-child HIV-transmission with the same or better degree of transmission protection than sd nevirapine but with less NNRTI resistance development.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Backup With Combivir or Single Dose (SD) Truvada in Order to Avoid Non-nucleoside Reverse Transcriptase Inhibitor (NNRTI) Resistance After SD Nevirapine for the Prevention of Mother-to-child Transmission (PMTCT)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Randomised open study comparing Zidovudine from 28 weeks gestation, single dose Nevirapine + 1 week of Combivir with Zidovudine from 28 weeks gestation, single dose Nevirapine + single dose of Truvada for the mothers during birth. In both arms the infants will receive one dose of nevirapine within the first days after births as well as 7 to 28 days Zidovudine. N = 450. The study will be conducted at Ngamiani and Makorora Health Centres and Bombo Regional Hospital in Tanga, Tanzania as a cooperation between Rigshospitalet, Denmark, University of Copenhagen and National Institute of Medical Research, Tanzania.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nevirapine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine, Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Reverse Transcriptase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zidovudine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lamivudine, zidovudine drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lamivudine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HIV infected, antiretroviral naive, not fulfilling national Tanzanian criteria for HAART treatment, giving informed consent, consenting to homevisitfollowup in case of noshow for scheduled hospital visit. CD4 less than 350 x10(6)/L, suffering from systemic diseases in need of medical treatment e.g. TB, renal or liver failure etc. Creatinin higher than 1,5 mg/dL, Alanine aminotransferase above 140 U/L</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>mother-to-child-transmission</keyword>
	<keyword>PMTCT</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>NNRTI</keyword>
</DOC>