<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00747513</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In an attempt to challenge the increasing prevalence of childhood obesity, many programs have been executed in order to improve childrens' lifestyle. Programs involved either school, family or environmental measures. In most, success was only limited. The purpose of this trial is to examine the ability of a low-cost multi-component program to improve behavioral, diet and activity habits in both school, family and afternoon settings. Ths ultimate goal is to construct and assess a lifestyle modification program that can be implemented in schools and kindergartens on a national level. Participants will be ~2,500 children aged 5-12 from 22 kindergartens and elementary schools, divided into control and intervention centers. Teachers and students will be provided with materials in order to perform activities on healthy food and drink choices and habits during the school day. Schools will offer increased physical activity opportunities to children, as will afternoon community centers. Children will be given personal exercise items. Parents will be offered lectures on topics of diet and activity. Diet and activity habits will be assessed by a questionnaire, and height, weight and body fat percentage will be measured before and after the program.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Multi-component Program to Reduce Obesity in Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>schools with lunch served school principal agreement school has 2 weekly PE classes parent and children consent given consent not given</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>13 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>school</keyword>
	<keyword>prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>overweight</keyword>
	<keyword>children</keyword>
	<keyword>diet</keyword>
	<keyword>physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>fitness</keyword>
</DOC>