<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00747136</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate the clinical utility of the WavSTAT Optical Biopsy System as an adjunctive tool to improve the endoscopist's clinical sensitivity to identify dysplasia or cancer in the esophagus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>WavSTAT® Optical Biopsy System to Target Esophageal Biopsies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In the clinical portion of this prospective study, the algorithm developed in the preclinical evaluation will be blindly tested using the pathologists' assessment of the biopsies as a gold standard to determine the clinical sensitivity and specificity of the WavSTAT Optical Biopsy System to identify dysplastic or cancerous tissue in the esophagus. In addition, the endoscopist's unaided clinical sensitivity and specificity to identify dysplasia or cancerous tissue will also be determined by recording the endoscopist's visual assessment of whether the physical biopsy has dysplasia or cancer or does not have dysplasia or cancer prior to performing the biopsy The endoscopist's assessment will be correlated and compared with the pathologist's interpretation. The clinical utility of the WavSTAT System to improve the endoscopist's clinical sensitivity to identify dysplasia or cancer in the esophagus will be evaluated by testing the hypothesis that the sensitivity of a WavSTAT-assisted endoscopic examination improves that of standard endoscopy alone.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Barrett Esophagus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient is between 18 and 80 years of age. The patient is willing to sign an informed consent form. The patient is a candidate for endoscopic examination Female patients of childbearing age, uncertain of pregnancy status, must have a negative pregnancy test. The patient has congenital deformities, which preclude a physical biopsy procedure during endoscopy. The patient is pregnant or nursing by admission. The patient has other contraindications for physical biopsy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Barrett's</keyword>
	<keyword>Dysplasia</keyword>
	<keyword>esophageal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Patients</keyword>
</DOC>