<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00747370</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to test the suitability of dynamic magnetic resonance imaging for the pelvic floor floor, bladder neck and urethra in healthy volunteers, in stress incontinent patient and in women with genital prolapse.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dynamic MRI of the Behaviour of Female Pelvic Floor</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Traditional methods for evaluation of urinary incontinence in women include urodynamics, cystourethroscopy, cystourethrography and ultrasonography.Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) offers a new tool for evaluation of morphology and function of the urogenital compartment of the female pelvis. Moreover, MRI gives opportunity to study function of the pelvic floor organs in terms of mobility and reactions during different physiological and provocative activities. The aim of the present study was by means of dynamic MRI to evaluate the behaviour of the mid-urethra, bladder neck, cervix and rectum in different maneuvers in three different study groups. Sixteen healthy volunteers with no complaints of urinary symptoms or urogenital prolapses, 42 stress urinary incontinence patients and 16 women with third degree genital prolapse were examined respectively.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Enuresis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prolapse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence, Stress</mesh_term>
	<criteria>healthy women without any urogenital symptoms stress urinary incontinence ( group II ) genital prolapse of third degree ( group III) previous incontinence or prolapse surgery lower urinary tract anomaly current UTI or &gt; 3 UTI episodes within the past year previous radiation therapy of the pelvis active malignancy neurogenic disease which can be associated with bladder disorders patient unable to understand the purpose of the study patient immobile</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>stress urinary incontinence</keyword>
	<keyword>Tension free vaginal tape</keyword>
	<keyword>tension free vaginal tape obturator</keyword>
	<keyword>genital prolapse</keyword>
</DOC>