<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02148835</DOC>
	<brief_summary>New approaches to increase eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA) and docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) in our diet are needed, but any new approach needs to demonstrate the bioavailability of EPA+DHA, and its safety and palatability. The HS-Omega-3 Index is a prime parameter to demonstrate bioavailability in the long-term. Study hypothesis is that increased intake of EPA+DHA will increase the HS-Omega-3 Index. Study aim is to investigate how supplementing various sausages with omega-3 fatty acids influences the HS-Omega-3 Index in healthy volunteers, as compared to unsupplemented matching sausages. Safety and palatability of the sausages are also to be assessed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Influence of Dietary Omega-3 Fatty Acids in Various triOMEG Sausages on the HS-Omega-3 Index in Healthy Individuals</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>1. Subjects must be willing to eat 80 g of the sausage to be investigated per day. 2. Age: 20 60 years 3. Low HSOmega3 Index (&lt;5%) 4. Subjects must have adequate fluency in German or English to complete baseline and followup interviews. 5. Stable intake of food containing EPA+DHA before and during study 6. Subjects must be able and willing to give written informed consent, and to comply with study procedures. 1. Subjects for whom the intake of omega3 fatty acids is mandatory according to recent treatment guidelines or who take omega3 fatty acids supplements on a regular basis. 2. Subjects consuming &gt;2 portions of fatty fish / week 3. Subjects with serious bleeding disorder. Use of platelet inhibitors or conventional anticoagulation with a target INR of 2.0 3.0 is not an exclusion criterion. 4. Subjects with any acute and lifethreatening condition, such as collapse and shock, acute myocardial infarction (last three months), stroke, embolism. 5. Subjects with significant medical comorbidity, seriously limiting life expectancy or insulintreated diabetes mellitus or a BMI&gt;30 6. Allergy/intolerance or history of hypersensitivity to components of study intervention. 7. Pregnant subjects and breastfeeding subjects. In addition, women of childbearing potential who will not practice a medically accepted method of contraception will be excluded. 8. Subjects who, in the investigator's judgement, will not likely be able to comply with the study protocol or with known drug or alcohol abuse/dependence in the past 2 years. 9. Use of any investigational agents within 30 days prior to t0</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Omega-3 Index</keyword>
	<keyword>Bioavailability</keyword>
	<keyword>Eicosapentaenoic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>Docosahexaenoic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>Fortified food</keyword>
</DOC>