<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01645748</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to evaluate the tolerability and efficacy of a combination of weekly docetaxel, cisplatin, and S-1 (weekly TPS) as induction chemotherapy in patients with locally advanced head and neck squamous cell carcinoma (HNSCC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Docetaxel, Cisplatin, and S-1 (TPS) Induction Chemotherapy in Locally Advanced Head and Neck Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Combination chemotherapy with cisplatin and fluorouracil (CF) is the standard treatment for patients with locally advanced squamous cancer of the head and neck. CF chemotherapy has been reported to increase survival and disease free survival in patients with unresectable disease when given before definitive radiotherapy, showing overall response rate as 75-85% including of CR rate of 25-35%. To improvement of treatment, docetaxel was incorporated into CF as induction treatment and it showed the prolongation of progression free survival and overall survival in large scale of randomized phase III trials, therefore triple combination induction regimen would be standard treatment in advanced head and neck cancer. Recently, the introduction of oral fluoropyrimidine showed similar or enhanced response rate, also favorable safety and convenience than intravenous fluoropyrimidine in advanced gastric cancer. Of the oral fluoropyrimidines, S-1 showed promising preliminary result in combination chemotherapy with cisplatin in head and neck cancer. In patients with advanced gastric cancer, phase I study of S-1, docetaxel and cisplatin combination chemotherapy was reported and the recommended doses were 40mg/m2 bid, 60mg/m2 (D1) and 60mg/m2 (D1), respectively. Therefore, the aim of this study was to evaluate the efficacy and safety of docetaxel, cisplatin and S-1 combination chemotherapy according to above dosage.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>locally advanced stage III or IV squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx, oropharynx, or hypopharynx ≥18 years old absolute neutrophil count ≥1,500/µL, platelets ≥100,000/µL serum bilirubin &lt;2.0 mg/dL creatinine &lt;1.5 mg/dL serum transaminase levels less than twice the upper limit of normal received previous chemotherapy another malignancy current or history of distant metastasis history of clinically significant cardiac disease within 6 months active serious infection nasopharyngeal carcinoma psychiatric illness that would preclude obtaining informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>head and neck cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>docetaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>cisplatin</keyword>
	<keyword>S-1</keyword>
</DOC>