<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01645943</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The guidelines of clinical practice, based on the randomized studies, recommend an invasive strategy in non-ST elevation acute coronary syndrome (NSTEACS). However, patients with comorbidities are excluded from the randomized studies and the observational registries showthat patients with comoribidities undergo fewer cardiac catheterizations. The aim is to investigate the benefit of the invasive strategy in patients with NSTEACS and comorbidities. Patients hospitalized with NSTEACS, older than 70 years and with significant comorbidities, will be included. The latter will be defined as at least 2 of the following: peripheral artery disease, cerebral vascular disease, dementia, chronic pulmonary disease, chronic renal failure and anemia. The included patients will be randomized to an invasive (routine coronary angiogram) or conservative (coronary angiogram only if recurrent or inducible ischemia) strategy. All patients will receive medical treatment according to current recommendations. The main outcome will be death, reinfarction or readmissions by heart cause at one-year follow-up. The hypothesis is that an invasive strategy will improve prognosis in patients with NSTEACS and comorbidities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Invasive vs Conservative Strategies in Non-ST-elevation Acute Coronary Syndrome and Comorbidities</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age =&gt;70 years old Angina chest pain Troponin elevation At least 2 of the following comorbidities: A) Documented peripheral artery disease. B)Renal filaure (GFR &lt;45 ml/min/m2). C) Neurological disease with permanent deficit. D) Dementia (Pfeiffer test). E) Chronic pulmonary disease (Gold&gt;2 or ambulatory oxigen therapy). Anemia (Hb =&lt;11 g/dl) Dynamic ST changes (=&gt;1 mm) in the initial ECG Prior known nonrevascularizable coronay disease Concomitant heart disease different to coronary disease Life expentancy &lt; 1 year</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>70 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-ST-elevation acute myocardial infarction</keyword>
	<keyword>Comorbidities</keyword>
</DOC>