<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00883727</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial aims to find out the safety and efficacy of adult mesenchymal stem cells in patients with myocardial infarction.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ex Vivo Cultured Bone Marrow Derived Allogenic MSCs in AMI</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Plasma-lyte 148</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with STEMI aged between 20 and 70 years, either males or females with nonchild bearing potential, after 2 days of successful PCI. Patient has global left ventricular systolic dysfunction with an ejection fraction of &lt;50% and &gt;30%. ECG with sign of acute anterior MI with STelevation ≥ 2 mm in at least 2 of the following leads I, AVL, V1V6, or ECG with sign of acute inferoposterior MI with STelevation ≥1 mm on all of the following leads II, III, V5V6 or STelevation ≥ 2 mm in at least 2 of the leads. The target lesion located in the proximal section of the left anterior descending, left circumflex or right coronary artery. Patient with acute myocardial infarction within 10 days prior to IP administration. Normal liver and renal function. Able to understand study information provided to him. Able to give voluntary written consent. History of acute/chronic inflammatory condition or severe aortic stenosis or insufficiency; severe mitral stenosis or severe mitral insufficiency. Severe comorbidity associated with a reduction in life expectancy of less than 1 year. Advanced renal dysfunction and creatinine ≥ 2mg%. Advanced hepatic dysfunction. Have clinically serious and/or unstable intercurrent infection, medical illnesses or conditions that are uncontrolled or whose control, in the opinion of the Investigator, may be jeopardized by participation in this study or by the complications of this therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>mesenchymal stem cells</keyword>
	<keyword>myocardial infarction</keyword>
</DOC>