<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00067899</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if oxidative stress derived from cigarette smoking increases vitamin E requirements. The study will also assess the role of vitamin C in modulating vitamin E requirements. Vitamin E requirements will be assessed by measuring vitamin E in plasma as well as by measuring the excreted vitamin E metabolite in the urine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Oxidative Stress and Vitamin E Requirements</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We will be investigating the fractional disappearance rate of tocopherols in cigarette smokers compared to nonsmokers. This will be accomplished by supplementing individuals with deuterium labeled alpha- and gamma-tocopherols. Quantification of plasma tocopherols as well as urinary metabolites, alpha- and gamma-carboxy ethyl hydroxychromanol, will be determined using liquid chromatography/mass spectrometry analysis. In addition, the role of vitamin C as it pertains to its influence on the fraction disappearance rate of vitamin E will also be evaluated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin E</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tocopherols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tocotrienols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>alpha-Tocopherol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: nonsmoking status or smokers (more than 1 pack per day) age: 1835 y stable body weight, ranging between 80% and 130%, maintenance of normal exercise and activity patterns total cholesterol ≤ 7.758 mmol/L (300 mg/dl) triglyceride concentration ≤ 3.387 mmol/L (300 mg/dl) Subjects will be excluded if they fulfill any one of the following: antioxidant supplement users resting blood pressure above 160/105 mm Hg engaged in aerobic activity more than five hours per week vegetarian or other restrictive dietary requirements fasting blood glucose concentration of ≥ 7.77 mmol/L (140 mg/dl) history of diabetes or uremia other known metabolic disease or medication use known to affect lipid metabolism</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>cigarette smoking</keyword>
	<keyword>tocopherol</keyword>
	<keyword>bioavailability</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolism</keyword>
	<keyword>oxidative stress</keyword>
</DOC>