<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01551823</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and the immunogenicity of Influenza Virus Vaccine (Split Virion, Inactivated)(children forms of drug) that do not contains Preservative.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Clinical Trial Protocol for the Influenza Virus Vaccine (Split Virion, Inactivated) （Children Forms of Drug）</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Influenza Virus Vaccine (Split Virion, Inactivated) that do not contain Preservative. HA contents 7.5μg/0.5ml per dose include H1N1、H3N2 and B. Inactivated Split Influenza Vaccine was manufactured by Sanofi Pasteur HA contents 7.5μg/0.5ml per dose include H1N1、H3N2 and B. This is a randomized, blind phase 3 clinical trial. Total 1200 adults (ages from 6 months to 36 months ) were selected, randomized to two groups [Influenza Virus Vaccine (Split Virion, Inactivated) and Inactivated Split Influenza Vaccine , each group n=600], adults in each group will be vaccinated with two doses of either Influenza Virus Vaccine (Split Virion, Inactivated) or Sanof IVV respectively,21 days apart.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and females, age from 6 months to 35 months ; Adults, parent(s) or guardians are able to understand and sign informed consent for participation; Participants or guardians are able to attend all planned clinical appointment and obey and follow all study instructions; Infants no vaccinated with influenza or other preventive biologicals in recent 7 days; Axillary temperature ≤37℃. Have medical record of participants or their family on allergy and egg, convulsion, falling sickness, encephalopathy and psychopathy; Low platelet or bleeding disorder do not allow vaccination into the muscle; Have damaged or lower immunological function; Received blood, plasma or immunoglobulin treatment since birth; Have inborn abnormality, develop obstacles or clinical diagnostic serious chronic ( Down Syndrome, diabetes, sickle cell anemia or neural GuillainBarre Syndrome ); Have or be doubtful of following diseases: respiratory system diseases, acute infection or active chronic, cardiovascular diseases, liver and kidney diseases, skin diseases, HIV. Exclusion Criteria for doses 2 Have serious anaphylaxis or high fever, convulsion during first dose; Have any circus of Exclusion Criteria after Eligible for study; Have serious adverse event which related to previous vaccination; Withdrawal and Discontinuance Criteria; Received necessary or interference study drugs such as: immuneinhibition or immunestimulating agents; Vaccinated with any other vaccine（except DTP）; Stop observation determined by investigator owing to occurring serious adverse event.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Influenza Virus Vaccine (Split Virion, Inactivated)</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza</keyword>
</DOC>