<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00924729</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being conducted to evaluate the intraocular penetration of Moxifloxacin 0.5% ophthalmic solution (Vigamox) and Besifloxacin 0.6% ophthalmic suspension (Besivance) after pre-operative topical administration in subjects undergoing cataract surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Ocular Penetration of Topically Administered Fluoroquinolones</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cataract</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eye Injuries, Penetrating</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluoroquinolones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Moxifloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>7-(3-aminohexahydro-1H-azepin-1-yl)-8-chloro-1-cyclopropyl-6-fluoro-1,4-dihydro-4-oxo-3-quinolinecarboxylic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Norgestimate, ethinyl estradiol drug combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who have a visually significant cataract and are planning to have cataract surgery. Subjects who are willing/able and have signed informed consent approved by the Institutional Review Board. Subjects who have a known hypersensitivity, allergy, or contraindication to any fluoroquinolone medication, in any form. Subjects who signs of ocular infection or active inflammation in the study eye. Subjects who have corneal pathology, including epithelial defect, corneal scarring, or severe dry eye syndrome. Subjects who have used any disallowed medication (including antibiotics) during the time period designated as described in the protocol. Subjects who have any active or chronic/recurrent ocular or systemic disease that is uncontrolled and is likely to increase the risk of infection to the patient or confound the results of the study. Subjects who are pregnant (or suspect to be pregnant) or nursing/lactating. Subjects who have participated in any study of an investigational drug or device within 30 days prior to enrollment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2009</verification_date>
</DOC>