<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00924443</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine if treatment of older patients indicated with untreated Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML) who are not considered to be suitable for intensive chemotherapy, can effectively be treated with Clofarabine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Clofarabine in Older Patients With Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML) for Whom Chemotherapy Is Not Suitable</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Note: This clinical trial was conducted by Bioenvision Ltd. Bioenvision Ltd. was acquired by Genzyme Corporation Oct 2007.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clofarabine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Provide signed, written informed consent Have untreated AML according to World Health Organization (WHO) classification Male or postmenopausal female ≥ 65 years of age Unsuitable for intensive chemotherapy Be able to comply with study procedures and followup examination Male patient who are fertile agree to use and effective barrier method of birth control to avoid pregnancies Have adequate liver and renal function as indicated by certain laboratory values Received previous treatment with clofarabine Are receiving other chemotherapy or corticosteroids (lowdose corticosteroid for premedication purposes are allowed) Have received prior treatment for leukemia. Growth factor, cytokine support, leukopheresis or hydroxyurea will be allowed but must be discontinued at least 24 hours prior to start of treatment with clofarabine Have a psychiatric disorder that would interfere with consent, study participation, or followup Have an active, uncontrolled systemic infection Are currently participating in other investigational drug studies or having received other investigational drugs within the previous 30 days Have symptomatic central nervous system (CNS) involvement Blast transformation of chronic myeloid leukemia or acute promyelocytic leukemia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>acute myelogenous leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>acute myeloid leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>clolar</keyword>
	<keyword>evoltra</keyword>
	<keyword>clofarabine</keyword>
	<keyword>untreated acute leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute leukemia</keyword>
</DOC>