<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00954538</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will estimate the radiochemical and radiation safety and assess the efficacy of [18F]MK-3328, a novel positron emission tomography (PET) tracer. The study safety hypotheses will test whether [18F]MK-3328 is sufficiently safe and well-tolerated, based on an assessment of clinical and laboratory evaluations and adverse experiences in healthy participants, including healthy elderly (HE) participants, and Alzheimer's disease (AD) participants, to permit continued investigation. The study efficacy hypothesis will test whether [18F]MK-3328 can discriminate between AD participants and cognitively normal elderly control participants based on tracer volume of distribution, or one of its surrogates, in brain posterior cingulate gyrus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Radiation Dosimetry, Biokinetics, and Effectiveness of [18F]MK3328 (MK-3328-001)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Part I: Participant is male or female of nonreproductive potential between 50 and 65 years old. Participant is less than 6'5" tall Participant is in good health Participant has been a nonsmoker for at least 10 years Parts II and III: Male or female of nonreproductive potential at least 55 years of age Participant is cognitively normal (HE participants), or has probable mildto moderate AD (AD participants) Participant is willing to have an arterial catheter placed in the radial artery (Part II only) Part I: Participant has a history of stroke, seizures, or neurological disorder Participant has or has a history of any disease or condition, or takes any medication that would interfere with assessment of the tracer or make participation unsafe or unduly uncomfortable Parts II and III: Participant has a history or current evidence of any neurological or neurodegenerative disorder other than AD that is associated with altered cognition Participant has or has a history of any disease or condition, or takes any medication that would interfere with assessment of the tracer or make participation unsafe or unduly uncomfortable Participant is living in a nursing home or skilled nursing facility</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>