<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00602797</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II trial studies the side effects and how well vinorelbine tartrate and paclitaxel works in treating older patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as vinorelbine tartrate and paclitaxel, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Giving combination chemotherapy may kill more tumor cells.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vinorelbine Tartrate and Paclitaxel in Treating Older Patients With Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the safety and efficacy of a combination of vinorelbine and paclitaxel administered weekly to elderly patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer. II. To assess the response rate of a combination of vinorelbine and paclitaxel administered weekly to elderly patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer. III. To assess the quality of life of elderly patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer during administration of weekly paclitaxel and vinorelbine. OUTLINE: Patients receive vinorelbine tartrate intravenously (IV) over 6-10 minutes and paclitaxel IV over 1 hour once weekly for 6 weeks. Treatment repeats every 8 weeks for up to 2 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 3 months for 2 years and then every 6 months for 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vinorelbine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vinblastine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pathologically proven nonsmall cell lung cancer with evidence of distant metastases/malignant pleural effusion Measurable disease on imaging studies in 2 dimensions No previous therapy with either paclitaxel or vinorelbine, or any chemotherapy for the past five years Patients who have had a previous resection for their lung cancer and present with recurrent disease will be eligible Patients with other prior malignancies will be included, provided they have been diseasefree for at least five years Patients with adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, adequately treated carcinoma insitu of the cervix and hormone sensitive prostate cancer will be eligible Karnofsky score &gt;= 70 (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group [ECOG] 02) White blood cell (WBC) count &gt;= 3,500/mm^3, OR Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1,500/ul Platelet count &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 Serum creatinine less than 1.5 times the upper limits of normal Serum aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) less than 1.5 times the upper limits of normal Serum alkaline phosphatase less than 2.5 times the upper limits of normal No active serious infections or other condition precluding chemotherapy Nonpregnant and nonnursing Men and women of reproductive potential may not participate unless they have agreed to use an effective contraceptive method while on the study Able to give informed consent Able to return for treatment and followup as specified in the protocol Known hypersensitivity to any component of vinorelbine or paclitaxel or other required drugs in the study Any comorbidity or condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with the assessments and procedures of this protocol Inability to fulfill the requirements of the protocol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>70 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>