<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02911350</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if the combination therapy of Hormone, Paclitaxel and Radiation therapy are effective in treatment of locally advanced prostate cancer</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of Combination of Hormone Therapy, Paclitaxel and Radiation Therapy to Treat Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Any one or more of the following characteristics will qualify patient with T2/T3 prostate cancer for eligibility to current study: Biopsy proven prostate cancer with Gleason score &gt; 7 Pathologic staging TXN1 (on MRI or CT) Prostatespecific antigen (PSA) &gt; 10 ng/ml done within a month prior to study entry (the day of first hormonal ablation) and &gt; 10 days after prostate biopsy. In addition patients must also have: Performance status &lt; 2 Hemoglobin &gt; 11 grams per deciliter (g/dL), White blood cell (WBC) &gt; 4000 and platelet count &gt; 100.000/l No evidence of other synchronous primary. Prior malignancies does not exclude if the patient is disease free &gt; 5 years. Prior or concurrent basal cell or noninvasive squamous carcinoma of the skin is eligible and Received hormone therapy with any of the following combination for less than 3 months Lupron / Flutamide Zoladex/ Flutamide Lupron/ Casodex Zoladex/ Casodex Clinical stage T1N0, PSA &lt; 10, and Gleason score less than 7. Evidence of distant metastasis Previous surgery for prostate cancer (radical prostatectomy). Current treatment with ketoconazole, cimetidine or hormone therapy for more than 3 months prior to inclusion in the protocol for prostate cancer Major medical or psychiatric illness, which in the investigator's opinion may prevent completion of the study and interfere with follow up. Bilirubin &gt; 1.5 Prior chemotherapy is not allowed</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>