<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01731197</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Proteins are known to be more satiating than the other macronutrients; however, the type and amount of protein needed to induce a significant effect on satiety (fullness between meals) is sometimes difficult to determine. In this study, 2 differentially processed isolated soy proteins will be tested for satiety using subjective visual analogue scales. The amount of food consumed following intake of the isolated soy proteins will be measured 3 hours after consuming the proteins. The hypothesis is that differentially processed isolated soy proteins will show unique satiety responses.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Satiating Effects of Isolated Soy Proteins</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>BMI between 20 and 30 kg/m2 Age between 1865y Unrestrained eater (score&lt;12) Regularly consume 3 meals per day Moderate exercise (eg running, aerobics classes, other sports activities) of no more than 7 hours per week use of drugs that influence carbohydrate or lipid metabolism (eg. hypoglycemic agents, antibiotics taken less than 6 weeks before study entry, glucocorticoids, antidiarrheal medication, weight loss medication, and antidiabetic medication) presence of any significant disease (eg gastrointestinal diseases, diabetes, a CVD event less than 12 weeks from study entry, current hepatic disease, etc) use of special dietary treatments within 4 weeks of study (eg weight loss diet, extremely high or low carbohydrate/protein/fat diet, use of meal replacements more than once a day) use of supplements within 1 week of study (does not include vitamin supplements or supplements which are routinely taken and were initiated 4 weeks before the study and which will be continued during the study period) restrained eater (score&gt;12) weight change (absolute body weight change of ≥ 10%) within the previous 6 weeks alcohol intake &gt;2 drinks/day food allergies of any kind swallowing difficulties exercising more than 7 hours per week</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>obesity, isolated soy protein, satiety, food intake</keyword>
</DOC>