<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01731366</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objective: To identify how specific changes of the whole grain content in the diet affect the host-gut microbiome interactions with implications for metabolic health . Design: A randomized, controlled, single-blinded, cross-over intervention trial consisting of two 8-week intervention periods, separated by a 6-week wash-out period. A total of 60 participants will be included. Intervention: low vs. high whole grain intake.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Whole Grain on Gut Microbiome and Metabolic Health</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is designed as a randomized, controlled, single-blinded, cross-over intervention trial consisting of two 8-week interventions periods, separated by a 6-week wash-out period. A total number of 60 participants will be included. Participants consume, in randomized order, a diet rich in whole grain in the active treatment period and a refined grain diet during the control period. Measurements: Insulin sensitivity will be assessed by means of a meal challenge test and by the Homeostasis Model Assessment of Insulin Resistance (HOMA-IR) which is the primary outcome of this study. Secondary outcomes include metabolic and inflammatory markers, appetite hormones, transit time, and GM composition. Furthermore, selected control measures are included; 4-day food records and a study intervention diary.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Body mass index (BMI): 25 35 kg/m2 No medical prescribed diet Weight stable No blood donation during the study Intense sporting activities less than 10h/ week Alcohol consumption less than 14 units/ week (female) and 21 units/ week (male) Signed written consent Pharmacological treatment; hypertension, diabetes and blood lipid regulation Lactating (or lactating, 6 weeks ago), pregnant (or pregnant, 3 months ago) or wish to become pregnant during the study Participation in another biomedical trial 1 month prior to study start Diagnosed with any form of diabetes, celiac disease or chronic pancreatitis Reported chronic gastrointestinal disorders Antibiotic treatment for 3 month prior to study start Intake of vitamin, mineral, or pre or probiotic supplements for 1 month prior to study start Blood hemoglobin &lt; 7.0 mmol/l Blood donation within 1 month prior to study start</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>