<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01350284</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether 3 g cinnamon was sufficient to delay the gastric emptying rate of a high-fat solid meal and subsequently reduce postprandial blood glucose and lipid responses, oxidative stress, arterial stiffness and satiety responses in a healthy adult population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Natural Food Flavourings on Gastrointestinal and Cardiovascular Physiological Responses.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cinnamon has been shown to delay gastric emptying (GE) of a high-carbohydrate meal and reduce postprandial glycaemia in healthy adults. However, it is dietary fat which is implicated in the etiology and is associated with obesity, type 2 diabetes (T2D) and cardiovascular disease (CVD). We aimed to determine the effect of 3 g cinnamon on GE, postprandial lipemic and glycemic responses, oxidative stress, arterial stiffness, as well as appetite sensations and subsequent food intake following a high-fat (HF) meal. The effect of acute oral administration of 3 g cinnamon on gastric emptying of a high-fat pancake test meal and subjective appetite sensations by visual analogue scale will be measured for six hours postprandially. During this time course, measurements of postprandial lipemic, glycemic, oxidative stress and arterial stiffness responses will be collected. Subsequently, food intake will be measured using an ad libitum buffet meal. The study will be conducted in a randomized, placebo-controlled, single-blinded manner in 9 healthy subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy adults aged 1835 years Recreationally trained individuals (participate in at least 2hrs/wk of individual/team sport) Not currently taking antioxidant or lipidlowering medication Fasting blood lipid, glucose and blood pressure (BP) levels were all within the normal limits. History of gastrointestinalrelated conditions, diabetes mellitus or cardiovascular disease. Allergies to foods in study. Blood disorder Pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Antioxidants</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucose Intolerance prevention and control</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus prevention and control</keyword>
</DOC>