<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02046317</DOC>
	<brief_summary>For bone fracture injuries, particularly femur fractures, the femoral nerve block (FNB) can provide a fast and effective means to control pain. However, this method is not always employed due to the fact that positioning the needle and therefore the block can be time consuming and challenging, and if not precisely placed, the nerve block results in poor pain control. Traditional methods for nerve blockade include the blind technique and use of a peripheral nerve stimulator (PNS). Unfortunately, neither of these methods provide a reliable guide for needle placement and can lead to intraneural placement and/or failed attempts. Hypothesis: When ultrasound technology is implemented in this procedure it may improve the success rate when compared to other techniques by providing real-time visual guidance. This may result in a faster and prolonged pain relief reducing the amount of analgesics needed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ultrasound Guided Femoral Nerve Block on Isolated Femur Fracture Using Echo Friendly Needles</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To date, the published information regarding ultrasound guided femoral blocks using echo friendly needle is very limited. More so, there is even less information regarding ultrasound guided nerve blocks using echogenic versus standard of care needles. This study hopes to add to the general knowledge of pain management in the ED setting and provide a unique perspective on ultrasound guided techniques using echogenic needles to enhance accuracy and success rate of nerve blocks in ED patients. Results from this study will be compared to the results of other similar studies to see if these findings are comparative to relevant factors. The study design will have two comparative arms; in both arms we use the same local anesthetic which is Bupivacaine 0.25% with epinephrine; in all cases a total of 15 ml will be injected around the femoral nerve. Once identified with ultrasound 5 ml will be injected at lateral, medial and posterior aspect of the nerve. The experimental arm, will receive a FNB using an echogenic needle; and the control group will receive a FNB using standard of care needles.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Femoral Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years and older Patients who present to the ED with isolated femur fracture (no other injuries) Patients who are cognitively alert and are able to verbalize their pain using a visual analog scale (VAS) Patients who are mentally competent to consent for the study Patients who can communicate in English or Spanish Gestation Prisoners Patients who cannot communicate in English or in Spanish Patients who have other significant injuries besides a femur fracture Patients who are cognitively impaired and/or unable to verbalize their pain using a visual analog scale (VAS) Patients with allergies to local anesthetics Patients with severe liver disease Patients with existing peripheral neuropathies in the affected limb Patients with history of complications from previous femoral blocks Patients with contraindications for needle insertion at inguinal area Local signs of infection Patient on anticoagulants and/or with history of coagulation disorders</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>