<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02046135</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The proposed study will investigate the effect of sodium bicarbonate on the prevention of acute kidney injury in children undergoing cardiac surgery with cardio-pulmonary bypass. The investigators hypothesize that the occurrence of acute kidney injury will be less in children treated with sodium bicarbonate in the perioperative period when compared to placebo. The specific aims of this proposal are as follows: 1. To institute a prospective, randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial in pediatric subjects undergoing cardiac surgery to determine the efficacy of sodium bicarbonate on prevention of acute kidney injury as measured by pRIFLE criteria. 2. To examine whether treatment with sodium bicarbonate modifies the duration of acute kidney injury, fluid balance, hospital length of stay, need for dialysis, and progression to kidney failure. 3. To determine the relevance of NGAL as a biomarker to predict development of acute kidney injury.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sodium Bicarbonate to Prevent Acute Kidney Injury in Children Undergoing Cardiac Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Defects, Congenital</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subjects age ≤18 years 2. Subjects scheduled for cardiac surgery with cardiopulmonary bypass 1. Subjects with abnormal creatinine clearance (&lt;90 ml/min/1.7m2) as measured by the Schwartz formula 2. Subjects with known cystic kidney disease or posterior ureteral valves (subjects with solitary kidney, single multicystic/dysplastic kidney, hydronephrosis will not be excluded if renal function is preserved) 3. Subjects with known metabolic disorder 4. Premature infants born &lt;30 weeks gestation and &lt;30 days old due to risk of intraventricular hemorrhage Subjects in severe cardiogenic shock postoperative requiring extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO) or left ventricular assist device (LVAD) will be withdrawn from the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pediatric</keyword>
	<keyword>Sodium bicarbonate</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute kidney injury</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac surgery</keyword>
</DOC>