<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01333488</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators hypothesize that hypothermia (body cooling) and additional magnesium sulfate will improve the outcome of severe Traumatic Brain Injury (TBI) patients. This is a study to compare the outcomes of patients with severe traumatic brain injury who have been allocated to one of the following three groups: Group 1 - Conventional therapy following traumatic brain injury Group 2 - Subjects will have their core body temperature lowered to 34C Group 3 - Subjects will have their core body temperature lowered to 34C and will receive a supplemental intravenous infusion of magnesium sulfate.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mild Hypothermia and Supplemental Magnesium Sulfate Infusion in Severe Traumatic Brain Injury (TBI) Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypothermia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Magnesium Sulfate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adult males or females ≥ 18 years of age 2. Subjects with Traumatic Brain Injury and a postresuscitation Glasgow Coma Score (GCS) ≤ 8 3. Inhospital and screened within 7 hours of injury. 4. Able to obtain legally effective written consent from authorized representative 5. Patients who are intubated and on mechanical ventilation 6. Admitted to ICU 1. Bladder or rectal core temperature below 32C (89.6F) upon admission 2. Clinical brain death 3. Patients with open abdomens. 4. Multiple orthopedic injuries (&gt; 2 long bone fractures) 5. Persistent hypotension (systolic blood pressure &lt; 90mmHg) 6. Persistent hypoxia (O2 Saturation &lt; 94%) 7. Persistent metabolic acidosis (Lactic acid &gt; 5 mmol/L, arterial pH &lt; 7.25) 8. Positive serum pregnancy test 9. Cardiac arrhythmia with deleterious hemodynamic effects; heart block or myocardial damage (as shown on ECG) 10. History of abnormal renal function 11. Significant Comorbidity (i.e. CAD;COPD; severe coagulopathy) 12. Pediatric patients (&lt; 18 years old)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Traumatic</keyword>
	<keyword>Brain</keyword>
	<keyword>Injury</keyword>
</DOC>