<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02859038</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to answer the fundamental question, should the physicians choose Surgery or Chemotherapy (SOC 2) in advanced ovarian cancer?</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Upfront Surgery Versus Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy in Patients With Advanced Ovarian Cancer (SUNNY)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Compare the efficacy and safety in patients with FIGO (2014) stage IIIC or IV epithelial ovarian cancer, fallopian tube cancer, or peritoneal carcinoma treated with neoadjuvant chemotherapy followed by interval debulking surgery versus upfront surgery. OUTLINE: This is a randomized phase III multicenter study. Patients will receive upfront maximal cytoreductive surgery followed by at least 6 cycles of adjuvant chemotherapy or 3 cycles of neoadjuvant chemotherapy followed by interval debulking surgery, and then at least 3 cycles of adjuvant chemotherapy. Patients are followed every 3 months within the first 5 years, and then every 6 months. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 456 patients will be accrued for this study within 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Glandular and Epithelial</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Women aged ≥ 18 years. 2. Pathologic confirmed stage IIIC and IV epithelial ovarian cancer, fallopian tube cancer or primary peritoneal carcinoma (diagnosis by biopsy or fine needle aspiration*). Laparoscopic biopsy with pictures is recommended. * If fine needle aspiration showing an adenocarcinoma, patients should satisfy the following conditions: a. the patient has a pelvic mass, and b. omental cake or other metastasis larger than 2 cm in the upper abdomen, or pathologic confirmed extraabdominal metastasis, and c. serum CA125/CEA ratio&gt;25. If serum CA125/CEA ratio&lt;25 or malignancies of other origins, such as breasts and digestive tract, are suspected from symptoms, physical examinations or imaging diagnosis, endoscopy or ultrasonography should be done to exclusive metastasis ovarian cancer. 3. ECOG performance status of 0 to 2. 4. ASA score of 1 to 2. 5. Adequate bone marrow, liver and renal function to receive chemotherapy and subsequently to undergo surgery: 1. white blood cells &gt;3,000/µL, absolute neutrophil count ≥1,500/µL, platelets ≥100,000/µL, hemoglobin ≥9 g/dL, 2. serum creatinine &lt;1.25 x upper normal limit (UNL) or creatinine clearance ≥60 mL/min according to CockroftGault formula or to local lab measurement, 3. serum bilirubin &lt;1.25 x UNL, AST(SGOT) and ALT(SGPT) &lt;2.5 x UNL. 6. Comply with the study protocol and followup. 7. Written informed consent. 1. Patients with nonepithelial tumors as well as borderline tumors. 2. Mucinous ovarian cancer. 3. Low grade ovarian cancer. 4. Synchronous or metachronous (within 5 years) malignancy other than carcinoma in situ. 5. Any other concurrent medical conditions contraindicating surgery or chemotherapy that could compromise the adherence to the protocol. 6. Other conditions, such as religious, psychological and other factors, that could interfere with provision of informed consent, compliance to study procedures, or followup.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>