<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02859662</DOC>
	<brief_summary>It is an observational study on ruptured abdominal aortic aneurysm and abdominal compartment syndrome. the aim of this study is to assess the qualities of a predictive score on the occurence of this syndrome after surgery of ruptured aortic aneurysm</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Abdominal Compartment Syndrome and Ruptured Aortic Aneurysm : Validation of a Predictive Test</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Despite improved management techniques of ruptured abdominal aortic aneurysm, especially in vascular surgery, the mortality rate has not decreased these last years. The abdominal compartment syndrome (ACS) has been clearly identified as one of the main etiologies of mortality after ruptured aortic aneurysm. The mortality grow up with ACS in this population. So, the investigators want to screen abdominal compartment syndrome in the operative room. It is an observational study on ruptured abdominal aortic aneurysm and abdominal compartment syndrome. the aim of this study is to assess the qualities of a predictive score on the occurence of this syndrome after surgery of ruptured aortic aneurysm Later the aim of a future study will be to screen ACS and manage patient as soon as possible to avoid it.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aortic Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rupture</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Compartment Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intra-Abdominal Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aortic Rupture</mesh_term>
	<criteria>over 18 to be hospitalized in participating hospitals ruptured aneurysm confirmed and operated pregnancy patients with bladder tumor or bladder surgery or trauma bladder can distort bladder pressure measurement cystectomy patients died before arrival in the operating room patients died during surgery or within one hour of the initial surgical procedure patient whose abdominal closure at the end of the procedure is impossible</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>abdominal compartment syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>abdominal aortic aneurysm</keyword>
	<keyword>ruptured aneurysm</keyword>
</DOC>