<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02177474</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In a randomized controlled trial the investigators intended to evaluate the effect of a telephone based peer support intervention on depressed or anxious women with coronary heart disease (CHD). The investigators intended to include 198 depressed or anxious women aged over 18 years with CHD. Participants were randomized to intervention (IG) or waiting list (WL). IG was offered immediate telephone-based contact to peer counselors while WL received the offer with a 6-month delay. All participants got at least one telephone call by a clinical psychologist (study information, feedback about the individual level of distress, proposal to get help). Main outcome variables were depressive symptoms (PHQ-9) and perceived social support (F-SozU K-14). In an additional quasi-experimental trial, the investigators included 11 peer counselors and 11 matched controls not taking part in the intervention. Main outcome variables were mood states (POMS) and perceived social support (F-SozU K-14).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of a Telephone Based Peer Support to Reduce Depressive Symptoms and Improve Social Support in Women With CHD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<criteria>coronary heart disease depressive symptoms (HADS &gt;7) insurants of former Kaufmännische Krankenkasse (KKH)Allianz German speaking at least 18 years old written informed consent hardness of hearing severe somatic illness current severe depressive episode or current suicidal tendency severe mental illness (dementia, psychosis)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>depressive symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>perceived social support</keyword>
	<keyword>coronary heart disease</keyword>
	<keyword>peer support</keyword>
	<keyword>women</keyword>
</DOC>