<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02177786</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of selonsertib (formerly GS-4997) in participants with diabetic kidney disease (DKD). Participants will be randomized with a 1:1:1:1 allocation to receive 1 of 3 doses of selonsertib (2 mg, 6 mg, or 18 mg) or matching placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy, Safety, and Tolerability of Selonsertib (GS-4997) in Participants With Diabetic Kidney Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Nephropathies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Adult male or females with prior diagnosis of Diabetic Kidney Disease Type 2 diabetes mellitus diagnosis for at least 6 months eGFR (MDRD) at screening ≥ 15 mL/min/1.73m^2 to &lt; 60 mL/min/1.73m^2 Urine albumin to creatinine ratio (UACR) as follows: Stage/Stratum 3a: eGFR range 45 to &lt; 60 mL/min; UACR ≥ 600 mg/g Stage/Stratum 3b: eGFR range 30 to &lt; 45 mL/min; UACR ≥ 300 mg/g Stage/Stratum 4: eGFR range 15 to &lt; 30 mL/min; UACR ≥ 150 mg/g Receiving angiotensinconvertingenzyme inhibitor (ACEi) or angiotensin receptor blockers (ARB) at a minimum dose deemed appropriate for the individual by the investigator and be at a stable dose for the last three months o Individuals not on ACEi/ARB may be screened if there is documented intolerance to ACE inhibitor and/or ARB Key Type 1 diabetes mellitus Nondiabetic kidney disease UACR &gt; 5000 mg/g on any measurement during screening End stage renal disease (ESRD; receiving peritoneal dialysis, hemodialysis, or status post renal transplantation) or anticipated to occur within the treatment period Anticipated progression to ESRD (need for dialysis or listing for renal transplantation) within the study treatment period Unstable cardiovascular disease Immunosuppressive drugs Pregnant or lactating females Note: Other protocol defined Inclusion/Exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetic Kidney Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Gilead</keyword>
</DOC>