<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01122927</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label study consisting of a screening period, a conversion/titration phase (Phase 1), an open-label treatment phase (Phase 2), and a follow-up period. The study will enroll new subjects (hereafter referred as "de novo" subjects) with schizophrenia, or bipolar I disorder, manic or mixed episode with or without psychotic features, and rollover subjects with schizophrenia from 31-09-266 (hereafter referred to as "Study 266"). All de novo subjects must enter the screening period of the study. Subjects who are screened and are not required to go through Phase 1 will complete a Phase 2 baseline visit prior to their participation in Phase 2. Study Design: Treatment, Single Group Assignment, Open Label, Active Control, Safety/Efficacy Study</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Tolerability of Aripiprazole in Adolescents With Schizophrenia or Children and Adolescents With Bipolar I Disorder, Manic or Mixed Episode With or Without Psychotic Features.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aripiprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects 1317 years old (Schizophrenia); Subjects 1017 years old (Bipolar manic or mixed episode)* [*Bulgaria will enroll Schizophrenia subjects only.] Subjects with a current diagnosis of schizophrenia, and a history of the illness (diagnosis or symptoms) for at least 6 months prior to screening (as per subject, family, or healthcare provider, or by previous medical records). Subjects with a current diagnosis of bipolar I disorder, manic or mixed episode with or without psychotic features (diagnosis or symptoms) experiencing symptoms for at least 1 week prior to screening. * [*These subjects will not be eligible to enroll in Bulgaria] Subjects who have shown previous response to antipsychotic treatment (other than clozapine) and are not resistant to treatment with other antipsychotics. Subjects who are currently being treated with oral antipsychotics other than clozapine, and are not resistant to treatment with other antipsychotics. Inpatient or outpatient status, with the exception of acute hospitalization due to psychiatric reasons at the time of screening or before Phase 2. All subjects: diagnosis of schizoaffective disorder, autism, pervasive developmental disorder (PDD), OCD, or PTSD. Subjects with schizophrenia: a current major depressive episode. Subjects with bipolar manic or mixed episode: presenting with a clinical picture and/or history that is consistent with a diagnosis of bipolar II disorder or bipolar disorder not otherwise specified. Subjects with delirium, dementia, amnesia or other cognitive disorders; subjects with psychotic symptoms that are better accounted for by another general medical condition(s) or direct effect of a substance (i.e., medication, illicit drug use, etc.). Subjects with any neurological disorder, with the exception of Tourette's syndrome. Subjects experiencing major depressive episode at the time of screening other than subjects diagnosed with bipolar I disorder mixed episode. Subjects who are currently receiving clozapine or have received clozapine at any time in the past are ineligible for entry into the study. Subjects who meet the DSMIVTR criteria for substance dependence (including alcohol and benzodiazepines, but excluding caffeine and nicotine) within the past 180 days prior to screening. Subjects who have epilepsy, a history of seizures (except for a single childhood febrile seizure or posttraumatic seizure), or a history of severe head trauma or stroke, or have a history or current evidence of other unstable medical conditions. Subjects with a history of subclinical hypothyroidism (TSH ≥ 4.0 mIU/L), known hypothyroidism, or hyperthyroidism (unless the condition has been stabilized with medications for at least 90 days prior to entry into Phase 1 or Phase 2). Subjects who have a medical history of uncontrolled diabetes, labile or unstable diabetes (brittle diabetes), newly diagnosed diabetes, or clinically significant abnormal blood glucose levels (defined as fasting blood glucose ≥ 125 mg/dL).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>adolescent</keyword>
	<keyword>bipolar</keyword>
</DOC>