<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01844843</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose of this study is to evaluate, after implantation of a drug eluting stent (DES), coverage of the stent struts by new tissue. The evaluation will be performed by means of intravascular imaging technology (optical frequency domain imaging, OFDI). Renewed tissue coverage over the implanted stent struts prevents direct contact between blood and metal/polymer, which could lead to adverse events: patients need to take blood-thinning drugs to prevent these events. Ous new stent has drug and polymer only on the outside of the stent, and the polymer is degraded by the body leaving a bare metal stent after 3-4 months. This should allow fast coverage of the struts, and might allow to reduce duration of the supportive medical treatment. Our hypothesis is that &lt;20% of the struts remain uncovered at 3 months after implantation, as assessed by OFDI.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Optical Frequency Domain Imaging (OFDI) Assessed Strut Coverage of New Terumo DES</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We will enroll patients with multiple coronary lesions, which, as is routine practice, will be treated with the new DES in 2 sessions (second one approximately 3-5 weeks after the first one). We will assess lesions by OFDI after the implantation and at the time of 3 months follow-up, when we will ask patients to undergo a coronary angiography. Patients will then have a follow-up contact at 1 year after initial implantation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient is at least 18 years old Patients is a suitable candidate for Percutaneous Coronary Intervention (PCI) Patient has multivessel disease with ≥2 denovo lesions in native coronary arteries suitable for treatment with TCD10023 DES Target lesions are suitable for OFDI examination; Patient requires staged procedure between 35 weeks after baseline procedure, according to investigator's judgement Target vessel reference diameter is between 2.5 4.0 mm (visual assessment) Patient has provided written informed consent Patient is affiliated to social security or equivalent system (France only) Patient has known allergy to sirolimus, cobalt, chromium, nickel, or contrast agent (that cannot be adequately premedicated) Patient is not a suitable candidate for use of Dual AntiPlatelet Therapy (DAPT) because of active or recent bleedings or for use of vitamin K antagonist, like warfarin, dabigatran, rivaroxaban or acenocoumarol; Patient is presenting with STsegment elevated MI (STEMI) at baseline procedure Patient has Killipclass &gt; 1 at admission Patient is in cardiogenic shock Patient is a female of childbearing potential Patient has life expectancy of less then 1 year Patient is expected to undergo major surgery within 3 months Patient has Left Main disease ≥ 50% Target lesion at bifurcation requiring 2 stents technique Target lesions are severely calcified Target lesion is located within 3 mm of aortaostium Patient has renal failure defined as estimated Glomerular Filtration Rate (eGFR) &lt;50 mL/min/1.73m² Target lesions require preparation other than balloon predilatation Patient is currently participating in an investigational drug or device study that has not completed the primary endpoint or that clinically interferes with the current study endpoints; Note: Trials requiring extended followup for products that were investigational, but have become commercially available since then, are not considered investigational trials In the Investigator's opinion patient has (a) comorbid condition(s) that could limit the patient's ability to participate in the study, compliance with followup requirements or impact the scientific integrity of the study Patient is under judicial protection (France only)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug eluting stents</keyword>
	<keyword>coronary artery disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Percutaneous Coronary Intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Tomography, Optical Coherence</keyword>
</DOC>