<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01844752</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a 12 week clinical trial in subjects with acne vulgaris. Subjects will be randomized to NVN1000 1% Gel, NVN1000 4% Gel or Vehicle Gel twice daily. Safety, tolerability and efficacy will be assessed over the course of the study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 2, 3 Arm Study of NVN1000 Gel and Vehicle Gel in Subjects With Acne</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multi-center, evaluator and subject blinded, randomized, vehicle-controlled, parallel group, dose-ranging study to be conducted in approximately 150 subjects with acne vulgaris. Subjects who satisfy the entry criteria at the Baseline visit will be randomized to NVN1000 1% Gel, NVN1000 4% Gel or Vehicle Gel in a 1:1:1 ratio. Efficacy assessments will include inflammatory and non-inflammatory lesion counts and investigator global assessments (IGA). Tolerability and safety assessments include cutaneous tolerability evaluation, adverse event collection, physical exams, and laboratory studies. Subjects will return for post-baseline evaluation at Weeks 2, 4, 8, and 12.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Acne Vulgaris</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects with acne vulgaris and at least 20 but no more than 40 inflammatory lesions, 2570 noninflammatory lesions, no more than 2 nodules on the face Baseline IGA score of mild, moderate or severe Women of childbearing potential must agree to use an effective method of birth control during the study and for 30 days after their final study visit Any dermatologic condition or other medical problem that could interfere with clinical evaluation or requires the use of topical or systemic therapy that make evaluations and lesion count inconclusive Female subjects who are pregnant, nursing, or considering becoming pregnant Methemoglobin &gt; 2% at baseline Clinically significant anemia at baseline Use of topical or systemic medications to treat acne Use of medications that make acne worse, associated with methemoglobinemia, or nitric oxide donors</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>acne</keyword>
</DOC>