<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02459756</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Regular consumption of fruits and vegetables may improve human health and reduce the risk of chronic diseases, such as heart disease, certain cancers and type 2 diabetes, but the active components and the underlying mechanisms are poorly understood. Berry fruits are abundant in anthocyanins and this study aims to test the hypothesis that ingestion of an anthocyanin-rich blackcurrant beverage will improve markers of cardiovascular health (health of blood vessels, inflammation and platelet function). Further, the study will investigate the anthocyanin bioavailability from the blackcurrant beverage.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Anthocyanin-rich Blackcurrant and Vascular Function</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ascorbic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citric Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged 3055 years Nonsmoker BMI between 20 30 kg/m2 Generally healthy as established by a 'health and lifestyle' questionnaire and a screening blood sample Blood pressure &lt; 140/90mmHg Total cholesterol &lt; 6.2 mmol/L Fasting glucose &lt; 7.0 mmol/L Diabetes mellitus Heart problems, stroke, vascular disease Inflammatory disease Kidney, liver, pancreas or gastrointestinal diseases Medication for hyperlipidaemia, hypertension, hypercoagulation, inflammatory conditions Asthma Allergies Smokers (social smokers who agree to abstain for 1 month before and during the study not excluded) Taking phytochemical, antioxidant or fish oil supplements (unless willing to stop for the study period) Taking aspirin &gt; 2 times per month and unwilling to abstain from aspirin ingestion for 14 days prior each study visit History of alcohol misuse Consumption of alcohol &gt;21 units (men) or &gt;15 units (women) Vegans Intense aerobic exercise &gt;20 min 3 x per week Participation in another clinical trial Antibiotics in previous 3 months before study Low haemoglobin levels Females who are pregnant, lactating, or if of reproductive age and not using a reliable form of contraception (including abstinence)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>anthocyanins</keyword>
	<keyword>bioavailability</keyword>
</DOC>