<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02459990</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Assess Fetal Mortality and Malformations in Women treated with antihypertensive medication during preganancy. Mother - Child pairs will be analysed in a cohort selected from the UK in the CPRD database. Years covered are 1997 to 2014. Aim is to assess the risk of Antihypertensive treatment in women.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Congenital Malformations and Maternal Use of Anti-hypertensive Medication in the United Kingdom</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Women with chronic hypertension are at risk of experiencing severe complications such as adverse effects of fetal growth, survival, and renal function during pregnancy. General recommendations advocate the treatment of high blood pressure during pregnancy to decrease these risks to the mother and child, with extreme caution. Many studies assessing the risk of congenital malformations in infants whose mothers were treated with anti-hypertensive medication have been inconclusive, in part due to the variability of the original data sources and possibly the robustness of the analyses.2 Studies regarding this health issue have been unable to stratify anti-hypertensive medications sufficiently to truly assess the risk per drug class, Angiotensin II Receptor Antagonists/Blockers (ARBs) and Angiotensin-converting-enzyme inhibitor (ACE inhibitor) in particular.We will attempt to assess the prescription rate of ARBs and ACE inhibitors among women with very high blood pressure in the United Kingdom (UK) and estimate the risk of serious foetal outcomes in women treated with ARBs and/or ACEs and who may also have the following co-morbid conditions: Diabetes Types I or II, Diabetic Nephropathy, and Congestive Heart Failure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Congenital Abnormalities</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antihypertensive Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age and gender</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hypertension malformation fetal mortality</keyword>
</DOC>