<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00937703</DOC>
	<brief_summary>TELEDIAB-2 is a national, multicenter, controlled, randomised trial. The primary objective of the study is to show that during the initiation of a basal insulin treatment , a computerized decision-making system of adaptation of the insulin, coupled to a distance follow-up (thanks to PDAphone or an interactive vocal server (IVS)), is able to improve metabolic control at the end of 4 mouths as compared with conventional care. Main judgment criteria: comparison of HbA1c means of the 2 groups profiting from a telemonitoring system compared to the reference group at 4 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicentric Evaluation of Two Telematics Systems in Type 2 Diabetic Patients in Failure of Oral Treatment and Having to Start Treatment by Basal Insulin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Secondary objectives : 1. - To compare the 2 methods of telemonitoring employed. 2. - To evaluate the speed of the glycemic attack of the objective to the rising, according to the method of follow-up employed. 3. - To evaluate the satisfaction of the patients and the doctors with respect to systems of telemonitoring, and improvement of the quality of life (DQOL).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Type 2 diabetes since more than 3 years and claiming a strict balance glycemic; Patients treated since at least 3 months, by metformin and secreting insulinic (KNOWN or glinide); Patients uncontrolled with HbA1c ≥ 7.5% and &lt; 10% at the inclusion. BMI &lt; 40 ; Patients requiring a insulin treatment Patients agree to start a slow insulin treatment Patients already practising the glycemic selfmonitoring or agree to learn it and practise it; Patients able to include/understand operation and to use the PDAphone and/or the SVI; Patient not taking part in another biomedical research study Patients agree to carry out at least 2 finger sticks per day; More than 18 years, there is no higher age limit. Patients introducing any evolutionary pathology associated and not stabilized, exhibitor with an uncontrolled diabetes during the year to come; Patients in a situation which justifies of a clinical followup diabetologic more frequent than that (quarterly) envisaged by the study Patients requiring a transitory passage to insulin; Patients needing a hospitalization for the adaptation of insulin doses; Patients presenting a cardiologic event Patients presenting a hemoglobinopathy interfering with the proportioning of HbA1c; Patients suffering from drugaddiction, alcoholism or psychological troubles Type 1 or secondary diabetes Patients who don't need strict metabolic objectives; Pregnant or parturient patients person with no freedom.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>