<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="46222">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02504502</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2013-0594</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02504502</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Enhancing Genomic Laboratory Reports to Enhance Communication and Empower Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Enhancing Genomic Laboratory Reports to Enhance Communication and Empower Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Geisinger Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Geisinger Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Current lab reports are designed to communicate results from the laboratory to the provider;
      they are not designed to be accessible to patients. The investigators believe that a new
      type of genomic test report, tailored for patient- as well as provider-use, will enable
      patients to have access to information they can understand allowing them to be more involved
      in the management of their disorders, better navigate the health care system, and make more
      informed decisions about their health and health care in conjunction with their providers.
      This approach has the potential to improve outcomes from both the patient and provider
      perspectives.

      The investigators propose to study the research question, &quot;Can a genomic laboratory report
      tailored for both providers and families of patients improve interpretation of complex
      results and facilitate recommended care by enhancing communication and shared decision
      making?&quot;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The experimental design to be used for this phase of the project is a randomized,
      single-blinded pre- post-intervention trial with crossover. Figure 2 depicts this phase. As
      noted below, the subjects for the study are parents of affected children enrolled in the
      Whole Genome Sequencing (WGS) Clinical Research Pilot Study (study within a study). Parents
      are the appropriate subjects for this study as they have the primary responsibility for the
      care and management of their child(ren) affected with these chronic, rare conditions and
      would be the recipient of communication of test results either from providers (usual care)
      or through the proposed enhanced report (intervention). Both parents are enrolled in the WGS
      study for purposes of the interpretation of the genomic results allowing capture of
      potential differences between fathers and mothers. According to the WGS study protocol all
      results of the WGS testing will be provided by a geneticist and genetic counselor at an
      informing session. At this session, results will be returned and explained, recommendations
      provided and questions answered. Following this session, parents will be consented for
      participation in the proposed study and consenting parents as couples will be randomized to
      either the usual care or intervention groups as randomization at the individual level would
      lead to contamination and spillover if one member of the couple were in the usual care arm
      and the other in the intervention arm. The initial data collection from the chosen survey
      instruments will take place at this time. Care from this point forward will be provided by
      the patient's referring provider although the WGS study team is available for consultation
      as needed. The PI of this study is staffing most of the informing sessions at present
      therefore he will be blinded to the randomization.

      Because the survey instruments, while chosen based on patient input in Phase 1 (process
      described in detail below in choice of outcomes), have not been designed specifically for
      this project, it is possible that important differences between the usual care and
      intervention arms could be missed. To insure capture of all important differences a second
      round of qualitative interviews will take place after the final survey is administered.
      Interviews will be done for approximately 20% of subjects in each arm, or until saturation
      is achieved as in Qualitative A. In addition, since referral providers will have the
      opportunity to interact with patients in both arms, it will be important to capture provider
      perspectives on the two approaches in order to synthesize the experiences of both
      stakeholder groups for use in improving the enhanced report.

      Given that there are a small number of referral providers, attempts will be made to
      interview all of these individuals to maximize data acquisition. Qualitative methods will be
      the same as in Phase I of the study.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Participant</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction and engagement</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Utilize standardized tools (Modified Multi-dimensional Impact of Cancer Risk Assessment-MICRA adapted for genome information, Decision Regret Scale-DRS, Parental Perceptions of Uncertainty Scale-PPUS, Perceived Involvement in Care Scale) for satisfaction and engagement in the routine care vs. enhanced report arms. The routine care participants will crossover to the enhanced report arm after 6 months. Satisfaction and engagement will be re-assessed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Provider satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Semi-structured interviews will be used to determine provider satisfaction with the enhanced report.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient/Provider Communication</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Semi-structured interviews will be used to determine patient and provider communication patterns following use of the enhanced report.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Intellectual Disability</condition>
  <condition>Autism</condition>
  <condition>Multiple Congenital Anomalies</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Routine Clinical Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Those resulting in variants of significance will receive routine clinical care and receive the enhanced genomic report in 6 months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Enhanced Genomic Report</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Those resulting in variants of significance will received routine clinical care and access to the enhanced genomic lab report.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Enhanced Genomic Report</intervention_name>
    <description>Routine clinical care vs. enhanced genomic report</description>
    <arm_group_label>Enhanced Genomic Report</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Routine Clinical Care</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive routine clinical care. After 6 months the participants will also receive the enhanced genomic report.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Routine Clinical Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Research participants who are consented to participate in the WGS Study (#2012-0187).

          -  Providers who have referred participants to the WGS Study (#2012-0187) and who have
             participated in the WGS genomic medicine workgroup or who have participated in the
             WGS Program Oversight Committee.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Participants who are not consented to participate in the WGS Study (#2012-0187)

          -  Providers who have not referred patients to the WGS Study (#2012-0187).

          -  Providers who have not had a relationship with the oversight of the WGS study (#2012-
             0187).
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marc S Williams, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Geisinger Genomic Medicine Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.rarediseasefoundation.org/patient_and_family_support</url>
    <description>Rare Disease Foundation</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Scriver CR, Neal JL, Saginur R, Clow A. The frequency of genetic disease and congenital malformation among patients in a pediatric hospital. Can Med Assoc J. 1973 May 5;108(9):1111-5.</citation>
    <PMID>4704890</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wilson J. Acknowledging the expertise of patients and their organisations. BMJ. 1999 Sep 18;319(7212):771-4. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10488011</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Levy HP, LoPresti L, Seibert DC. Twenty questions in genetic medicine--an assessment of World Wide Web databases for genetics information at the point of care. Genet Med. 2008 Sep;10(9):659-67. doi: 10.1097GIM.0b013e318180639d.</citation>
    <PMID>18978677</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Morgan MA, Driscoll DA, Zinberg S, Schulkin J, Mennuti MT. Impact of self-reported familiarity with guidelines for cystic fibrosis carrier screening. Obstet Gynecol. 2005 Jun;105(6):1355-61.</citation>
    <PMID>15932829</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Giardiello FM, Brensinger JD, Petersen GM, Luce MC, Hylind LM, Bacon JA, Booker SV, Parker RD, Hamilton SR. The use and interpretation of commercial APC gene testing for familial adenomatous polyposis. N Engl J Med. 1997 Mar 20;336(12):823-7.</citation>
    <PMID>9062090</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sandhaus LM, Singer ME, Dawson NV, Wiesner GL. Reporting BRCA test results to primary care physicians. Genet Med. 2001 Sep-Oct;3(5):327-34.</citation>
    <PMID>11545685</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bloom BS. Effects of continuing medical education on improving physician clinical care and patient health: a review of systematic reviews. Int J Technol Assess Health Care. 2005 Summer;21(3):380-5. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16110718</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hammond EH, Flinner RL. Clinically relevant breast cancer reporting: using process measures to improve anatomic pathology reporting. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 1997 Nov;121(11):1171-5.</citation>
    <PMID>9372744</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Laposata ME, Laposata M, Van Cott EM, Buchner DS, Kashalo MS, Dighe AS. Physician survey of a laboratory medicine interpretive service and evaluation of the influence of interpretations on laboratory test ordering. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2004 Dec;128(12):1424-7.</citation>
    <PMID>15578888</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lubin IM, McGovern MM, Gibson Z, Gross SJ, Lyon E, Pagon RA, Pratt VM, Rashid J, Shaw C, Stoddard L, Trotter TL, Williams MS, Amos Wilson J, Pass K. Clinician perspectives about molecular genetic testing for heritable conditions and development of a clinician-friendly laboratory report. J Mol Diagn. 2009 Mar;11(2):162-71. doi: 10.2353/jmoldx.2009.080130. Epub 2009 Feb 5.</citation>
    <PMID>19197001</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Scheuner MT, Hilborne L, Brown J, Lubin IM; members of the RAND Molecular Genetic Test Report Advisory Board.. A report template for molecular genetic tests designed to improve communication between the clinician and laboratory. Genet Test Mol Biomarkers. 2012 Jul;16(7):761-9. doi: 10.1089/gtmb.2011.0328. Epub 2012 Jun 25.</citation>
    <PMID>22731646</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Scheuner MT, Edelen MO, Hilborne LH, Lubin IM; RAND Molecular Genetic Test Report Advisory Board.. Effective communication of molecular genetic test results to primary care providers. Genet Med. 2013 Jun;15(6):444-9. doi: 10.1038/gim.2012.151. Epub 2012 Dec 6.</citation>
    <PMID>23222660</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lerman CE, Brody DS, Caputo GC, Smith DG, Lazaro CG, Wolfson HG. Patients' Perceived Involvement in Care Scale: relationship to attitudes about illness and medical care. J Gen Intern Med. 1990 Jan-Feb;5(1):29-33.</citation>
    <PMID>2299426</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cella D, Hughes C, Peterman A, Chang CH, Peshkin BN, Schwartz MD, Wenzel L, Lemke A, Marcus AC, Lerman C. A brief assessment of concerns associated with genetic testing for cancer: the Multidimensional Impact of Cancer Risk Assessment (MICRA) questionnaire. Health Psychol. 2002 Nov;21(6):564-72.</citation>
    <PMID>12433008</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chung WW, Chen CA, Cupples LA, Roberts JS, Hiraki SC, Nair AK, Green RC, Stern RA. A new scale measuring psychologic impact of genetic susceptibility testing for Alzheimer disease. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord. 2009 Jan-Mar;23(1):50-6.</citation>
    <PMID>19266699</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mishel MH. Parents' perception of uncertainty concerning their hospitalized child. Nurs Res. 1983 Nov-Dec;32(6):324-30.</citation>
    <PMID>6567851</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>DuBenske LL, Burke Beckjord E, Hawkins RP, Gustafson DH. Psychometric evaluation of the Health Information Orientation Scale: a brief measure for assessing health information engagement and apprehension. J Health Psychol. 2009 Sep;14(6):721-30. doi: 10.1177/1359105309338892.</citation>
    <PMID>19687109</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brehaut JC, O'Connor AM, Wood TJ, Hack TF, Siminoff L, Gordon E, Feldman-Stewart D. Validation of a decision regret scale. Med Decis Making. 2003 Jul-Aug;23(4):281-92.</citation>
    <PMID>12926578</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>O'Connor AM. Validation of a decisional conflict scale. Med Decis Making. 1995 Jan-Mar;15(1):25-30.</citation>
    <PMID>7898294</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Emery AEH, Rimoin DL. 1990. Principles and Practice of Medical Genetics, Second Edition. New York, Churchill Livingstone</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 17, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 7, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Geisinger Clinic</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marc S. Williams</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director, Genomic Medicine Institute</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Whole Genome Sequencing</keyword>
  <keyword>Laboratory Report</keyword>
  <keyword>Patient Centered</keyword>
  <keyword>Communication of Results</keyword>
  <keyword>Patient Provider Communication</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Intellectual Disability</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Congenital Abnormalities</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Abnormalities, Multiple</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
