<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00191282</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective was to demonstrate a difference between two insulin strategies, one targeting postprandial (PP) hyperglycemia and the other targeting fasting and interprandial hyperglycemia, on time until the first combined adjudicated cardiovascular (CV) event (primary outcome defined as CV death, nonfatal myocardial infarction [MI], nonfatal stroke, coronary revascularization, or hospitalized acute coronary syndrome).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hyperglycemia and Cardiovascular Outcomes With Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effect of two different treatment strategies on CV outcomes in patients with type 2 diabetes while aiming to achieve and maintain HbA1c &lt;7.0% in both groups. Only patients who have recently experienced an acute MI will be considered for participation in this trial.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperglycemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isophane insulin, beef</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Lispro</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Glargine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isophane Insulin, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Isophane</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Are at least 30 years old Have had type 2 diabetes for at least 3 months prior to Visit 1 Were admitted to the Coronary Care Unit (CCU) within 18 days prior to Visit 1 for an acute MI Are capable and willing to do specified study procedures Have given informed consent to participate in the study in accordance with local regulations Were on one of the following therapies prior to admission to the CCU for the recent MI: a)diet therapy only and have glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1c) &lt;1.15 times the upper limit of normal or b) an intensive basal/bolus insulin regimen Are using any oral antihyperglycemic medication at the time of Visit 2 and are unwilling to stop the use of such medication for the duration of the study Have substantial myocardial damage, which would significantly outweigh the potential benefit of the treatment strategies for diabetes Have the most severe form of congestive heart failure Have liver disease so severe that it precludes the patient from following and completing the protocol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>MI</keyword>
	<keyword>heart attack</keyword>
</DOC>