<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02228421</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase IV multicenter trial to evaluate the pharmacoeconomic (PE) impact of crizotinib and its companion diagnostic test used in a real-life setting in advanced ALK-positive non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) patients. NSCLC represent 80% of all new cases of lung cancer. One molecular subtype of NSCLC is the ALK-positive subtype. The anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK) is a transmembrane receptor tyrosine kinase. Activation of ALK occurs through the formation of gene fusions and in NSCLC, the gene fusion partner for ALK is primarily EML4. The resulting fusion protein is capable of activating the ALK kinase domain, leading to cell growth. The estimated prevalence for ALK rearrangements in NSCLC is 3-5%, and is more commonly found amongst patients with adenocarcinoma histology, in never smokers and in those who are known to be wild type for EGFR and KRAS. Crizotinib is a potent inhibitor of ALK and is approved for the treatment of advanced ALK+ NSCLC patients. This is an example of personalized medicine, where patients are selected for treatment based upon a molecular assay, and are provided a specific therapy (crizotinib) for their disease. The pharmacoeconomic impact of using genetic information in early treatment decisions in NSCLC has not been determined. The study will enable real-life Heath Economics and Outcome Research (HEOR). Approximately 90 patients will be recruited. Patients will be asked to complete quality-of-life questionnaires at regular intervals in a real-life setting of treatment with crizotinib.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate Real-world Pharmacoeconomics of Crizotinib in NSCLC Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Crizotinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with histologically confirmed locally advanced or metastatic NSCLC Presence of the ALKfusion oncogene (ALK+) as determined using a validated testing platform Planned first or secondline treatment with crizotinib Signed and dated IRBapproved informed consent document Ability to read and understand English or French 18 years of age or older</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>