<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02228031</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this project is to investigate the possible effect of intranasally administered Oxytocin (OT) on specific mirror neuron areas in human brain. The mirror neuron system (MNS) is thought to be involved in action perception and understanding, and may also underlie more complex cognitive processes such as imitation. We will use electroencephalographic (EEG) investigations to examine brain activity while participants complete two different tasks, consisting of the observation and imitation of emotional facial expressions (video presented) and the observation and execution of simple grasping actions (live presented), respectively. In addition, before the beginning of the EEG recording session, subjects will be randomly assigned to two different groups (Oxytocin or Placebo group) and will receive a dose of either intranasal Oxytocin or Placebo solution. Oxytocin is a polypeptide hormone that plays a critical role in social behavior. We will identify mu and beta rhythm from the ongoing EEG and examine suppression as a function of emotion and goal directed action perception and imitation/execution.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Oxytocin, Emotions and Mirror Neurons</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Oxytocin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Righthand dominant Sufficient spoken English so as to be able to complete testing validly and give informed consent Currently taking any psychotropic or cognition enhancing medication History of schizophrenia or any other psychotic disorder, including Bipolar Disorder Family history of psychosis Neurological disease or clinically significant head injury Physical disability that substantially impairs motor function Current diagnosis of polydypsicinduced hyponatremia Substance dependence or abuse in the past 6 months</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mirror neurons</keyword>
	<keyword>Imitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Oxytocin</keyword>
</DOC>