<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02228759</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients scheduled to undergo total knee arthroplasty will receive motor sparing knee blocks with continuous adductor canal block along with multimodal analgesia started pre-operatively and continued into the postoperative period. The study will evaluate the feasibility of home discharge within the first 24 hours following total knee arthroplasty. We will also evaluate the pain scores in the first 5 days following the surgery, causes of delayed discharge and any adverse events.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ambulatory Continuous Adductor Canal Block to Facilitate Same Day Discharge Following Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Pilot Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male and females of 4070years of age 2. Scheduled to undergo unilateral primary total knee arthroplasty 3. ASA Class I, II 1. ASA 3, 4 2. Revision surgery 3. Narcotic dependent (opioid intake morphine equivalent &gt; 10 mg/ day for more than 3 months) 4. Other sources of chronic pain like fibromyalgia 5. Patients with associated significant cardiac, CNS or respiratory disease (poor cardiorespiratory reserve) 6. Major conduction defects in EKG (bifascilular block, CHB); significant valvular heart disease 7. Recent MI/ Stroke/ CHF (in the past 3 months) 8. BMI&gt; 35 9. Obstructive sleep apnea (AHI &gt; 15) 10. Patients with coexisting hematological disorder or with deranged coagulation parameters. 11. Patients with preexisting major organ dysfunction such as hepatic and renal failure. 12. Psychiatric illnesses 13. Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus 14. Lack of informed consent. 15. Allergy to any of the drugs used in the study 16. Preoperative neurological deficits 17. Use of walking aids preoperatively 18. Living alone (Lack of Chaperone/home help) 19. Language barrier 20. Contralateral leg weakness 21. Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ambulatory home regional</keyword>
	<keyword>adductor canal block</keyword>
	<keyword>Postoperative pain</keyword>
	<keyword>total knee arthroplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Home regional</keyword>
	<keyword>Fast track arthroplasty</keyword>
</DOC>