<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02813096</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is to investigate the efficacy and safety of Folfox4 chemotherapy regimen to prevent early recurrence for hepatocellular carcinoma patients with portal vein tumor thrombus following curative resection</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Folfox4 Chemotherapy Regimen to Prevent Early Postoperative Recurrence for HCC-PVTT Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Curative resective is well-accepted as the predominant treatment for hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) patients. Unfortunately, the long-term prognosis remains poor due to frequent postoperative recurrence, especially in HCC patients with portal vein tumor thrombus (PVTT). When PVTT invades into the portal vein system, tumor cell spreads and distributes along with the portal vein and its branches,thus resulting in intra-hepatic micro-metastasis which contributes to early recurrence for patients following curative resection. Postoperative adjuvant interventions include TACE, antiviral therapy, immunotherapy, local radiotherapy were applied to prevent recurrence. However, the efficacy and safety of these regimens remains unsatisfactory. Thus new therapeutic strategy remains to be investigated. This study is to investigate the efficacy and safety of Folfox4 chemotherapy regimen to prevent early recurrence for HCC patients with PVTT following curative resection.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients undergo curative resection HCC with PVTT is confirmed by pathological examination patients undergo chemotherapy of Folfox4 regimen patients without recurrence within the first month after curative resection residual hepatic function is Childpugh A or B which is capable to tolerate chemotherapy patients without other postoperative adjuvant treatments including TACE, radiotherapy, immunotherapy Multipal intrahepatic or outrahepatic tastasis within the first month after curative resection patients with residual hepatic function Childpugh C is not capable to tolerate chemotherapy patients undergo postoperative adjuvant treatments except chemotherapy of Folfox4 regimen patients with badly chemotherapy complications who can finish the whole Folfox4 treatment course</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HCC</keyword>
	<keyword>PVTT</keyword>
	<keyword>Folofox4</keyword>
	<keyword>Early Recurrence</keyword>
</DOC>