<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02968836</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Assessment of the Safety and efficacy of an amino acid blend on muscle and gut functionality in Intensive Care Unit (ICU) patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of an Amino Acid Blend on Muscle and Gut Functionality in ICU Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This monocentric trial will be a parallel, randomized, double-blind, controlled study. Patients hospitalized in the ICU for sepsis will be enrolled. The treatment group (n=15) will be administered the study product (amino acid blend) and the negative control group (=15) will be administrated maltodextrin only. The mode of administration is nasogastric probe. The treatment period is 21 days. Subject will be followed during stay in High care and intermediate care units up to 2 months or after hospital discharge with a follow up until 12 months. Recruitment will stop when 30 patients (15 in each group) have reached V4.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Patients aged 18 and over 2. Sepsis patients: expected to stay at least 21 days in ICU (or midcare), to the opinion of the investigator 3. Documented infection with a Sequential Organ Failure Assessment (SOFA) score of 2 points or more 4. Informed consent signed by the patient or/and by his/her representative 1. Patient with muscle mass loss due to previous hospitalization 2. Intolerance to enteral feeding 3. Patients using parenteral feeding 4. Chronic renal failure to the opinion of the investigator 5. Chronic liver disease to the opinion of the investigator 6. Chronic intestinal disease (Inflammatory Bowel disease IBD,Crohn's, ulcerative colitis) 7. Current treatment with chemotherapy of radiotherapy for cancer 8. Cachectic patients 9. Current treatment with paralyzing drugs 10. No pacemaker or metal implants interacting with MRI and magnetic stimulation 11. Pregnant woman (known) 12. Persons without social security 13. Under guardianship 14. Currently participating or having participated in another clinical trial within 4 weeks prior to trial start 15. Patient who is expected not to comply with the study procedures, to the opinion of the investigator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>