<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02968992</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate how apolactoferrin (an iron-depleted form of lactoferrin) may improve mobility and memory in older adults with chronic inflammation. Lactoferrin, a known anti-inflammatory agent found in milk, has recently been made available in a controlled, pharmaceutical grade capsule. As part of this double blinded and randomized study, participants will take daily dosages of lactoferrin or its matched placebo. To measure the effects of lactoferrin on chronic inflammation and ultimately on improving mobility and memory over 6 months, participants will provide blood samples and complete physical and cognitive tests. By measuring biomarkers in the blood as well as changes in physical and cognitive measures, the investigators will gain an understanding of how lactoferrin may improve chronic inflammation in older adults, and an understanding of whether improving chronic inflammation will improve cognitive and physical function.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of rhLactoferrin on Chronic Inflammation in the Elderly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 70 and older able to complete 4 meter timed walk; walking speed &lt;1.0 m/sec serum IL6 level ≥ 2.5 pg/ml or TNFR1 level ≥1500 pg/ml Daily antiinflammatory drug use (prednisone, Advil, Aleve, Remicade, Enbrel, methotrexate, standing nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAID), aspirin greater than 325 mg per day) lower extremity mobility disability caused by Parkinson's disease, cerebral vascular accident (CVA) with residual motor deficit, severe osteoarthritis or rheumatoid arthritis symptomatic claudication hospitalization within 3 months for myocardial infarction (MI), angina, infection requiring antibiotics, or joint replacement. MiniMental State Examination (MMSE) &lt; 21. Lactose intolerant allergy or intolerance to bovine products being a vegan (since vegans will want to avoid Bovine products.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>70 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>