<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02968784</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is intended to show that ExAblate™ MRgFUS is a safe procedure that can significantly postpone or eliminate the need of patients with organ confined intermediate risk prostate cancer to undergo a definitive treatment (i.e., Radical Prostatectomy or Radiation therapy) for their disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Focal ExAblate MR-Guided Focused Ultrasound Treatment for Management of Organ-Confined Intermediate Risk Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will evaluate the proportion of patients with organ-confined intermediate risk prostate cancer (OC-IRPC) undergoing focal ExAblate™ MRgFUS prostate treatment that will be free of clinically significant PCa which requires definitive treatment at 2 years after completion of their ExAblate™ treatment and to demonstrate the safety of focal ExAblate™ MRgFUS treatment. Clinically significant PCa requiring definitive treatment is defined as pathology findings from whole-gland, imaging-guided, extended mapping biopsy of Gleason Score (GS) &gt; 7 The primary efficacy endpoint in this trial, measured at 24 months with whole-gland extended imaging-guided mapping biopsy, is Response scored dichotomously for each subject as follows: - Response = 0 ("Failure"): Positive mapping biopsy defined as Gleason Score &gt; 7 (indicating definitive treatment) in any part of their prostate gland - Response = 1 ("Success"): Negative mapping biopsy defined as Gleason Score &lt; 7. Safety of ExAblate™ treatment will be determined by evaluation of the incidence and severity of device related complications from the first treatment day visit throughout entire follow-up duration. All adverse events will be captured and recorded. However, the safety of the ExAblate™ treatment will be defined by the incidence and severity of treatment or device related adverse events, grades III - V (CTCAE version 4.03; 2010-06-14). Secondary Effectiveness Outcomes: 1. % of patients with negative 5-month follow-up biopsy results in the treated part of the prostate 2. Treatment effect on patients' Quality of Life (QoL), the following validated self-reported urogenital functioning assessment instruments will be used before and following treatment at pre-specified intervals. 1. Urinary symptoms - IPSS 2. Urinary continence - ICIQ-UI-SF 3. Sexual function - IIEF-15 3. PSA levels and post-treatment PSA kinetics will also be assessed</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male ≥ 50 years old 2. Life expectancy &gt; 10 years 3. Prostate volume &lt; 60 cc 4. PSA ≤ 20 ng/ml 5. Histologically proven PCa on imagingguided transrectal or transperineal extended mapping biopsy 6. Based on imagingguided extended mapping biopsy: 1. T1T2b (positive foci detected in a single side of the prostate) 2. Gleason Score of at least one focus will be: 7 (=3+4 or 4+3; no Gleason 5 pattern) 3. Additional foci may be found in the same lobe, and may be of Gleason≤7 (up to 3+4 or 4+3; no Gleason 5 pattern) 4. N0,M0 7. Index lesion (of Gleason 7) must be visible on MRI 8. Maximal diameter of any cancerous focus is 20mm, on MRI 9. Maximal tumor length in contact with the prostate capsule is 5mm 10. No extracapsular extension 11. No involvement of the seminal vesicles 12. Patient weight &lt; 113 Kg 13. Patient eligible for epidural or general anesthesia (as assessed by an anesthesiologist) 14. Patient willing and able to give consent and attend all study visits as defined in the protocol. 1. Biopsy confirmed or MRI suspected lesion on the contralateral side of the prostate at screening 2. ASA status &gt; 2 3. Any Contraindication to MRI, such as: 3.1. Oversize limitations avoiding patient's positioning in the bore of MRI scanner 3.2. Claustrophobia 3.3. Implanted ferromagnetic materials or foreign objects 3.4. Known contraindication to utilization of MRI contrast agent (e.g., Gadolinium/Magnevist) 4. Severely abnormal coagulation (INR&gt;1.5) 5. Patient with unstable cardiovascular status including: 5.1. Unstable angina pectoris on medication 5.2. Documented myocardial infarction within 90 days prior to enrolment 5.3. Congestive heart failure NYHA class IV 5.4. Unstable arrhythmia status, already on antiarrhythmic drugs 5.5. Severe hypertension (diastolic BP &gt; 100 on medication) 5.6. Severe cerebrovascular disease (multiple CVA or CVA within the last 6 months) 6. History of prostatectomy, radiation therapy to the pelvis for any other malignancy, brachytherapy, Cryotherapy, USguided HIFU, orchiectomy, prostate photodynamic therapy, or prostate cancerspecific chemotherapy. 7. Patients with apical index lesion that cannot be treated with tumor free margins while preserving at least 10mm of their urethral sphincter. 8. Patient under androgen deprivation therapy (ADT), alpha reductase inhibitors, and/or other hormonal treatment within the past 6 months 9. Any rectal disease, pathology, anomaly, injury, previous treatment, or scarring which could change acoustic properties of the rectal wall, or might prevent safe probe insertion (e.g., inflammatory bowel disease, fistula, stenosis, fibrosis, or symptomatic hemorrhoids) 10. History of an invasive malignancy other than basal or squamous skin cancers in the last 5 years 11. Existing urethral or bladder neck contracture/stricture 12. Patient with baseline symptoms of incontinence, defined as score of &gt; 3 in the ICIQSF Questionnaire 13. Active UTI 14. Prostatitis NIH categories I, II and III 15. Implant near (&lt;1cm) the prostate 16. Inability to avoid injury of any of the urethral sphincters or the bladder neck during treatment due to vicinity of detected cancer. 17. Calcification of 2 mm or more in largest diameter neighboring the rectal wall (in a distance of less than 5 mm from the rectal wall) potentially interfering with the acoustic beam path. 18. Interest in future fertility 19. Current participation in another clinical investigation of a medical device or a drug or has participated in such a study within 30 days prior to study enrollment.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prostate Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>MRgFUS</keyword>
	<keyword>ExAblate</keyword>
	<keyword>Focused Ultrasound</keyword>
</DOC>