<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01285076</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multi-center, observational, retrospective and cross-sectional study to be conducted in a cohort of consecutively selected participants with Type 2 diabetes mellitus (DM) who have been treated with sulphonylurea (SU) monotherapy or SU + metformin (MF) combination therapy by their cardiologist, nephrologist, neurologist, or family practice doctor for at least 6 months prior to Study Enrollment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Low Blood Sugar Events in Participants With Diabetes (MK-0431-401)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants diagnosed with Type 2 DM. Participants at least 30 years of age at time of Type 2 DM diagnosis. Participants treated with SU monotherapy or SU + MF combination therapy for at least 6 months prior to enrollment. Participants receiving diabetes care from a cardiologist, nephrologist, neurologist, or family practice doctor for at least 6 months. Participants with a clinical record in the health care center. Participants in whose medical records a minimum core data set can be found; core data defined as: age, gender, duration of diabetes/age at diagnosis, all glucoselowering medications (branded and generic names, dosage, dosing frequency, starting and stopping dates) since the start of all antihyperglycemic medications. Participants with Type 1 DM. Participants who are pregnant or with gestational DM. Participants receiving any antidiabetic treatment from an endocrinologist/diabetologist in the previous 6 months. Participants requiring daily concomitant usage of insulin. Participants receiving any oral diabetes medications other than SU or SU + MF. Participants who are already participating in a clinical trial or other clinical study. Participants for whom it would be impossible to complete the questionnaire.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>