<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03100721</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic musculoskeletal pain (CMP) is highly prevalent, disabling and with high socio-economic costs, with many negative effects on quality of life. CMP affects the ability to perform work, social, recreational and domestic tasks by changing the mood and concentration of this population that suffers. In a study carried out in 2010, 17% of the Spanish population had experienced pain in the last month and according to the severity of symptoms 12% felt severe , 64% moderate and 24% mild pain. In this same study it is specified that 61% was due to back pain, 29% due to neck pain and 23% due to shoulder pain. Pain neuroscience education (PNE) has been shown as an effective treatment strategy in increasing knowledge and understanding of neurobiology, neurophysiology and pain processing, modifying beliefs about it, improving patient skills and encouraging to the accomplishment of physical and social activities in different chronic pathologies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Pain Neuroscience Education in Chronic Musculoskeletal Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study design and setting: The design of the present study will be a randomized controlled trial with 2 follow-ups (ten days and three months after intervention) that will be performed between May 2017 and June 2017 in public health system in Malaga, Spain. The outcomes will be assessed at baseline (t1), ten days after intervention (t2), and three months after intervention (t3). Written informed consent will be acquired for all participants prior to their participation. The study will be implemented and reported in line with the CONSORT statement.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age between 1865 years Willing and able to participate Diagnosis of Chronic Musculoskeletal Pain Systemic disorders Medical history of severe trauma or trauma in the last 6 months Significant changes in pharmacological treatment Participating in another clinical trial Unable to understand spanish spoken and written</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Musculoskeletal diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain Neuroscience Education</keyword>
	<keyword>Physiotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>