<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00544219</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Studying PET scans given to patients with cancer who are undergoing treatment may help doctors predict how patients will respond to treatment. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is studying PET scans in patients with diffuse large B-cell lymphoma who are receiving rituximab together with cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, vincristine, and prednisone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PET Scans in Patients With Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma Receiving Rituximab, Cyclophosphamide, Doxorubicin, Vincristine, and Prednisone</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - To evaluate if an early positive positron emission tomography (PET) scan after 2 courses of rituximab with cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin hydrochloride, vincristine, and prednisone can be used to identify a group of patients having a poor prognosis. Secondary - To compare modified PET/CT scan response criteria with revised standard response criteria. - To evaluate, in a prospective manner, whether a proliferation-inducing ligand (APRIL) expression is a prognostic factor in patients treated with this regimen. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients receive rituximab IV, cyclophosphamide IV, doxorubicin hydrochloride IV, and vincristine IV on day 1 and oral prednisone on days 1-5. Treatment repeats every 14 days for up to 6 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Rituximab IV alone is continued for an additional 2 courses after completion of the initial 6 courses. Patients undergo positron emission tomography (PET) scan prior to and after completion of study therapy. Patients also undergo PET scan after course 2, and those with a positive PET result undergo an additional PET scan after course 4. Previously collected tumor samples are analyzed for a proliferation-inducing ligand (APRIL) expression. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed periodically for up to 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vincristine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Inclusion criteria: Histologically confirmed diagnosis of CD20+ diffuse large Bcell lymphoma (DLBCL) Stage IIV disease All IPI risk groups Must be positron emission tomography (PET)positive At least one measurable lesion ≥ 15 mm in its shortest axis (greatest transverse diameter) for jugulodigastric and infracarinal lymph nodes with CT scan (MRI is allowed only if CT scan cannot be performed) Otherwise the shortest axis (greatest transverse diameter) must be ≥ 10 mm Lesions should be selected according to the following features: Clearly measurable in two perpendicular dimensions From as disparate regions of the body as possible Include mediastinal and retroperitoneal areas of disease whenever these sites are involved Exclusion criteria: Secondary DLBCL (in transformation) Evidence of symptomatic CNS disease PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Inclusion criteria: ECOG or WHO performance status 02 Cardiac ejection fraction ≥ 50% as assessed by echocardiography Sufficient hematological values, hepatic and renal function Patient condition, compliance, and geographic proximity must allow proper staging and completion of treatment and followup Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 12 months after completion of study therapy Exclusion criteria: Prior or concurrent hematological malignancies Patients who have had prior solid organ tumors that required no treatment over the past 5 years and are currently diseasefree are allowed Unstable cardiac disease within the past 6 months Any serious underlying medical condition (at the judgment of the investigator) that could impair the ability of the patient to participate in the study (e.g., active autoimmune disease, uncontrolled diabetes, HIV and hepatitisinfection) Known hypersensitivity to any component of the study drugs PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Exclusion criteria: Prior chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or immunotherapy (e.g., rituximab) for lymphoma Prior anthracycline treatment Concurrent radiotherapy Concurrent regular corticosteroids in the past 4 weeks Doses ≤ 20 mg/day of prednisone for indications other than lymphoma or lymphomarelated symptoms allowed Concurrent drugs contraindicated for use with the study drugs according to the Swissmedicapproved product information Other concurrent experimental drugs or other anticancer therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>contiguous stage II adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>noncontiguous stage II adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>