<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00040092</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Virulizin is an immunotherapy drug preparation that is thought to stimulate the patient's immune system, which in turn may slow the growth of tumors. It is presented in vials as a sterile preparation for IM injection. The purpose of the trial is to investigate if Virulizin in combination with gemcitabine provides better efficacy than gemcitabine alone (with placebo) against pancreatic cancer.Virulizin® efficacy will continue to be assessed if chemotherapy is changed to 5-Fluorouracil.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Test the Effectiveness of Virulizin® Given in Combination With Standard Chemotherapy for Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Phase III, Double-blind, Multicenter, Randomized Study in Chemonaive Patients with Locally Advanced or Metastatic Pancreatic Cancer to Compare a Combination Therapy of Virulizin® plus Gemcitabine versus Placebo plus Gemcitabine; Optional Secondline Therapy may Include Continuation of Virulizin® or Placebo, Alone or in Combination with 5-Fluorouracil. Patients who have not received any prior chemotherapy will be randomized to receive Gemcitabine plus Virulizin® versus Gemcitabine plus placebo in a double blind fashion. On disease progression patients may be switched to 5-Fluorouracil and continue to receive Virulizin® or placebo. Patients may continue Virulizin® alone, if clinically indicated when 5-Fluorouracil is discontinued.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with advanced (unresectable or metastatic) pancreatic adenocarcinoma (TNM stages II, III or IV) No previous systemic chemotherapy(unless given as a radiosensitizer). ECOG Performance Status 02 Life expectancy equal to or greater than 12 weeks Adequate laboratory and organ functions Stabilizable pain (stable analgesic intake) No radiotherapy during 4 weeks prior to trial entry No evidence of ascites, pleural effusion or third space fluid accumulation Not currently using, and have not used in 4 weeks prior to entering trial, systemic steroids or hormonal therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Virulizin</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Pancreas</keyword>
	<keyword>Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>clinical trial</keyword>
</DOC>