<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01689714</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The folate receptor is overexpressed in many types of cancer, including ovarian and endometrial cancer, and the level of folate receptor expression increases with the stage of the disease. Technetium Tc 99m EC20 (99mTc-EC20; FolateScan), a folate-targeted diagnostic radiopharmaceutical, is designed to bind to the folate receptor. Thus, FolateScan may provide an effective method to determine folate receptor-positive (FR+) target tumors, thereby assisting in the identification of those patients who may benefit from folate-targeted therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Folatescan (Technetium TC 99M EC20) in Patients With Suspected Ovarian Carcinoma or Recurrent Endometrial Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This phase 2, two-center, open-label, single-treatment group, within-patient-controlled study was conducted to: - Expand the safety database and gather data on the percentage of patients with known or suspected ovarian carcinoma or recurrent endometrial carcinoma who show increased uptake of FolateScan in tumors (primary objective). - Calculate the sensitivity, specificity, accuracy, positive predictive value, and negative predictive value of FolateScan compared with immunohistochemical (IHC) staining (secondary objective).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Glandular and Epithelial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Technetium Tc 99m-ethylenedicysteine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must meet the following eligibility requirements to be enrolled in the study. 1. Subject must be 18 years of age or older. 2. Subject must have known or strongly suspected ovarian carcinoma or recurrent endometrial carcinoma with at least one identifiable lesion &gt; 1.5 cm as diagnosed by ultrasonography, MRI, or CT. 3. Subject must have good kidney function. 4. Subject must provide written informed consent prior to enrollment. Subjects must be excluded if any of the following conditions are present: 1. Subject is pregnant or breastfeeding. 2. Subject is simultaneously participating in another investigational drug study. 3. Subject has completed the followup phase of any previous study less than 30 days prior to enrollment in this study. 4. Subject is unable to tolerate conditions for radionuclide imaging. 5. Subject has been administered another radiopharmaceutical that would interfere with the assessment of Technetium Tc 99m EC20.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ovarian Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Recurrent Endometrial Carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>