<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01689506</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical study compares two fluid resuscitation treatments in patients suffering from burns injury. The treatments are Volulyte® and Human Serum Albumin (HSA) which will be administered as infusion solutions. It will be evaluated whether Volulyte® is effective and safe, and provides any benefit.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fluid Resuscitation in Patients Suffering From Burns Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Severe burns injury presents a unique resuscitation problem due to simultaneous loss of electrolyte and protein-rich exudate from the burn wound itself and leakage of fluid and protein from the circulation into the interstitial compartment. In the post shock phase of burn resuscitation, patients frequently suffer oedema of unburned tissues and organs and a positive fluid balance of many litres. This pilot study will compare two burns fluid resuscitation regimes (supplementation with 6% HES 130/0.4 in an isotonic electrolyte solution, Volulyte 6%, versus supplementation with Human Serum Albumin, HSA 50g/L) on patient outcome with particular regard to fluid balance at 24 hours after burns injury (primary variable).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Burns</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxyethyl Starch Derivatives</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patients ≥18 years of age 15%≥ Burn Total Body Surface Area Injury ≤60% Signed written informed consent from patient or legal representative Patient age &gt;80 years Delay of patient randomisation &gt;8 hours postburn Known pregnancy Known renal failure with oliguria or anuria not related to hypovolaemia (e.g. patients receiving dialysis treatment) High voltage electrical conduction injury Known severe liver disease Known fluid overload (hyperhydration), especially in cases of pulmonary oedema and congestive cardiac failure Intracranial bleeding (known active or suspicion of intracranial bleeding)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>