<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02622438</DOC>
	<brief_summary>On the basis of published data and our results indicating that oxidative stress may contribute to the peripheral skeletal muscle dysfunction in patients with FSHD, investigators conducted a pilot randomized double-blind placebo controlled trial to test whether oral administration of vitamins and mineral could improve the physical performance of patients with FSHD.The result of this clinical trial showed that antioxidants supplementation may improve skeletal muscle function of patients with FSHD and suggest that an antioxidant strategy adapted may be a relevant therapeutic approach for these patients. Since then, patients with FSHD who attend consultation at Montpellier hospital are systematically supplemented with antioxidants according their own blood tests.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Routine Health Care of Patients With FSHD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will assess course of patients with FSHD in accordance with usual care performed within the Department of clinical physiology at the University hospital of Montpellier. This prospective longitudinal study include an initial assessment. Then the follow up of patients will be monitored at 6 months and annually for a period of two years. The eventual objective will be to develop a FSHD disease cohort in care at the Montpellier hospital.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Molecular and clinical diagnosis for FSHD patients, men and women aged &lt; 7 years, pregnant women Inability to understand the nature and goals of the study and / or communication difficulties with the investigator Major protected by law (guardianship, curatorship or under judicial protection)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>FSHD</keyword>
	<keyword>Usual care performed at Montpellier hospital</keyword>
	<keyword>Muscle function</keyword>
	<keyword>Antioxidants</keyword>
	<keyword>Oxidative stress</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical activities, development of food-based dietary guidelines</keyword>
	<keyword>Co-morbidity</keyword>
</DOC>