<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01759303</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the 4-month Progression-Free Survival (PFS), with demonstrated increase in tumor doubling time, of eligible subjects treated with pazopanib according to RECIST version 1.1 guidelines.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Pazopanib in the Treatment of Osteosarcoma Metastatic to the Lung</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent or assent Age &gt; or = to 16 years Histologically confirmed diagnosis of osteosarcoma with lung metastasis, who have progressed on the prior line of therapy, or relapsed Ineligible for curative pulmonary metastasectomy Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 02 Measurable disease per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 guidelines. At least one measurable lesion must be in the lungs. Eligible subjects are required to have &gt; or = to 1 line of multiagent chemotherapy either neoadjuvantly or adjuvantly. Subjects may have had 02 lines of therapy for metastatic disease. Measured cardiac ejection fraction &gt; or = to 50% or the institutional lower limit of normal by echocardiogram or MUGA scan. Adequate organ system function. Females must be either nonchild bearing potential or have a negative pregnancy test within 3 to 5 days prior to the first dose of study drug. Children not in the care or custody of a biological parent, adoptive parent, appointed legal guardian, or legally appointed foster care. Prior exposure to VEGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitor (small molecule or antibody) or VEGFR antibody. Prior malignancy. Note: Subjects who have had another malignancy and have been diseasefree for 3 years, or subjects with a history of completely resected nonmelanomatous skin carcinoma or successfully treated in situ carcinoma are eligible. History or clinical evidence of central nervous system (CNS) metastases or leptomeningeal carcinomatosis, unless previously treated, asymptomatic, and off steroids and antiseizure medication for 6 months prior to first dose of study drug Clinically significant gastrointestinal abnormalities that may increase the risk for gastrointestinal bleeding. Clinically significant gastrointestinal abnormalities that may affect absorption of investigational product. Presence of uncontrolled infection. Corrected QT interval (QTc) &gt; 480 msecs using Bazett's formula. History of certain cardiovascular conditions within the past 6 months. Class IIIV congestive heart failure, as defined by the New York Heart Association Poorly controlled hypertension [defined as systolic blood pressure (SBP) of ≥ 140 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure (DBP) of ≥ 90mmHg]. History of cerebrovascular accident including transient ischemic attack (TIA), pulmonary embolism or untreated deep venous thrombosis (DVT) within the past 6 months. Prior major surgery or trauma within 28 days prior to the protocolmandated 4week drug holiday and/or presence of any nonhealing wound, fracture, or ulcer. Evidence of active bleeding or bleeding diathesis. Known endobronchial lesions and/or lesions infiltrating major pulmonary vessels that increase the risk of pulmonary hemorrhage. Hemoptysis of red blood in excess of 2.5 mL (or one half teaspoon) within 8 weeks of first dose of study drug. Any serious and/or unstable preexisting medical, psychiatric, or other condition that could interfere with subject's safety, provision of informed consent/assent, or compliance to study procedures. Unable or unwilling to discontinue use of prohibited medications for at least 14 days or five halflives of a drug, whichever is longer, prior to the first dose of study drug and for the duration of the study treatment. Radiation therapy, minor surgery, tumor embolization, chemotherapy, immunotherapy, biologic therapy, investigational therapy or hormonal therapy within 14 days prior to the protocolmandated 4week drug holiday. Administration of any nononcologic investigational drug within 30 days or five halflives (whichever is longer) prior to the protocolmandated 4week drug holiday. Any ongoing toxicity from prior anticancer therapy that is &gt; Grade 1 and/or that is progressing in severity, except alopecia. Known immediate or delayed hypersensitivity reaction or idiosyncrasy to drugs chemically related to pazopanib or excipients that contraindicates participation. An untreated tumor growth rate of &lt; 6.1% during the Screening period may exclude some patients.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>