<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02446132</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an extension study of the Phase 3 Studies 15-AVP-786-301 and 15-AVP-786-302, which also allows participants from the Phase 2 Study 12-AVR-131 to be included.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long Term, Extension Study of the Safety and Efficacy of AVP-786 (Deuterated [d6] Dextromethorphan Hydrobromide [d6-DM]/Quinidine Sulfate [Q]) for the Treatment of Agitation in Patients With Dementia of the Alzheimer's Type</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participant has successfully completed Studies 15-AVP-786-301, 15-AVP-786-302, or 12-AVR-131. Participants will be enrolled in the study for approximately 52 weeks. Approximately 550 participants will be enrolled at approximately 110 centers in North America. All participants enrolled will receive AVP-786; the treatment dose assigned will be masked to the participant, investigator, study staff, and the sponsor.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychomotor Agitation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dextromethorphan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Quinidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Quinidine gluconate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participant has successfully completed Studies 15AVP786301, 15AVP786302, or 12AVR131 Participants from Study 12AVR131 with a diagnosis of probable AD according to the 2011 National Institute on AgingAlzheimer's Association (NIAAA) working group criteria Either outpatients or residents of an assistedliving facility or a skilled nursing home Participants from Study 12AVR131 who have clinically significant, moderate/severe agitation at least 2 weeks prior to baseline Participants from Study 12AVR131 with a diagnosis of agitation that must meet the International Psychogeriatric Association (IPA) provisional definition of agitation Participants from Study 12AVR131 with a Clinical Global Impression of Change (CGIS) score assessing Agitation of ≥ 4 (moderately ill) at baseline Participants from Study 12AVR131 with a MiniMental State Examination (MMSE) score between 6 and 26 (inclusive) at screening and baseline Participants with coexistent clinically significant or unstable systemic diseases that could confound the interpretation of the safety results of the study (e.g., malignancy, poorly controlled diabetes, poorly controlled hypertension, unstable pulmonary, renal or hepatic disease, unstable ischemic cardiac disease, dilated cardiomyopathy, or unstable valvular heart disease) Participants determined to have a high imminent risk of falls during the study based on a clinical evaluation by the investigator Participants who are currently using or were on NUEDEXTA® in the 4 weeks preceding baseline</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>