<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01595269</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This project addresses the following Null Hypotheses: 1. There will be no difference will be found in the use of the search engine and the information accessed among the three education modes. 2. There will be no difference in education mode's effect on metabolic control, self-care management practices, and medical resource utilization. 3. There will be no difference in the economic impact on the health care system based on differing education modes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Clinical and Economic Impacts of e-Heath on Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In addition to the face-to-face education process currently used at the CHR, this project will develop two modes of eHealth education. Education mode 1 (control) is comprised of participants educated using CHR's current traditional face-to-face delivery method, with printed materials and written log journals. These participants will be trained to use the University's web portal if they elect to access internet-based diabetes information. This allows for the tracking of the type and amounts of diabetes information accessed by participants. Education mode 2 (static interface) participants will be educated using digitized forms of the traditional materials provided by CHR as well as an electronic log journal (e-journal) where participants will record their diabetes-related outcomes and behavioural information. Education mode 2 will be assessed and approved by CHR. Education mode 3 (dynamic interface) participants will be educated using the digitized traditional materials from education mode 2 as well as an enhanced dynamic e-journal (visualization of blood glucose and alerts). In addition, this mode will provide informative disease-related internet sites and diabetes news and articles vetted by the medical team. Participants and health professionals will then be able to electronically discuss the content and quality of this information (discussion board). New sites and articles will be added on an ongoing basis. Participants will also have access to a chat room that will encourage information sharing with other education mode 3 participants and health professionals at CHR. Education mode 3 will be assessed and approved by CHR.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged 18 or older Literate Not participating in other clinical trials Diabetes diagnosed within the last three months Type 2 diabetes No medical conditions that could compromise metabolic control No linguistic, cognitive or psychosocial barriers that would hinder study completion Computer and internet literate Access to highspeed internet Under the age of 18 Not literate Participating in other clinical trials Diabetes diagnosed greater than three months ago Type 1 diabetes Gestational diabetes Additional medical conditions that could compromise metabolic control Linguistic, cognitive or psychosocial barriers that would hinder study completion Not computer and internet literate No access to highspeed internet</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>eHealth</keyword>
	<keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Education</keyword>
	<keyword>Calgary Health Region</keyword>
</DOC>