<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00177996</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research study is being conducted to find out if certain individuals benefit from taking medication for their depression with a low dose of the antidepressant medication Zoloft.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacotherapy in Depression With Panic Spectrum</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Researchers at the University of Pittsburgh Medical Center Health System are currently recruiting men and women, ages 18 to 60, to examine the effectiveness of the FDA-approved medication sertraline (Zoloft) for major depression. Participants will be randomly assigned to one of two groups. Each group will begin and continue taking Zoloft at different doses. A physician will follow eligible participants weekly for approximately 12 weeks</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sertraline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female ages 1860; Current diagnosis of major depression, and a rating of ³15 on the HRSD25; Presence of significant, coexisting panicagoraphobic spectrum symptoms, Absence of ongoing therapy with psychotropic medications (except for intermittent use of nonbenzodiazepine hypnotics) or willingness to be withdrawn from an ineffective ongoing antidepressant medications Physically healthy, Female participants of childbearing potential must be practicing a medically acceptable form of doublebarrier birth control or using oral contraceptives such as birth control pills, implants, or injections; Females who are pregnant or breastfeeding; History of suicide attempt in the 6 months prior to entry, active suicidal ideation, or significant suicide risk; History of hypersensitivity to or current use of sertraline; Unstable or untreated medical conditions, Participants who do not wish to discontinue current, ineffective antidepressant treatment; Participants who have recently begun psychotherapy (less than 3 months prior to study entry); Diagnosis of current panic disorder, psychosis, substance or alcohol abuse, anorexia, bulimia, dissociative, bipolar disorder, or any other psychiatric or medical illness that would interfere with the best treatment strategy for the potential participant.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>depression</keyword>
	<keyword>anxiety</keyword>
</DOC>