<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00177008</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will determine the efficacy of a medication switch to Aripiprazole for the treatment of schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder in patients with moderate to high symptoms of social anxiety. Specifically the study will test the possibility that a medication switch to Aripiprazole reduces symptoms of social anxiety in this patient population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aripiprazole for the Treatment of Schizophrenia With Co-Morbid Social Anxiety</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Although research has shown that social anxiety is very common among patients suffering from schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder, it is rarely diagnosed and treated in this patient population. This study will determine the efficacy of a medication switch to Aripiprazole for the treatment of schizophrenia in patients with moderate to high symptoms of social anxiety. Specifically the study will test the possibility that a medication switch to Aripiprazole reduces symptoms of social anxiety in this patient population. In addition, the study will test the possibility that Aripiprazole significantly improves social adjustment, quality of life and level of functioning in these patients. The study may also assess the ability of Aripiprazole to reduce sexual dysfunction.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phobic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aripiprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 1. Patients meeting DSM IV diagnostic criteria for schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder. 2. Patients presenting with comorbid social anxiety symptoms of moderate to high severity are eligible for participation in the study. Only patients with LSAS scores above 30* qualify for the study. 3. Age 1865 4. Gender: males or females 5. Females: nonpregnant, not of childbearing potential; if of childbearing age must be on contraceptive such as pill or shot (condom alone not sufficient) 6. Good general health 1. Patient does not meet DSM IV diagnostic criteria for schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder 2. Patient carries a diagnosis of dementia, degenerative CNS disorders, mental retardation, substance abuse or dependence other than nicotine dependence or alcohol abuse will be excluded from the study. 3. Patients with acute medical conditions are not eligible. 4. Patients allergic or otherwise intolerant or nonresponsive to Aripiprazole 5. Patient with history of suicidal, homicidal or assaultive plans or attempts in the past 6 months. 6. Clinically significant EKG or lab abnormalities</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Schizoaffective Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Social Anxiety Disorder</keyword>
</DOC>