<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03029481</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Despite improvements in outcomes for patients with localized Ewing sarcoma, patients with relapsed metastatic Ewing sarcoma continue to have poor outcomes with current chemotherapy options. A large body of preclinical data supports a role for IGF-1R inhibition in the treatment of Ewing sarcoma. More recently, clinical trials of IGF-1R monoclonal antibodies have demonstrated single- agent activity in patients with relapsed Ewing sarcoma. Ganitumab (AMG 479) is a fully human monoclonal antibody directed against IGF-1R. We are proposing this single-agent expanded access IND to provide our patient the opportunity to benefit from this treatment after having developed progressive disease after multiple lines of prior therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Single Patient Expanded Access to Ganitumab for Metastatic Ewing Sarcoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Despite improvements in outcomes for patients with localized Ewing sarcoma, patients with relapsed metastatic Ewing sarcoma continue to have poor outcomes with current chemotherapy options. A large body of preclinical data supports a role for IGF-1R inhibition in the treatment of Ewing sarcoma. More recently, clinical trials of IGF-1R monoclonal antibodies have demonstrated single- agent activity in patients with relapsed Ewing sarcoma. Ganitumab (AMG 479) is a fully human monoclonal antibody directed against IGF-1R. We are proposing this single-agent expanded access IND to provide our patient the opportunity to benefit from this treatment after having developed progressive disease after multiple lines of prior therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma, Ewing</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis: Confirmed translocationpositive Ewing sarcoma Organ Function Requirements: Serum creatinine &lt; 1.4 Adequate liver function Total bilitubin &lt;1.5x upper limit of normal for age SGPT (ALT) &lt; 5x upper limit of normal for age Adequate cardiac function &gt; 50% by echocardiogram Bone Marrow Absolute neutrophil count &gt; 750 Platelet count &gt; 75 Female patients of childbearing potential are not eligible unless a negative pregnancy test result has been obtained. Lactating females are not eligible unless they have agreed not to breastfeed their infants for the duration of protocol therapy. Sexually active patients of reproductive potential are not eligible unless they have agreed to use an effective contraceptive method for the duration of protocol therapy. Patients with known preexisting diabetes mellitus will be excluded from study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>48 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>