<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03029923</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Quitting smoking following acute coronary syndrome can reduce mortality up to 50%. However, depression and smoking are highly co-morbid and depressed mood may interfere with cessation and independently predicts mortality. Thus, a single, integrated treatment for both smoking and depression could be highly effective in reducing post-acute coronary syndrome mortality. Behavioral Activation (BA) is a well established treatment for depression and has recently shown promise as a treatment for smoking cessation. The investigators systematically developed an intervention integrating gold standard smoking cessation counseling with existing BA based mood management techniques for post-ACS smokers; Behavioral Activation Treatment for Cardiac Smokers (BAT-CS). Objective: For this R56 the investigators will conduct a vanguard trial to pilot all methods, materials, and systems for the later fully powered BAT-CS vs. attention control trial. The investigators will enroll up to 36 smokers with ACS and randomize them to 12 weeks of BAT-CS or an attention control (Health and Wellness Education). Both groups will be offered the nicotine patch if medically safe.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Integrated Smoking Cessation and Mood Management for ACS Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nicotine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. hospital inpatients with an ACS diagnosis documented in medical record, 2. smoked 1 or more cigarettes per day before being hospitalized, 3. age of 1875, 4. English fluency, 5. lives within a 1 hour drive of the admitting hospital and has no plans to move away from the area for 1 year, 6. willing to consider quitting smoking at discharge, 7. has telephone, and 8. willing to consent to all study procedures. 1. limited mental competency (i.e., Mini Mental Status Exam score ≤ 23); 2. presence of severe mental illness that would interfere with participation (e.g., schizophrenia) or suicidality; 3. expected discharge to hospice; and 4. currently attending counseling for depression or smoking cessation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>smoking</keyword>
	<keyword>depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavioral Activation</keyword>
</DOC>