<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03029988</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to evaluate the use of Tc 99m tilmanocept as an imaging agent in subjects with known active liver metastasis from colorectal carcinoma by comparing previously acquired (within 30 days of tilmanocept injection) FDG PET images .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Tilmanocept by IV Injection and SC Injection vs PET Imaging in Subjects With Liver Metastases.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is designed to evaluate the safety and tolerability of a single dose of Tc 99m tilmanocept administered either subcutaneously or intravenously. SPECT/CT imaging of the subject's abdominal cavity will be reviewed to establish concordance with images previously acquired with FDG PET imaging. This study is designed to evaluate the use of Tc 99m tilmanocept as an imaging agent in subjects with known active liver metastasis from colorectal carcinoma by comparing previously acquired (within 30 days of tilmanocept injection) FDG PET images .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Second Primary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The subject has provided written informed consent with Health Information Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) authorization before the initiation of any studyrelated procedures. Subjects must be ≥18 years old; Have a diagnosis of adenocarcinoma of the colon and/or rectum with FDG PET confirmed metastases to the liver; Subjects must have an ECOG performance status of 03; Subjects must be at least 4 weeks past any major intraabdominal surgery, including surgery to the liver; Subjects with prior malignancies other than colon and/or rectum cancer are allowed, provided they have been treated with curative intent, and have no evidence of recurrence of that malignancy; Each subject must have no more than 10 qualifying liver lesions that have been clinically confirmed metastatic adenocarcinoma of the colon by PET imaging. If of childbearing potential, the subject has a negative pregnancy test within 48 hours before administration of Tc 99m Tilmanocept, has been surgically sterilized, or has been postmenopausal for at least 1 year The subject is pregnant or lactating. The subject has undergone any liver surgery, exclusive of a biopsy. The subject has known sensitivity to dextran. The subject has had preoperative chemotherapy, immunotherapy, or radiation therapy within the 10 days prior to Tc 99m Tilmanocept administration Before the administration of Tc 99m Tilmanocept, has received any radiopharmaceutical within 7 radioactive halflives of that radiopharmaceutical Has received an investigational product within the 30 days prior to Tc 99m Tilmanocept administration</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma, Colorectal Carcinoma, liver metastases</keyword>
</DOC>