<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01414803</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Although the combination of statin and fenofibrate is one of the options for patients with combined hyperlipidemia, non-lipid effects of it has not been completely understood yet. In this study we compared the effects of rosuvastatin 10 mg/fenofibrate 160 mg combination and rosuvastatin 10 mg monotherapy on muscle and liver enzyme, homocysteine levels, kidney, blood glucose control, and blood cell counts.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tolerability and Efficacy of Rosuvastatin - Fenofibrate Combine Therapy in Korean Patients With Combined Hyperlipidemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hyperlipidemias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fenofibrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rosuvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>mixed hyperlipidemia: total cholesterol levels higher than 220 mg/dL, triglyceride (TG) levels between 200 and 500 mg/dL, and lowdensity lipoprotein (LDL)cholesterol levels higher than 130 mg/dL after 6week diet/life style change Men and women who were between 20 and 70 years of age Having at least one history of: coronary artery disease, cerebrovascular disease or transient ischemic attack, peripheral vascular disease, or diabetes mellitus. Having risk factors at least two of: age ≥45 years in male or ≥55 years in female, elevated blood pressure (systolic blood pressure ≥130 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure ≥85 mmHg, or treatment of previously diagnosed hypertension), highdensity lipoprotein (HDL)cholesterol &lt;40 mg/dL, family history of coronary artery disease at age &lt;55 years in male or &lt;65 years in female, central obesity (waist circumference ≥90 cm for male or ≥80 cm for female), fasting plasma glucose ≥110 mg/dL, or left ventricular hypertrophy on electrocardiogram Written informed consent. pregnant or breastfeeding uncontrolled hypertension uncontrolled diabetes mellitus thyroid dysfunction serum transaminase level &gt;2 times the upper limit of normal history of gall bladder disease chronic alcoholic serum creatinine level &gt;1.5 mg/dL history of myopathy history of acute myocardial infarction or acute stroke within 3 months before the study began acute or chronic infection or inflammation history of cancer history of adverse events associated with test drugs.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>rosuvastatin, fenofibrate, creatine kinase, alanine aminotransferase</keyword>
</DOC>