<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00108901</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is a behavioral clinical trial of aerobic exercise to determine dose-response effects on risk for type 2 diabetes, fatness, fitness, blood cholesterol levels, and other cardiovascular risk factors in overweight elementary schoolchildren. The hypothesis is that the more exercise a child does, the more benefit he or she will gain in reducing the risk of diabetes and other cardiovascular diseases. An ancillary study examined effects on cognition and achievement.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Medical College of Georgia PLAY Project: Exercise Dose and Insulin Sensitivity in Obese Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is a behavioral clinical trial of aerobic exercise to determine dose-response effects on insulin response to the oral glucose tolerance test, body composition, fitness, lipid profile, inflammation and other metabolic syndrome components in overweight elementary schoolchildren. Blinded psychological assessments of cognition and achievement were obtained.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Overweight, sedentary children Black or white race Attending specific schools in Augusta, GA area from which this study is recruiting Unable to participate in testing or vigorous exercise program Diabetes Taking medication that would affect study results Sibling enrolled in project</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>children</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>overweight</keyword>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>insulin resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>female</keyword>
	<keyword>male</keyword>
	<keyword>black, African-American</keyword>
	<keyword>white, Caucasian</keyword>
	<keyword>cognition</keyword>
	<keyword>executive function</keyword>
</DOC>