<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00108784</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will test the hypothesis that reducing the energy density of the diet by incorporating more water-rich foods will result in: 1) greater weight loss and weight maintenance; 2) greater diet satisfaction and satiety; and 3) more healthful dietary patterns than reducing dietary fat alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Factors Affecting Caloric Regulation in Human Feeding</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Energy density refers to the amount of calories (energy) in a given weight of food. For the same amount of energy, a larger volume (weight) of food can be consumed if the food or diet is low in energy density than if the food or diet is high in energy density. The two nutrients that have the largest impact on energy density are fat and water. Foods high in fat and low in water content are typically high in energy density, whereas foods low in fat and high in water content, such as fruits and vegetables, are low in energy density. This study will examine whether there are increased benefits for weight loss and weight maintenance when the ad libitum consumption of water-rich foods is added to a reduced-fat diet, thus making it even lower in energy density. Comparisons: Reduced-energy-dense diet and Reduced-fat diet</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Healthy women BMI (body mass index) 30 through 40 kg/m2 Normal blood pressure LDL (low density lipoprotein)cholesterol &lt; 90th percentile recommendations Triglycerides, fasting blood glucose, and all other blood values within normal ranges Able to participate in low to moderate physical activity. Heart disease Diabetes type I or II High blood pressure Renal or kidney disease Gastrointestinal disease Blood clotting disorder Liver disease or cirrhosis Any oral steroids Gout (requiring treatment) Anemia Lung disease Cancer within the last 5 years Thyroid disease</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>reduced-energy-density diet</keyword>
	<keyword>fat-restricted diet</keyword>
	<keyword>fruit</keyword>
	<keyword>vegetables</keyword>
	<keyword>ad libitum intake</keyword>
	<keyword>weight loss</keyword>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
</DOC>