<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02464995</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate the effectiveness of bronchial thermoplasty in a severe asthmatic population with frequent exacerbations. This will be a single center randomized and controlled study. Thirty subjects with severe asthma (Gina 4 and 5) with frequent severe exacerbations (four or more bursts of systemic corticosteroids &gt;3 days each in the previous year) will be randomized 1:1 to either the thermoplasty group (bronchial thermoplasty and medical management) or control group (medical management only).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bronchial Thermoplasty in Severe Asthma With Frequent Exacerbations</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Age 1865 years Asthma which requires treatment with guidelines suggested medications for GINA steps 45 Four or more bursts of systemic corticosteroids &gt;3 days each in the previous year Willingness and ability to give written informed consent Exclusion criteria: Current smoker and former smoker &gt; 10 pack years total smoking history Participation in another clinical trial within the prior 4 months Omalizumab therapy within the prior 4 months Allergic bronchopulmonary aspergillosis Patient having had severe exacerbation of their asthma requiring high doses of oral corticosteroids (&gt; 60 mg equivalent prednisolone) more than one month in the previous year Postbronchodilator FEV1 of less than 30% Past diagnosis of COPD and chronic respiratory insufficiency Known coagulopathy or platelet dysfunction Use of anticoagulants Use of an internal or external pacemaker or internal cardiac defibrillator Contraindication to perform bronchoscopy Contraindication to perform general anesthesia Significant cardiovascular disease Current or recent respiratory tract infection resolved less than 4 weeks Known cancer or cancer history less than 12 months Pregnancy and nursing mother</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma,</keyword>
	<keyword>Asthma exacerbation</keyword>
	<keyword>Bronchial thermoplasty</keyword>
</DOC>