<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02464137</DOC>
	<brief_summary>single-modality phase I dose escalation toxicity study for first-line curative treatment of head and neck squamous cell carcinoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>HYpofractionateD RadioAblative (HYDRA) Treatment of Advanced Laryngeal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>HYDRA will consist of 5 fraction SBRT treatment targeting only grossly evident disease localized by examination and standard diagnostic CT, MR, and PET-CT imaging. Prophylactic coverage of uninvolved at-risk mucosal and nodal drainage basins will be strictly disallowed. The initial dose cohort will be treated to a total of 42.5 Gy in five equal fractions delivered every other day over a two week period (biologically equivalent to 66 Gy delivered in 2 Gy daily fractions), drawn from our successful institutional experience with similar dosing and fractionation for early-stage larynx SBRT. Escalation of total dose will proceed in 2.5 Gy increments, up to a final target dose of 50 Gy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Laryngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients older than 18 years of age with histologically proven squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx. Stage T12N12c/T34N02c disease, as defined by American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC) criteria. ECOG (Zubrod) performance status 02. Must be functionally and technically fit for partial laryngectomy. Women of childbearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry, for the duration of study participation, and for 90 days following completion of therapy. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent Patients who have undergone resection of primary disease. Patients who have received induction chemotherapy for their cancer diagnosis. Patients who have undergone a diverting tracheostomy which is either a) traversing directly through tumor, b) has been placed for true airway insufficiency. Patients with a tracheostomy placed preemptively for impending airway compromise remain eligible for enrollment. Prior cancer diagnosis, except appropriately treated localized epithelial skin cancer or cervical cancer. Prior radiation therapy to the head and neck region. Women of childbearing potential (a woman of childbearing potential is a reproductively mature woman who has not undergone a hysterectomy or who has not been naturally postmenopausal for at least 24 consecutive months [i.e., who has had menses at any time in the preceding 24 consecutive months]) and male participants must practice effective contraception (oral, injectable, or implantable hormonal contraceptive; tubal ligation; intrauterine device; barrier contraceptive with spermicide; or vasectomized partner) throughout the study. Patients unable or unwilling to give written, informed consent. Severe, active comorbidity, defined as follows: 1. Unstable angina and/or congestive heart failure requiring hospitalization within the last 6 months. 2. Transmural myocardial infarction within the last 6 months. 3. Acute bacterial or fungal infection requiring intravenous antibiotics at the time of registration. 4. Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease exacerbation or other respiratory illness requiring hospitalization or precluding study therapy within 30 days before registration. 5. Hepatic insufficiency resulting in clinical jaundice and/or coagulation defects; note, however, that laboratory tests for liver function and coagulation parameters are not required for entry into this protocol. 6. Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS) based upon current CDC definition; note, however, that HIV testing is not required for entry into this protocol. Protocolspecific requirements may also exclude immunocompromised patients. 7. History of treatment with potent immunosuppressive drugs for such conditions as post organ transplant, severe rheumatoid arthritis, etc. within the past 6 months. Subjects must not be pregnant or nursing due to the potential for congenital abnormalities and the potential of this regimen to harm nursing infants Evidence of metastatic disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>