<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00518362</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the efficacy and safety of Tripterygium (TW) versus Valsartan (ARB) in the Diabetic Nephropathy (DN).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>To Compare the Efficacy and Safety of Tripterygium (TW) Versus Valsartan in the Diabetic Nephropathy (DN)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Diabetic nephropathy with heavy proteinuria have high risks of progressing to end stage renal disease. Though recent studies have shown that ACEI or ARB could reduce proteinuria of DN and slowed the progression to ESRD. But ARBs can only reduce proteinuria about 30%, so some patients still have heavy proteinuria,and then loss their renal function rapidly. So, to reduce the proteinuria of DN is a very important therapy target. Tripterygium (TW) is a Chinese traditional patent drug, it can reduce proteinuria of chronic glomerular nephritis. So, we designed this randomized, prospective clinical trial to assess the efficacy and safety of TW versus ARB in the treatment of heavy proteinuria of DN.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Nephropathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Valsartan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. A new diagnosis of diabetic nephropathy proved by histology and(or) serology. 2. Proteinuria &gt; 2.5 g/24 h 3. serum creatinine &lt; 3 mg/dl 4. age 3565 years 1. Coexistence of anther chronic glomerular nephritis. 2. Severe disfunction of the liver 3. White blood cell &lt; 3000/ul 4. Severe infection in the past 1 month 5. Malignant hypertension which in hard to control 6. Myocardial infarct or heart failure or sever cerebral vessels complication in the past 6 month</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>TW</keyword>
	<keyword>Valsartan</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetic nephropathy</keyword>
	<keyword>Proteinuria</keyword>
</DOC>