<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00518804</DOC>
	<brief_summary>LAY SUMMARY: IBI is costly and there are currently long waitlists of children who are in need of treatment. The investigators have clinical and ethical obligations to determine more appropriate alternatives to IBI for children making few gains because all children with autism deserve treatment based on their needs. This study is designed to determine the effectiveness of a functional skills group intervention, based on the principles of applied behaviour analysis, for children responding slowly to IBI. Specifically, it will investigate the effectiveness of functional behavioural skills training in addition to IBI at increasing a child's independence in day to day communication and self-help skills and reducing behaviour problems, as well as increasing parental competence and decreasing caregiver strain compared with IBI alone. Having an effective alternative to IBI for children making few gains is relevant from the standpoint of i) preventing exposure to potentially intrusive interventions for those children making few gains in IBI, ii) allowing children making few gains in IBI to access effective treatment, iii) opening limited IBI spots for children who would benefit from IBI, and iv) making better use of limited health resources. Overall, the results will be of interest to parent, clinicians, researchers and funding bodies. HYPOTHESES Four main hypotheses are presented to examine the effectiveness of involvement in the ABA functional skills group in improving parent training and functional skills and behaviour in young children with ASD who do not master the ELM. We focus our hypotheses on child measures of functional self help skills, behaviour and cognition as well as parental measures of caregiver strain and sense of competence. Participants (i.e. children predicted to have poor response to IBI alone) who attend the functional skills group for 8 months will have: 1. greater decreases in interfering behaviour as measured on the Developmental Behaviour Checklist and ratings of behaviour during observations compared to children receiving IBI alone. 2. greater increases in self-help as measured on the Vineland Adaptive Behaviour Scales II, and greater independence in eating, toileting, requesting, hand washing, and responding to name as measured by independent ratings of these skills compared with those children receiving IBI alone. 3. parents of these children will have greater improvements in their sense of competence as a parent and greater reductions in caregiver strain, compared with parents of children receiving IBI alone. 4. a similar pattern of little or no change in cognitive function compared with children who receive only IBI based on the Stanford Binet. In other words, there will be no difference between the experimental and control group on the measure of cognitive functioning</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Functional Behavioural Skill Training for Young Children With Severe Autism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children receiving Intensive Behavioural Intervention from the Hamilton Niagara Regional Early Autism Intervention Program who do not master the Early Learning Measure after 4 months of treatment Children receiving Intensive Behavioural Intervention from the Hamilton Niagara Regional Early Autism Intervention Program who master the Early Learning Measure after 4 months of treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2008</verification_date>
</DOC>