<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02690818</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this pilot study is to determine whether regularly scheduled medication reminder text messages (SMS) are effective in increasing latent tuberculosis infection (LTBI) treatment completion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Promoting Adherence to Treatment for Latent TB Infection Through Text Messaging</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We aim to determine the feasibility and acceptability of text reminders for improving adherence in latent TB patients. Specific objectives of the current study are to: 1) Assess the feasibility of the intervention as indicated by participant recruitment and retention and; 2) Evaluate the acceptability of the intervention, as indicated by intervention adherence, outcome measurement rates, and feedback from participants. Data will be used to design a definitive trial which will test the hypothesis that the intervention will improve medication adherence, as measured through an increase in treatment completion rates, and result in higher self-reported medication adherence, fewer missed appointments and doses, and a shorter course of treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Latent Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Consent to the study Own a mobile phone which operates on a telecom provider supported by our SMS platform Initiating or actively receiving treatment for LTBI at the Pima County TB Clinic in Tucson, AZ Prescribed selfadministered therapy Report not having prior or current active TB disease Know how to and are able to receive SMS messages At least 18 years of age Do not meet inclusion criteria Do not consent to study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tuberculosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Latent Tuberculosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Texting</keyword>
	<keyword>Adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>Medication</keyword>
</DOC>