<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02690766</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Investigators proposed to refine and test the feasibility and acceptability of a 4-month multi-modal lifestyle intervention in African American female breast or endometrial cancer survivors diagnosed with type 2 diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Translating Healthy Lifestyle Interventions for Cancer Survivors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Recent systematic reviews and meta-analyses of cohort studies show that physical activity can reduce mortality and morbidity in diabetes and obesity-related cancers. Yet, there have been few efforts to promote physical activity within the context of female cancer survivorship, particularly among women with diabetes. In response, investigators proposed to refine and test the feasibility and acceptability of a 4-month multi-modal lifestyle intervention in African Americans (AA) with diabetes and who are breast or endometrial cancer survivors. This web-based, lifestyle intervention, coupled with coaching calls and in-person exercise sessions, may be an effective way to promote physical activity and healthy survivorship. The primary goal is for participants to participate in 30 minutes of moderate-to-vigorous physical activity five times a week. The investigators' aims : i) refine a theory-driven healthy lifestyle intervention, that is delivered via computer technologies and periodic in-person group exercise sessions with appropriate content, literacy demand and graphics, ii) assess the preliminary effects of the intervention on the primary outcome of level of moderate to vigorous physical activity (MVPA), as measured by accelerometry; weight A1C and evaluate the effect of eating behaviors, wellbeing/functioning (quality of life, depressive symptoms, self-efficacy), compliance/adherence to protocol and acceptability on response to the intervention.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>African American women, ages 30 No evidence of pregnancy, as evidenced by negative urine pregnancy test. Diagnosed with type 2 diabetes by their provider Diagnosed with Stage IIII breast or endometrial cancer Completed treatment for breast or endometrial cancer at least 4 months and no more 5 years ago Englishspeaking Agree to participate in all aspects of the semistructured interview (Aim 1) Agree to participate in all aspects of the feasibility study, including group sessions (Aim 2) Access to the internet via phone or computer Access to a working phone for personal use NonEnglish speaking Recent epilepsy, cardiac event or stroke in last 6 months,special nutritional needs (e.g. current evidence of malignancy; HIV) History of epilepsy, cardiac event or stroke within the last year Known diagnosis of HIV Known new malignancy Less than 4 months or more than 2 years post treatment of Stage IIII breast or endometrial cancer. No diagnosis of type 2 diabetes No selfreport of African American race/ethnicity No access to a phone for personal use No access to the internet via computer or mobile phone</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Endometrial cancer,</keyword>
	<keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
</DOC>