<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00719264</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To estimate the difference in efficacy and safety of bevacizumab and RAD001 compared to bevacizumab and interferon alfa-2a for first-line treatment of patients with metastatic carcinoma of the kidney.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Bevacizumab Plus RAD001 Versus Interferon Alfa-2a and Bevacizumab for the First-line Treatment in Adult Patients With Kidney Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients with metastatic renal cell carcinoma 2. Patients with at least one measurable lesion 3. Patients with progressive metastatic renal cell carcinoma 4. Patients who had a prior partial or complete nephrectomy 5. Patients with a Karnofsky Performance Status ≥70%. 6. Adequate bone marrow function 7. Adequate liver function 8. Adequate renal function 9. Adequate coagulation profile 1. 4 weeks postmajor surgery 2. Patients who had radiation therapy within 28 days prior to start of study 3. Patients in need for major surgical procedure during the course of the study. 4. Patients with a serious nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture. 5. Patients with a history of seizure(s) not controlled with standard medical therapy. 6. Patients who have received prior systemic treatment for their metastatic RCC. 7. Patients who received prior therapy with VEGF pathway inhibitor 8. Patients who have previously received systemic mTOR inhibitors 9. Patients with a known hypersensitivity RAD001 (everolimus) or other rapamycins or to its excipients. 10. Patients with history or current central nervous system (CNS) metastases or spinal cord compression. 11. Patients with a history of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation, or intraabdominal abscess within 6 months prior to study enrollment. 12. Patients with proteinuria at screening. 13. Patients with inadequately controlled hypertension 14. Patients receiving ongoing or with recent need for full therapeutic dose of oral or parenteral anticoagulants or chronic daily treatment with aspirin 15. Patients receiving chronic systemic treatment with corticosteroids or another immunosuppressive agent. 16. Patients with a known history of HIV 17. Patients with hypersensitivity to interferon alfa2a or any component of the product. 18. Patients with an active, bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy or recurrent thromboembolism 19. Patients who have any severe and/or uncontrolled medical conditions or other conditions 20. Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction &lt; lower limit of institutional normal assessed by ECHO or MUGA 21. Patients who have a history of another primary malignancy ≤ 3 years 22. Female patients who are pregnant or breast feeding 23. Patients who are using other investigational agents or who had received investigational drugs ≤ 4 weeks prior to study treatment start. 24. Patients unwilling to or unable to comply with the protocol Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Renal cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Adults</keyword>
	<keyword>Bevacizumab</keyword>
	<keyword>RAD001</keyword>
	<keyword>Everolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>Interferon</keyword>
	<keyword>Clear</keyword>
	<keyword>Roferon</keyword>
	<keyword>Avastin</keyword>
	<keyword>Nephrectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>newly diagnosed</keyword>
</DOC>