<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00719576</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this trial is to investigate how the outcome of the treatment with autologous chondrocytes compares to microfracture technique in patients with symptomatic knee disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Comparison Between the Performance of Chondrocytes Versus Microfracture Technique on Knee Symptoms</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, randomized, open-label, parallel-group, multicenter study designed to investigate the outcome of MACI implant versus arthroscopic microfracture in the treatment of articular cartilage defects in the knee in patients between ages of 18 and 55 years. All patients who meet the eligibility criteria and are considered suitable for inclusion will have a cartilage biopsy taken prior to randomization to study treatment. Eligible patients will then be randomized during the index arthroscopy procedure to receive either MACI implant or microfracture treatment. Patients randomized to treatment with MACI implant will return within approximately 4 to 8 weeks of the index arthroscopy to undergo the chondrocyte implantation procedure via arthrotomy. Patients randomized to microfracture will undergo the procedure during the index arthroscopy. Patients will be assessed post-arthroscopy and post-arthrotomy at intervals during 2 years follow-up. Evaluations include adverse events, functional and pain outcomes, arthroscopic and histologic evaluation and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cartilage Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with symptomatic articular cartilage defects in the knee. Patients who have had surgery on the knee joint within 6 months prior to enrollment. Patients with significant malalignment. Patients with instability of the knee. Patients with the majority of functional meniscus absent or severe osteoarthritis in the target knee.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cartilage legions,</keyword>
	<keyword>symptomatic focal cartilage defects,</keyword>
	<keyword>microfracture,</keyword>
	<keyword>MACI,</keyword>
	<keyword>autologous chondrocyte</keyword>
</DOC>