<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01300026</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multi-center, phase 1, open-label first-in-human study of AMG 319 in subjects with relapsed or refractory lymphoid malignancies. This study consists of two parts. The dose exploration in part 1, studies cohorts of 3 subjects with relapsed or refractory lymphoid malignancies and uses a practical continuous reassessment model [CRM] to guide dose escalation and to define the MTD. The dose expansion in part 2 will enroll 20 subjects with CLL at a dose no higher than the MTD and further explore the safety, PK, and clinical activity of AMG 319 in this patient population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>AMG 319 Lymphoid Malignancy FIH</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Mantle-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenosine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Part 1 (Dose Exploration): Relapsed or refractory lymphoid malignancy of the following type for which standard treatment does not exist or is no longer effective: Bcell Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL) confirmed by immunophenotype or NonHodgkin Lymphoma: Low or intermediate grade Bcell NHL, mantle cell lymphoma, noncutaneous Tcell NHL confirmed by histology and/or immunophenotype Part 2 (Dose Expansion): Subjects must have relapsed or refractory Bcell Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia confirmed by immunophenotype for which standard treatment does not exist or is no longer effective. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status ≤ 2 Life expectancy of &gt; 3 months, in the opinion of the investigator Men or women ≥ 18 years old Hematological function, as follows: Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 x 109/L (unless due to diseaserelated bone marrow involvement as documented by bone marrow biopsy, ≥ 0.5 x 109/L) Platelet count ≥ 50 x 109/L (without a transfusion within 14 days before enrollment) Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL Hepatic function, as follows: Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &lt; 3.0 x ULN Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &lt; 3.0 x ULN Alkaline phosphatase (ALP) &lt; 2.0 x ULN (&lt; 5 x ULN in subjects whom the PI and sponsor agree that clinical data suggest an extrahepatic source of elevation) Total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 x ULN (&lt; 3.0 x ULN for subjects with documented Gilbert's Disease or for whom the indirect bilirubin level suggests an extrahepatic source of elevation) Amylase ≤ 2.0 x IULN Lipase ≤ 2.0 x IULN Primary or disseminated tumor involving the central nervous system (CNS) A history of other malignancies, except: adequately treated nonmelanoma skin cancer, curatively treated insitu cancer, or other solid tumors curatively treated with no evidence of disease for ≥ 2 years History of allogeneic stemcell (or other organ) transplantation Clinically significant ECG changes which obscure the ability to assess the PR, QT, and QRS interval; congenital long QT syndrome QTcF interval &gt; 470 msec Active or chronic hepatitis B or hepatitis C infection, determined by serologic tests Recent infection requiring intravenous antiinfective treatment that was completed ≤ 14 days before enrollment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Low intermediate grade B cell Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-cutaneous T-cell NHL</keyword>
	<keyword>Mantle Cell Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>PI3K delta</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphoid</keyword>
	<keyword>NHL</keyword>
	<keyword>MCL</keyword>
	<keyword>Hematologic</keyword>
	<keyword>CLL</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia</keyword>
</DOC>