<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01300182</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate the effect of early WBVT on neuromuscular control after ACLR.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Early WBVT on Neuromuscular Control After ACLR</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The knee joint position sense, postural control, muscular strength and functional ability after anterior cruciate ligament construction (ACLR) are distorted, and even after a period of rehabilitation. Previous studies had demonstrated that there was improvement in knee joint, postural balance, muscle strength and functional outcome in elderly, stroke and spastic patients already. It has also been concluded that the balance in elderly, postmenopausal women, Parkinson's disease, multiple sclerosis, stroke and spastic patients were all significantly improved. Some studies showed that the proprioception in osteoarthritis patients significantly improve. Knee strength is also one of the aspect being improved. However, no studies focus on the early effect of WBVT on knee joint proprioception, postural control, muscle strength, knee joint stability and functional ability in ACLR cases. This study is to answer this research gap.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rupture</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ACLR with a singlebundle approach no complication such as wound infection after the ACLR able to walk with a pair of elbow crutches independently at one month post operation concomitant posterior cruciate ligament, lateral collateral ligament, and medial collateral ligament injury in the same knee previous operation on either lower limbs medical problems such as pregnancy, acute thrombosis, serious cardiovascular disease, pacemaker, acute hernia, discopathy, spondylolysis, severe diabetes, epilepsy, recent infections, severe migraine, tumors or kidney stones etc neurological conditions such as GuillainBarre ́ syndrome, myasthenia gravis, and postpolio syndrome prior experience of WBVT</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>ACLR</keyword>
</DOC>