<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02263911</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to understand the relationship of 3 different dosage forms of baricitinib. This study will also explore the effect of food on how the body absorbs baricitinib. This study will last about 5 weeks, not including screening. Screening is required within 28 days prior to the date of first dosing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Baricitinib in Healthy Japanese Participants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Overtly healthy Japanese male and female (women not of childbearing potential or after menopause), as determined by medical history and physical examination Have a body mass index (BMI) of 18.5 to 29.9 kilogram per square meter (kg/m^2) Are reliable and willing to make themselves available for the duration of the study and are willing to follow study procedures Have an abnormality in the 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG) that, in the opinion of the investigator, increases the risks associated with participating in the study Have an abnormal blood pressure as determined by the investigator Have a history of or current cardiovascular, respiratory, hepatic, renal, gastrointestinal, endocrine, hematological, or neurological disorders capable of significantly altering the absorption, metabolism, or elimination of drugs; of constituting a risk when taking the study medication; or of interfering with the interpretation of data Are women who are pregnant or lactating Have used or intend to use overthecounter or prescription medication, including herbal medications, within 14 days prior to dosing and during the study. Have donated blood of more than 400 milliliter (mL) in the last 12 weeks (males) or in the last 16 weeks (females), or any blood donation (including apheresis) within the last 4 weeks, or total volume of blood donation within 12 months is 1200 mL (males) or 800 mL (females) at screening. Have an average weekly alcohol intake that exceeds 21 units per week (males) and 14 units per week (females), or are unwilling to abide by alcohol restrictions Are participants who currently smoke more than 10 cigarettes per day (or equivalent in tobacco or nicotine products) or are unwilling to abide by smoking restrictions Have a current or recent history of a clinically significant bacterial, fungal, parasitic, viral (not including rhinopharyngitis), or mycobacterial infection Have an absolute neutrophil count (ANC) less than 2000 cells/microliter (µL)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>