<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02292290</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Dual therapy with metformin and Liraglutide is more effective at helping people with established Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus (T2DM) observing Ramadan achieve a triple composite endpoint of weight reduction and/or maintenance and improved HaemaglobinA1c (HbA1c) and no severe hypoglycaemic events.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial for People With Established Type 2 Diabetes During Ramadan</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants in the control arm will essentially continue with their standard routine care and those in the intervention groups will either receive Liraglutide in addition to metformin or those on dual therapy will switch from their sulphonylurea/pioglitazone to Liraglutide and continue with metformin. Informed consent and baseline data will be collected 4-8 weeks prior to the start of Ramadan. This will allow time for a run in period for the titration of Liraglutide prior to the fasting period. Ramadan is followed by Eid-al-Fitr a 3-day Islamic holiday that marks the end of this holy month. Tradition includes amongst early morning prayers/celebration through feasting. Therefore, participants will be invited to attend the first follow-up after this event (between weeks 2 - 4) and then at 12 weeks post Ramadan. Randomisation will not be revealed until after the baseline data have been collected.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pioglitazone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Benzocaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Individuals ≥ 18 years old with established T2DM on metformin only or dual therapy of metformin plus a sulphonylurea or pioglitazone with a HbA1c between 7 11 % if on monotherapy and between 6.5 12% if on dual therapy Are pregnant or breast feeding Suffer from terminal illness Have significant renal or liver impairment Are unable to provide informed consent Have severe and enduring mental health problems Are not primarily responsible for their own care Are receiving insulin therapy Type 1 diabetes</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Liraglutide</keyword>
	<keyword>Ramadan</keyword>
	<keyword>fasting</keyword>
</DOC>