<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01981330</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a pilot-study of 25 selected Swedish patients which all have severe hoarseness or aphonia due to vocal fold scarring (from previous surgery, radiation therapy, inflammation or possibly hereditary). The patients are operated with phonomicrosurgical dissection of the scarred vocal folds, removal or scar tissue and injection of autologous mesenchymal stroma cells, aMSC (which were previously harvested from each patients´s bone marrow, purified, expanded and characterized according to standard procedure at the Center of Hematology and Regenerative Medicine Karolinska University Hospital Huddinge). 14 Patients is planned to be treated with a single injection of aMSC and 11 patients with injection of aMSC mixed with a carrier hyaluronan gel developed at Uppsala University Sweden and at the Karolinska Institute. The laryngeal status, vocal fold function, and voice function will be followed individually with an advanced battery of examinations performed before and up to 1 year postoperatively. Side effects and complications are noted and reported during surgery and following surgery at regular intervals during at least 1 year Since autumn 2015 no new patients have been recruited and no treatments are given during 2016. The monitoring authority was changed from Swedish National Board of Health to Swedish Medical Product Agency (MPA) in March/April 2016. Further inclusions and treatments are postponed until permission is granted from MPA to continue the study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Study of Stem Cell Treatment of Patients With Vocal Fold Scarring</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cicatrix</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyaluronic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>severe hoarseness vocal fold scarring no active other treatment age above 18 years active treatment of laryngeal disorder active inflammatory condition of the larynx diagnosed or suspicions of local malignancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>vocal fold scarring</keyword>
	<keyword>mesenchymal stem cells</keyword>
</DOC>