<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02798510</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present study is designed to determine whether adjuvant concurrent chemoradiotherapy improves overall survivals.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trial of Adjuvant Chemotherapy Followed by Concurrent Chemoradiotherapy Compared With Adjuvant Chemotherapy Alone in Patients With Gallbladder Carcinoma and Extrahepatic Cholangiocarcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The role of adjuvant radiotherapy in gallbladder carcinoma (GBCA) or extrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma (EHCC) is unknown. A retrospective study suggested that chemoradiotherapy provides greater benefit than chemotherapy alone in GBCA patients. SWOG S0809, a phase II study showed that adjuvant chemoradiotherapy has promising efficacy in GBCA or EHCC. The present phase III clinical trial is designed to compare adjuvant concurrent chemoradiotherapy with chemotherapy alone.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cholangiocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patients with pathologic diagnosis of gallbladder carcinoma (GBCA) or extrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma (EHCC) after radical resection. The patients with pathologic stage T24 or N1 in R0 resection or positive resection margins (R1). Aged 18 to 70 years old, male or female, body condition score generally ECOG 0～2, expected survival ≥ 6 months. Subjects were no major organ dysfunction, blood, liver, kidney and heart function was normal, the specific requirements of laboratory indicators: Blood: Absolute neutrophil count &gt; 1.5 × 109 / L, Platelet count &gt; 100 × 109 / L, Hb &gt; 8.0g/dl. Liver function: serum bilirubin less than 1.5 times the upper limit of normal; ALT and AST less than 2.5 times the upper limit of normal. Renal function: creatinine less than 1.5 times the upper limit of normal. Patients who can understand the circumstances of this study and signed informed consent. Pregnancy, breastfeeding patients； Patients received prior anticancer therapy for the current malignancy or upper abdominal radiotherapy or chemotherapy at any time. Patients with malignant ascites. Patients with purulent and chronic infected wounds which delayed healing. Patients with liver, kidney and heart failure and coronary heart disease, angina, myocardial infarction, arrhythmia, cerebral thrombosis, stroke and other serious cardiovascular and cerebrovascular disease; Patients has a history of mental illness and difficult to control; Patients who was considered inappropriate to participate in the trials by the researchers.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gallbladder Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Extrahepatic Cholangiocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemoradiotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>