<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01892293</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will enroll patients with multiple myeloma who have received prior therapy for their disease but their disease has progressed or relapsed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CT Antigen TCR-Engineered T Cells for Myeloma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective of the study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of autologous genetically modified T cells transduced to express the high affinity NY-ESO-1c259 TCR in HLA-A201 patients. Eligibility screening will be performed in two steps. First, patients will undergo prescreening to determine if they have the correct HLA type in order to respond to the engineered T cell therapy, and to test for presence of the target antigen, NY-ESO-1 and LAGE-1, in their tumor cells. Patients, who are HLA-A201 positive and test positive for expression of NY-ESO-1 and/or LAGE-1 in their myeloma tumor will move on to complete all screening procedures to determine eligibility for the study. Patients will initially undergo a steady-state mononuclear cell apheresis for T cell collection. About 3-4 weeks later (to allow expansion/engineering/releasing the engineered T cells), patients will receive a short course of cytoreductive chemotherapy prior to receiving the engineered T cell infusion, comprised of 1.5 gm/m2 of cyclophosphamide, mesna will be given if in accordance with institutional standards. At day 0, patients will receive a dose of ≥0.1-1 x 1010 anti-CD3/anti-CD28-costimulated autologous T cells which have been genetically modified to express affinity-enhanced NY-ESO-1 T cell receptors (TCRs). A minimum dose of 0.1≤x&lt;1 x 109 will be permitted. Patients receiving this low dose level will be evaluated separately for safety and efficacy. Patients will undergo myeloma restaging approximately 1 week prior to the T cell infusion, and post infusion at days +28, +42 (week 6), +100 and 6 months post infusion and then every 3 months until relapse/progression or until 1 year, whenever comes first. At this point, patients will be followed semi-annually for up to 5 years and then annually for long term follow-up for monitoring for delayed adverse events until 15 years after receiving the genetically modified T cells, in accordance with FDA Guidelines.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Written informed consent must be obtained from all patients before entry into the study 2. Patients must have a diagnosis of myeloma (see Appendix A for diagnostic criteria). 3. Patients must have progressive or active disease following prior therapy for their myeloma which: 1. includes an IMiD and proteasome inhibitor as separate lines or a combined line of therapy 2. May include prior autoSCT but not prior alloSCT Patients who have failed second or third line therapy and beyond, such as DPACE, and who are experiencing a partial response rather than progressive disease are also eligible. 4. Patients must have measurable disease on study entry. Measurable disease may include quantifiable or detectable levels of serum or urine paraprotein. For patients with minimally secretory disease on study entry, serum free kappa or lambda light chain levels, or the serum free light chain ratio may be measured and used for disease monitoring if abnormal. 5. Patients must be HLAA201 as determined by a CLIA certified (or equivalent) clinical laboratory. (This determination will be made under a preenrollment screening ICF) 6. Patients must have confirmed expression of NYESO1 and/or LAGE1 by RTPCR, immunohistochemistry or quantigene analysis. (This determination will be made under a preenrollment screening ICF) 1. Pregnant or nursing females 2. HIV or HTLV1/2 seropositivity 3. Known history of myelodysplasia 4. Known history of chronic active hepatitis or liver cirrhosis (if suspected by laboratory studies, should be confirmed by liver biopsy). 5. Active Infection with HBV or HCV Active hepatitis B infection as determined by test for hepatitis B surface antigen. Active hepatitis C. Patients will be screened for HCV antibody. If the HCV antibody is positive, a screening HCV RNA by any RT PCR or bDNA assay must be performed at screening by a local laboratory with a CLIA certification or its equivalent. Eligibility will be determined based on a negative screening value. The test is not required if documentation of a negative result of a HCV RNA test performed within 60 days prior to screening is provided. 6. Prior allogeneic transplant 7. History of severe autoimmune disease requiring steroids or other immunosuppressive treatments. 8. Active immunemediated diseases including: connective tissue diseases, uveitis, sarcoidosis, inflammatory bowel disease, multiple sclerosis. 9. Evidence or history of other significant cardiac, hepatic, renal, ophthalmologic, psychiatric, or gastrointestinal disease which would likely increase the risks of participating in the study. The specific type of stress test will be selected at the PI's discretion. 10. Active bacterial or systemic viral or fungal infections.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Autologous stem cell transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Received initial treatment previously</keyword>
</DOC>