<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00006591</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if treatment with an anti-HIV drug containing ritonavir and Agenerase is safe and can lower the level of HIV in the blood in patients who have failed an anti-HIV drug treatment containing nelfinavir.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ritonavir and Agenerase Treatment for Patients Who Have Failed Previous Anti-HIV Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>HIV-infected patients will be treated with a ritonavir-enhanced Agenerase regimen.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amprenavir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients may be eligible for this study if they: Are 18 years of age or older. Are HIVpositive. Have a viral load (level of HIV in the body) of more than 1,000 copies/ml. Have had more than 12 weeks of prior antiHIV drug treatment. Have failed a previous antiHIV treatment containing nelfinavir as the only protease inhibitor. Are responsive to Agenerase. Are able to follow study requirements. Exclusion Criteria Patients will not be eligible for this study if they: Are intolerant to ritonavir (an antiHIV drug). Have or have had problems with absorption. Have liver disease or damage. Have pancreatic disease or damage. Have taken any protease inhibitor other than nelfinavir. Are receiving investigational drugs or devices from another study. Are pregnant or breastfeeding. Currently use triazolam, astemizole, ergot medications, cisapride, midazolam, bepridil, rifampin, terfenadine, or pimozide. Have a bleeding disorder. Have previously been treated with Agenerase. Are receiving nonnucleosides.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2004</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy, Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Protease Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>Ritonavir</keyword>
	<keyword>VX 478</keyword>
	<keyword>Salvage Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-HIV Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Monitoring</keyword>
	<keyword>Nelfinavir</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment Experienced</keyword>
</DOC>