<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00006214</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Chemoprevention therapy is the use of certain drugs such as flutamide to try to prevent the development of cancer. Flutamide may be effective in the prevention of prostate cancer. PURPOSE: Randomized clinical trial to study the effectiveness of flutamide in preventing prostate cancer in patients who have neoplasia of the prostate.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Flutamide In the Prevention of Prostate Cancer in Patients With Neoplasia of the Prostate</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the ability of flutamide to reduce the incidence of prostate cancer in patients with high grade prostatic intraepithelial neoplasia. II. Determine the effect of this regimen on a series of endpoint biomarkers in these patients. III. Assess the quality of life of these patients. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, double blind, placebo controlled, multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to age (under 65 versus 65 and over), PSA (0-2.5 versus 2.6-4.0 versus 4.1-10 versus greater than 10 ng/mL), PIN (on one biopsy versus on two biopsies), and family history (prostate cancer in brother, father, or uncle versus no prostate cancer in these relatives). Patients are randomized to one of two treatment arms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Intraepithelial Neoplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Flutamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed high grade prostatic intraepithelial neoplasia Confirmed by second prostate biopsy within 180 days of first biopsy No prior or concurrent prostatic carcinoma No prior hormonal replacement or antiandrogen therapy PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: ECOG 01 Life expectancy: Greater than 5 years Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: SGOT and alkaline phosphatase no greater than 2 times upper limit of normal No hepatitis B or C or liver cirrhosis Renal: Not specified Other: Fertile patients must use effective contraception No other prior malignancy in past 5 years except carcinoma in situ or nonmelanoma skin cancer PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: Not specified Endocrine therapy: See Disease Characteristics Radiotherapy: No prior radiotherapy Surgery: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>prostate cancer</keyword>
</DOC>