<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00006478</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Vaccines made from a person's cancer cells may make the body build an immune response to kill cancer cells. Vaccine therapy may be an effective treatment for non-Hodgkin's lymphoma. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of vaccine therapy following chemotherapy and peripheral stem cell transplantation in treating patients who have non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vaccine Therapy Following Chemotherapy and Peripheral Stem Cell Transplantation in Treating Patients With Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the humoral and cellular immune responses in patients with follicular non-Hodgkin's lymphoma treated with autologous lymphoma-derived idiotype vaccine with keyhole limpet hemocyanin plus sargramostim (GM-CSF). - Determine the safety and toxicity of this regimen in these patients in the post-transplant setting. - Determine the changes in quantitative bcl-2 in the blood and bone marrow of these patients before and at various times after the series of idiotype vaccines. OUTLINE: Vaccinations begin at day 100 or up to 6 months after hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Patients receive autologous lymphoma-derived idiotype vaccine plus keyhole limpet hemocyanin subcutaneously (SC) on day 1. Sargramostim (GM-CSF) SC is administered on days 1-4. Treatment repeats every 4 weeks for 4 doses, followed 12 weeks later by the fifth and final dose. Patients are followed every 3 months for 2 years, every 6 months for 2 years, and then annually thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 20 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Follicular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Keyhole-limpet hemocyanin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically proven grade I, II, or III follicular nonHodgkin's lymphoma that failed induction therapy Previously received no more than 2 highdose chemotherapies before hematopoietic stem cell transplantation Minimal disease state at day 100 to 6 months posttransplantation Lymph nodes smaller than 2 centimeters (cm) Less than 20% bone marrow involvement with lymphoma Uncertain complete remission, defined by greater than 75% reduction in the size of the pretransplantation mass not representing active disease Tissue sample safely accessible by biopsy, needle aspiration, or phlebotomy Must have adequate circulating lymphoma cells PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: Over 19 Performance status: Karnofsky greater than 70% Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: See Disease Characteristics Absolute neutrophil count greater than 1,000/mm^3* CD4+ count greater than 200/microliter* NOTE: *No restrictions if study vaccine administered at 6 months after transplantation Hepatic: Bilirubin less than 2.0 mg/dL (unless due to lymphomatous involvement) Serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT) and serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase (SGPT) less than 2 times normal (unless due to lymphomatous involvement) Renal: Creatinine no greater than 2.0 mg/dL Other: Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 6 months after study participation PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: See Disease Characteristics Chemotherapy: See Disease Characteristics Endocrine therapy: Not specified Radiotherapy: Not specified Surgery: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 1 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 2 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 3 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>