<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00006327</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if the vaccine, AIDSVAX B/E, will protect intravenous drug users from becoming infected with HIV.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of AIDSVAX B/E Vaccine in Intravenous Drug Users in Bangkok, Thailand</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Volunteers are immunized and followed for a minimum of 2 years. Any volunteer that becomes infected with HIV-1 is followed every 4 months post infection for up to 36 months. Behavior effects associated with study participation are assessed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Volunteers may be eligible for this study if they: Are 20 to 60 years old. Are HIVnegative. Have used intravenous drugs in the previous 12 months. Are available and commit to 3 years of followup. Have a Thai National ID or its equivalent such as government official ID or state enterprise ID. Are able to understand the study and pass a test showing they understand it, and give written informed consent. Exclusion Criteria Volunteers will not be eligible for this study if they: Have a serious disease or condition, or history of a serious disease or condition such as lymphoma, that would interfere with the study. Are HIVpositive. Have ever received an experimental HIV1 vaccine. Have had or expect to have any treatments or medications that interfere with the immune system (e.g., longterm use of systemic steroids, chemotherapy, or radiation). Have received a vaccine or immunoglobulin within 2 weeks of receiving the first study injection, or other vaccines within 4 weeks of the first study injection. Have received immunoglobulins for a long time. Have received nonlicensed, research agents within 4 weeks of the first study injection. Expect to miss study visits or plan to move within 36 months. Are pregnant or breastfeeding or plan to become pregnant during the 36month study period. Are women who have sex with men and do not plan to use effective birth control.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2003</verification_date>
	<keyword>Recombinant Proteins</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV-1</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS Serodiagnosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Substance Abuse, Intravenous</keyword>
	<keyword>Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay</keyword>
	<keyword>Blotting, Western</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Envelope Protein gp120</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDSVAX</keyword>
</DOC>