<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00006354</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Mistletoe lectin may slow the growth of cancer cells and be an effective treatment for solid tumors. PURPOSE: Phase I trial to study the effectiveness of mistletoe lectin in treating patients who have advanced solid tumors that have not responded to previous therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mistletoe Lectin in Treating Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors That Have Not Responded to Previous Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the maximum tolerated dose and dose-limiting toxicity of mistletoe lectin (recombinant viscumin) in patients with advanced solid tumors who have failed standard therapy. - Determine the pharmacokinetics of this regimen in these patients. - Determine whether induction of antibodies against recombinant viscumin occurs in these patients. - Determine whether immunological stimulation at the RNA level of immune cells occurs in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine whether modification of endothelial parameters occurs in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the objective response rates in patients treated with this regimen. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study. Patients receive mistletoe lectin (recombinant viscumin) IV over 1 hour twice weekly. Courses repeat every 3 weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Cohorts of 1-3 patients receive escalating doses of recombinant viscumin until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose at which 20% of patients experience dose-limiting toxicity during the first course. Additional patients are treated at the MTD. Patients are followed every 3 months until disease progression or initiation of another therapy. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A minimum of 37 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically proven progressive advanced solid tumor that is not amenable to standard therapy (i.e., resistant to standard therapy or for which no standard therapy exists) No clinically symptomatic CNS involvement PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: ECOG 02 Life expectancy: At least 3 months Hematopoietic: WBC at least 3,000/mm^3 Neutrophil count at least 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm^3 Hepatic: Bilirubin no greater than 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) AST and ALT less than 2.5 times ULN (5 times ULN if liver metastases present) Alkaline phosphatase less than 2.5 times ULN (5 times ULN if liver metastases present) Renal: Creatinine less than 1.4 mg/dL Cardiovascular: No ECG abnormalities of clinical relevance Other: No severe or unstable systemic disease or infection No circumstances (e.g., alcoholism or substance abuse) that would preclude study participation HIV negative Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: At least 4 weeks since prior immunostimulating substances, biologic response modifiers, or colonystimulating factors No concurrent immunostimulating substances, colonystimulating factors (except in lifethreatening situations), biologic response modifiers, or monoclonal antibodies Chemotherapy: At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: At least 4 weeks since prior hormonal therapy At least 4 weeks since prior systemic steroids No concurrent systemic steroids Radiotherapy: At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy No concurrent radiotherapy Surgery: Not specified Other: No prior mistletoe preparations At least 4 weeks since prior investigational treatment No other concurrent anticancer agents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>unspecified adult solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
</DOC>