<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00006131</DOC>
	<brief_summary>OBJECTIVES: I. Compare the efficacy and safety of two doses of oral valacyclovir in immunocompromised patients with uncomplicated herpes zoster. II. Compare quality of life, pain, and medical resource utilization in patients treated with these 2 regimens.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized Study of Two Doses of Oral Valacyclovir in Immunocompromised Patients With Uncomplicated Herpes Zoster</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PROTOCOL OUTLINE: This is a randomized, double blind study. Patients are randomized to one of two treatment arms. Arm I: Patients receive standard dose oral valacyclovir three times a day on Days 1-7. Arm II: Patients receive higher dose oral valacyclovir three times a day on Days 1-7. Both arms: Patients begin treatment within 72 hours after onset of zoster rash. Quality of life is assessed on Days 1, 14, and 28 during study and then every 4 weeks through Week 24. Pain is assessed on Days 1-28 during study, and then weekly through Week 24. Medical resource utilization is assessed on Days 1, 8, 14, and 18 during study and then every 4 weeks through Week 24. Patients are followed every 4 weeks through Week 24.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Herpes Zoster</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Valacyclovir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PROTOCOL ENTRY CRITERIA: Disease Characteristics Patients with a clinical diagnosis of uncomplicated herpes zoster presenting within 72 hours after onset of zoster rash No evidence of cutaneous or visceral dissemination of herpes zoster infection; cutaneous dissemination defined as at least 20 discrete lesions outside adjacent dermatomes Must have immune dysfunction caused by any of the following: congenital immune deficiency; active malignancy of any type; collagen vascular diseases; organ or bone marrow transplantation; HIV infection; severe atopic dermatitis; received cytotoxic drugs or immunosuppressive therapy (e.g., chronic systemic corticosteroids) within past 3 months CD4 count at least 50% Prior/Concurrent Therapy Biologic therapy: Greater than 9 months since prior bone marrow transplantation Surgery: Greater than 9 months since prior liver or heart transplantation Other: At least 4 weeks since prior topical or systemic antivaricella zoster virus (antiVZV) medications; no concurrent systemic agents with antiVZV activity from enrollment to Day 10; no concurrent probenecid from 24 hours before the first dose of study drug until Day 10 Patient Characteristics Hepatic: AST or ALT no greater than 5 times upper limit of normal Renal: Creatinine clearance at least 30 mL/min Other: Not pregnant or nursing; negative pregnancy test; fertile patients must use effective contraception; no history of intolerance or hypersensitivity to acyclovir, penciclovir, valacyclovir, or famciclovir</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2003</verification_date>
</DOC>