<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00006377</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Combining more than one drug may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of combining doxorubicin, paclitaxel, and carboplatin in treating patients who have primary stage III, stage IV, or recurrent endometrial cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Doxorubicin, Paclitaxel, and Carboplatin in Treating Patients With Primary Stage III, Stage IV, or Recurrent Endometrial Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the response rate and duration of response in patients with primary stage III or IV or recurrent endometrial cancer treated with sequential doxorubicin, paclitaxel, and carboplatin. OUTLINE: Patients receive sequential chemotherapy comprised of doxorubicin IV once every 2 weeks for 3 courses, followed by paclitaxel IV over 1 hour once weekly for 9 courses, and then carboplatin IV once every 3 weeks for 3 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 18-46 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically proven primary stage III or IV or recurrent endometrial cancer Bidimensionally measurable disease by xray, CT scan, MRI scan, or physical exam Sole site may be within a previously irradiated area if documented disease progression since prior radiotherapy PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: Adult Performance status: Karnofsky 70100% Life expectancy: At least 12 weeks Hematopoietic: Absolute neutrophil count greater than 1,000/mm^3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm^3 Hepatic: Bilirubin, SGOT, and alkaline phosphatase no greater than 1.5 times normal Renal: Creatinine no greater than 1.8 mg/dL Cardiovascular: Left ventricular ejection fraction at least 50% Other: No active uncontrolled infection No greater than grade II neuropathy No other active malignancy Not pregnant Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: No prior doxorubicin Greater than 6 months since prior paclitaxel, carboplatin, or other platinum compounds Endocrine therapy: Not specified Radiotherapy: See Disease Characteristics At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy and recovered Surgery: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage III endometrial carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV endometrial carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent endometrial carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>