<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01755299</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The line of "5-hour Energy"® products are available over-the-counter as energy supplements. The appeal of these products involves ease of use, low caloric value, and the absence of sugar to prevent a "crash" later in the day. The definitive efficacy and potency of the products is unknown due to the lack of evidence-based clinical reports. It is suspected that the efficacy related to these products is due to the caffeine content, which was reported as 138 mg per 2-ounce bottle in an online caffeine content chart. The purpose of this randomized, double-blind, placebo controlled, four way crossover study is to evaluate the efficacy of "5-hour Energy"®, "5-Hour Energy Decaf"®, caffeine, and placebo for perceived energy and wakefulness.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Energy Shots and Caffeine for Energy and Wakefulness Levels</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Please see brief summary contained above.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Caffeine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must be age 18 years or older who consume no more than five caffeinated beverages and products per day. One caffeinated beverage is defined as any of the following: six ounces of cold or hot coffee or tea, twelve ounces of soda with caffeine, or one energy drink. Age less than 18 years Subjects who are pregnant or breastfeeding Diagnosis of any of the following disease states: Attention Deficit Hyperactive Disorder Anxiety Coronary Artery Disease Cardiac arrhythmias Cerebral vascular accident Narcolepsy Seizure disorders Uncontrolled hypertension Active therapy with stimulant medications any medications containing amphetamine, atomoxetine, dextroamphetamine, diethylpropion, lisdexamfetamine, methylphenidate, phentermine, or modafinil Use of decongestants or other products containing phenylephrine or pseudoephedrine for more than 15 days within the past 30 days Subjects who work third shift or rotate to two or more different shifts for their job, not allowing them to have a regular sleep schedule</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Energy drinks</keyword>
	<keyword>Wakefulness</keyword>
	<keyword>Caffeine</keyword>
</DOC>