<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01755598</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the protective efficacy of two doses of GSK Biologicals' candidate TB vaccine against pulmonary TB, as compared to placebo. The efficacy will be evaluated in adults living in TB endemic countries and aged 18 - 50 years because pulmonary TB occurs frequently in these countries and age range. In addition, the safety and immunogenicity of the candidate tuberculosis vaccine will be evaluated in a subset of volunteers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Efficacy of GlaxoSmithKline (GSK) Biologicals' Candidate Tuberculosis (TB) Vaccine in Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Case Definitions: • First case definition: A subject with clinical suspicion of pulmonary TB disease, with MTB complex identified from a sputum specimen, taken before initiation of TB treatment, by Xpert MTB/RIF and/or microbiological culture and confirmed HIV-negative at the time of TB diagnosis. • Second case definition: A subject with clinical suspicion of pulmonary TB disease, with MTB complex identified from a sputum specimen, taken before initiation of TB treatment, by Xpert MTB/RIF and confirmed HIV-negative at the time of TB diagnosis. • Third case definition: A subject with clinical suspicion of pulmonary TB disease, with MTB complex identified from a sputum specimen, taken up to four weeks after initiation of TB treatment, by Xpert MTB/RIF and/or microbiological culture and confirmed HIV-negative at the time of TB diagnosis. • Fourth case definition: A subject with clinical suspicion of pulmonary TB disease, with MTB complex identified from a sputum specimen, taken up to four weeks after initiation of TB treatment, by Xpert MTB/RIF and/or microbiological culture. • Fifth case definition: A subject for whom a clinician has diagnosed TB disease and has decided to treat the patient with TB treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who, in the opinion of the investigator, can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol. A male or female between, and including, 18 and 50 years of age at the time of obtaining informed consent. Written (or thumb printed and witnessed) informed consent obtained from the subject. Baseline positive IGRA test result. Baseline negative HIV screen. Baseline negative clinical screening questionnaire and negative sputum sample for Pulmonary TB disease. Healthy subjects or those with chronic wellcontrolled disease as established by medical history and clinical examination. Female subjects of nonchildbearing potential may be enrolled in the study. Nonchildbearing potential is defined as premenarche, current tubal ligation, hysterectomy, ovariectomy or postmenopause. Female subjects of childbearing potential may be enrolled in the study, if the subject: has practiced adequate contraception for 25 days prior to vaccination, and has a negative pregnancy test on the day of screening and the day of first vaccination, and has agreed to continue adequate contraception during the entire vaccination period and for 2 months after completion of the vaccination series. Current TB disease or history of TB disease and/or treatment for TB. Use of any investigational or nonregistered product other than the study vaccines within 30 days preceding the first dose of study vaccine, or planned use during the study period. Planned administration/administration of a vaccine not foreseen by the study protocol in the period starting 30 days before and ending 30 days after each dose of vaccine. History of previous administration of experimental Mtb vaccines. Chronic administration of immunosuppressants or other immunemodifying drugs within six months prior to the first vaccine dose. Inhaled and topical steroids are allowed. Any condition or illness or medication, which in the opinion of the Investigator might interfere with the evaluation of the safety or immunogenicity of the vaccine. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, based on medical history and physical examination. Planned participation or participation in another experimental protocol during the study. Concurrently participating in another clinical study, at any time during the study period, in which the subject has been or will be exposed to an investigational or a noninvestigational product. Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within the 3 months preceding the first dose of study vaccine or planned administration during the study period. History of any reaction or hypersensitivity likely to be exacerbated by any component of the vaccines. History of medically confirmed autoimmune disease. Pregnant or lactating female. Female planning to become pregnant or planning to discontinue contraceptive precautions during the vaccination period and/or before 2 months after completion of the vaccination series.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Positive Interferon-γ release assay</keyword>
	<keyword>Efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Adults</keyword>
	<keyword>Tuberculosis vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Endemic region</keyword>
</DOC>