<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01927185</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Central venous catheterization is commonly applied in patients undergoing cardiac surgery. The subclavian vein has lower risk of infection and provides more patients comfort. However central venous catheterization may results in complications such as pneumothorax, hemothorax or arterial puncture. It has been suggested that ultrasound (US) guidance could improve the success rate, reduce the number of needle passes and decrease complications. Two different real-time 2-dimensional US techniques can be employed in the insertion of central venous catheters. The first technique involves real-time US-guided cannulation of subclavian vein using a long axis/in-plane approach. The second one involves real-time US-guided using a short axis/out-off-plane approach. However to date no studies have compared their efficacy and safety. The purpose of this study was to compare the US-guided long-axis versus short-axis approach for the SCV catheterization in adult critical care patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-versus Short-Axis Ultrasound Guidance for Subclavian Vein Cannulation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The two techniques used for vessel visualization are far different: The Short-Axis (SA) approach attempts to view the vessel in cross-section while venous access is obtained. The strength of the SA approach is that the vein is centered under the transducer and that the midpoint of the transducer becomes a reference point for the insertion of the needle, and that at the same time is possible to visualize SC artery and the pleural line. SA approach is easy to learn by novice sonologists. The Long-Axis (LA) approach employs a technique that views the length of the vessel during cannulation.For this reason, with LA approach is possible to visualize the needle advance during the entire procedure from the soft tissues until the lumen of the vein, but SC artery and pleural line are not visualized in the same scan. For LA approach, practice is required to keep the needle precisely within the image and care must be taken to avoid the probe inadvertently moving away from the target structure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Postoperative Complications</mesh_term>
	<criteria>aged =&gt;18 years patients who needed central venous catheter for clinical reasons aged &lt;18a years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>central venous access</keyword>
	<keyword>ultrasonography</keyword>
	<keyword>subclavian vein</keyword>
	<keyword>pneumothorax</keyword>
	<keyword>vessel view</keyword>
</DOC>