<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01927848</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Knee related mobility limitations are the leading cause of disability in the western world. It is a very expensive and debilitating condition when the cost of lost productivity and personal assistance is considered. In recent years there has been a growing interest in alternative medicine and many individuals seek such treatments. Rosehip, that is sold as a nutritional supplement, has been particular popular, and has been shown effective in relieiving pain - albeit the evidence is scarce. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of specialized rosehip powder nutritional additives (Rosenoids®) on knee joint function during walking in subjects with knee-related walking limitations.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Gait in Persons With Knee Related Mobility Limitations by Rosenoids® Food Supplement: a Randomized Double-blind Placebo-controlled Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Aged above 40 Selfreported kneerelated walking disability In general good health, in the opinion of the Investigator, based on medical history and physical examination and, if necessary, laboratory values. Laboratory tests are prescribed by the Investigator at the screening visit. A body mass index (BMI) of ≤35 kg/m2 Speaks, reads and writes Danish language Usage of Rosehip nutritional supplements within the last 3 months History of symptoms of autoimmune disorders. Planned surgical procedure during the duration of the study History, diagnosis, or signs and symptoms of clinically significant neurological disease Alcohol or drug abuse within the last 5 years History, diagnosis, signs or symptoms of any clinically significant psychiatric disorder Subjects with regional pain syndromes suggestive of lumbar compressions with radiculopathy or at risk of developing radiculopathy. Any other condition, which in the opinion of the Investigator, would put the subject at increased safety risk or otherwise make the subject unsuitable for this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>