<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03000543</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: 1. Burden: Recently Bangladesh has introduced mandatory vitamin A (VA) fortification of refined edible oil while high dose VA supplementations for infants and children are still in place as part of national program. Thus preschool children are plausible at risk of hypervitaminosis A. 2. Knowledge gap: Serum VA concentration is not an authenticate indicator of VA status, while existing deuterium- VA isotope dilution methods to determine whole body VA status require 3 weeks and not applicable for infants and children. 3. Relevance: Our research group has recently developed a new simplified equation to measure VA pool size in 4-5 days, highly correlated with compartmental model-predicted value and estimate VA pool size in adults with high precision. However, it is not clear whether this new simplified equation also works in infants and children. In this proposed study, we validate the method in healthy infants and infants with inflammatory condition as well as in children with adequate and high dietary VA intake. Hypothesis: (1) Whole-body VA status in infant and children can be estimated without accounting for fractional catabolic rate in the context of inflammatory condition or higher dietary VA intake (2) Fortification of commonly consumed food item with VA along with periodic high dose VA supplementation would increase the risk of hypervitaminosis A among preschool children in Bangladesh Methods: Our study comprises two studies. "Study 01" will be undertaken in infants while "Study 02" for preschool children. At first we need to undertake one feasibility study to verify whether the oral dose of 400 μg 13C10 or 13C3- retinyl acetate (isotopic VA) that we propose to use in this study would work in infants as we observed in adults, secondly, whether PENTA valent vaccines induce inflammation in infants (plasma CRP as maker) that closely mimics natural infection. We need such infants with inflammatory condition in "Study 01" to answer the question of whether the isotope dilution technique will still work in children who undergo inflammation. Information of the reliability of the retinol isotope dilution technique in infectious conditions is important as national dietary assessment surveys often observe children with chronic or latent infection. To minimize the taking of multiple blood samples from each infant/child in both studies, a "super kid study" design will be adopted that ensure no more than 2 venous blood samples from each infant/child, even though multiple time points (at least 5 subjects / time-point) over a 28-day study period will be available for mathematical modelling. In "Study 01" a total of 115 infants (9-11 mo) will receive an oral dose of 13C10- retinyl acetate (400 μg) dissolved in 0.5 mL of sunflower oil and then blood samples will be taken from 6h to 16th day at 9 different time-points. On day 16, a single dose PENTA vaccine will be provided to the randomly selected 50% of infants. On day 17, another type of stable isotopic VA e.g. 13C3- retinyl acetate (400 μg) will be orally supplemented to all infants. Blood sample will be collected from day 16 to day 28 at 11 different time-points for each of the vaccine and non-vaccine groups. In "Study 02" 50 children (3-5y) in each of the "adequate dietary VA" intake group and "higher dietary VA" intake group will be enrolled to receive an oral dose of 13C10- retinyl acetate (400 μg). Blood sample will be collected from 6h to day 28 at 11 time-points for each of the two groups. Specific activity of 13C10-VA and 13C3-VA from the blood samples will be measured by liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry (LC/MS/MS). Plasma biomarkers of VA toxicity e.g. bone metabolism, liver fibrogenesis and VA metabolites will be measured in the children of "Study 02". Outcome measures/variables: (1) The early time point equation for assessing VA pool size in a group of infants with or without inflammation and in a group of children with adequate or with high dietary VA intake. (2) The association between biomarkers of VA toxicity and estimated liver vitamin A concentration in preschool children at risk of hypervitaminosis A.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Novel Isotope Dilution Technique to Assess Vitamin A Status and Hypervitaminosis A</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypervitaminosis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinol palmitate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinol acetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for study 01: 1. 9 11 months of age 2. Infants with normal body temperature and normal CRP (&lt;5 mg/L) 3. Infants receive breast milk from the mother at least once per day 4. Mothers produce a breast milk containing 3040 nmol vitamin A /g milk fat (~1.52.0 µmol/L) 5. Infants received a highdose vitamin A capsules at the time of the most recent national distribution campaign (within the last 24 months) 6. Mother is 18 45 years of age 7. Mother and her infant plan to stay in the study area for the duration of the study Inclusion criteria for study 02: 1. 35 years of age 2. Children with normal body temperature and normal CRP (&lt;5 mg/L) 3. Received a highdose vitamin A capsules at the time of the most recent national distribution campaign (within the last 24 months) 4. Mother is 18 45 years of age 5. Mother and her child plan to stay in the study area for the duration of the study Exclusion criteria for study 01: 1. Mother or infant has chronic disease 2. Mother or infant has acute illness on the day of data collection 3. Infant is anemic (Hb &lt;100 g/L) 4. Infant has weight for length &lt;80% of the reference median 5. Infants do not develop inflammation (CRP &gt;5 mg/L) after PENTA vaccination. Exclusion criteria for study 02: 1. Mother or child has chronic disease 2. Mother or child has acute illness on the day of data collection 3. Child is anemic (Hb &lt;110 g/L) 4. Child has weight for length &lt;80% of the reference median</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>9 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Infants</keyword>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
	<keyword>Adequate or high vitamin A store</keyword>
</DOC>