<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03000985</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The involvement of family members is crucial and improves the prognosis of psychiatric patients and reinforces therapeutic adherence and reduces the frequency of relapses. For schizophrenia, the scientific literature clearly shows that it's in the interest of the patient to offer to his family a psychoeducational program. Therapeutic education programs are now part of the recommendations of good clinical practice and in the French health through the law n ° 2009-879 of July 21, 2009 on the reform of the hospital and relating to patients, health and territories.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of a Psychoeducation Program for Families Caregivers of Schizophrenic Patients : Randomized Study in Two Arms</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objectives We conducted a randomized study in two groups to evaluate the impact of a psychoeducational program for caregivers. Methods 60 patients with a DSM-V diagnosis of schizophrenia and their families' caregivers are recruited. Families' caregivers are randomly assigned to receive either a 6 session psychoeducation program, or no psychoeducation. Baseline evaluations: Patients: symptomatology (PANSS), medication adherence (MARS); Families' Caregivers: Quality of Life (S-CGQoL), Burden (Zarit), knowledge of disease (KAST), therapeutic alliance (4PAS caregivers), depression (CES-D), medication adherence (CRS).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Problem Behavior</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of schizophrenia, based on ICD10 (F20 to F29) Receive inpatient treatment at hospital (or medical center linked to Charles Perrens Hospital) Be the caregiver or parent of the patient Patient informed of the diagnosis of his disease Mental retardation or other diagnoses that could affect the ability to answer questionnaires, after the acute schizophrenia psychosis is controlled Suicidal ideation Noncomprehension of the French language</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>psychoeducation program</keyword>
	<keyword>family caregiver</keyword>
	<keyword>relapse</keyword>
	<keyword>medication adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>burden</keyword>
</DOC>