<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="6631">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03020602</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BRN0035</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2016-01973</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>BRN0035</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30CA124435</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03020602</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>BPM31510 in Treating Patients With Recurrent Glioblastoma or Gliosarcoma Previously Treated With Bevacizumab</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Study of BPM31510 Plus Vitamin K in Subjects With Glioblastoma That Has Recurred on a Bevacizumab-Containing Regimen</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Seema Nagpal</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Stanford University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I trial studies the side effects and best dose of ubidecarenone injectable
      nanosuspension (BPM31510) in treating patients with glioblastoma or gliosarcoma that has
      come back and have been previously treated with bevacizumab. BPM31510 may stop the growth of
      tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. Assess the safety and tolerability of BPM31510 plus vitamin K in subjects with
      glioblastoma (GB) that has recurred on a bevacizumab (BEV)-containing regimen.

      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. To evaluate plasma pharmacokinetics (PK) when BPM31510 plus vitamin K is given to
      subjects with GB recurrent on a BEV-containing regimen.

      TERTIARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. Estimate the overall survival in subjects with GB recurrent on a BEV-containing regimen
      from the 1st day of infusion of BPM31510 plus vitamin K to death.

      II. To evaluate the effects of BPM31510 plus vitamin K on shifting GB metabolism to aerobic
      respiration by positron emission tomography (PET) imaging.

      III. To evaluate the effects of BPM1510 plus vitamin K on magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)
      imaging by Response Assessment in Neuro-Oncology (RANO) criteria (specifically
      progression-free survival [PFS] and response rate [RR]).

      IV. To evaluate plasma pharmacodynamics (PD) when BPM31510 plus vitamin K is given to
      subjects with GB recurrent on a BEV-containing regimen.

      OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study.

      Patients receive ubidecarenone injectable nanosuspension intravenously (IV) over 72 hours
      twice weekly. Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or
      unacceptable toxicity.

      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 12 weeks.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with dose-limiting toxicities defined as thrombocytopenia &gt;= grade 3, hemorrhage &gt;= grade 3, and INR elevation &gt;= grade 2 assessed by CTCAE v4.03</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Will be tabulated at each dose, along with the result of the pooled adjacent violators algorithm as implemented in the Modified Toxicity Probability Interval (equal weights, and the weighted mean solver).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events graded according to the Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version (v)4.03</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days after last dose of BPM3150</time_frame>
    <description>Will be tabulated separately for each dose cohort, by Medical Dictionary for Regulatory Activities (MedDRA) major organ system and severity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Brain tumor metabolism as measured by PET</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Standardized uptake value (SUV) of the GB will be measured. SUV is the standard PET measure.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of BPM31510 initiation to death, assessed for up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Kaplan-Meier survival estimates for OS will be presented for data at the maximum tolerated dose, with a 95% confidence interval using Greenwood's formula at 3.5 months and 7 months.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>PFS assessed by RANO criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Response rate assessed by RANO criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Gliosarcoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Glioblastoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (BPM31510)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive ubidecarenone injectable nanosuspension IV over 72 hours twice weekly. Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laboratory Biomarker Analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (BPM31510)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pharmacological Study</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (BPM31510)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ubidecarenone Injectable Nanosuspension</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (BPM31510)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BP31510</other_name>
    <other_name>Coenzyme Q10 Injectable Nanosuspension</other_name>
    <other_name>Ubiquinone Injectable Nanosuspension</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Have a life expectancy &gt;= 6 weeks

          -  Have a Karnofsky performance score (KPS) &gt;= 60

          -  Have pathologically-proven GB or gliosarcoma (World Health Organization [WHO] IV), in
             recurrence after treatment with bevacizumab

          -  Be at least 14 days from the last administration of bevacizumab

          -  Be at least 28 days from last administration of cytotoxic chemotherapy or other
             investigational agent

          -  Have received conventional radiation therapy with concurrent temozolomide; total
             radiation dosage can range from 5400 to 6000 cGy administered in daily fractions of
             150 to 200 cGy over 6 weeks, or the equivalent in a hypofractionated protocol (for
             example, 4000cGy in 15 fractions or 2500cGy in 5 fractions)

          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1500 mm^3

          -  Platelets &gt;= 100,000/mm^3

          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9 g/dL

          -  Serum creatinine =&lt; 1.8 mg/dL or creatinine clearance &gt; 50 mL/min

          -  Bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 mg/dL

          -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) =&lt; 2.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN)

          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; 2.5 x ULN

          -  Prothrombin time (PT) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN

          -  International normalized ratio (INR) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN

          -  Partial thromboplastin time (PTT) =&lt; 1.5 x ULN

          -  Subjects of childbearing potential must agree to use hormonal or barrier birth
             control with spermicidal gel to avoid pregnancy during the study

          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Has a history of spontaneous or tumor-related cerebral hemorrhage; or has cerebral
             hemorrhage as determined by the screening fludeoxyglucose F-18 (FDG)-PET-computed
             tomography (CT) and MRI; this does not include stable post-operative blood products
             seen on a gradient echo MRI sequence

          -  Has the any of the following cardiac history:

               -  Active heart disease including myocardial infarction within previous 3 months

               -  Symptomatic coronary artery disease

               -  Arrhythmias not controlled by medication

               -  Unstable angina pectoris

               -  Uncontrolled or symptomatic congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association
                  [NYHA] class III and IV)

          -  Uncontrolled or severe coagulopathies or a history of clinically-significant bleeding
             within the past 6 months, including any of the following, but not limited to:

               -  Epistaxis

               -  Hemoptysis

               -  Hematochezia

               -  Hematuria

               -  Gastrointestinal bleeding

               -  Spontaneous or tumor related intracranial hemorrhage

          -  Known predisposition for bleeding such as von Willebrand's disease or other such
             condition(s)

          -  Uncontrolled concurrent illness that would limit compliance with study requirements,
             including any of the following, but limited to:

               -  Uncontrolled infection

               -  Psychiatric illness/social situations

          -  Prior malignancy except for non-melanoma skin cancer and carcinoma in situ (of the
             cervix or bladder), unless diagnosed and definitively treated more than 3 years prior
             to 1st dose of investigational drug

          -  Receiving any of the following medications:

               -  Therapeutic doses of any anticoagulant, including low-molecular weight heparin
                  (LMWH); concomitant use of warfarin, even at prophylactic doses, is prohibited

               -  Digoxin, digitoxin, lanatoside C, or any type of digitalis alkaloids

               -  Colony-stimulating factors (CSFs) that cannot be held during the monitoring
                  period for dose-limiting toxicities (DLT)

          -  Has significant toxicities from prior treatment that have not resolved or stabilized

          -  Known allergy to coenzyme Q10

          -  Known allergy or adverse reaction to oral, subcutaneous, or intravenous vitamin K

          -  Is pregnant or lactating

          -  Known to be positive for the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV); note: HIV-testing is
             not required for eligibility, but if performed previously and was positive, the
             subject is ineligible
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Seema Nagpal</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Stanford University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sophie Bertrand</last_name>
    <phone>650-723-4467</phone>
    <email>sophieb@stanford.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University, School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palo Alto</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sophie Bertrand</last_name>
      <phone>650-723-4467</phone>
      <email>sophieb@stanford.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Seema Nagpal</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 11, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 5, 2017</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Stanford University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Seema Nagpal</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gliosarcoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coenzyme Q10</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
