<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="139741">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01281813</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR017230</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>TMC114IFD3001</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01281813</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT03027297</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>TMC114IFD3001 - Study Providing Continued Access to Treatment With Darunavir (DRV)/Ritonavir (Rtv) for Adults Coming From Any of the Three Ongoing Tibotec-Sponsored Studies With DRV</brief_title>
  <official_title>Continued Access to Darunavir/Ritonavir (DRV/Rtv) in HIV-1-Infected Adults (Roll Over Patients From C211, C214 &amp; C229)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Sciences Ireland UC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Sciences Ireland UC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this trial is to continue the provision of DRV/rtv to adult
      patients who have completed treatment with DRV/rtv in the clinical trials TMC114-C211,
      TMC114-C214, or TMC114-TiDP31-C229, sponsored by Tibotec Pharmaceuticals, who continue to
      benefit from the use of DRV/rtv, and who live in a country where DRV is not commercially
      available, is not reimbursed, or cannot be accessed through another source (eg, access
      program, government program).
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a continued access trial for adults who have completed treatment with darunavir /
      ritonavir (DRV/rtv) in the clinical trials TMC114-C211, TMC114-C214, or TMC114-TiDP31-C229,
      sponsored by Tibotec Pharmaceuticals, who continue to benefit from the use of DRV/rtv, and
      who live in a country where DRV is not accessible. At the baseline visit, inclusion and
      exclusion criteria will be checked to confirm eligibility. Once the eligibility criteria are
      met, patients will continue treatment as follows: HIV-1-infected patients participating in
      the TMC114-C211 trial will continue on the DRV/rtv 800/100 mg once daily dosing regimen and
      emtricitabine / tenofovir (TDF/FTC) as administered in the original trial. HIV-1-infected
      patients participating in the TMC114-C214 or TMC114-TiDP31-C229 trial will continue on the
      DRV/rtv 600/100 mg twice daily dosing regimen as administered in the original trial.
      Assessment visits are recommended according to local, generally accepted standards of care,
      but not less frequently than every 6 months. Adverse events (AEs) considered at least
      possibly related to DRV/rtv, AEs leading to discontinuation or treatment interruption,
      serious AEs (SAEs), and pregnancies (or all AEs if applicable per local regulation) will be
      recorded at each visit. Patients will be instructed to report any AEs to the investigator,
      who will report SAEs within 24 hours to the Sponsor. In addition to the assessments in the
      flowchart, the following assessments are recommended to be performed locally every 3 months
      or according to local, generally accepted standards of care: efficacy assessments
      (immunology and plasma viral load) and laboratory safety assessments (hematology and
      biochemistry, including pancreatic amylase [if available] or lipase and lipid analyses).
      Treatment will be continued until one of the following criteria is met (whichever occurs
      first): significant increase in viral load; treatment-limiting toxicity; loss to follow-up;
      withdrawal of consent by the patient; pregnancy; termination of the trial by the sponsor;
      DRV becomes commercially available for the adult patient, is reimbursed, or can be accessed
      through another source (eg, access program, government program) in the region the patient is
      living in. A post-treatment follow-up contact will be performed 4 weeks after the last dose
      of trial medication for patients with an ongoing adverse event. This is consistent with the
      primary objective of the study to provide continued access to DRV/rtv for adult patients who
      previously received DR/rtv in the clinical trials sponsored by Tibotec Pharmaceuticals. This
      study is not set up to address any specific hypothesis. Depending on the previous trial the
      patients were in, they will continue to take either : DRV/rtv 800/100 mg once a day as 2
      tablets of 400 mg DRV and 100 mg ritonavir; or DRV/rtv 600/100 mg twice a day as 1 tablet of
      600 mg DRV and 100 mg ritonavir twice a day.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>No masking</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>All serious adverse events, adverse events leading to discontinuation, and adverse events at least possibly related to the DRV treatment, as measures of the safety and tolerability of DRV/rtv in combination with other ARVs</measure>
    <time_frame>Upto 4 years (ie Qtr 1 2015)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">133</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV-1 Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>001</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Darunavir 400 mg tablet intake of 2 tablets once daily in combination with ritonavir</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>002</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Darunavir 600 mg tablet intake of 1 tablet twice a day in combination with ritonavir</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>003</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>ritonavir 100 mg capsule to be taken once or twice daily in combination with Darunavir and following the Darunavir dosing schedule</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>004</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>ritonavir 100 mg tablet to be taken once or twice daily in combination with Darunavir and following the Darunavir dosing schedule</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Darunavir</intervention_name>
    <description>600 mg tablet, intake of 1 tablet twice a day in combination with ritonavir</description>
    <arm_group_label>002</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ritonavir</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg capsule, to be taken once or twice daily in combination with Darunavir and following the Darunavir dosing schedule</description>
    <arm_group_label>003</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Darunavir</intervention_name>
    <description>400 mg tablet, intake of 2 tablets once daily in combination with ritonavir</description>
    <arm_group_label>001</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ritonavir</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg tablet, to be taken once or twice daily in combination with Darunavir and following the Darunavir dosing schedule</description>
    <arm_group_label>004</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients treated with DRV/rtv who have successfully completed the TMC114-C211,
             TMC114-C214, or TMC114-TiDP31-C229 trial and in the opinion of the investigator
             continue to receive benefit from using DRV/rtv

          -  DRV is not commercially available for the patients, is not reimbursed, or cannot be
             accessed through another source (eg, access program, government program) in the
             region the patient is living in.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Any condition (including but not limited to alcohol and drug use) which, in the
             opinion of the investigator, could compromise the patient's safety or adherence to
             treatment with DRV/rtv

          -  Any active, clinically significant disease (such as pancreas or cardiac problems) or
             findings which could compromise the patient's safety during treatment with DRV/rtv

          -  Previously demonstrated clinically significant allergy or hypersensitivity to any of
             the excipients of the investigational medication (DRV) or ritonavir

          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding female patients.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen R&amp;D Ireland Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen R&amp;D Ireland</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>San Jose</city>
        <country>Costa Rica</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Guatemala</city>
        <country>Guatemala</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Selangor</city>
        <country>Malaysia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Panama</city>
        <country>Panama</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Cape Town</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Cyrildene Johannesburg Gauteng</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Dundee</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Durban</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Johannesburg</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Pretoria N/A</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Westdene Johannesburg Gauteng</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Bangkok</city>
        <country>Thailand</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Chiang Mai</city>
        <country>Thailand</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Khon Kaen</city>
        <country>Thailand</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Costa Rica</country>
    <country>Guatemala</country>
    <country>Malaysia</country>
    <country>Panama</country>
    <country>South Africa</country>
    <country>Thailand</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 6, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 30, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>TMC114IFD3001</keyword>
  <keyword>TMC114</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>Darunavir</keyword>
  <keyword>PREZISTA</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Polystyrene sulfonic acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Darunavir</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
