<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="224614">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00158444</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FKSMC-Industry-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00158444</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of the HemiCAP™ Unicondylar Femoral Resurfacing Prosthesis.&quot;</brief_title>
  <official_title>&quot;A Prospective, Non-Randomized, Non-Comparative, Open Label Multi-Center, Feasibility Study to Examine the Safety and Effectiveness of the HemiCAP™ Unicondylar Femoral Resurfacing Prosthesis.&quot;</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Arthrosurface, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Boston Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>UHZ Sports Medicine Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Iowa</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fowler Kennedy Sport Medicine Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital for Special Surgery, New York</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Arthrosurface, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients with large unstable Grade IV articular surface defects, with significant
      subchondral bone exposure and who will likely receive a joint replacement will receive the
      HemiCAP™ Femoral Resurfacing Prosthesis. The Subject Device intends to offer a surgical
      alternative to these patients who might otherwise endure years of pain and loss of function
      while awaiting a more appropriate age for joint replacement surgery.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The objective of the proposed clinical investigation is to determine safety and
      effectiveness of the investigational device in the management of pain and restoration of
      joint function as part of an interim clinical treatment strategy.

      This is a pivotal, prospective, non-randomized, non-comparative, open label clinical study,
      to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of the HemiCAP™ Femoral Resurfacing Prosthesis.

      The study will involve up to 15 qualified investigational sites.

      Patients who meet the inclusion/exclusion criteria will be consented by the coordinator for
      the study at the centre and receive a baseline evaluation and knee exam. Standard
      radiographs will be taken and the subject will fill out quality of life questionnaires. The
      surgical procedure will take place within 1 month of the baseline evaluation.

      Follow-up evaluations will occur at 2 weeks, 6 weeks and 3 months following the surgery. At
      these evaluations, radiographs will be taken and the patient will fill out a post-op
      progress and satisfaction assessment forms. Any concomitant medications and adverse events
      will be documented. In addition at 6, 12 and 24 months following the surgery, the patients
      will fill out the quality of life questionnaires.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>20% or greater improvement in WOMAC score</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>No secondary surgical intervention related to a device-related adverse event occurred</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stable implant (no subsidence, loosening or radiolucency) on radiographic evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SF36</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WOMAC</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>physical examination</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1</enrollment>
  <condition>Osteoarthritis</condition>
  <condition>Avascular Necrosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HemiCAP resurfacing</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>insertion of a focal thermocondyl resurfacing device for inlay athroplasty</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HemiCAP Resurfacing</intervention_name>
    <description>intraoperative joint surface mapping and implantation of patient specific, matching inlay resurfacing prosthetic</description>
    <arm_group_label>HemiCAP resurfacing</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        - We can only include Canadians in our study

          -  Pre-operative Inclusion Criteria: Patients must meet all of the following criteria to
             be eligible to be enrolled into the study:

               -  Patient age greater than or equal to 40 years.

               -  Articular surface defect located on the medial or lateral femoral condyle.

               -  Articular surface defect that penetrates or exposes subchondral bone.

               -  Clinical symptoms meet criteria established in the Cincinnati Knee Rating
                  System, Symptom Rating Form for Patient Grade less than or equal to 5 (on 1-10
                  scale) or, Pain associated with function is less than or equal to 5 (on 1-10
                  scale) or symptoms of weight bearing pain significantly limit the patients
                  quality of life.

               -  Patient must have failed conservative care and a) undergone recognized
                  arthroscopic surgical interventions, such as previous marrow stimulation
                  cartilage repairs (drilling, micro-fracture or abrasions); or not be an
                  appropriate candidate for these surgical interventions or b) have not undergone
                  a recognized arthroscopic intervention for the treatment of defect, including
                  patients suffering from Avascular Necrosis (AVN).

               -  Patient exhibits overall well being, has signed the informed consent form, and
                  is willing to follow instructions and comply with activity restrictions.

               -  Patient understands and is willing to comply with the follow-up requirements of
                  the study.Intra-Operative Inclusion CriteriaPatients must meet all of the
                  following intra-operative criteria to be included in the study:

               -  Articular surface defect can be largely circumscribed by a 15mm or 20mm diameter
                  circular sizing guide.

               -  Articular surface defect is located relatively central to the femoral condyle so
                  that resurfacing implant does not extend beyond the limit of the condyle. -

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Patient is obese, defined as BMI &gt; 30kg/m2, at screening.

          2. Patient is known to be infected with HIV or has acquired AIDS.

          3. Patient is known to have a history of substance abuse.

          4. Patient displays varus joint mal-alignment, in the affected limb only, of greater
             than 2º anatomic or 7º mechanical.

          5. Patient presents evidence of metabolic disorders, which may impair the formation or
             healing of bone.

          6. Patient presents evidence of infections at remote sites, which may spread to the
             implant site.

          7. Patient presents evidence of rheumatoid arthritis, gross joint destruction,
             infectious/crystal arthropathies or bone resorption visible on roentgenogram.

          8. Patient presents evidence of chronic instability or deficient soft tissues, support
             structures, vascular or muscular insufficiency.

          9. Patient has a known sensitivity to materials typically used in orthopedic implants.

         10. Patient has irresolvable joint pain or loss of function with an undeterminable cause.

         11. Patient who suspects or is confirmed to be pregnant. -
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert B Litchfield, MD, FRCSC</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fowler Kennedy Sport Medicine Clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fowler Kennedy Sport Medicine Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>N6A 3K7</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Curl WW, Krome J, Gordon ES, Rushing J, Smith BP, Poehling GG. Cartilage injuries: a review of 31,516 knee arthroscopies. Arthroscopy. 1997 Aug;13(4):456-60.</citation>
    <PMID>9276052</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hjelle K, Solheim E, Strand T, Muri R, Brittberg M. Articular cartilage defects in 1,000 knee arthroscopies. Arthroscopy. 2002 Sep;18(7):730-4.</citation>
    <PMID>12209430</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Minas T. Chondrocyte implantation in the repair of chondral lesions of the knee: economics and quality of life. Am J Orthop (Belle Mead NJ). 1998 Nov;27(11):739-44.</citation>
    <PMID>9839958</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Blevins FT, Steadman JR, Rodrigo JJ, Silliman J. Treatment of articular cartilage defects in athletes: an analysis of functional outcome and lesion appearance. Orthopedics. 1998 Jul;21(7):761-7; discussion 767-8.</citation>
    <PMID>9672913</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kish G, Módis L, Hangody L. Osteochondral mosaicplasty for the treatment of focal chondral and osteochondral lesions of the knee and talus in the athlete. Rationale, indications, techniques, and results. Clin Sports Med. 1999 Jan;18(1):45-66, vi. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10028116</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>O'Driscoll SW. The healing and regeneration of articular cartilage. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1998 Dec;80(12):1795-812. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>9875939</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Buckwalter JA, Mankin HJ. Articular Cartilage, Part II: Degeneration and Osteoarthrosis, repair, regeneration, and transplantation. JBJS 79A:612-632, 1997.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jackson DW, Lalor PA, Aberman HM, Simon TM. Spontaneous repair of full-thickness defects of articular cartilage in a goat model. A preliminary study. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2001 Jan;83-A(1):53-64.</citation>
    <PMID>11205859</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Linden B. Osteochondritis dissecans of the femoral condyles: a long-term follow-up study. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1977 Sep;59(6):769-76.</citation>
    <PMID>908702</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gilbert JE. Current treatment options for the restoration of articular cartilage. Am J Knee Surg. 1998 Winter;11(1):42-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>9533054</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>De Smet AA, Ilahi OA, Graf BK. Untreated osteochondritis dissecans of the femoral condyles: prediction of patient outcome using radiographic and MR findings. Skeletal Radiol. 1997 Aug;26(8):463-7.</citation>
    <PMID>9297750</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jürgensen I, Bachmann G, Schleicher I, Haas H. Arthroscopic versus conservative treatment of osteochondritis dissecans of the knee: value of magnetic resonance imaging in therapy planning and follow-up. Arthroscopy. 2002 Apr;18(4):378-86.</citation>
    <PMID>11951196</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cain EL, Clancy WG. Treatment algorithm for osteochondral injuries of the knee. Clin Sports Med. 2001 Apr;20(2):321-42. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11398361</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hangody L, Feczkó P, Bartha L, Bodó G, Kish G. Mosaicplasty for the treatment of articular defects of the knee and ankle. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2001 Oct;(391 Suppl):S328-36. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11603716</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Micheli LJ, Browne JE, Erggelet C, Fu F, Mandelbaum B, Moseley JB, Zurakowski D. Autologous chondrocyte implantation of the knee: multicenter experience and minimum 3-year follow-up. Clin J Sport Med. 2001 Oct;11(4):223-8.</citation>
    <PMID>11753058</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hungerford MW, Mont MA, Scott R, Fiore C, Hungerford DS, Krackow KA. Surface replacement hemiarthroplasty for the treatment of osteonecrosis of the femoral head. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1998 Nov;80(11):1656-64.</citation>
    <PMID>9840635</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Siguier M, Judet T, Siguier T, Charnley G, Brumpt B, Yugue I. Preliminary results of partial surface replacement of the femoral head in osteonecrosis. J Arthroplasty. 1999 Jan;14(1):45-51.</citation>
    <PMID>9926952</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sharkey PF, Hozack WJ, Rothman RH, Shastri S, Jacoby SM. Insall Award paper. Why are total knee arthroplasties failing today? Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2002 Nov;(404):7-13.</citation>
    <PMID>12439231</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mont MA, Myers TH, Krackow KA, Hungerford DS. Total knee arthroplasty for corticosteroid associated avascular necrosis of the knee. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1997 May;(338):124-30.</citation>
    <PMID>9170373</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Salai M, Ganel A, Horoszowski H. Fresh osteochondral allografts at the knee joint: good functional results in a follow-up study of more than 15 years. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 1997;116(6-7):423-5.</citation>
    <PMID>9266056</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Soucacos PN, Xenakis TH, Beris AE, Soucacos PK, Georgoulis A. Idiopathic osteonecrosis of the medial femoral condyle. Classification and treatment. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1997 Aug;(341):82-9.</citation>
    <PMID>9269159</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Callahan CM, Drake BG, Heck DA, Dittus RS. Patient outcomes following tricompartmental total knee replacement. A meta-analysis. JAMA. 1994 May 4;271(17):1349-57.</citation>
    <PMID>8158821</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gustilo T, Comadoll JL, Gustilo RB. Long-term results of 56 revision total knee replacements. Orthopedics. 1996 Feb;19(2):99-103.</citation>
    <PMID>8834285</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sledge SL. Microfracture techniques in the treatment of osteochondral injuries. Clin Sports Med. 2001 Apr;20(2):365-77. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11398363</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bugbee WD, Convery FR. Osteochondral allograft transplantation. Clin Sports Med. 1999 Jan;18(1):67-75.</citation>
    <PMID>10028117</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bugbee WD. Fresh osteochondral allografts. J Knee Surg. 2002 Summer;15(3):191-5.</citation>
    <PMID>12152982</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Noyes FR, Bassett RW, Grood ES, Butler DL. Arthroscopy in acute traumatic hemarthrosis of the knee. Incidence of anterior cruciate tears and other injuries. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1980 Jul;62(5):687-95, 757.</citation>
    <PMID>7391091</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hangody L, Kish G, Kárpáti Z, Udvarhelyi I, Szigeti I, Bély M. Mosaicplasty for the treatment of articular cartilage defects: application in clinical practice. Orthopedics. 1998 Jul;21(7):751-6.</citation>
    <PMID>9672912</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cole MD, Brian J, D'Amato M. Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation. Operative Techniques in Orthopaedics 115-131, April 2001.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rosenberg TD, Weiss JA, Moulis PM, Deffner KT, Cooley VJ. Finite Element Simulation of Stresses in Chondral Defects. Int Cart Repair Soc Newsletter 2:14, 1999.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bobic MD, Vladimir. The Utilisation of Osteochondral Autografts in the Treatment of Articular Cartilage Lesions. International Society of Arthroscopy, Knee Surgery and Orthopaedic Sport Medicine 2000, www.isakos.com.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>July 20, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>September 8, 2005</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>arthroplasty</keyword>
  <keyword>Resurfacing</keyword>
  <keyword>implant</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Necrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
