<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00055198</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to provide daptomycin, an antibiotic, to patients who are failing conventional therapy, or who cannot take approved antibiotics for one reason or another.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Daptomycin for the Treatment of Infections Due to Gram-Positive Bacteria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bacterial Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gram-Positive Bacterial Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Daptomycin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Main Infection caused by Staphylococcus aureus, Staphylococcus epidermidis, Enterococcus faecalis, or Enterococcus faecium that requires inpatient hospitalization and treatment with injectable antibiotics** Site of infection: complicated skin and skin structure infection; urinary tract infection; intraabdominal infection; infective endocarditis; or bloodstream infection (including catheterrelated). Pathogen resistant to, or patient intolerant of: betalactams, vancomycin, quinupristin/dalfopristin, or linezolid. Unable to receive any other standard commercially available antibacterial therapy for the infection. Main Creatinine clearance less than 40 mL/min** Hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis Admitted to the hospital for drug overdose or other conditions associated with rhabdomyolysis, or is expected to require repeated intramuscular injections Creatine phosphokinase (CPK) level greater than 2.5 times above the upper limit of normal (ULN) at screening; if the elevation in CPK can be attributed to an obvious cause (eg, surgery)** Central nervous system infection Pulmonary infection. (**) An exemption may be granted for patients not satisfying these criteria following a conversation with the Medical Monitor.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gram positive bacterial infections</keyword>
	<keyword>expanded access program</keyword>
	<keyword>resistant infections</keyword>
	<keyword>bacteremia</keyword>
	<keyword>Bacterial and fungal infections</keyword>
	<keyword>bacterial infections</keyword>
</DOC>