<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02052739</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of SAGE-547 in subjects in super-refractory status epilepticus (SRSE).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate SAGE-547 Injection as Adjunctive Therapy for the Treatment of Super-Refractory Status Epilepticus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label study consisting of a Screening period (1 day), 4-day treatment period (96 hours) followed by a 1-day dose taper period (24 hours), a 2-day acute follow-up period, and a 3 week extended follow-up period. On Day 1 of treatment SRSE subjects under seizure suppression or burst-suppression with a continuous IV AED (third-line agent) will be given a 1-hour IV loading infusion of SAGE-547 followed by a maintenance infusion. After 48 hours of SAGE-547 treatment, the continuous IV AED (third-line agent) will be weaned while continuing SAGE-547 at the maintenance infusion for the remainder of the treatment period. After 96 hours (4 days) of therapy with SAGE-547, the dose will be tapered and discontinued over 24 hours. The subjects will have routine continuous EEG monitoring during the Screening period, and continuing until 48 hours after SAGE-547 treatment has completed. Subjects will then have follow-up examinations weekly for the next 3 weeks (Days 8, 15, 22, and 29), during which safety and functional assessments will be obtained. Apart from treatment with SAGE-547, all subjects will receive the standard of care for adults in SRSE along with ongoing treatment for all underlying medical conditions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Status Epilepticus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects 2 years of age and older. Subjects with an EEGconfirmed SRSE diagnosis under concomitant therapy with a continuous IV AED (thirdline agent) for ≥ 24 hours. For this study, SRSE is defined by the following criteria and in accordance with those used at major epilepsy treatment centers: Failure to respond to the administration of at least one firstline agent (e.g., benzodiazepine or other emergent initial AED treatment), according to institution standard of care, and Failure to respond to at least one secondline agent (e.g., phenytoin, fosphenytoin, valproate, phenobarbital, levetiracetam or other urgent control AED) according to institution standard of care, and Presence of one or more breakthrough seizures &gt; 6 hours after initiation of the continuous IV AED/thirdline agent (e.g., pentobarbital, midazolam, propofol) Subjects with SRSE due to anoxic/hypoxic encephalopathy, children (subjects aged less than 18 years) with an encephalopathy due to an underlying progressive neurological disorder. Subjects with clinically significant electrocardiogram (ECG) abnormalities. Subjects with a significant medical or surgical condition that may compromise vital organ systems, or other conditions that would place the subject at increased risk such as dialysis or acute respiratory distress syndrome, severe cardiogenic or vasodilatory shock requiring 2 or more pressors, fulminant hepatic failure, etc. Subjects who are receiving a continuous IV AED (thirdline agent) for seizure suppression or burstsuppression that will require greater than 24 hours to wean.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Status Epilepticus</keyword>
	<keyword>Refractory status epilepticus</keyword>
	<keyword>Super-refractory status epilepticus</keyword>
	<keyword>SAGE-547</keyword>
	<keyword>SAGE</keyword>
	<keyword>Sage Therapeutics</keyword>
</DOC>