<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00855920</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This purpose of this clinical research is to determine the efficacy and safety of an experimental drug called rilonacept in subjects with an acute gout attack. Subjects will participate in in this study for 30 days. Rilonacept alone is being compared with indomethacin alone and the combination of rilonacept plus indomethacin in treating acute gout flares.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Utilizing Rilonacept in Gout Exacerbations</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Gout</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Indomethacin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female 18 70 years of age 2. Previously met the preliminary criteria of ARA for the classification of the acute arthritis of primary gout 3. Presenting with an acute attack (flare) of gout within 48 hours of pain onset and pain of at least moderate severity 4. Must have at least 1 on the 03 scale for the swelling and the tenderness assessments of the gouty index joint 5. Current presentation of acute gout flare in 3 joints or less 1. Treatment with any NSAIDs or opiates within 48 hours prior to baseline assessments. Treatment with longacting NSAIDs within 1 month prior to baseline visit. Treatment with naproxen, meloxicam, nabumetone, celecoxib and indomethacin SR within 5 days prior to baseline visit. 2. Treatment with oral analgesics within 6 hours before baseline assessments. Treatment with topical analgesics within 12 hours before baseline assessments 3. History of NSAID intolerance 4. Subjects with history of chronic, gouty arthritis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metabolism, Inborn Errors</keyword>
	<keyword>Allopurinol</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Genetic Diseases, Inborn</keyword>
	<keyword>Musculoskeletal Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Joint Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>Rheumatic Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Purine-Pyrimidine Metabolism, Inborn Errors</keyword>
	<keyword>Gout</keyword>
	<keyword>Flare</keyword>
</DOC>