<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00855400</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical trial is to asses the feasibility and the security of the intraspinal infusion of autologous bone marrow stem cells for the treatment of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trial on the Use of Autologous Bone Marrow Stem Cells in Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) typically endure a progressive paralysis due to the continued loss of motoneurons that leads them to death in less than 5 years. No treatment has changed its natural history. Intraspinal injections of bone marrow mononuclear cells (MNC) have been able to ameliorate the course of ALS in murine models, acting as pumps of trophic factors that keep the motoneurons functional. We have designed a phase I/II clinical trial to check the feasibility of this approach in humans.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Motor Neuron Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnose established following the World Federation of Neurology criteria More than 6 and less than 36 months of evolution of the disease Medullar onset of the disease More than 20 and less than 65 years old Forced Vital Capacity equal or superior to 50% Total time of oxygen saturation &lt;90% inferior to 2% of the sleeping time Signed informed consent Neurological or psychiatric concomitant disease Need of parenteral or enteral nutrition through percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy or nasogastric tube Concomitant systemic disease Treatment with corticosteroids, immunoglobulins or immunosuppressors during the last 12 months Inclusion in other clinical trials Unability to understand the informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone marrow</keyword>
	<keyword>Stem cells</keyword>
	<keyword>Autologous</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
</DOC>