<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01029795</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to help answer the following research question(s): - To test if taking LY2599506 for 12 weeks controls blood sugar better than taking glyburide for 12 weeks. - To evaluate the safety of LY2599506 in participants with diabetes. - To determine if LY2599506 has the ability to control blood sugar in participants with diabetes. - To determine how much LY2599506 should be given to participants. - To determine if LY2599506 has an effect on a participant's weight. The study design consists of 4 study periods: a screening period, a 4-week dose adjustment period, an 8-week treatment period, and a 4-week follow up period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of LY2599506 (Oral Agent Medication: Glucokinase Activator 1) in Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glyburide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have type 2 diabetes mellitus prior to entering the trial Are currently being treated with diet and exercise therapy consistent with the local standards of medical care Treated with: Diet and exercise alone; or Diet and exercise in combination with a stable dose of metformin for at least 3 months prior to entering the trial; or Diet and exercise in combination with a stable dose of sulfonylurea for at least 3 months prior to entering the trial; or Diet and exercise in combination with stable doses of metformin and sulfonylurea for at least 3 months prior to entering the trial and have had diabetes for at least 6 years. Have an HbA1c value between 7% and 10% Are women not of childbearing potential due to surgical sterilization (hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy or tubal ligation) or menopause. Male patients will be advised to use a reliable method of birth control during the study and until 3 months after the last dose of study medication if their partner is of childbearing potential. Use of insulin or any antidiabetic agent other than metformin or sulfonylurea during the 3 months prior to entering the trial. Have a gastrointestinal disease that significantly impacts gastric emptying or motility (for example, severe gastroparesis or pyloric stenosis), in the opinion of the Investigator, or have undergone gastric bypass or gastric banding surgery. Have had more than 1 episode of severe hypoglycemia within 6 months prior to entry into the study, or are currently diagnosed as having hypoglycemia unawareness Have had 2 or more emergency room visits or hospitalizations due to poor glucose control in the past 6 months. Have cardiac autonomic neuropathy (for example, resting tachycardia or orthostatic hypotension), based on clinical signs, symptoms, or appropriate diagnostic testing. Have cardiac disease with functional status that is New York Heart Association Class II, III, or IV or a history of myocardial infarction, unstable angina, or decompensated congestive heart failure in the past 6 months. Have poorly controlled hypertension (that is, mean systolic blood pressure &gt;160 mm Hg or mean diastolic blood pressure &gt;100 mm Hg) history of malignant hypertension, evidence of renal artery stenosis, and/or evidence of labile blood pressure including symptomatic postural hypotension. Doses of antihypertensive medications must be stable for 30 days before randomization. Have fed or fasting state hypertriglyceridemia (defined as &gt;6.8 millimoles per liter [mmol/L], 600 milligrams per deciliter [mg/dL]) at screening. If taking lipidlowering agents, doses of these medications must be stable for 30 days prior to randomization. Have obvious clinical signs or symptoms of liver disease, acute or chronic hepatitis, or repeated alanine transaminase (ALT) levels &gt;2.5 times the upper limit of the reference range at screening. Have evidence of a significant active, uncontrolled endocrine or autoimmune abnormality, as judged by the Investigator at screening. Have an active or untreated malignancy or have been in remission from a clinically significant malignancy (other than basal or squamous cell skin cancer, in situ carcinomas of the cervix, or in situ prostate cancer) for less than 5 years. Have a history of seizure disorder.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>