<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01029340</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will assess the pharmacokinetics (part A) safety, tolerability, and efficacy of prophylaxis treatment (2 to 3 times a week) (part B) with BAY81-8973 over a one year period (split into two six month treatment periods). The study will compare 2 different methods (assays) for measuring the amount of study drug, the chromogenic substrate assay per European Pharmacopeia (CS/EP) with the classical assay (Chromogenic Substrate Adjusted, CS/ADJ). During one six month period patients will receive the study drug where the dose has been measured using the" (CS/EP) and during the other six months period the dose will be measured based on the Chromogenic Substrate Adjusted assay CS/ADJ)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of a New Full Length Recombinant Human FVIII for Hemophilia A</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Blood Coagulation Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemostatic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Factor VIII</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male, aged 12 to 65 years Severe hemophilia A defined as &lt; 1% FVIII:C &gt;/= 150 days of previous treatment with FVIII in lifetime Currently receiving ondemand or any type of prophylaxis treatment regimen with any FVIII product No history of or current FVIII inhibitors Presence of another bleeding disease that is different from hemophilia A (e.g., von Willebrand disease, hemophilia B) Low platelet count, abnormal kidney function, or liver disease Received treatment with immune suppressing drugs within the last 3 months prior or requires treatment during the study. (Some drugs for hepatitis C, Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), and steroids are allowed) Receiving or has received other experimental drugs within 3 months prior to study entry Allergy to Factor VIII or hamsters or mouse protein</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hemophilia A</keyword>
	<keyword>Factor VIII</keyword>
	<keyword>Prophylaxis</keyword>
</DOC>