<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02463344</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is the long term follow-up of a safety and tolerability trial to evaluate the effect of subretinal injection of human embryonic stem cell derived retinal pigment epithelium cells in patients with Age-Related Macular Degeneration(AMD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long Term Follow Up of Sub-retinal Transplantation of hESC Derived RPE Cells in Patients With AMD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a long term, non interventional follow up to the phase I/II, open-label, non randomized, sequential, multi-center trial (referred to as the core protocol) in which 13 AMD patients were treated. Ten poor vision patients (20/400) were transplanted with sequential doses of hESC-RPE cells, starting at a dose of 50,000 hESC-RPE cells transplanted (three subjects), 100,000 hESC-RPE cells transplanted (three subjects), 150,000 hESC-RPE cells transplanted (three subjects) and increasing to a maximum dose of 200,000 hESC-RPE cells transplanted(one subject). Three better vision patients (20/100) were transplanted with a dose of 100,000 hESC-RPE cells. Eligible patients will be those who sign a consent form for the extension study, and who fulfill all inclusion/exclusion criteria. The first visit of this extension protocol will correspond to the last visit of the core protocol, and will take place at 12 months post cell implantation. During the first 2 years after completion of the core protocol, i.e. from Year 1 to Year 2 and from Year 2 to Year 3 post transplantation, the patients will be evaluated at approximately 3 month intervals; during years three thru five patients will be evaluated at approximately six month intervals. During years 6-15, patients will either be required to return to the study center or provide the name of an ophthalmologist in their locality who would provide an evaluation of the patient's vision and any abnormal findings and report these results to the study site annually. Follow up will include obtaining information about visual acuity, ophthalmological findings and adverse events (AEs), specifically including cancer, neurological, autoimmune or hematological disorders that developed or worsened since the last visit.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must have met the eligibility of the core protocol. Able to understand and willing to sign the informed consent to participate in the follow up. Treated with hESCRPE cell transplant in the core protocol. Previous participation in study Unwilling or unable to participate in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dry AMD</keyword>
	<keyword>Geographic atrophy</keyword>
</DOC>