<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01895010</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Observation on acupoint electric stimulation combined with tropisetron in preventing and treating nausea and vomiting and improving the patient's appetite after TACE for primary or metastatic liver cancer patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acupoint Electric Stimulation Combined With Tropisetron in Preventing and Treating Nausea and Vomiting After TACE</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>- Classification of nausea and vomiting, as measured by NCI CTC-AE version 3 - The improvement of appetite, as measure by the classification of Appetite in accordance with NCI CTC-AE version 3. - Quality of life: use M. D. Anderson symptom scale (the m. d. Anderson Symptom Inventory,MDASI)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Nausea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tropisetron</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ECOG physical status 0,1,2 would accept the transcatheter hepatic arterial chemoembolization of primary or metastatic liver cancer patients; Adult male and female 3, age 18 years old; the chemscheme of arterial infusion chemotherapy based on oxaliplatin dosage of 200mg; signed the informed consent and understand the study design; Organ function examination in patients must meet the following laboratory indexes: Neutrophil&gt;500/Ul, hemoglobin &gt; 8 gm/dL, platelet &gt;100000/uL,Creatinine &lt; 2 mg/dL bilirubin &lt; 1.5 mg/dL, , alanine aminotransferase &lt; 3 times the normal value, albumin &gt;30g/L understand and complete quality of life scale ; women of childbearing age urine pregnancy test was negative. The combined use of other venous chemotherapy within 5 days after TACE; skin infection on or near the points; skin hyperalgesia, unable to withstand electrical stimulation; other confounding factors may cause nausea and vomiting (such as intestinal obstruction, anorexia, etc.); heart, cerebrovascular accident history or the history of spinal cord injury; intestinal obstruction lead to nausea and vomiting installing pacemaker; cognitive dysfunction, unable to finish Scale; currently using acupuncture therapy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>prevention and treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>improvement of the patient's appetite</keyword>
	<keyword>TACE</keyword>
</DOC>