<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01895439</DOC>
	<brief_summary>1. Expanding and priming Bone Marrow (BM)- Mesenchymal Stem Cells (MSCs) to a clinical scale according to Good Laboratory Practice using xenogenic free media instead of the previously used FCS. 2. Assessing the safety of injecting autologous BM-MSCs to Multiple Sclerosis (MS)patients who fail to respond to conventional treatment. 3. Assessing the therapeutic benefits on the participants in the trial as per established methods.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of Autologus Bone Marrow Mesenchymal Stem Cells in Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A clinical diagnosis of definite MS according to the revised McDonald Criteria. Expanded Disability Status Scale (EDSS) ≤ 6 Failure of standard medical therapy Disease duration of at least three years prior to enrollment. Pregnant and lactating women Previous treatment with immunosuppressive agents in the last 12 months prior to enrollment Recent MS relapse in the month prior to enrollment Treatment with oral or parenteral steroids for any cause in the month prior to enrollment Significant systemic medical disorders including cardiac, renal, hepatic, hematologic, immunologic or endocrine disorders Previous treatment with interferons or glatiramer acetate in the 3 months prior to enrollment Any contraindication for magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) or gadolinium contrast. Positive serology for HIV, Hepatitis B or Hepatitis C Any history of malignancy or exposure to radiation at any time prior to enrollment Any contraindication to lumbar puncture Severe cognitive impairment that would interfere with the patient's ability to understand and sign the informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bone marrow derived Mesenchymal Stem Cells</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiple Sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Oligodendrocytes</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuroimmunology</keyword>
	<keyword>Autoimmune disease</keyword>
</DOC>