<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02692703</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety and efficacy of 12 weeks of treatment of ABT-493/ABT-530 in adults who are post primary orthotopic liver or renal transplant with chronic Hepatitis C Virus infection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of ABT-493/ABT-530 in Adult Post-Liver or Post-Renal Transplant Recipients With Chronic Hepatitis C Virus (MAGELLAN-2)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female, at least 18 years of age at time of screening. Screening laboratory result indicating HCV GT1 6 infection. Subject is a recipient of a cadaveric or living donor liver transplant which was a consequence of HCV infection at least 3 months prior to screening Or Subject received a cadaveric or living donor kidney at least 3 months before screening. Subjects must be documented as noncirrhotic. Subject is currently taking a stable immunosuppression regimen based on tacrolimus, sirolimus, everolimus, mycophenolate mofetil (MMF), mycophenolic acid, azathioprine, and/or cyclosporine. Female subject who is pregnant, breastfeeding or is considering becoming pregnant during the study or for approximately 30 days after the last dose of study drug. Clinical history of fibrosing cholestatic hepatitis posttransplant. Retransplantation of the liver or kidney. Steroid resistant rejection of the transplanted liver or kidney, or a history of rejection treated with high dose steroid within 3 months of screening. History of posttransplant complications related to hepatic or renal vasculature.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>HCV Treatment Experienced</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Genotype 3</keyword>
	<keyword>Without cirrhosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-cirrhotic</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Genotype 2</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Treatment Naive</keyword>
	<keyword>Post transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Genotype 6</keyword>
	<keyword>Liver Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Genotype 5</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Genotype 4</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Genotype 1</keyword>
</DOC>