<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02692560</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators are doing a study to learn how to support patients aged 60+ in taking more breaks from sitting and reducing total sitting time. The goal of the study is to find out if a sitting time reduction intervention reduces sitting time compared with a control group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>I-STAND R21: Reducing Sedentary Time in Older Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>More than one-third of American adults over 60 have a body mass index &gt; 30 kg/m2. These older adults have more sedentary time than any other group -- an average of 10-11 hours per day. Reducing the sedentary behavior of older adults with obesity, rather than only promoting more intensive physical activity, could provide a more feasible approach to health promotion. This randomized control pilot trial will evaluate a 12-week intervention to decrease sitting time and increase standing time and light physical activity among sedentary older adults a body mass index &gt; 30 kg/m2 as compared to control group. Baseline and 12-week measurements include anthropometric measures, blood draw by finger stick, cardiovascular health assessments, physical function tasks, and a survey. The intervention will consist of two in-person visits with a health coach followed by phone-based coaching.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Group Health Cooperative enrollees Men and women Age 60 89 BMI 30 50 (calculated based on most recent height ever and most recent weight taken within previous 18 months) Primary care within Integrated Group Practice Continuously enrolled at Group Health Cooperative for previous 12 months No record of death Not on the No Contact list Speaks and writes English Able to hold a conversation by phone (no hearing or other limitations) Selfreported sitting time of 6 hours/day or more Selfreported ability to stand with or without an assistive device Selfreported ability to walk one block with or without an assistive device Available for the study duration Able to come to Group Health Research Institute's research clinic for measurement visits Willing to wear study activity monitors Resides in longterm care, hospice care, or skilled nursing facility (previous 12 months) Wheelchair bound Diagnosis of dementia, serious mental health disorder, or substance use disorder (previous 24 months) Use of an assistive device</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sedentary time</keyword>
	<keyword>Sit-to-stand transitions</keyword>
</DOC>