<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02692157</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Healthy adult men who abuse opioids and are physically dependent on them will be invited to participate in a study to examine the ability of NT-814, a neurokinin (NK) antagonist at the 1 and 3 receptor subtypes, to alter the abuse liability of oxycodone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>NT-814: Evaluation of Its Ability to Alter the Abuse Liability of Oxycodone in an Exploratory Clinical Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After completing the screening process, participants will be scheduled for admission onto the General Clinical Research Unit on 5-South for a 13-week study. During Week 1, participants will be detoxified from opioids. During Week 2 after the detoxification period, participants will be randomized to receive one of four maintenance doses of NT-814. During Weeks 3-4 participants may receive oxycodone during laboratory sessions and will complete a cue exposure session involving presentation of neutral and drug cues. Participants then will have the opportunity to self-administer drug by making clicks on a computer mouse. Weeks 2, 5, 8, and 11 will be medication stabilization weeks following by testing during Weeks 3-4, 6-7, 9-10, and 12-13. At the conclusion of the study, participants will be given an exit interview during which the study will be described. Those who are interested in treatment for their drug use at the end of the study will be offered referrals to studies at our Substance Treatment and Research Service or other treatment providers.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Oxycodone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DSM V criteria for Opioid Use Disorder moderatesevere (304.00) Physically healthy Able to perform study procedures Normal body weight (BMI &lt;30 and &gt;17.5), and total body weight &gt;50 kg (110 lbs) Total testosterone in the laboratory normal range (2501100 ng/dl) Current or history of intranasal opioid use. Must be willing to use adequate forms of contraception (e.g. condoms in combination with spermicide) for the duration of the study and a specified amount of time after participation. On parole or probation Elevated liver function (i.e. AST and ALT &gt;2 times the upper limit of normal) or impaired renal function (creatinine within normal limits) 12lead ECGbased repeated demonstration of QTcF &gt; 450 msec at screening HIV positive Any physical disorders that might make participation hazardous</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>59 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>