<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02692040</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A randomised, placebo controlled Phase I study to investigate the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of G3215 in adult subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Gut Hormone Analogue G3215 in Adult Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objectives: Primary Objective - To investigate the safety and tolerability of single doses of G3215 in overweight but otherwise healthy male subjects. - To investigate the safety and tolerability of multiple doses of G3215 in overweight male subjects with mild stable Type 2 diabetes or prediabetes. Secondary Objectives • To assess the pharmacokinetic (PK) profile of single and multiple ascending doses of G3215 in overweight but otherwise healthy male subjects or overweight / obese male subjects with mild stable Type 2 diabetes or prediabetes. Exploratory Objective • To investigate the effects of multiple doses of G3215 on food consumption, body weight, enteropancreatic hormone changes and glucose tolerance in overweight male subjects with mild Type 2 diabetes or prediabetes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adult males aged 18 to 60 years inclusive with body mass index (BMI) between 25.0 and 35.0 kg/m2 inclusive; 2. Subjects who are otherwise healthy enough to participate, as determined by prestudy medical history, physical examination and 12 lead ECG; 3. Subjects whose clinical laboratory test results are either within the normal range or if outside this range the abnormalities are judged to be not clinically relevant and are acceptable to the Investigator; 4. Subjects who are negative for hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), hepatitis C antibody and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) I and II tests at screening; 5. Subjects who are negative for drugs of abuse and alcohol tests at screening and admissions; 6. Subjects who are nonsmokers for at least 3 months preceding screening; 7. Subjects who agree to use medically acceptable methods of contraception for at least 3 months after study drug administration; 8. Subjects who are able and willing to give written informed consent. 1. Subjects who do not conform to the above inclusion criteria; 2. Subjects who have a clinically relevant history or presence of gastrointestinal (especially associated with vomiting), respiratory, renal, hepatic, haematological, lymphatic, neurological (especially if associated with balance disorders or vomiting e.g. migraine or labyrinthitis), cardiovascular, psychiatric, musculoskeletal, genitourinary, immunological, dermatological, connective tissue diseases or disorders; 3. Subjects who have a clinically relevant surgical history; 4. Subjects who are currently taking thiazolidinediones, dipeptidyl peptidase IV inhibitors ('gliptins'), glucagonlike peptide1 (GLP1) analogues, sodiumglucose cotransporter (SGLT2) inhibitors, and insulin; 5. Subjects who have a history of relevant and severe atopy e.g. asthma, angioedema requiring emergency treatment, severe hayfever requiring regular treatment, severe eczema requiring regular treatment; 6. Subjects who have a history of relevant drug hypersensitivity; 7. Subjects who have a history of alcohol abuse or alcohol dependence according to Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 4th Edition (DSMIV) criteria within the last two years; 8. Subjects who have a history of drug or substance abuse according to DSMIV criteria within the last 2 years; 9. Subjects who have a history of clinically significant migraine as judged by the Investigator. Subjects can be included if they have not had a migraine for the last 3 years; 10. Subjects with a history of pancreatitis or pancreatic cancer; 11. Subjects who consume more than 21 units of alcohol a week (unit = 1 glass of wine (125 mL) = 1 measure of spirits = ½ pint of beer); 12. Subjects who have a significant infection or known inflammatory process on screening; 13. Subjects who have acute gastrointestinal symptoms at the time of screening or admission (e.g. nausea, vomiting, diarrhoea, heartburn); 14. Subjects who have an acute infection such as influenza at the time of screening or admission; 15. Subjects who have used prescription drugs within 2 weeks of first dosing. For Part B, patients are allowed; monotherapy with sulphonylureas, or metformin. In addition patients in Part B are allowed to take hypolipidaemic and/or antihypertensive treatments, provided that the doses have not been altered within the 4 weeks prior to entering the study. Other medications may be allowed if the Investigator and Sponsor both agree that they will not affect the outcome of the study or the safety of the subject. 16. Subjects who have used over the counter medication excluding routine vitamins and paracetamol but including megadose (intake of 20 to 600 times the recommended daily dose) vitamin therapy within 7 days of first dosing, unless agreed as not clinically relevant by the Principal Investigator and Sponsor; 17. Subjects who have donated blood within 3 months prior to screening; Subjects who have donated plasma within the 7 days prior to screening; Subjects who have donated platelets within the 6 weeks prior to screening 18. Subjects who have used any investigational drug in any clinical trial within 3 months of their first admission date; 19. Subjects who have received the last dose of investigational drug greater than 3 months ago but who are on extended followup; 20. Subjects who have previously received G3215; 21. Subjects who are vegans or have any dietary restrictions; 22. Subjects who cannot communicate reliably with the Investigator; 23. Subjects who are unlikely to cooperate with the requirements of the study; 24. History or evidence of abnormal eating behaviour, as observed through the Dutch Eating Behaviour (DEBQ) and SCOFF (Sick, Control, One Stone, Fat, Food) questionnaires at screening.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>glucagon-like peptide-1</keyword>
</DOC>