<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01615991</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Radiation synovectomy by intra-articular injection of beta-emitting radionuclides is considered a reliable and easy-to-perform therapy without harmful side-effects for the treatment of inflammatory joint disease in many countries. The goal of this study is to demonstrate Yttrium-90 citrate colloid or Rhenium-186 sulfide synovectomy are appropriate therapeutic interventions in patients with persistent active synovitis of a joint (characterized by pain, tenderness, and effusion) which is resistant to systemic therapy and intra-articular corticosteroid injections. The primary objective will be to assess the safety of an intra-articular administration of Yttrium-90 citrate colloid or Rhenium-186 sulfide. The secondary objective will be to assess the efficacy on synovitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicentre Canadian Study to Measure the Safety and Efficacy of Radiosynoviorthesis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>There is no age limit for RSO Patient referred by a medical joint specialist (orthopedist, rheumatologist or internal medicine in the absence of local joint specialist) Patient having a refractory inflammatory articular disease: Failure of medical therapy after 6 months Clinical signs of an active mono or oligo synovitis Joint Xray, echo or MR showing minimal cartilage or bone destruction Pain limits normal activities or requires significant analgesic medication Prior RSO within last 3 months in that joint Collapse of the articular plateau or intraarticular fracture Surgery or arthroscopy within last 6 weeks Painful prosthesis Joint infection, local skin infection, bacteremia Joint puncture within last 2 weeks (increased risk of soft tissue necrosis along the needle track) Pregnancy or breast feeding Synovial cyst rupture Massive hemarthrosis Generalized synovitis defined as more than 5 uncontrolled joints by clinical examination or 3 phases bone scan Surgical synovectomy within 6months Cancer with bone metastases Hypersensitivity, allergies or contraindication to the used radiopharmaceutical agent Participation in any other ongoing clinical trial for the underlying inflammatory condition</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>