<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01615718</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study, the investigators aim to investigate the effects of non-invasive neurostimulation - low-intensity transcranial electrical stimulation in conjunction with transcranial ultrasound (TUS)- on the motor symptoms associated with Parkinson's disease. The investigators want to see if there is a difference between active and sham stimulation on these motor symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Non-invasive Neurostimulation in Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Documentation of PD diagnosis from their clinician by either a letter or verification through their medical record Research criteria of "possible" or "probable" PD, as defined by Gelb et al (Gelb D, Oliver E, Gilman S. Diagnostic Criteria for Parkinson Disease. Arch Neurol.1999;56:3339)[1] Age 40 or over; Taking stable medications for at least 30 days Features suggestive of other causes of parkinsonism/Parkinson'splus syndromes; History of deep brain stimulation or ablation surgery, mass brain lesions; History of schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder, other psychosis, episode of bipolar illness, alcohol/drug abuse within the past year; Need for rapid clinical response due to conditions such as initiation, psychosis, or suicidal; Contraindications to transcranial brain stimulation or TUS, i.e. metal in the head, implanted brain medical devices, etc; Unstable medical conditions (e.g. uncontrolled diabetes, uncompensated cardiac issues, heart failure, pulmonary issues, or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease); Pregnancy. Epilepsy or disorders that increase likelihood of seizures including: moderate or severe traumatic brain injury, congenital birth defects leading to seizures, brain tumor, metabolism disorders associated with seizures, and nonlacunar stroke.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>noninvasive stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>motor function</keyword>
	<keyword>transcranial stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>transcranial ultrasound</keyword>
	<keyword>brain stimulation</keyword>
</DOC>