<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02897232</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a minimal risk, anonymous, convenience sample, social behavioral study using qualitative descriptive survey methods. It is to ascertain community member, physician, resident and medical student perspectives regarding Human Papillomavirus (HPV) infection, associated diseases and to identify barriers which prevent these groups from ensuring that males 9-26 receive the three-shot vaccine series to prevent HPV infection. The research is focused on these questions: Do community members understand the ease of transmission of the HPV virus in males 9-26? Do community members, physicians, residents and medical students have knowledge of the associated diseases that may occur with the HPV virus infection in males age 9-26? Do community members, physicians, residents and medical students know the ages in which males should receive the HPV vaccine three-shot series? What barriers prevent community members and physicians, residents and medical students from ensuring that males 9-26 receive the three-shot vaccine series to prevent HPV infection?</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Community and Physician Perspectives Regarding Male Youth Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Disease and Vaccination</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a minimal risk, anonymous, convenience sample, social behavioral study using qualitative descriptive survey methods. It is to ascertain community member, physician, resident and medical student perspectives regarding Human Papillomavirus (HPV) infection, associated diseases and to identify barriers which prevent these groups from ensuring that males 9-26 receive the three-shot vaccine series to prevent HPV infection. The research is focused on these questions: Do community members understand the ease of transmission of the HPV virus in males 9-26? Do community members, physicians, residents and medical students have knowledge of the associated diseases that may occur with the HPV virus infection in males age 9-26? Do community members, physicians, residents and medical students know the ages in which males should receive the HPV vaccine three-shot series? What barriers prevent community members and physicians, residents and medical students from ensuring that males 9-26 receive the three-shot vaccine series to prevent HPV infection?</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Papilloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Papillomavirus Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Community Participants Inclusion All visitors to the Pediatric or Internal Medicine University Health Shreveport Clinics willing to complete a survey Community Study Exclusion Those do not wish to participate in the study Those who English is not their first language Clinical Faculty, Resident, and Medical Student Study Inclusion All Louisiana State University Shreveport Health Clinical Faculty, Resident, and Medical Student Inclusion willing to to complete the online survey. Clinical Faculty, Resident, and Medical Student Study Exclusion Any LSU Health Shreveport Clinical Faculty, Resident, and Medical Student which declines to take the survey or do not attempt to complete it.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Human Papillomavirus Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>HPV</keyword>
	<keyword>Patient Acceptance</keyword>
	<keyword>Physician Comfort</keyword>
	<keyword>Male Vaccination</keyword>
	<keyword>HPV Associated Cancers</keyword>
</DOC>