<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02897180</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The use of a supplement food like "Nyaditum resae" is a reliable opportunity to stop the progression towards active TB through the most updated knowledge of this disease:the induction of tolerance. In order to demonstrate the percentage of efficacy of this approach, different studies must be run to elucidate the percentage of protection in different setting all over the world. The strategy is to establish its efficacy through a simple clinical trial, aimed just to know the incidence of TB in Placebo and NR treated contacts of active TB cases.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Nyaditum Resae(R) Against Active TB in Georgia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Evaluation of a supplement food "Nyaditum resae" in the uincidence of TB. This is a ranzomized doube-blind controlled clinical trial to evaluate the efficacy and safety of a supplememt food in comparison to placebo in TB.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Have completed the written informed consent process prior to undergoing any screening evaluations. 2. Have ability to complete followup period as required by the protocol. 3. Willing to allow the investigators to discuss the subject's medical history with the subject's health care provider. 4. Close contact of an active TB case not eligible for chemoprophylaxis. 1. Investigator assessment of lack of understanding or willingness to participate and comply with all requirements of the trial protocol. 2. Any other finding which in the opinion of the investigator would compromise the protocol compliance or significantly influence the interpretation of results on the effects of the vaccine. 3. Being eligible for chemoprophylaxis (children of &lt;5 years old and HIVpositive adults) 4. Pregnancy or lactation 5. Hypersensitivity to mannitol 6. Suffering active TB</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>tuberculosis</keyword>
	<keyword>latent tuberculosis infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Food supplement</keyword>
	<keyword>Mycobacterium manresensis</keyword>
	<keyword>Nyaditum resae</keyword>
	<keyword>Efficacy trial</keyword>
</DOC>