<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02897115</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A study comparing a treat-to-target (T2T) intense treatment approach in participants with axial spondyloarthritis (axSpA) with routine treatment (Standard of Care (SOC)) concerning a reduction in disease activity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Treating Participants With Early Axial Spondyloarthritis (axSpA) Taking an Intense Treatment Approach Versus Routine Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Spondylarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed written informed consent before start of studyrelated assessments or procedures Diagnosis of axSpA (either ankylosing spondylitis or nonradiographic axSpA) and fulfilling the ASAS classification criteria for axSpA Participants aged &gt;= 18 years Disease duration &lt; 5 years Participants must have a Baseline disease activity as defined by an ASDAS &gt;= 2.1 or a BASDAI &gt;= 4 NSAIDnaive or not treated with the maximal recommended NSAID dose during the last 2 weeks prior to the Baseline visit Participants must never have failed a NSAID taken at maximal recommended dose for 2 weeks or more. Contraindications for NSAIDs or Tumor Necrosis Factor (TNF) blocker according to local labeling If entering the study on concomitant NSAIDs, participants taking the maximal recommended dose during the last 2 weeks prior to the Baseline Visit or have failed or developed intolerance to a NSAID taken at maximal recommended dose for 2 weeks or more at any time Prior exposure to any antiTNF therapy; any biologic therapy with a potential therapeutic impact on SpA, or participant has been treated with any investigational drug of chemical or biologic nature within a minimum of 30 days or five halflives (whichever is longer) of the drug prior to the Baseline visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Humira</keyword>
	<keyword>Axial Spondyloarthritis</keyword>
</DOC>