<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02897596</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluate the efficacy of 12 or 8 weeks treatment with Grazoprevir/Elbasvir in Early Chronic Hepatitis C GT1,4 in HIV co-infected patients and evaluate the safety and tolerability of Grazoprevir + Elbasvir in HIV-HCV co-infected patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of GZR/EBR in Early Chronic Hepatitis C in HIV/HCV Co-infected Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Genotype 1b: 8 weeks treatment with Grazoprevir/Elbasvir Genotype 1a and 4: 12 weeks treatment with Grazoprevir/Elbasvir</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>≥18 years of age Patients with early chronic hepatitis C (Genotype 1 or 4) which is defined as chronic hepatitis C with known episode of AHC within the last 4 years including those who failed to PEG/RBV or those who never received therapy for AHC. AHC infection is diagnosed on the basis of documented HCVRNA positivity (&gt; 10.000 IU/mL) and antiHCV seroconversion. No history of ascites, bleeding esophageal varices, hepatic encephalopathy, or other signs/symptoms of advanced liver disease Have liver disease staging assessment as follows: Fibroscan performed within 3 previous months of Day 1 of this study showing result &lt;8 kPa Be HIV1 infected, documented by any licensed rapid HIV test and confirmed by a licensed Western blot or a second antibody test by a method other than the initial rapid HIV and/or E/CIA, or by HIV1 p24 antigen, or plasma HIV1 RNA viral load. Be on stable HIV Antiretroviral Therapy (ART) for at least 8 weeks prior to study entry using a dual NRTI backbone of tenofovir or abacavir &lt; 18 years of age Patients with chronic hepatitis C genotypes other than 1 or 4. History of ascites, bleeding esophageal varices, hepatic encephalopathy, or other signs/symptoms of advanced liver disease Have liver disease staging assessment as follows: Fibroscan performed within 3 previous months of Day 1 of this study showing result &gt; 8kPa Not be HIV1 infected, documented by any licensed rapid HIV test and confirmed by a licensed Western blot or a second antibody test by a method other than the initial rapid HIV and/or E/CIA, or by HIV1 p24 antigen, or plasma HIV1 RNA viral load. Due to known or suspected drugdrug interactions, for the purpose of this study, the use of Non Nucleoside Reverse Transcriptase Inhibitors, Inhibitors or Protease Inhibitors against HIV will be not allow.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>