<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="160095">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01014533</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HUM00010947</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1R01AA016117-01A1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01014533</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pharmacotherapy and Mechanisms of Sleep Disturbance in Alcohol Dependence</brief_title>
  <acronym>MA</acronym>
  <official_title>This is a Study Exploring the Reasons Why People With Alcohol Dependence Have Sleep Disturbances, and Whether or Not a Study Medication, Gabapentin, vs. Placebo, Affects Those Sleep Patterns.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dr. Kirk Brower</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health (NIH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Michigan</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Insomnia and other sleep abnormalities are common, persistent, and associated with relapse
      in alcohol-dependent patients. The overall, long-term objectives of the proposed research
      are to investigate the neurophysiologic mechanisms of sleep disturbance that are associated
      with relapse in patients with alcohol dependence, and to target those mechanisms with
      medication in order to reduce relapse risk.

      The specific research aims are:

        1. To investigate three potential mechanisms of sleep disturbance in alcoholic patients:
           impaired sleep drive, impaired circadian regulation of alertness, and brain
           hyperactivation;

        2. To investigate short-term effects of medication on sleep and its regulatory mechanisms
           in alcoholics;

        3. To investigate the short-term clinical course of alcoholism as a function of baseline
           sleep parameters.

      In Study Phases I &amp; II (Screening &amp; Baseline: 10+ days), subjects are assessed to diagnose
      alcohol dependence, determine baseline values for drinking and sleeping, and rule out
      confounding sleep-impairing causes.

      Phase III (Medication: 10 days), is a randomized, double-blind parallel design comparison of
      gabapentin vs. placebo on mechanisms of sleep. It is not a therapeutic or clinical trial.
      Phases II &amp; III each have 7 days of monitoring sleep and activity, followed by 3 nights in
      the sleep laboratory to assess all-night EEG activity and Dim-Light Melatonin Onset (DLMO),
      a measure of circadian rhythm.

      Phase IV is a 2-day medication taper and Phase V (Follow-up) consists of one visit after 12
      weeks to assess course of drinking.

      In summary, sleep disturbance in alcoholic patients increases their risk of relapse. This
      study proposes to investigate the mechanisms causing sleep disturbance in alcoholics and to
      determine if those mechanisms predict return to drinking after 12 weeks.

      Relevance: Alcoholism is a devastating chronic disorder that in any one year affects 10% of
      adults, costs over $185 billion, and causes more than 100,000 deaths in the U.S. Despite
      treatment, most alcoholic patients achieve only short-term abstinence. Medically-based
      treatment improvements are needed that target neurophysiologic mechanisms of relapse.
      Overall public health will be improved by developing science-based treatments that can
      augment existing, but only partially effective, treatment approaches.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep architecture (quality of sleep)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relapse to heavy drinking</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">59</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcohol Dependence</condition>
  <condition>Insomnia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Alcohol dependent subjects spend 3 nights in the UM sleep lab, then are randomized to receive either gabapentin or placebo for one week. They then return to the sleep lab for the same procedures. Healthy control subjects don not participate in the medication arm of the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Gabapentin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Alcohol dependent subjects are randomized to receive gabapentin or placebo after spending 3 baseline nights in the UM sleep lab. On Night 8 of medication, subjects return to the UM sleep lab and complete 3 sleep nights with the same procedures.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gabapentin or placebo dispensed to subject.</intervention_name>
    <description>Alcohol dependent subjects have polysomnography in the UM Sleep Lab for three nights, then are randomized to receive gabapentin or placebo for 11 days, (600mg at bedtime on night 1, 1200mg at bedtime on nights 2-10, and 600mg at bedtime on night 11, then D/C). They return to the Sleep Lab for polysomnography on night 8 of medication so their sleep data can be compared.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Gabapentin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Neurontin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gabapentin or placebo dispensed to subject.</intervention_name>
    <description>After spending 3 baseline nights in the UM Sleep Lab, alcohol dependent subjects are randomized to receive either gabapentin or placebo for 11 days. On the 8th night of medication, subjects return to the lab and sleep 3 more nights with the same procedures. Control subjects don't participate in the medication arm of the study; they just complete the first 3 baseline sleep nights.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Gabapentin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Neurontin is the brand name for Gabapentin.</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Meet DSM-IV criteria for alcohol dependence (as confirmed by the SCID)

          -  Between 3 and 12 weeks since last drink (as measured by the TLFB)

          -  At least 2 weeks since last detoxification medication, if relevant

          -  An alcohol withdrawal rating score &lt; 8 (as measured by the CIWA-Ar) to rule out acute
             alcohol withdrawal effects on sleep.

          -  Expresses a desire to stop drinking or a willingness to abstain from alcohol and/or
             other drugs of abuse (except nicotine)

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Subjects who meet DSM-IV criteria for dependence on any psychoactive substance other
             than alcohol (except nicotine) in the past 3 months (per SCID interview).

          -  Subjects with a current (past 1 month) DSM-IV diagnosis of panic disorder,
             generalized anxiety disorder, post-traumatic stress disorder, major depression,
             anorexia nervosa, or bulimia nervosa (per SCID interview) and/or that require ongoing
             psychotropic medication.

          -  Subjects who have a lifetime diagnosis meeting DSM-IV criteria for bipolar disorder,
             schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder, delusional (paranoid) disorders, or
             obsessive-compulsive disorder.

          -  Urine drug screen positive for amphetamines, barbiturates, benzodiazepines, cocaine,
             marijuana, or opioids. (If positive, subjects have one opportunity to test negative
             after a week of abstinence).

          -  Medical disorders or pain syndromes that may affect sleep; history of head trauma
             with loss of consciousness; history of seizures (except alcohol-related seizures).

          -  Subjects with elevated renal tests (blood urea nitrogen or creatinine), because
             gabapentin is renally eliminated, or elevated liver transaminases (&gt;3X normal), or
             abnormal thyroid tests as thyroid problems can affect sleep.

          -  Sleep disorders other than insomnia such as sleep apnea/hypopnea index &gt;10 per hour
             or periodic limb movement disorder; PLM&gt;15 movements per hour with arousals.

          -  On medications known to affect sleep (e.g., antidepressants, anticonvulsants,
             centrally acting antihistamines, neuroleptics, sedative-hypnotics, stimulants,
             centrally acting antihypertensives [alpha-methyldopa, reserpine, clonidine], oral
             corticosteroids, and theophylline within the past 2 weeks or 5 weeks for fluoxetine).

          -  Subjects on medications used to treat addiction (e.g., disulfiram, naltrexone or
             acamprosate) are excluded because of unknown effects on sleep.

          -  Subjects who do evening or midnight shift work. (Subjects who have traveled across
             multiple time zones in the previous two weeks will be included only at the discretion
             of the P.I.)

          -  Pregnancy, breast feeding, or inadequate contraception in women of child-bearing
             potential.

          -  Subjects who are unable or unlikely to follow the study protocol in the investigator
             's opinion, because of cognitive deficits (Mini-Mental State Exam score &lt; 27), a
             personality disorder, a serious suicide risk, dangerousness to others, illiteracy, or
             unstable or distant living situation.

          -  Subjects with a known allergy, hypersensitivity or contraindication to study
             medication.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kirk J Brower, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Michigan</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Michigan Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 23, 2013</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>November 16, 2009</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Michigan</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Kirk Brower</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Psychiatry</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Alcoholism</keyword>
  <keyword>Alcohol dependence</keyword>
  <keyword>Insomnia</keyword>
  <keyword>Dim light melatonin onset</keyword>
  <keyword>Gabapentin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dyssomnias</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gabapentin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>gamma-Aminobutyric Acid</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
