<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00578526</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out if SU011248 works and if it is safe in patients with advanced transitional cell carcinoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SU011248 for Platinum-Refractory Urothelial Cancer Evaluation Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study objectives include the determination of the antitumor effect of SU011248 in patients with urothelial transitional cell carcinoma and to also determine the toxicities and tolerability of SU011248 in patients with urothelial transitional cell carcinoma who have failed or are intolerant to cisplatin-based chemotherapy. The primary endpoint of the study is to compare progression free survival at 4 months in patients who received SU011248 plus BSC versus patients who received placebo plus BSC The secondary endpoint is to compare the objective response rate and duration of response in patients who received SU011248 plus BSC versus patients who received placebo plus BSC, to describe the QOL and safety profile of SU011248 when compared to placebo and to describe the overall survival in patients who received SU011248 plus BSC versus patients who received placebo plus BSC</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sunitinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically/cytologically proven inoperable, metastatic or recurrent transitional cell carcinoma of the urothelial tract Mixed histology with predominant TCC allowed. Failed, intolerant or ineligible for cisplatin based chemo Measurable Disease (RECIST)Not previously irradiated. Recovered from previous acute treatment to grade 1(CTCAE Vers. 3.0) No weight loss &gt;/ 10% within 28 days of day 0 Adequate Organ Function Adenocarcinoma, squamous carcinoma or other histology without any components of transitional carcinoma. Small cell histology More than one previous systemic chemo Excised metastases without remaining measureable disease Prior therapy with angiogenesis inhibitors</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>urothelial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>targeted therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>antiangiogenesis therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>SU011248</keyword>
	<keyword>clinical trial</keyword>
</DOC>