<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00578942</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Allogeneic transplantation is used to treat many malignant and non-malignant diseases, though the potential toxicities of the procedure remain high. We and others have shown that a less toxic preparative regimen allows reliable allogeneic engraftment for allogeneic transplantation. The primary purpose of this treatment trial is to follow subjects undergoing allogeneic transplantation for long term outcomes. The regimen used has been tested in our prior phase I / II trial which has completed accrual. The issues of engraftment and rate of graft versus host disease have been answered and our success has led to this regimen being a standard approach for less toxic allogeneic therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Allo Non-myeloablative SCT Utilizing Matched Family Member Stem Cells Purged Using Campath</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Allogeneic bone marrow transplantation may cure or ameliorate illnesses of many types; however the toxicity of the procedure limits its broad applicability. Hematologic malignancies of all types have shown responses. Those with marrow failure, such as aplasia, and hemoglobinopathies have further shown responses in multiple trials as well. Even patients with certain solid tumors, such as breast, renal cell, and melanoma have shown partial or complete responses to allogeneic therapy. The limiting effect of the historical methods of aggressive induction for allogeneic therapy were extremely toxic, requiring limiting those offered allogeneic therapy to the healthiest of the ill patients. Work over the last decade has shown that less toxic agents targeting the immune system effectively allowed engraftment with less effects on the patient's liver, lungs, and other vital organs. We and others have completed multiple trials showing the effective use of these less toxic, non-myeloablative, regimens for allogeneic therapy. Trials with fludarabine and cyclophosphamide at standard doses (patients are not ablated and recover blood counts in 2 weeks) allow for 80% of patients to engraft donor cells. Some groups have added low doses of radiation to this combination, with 80-100% allogeneic engraftment. The lessened toxicity of this approach has been confirmed in multiple studies, including our own data with the specific schema in this treatment plan reviewed below. Phase I results with this combination: Our group has combined the above combination of fludarabine and cyclophosphamide with the antibody CAMPATH 1H. This antibody is given to the patient to purge the immune system and prevent rejection. It also purges the T cells in the donated stem cells to minimize graft versus host disease (GVHD). This approach has been proven successful in multiple trials using standard more toxic ablative procedures. Our approach over the last 3 years has been very successful using this antibody with the less toxic non-myeloablative procedure and our trials have completed. We have presented our preliminary results, with data on long term follow up for outcomes being collected. We have shown that 100% of patients with a malignancy or marrow failure treated with this regimen in our early phase trial engrafted donor cells. There was only an 8% severe GVHD risk, though the risk for infection remains high with a risk of fungal and viral infection about 5% each. Despite working with older, more infirmed patients, only 3/40 patients died within the first 100 days from therapy. Similar approaches on matched unrelated donors have been reported by other groups as well. As the phase I feasibility trial is complete and the outcomes encouraging, this protocol will follow the same general treatment plan and allow further information to be gained for long term follow up of subjects treated with this approach.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alemtuzumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must have their pathology reviewed and the diagnosis confirmed. Performance status must be Cancer and Leukemia Group B (CALGB) performance score 0, 1, or 2 Subjects must have a 6/6 Human leukocyte antigen (HLA)matched related donor who is evaluated and deemed able to provide peripheral blood progenitor cells (PBPC) and/or marrow by the transplant team. HIV antibody negative. Subjects must test negative serum betahuman chorionic gonadotropin (HCG) and must agree to use some form of adequate birth control during the periods they receive chemotherapy and any postchemotherapy medications related to the transplant. Subjects must be &gt;/=17 years of age Subjects must also have a resting multigated acquisition (MUGA) and/or ECHO and pulmonary function test (PFT) with diffusion capacity of lung (DLCO) performed before transplant and found to be acceptable according to the treating institution's guidelines. The required minimum standards include MUGA and/or ECHO showing an ejection fraction (EF) of 40% and PFTs showing DLCO of 40%. Those with an EF 4050%, undergo cardiac evaluation and consultation. Also, those with DLCO 4050%, undergo pulmonary evaluation and consultation. Specific populations for each disease category: A) Hematologic malignancies Those with high risk or relapsed hematologic malignancy (including myeloid and lymphoid leukemias and lymphomas, myeloma or myelomatous like diseases, myeloproliferative disease, myelodysplasia). Those with good risk disease (first remission acute myeloid leukemia (AML) with inv 16 M4 Eos, M3 AML with t(15;17); or t(8;21) in first remission are not eligible). B) Bone marrow failure 1. Those specifically with idiopathic or secondary moderate, severe or very severe aplastic anemia (idiopathic or secondary) according to the accepted 'Camitta criteria' would be candidates. 2. Those with diseases known to lead to severe marrow failure are eligible as well. These include those with myelofibrosis or paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria (PNH). C) Solid Tumors Subjects must have had a biopsy confirming disease recurrence (metastases) at some point in their history, unless the patient presented with metastatic disease, in which case the initial primary site biopsy is adequate. 1. Subjects with renal cell cancer, or melanoma will be eligible for this approach at this time. Subjects will have had documented metastatic disease at some time in the past. Subjects who are in remission or with residual disease after prior therapy for their metastatic disease are eligible, as there is no accepted cure for these patients with metastatic disease. 2. Breast Cancer Subjects will have had documented metastatic disease at some time in the past. Subjects who are in remission or with residual disease after prior therapy for their metastatic disease are eligible. Subjects must have failed at least one chemotherapy regimen for their metastatic disease and 1 hormonal agent if they are receptor positive. 1. pregnant or lactating women, 2. patients with other major medical or psychiatric illnesses which the treating physician feels could seriously compromise tolerance to this protocol, and 3. Leukemia patients in first remission with good risk cytogenetics for leukemia [t(15;17); t(8,22)]</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Allogeneic Stem Cell Transplantation, Campath, HLA-Matched</keyword>
</DOC>