<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02695667</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Quantitative Genioglossal muscle strength in Obstructive Sleep Apnea (OSAS) defined in the clinical spectrum of subjects with Snoring Disturbance, Oral Appliance Therapy Responsive, and CPAP Responsive</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Genioglossus Strength and OSAS</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To describe by statistical analysis the normal distribution domain of genioglossus muscle strength in each of the four clinical stages of Sleep Apnea; and, by regression analysis, to explore the possibility of an inverse relationship between decreasing genioglossus strength and progression of the clinical stages of OSAS. 1.3. To test the hypothesis that a "subpopulation of subject" exists within the clinical spectrum of OSAS, in whom decreasing strength of the genioglossus muscle may represent a common element in spite of differing possible pathophysiologic pathways leading to Obstructive Sleep Apnea in man. 1.4. The major hypothesis of this proposal is thus that "Genioglossal Strength is inversely correlated with Obstructive Sleep Apnea Pathology."</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 2040 years inclusive BMI 1825 Nonsmoking history and no current use for a minimum of 6 months No smokeless tobacco products (including ecigarettes) for a minimum of 6 months No sleep snoring reported by subject and by bedroom "companion" Selfdescribed as active/athletic (i.e. regular hikes, walks, jogging, running, active Sports, such as volleyball, soccer, etc.) Selfdescribed as healthy, with no known disease or recent illness Selfcompleted Epworth Sleepiness Scale of &lt;6 (Johns, MW, A new method for Measuring daytime sleepiness: the Epworth Sleepiness Scale; SLEEP 14:4505, 1991). Physical Examination Mallampati Score of Class 1 (Nuckton, TJ, et al: Physical Examination: Mallampati Score as an Independent Predictor of OSAS; SLEEP 29: 903908, 2006).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>