<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02013336</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 1 study of the combination of two drugs: MM-398 and Cyclophosphamide. The goal is to find the highest dose of MM-398 that can be given safely when it is used together with the chemotherapy drug Cyclophosphamide.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 1 Study of MM-398 Plus Cyclophosphamide in Pediatric Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma, Ewing</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhabdomyosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologicallyconfirmed Ewing sarcoma, rhabdomyosarcoma, neuroblastoma, or osteosarcoma Disease progression after prior therapy in locally advanced or metastatic setting Measurable or evaluable disease based on the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST v1.1) criteria Age 12 months to &lt;21 years Adequate bone marrow reserves, hepatic function, and renal function Recovered from effects of any prior surgery or cancer therapy Patients 18 years or older will provide written consent. A parent or legal guardian of a patient &lt;18 years of age will provide informed consent and patients 11 to 18 years of age will provide written assent or as per participating institutional policy. Clinically significant gastrointestinal disorders NYHA Class III or IV congestive heart failure, ventricular arrhythmias or uncontrolled blood pressure Active infection or unexplained fever Known hypersensitivity to any of the components of MM398 or other liposomal products Recent Investigational therapy Pregnant or breast feeding; females of childbearing potential must test negative for pregnancy at the time of enrollment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>20 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>pediatric</keyword>
	<keyword>MM-398</keyword>
	<keyword>cyclophosphamide</keyword>
	<keyword>irinotecan</keyword>
</DOC>