<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02399644</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Only to a limited extent has been compared the effectiveness of physical exercise and psychological interventions in subjects with chronic pain. Knowledge about this is necessary in order to compose optimal multimodal rehabilitation programs at different health care levels. Moreover, assuming that both types of interventions have effects, these effects may necessarily not concern the same outcome variables. Therefore it may be important to understand to what extent the effects overlap and the extent to which the effects are isolated to an intervention. The overall strategic purpose of the present study is to develop effective multimodal rehabilitation programs. In this study the effectiveness of following three interventions are compared. - Group-based rehabilitation according to a concept based on an Acceptance and Commitment Training -Stress Management Intervention (ACT-SMI) - Group-based rehabilitation compromised of physical exercise (Exercise). - Group-based discussion concerning pain and its consequences (i.e., the control group, CON) The effectiveness is investigated with respect to long-term effects on pain and its consequences, including perceived health and return to work / sick leave. The overall hypothesis is that the former intervention means better long-term results because it clearly helps the individual to process the psychological aspects of itself likely to have long lasting effects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physical Activity and Acceptance and Commitment Therapy as Treatment for Long Term Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>chronic pain in the neck and/or back with or without pain in one or more quadrants of the body Inflammatory and neurological diseases, severe social and/or psychological problems, patients that already have taken part in multidisciplinary rehabilitation programs</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>psychological</keyword>
	<keyword>intervention</keyword>
</DOC>