<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02672878</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Treatment of patients with in-stent restenosis (ISR) remains a challenge. This study will assess the efficacy of Bioresorbable Vascular Scaffolds (BVS) (Abbott Vascular) in the treatment of patients suffering from ISR.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Restenosis Intrastent: Bioresorbable Vascular Scaffolds Treatment (RIBS VI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Treatment of patients with ISR remains a challenge. Currently both drug-eluting stents (DES) and drug-coated balloons (DCB) are considered as the strategies of choice in this setting. However, data on the value of BVS in patients with ISR is scarce. BVS are very effective to inhibit neointimal proliferation and they avoid the need of implanting a new permanent metal layer. Accordingly, currently, there is a major interest to elucidate the potential value of BVS in patients with ISR. This prospective Spanish multicenter study will assess the clinical and angiographic outcome of patients with ISR treated with BVS. BVS will be implanted in selected patients (fulfilling inclusion and exclusion criteria) presenting with either BMS-ISR or DES-ISR. Care will be paid to ensure device optimization. Angiographic follow-up will be obtained at 6-9 months. A centralized angiographic corelab will be used to provide QCA measurements. Clinical follow-up will be also obtained at 1 year and then yearly. Clinical events will be adjudicated by an independent Clinical Event Committee.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Instent restenosis with ischemia. Signed Informed Consent IRB approval INCLUSION CRITERIA: PATIENT Age &gt; 20 and &lt; 85 years of age Acceptance of late angiographic evaluation Angina or objective evidence of ischemia LESION ISR (&gt;50% diameter stenosis on visual assessment) Previous stent location known EXCLUSION CRITERIA: PATIENT Inclusion in other clinical research protocol Allergy to antiplatelet agents Women in childbearing age Severe associated systemic diseases (including renal or liver failure) or diseases affecting life expectancy Recent myocardial infarction Time from index stent implantation &lt; 1 month Anticipated difficulties for late angiographic evaluation LESION Stent thrombosis or large thrombus within the stent Angiographic failure during initial stent implantation or persistence or large dissection. Severe tortuosity or calcification or major difficulties during previous stent implantation Vessel diameter &lt; 2.25 mm (visual assessment) Stenosis outside stent stent edge (edge ISR are eligible) Very diffuse ISR (&gt;30 mm in length)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>In-stent restenosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Bioresorbable vascular scaffold</keyword>
	<keyword>Stent</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug-eluting stent</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary angiography</keyword>
</DOC>