<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02672917</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Phase I Safety and Tolerability Study in Subjects with Pancreatic Cancer or Other CA19-9 Positive Malignancies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of HuMab-5B1 (MVT-5873) in Subjects With Pancreatic Cancer or Other Cancer Antigen 19-9 (CA19-9) Positive Malignancies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Open label, multi-center, nonrandomized, dose escalation trial of MVT-5873 to evaluate safety and determine the MTD and recommended phase II dose of MVT-5873 both as monotherapy (Group A) and in combination with a standard of care chemotherapy (Group B) in subjects with pancreatic and other CA19-9 positive malignancies. Both groups will utilize a conventional 3+3 study design to identify the MTD and recommended phase II dose (RP2D). following determination of MTD, 10 additional subjects will be treated at the RP2D in each group. The pharmacokinetics (PK) of MVT-5873 will be determined in each Group.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 1. Signed, informed consent 2. Age 18 or more years 3. Histologically confirmed, locallyadvanced or metastatic pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) or other CA199 positive malignancies 4. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 or 1 or KPS of 100% to 80% 5. Adequate hematologic, hepatic, and renal function Exclusion Criteria 1. Brain metastases unless previously treated and well controlled for at least 3 months 2. Other known active cancer(s) likely to require treatment in the next two (2) years 3. Active, uncontrolled bacterial, viral, or fungal infection(s) requiring systemic therapy 4. Fewer than 28 days from prior anticancer therapy including chemotherapy, hormonal, investigational, and/or biological therapies and irradiation except for prostate cancer hormonal therapy, and treatment with MVT5873 and MVT2163. 5. Major surgery other than diagnostic surgery within 28 days of Study Day 1 6. History of anaphylactic reaction to human, or humanized, antibody 7. Pregnant or currently breastfeeding 8. Known HIVpositive or Hepatitis C 9. Psychiatric illness/social situations that would interfere with compliance with study requirements 10. Significant cardiovascular risk including, but not limited to, recent (within 4 weeks) coronary stenting or myocardial infarction within 6 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>CA19-9 Positive Malignancies</keyword>
</DOC>