<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02672345</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cardiac surgery has evolved considerably after the advent of cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB), a feature that allowed more precision and tranquility to the heart surgeon. But their influence on exacerbation of inflammatory response can unbalance the whole homeostasis so happens surgical trauma. The attenuation of the systemic inflammatory response in major surgeries like cardiac surgery for aortic aneurysm appears to represent an important advance in reducing morbidity and mortality of these patients. Some studies suggest that inhaled anesthetics such as sevoflurane appear to play an important role in this control, but the mechanism by which this happens is still unclear. This study has the primary purpose of analyzing from a clinical study sevoflurane inhalation anesthetic can change the inflammatory response induced by CPB, significantly reducing the release of inflammatory markers, especially elastase PMN.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Systemic Inflammatory Response Evaluation With the Use of Inhaled Anesthetic Sevoflurane During CPB</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sevoflurane</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age over 18 years Cardiac Surgery elective ascending thoracic aortic aneurysm repair with cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB) The informed consent signature savvy Use of steroids or antiinflammatory drugs routine Presence of asthma, COPD, autoimmune diseases Participation in other clinical studies Presence of heart failures (functional class III or IV), liver or kidney Combined elective surgery (ex .: aneurysm correction + CABG) Acute myocardial infarction in the last 30 days Unstable angina And obesity (BMI&gt; 30kg / m2)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sevoflurane</keyword>
	<keyword>MicroRNAs</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammatory Response</keyword>
	<keyword>Cytokines</keyword>
	<keyword>Anesthetics, Inhalation</keyword>
	<keyword>Macrophage Inflammatory Proteins</keyword>
</DOC>