<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01201759</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall study objectives are to examine whether: 1. Persons with spinal cord injury (SCI) having elevated body mass are at greater cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk for fasting and postprandial lipidemia, glycemia, and vascular inflammation than persons with SCI having 'normal' body mass, and 2. An inexpensive, low-risk, widely-available pharmacotherapy safely reduces CVD risks associated with fasting and postprandial lipidemia, glycemia, and vascular inflammation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Salsalate on Prandial-Induced Vascular Inflammation After Spinal Cord Injury (SCI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To test Study Objective 1, 'overweight' and 'non-overweight' persons with SCI will be compared at baseline for fasting and postprandial responses. For Study Objective 2, all persons tested for Study Objective 1 will undergo randomization to either 1 month of Salsalate (4.0 g/day) or placebo. An untreated wash-in (1 month) will precede treatment (1 month), and a washout cross-over period (1 month) will follow. The last month will test effects of drug-placebo not examined in month 2. Fasting and postprandial responses will be tested at each time point. Intention-to-treat clinical standards ("…as randomized, so analyzed…") and 'last observation carried forward' clinical methods will be adopted. Participants with tetraplegia are sought, as they have fewer exercise options than those with paraplegia and are at greater risk for sedentary lifestyle resulting in CVD, CVD risks, and obesity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Salicylsalicylic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sodium Salicylate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>SCI resulting in tetraplegia at C3C7 injury for more than one year 1. any recent dietary or other lifestyle changes; 2. diabetes or inflammatory medical conditions; 3. a pressure ulcer; 4. lung or bladder infection; 5. undiagnosed illness or fever; 6. recent surgery; 7. stomach ulcer or a history of stomach upset when taking aspirin or medicines like aspirin, or , 8. currently taking medicines used for pain or inflammation (aspirin and nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs, corticosteroids), blood vessel diseases (statins or fibric acid derivatives), blood clotting disorders (Coumadin, Plavix), infections (antibiotics), diabetes (Metformin), and burning 'central' pain (voltage regulators).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>cardiovascular risk</keyword>
</DOC>