<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02024412</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The morbidity of colorectal cancer(CRC) is 10%～15% in China.mFolfox6 has become one of the standard regimes for metastatic colorectal cancer (mCRC). Neutropenia and oxaliplatin-induced neurotoxicity are the most common adverse effects which even result in discontinue of chemotherapy, especially for patients suffered from heavily acute neurotoxicity. Monosialotetrahexosylganglioside is a component of membrane of nerve cells. Previous phase II clinical trial showed, it can reduce oxaliplatin-induced neurotoxicity(OIN). But it did not certificated by phase III trial. Investigators designed the phase III trial to investigate the effect and safety of monosialotetrahexosylganglioside Sodium Injection for prevention OIN at colorectal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Monosialotetrahexosylganglioside Sodium Injection for Prevention Neurotoxicity of mFOLFOX 6 in mCRC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>it is a placebo controlled phase III trial. investigators plan to enroll 240 patients with 1:1 to A arm and B arm</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neurotoxicity Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients shall have normal organic function such as liver function, Cardiac function and renal function; 2. age &gt;18 years old; 3. diagnosis mCRC with histology; 4. Did not received firstline chemotherapy 5. Karnofsky Performance scores &gt;70 scores 6. should have target lesions or nontarget lesions 7. For patients received oxaliplatin before, the residual neurotoxicity should less than grade 2 8. For diabetes without neuropathy, blood glucose before meal should less than 8mmol/L and HBA1C&lt;7.0% 9. Patients should be expected to live no shorter than 3 months 1. patients who is receiving chemotherapy; 2. WBC＜4.0×109/L，ANC＜1.5×109/L,PLT＜100×109/L，Hb＜90g/L,TBIL＞1.5Limitation;BUN）＞1.5Limitation；Cr）＞1.5Limitation；ALT or AST＞2.5Limitation（without liver metastasis）；ALT or AST）＞5Limitation（with liver metastasis）; 3. heart dysfunction; 4. brain metastasis; 5. peripheral nervous system or central nervous system abnormal including diabetes mellitus patients with neuropathy; 6. patients who received Glutathione, acetylcysteine, calcium / magnesium, amifostine, carbamazepine, B vitamins, vitamin E within 30 days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>metastatic colorectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>neurotoxicity</keyword>
	<keyword>mFOLFOX6</keyword>
	<keyword>monosialotetrahexosylganglioside Sodium Injection</keyword>
</DOC>