<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00019994</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Vaccines may make the body build an immune response to kill tumor cells. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of vaccine therapy in treating patients who have metastatic melanoma that has not responded to previous therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vaccine Therapy in Treating Patients With Metastatic Melanoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the clinical response to immunization using gp100:44-59 antigen peptide plus gp100:209-217 (210M) and MART-1:26-35 (27L) antigen peptides in patients with metastatic melanoma who are HLA-DRB1*0401 and HLA-A0201 positive. - Determine the clinical response to immunization using gp100:44-59 antigen peptide alone in patients with metastatic melanoma who are HLA-DRB1*0401 positive but HLA-A0201 negative. - Determine the immunologic response in patients treated with these regimens as measured by changes in T-cell precursors from before to after treatment. - Evaluate the toxicity profiles of these regimens in these patients. OUTLINE: Patients are assigned to one of three immunization groups based on HLA-A0201 status and prior gp100:209-217 (210M) antigen peptide immunization: - Group 1 (HLA-A0201 positive and no prior gp100:209-217 [210M] antigen peptide): Patients receive gp100:44-59 and gp100:209-217 (210M) antigen peptides emulsified together in Montanide ISA-51 (ISA-51) subcutaneously (SC) and gp100:44-59 and MART-1:26-35 (27L) antigen peptides emulsified together in ISA-51 SC. - Group 2 (HLA-A0201 positive and prior gp100:209-217 [210M] antigen peptide): Patients receive treatment as in group 1. - Group 3 (HLA-A0201 negative and no prior gp100:209-217 [210M] antigen peptide): Patients receive gp100:44-59 antigen peptide emulsified in ISA-51 SC alone. - All groups: Treatment repeats every 3 weeks for 4 doses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients with complete response after 4 doses receive a maximum of 2 additional doses. Patients with stable disease or minor, mixed, or partial response after 4 doses receive a maximum of 12 additional doses. Patients with no response after 4 doses receive immunization with the same peptides and interleukin-2 IV over 15 minutes every 8 hours for a maximum of 12 doses beginning 1 day after each immunization. Patients are followed at 3-4 weeks. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 45-75 patients (15-25 per immunization group) will be accrued for this study within 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aldesleukin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Freund's Adjuvant</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically proven metastatic melanoma that has failed standard treatment HLADRB1*0401 positive Known HLAA0201 status PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 16 and over Performance status: ECOG 02 Life expectancy: More than 3 months Hematopoietic: WBC at least 3,000/mm^3 Platelet count at least 90,000/mm^3 Hepatic: Bilirubin no greater than 2.0 mg/dL AST or ALT less than 3 times normal Hepatitis B surface antigen negative Renal: Creatinine no greater than 2.0 mg/dL Cardiovascular: No symptomatic cardiac disease Immunologic: No autoimmune disease No primary or secondary immunodeficiency disease HIV negative Other: Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception No active systemic infection PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: No prior immunization to the entire gp100 molecule At least 3 weeks since prior gp100:209217 antigen peptide At least 3 weeks since other prior biologic therapy Chemotherapy: At least 3 weeks since prior chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: At least 3 weeks since prior endocrine therapy No concurrent steroid therapy Radiotherapy: At least 3 weeks since prior radiotherapy Surgery: Prior surgery for cancer allowed Other: At least 3 weeks since any prior therapy except surgery for cancer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2003</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IV melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent melanoma</keyword>
</DOC>