<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00019461</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of carboxyamidotriazole in treating patients with refractory or recurrent ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, or primary peritoneal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Carboxyamidotriazole in Treating Patients With Refractory or Recurrent Ovarian Epithelial, Fallopian Tube, or Primary Peritoneal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the clinical outcome in patients with ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, or primary peritoneal cancer treated with carboxyamidotriazole. OUTLINE: Patients receive oral carboxyamidotriazole daily beginning on day 1. Treatment continues in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 19-40 patients will be accrued for this study within 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peritoneal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboxyamido-triazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed refractory or recurrent ovarian epithelial, fallopian tube, or primary peritoneal cancer Measurable disease by physical exam, radiography, peritoneoscopy, or laparoscopy No more than 4 weeks since prior peritoneoscopy No brain metastases PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: ECOG 02 Life expectancy: At least 4 months Hematopoietic: Absolute neutrophil count at least 1,000/mm^3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin at least 9.0 g/dL AND/OR Hematocrit at least 27% Hepatic: SGOT/SGPT no greater than 3 times upper limit of normal Bilirubin normal Renal: Creatinine no greater than 1.5 mg/dL OR Creatinine clearance at least 50 mL/min Cardiovascular: No history of symptomatic cardiac dysrhythmias requiring medication At least 6 months since prior myocardial infarction No unstable or newly diagnosed angina Pulmonary: No obstructive lung disease requiring oxygen therapy Other: Not pregnant or nursing HIV negative Must be able to take oral medication No concurrent medical condition (e.g., impending bowel obstruction) No grade 2 or greater residual peripheral neuropathy No active infection No other prior or concurrent invasive malignancy within the past 5 years No history of acute visual loss other than that associated with retinal detachment PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: At least 4 weeks since prior cytokine therapy No concurrent cytokine therapy to maintain WBC count Chemotherapy: At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy (6 weeks for nitrosoureas, carboplatin, or mitomycin) No other concurrent chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: At least 4 weeks since prior hormonal therapy No concurrent corticosteroids at doses greater than physiological replacement doses No concurrent hormonal therapy Radiotherapy: At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy No concurrent radiotherapy Surgery: See Disease Characteristics Other: No more than 3 prior treatment regimens At least 1 week since prior systemic antibiotics for infection No chronic antifungal treatment with antimycotic imidazoles No concurrent alternative therapies</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2003</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent ovarian epithelial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>fallopian tube cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>primary peritoneal cavity cancer</keyword>
</DOC>