<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01394497</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Randomized prospective study on the impact on the post-LT outcome by the infusion of N-acetylcysteine (NAC) during the liver procurement procedure, as an anti-oxidant agent to reduce the ischemia-reperfusion damage of organs for liver transplantation (LT).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of N-Acetylcysteine During Liver Procurement</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Anti-oxidant agents have the potential to reduce the ischemia-reperfusion damage of organs for liver transplantation (LT). In this randomized prospective study, we seek to study the impact on the post-LT outcome of the infusion of N-acetylcysteine (NAC) during the liver procurement procedure. Potential grafts, assigned to adult candidates with chronic liver disease enlisted for first LT, will randomly be included in a one‑to‑one ratio with a sequential closed envelope single-blinded assignation procedure to either the NAC protocol or in the standard procedure (without NAC). The NAC protocol comprises: a systemic NAC infusion (30 mg/kg) one hour before the beginning of liver procurement; a loco-regional NAC infusion (300 mg through the portal vein) just before cross‑clamping.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Failure, Acute</mesh_term>
	<criteria>all consecutive subjects with chronic liver disease undergoing first Liver Transplantation receiving deceased donor livers recipients with acute liver disease; paediatric patients or adult patients receiving a liver from a paediatric donor; patients undergoing multipleorgan transplantation; patients undergoing retransplantation of the Liver; patients undergoing living donor Liver Transplantation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Liver Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Graft Survival</keyword>
	<keyword>Graft Rejection</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary Graft Dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Tissue and Organ Harvesting</keyword>
	<keyword>Tissue and Organ Procurement</keyword>
	<keyword>Tissue Donors</keyword>
	<keyword>Cold Ischemia</keyword>
</DOC>