<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="32727">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02680613</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Q-6015511</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02680613</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pilot Study of a Mobile Health Approach to Reduce Barriers to Cervical Cancer Screening in Tanzania</brief_title>
  <acronym>KCCPAS</acronym>
  <official_title>Pilot Study of a Mobile Health Approach to Reduce Barriers to Cervical Cancer Screening in Tanzania</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Queen's University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Terry Fox Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Queen's University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether motivational text messages and/or travel
      vouchers are effective in increasing cervical cancer screening rates in urban and rural
      regions of Northern Tanzania.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction:

      Cervical cancer is the leading cause of cancer-related deaths in Tanzania. The age-adjusted
      incidence rate is estimated to be 54 cases per 100,000 (IARC, 2012) and 80% of Tanzanian
      women affected by cervical cancer will die due to advanced stage at diagnosis (Kahesa, et
      al., 2012). Visual Inspection of the cervix under Acetic Acid (VIA) is an effective
      alternative to the Pap smear, unavailable in most low-resource countries due to weak health
      systems (Palanuwong, 2007). Nurses typically receive 6 days of training before returning to
      their communities to provide VIA; however, they often face a total lack of oversight to
      ensure they are providing quality screening and cryotherapy. This lack of quality control
      has prevented a decline in cervical cancer morbidity and mortality despite significant
      investment and implementation of VIA programs.

      The Kilimanjaro Cervical Cancer Screening Project (KCCP) is a pilot study of 1000 women that
      developed and tested a cervicography (taking a digital photo of the cervix) training method
      using a smartphone camera in the hands of nurses performing cervical cancer screening and
      receiving 'real time' mentorship through a closed user group of image transfer and guidance
      by cervicographers located elsewhere in Tanzania. A pilot study completed in February 2015
      showed that this method provides safe and high quality screening and the method is moving to
      implementation and scale up within multiple VIA programs in late 2015 (Yeates et al.,
      Manuscript in preparation). The KCCP continues to screen patients and this provides a
      significant opportunity to perform further research that will inform the scale-up program.

      Measures to encourage increased uptake of cervical cancer screening in the region, and in
      many low-resource contexts are drastically needed to reduce the burden of cervical cancer in
      these contexts. The prevalence of screening in the Kilimanjaro is 6%(Cunningham et al,
      2015), which is close to the WHO figure of 5% of women in developing countries having been
      screened in the last five years (World Health Organization, 1986). The largest perceived
      barriers to cervical cancer screening in the Kilimanjaro region were found to be a lack of
      knowledge that screening services were available and women anticipated that they would not
      be able to afford the costs associated with screening, including travel (Cunningham et al,
      2015).

      Objectives:

      A) To determine attitudes, barriers and enablers towards smartphone cervicography to ensure
      an accessible, culturally relevant smartphone cervicography screening program

      B) To evaluate the impact of a voucher for return transportation towards increasing cervical
      cancer screening attendance

      C) To evaluate the impact of motivational text messages towards increasing cervical cancer
      screening attendance

      Methodology:

      This study will comprise of a descriptive cross-sectional survey and a randomized controlled
      trial (RCT). Household surveys, capturing baseline characteristics, using stratified
      systematic random sampling in urban and rural areas will be used to recruit participants for
      the RCT. Cross-sectional survey participants will be recruited opportunistically at
      screening clinics associated with the study.

      Participants will be randomized into one of three arms. The first arm will be a control
      group and will not receive any correspondence. The second arm will receive a series of
      motivational text messages, including screening dates and locations. The third group will
      receive a travel voucher code via SMS and motivational text messages with the same content
      as the second group.

      A post-screening survey will be conducted following cervical cancer screening at clinics
      participating in the study to evaluate screening attendance and attitudes towards smartphone
      digital cervicography.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cervical Cancer Screening Attendance survey</measure>
    <time_frame>within 1 month from recruitment into study</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Satisfaction with Smartphone Digital Cervicography survey</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Cervical Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Motivational SMS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will receive 10-12 motivational SMS about cervical cancer and screening.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Travel Voucher</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will receive a voucher covering return transport from the screening clinic. This arm will also receive identical 10-12 motivational SMS about cervical cancer and screening as the Motivational SMS arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will receive no intervention during the study and follow-up period. At the conclusion of the study, participants in the arm will receive identical motivational SMS as the other two arms.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Motivational SMS</intervention_name>
    <description>Behaviour change messages delivered via SMS developed with the theoretical guidance of the Health Belief Model.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Motivational SMS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Travel Voucher</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Travel Voucher</intervention_name>
    <description>A code for return public transportation to closest cervical cancer screening clinic included in the research.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Travel Voucher</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Own a mobile phone or have access to husband's mobile phone

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Previous history of cervical cancer or hysterectomy

          -  Having been screened for cervical cancer in the past year
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Karen Yeates, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Queen's University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Karen Yeates, MD MPH</last_name>
    <phone>613-533-6730</phone>
    <email>yeatesk@queensu.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Olola Oneko, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+255754478917</phone>
    <email>ololaoneko03@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pamoja Tunaweza Women's Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moshi</city>
        <state>Kilimanjaro</state>
        <zip>PO Box 8434</zip>
        <country>Tanzania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Erica Erwin, B SocSci</last_name>
      <phone>+255767933364</phone>
      <email>14ee3@queensu.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Olola Oneko, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Erica Erwin, B SocSci</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Karen Yeates, MD MPH</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jessica Sleeth, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Tanzania</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cunningham MS, Skrastins E, Fitzpatrick R, Jindal P, Oneko O, Yeates K, Booth CM, Carpenter J, Aronson KJ. Cervical cancer screening and HPV vaccine acceptability among rural and urban women in Kilimanjaro Region, Tanzania. BMJ Open. 2015 Mar 10;5(3):e005828. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2014-005828.</citation>
    <PMID>25757944</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kahesa C, Kjaer S, Mwaiselage J, Ngoma T, Tersbol B, Dartell M, Rasch V. Determinants of acceptance of cervical cancer screening in Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. BMC Public Health. 2012 Dec 19;12:1093. doi: 10.1186/1471-2458-12-1093.</citation>
    <PMID>23253445</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yeates, K., Sleeth, J., Hopman, W., Heus, K., Msuya, A., Macheku, G., Oneko, O. et al. The evaluation of a smartphone-based mHealth strategy among non-physician health workers to screen for cervical cancer in Tanzania: The Kilimanjaro Method (manuscript in Preparation).</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>World Health Organization, International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC) (2012). WHO 2012 estimated cancer incidence, mortality and prevalence in 2012 Available at: http://globocan.iarc.fr/Pages/fact_sheets_population.aspx Accessed February 25, 2015</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Palanuwong B. Alternative cervical cancer prevention in low-resource settings: Experiences of visual inspection by acetic acid with single-visit approach in the first five provinces of Thailand. Aust N Z J Obstet Gynaecol. 2007 Feb;47(1):54-60.</citation>
    <PMID>17261102</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 12, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 9, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Queen's University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Karen Yeates</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
