<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00642954</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this Phase I study of vorinostat in combination with lenalidomide and dexamethasone in participants with relapsed or refractory multiple myeloma is to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D). The safety and tolerability of the combination regimen will also be evaluated in this study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vorinostat (MK-0683, SAHA [Suberoylanilide Hydroxamic Acid]) + Lenalidomide + Dexamethasone in Multiple Myeloma (MM) (MK-0683-074)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenalidomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vorinostat</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thalidomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participant is a male or female at least 18 years old Participant has relapsed or refractory MM and has had at least one prior therapy Female participants of childbearing potential must have 2 negative serum pregnancy tests prior to receiving the first dose of study drugs Female participants who can become pregnant must agree to use 2 separate forms of effective birth control at the same time, 4 weeks before, while taking, and for 4 weeks after stopping lenalidomide. Post menopausal participants should be free from menses for &gt;2 years, or are surgically sterilized Male participant agrees to use an adequate method of contraception for the duration of the study, even if the participant has undergone a successful vasectomy Male participants must agree to use a latex condom during sexual contact with a pregnant female or a female who can become pregnant. This is required for the duration of the study, and for 4 weeks after stopping therapy Participant has at least 3 weeks washout prior to treatment Participant is able to swallow capsules and is able to take or tolerate oral medications on a continuous basis Participant has prior treatment with an histone deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitor Participant has prior allogenetic bone marrow transplant Participant has received intravenous antibiotics, antiviral, or antifungal agents within 2 weeks prior to the start of the study drug Participant uses illicit drugs, substance abuse or had a recent history (within the last year) of drug or alcohol abuse Participant is pregnant or breast feeding or expecting to have a baby during the course of the study Participant has human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection Participant has Hepatitis B/C infection Participant is currently receiving treatment for another type of cancer other than skin or cervical cancer that has not been in remission for 5 years or longer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>