<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00642460</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the efficacy and safety of RoActemra/Actemra (tocilizumab) in patients with active systemic juvenile idiopathic arthritis (sJIA) who have an inadequate clinical response to NSAIDs and corticosteroids. In Part I of the study patients will be randomized 2:1 to receive iv infusions of RoActemra/Actemra (8mg/kg iv for patients &gt;=30kg, or 12mg/kg for patients &lt;30kg) or placebo, every 2 weeks. Stable NSAIDs and methotrexate will be continued throughout. After 12 weeks of double-blind treatment, all patients will have the option to enter Part II of the study to receive open-label treatment with RoActemra/Actemra for a further 92 weeks, followed by a 3-year continuation of the study in Part III in which, for patients who meet specific criteria, an optional alternative dosing schedule decreasing the study drug administration frequency will be introduced. Anticipated time on study treatment is up to 5 years.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of RoActemra/Actemra (Tocilizumab) in Patients With Active Systemic Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis (JIA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients aged 217 years of age Systemic juvenile idiopathic arthritis with &gt;= 6 months persistent activity Presence of active disease (&gt;=5 active joints, or &gt;=2 active joints + fever + steroids) Inadequate clinical response to nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) and corticosteroids due to toxicity or lack of efficacy Wheelchairbound or bedridden Any other autoimmune, rheumatic disease or overlap syndrome other than systemic juvenile idiopathic arthritis Intravenous longacting corticosteroids or intraarticular corticosteroids within 4 weeks of baseline, or throughout study Diseasemodifying antirheumatic drugs (DMARDs), other than methotrexate Previous treatment with tocilizumab</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>