<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00642343</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose is to test the balance of children with unilateral,bilateral cochlear implants and patients having unilateral implants before,bilateral implants after surgery,using the Bruininks-Oseretsky Test 2nd ed. to find out if the cochlear implants have an effect.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Balance in Children With Cochlear Implants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Hearing impairment has a significant impact on individual quality of life and stresses community resources. In the last two decades cochlear implantation has developed into the new standard of care for severe to profound haring loss. Recent studies have shown bilateral implantation improves sound localization and understanding of speech in noise. For children, this is seen as a significant benefit. As we begin to offer bilateral cochlear implants to a growing number of children it would be in our patient's best interest to evaluate whether or not this may cause balance impairment. We will evaluate the balance scores of children with bilateral cochlear implants, and compare their results to unilaterally implanted children and a hearing impaired population, with the Bruininks-Oseretsky Test 2nd ed (BOT2). In addition we will take a small group of unilaterally implanted patients and test them before and after a contralateral cochlear implant as a prospective study group.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Deafness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hearing Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children with cochlear implant(s) activated for at least two weeks before participation. Children with severe to profound deafness that have not received intervention. Children with mental retardation, associated physical handicaps, or chronic sedative use prohibiting completion of the balance tests.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Balance</keyword>
	<keyword>Severe, Profound deafness</keyword>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
	<keyword>unilateral/bilateral cochlear implants</keyword>
	<keyword>unilateral cochlear implant</keyword>
	<keyword>bilateral cochlear implants</keyword>
</DOC>