<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02497794</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a randomised controlled trial that included 150 pregnant women undergoing cesarean in Sisli Ethal Training and Research Hospital, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Istanbul, Turkey. It was carried out in the period from October 1, 2015 to December 31, 2015. After operation, the participants are going to randomly assigned into two groups by using cards. The patients are going to randomized into two groups by using a sealed enveloped system.The patients in the study group, will chew one sugar less gum for 30 minutes in postoperative 3., 5. and 7. hours. The control group will be followed without chew gum. All patients will note the time of first rumbling of the stomach, first feeling of hunger and the first gas outlet.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Gum Chewing on Bowel Function After Cesarean Section</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>For elective cases, all participants are going to given nothing by mouth since midnight before surgery, and all operations are going to perform in the morning. For those who had emergency cesarean section, nothing is going to given per oral for at least 4 hours before the start of the operation. Operation data is going to recorded including surgical setting, type of cesarean section, previous surgery, adhesion and operation time. After operation, the participants are going to randomly assigned into two groups by using cards. The patients are going to randomized into two groups by using a sealed enveloped system. A blue card and an orange card are going to sealed in separate envelopes. Blue card means patients will chewgum. The patients in the study group, will chew one sugar less gum for 30 minutes in postoperative 3., 5. and 7. hours. The control group will be followed without chew gum. Both patient groups will be mobilized in postoperative 6 hour and 8 hour after the operation, juicy food will be given. It will be introduced to solid foods after bowel movements and gas output occurs. All patients postoperatively 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 24 and 48 hours will be examined and bowel sounds will be oscult. Gas evolution is still not, enema will be applied. All patients will note the time of first rumbling of the stomach, first feeling of hunger and the first gas outlet.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. pregnant women who is at least 18 years of age 2. pregnant women whose body mass index is under 35 3. pregnant women who is going to have cesarean section. 1. cesarean hysterectomy, 2. surgical management of severe postpartum hemorrhage 3. previous bowel surgery 4. women with history of drug consumption,especially opioids 5. water and electrolyte disturbances 6. pancreatitis or peritonitis 7. inability to chew gum 8. diabetes, pregnancies accompanied by coagulopathy like preeclampsia, hypothyroidism, muscular and neurological disorders 9. postoperative admission to intensive care unit 10. history of abdominal surgery except cesarean section 11. history of postoperative ileus 12. patients with drains</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>44 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>chew gum</keyword>
	<keyword>bowel movements</keyword>
	<keyword>cesarean section</keyword>
</DOC>