<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02497040</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Ninety American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) Physical Status classification system I-II patients were recruited for a randomised, placebo-controlled, double-blind study and were randomly divided into three groups to receive either 20 ml of 0.5% bupivacaine (Group B; n=30), 20 ml of 0.5% levobupivacaine (Group L; n=30) or saline as a placebo (Group C; n=30). Scalp block was performed 5 min before head pinning. Systolic, diastolic and mean arterial pressure (MAP), heart rate (HR), peripheral oxygen saturation and end-tidal carbon dioxide were recorded. Postoperative pain was evaluated using a 10-cm visual analogue scale (VAS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effects of Scalp Block With Bupivacaine Versus Levobupivacaine</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Following approval from the Research Ethics Committee of the Medical Faculty of Uludağ University, (the date and protocol number assigned by this ethics committee were March 4, 2008 and 5/30, respectively),written informed consent was obtained from patients undergoing elective scheduled operations involving craniotomy during anaesthesia consultations. Ninety American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) Physical Status classification system I or II patients of either sex between 18-85 years of age were allocated to this randomised, prospective, placebo-controlled, double-blind study. The patients were randomly divided into three groups using a sealed-enveloped technique to receive either 20 ml of 0.5% bupivacaine (Group B (n=30)), 20 ml of 0.5% levobupivacaine (Group L (n=30)) or saline as a placebo (Group C (n=30)). Twenty-millilitre syringes for the block were prepared and numbered by a blinded assistant.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levobupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) Physical Status classification system 12 Uncontrolled hypertension, arrhythmia, diabetes mellitus or coagulopathy, coronary artery disease or a proven or suspected allergy to bupivacaine or levobupivacaine</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>craniotomy</keyword>
	<keyword>local anesthetics</keyword>
	<keyword>scalp block</keyword>
	<keyword>head pinning</keyword>
</DOC>