<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02497638</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is a randomized trial examining the administration of a combination of biguanide metformin and atorvastatin ("Lipitor") to men who are experiencing rising prostate-specific antigen (PSA) levels, despite having undergone radical therapy (surgery and/or radiation).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>LIpitor and biGuanide to Androgen Delay Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atorvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Willing and able to provide informed consent Histologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the prostate History of radical therapy (i.e., radical prostatectomy, radiotherapy, brachytherapy or prostatectomy with salvage radiotherapy) Serum testosterone levels 8.0 nmol/L (230 ng/dL) or greater Not currently undergoing treatment for hyperlipidemia or diabetes mellitus LDLcholesterol levels 5 mmol/L or lower HgA1c 6.5% or lower PSA levels between 2 and 5 ng/mL Subjects that have been treated for prostate cancer with any of the following: i. Cytotoxic chemotherapy; ii. Hormonal therapy within past 3 years; iii. Oral glucocorticoids; iv. Gonadotropinreleasing hormone (GnRH) analogues (e.g., leuprolide, goserelin, degarelix) Past treatment with the 5α reductase inhibitors finasteride and dutasteride within past 5 years Past treatment with drugs with antiandrogenic properties (e.g., flutamide, bicalutamide, ketoconazole, progestational agents) within 6 months prior to screening Use of metformin or statins within past 2 years Planned or concurrent use of metformin, sulfonylureas, thiazolidinediones or insulin for any reason Known hypersensitivity or intolerance to metformin or atorvastatin Any clinically significant laboratory abnormalities (e.g., severe renal or hepatic impairment) which in the judgment of the investigator would affect the patient's health or the outcome of the trial Any condition associated with increased risk of metforminassociated lactic acidosis (e.g., congestive heart failure defined as New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III or IV, history of any type of acidosis, habitual intake of 4 or more alcoholic beverages per day) Abnormal liver function test Abnormal organ and marrow function</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>metformin</keyword>
	<keyword>atorvastatin</keyword>
	<keyword>prostate-specific antigen</keyword>
	<keyword>biochemical recurrence</keyword>
</DOC>