<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02497066</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this protocol is to determine the effectiveness of using compounded topical pain creams for treating neuropathic, nociceptive, or mixed-pain syndromes. Since these compounded pain creams may be associated with burning or irritation at the application site, and possible systemic effects may present, the secondary objective is to determine the relative satisfaction with the creams. The investigators hypothesis is that the active pain creams may provide significant benefit compared to placebo cream. 3.1 Specific Aims 1. Specific Aim 1 will determine pain relief following treatment with the appropriate (based on specified pain) compounded topical pain cream or a placebo cream. The investigators hypothesis is that the compounded topical pain creams will provide greater pain relief than placebo creams. 2. Specific Aim 2 will measure the patient satisfaction with the cream (compound or placebo). The investigators hypothesis is that the compounded topical pain creams will improve patient satisfaction, while the placebo cream will not result in a change in patient satisfaction with their pain treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Study Comparing Compounded Topical Pain Creams vs. Placebo for Treating Pain Symptoms</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this study, the investigators are attempting to determine whether compounded topical pain creams are more effective than placebo; as well as measuring the subjects' satisfaction with the compounded pain creams. Three different compounded pain creams (specific to the type of pain being treated) will be used to examine effectiveness and satisfaction in treating neuropathic, nociceptive, or mixed pain syndromes. Up to 399 subjects will be randomized to receive a compounded pain cream or placebo. The type of pain cream to be used will be based on the subjects' pain diagnosis. Pain relief will be measured by a 0-10 Numeric Rating Scale and satisfaction by a 1-5 Likert Satisfaction Scale. The outcome measures will include a 'positive outcome' defined as a two point or greater reduction in average pain (as measured by a NRS) and a score of 4 or 5 (on a 1-5 Likert scale measuring satisfaction) at 1-month. The investigators will use the Rand Corporation SF-36 to measure changes in health status during enrollment. Subjects who obtain benefit at 1-month will be followed at 3-months, while those who fail to obtain benefit (i.e., ≥ 2 point reduction in NRS with a 4 or 5 Likert satisfaction score) will exit the study to receive alternative care. Patients will be given a pain diary so that their NRS can be calculated at follow up visits.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age &gt; 18;90 2. A localized pain complaint to include: the low back, neck, groin, buttocks or up to two extremities 3. Average pain score ≥ 4/10 over the past week; 4. Pain duration &gt; 6 weeks 5. DEERS eligibility. 1. Previous prescription for a compounded pain cream. 2. Cannot read or understand English. 3. Allergic reaction to Ketamine, Gabapentin, Diclofenac, Baclofen, Cyclobenzaprine, Ketoprofen, Clonidine or lidocaine. 4. Pregnancy. Ruling out pregnancy will be done in accordance with our standard procedures, which is to obtain a urine HCG in any female of childbearing age who may be pregnant prior to starting any new medications.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>topical</keyword>
	<keyword>compound</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
</DOC>