<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00336401</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Non-cardiac surgery is associated with significant cardiac morbidity and mortality. Volatile anesthetics have a cardioprotective effects which results in preservation of left ventricular function and lower troponin I levels. Lower troponin release has been correlated with better long term event free survival in both cardiac and non cardiac surgery. A recently completed meta-analysis suggests that sevoflurane is a superior volatile agent. The evidence of a cardioprotective effect in non-cardiac surgery is lacking. Base on the current literature, we intend to evaluate the protective potential of sevoflurane versus propofol anesthesia in high risk patients undergoing elective non-cardiac procedures. Hypothesis: The use of Sevoflurane as a general anesthetic reduces postoperative troponin release, the incidence of myocardial infarction and/or long term morbidity in patients at low to moderate risk of postoperative cardiac complications, who are undergoing noncardiac surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Peri-Operative And Long-Term Cardioprotective Properties Of Sevoflurane In High Risk Patients Undergoing Non-Cardiac Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Propofol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sevoflurane</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Any patient undergoing noncardiac surgery is eligible if s/he: 1.) is ≥45 years old;2.) Has an expected length of stay ≥48 hours; AND3.) Fulfills any 2 of the six criteria for high cardiac risk as defined by the revised Cardiac Risk Index.(see details in protocol)4.) Informed consent Exclusion criteria:A patient will be ineligible for this study if s/he:1) Prior adverse reaction to sevoflurane (MH patient) or propofol.2) Previous coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) surgery with complete revascularization in the preceding five years with no evidence of cardiac ischemia since the procedure; or3) Has concomitant lifethreatening disease likely to limit life expectancy to &lt;30 days.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>anesthesia</keyword>
	<keyword>non cardiac surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiac outcomes</keyword>
</DOC>