<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02845076</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Noninvasive ventilation (NIV) weaning strategies differ considerably from one another. These strategies have yet not been compared to each other. Therefore, the investigators planned to perform a prospective, randomized, pilot study involving hypercapnic acute respiratory failure patients ready to be weaned off from NIV. The investigators are going to compare the success rate of NIV weaning and the duration of NIV after randomization between 3 NIV weaning methods: gradual decrease in duration of NIV or level of ventilator support, and abrupt discontinuation of NIV.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Weaning From Noninvasive Ventilation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypercapnia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients will be screened by the physician 24 hours (±6 hours) after initiation of NIV treatment if: Age ≥18 years old Hypercapnic ARF ( baseline pH&lt;7.35, paCO2&gt;45 mmHg, BORG&gt;4) Breathing frequency&lt; 25 bpm under NIV pH &gt;7.35 under NIV 20% or more decrease from baseline PaCO2 under NIV Kelly ≤ 2 under NIV (Alert. Follows simple/3 step complex commands) PaO2 between 60 and 70 mmHg under NIV No need for sedation Systolic blood pressure 90180 mmHg without vasopressors Body temperature 3638°C Heart rate 50120 bpm The patient will be enrolled to the study and will be randomized to one of the NIV weaning protocols, if passes daily weaning criteria listed below after 1 hour of spontaneous breathing (with supplementary oxygen), Respiratory rate 830 bpm Systolic blood pressure 90180 mmHg without vasopressors Body temperature 3638°C Heart rate 50120 bpm Neurologic score of Kelly ≤2 (Alert. Follows simple/ 3step complex commands), SaO2 ≥8892% with a FiO2≤40%. pH≥7.35 Absence of severe dyspnea (BORG&gt;4). Age &lt;18 years old NIV use at home for chronic respiratory failure CPAP use for acute respiratory failure NIV use as palliative treatment Severe heart failure with cardiac index ≤ 2 L/min/m2 Severe hepatic failure with bilirubin ≥ 34.2µmol/L Severe renal failure with creatinine ≥ 220 µmol/L</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Noninvasive ventilation</keyword>
	<keyword>Respiratory insufficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypercapnia</keyword>
	<keyword>ventilator weaning</keyword>
</DOC>