<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02845453</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether quetiapine is effective in the treatment of youth with co-occurring substance use disorders and bipolar disorder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment With Quetiapine for Youth With Substance Use Disorders and Bipolar Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Quetiapine Fumarate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female age 15 to 24 Meet DSM5 criteria for a substance use disorder Substance use ≥ 14 days of past 28 days (i.e. use ≥ 50% of days in the past 28 days) If subject in restricted setting/care (e.g. detox or residential treatment) for ≤ 2 weeks, then use ≥ 50% of days while outside of restricted setting (e.g. 7 days of substance use out of 14 days in unrestricted setting) Meet DSM5 criteria for bipolar disorder YMRS ≥ 20 Stable to be treated in outpatient level of care Current opioid or methamphetamine use disorder Pregnant or breastfeeding Placement in a restricted setting (e.g. detox or residential treatment) for ≥ 2 weeks out of past 28 days Unwilling or unable to use effective birth control Unwilling or unable to sign release of information for the treatment program providing behavioral treatment For participants &gt;17 years—unable or unwilling to identify emergency contact Medical or psychiatric condition likely to make participation unsafe as judged by the clinical investigator History of QTc&gt;450 or arrhythmia, family history of malignant arrhythmia, for sudden death AST or ALT greater than three times normal BMI ≥ 95th percentile Poor command of the English language Current treatment with quetiapine, or an allergy to quetiapine</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>youth</keyword>
	<keyword>adolescent</keyword>
	<keyword>young adult</keyword>
	<keyword>substance use disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>bipolar disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>quetiapine</keyword>
</DOC>