<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02845908</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study was to compare the efficacy and safety of FOLFOX, POF and FOLFOX plus paclitaxel(ip) as first-line treatment in AGC a phase II clinical trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>POF Versus FOLFOX Versus FOLFOX Plus ip Paclitaxel in AGC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The biweekly 5-fluorouracil and leucovorin (LV5FU2) regimen associated with oxaliplatin (FOLFOX) is active in patients with AGC. Meanwhile, Paclitaxel monotherapy is also active in patients with AGC. In previous studies, we found that POF(A combination of oxaliplatin, fluorouracil and Paclitaxel) regimen appears to be of good efficacy and is well tolerated in patients with advanced gastric cancer. This study is being done to find out if three drugs combination maintain manageable side effects but have better benefit than two drugs combination. Intraperitoneal paclitaxel showed high local concentration in abdominal cavity and low systemic toxicity. This study is being done to find out if the combination with Intraperitoneal paclitaxel and FOLFOX have higher local control rate and lower systemic toxicity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ECOGPS 01 Age: 7075 years old; ECOGPS 02 Age: 1870 years old; Patients must have histologically or cytologically confirmed metastatic or unresectable gastric or gastroesophageal junction (GEJ) adenocarcinoma. GEJ adenocarcinoma may be classified according to Siewert's classification type I, II, or III Histological documentation of local recurrence or metastasis is strongly encouraged, unless the risk of such a procedure outweighs the potential benefit of confirming the metastatic disease. If no histologic confirmation, then the metastases or recurrence will require documentation by a 2nd radiographic procedure (eg. PET/CT scan or MRI in addition to the CT scan). If the imaging procedure does not confirm recurrent or metastatic disease, biopsy confirmation will be required. Patients must have disease that can be evaluated radiographically. This may be measurable disease or nonmeasurable disease. Measurable disease is defined as that which can be measured in at least one dimension as &gt; 20 mm with conventional techniques, or &gt;10 mm by high resolution imaging. Disease that is identified on radiology studies, but does not meet the criteria for measurable disease, is considered nonmeasurable. Patients may have received no prior chemotherapy for metastatic or unresectable disease. Patients may have received prior adjuvant therapy (chemotherapy and/or chemoradiation) if more than 6 months have elapsed between the end of adjuvant therapy and registration. Patients may not have received prior oxaliplatin, fluorouracil or Paclitaxel. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status (ECOG PS) of 02; An expected survival of ≥ 3 months; Major organ function has to meet the following criteria; (1) For results of blood routine test: Hemoglobin (HB) ≥ 80g / L, ANC(absolute neutrophil count) ≥ 1.5 × 109 / L, PLT(blood platelet) ≥ 75 × 109 / L, (2) For results of biochemical tests: BLT（total bilirubin） ≤ 1.25 times the upper limit of normal (ULN), ALT(Alanine aminotransferase) and AST(aspartate aminotransferase ) ≤ 2.5 × ·ULN, liver metastases, if any, the ALT and AST≤ 5 × ULN, Serum Cr（creatinine）≤1ULN, Endogenous creatinine clearance rate ＞50ml/min; The patient has a PT（prothrombintime） (INR international normalized ratio) &lt; or = to 1.5 and an PTT（Partial Thromboplastin Time）&lt; than or = to 3 seconds above the upper limits of normal if the patientia t is not on anticoagulation. ·If a patient is on fulldose anticoagulants, the following criteria should be met for enrollment: The patient must have an inrange INR (usually between 2 and 3) on a stable dose of warfarin or on stable dose of LMW(Low molecular weight) heparin The patient must not have active bleeding or pathological conditions that carry high risk of bleeding (e.g. tumor involving major vessels, known varices) Pregnancy test (serum or urine) has to be performed for woman of childbearing age within 7 days before enrolment and the test result must be negative. Men and women of childbearing potential must be willing to consent to using effective contraception while on treatment and for at least 3 months thereafter. Ability to understand informed consent and signing of written informed consent document prior to initiation of protocol therapy. Patients who have received previous chemotherapy for the treatment of metastatic or unresectable gastric or GEJ adenocarcinoma are ineligible. Patients who have received previous pre or postoperative chemotherapy or chemoradiation are ineligible if therapy was completed less than 6 months prior to study registration. Patients must have recovered from adverse events from any previous therapy. Patients who have received previous oxaliplatin, fluorouracil or Paclitaxel. Patients with a history of another neoplastic disease within the past three years, excluding basal cell carcinoma of the skin, cervical carcinoma in situ, or nonmetastatic prostate cancer. Patients with brain or central nervous system metastases, including leptomeningeal disease. Pregnant (positive pregnancy test) or breast feeding. Serious, nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture. Significant cardiac disease as defined as: unstable angina, New York Heart Association (NYHA) grade II or greater, congestive heart failure, history of myocardial infarction within 6 months Evidence of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy. History of a stroke or CVA within 6 months Clinically significant peripheral vascular disease. Inability to comply with study and/or followup procedures. Patients with any other medical condition or reason, in that investigator's opinion, makes the patient unstable to participate in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>