<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01444664</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this prospective registry is to determine if patients harboring intracranial aneurysms have any predictive markers between aneurysm wall tissue, cerebrospinal fluid and blood plasma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aneurysm Wall Histology Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To design a registry to evaluate the wall of intracranial aneurysms during open surgical clipping by direct photographic appearance, wall biopsy samples, CSF and blood plasma fluid collection (Interleukins; IL-8/ Matrix Metalloproteinase; MMP-9) for complete evaluation and comparison. The focus of the registry will be to determine the presence of aneurysmal wall defects, mural clot, atherosclerotic and atheroma, wall permeability and delamination. These findings will then be correlated to the collected CSF and blood values to determine if there is any direct features of the aneurysm wall that would predict any of the reported post embolic syndromes. The collected data can also be correlated to the peroperative imaging, (MRI, CT and Angiogram).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intracranial Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient &gt; 18 years but &lt; 80 years of age Patient with an unruptured Intracranial aneurysm 8mm or larger Patient that surgical exposure and clipping will be the primary treatment option Any patient that has a ruptured intracranial aneurysm Any Pediatric patients Any patient presenting with any pretreatment intracranial lesions Vascular malformations Hemorrhage Normal Pressure Hydrocephalus Obstructive Hydrocephalus White matter disease Tumors Trauma Other vascular type lesions Any meningitis type symptoms Medical or surgical comorbidities such that the patient's life expectancy is less than 1 year Inability to obtain consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>