<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01444456</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicenter, international, prospective, observational study of patients who are receiving systemic chemotherapy for solid tumour cancers (breast, colorectal, ovarian, prostate, lung, bladder, endometrial, renal, pancreatic, esophageal or gastric) and who are receiving darbepoetin alfa (Aranesp®) or other erythropoiesis-stimulating agent (ESA) to treat symptomatic anaemia. Quality of Life will be assessed electronically with the aim of estimating improvement in quality of life for those patients receiving darbepoetin alfa (Aranesp®) who also have an increase in haemoglobin (Hb) of ≥1 g/dL</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of Quality of Life in Patients With Symptomatic Chemotherapy-induced Anaemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Before enrolling participants, each country was assigned to either cohort 1 (patients receiving only darbepoetin alfa) or cohort 2 (patients receiving any ESA). Cohort 2 was assigned only to those countries in which local regulations did not permit observational study participation by patients receiving a specific agent in a drug class.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Darbepoetin alfa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosed with breast, colorectal, ovarian, prostate, lung, bladder, endometrial, renal, pancreatic, esophageal or gastric cancer Expected to receive at least 8 additional weeks of a given regimen of myelosuppressive chemotherapy after enrolment Starting treatment with either darbepoetin alfa (in Cohort 1 countries) or any ESA (in Cohort 2 countries) as per European Summary of Product Characteristics (SPC) for symptomatic anaemia. Received any ESA treatment or Red Blood Cell (RBC) transfusion within 28 days prior to enrolment Known primary benign or malignant haematologic disorder which can cause anaemia Known hypersensitivity to ESAs</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Ovarian Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostate Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Colorectal Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Aranesp</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemotherapy induced anaemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Bladder Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Endometrial Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Esophageal Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Gastric Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>