<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01444196</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the study is to assess the dosis of DL which is sufficient to inhibit cold urticaria symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Desloratadine 5, 10 and 20mg in Patients With Cold Urticaria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A total of 30 patients (male and female) with ACU will be included in this study</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urticaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Desloratadine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Loratadine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent signed and dated Reliable method of contraception for both women of childbearing potential as well as man during the study and 3 months thereafter. A highly effective method of birth control is defined as those which result in a low failure rate (i.e. less than 1% per year) when used consistently and correctly such as implants, injectables, combined oral contraceptives, some IUDs, sexual abstinence or vasectomised partner Outpatients with ACU for more than 6 weeks. Urticaria symptoms must comprise wheal and itch. Age between 18 and 75 years Subjects who are inmates of psychiatric wards, prisons, or other state institutions. Existing or planned placement in an institution after ruling according to ยง 40 passage 1 number 4 AMG (Arzneimittelgesetz). The presence of permanent severe diseases, especially those affecting the immune system, except urticaria and cold urticaria The presence of permanent gastrointestinal condition which may influence the oral therapy (chronic diarrhoea diseases, congenital malformations or surgical mutilations of gastrointestinal tract) History or presence of epilepsy, significant neurological disorders, cerebrovascular attacks or ischemia History or presence of myocardial infarction or cardiac arrhythmia which requires drug therapy Evidence of severe renal dysfunction Evidence of significant hepatic disease (liver enzymes twice the upper reference value) History of adverse reactions to DL Presence of active cancer which requires chemotherapy or radiation therapy Presence of alcohol abuse or drug addiction Intake of oral corticosteroids within 14 days prior to screening visit Use of depot corticosteroids or chronic systemic corticosteroids within 21 days prior to screening visit Use of systemic immunosupressants/immunomodulators like ciclosporine A, dapsone, methotrexate, mycophenolate, chloroquine, and comparable drugs within 28 days prior to screening visit. Pregnancy or breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>ACU</keyword>
	<keyword>acquired cold urticaria</keyword>
</DOC>