<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02868723</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This will be a prospective randomized 2 year study of patients admitted to the Hamad General Hospital (HGH) and the Stroke Prevention Clinic with a diagnosis of ischemic stroke (IS) and Transit ischemic attacks (TIAs). After signing of the informed consent forms and initial evaluation and investigations, all patients enrolled in the two arms ( study arm and control arm) of the study will be followed for one year (monthly visits for the first three months followed by visits three months until completion of study: total of 6 follow up visits) and the pre-specified investigations repeated at the one year follow up. In one arm (the control group), the patients will be offered best risk factor management strategies as currently being practiced by stroke specialists at HGH in Qatar. And in the second ( the subject group) arm, with assistance of a nurse-practitioner and pharmacist, the investigators will make aggressive attempts to meet "to target" defined risk factors and have the evaluations and investigations completed as in the initial year cohort. All patients will have risk factor stratification according the Framingham Risk Score (FRS) and the change in score measured over time.The primary objective will be to determine if an approach that utilizes a comprehensive strategy results in a significantly outcome. A clinically 'meaningful' difference in the blood pressure (BP) and lipid control of 10% between the aggressively managed versus patients treated with the standard of care will require minimum of 200 patients in each group (alpha error set at 0.05 and beta error at 0.20, power 80%) to be recruited over 1 year and followed for one year (total study duration 2 years). All patients will have screening magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) (including gradient echo (GRE) sequence), carotid 3D Doppler measurement of plaque volume, and PAD assessments, C-reactive protein (CRP) and evaluation for protein urea at baseline. These studies will be repeated in 1 year at the time of exit from the study. The co-primary objective would be to monitor progression (or regression) of plaque build-up on 3D Doppler imaging of the carotid arteries between the two cohorts. The investigators hypothesize that aggressive management of vascular risk factors to "recommended target levels" will lead to better vascular health. Compared to current practice, comprehensive and coordinated approach at preventive measures will lead to more patients with better control of blood pressure and lipid levels. Improved risk factor management will result in slowing of atherosclerosis and its downstream effects which will be measurable on sophisticated blood and imaging testing. Clinically this will translate into fewer hospital re-admissions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PROspective Study to OPTimize thE HEALTH of Patients With TIAs (Transient Ischemic Attacks) and Stroke Admitted to the Hamad General Hospital</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemic Attack, Transient</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient within age of 18 years to 90 years willing to give informed consent. Diagnosis of ischemic stroke (confirmed on CT or MRI) or TIA with history of hypertension or high LDL cholesterol. Willing to be followed with regular visits for one year from the time of enrollment into the study CT or MRI shows evidence of primary intracranial hemorrhage or neoplasm Active coronary artery disease Renal or Hepatic dysfunction t Cognitive dysfunction severe enough to interfere with patients ability to give informed consent Severe systemic illness that will not allow for the patient to complete the one year trial History of intolerance to statins or commonly used antihypertensive medications Unable to tolerate antiplatelet agents Decline of consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cerebrovascular disease</keyword>
	<keyword>patient management</keyword>
	<keyword>stroke management</keyword>
	<keyword>prognosis</keyword>
	<keyword>3D Carotid Doppler Imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomization</keyword>
</DOC>