<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02868112</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to pilot test a transdisciplinary intervention that integrates both geriatrics and palliative care with routine oncology care for older adults with incurable cancer. The investigators will explore their perceptions of the supportive care needs of older patients with cancer. Using these data, the investigators will finalize the transdisciplinary intervention and perform a pilot, randomized trial of the transdisciplinary intervention versus usual care in patients age ≥65 with newly diagnosed, incurable cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Transdisciplinary Intervention Integrating Geriatric And Palliative Care With Oncology Care For Older Adults With Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>While evidence suggests that older adults with incurable cancer have unique geriatric and palliative care needs, models of care that are focused on these needs are lacking. The investigators propose to pilot test an intervention targeting the geriatric and palliative care needs of older adults with incurable cancer, referred to as a "transdisciplinary intervention." The goals of the proposed study are: (1) conduct focus groups with clinicians (from oncology, geriatrics and palliative care) and interviews with patients to explore their perceptions of older patients' supportive care needs and finalize the transdisciplinary intervention; (2) to demonstrate the feasibility and acceptability of delivering the transdisciplinary intervention to older patients with incurable GI and lung cancers; and (3) to estimate the effect size of the transdisciplinary intervention for patient-reported outcomes (e.g., between-group differences from baseline to week 12 in quality of life, physical function, physical and psychological symptoms).</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Age 65 or older Diagnosed with incurable (defined as metastatic or receiving chemotherapy with palliative intent) esophageal, gastric, pancreas, hepatobiliary, colorectal, or lung cancer within the prior 8 weeks (including patients with prior diagnosis of cancer who developed incurable disease) Verbal fluency in English Planning to receive care at Massachusetts General Hospital (MGH) Unwilling or unable to participate in the study Significant psychiatric, cognitive or other comorbid disease which the treating clinician believes prohibits informed consent or participation in the study No medical problems for geriatric clinician to address (e.g. comorbidities, polypharmacy, etc.)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cancer Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Palliative Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Geriatrics</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
</DOC>