<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00861861</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the effects of pitavastatin and atorvastatin on adiponectin percentage change in patients with hypercholesteremia comorbid stable CAD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Pitavastatin With Atorvastatin in Increasing High Density Lipoprotein - Cholesterol (HDL-C) and Adiponectin in Patients With Dyslipidemia and Coronary Artery Disease (CAD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The efficiency of lipid lowering therapy was already proven by the clinical trials of statins. According to these results, the target value of LDL-C is recommended under 100mg/dL in the Japan Atherosclerosis Society Guidelines. However, the efficiency of intensive therapy to lower LDL-C more than 100mg/dL has not been proven yet.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypercholesterolemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyslipidemias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atorvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pitavastatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with dyslipidemia as defined by any of the parameters: HDLC &lt; 50 mg/dL LDLC ≥ 140 mg/dL LDLC ≥ 100 mg/dL and cholesterollowering treatment is necessary in accordance with the investigator's judgement Patients who passed three months or more after acute myocardial infarction Patients who passed one month or more after unstable angina Patients who passed one month or more after PCI Patients with written consent by their own volition after being provided sufficient explanation for the participation into this clinical trial Patients with any allergy to pitavastatin or atorvastatin Patients with familial hypercholesterolemia Patients receiving pitavastatin Patients with severe hypertension Patients with renal disorders or undergoing dialysis Patients with hepatobiliary disorders Patients with hepatobiliary disorders Patients with family history of hypothyroidism or muscular dystrophy Patients with history of druginduced hepatic disorder Drug abuser or dipsomaniac Patients with cardiogenic shock. Patients who hopes for pregnancy during this study Contraindications, Relative Contraindications, Absolute Contraindications for Coadministration and Relative Contraindications for Coadministration for pitavastatin or atorvastatin Patients who are ineligible in the opinion of the investigator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pitavastatin</keyword>
	<keyword>Atorvastatin</keyword>
	<keyword>CAD</keyword>
	<keyword>HDL-C</keyword>
	<keyword>Adiponectin</keyword>
</DOC>