<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00314509</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to compare the efficacy of two doses of a fixed combination of ciclesonide/formoterol fumarate versus ciclesonide alone versus formoterol fumarate alone in patients with asthma. The study duration consists of a baseline period (2 to 3 weeks) and a treatment period (8 weeks). The study will provide further data on safety and tolerability of ciclesonide/formoterol fumarate.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Tolerability of Ciclesonide and Formoterol Fumarate Inhaled Once Daily in Patients With Asthma (18 to 75 y) (BY9010/M1-506)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Formoterol Fumarate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ciclesonide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Main Written informed consent Good health with the exception of bronchial asthma (for at least 6 months) FEV1 &gt; 60% to &lt; 80% of predicted (if pretreated with inhaled steroids only) FEV1 &gt; 60% to ≤ 85% of predicted (if pretreated with inhaled steroids in combination with other asthma controller) Main Concomitant severe diseases or diseases which are contraindications for the use of inhaled steroids or longacting beta2agonists Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), i.e. chronic bronchitis or emphysema, and/or other relevant lung diseases causing alternating impairment in pulmonary function Current smoking or cessation of smoking within the last 6 months or previous smoking with a smoking history ≥ 10 cigarette packyears Use of other drugs not allowed Pregnancy or intention to become pregnant during the course of the study, breast feeding, or lack of safe contraception in women of childbearing potential</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>Ciclesonide</keyword>
	<keyword>Formoterol Fumarate</keyword>
	<keyword>Long-acting beta2-agonists</keyword>
	<keyword>LABA</keyword>
	<keyword>Steroids</keyword>
</DOC>