<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02722525</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Learning about the impact of anti-androgen treatment has on cardiac function in patients with prostate cancer may help plan treatment and help patients live more comfortably. This pilot clinical trial will utilize cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) before a patient starts hormone therapy and after 4 to 7 months of hormone therapy. The objective is to measure the impact of hormone therapy (anti-androgen treatment) on cardiac function in patients with prostate cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cardiac MRI in Measuring the Impact of Anti-androgen Treatment on Cardiac Function in Patients With Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the impact of a minimum of 4 months of full androgen deprivation therapy (ADT) on cardiac and skeletal muscle structure and performance using novel cardiovascular magnetic resonance (CMR) approach. OUTLINE: Study participants will undergo a treadmill stress CMR focused on cardiac muscle comprised of resting MRI over 10-15 minutes followed by treadmill exercise until peak stress. Patients then undergo MRI and gadopentetate dimeglumine (Gd-diethylenetriamine penta-acetic acid [DTPA]) perfusion imaging immediately after exercise and after a 6-8 minute recovery period. Within 24 hours of treadmill CMR exam, patients also undergo skeletal muscle phosphorus magnetic resonance spectroscopy (PMRS) while at rest, during, and in the recovery phase of resistive lower extremity exercise which patients complete over 30 seconds. Both procedures are performed before initiation of ADT treatment (baseline) and 4-7 months after initiation of ADT treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Androgen Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have biopsy proven carcinoma of the prostate Be planning to begin a course of at least 4 months of ADT; the ADT is defined as: (a) surgical castration; (b) gonadotropinreleasing hormone (GNRH) antagonist alone; (c) GNRH antagonist with oral androgen receptor blockade, and (d) GNRH antagonist, oral androgen receptor blockade, and 5alpha reductase inhibitors; we will not include men with only oral antiandrogen therapy such as 5alpha reductase inhibitors alone or oral antiandrogens alone Have an ECOG (Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) performance status of 01 Have plasma total cholesterol &lt; 200 mg/dL Have plasma triglycerides &lt; 200 mg/dL Have BUN/Cr (Blood urea nitrogen and serum creatinine) without clinically significant abnormalities after review by the study physicians Liver enzymes without clinically significant abnormalities after review by the study physicians CBC (complete blood count) without clinically significant abnormalities after review by the study physicians PT/PTT/INR (prothrombin time/partial thromboplastin time) without clinically significant abnormalities after review by the study physicians Voluntarily agree to participate and sign an informed consent document Have an active malignancy other than prostate cancer that requires therapy Not be undergoing evaluation and workup for active cardiovascular disease; men with treated and stable cardiovascular disease may participate Have plasma total cholesterol &gt; 200 mg/dL or plasma triglycerides &gt; 200 mg/dL Have a calculated glomerular filtration rate (GFR) =&lt; 30 mL/min/1.73 m^2 Are not free of unstable angina, arrhythmia, or severe systemic disease that would make moderate intensity exercise participation unsafe Have any contraindications to magnetic resonance (MR) examination such as allergy to MRI contrast media (gadoliniumDTPA [gadopentetate dimeglumine]), metallic foreign objects within the body, orbital metal, cerebral aneurysm clip, pacemaker, defibrillator, neurostimulator, any other medical metallic implant, claustrophobia, inability to lie flat for 30 minutes, and weight exceeding 300 pounds; if an MR contraindication is discovered during scanning that was overlooked during the screening process, the procedure will be stopped immediately and the subject will be removed from the scanner Are receiving any form of renal replacement therapy or have a calculated glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt; 30 mL/min/1.75 m²; results of serum creatinine testing will be reviewed for calculation of glomerular filtration rate (GFR); patients without a serum creatinine level drawn within the prior 3 months will have this drawn upon enrollment Have uncontrolled hypertension and resting blood pressure exceeding 140/80 mmHg In addition, subjects with any contraindications to exercise testing according to American Heart Association guidelines will not be enrolled; nonetheless, the cardiovascular magnetic resonance (CMR) cardiologist supervising the research portion of the exam will also evaluate each subject for evidence of any contraindications; the absolute contraindications include acute myocardial infarction, highrisk unstable angina, uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmias, active endocarditis, symptomatic severe aortic stenosis, decompensated symptomatic heart failure, acute pulmonary embolus or pulmonary infarction, acute noncardiac disorder that may be aggravated by exercise, acute myocarditis or pericarditis, physical disability that would preclude safe and adequate test performance, and inability to provide consent; the relative contraindications include left main coronary stenosis, moderate stenotic valvular heart disease, electrolyte abnormalities, tachyarrhythmias or bradyarrhythmias, atrial fibrillation with uncontrolled ventricular rate, hypertrophic cardiomyopathy, and highdegree atrioventricular node block; subjects with uncontrolled hypertension and resting blood pressure exceeding 140/80 mmHg will be excluded</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ADT</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostate cancer</keyword>
</DOC>