<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02722057</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to confirm the long-term safety and effectiveness of Kalydeco® (ivacaftor) in US CF patients with the R117H-CFTR mutation &lt;18 years of age and to describe the long-term safety and effectiveness of Kalydeco in CF patients with the R117H-CFTR mutation overall and in patients ≥18 years. The long-term safety and effectiveness of Kalydeco will be examined in totality through the evaluation of the primary outcome measures.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Confirm the Long-term Safety and Effectiveness of Kalydeco in Patients With Cystic Fibrosis Who Have an R117H-CFTR Mutation, Including Pediatric Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patient follow-up (i.e., collection of outcomes data after treatment initiation) in the Non-Interventional Cohort will be at least 36 months. The study also includes retrieval of retrospective data entered into the registry for 36 months before the initiation of Kalydeco treatment, from patients matched for both the Interventional and Non-Interventional Cohorts. This will permit a within-group comparison of outcomes before and after Kalydeco treatment for effectiveness and safety.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Interventional Cohort Male or female with confirmed diagnosis of CF Must have at least 1 allele of the R117HCFTR mutation Enrolled in the US CFF Patient Registry at the time of entry into the study Patients will be 6 to &lt;18 years of age on the date of signed ICF, and where appropriate,date of assent If sexually active, male patients who can father a child and female patients of childbearing potential must agree to meet the contraception requirements Non Interventional Cohort Male or female with confirmed diagnosis of CF Must have at least 1 allele of the R117HCFTR mutation Enrolled in the US CFF Patient Registry With a record of Kalydeco treatment initiation from 01 January 2015 through 31 December 2016 Historical Cohort Patients with CF in the CFF Patient Registry as of 01 January 2009 Must have at least 1 allele of the R117HCFTR mutation Patients with no evidence of any prior Kalydeco exposure Interventional Cohort History of any illness or condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, might confound the results of the study or pose an additional risk in administering study drug to the subject Pregnant, planning a pregnancy, breastfeeding, or not willing to follow contraception requirements Abnormal liver function at enrollment Abnormal renal function at enrollment History of solid organ or hematological transplantation Ongoing participation in another therapeutic clinical study or prior participation in an investigational drug study within 30 days before Enrollment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>