<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02722304</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to conduct a pilot study to evaluate the safety and efficacy of weekly administration of Alpha1-Proteinase Inhibitor (A1PI) augmentation therapy in subjects with A1PI deficiency and Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Stage 1 Study of ARALAST NP and GLASSIA in A1PI</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alpha 1-Antitrypsin Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alpha 1-Antitrypsin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Protease Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. ≥18 years of age at the time of screening 2. Endogenous plasma Alpha1Proteinase Inhibitor (A1PI) level &lt;8 μM at any time during the Screening period for treatmentnaïve participants, or following 4weeks minimum washout from previous augmentation therapy in treatmentexperienced participants. The screening plasma A1PI level may be repeated if a participant obtains an exclusionary value that is suspected to be due to inadequate washout of A1PI). 3. Participant has documented A1PI genotype of Pi*Z/Z, Pi*Z/Null, Pi*Malton/Z, Pi*Null/Null, or other rare genotypes (except PI*MS, PI*MZ, or PI*SZ). 4. Clinically evident mildmoderate chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) (according to GOLD criteria for diagnosis) at the time of screening. 5. If the participant is treated with any respiratory medications including inhaled bronchodilators, inhaled corticosteroids, or systemic corticosteroids (e.g. prednisone ≤ 10 mg/day or its equivalent), the doses of the participant's medications have remained stable for at least 28 days prior to screening. 6. No clinically significant abnormalities (other than emphysema, bronchitis or bronchiectasis) detected via a chest computed tomography (CT) or chest Xray at the time of screening. 7. If female of childbearing potential, participant must have a negative pregnancy test at screening and agree to employ adequate birth control measures for the duration of the study. 8. Participant is willing and able to comply with the requirements of the protocol. 1. Known ongoing or history of clinically significant pulmonary impairment other than COPD. 2. The participant is experiencing lower respiratory infection (LRTI)/acute pulmonary exacerbation (APE) at the time of enrollment (signing Informed consent form (ICF)). Participant may be rescreened after both clinical resolution of LRTI/APE and having also remained stable for at least 4 weeks after the end of LRTI/APE). 3. Known ongoing or history of cor pulmonale. 4. Known resting partial pressure of carbon dioxide (PaCO2) levels of &gt; 45 mmHg. 5. Clinically significant congestive heart failure with New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class III/IV symptoms. 6. The participant has received an organ transplant, has undergone major lung surgery, or is currently on a transplant list. 7. Known history of ongoing malignancy (other than adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or carcinoma in situ of the cervix). 8. Smoker or participant that has ceased smoking for less than one year prior to screening whose levels of cotinine are outside of the normal range of a nonsmoker. All participants must agree to refrain from smoking throughout the course of the study. 9. The participant is receiving longterm therapy (&gt; 28 days) of parenteral corticosteroids or oral corticosteroids at doses greater than 10 mg/day of prednisone or its equivalent. 10. The participant is receiving longterm roundtheclock oxygen supplementation (other than temporary for acute COPD exacerbation, or supplemental oxygen (O2) with continuous positive airway pressure [CPAP], or bilevel positive airway pressure [BiPAP]). 11. Participant has contraindications for CT 12. Participant is unwilling or unable to modify bronchodilator medications for 6 hours for short acting β2 agonists, 24 hours for longacting β2 agonists, and 48 hours for long acting anticholinergics prior to the scheduled quantitative CT scan. 13. Known severe immunoglobulin A (IgA) deficiency (ie, IgA level &lt; 8 mg/dL at screening). 14. Known history of hypersensitivity following infusions of human blood or blood components (eg, human immunoglobulins or human albumin). 15. Presence of clinically significant laboratory abnormalities at the screening 16. The participant has a clinically significant medical, psychiatric, or cognitive illness, is a recreational drug/alcohol user, or has any other uncontrolled medical condition (eg, unstable angina, transient ischemic attack, uncontrolled hypertension) that, in the opinion of the investigator, would affect participant's safety or compliance or confound the results of the study. 17. Participant has been exposed to another IP within 28 days prior to enrollment or is scheduled to participate in another clinical study involving an IP or investigational device during the course of this study. 18. Participant is a family member or employee of the investigator. 19. If female, participant is pregnant or nursing at the time of enrollment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>