<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02930447</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Autologous glue therapy with platelet-rich plasma (PRP) was reported to improve outcomes in plastic surgery. However, only pilot studies and retrospective uncontrolled trials have reported the potential benefits of autologous glue treatment up to now. Therefore, a larger, blinded, randomized and placebo-controlled clinical trial would be useful to determine whether platelet-rich plasma is safe and effective in abdominoplasty procedures. Currently, there are pharmacological options such as artificial fibrin glues composed of homologous fibrinogen and animal-derived thrombin. However, these therapeutics present a risk of transmissible diseases and may induce allergic reactions. Therefore, autologous glues, which are fully made of blood components from the patient itself (autologous fibrinogen contained in PRP and autologous thrombin) represents a safe alternative to artificial biological glues. Regen Lab SA developed RegenKit速-Surgery to prepare autologous PRP, on one hand, and an autologous activated thrombin serum, on the other hand, in a safe and rapid manner. RegenKit速-Surgery is a CE-marked class IIb medical device. This study, conducted on 56 patients, will evaluate the effects of autologous glue prepared with RegenKit速-Surgery when used in reconstructive abdominoplasty.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Benefit of the Use of Autologous Glue Prepared With RegenKit速-Surgery Device in Abdominoplasty</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Patients over 18 years of age with an indication for abdominoplasty Signature of informed consent form Capable of understanding the study's imperatives Participation ongoing or in the last two months in another clinical trial Pregnancy or breastfeeding Autoimmune disease (e.g. Hashimoto, rheumatoid arthritis, lupus, etc.) Hereditary or acquired hematologic disorder (e.g. drepanocytosis, etc.) Haemoglobin &lt; 10g/dl Haematocrit &lt; 33% Hereditary or acquired coagulation disorder (e.g. platelet dysfunction syndrome, critical thrombocytopenia with a platelet count &lt; 150'000/microlitre, impaired coagulation,etc.) Systemic disorders such as diabetes, or hepatitis Acute infection Any active malignancy Chemotherapy Refusal or incapacity to give Informed Consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>