<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02930668</DOC>
	<brief_summary>It was proven in a previous clinical study that Glucosanol™ is effective and safe in reducing weight in the overweight and obese. The present study aims at expanding the data concerning the weight management effect of Glucosanol™ in overweight and moderately obese population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Glucosanol™ in Body Weight Reduction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>BMI 25 kg/m2 34,9 kg/m2 Generally in good health• Desire to lose weight Accustomed to regular daily consumption of 3 main meals (breakfast, lunch, dinner) Consistent and stable body weight in the last 3 months prior to V1 (less than 5% selfreported change)• Readiness to take IP as recommended Readiness to avoid the use of other weight loss and/or management products and/or programs during the study Readiness to adhere to diet recommendation during the study Readiness to keep the habitual level of physical activity as prior to the study during the study Readiness and ability to complete the subject diary and study questionnaires Negative pregnancy testing (beta HCGtest in urine) at V1 in women of childbearing potential Women of childbearing potential: commitment to use contraception methods Known allergy or hypersensitivity to the components of the investigational products Known allergy or hypersensitivity to members of the Fabaceae family Known food allergy (e.g. to cow's milk, eggs, wheat, crustacean, nuts etc.) Significant disorders: untreated or unstable thyroid gland disorder untreated or unstable hypertension (&gt;140/90 mm Hg) acute or chronic gastrointestinal (GI) disease or malabsorption disorders (e.g. inflammatory bowel disease, coeliac disease, pancreatitis etc.) diabetes mellitus coagulation disorder any other serious organ or systemic diseases that could influence the conduct and/or outcome of the study and/or could affect the tolerability of the subject (in the opinion of the investigator) Significant surgery within the last 6 months prior to V1: GI surgery liposuction History of eating disorders like bulimia, anorexia nervosa, bingeeating within the last 12 monthsprior to V1 Clinically relevant excursions of safety laboratoryparameters Any electronic medical implant Regular use of anticoagulants Regular medication and/or supplementation and/or treatment within the last 3 months prior to V1 and during the study: that could influence body weight (e.g. systemic corticosteroids) that could influence gastrointestinal functions (e.g. antibiotics, laxatives, opioids, glucocorticoids, anticholinergics, antidiarrheals etc.) as per investigator judgement for weight management (e.g. fat binder, carbohydrate/starch blocker, fat burner, satiety products, acupuncture etc.) Consumption of food supplements or natural health products for the duration of the study Diet to lose and/or manage weight (except according to the study protocol) Vegetarian, vegan or macrobiotic diet Smoking cessation within 6 months prior to V1 or during the study (regular smoking during the study at the same level as prior to the study is allowed) Pregnancy or nursing History of or current abuse of drugs, alcohol or medication Inability to comply with study requirements Subjects who are deprived of their freedom by administrative or legal decision or who are in guardianship Participation in another clinical study in the 30 days prior to V1 and during the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>