<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01865656</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the effectiveness of a First Referral Unit (FRU) Emergency Obstetric and Newborn Care (EmONC) skills and drills intervention, to estimate the appropriateness and effectiveness of referrals in intervention arm compared to control arm and to calculate the incremental cost and cost effectiveness of EmONC skills and drills intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Skills and Drills Intervention for Emergency Obstetrics and Neonatal Care at First Referral Units of North Karnataka</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of this intervention is to improve the quality of care for institutional births with a special focus on improving the quality of Emergency Obstetric and Newborn Care (EmONC). This intervention will focus on improving the skills and practices of providers and through the improvement of referral networks, ensure timely and appropriate management of complications. The specific objectives include: 1. Evaluate the effectiveness of an FRU-level Basic and EmONC Skills and Drills intervention combined with the existing primary health centre (PHC) based nurse mentoring intervention in improving appropriate diagnosis and management of obstetric and perinatal complications. 2. Assess the additional benefit of the EmONC Skills and drills intervention at FRUs in terms of improvement of obstetric and perinatal outcomes compared to the PHC-level intervention alone. 3. Estimate the appropriateness and effectiveness of referrals in intervention facilities compared to controls. 4. Calculate the incremental cost and cost-effectiveness of the EmONC skills and drills intervention</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Postpartum Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Asphyxia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Asphyxia Neonatorum</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All women age who are referred or admitted directly to the first referral unit for a delivery or with a complication Staff working in the First Referral Units no specific exclusion criteria</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>provider skill and self-efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Appropriate and timely referral for obstetric emergencies</keyword>
	<keyword>Intervention feasibility and acceptability</keyword>
</DOC>