<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01865357</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Clinically isolated demyelinating syndromes (CIS) can evolve into multiple sclerosis (MS). Cognitive deficiencies could occur at this early stage and concern mainly information processing speed (IPS) and their mechanisms are not fully understood. Diffusion Tensor Imaging (DTI) can help in the understanding of these mechanisms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Longitudinal 1-year Study of the Correlation Between Cognitive Functioning in Patients With Clinically Isolated Syndrome Suggestive of Multiple Sclerosis and Disconnection in the Brain Assessed by MRI</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective cohort, observational, longitudinal, monocentric study. This study will include 60 patients with CIS followed for 1 year and 60 healthy subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients: Men and Women ≥16 years Fluent French speaker Clinically isolated neurological syndrome (CIS) compatible with a demyelinating inflammatory episode within the central nervous system, potentially beginning multiple sclerosis (MS) whatever the mode of presentation Between 60 and 180 days from the onset At least two clinically silent lesions on their T2weighted brain or spinal MRI scan with a size of at least 3 mm, at least one of which being cerebral, ovoid, or periventricular Having a medical insurance Free and informed consent signed Controls: Men and Women ≥18 years Fluent French speaker Having a medical insurance Free and informed consent signed Patients: Prior documented neurological episode suggestive of MS. Other ongoing neurological diseases. Known chronic systemic diseases as judged by the investigator (for instance: lupus, GougerotSjögren, sarcoidosis, sclerodermia, Crohn disease,…). Other causes (trauma, tumor, radiotherapy, infections, vascular diseases, neuromyelitis optica). Current dependence on alcohol or drugs. Dosage change, stop or start of hypnotic or anxiolytic or antidepressive treatment less than 15 days MRI contraindications. Steroid treatment less than one month (be taken orally or by infusion) at the dosage of 500mg daily. Controls: Known chronic psychiatric or neurologic diseases which could interfere with neuropsychological testing, not taking into account stable and mild depressive syndrome Known chronic systemic diseases as judged by the investigator (for instance: lupus, GougerotSjögren, sarcoidosis, scleroderma, Crohn disease…). MS familial history Current dependence on alcohol or drugs Known cognitive impairment Prior neuropsychological testing with the same tests less than one year Dosage change, stop or start of hypnotic or anxiolytic or antidepressive treatment less than 2 months Steroid treatment less than one month (be taken orally or by infusion) at the dosage of 500mg daily. MRI contraindications Steroid treatment less than one month (be taken orally or by infusion) at the dosage of 500mg daily.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>