<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01649778</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a global, multi-centre, long-term, prospective, observational study to evaluate treatment patterns and clinical outcomes in patients with advanced or metastatic RCC treated for the first time with pazopanib. The study is designed to enroll approximately 700-1000 patients in over the course of an enrollment period of approximately 18 months.There are no protocol-mandated visits or procedures associated with the study. Each patient is expected to participate for a maximum of 30 months or until premature discontinuation (i.e., due to death, withdrawal of consent, lost to follow-up or study termination).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Observational Study of Real World Effectiveness Data and Safety in Patients Receiving Pazopanib With Advanced or Metastatic Renal Cell Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a global, multi-centre, long-term, prospective, observational study to evaluate treatment patterns and clinical outcomes in patients with advanced or metastatic RCC treated for the first time with pazopanib. The study is designed to enroll approximately 700-1000 patients in over the course of an enrollment period of approximately 18 months. Sites will be contacted and qualified by the estimated number of advanced or metastatic RCC patients available for enrollment annually. To the extent possible, consecutive patients meeting inclusion/exclusion criteria will be enrolled. Sites will be required to maintain a patient enrolment log of eligible patients at their treatment centres. This log will document how patients came to be included or excluded from the study, in order to assess the representativeness of the study population. The overall number of patients and sites may be adjusted during the study to meet enrollment goals, if needed. Eligible patients will be enrolled by medical oncologists and potentially by urologists experienced in the management of patients with RCC, if consistent with local practice. There are no protocol-mandated visits or procedures associated with the study. Each patient is expected to participate for a maximum of 30 months or until premature discontinuation (i.e., due to death, withdrawal of consent, lost to follow-up or study termination). Follow-up information will be collected approximately every 3 months (a window of ± 4 weeks around the date of the suggested data collection will be allowed). If the patient is not seen for a regularly scheduled visit at that time, the site may contact the patient by telephone to solicit information regarding the events of interest and to limit loss to follow up. It is anticipated that frequency of patient assessment and imaging will differ according to local standard practice; therefore the quarterly data collection time points are intended to collect all assessments (with the date of assessment) since the previous visit date.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients eligible for enrolment in the study must meet all of the following criteria: Age ≥ 18 years at enrollment Documented diagnosis of advanced and/or metastatic clear cell or predominantly clear cell RCC Clinical decision made to initiate treatment with pazopanib prior to enrollment in the study, but within 30 days of enrollment Willing and able to provide written informed consent Patients meeting any of the following criteria must not be enrolled in the study: Patients currently participating in any interventional clinical trials in which treatment regimen and/or monitoring is dictated by a protocol Previous exposure to an investigational or licensed multikinase inhibitor or an anti VEGF angiogenesis inhibitor for advanced or metastatic disease Life expectancy &lt; 12 weeks</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>