<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00212251</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate, in a five-year randomized controlled trial, the efficacy of an intervention (AMP - ACTIVE MOTHERS POSTPARTUM) to increase physical activity and promote a healthy diet (decreased calorie and fat intake) for weight loss among postpartum women who were overweight or obese prior to pregnancy. The hypothesis is that the proportion of women losing at least 10% of BMI from baseline to 12 months post-intervention will be significantly greater in the AMP intervention arm than in the minimal care arm.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Promoting Postpartum Weight Loss in Overweight Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Retention of weight gained in pregnancy contributes to the development of overweight and obesity in middle age, now at epidemic proportions in America. While interventions to reduce weight retention specifically targeting the postpartum period have been few, interventions that promote modest weight loss starting in early postpartum are safe and could be efficacious, particularly for women who were overweight prior to pregnancy. Moreover, postpartum-related changes in cognitive factors (risk perceptions), behavioral factors (physical activity, diet), self concept (self-esteem) and social role (work, food preparation, child care) may make this time a "teachable moment" that could be capitalized upon by formal interventions. Interventions could leverage natural weight changes to encourage adoption of a healthy diet and increase physical activity, which together could accelerate and/or increase natural weight loss in postpartum. Whether the postpartum period is a teachable moment for weight loss interventions can be investigated empirically.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>prepregnancy BMI&gt;24 over 18 delivered baby in past 6 weeks English speaking driving distance to Duke University Medical Center Hemodynamically significant heart disease Restrictive lung disease Severe anemia Unevaluated maternal cardiac arrythmia Chronic bronchitis Poorly controlled Type 1 diabetes Poorly controlled hypertension Orthopedic limitations Poorly controlled seizure disorder Poorly controlled hyperthyroidism</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>postpartum period</keyword>
	<keyword>exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>diet</keyword>
	<keyword>motivation</keyword>
</DOC>