<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02458157</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this pilot trial is to assess the feasibility of forced fluid removal in patients admitted to the intensive care unit (ICU) with high-risk AKI and severe fluid overload. The intervention will use furosemide infusion and/or continuous renal replacement therapy (CRRT) to achieve and maintain a neutral cumulative fluid balance. The intervention will be compared to standard of care as reflected in the kidney disease improving global outcome (KDIGO) guidelines.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Forced Fluid Removal in High Risk Acute Kidney Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a common and serious complication in patients admitted to ICU. A core element of critical care is resuscitation with crystalloid solutions. In many cases fluid accumulates and patients become fluid overloaded (positive fluid balance &gt; 10% of bodyweight). This is especially true in patients with AKI, since they often have impaired ability to excrete salt and water. Most observational suggests harm with increased positive fluid balance. Objectives: To assess feasibility of forced fluid removal with diuretics and/or CRRT in ICU patients with AKI and severe fluid overload, compared to current clinical practice. Design: Multicentre, parallel group, randomized, assessor blinded pilot-trial with adequate generation of allocation sequence, and allocation concealment. Trial Size: The pilot study is planned to include 50 patients. Inclusion is expected to start in August 2015.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Furosemide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years of age Acute Kidney Injury defined according to the KDIGO criteria Renal Recovery Score ≤ 60%. (Calculated using www.renalrecoveryscore.com) Fluid overload defined as a positive fluid balance ≥ 10% of ideal body weight. Able to undergo randomization within 12 hours of fulfilling other inclusion criteria Known prehospitalization advanced chronic kidney disease. (eGFR &lt; 30 mL/minute/1.73 m2 or chronic RRT.) Severe hypoxic respiratory failure (use of invasive ventilation and FiO2 &gt; 80% and PEEP &gt; 10 cm H2O) Severe burn injury (≥ 10% TBSA) Severe hypo or hyper natremia (&lt; 120 or &gt; 155 mmol/l) Hepatic coma Mentally disabled undergoing forced treatment Pregnancy/breast feeding Lack of commitment for ongoing life support including RRT Lack of informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ICU</keyword>
	<keyword>Intensive</keyword>
	<keyword>CRRT</keyword>
	<keyword>Fluid Removal</keyword>
	<keyword>AKI</keyword>
	<keyword>Critical Care</keyword>
</DOC>