<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01212757</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether apremilast is safe and effective in the treatment of patients with psoriatic arthritis. Apremilast is proposed to improve signs and symptoms of psoriatic arthritis (tender and swollen joints, pain, physical function) in treated patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PALACE 2: Efficacy and Safety Study of Apremilast to Treat Active Psoriatic Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Psoriatic arthritis (PsA) is an inflammatory arthritis that occurs in 6-39% of psoriasis patients. The immunopathogenesis of PsA, which mirrors but is not identical to that seen in psoriatic plaques, reflects a complex interaction among resident dendritic, fibroblastic and endothelial cells, and inflammatory cells attracted to the synovium by cytokines and chemokines. Apremilast (CC-10004) is a novel oral agent that modulates multiple inflammatory pathways through targeted phosphodiesterase type 4 (PDE4) enzyme inhibition. Therefore, apremilast has the potential to be effective in the treatment of PsA.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Psoriatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thalidomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Apremilast</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males or females, aged ≥ 18 years at time of consent. Have a diagnosis of Psoriatic Arthritis (PsA, by any criteria) of ≥ 6 months duration. Meet the Classification Criteria for Psoriatic Arthritis (CASPAR) PsA at time of screening. Must have been inadequately treated by diseasemodifying antirheumatic drugs (DMARDs) May not have axial involvement alone Concurrent Treatment allowed with methotrexate, leflunomide, or sulfasalazine Have ≥ 3 swollen AND ≥ 3 tender joints. Males &amp; Females must use contraception Stable dose of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), narcotics and low dose oral corticosteroids allowed. Pregnant or breast feeding. History of allergy to any component of the investigational product. Hepatitis B surface antigen and/or Hepatitis C antibody positive at screening. Therapeutic failure on &gt; 3 agents for PsA or &gt; 1 biologic tumor necrosis factor (TNF) blocker</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>Psoriatic Arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>skin condition</keyword>
	<keyword>inflammatory cells</keyword>
	<keyword>apremilast</keyword>
	<keyword>CC-10004</keyword>
	<keyword>phosphodiesterase type 4</keyword>
</DOC>