<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02000089</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Johns Hopkins clinical research office quality assurance group will monitor and audit this study at Johns Hopkins. The Sub Investigator at each site will be responsible for internal monitoring at their site.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Cancer of the Pancreas Screening-5 CAPS5)Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Sub Investigator at each site will be responsible for internal monitoring at their site. The site sub Investigator and study team will report any serious adverse events to Principal Investigator and annually report adverse events.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms, Hereditary Nonpolyposis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peutz-Jeghers Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Secretin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancrelipase</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Hereditary Pancreatitis or PeutzJeghers Syndrome or Strong family history of pancreas cancer on one side of the family tree or Confirmed germline mutation carrier (BRCA2, FAMMM, PALB2, BRCA1, HNPCC, PRSS1/2, or CTRC Endoscopic evaluation of pancreas scheduled Medical comorbidities or coagulopathy that contraindicate endoscopy Prior surgery that prevent optimal endoscopic ultrasound such as partial or complete gastrectomy with Bilroth or RouxenY anastomosis Stricture or obstruction in the upper GI tract that does not allow passage of the echoendoscope Poor performance status Inability to provide informed consent Pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>familial pancreas cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>(Peutz-Jeghers Syndrome) PJS</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast cancer (BRCA) 2</keyword>
	<keyword>Partner and Locator of BRCA2 (PALB2)</keyword>
	<keyword>Familial Atypical Multiple Mole- Melanoma (FAMMM)</keyword>
	<keyword>p16</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer (BRCA)1</keyword>
	<keyword>(hereditary non-polyposis colorectal cancer or Lynch syndrome) HNPCC</keyword>
	<keyword>Lynch Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>hereditary pancreatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Protease Serine (PRSS)</keyword>
	<keyword>Chymotrypsin C (CTRC)</keyword>
	<keyword>Ataxia Telangiectasia Mutated(ATM)</keyword>
</DOC>