<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02000934</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is an open-label, multicenter, phase 1, dose escalation study of TAK-659 in adult patients with advanced solid tumor and lymphoma malignancies. This study will be the first to administer TAK-659 to humans. The patient population during dose escalation (Part A) will consist of adults previously diagnosed with any form of a solid tumor or lymphoma for which standard, curative, or life-prolonging treatment does not exist or is no longer effective. This first-in-human (FIH) study will include 5 dose expansion cohorts in refractory and/or relapsed Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL), Diffuse Large B Cell Lymphoma (DLBCL), indolent Non Hodgkin Lymphoma (iNHL), Mantle Cell Lymphoma (MCL), Post Transplant Lymphoproliferative Disorder (PTLD) (Part B) following completion of dose escalation (Part A).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of TAK-659 in Adult Patients With Advanced Solid Tumor and Lymphoma Malignancies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Each patient must meet all of the following inclusion criteria to be enrolled in the study: 1. Male or female patients 18 years or older 2. To be enrolled to the dose escalation (Part A), patients must have 1. histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of metastatic and/or advanced solid tumor malignancy or lymphoma, for which no effective standard treatment is available. However, patients with primary brain tumors or WM will be excluded. 2. Radiographically or clinically measurable or nonmeasurable (but evaluable) disease. Radiographically measurable disease is determined by RECIST(version 1.1) for solid tumors or by IWG criteria for malignant lymphoma (2007 IWG). 3. To be enrolled to the dose expansion cohorts (Part B), patients must meet the following criteria: 1. Histologically confirmed or diagnosis of CLL that meets IWCLL 2008 criteria for Cohort 1; DLBCL for Cohort 2; Bcell NHL (FL [Grade 1, 2, or 3a], SLL, LPL/WM, MZL [splenic, nodal, or extranodal]) for Cohort 3; MCL for Cohort 4; and PTLD (early lesion, polymorphic, monomorphic, classical Hodgkin lymphomatype, EBVpositive DLBCL of the elderly, DLBCL associated with chronic inflammation; along with documented or documentable EBER status by tissue ISH) for Cohort 5 2. Must have received ≥ 1 prior therapy (excluding radiation); either treatment naïve to, relapsed/refractory to, or treatment failure due to other reasons with ibrutinib, idelalisib, or any other investigational BCR in pathway inhibitors not directly targeting SYK; considered not appropriate for treatment or retreatment with purine analogbased therapy (CLL); or considered ineligible for at least 1 prior therapy (PTLD) 3. Radiographically or clinically measurable and/or evaluable disease as specified in the protocol 4. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 or 1. 5. Patients must have adequate organ function, including bone marrow reserve, hepatic, and renal function as described in the protocol 6. Female patients who are postmenopausal for at least 1 year, are surgically sterile, or if of childbearing potential who agree to use 2 effective method(s) of contraception during the study treatment period through 6 months after the last dose of study drug or practice true abstinence. Male patients, even if surgically sterilized, who agree to practice effective barrier contraception during the study treatment period through 6 months after the last dose of study drug or practice true abstinence. 7. Voluntary written consent must be given before performance of any study related procedure not part of standard medical care, with the understanding that consent may be withdrawn by the patient at any time without prejudice to future medical care. 8. Patients must have recovered from the reversible effects of prior anticancer therapy (to Grade ≤ 1). Exclusion Criteria Patients meeting any of the following exclusion criteria are not to be enrolled in the study. 1. Patients with brain metastasis, or patients with active secondary malignancy that requires treatment, with exceptions as described in the protocol 2. Any serious medical or psychiatric illness, including drug or alcohol abuse, that could, in the investigator's opinion, potentially interfere with the completion of treatment according to this protocol. 3. Lifethreatening illness unrelated to cancer; major surgery, systemic infection requiring intravenous (IV) antibiotic therapy or other serious infection within 14 days before the first dose of study drug. 4. Female patients who are pregnant or lactating. 5. Any immunotherapy, chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or investigational therapy within 24 weeks before the first dose of study treatment, as detailed in the protocol 6. For escalation cohort or expansion cohorts excluding PTLD, autologous stem cell transplant within 6 months before Day 1 of Cycle 1, or prior allogeneic stem cell transplant at any time. 7. Treatment with high dose corticosteroids (&gt; daily dose equivalent to 10 mg oral prednisone) for anticancer purposes within 7 days before the first dose of TAK659. 8. Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) positive; known hepatitis B surface antigenpositive; or known or suspected active hepatitis C infection (testing not required). 9. Evidence of currently uncontrolled cardiovascular conditions as listed in the protocol. 10. Known GI disease or GI procedure that could interfere with the oral absorption or tolerance of TAK659 including difficulty swallowing tablets; diarrhea &gt; Grade 1 despite supportive therapy. 11. Lack of suitable venous access for required blood sampling 12. Use or consumption of Pgp inducers/inhibitors and strong CYP3A inducers/inhibitors as described in the protocol, and grapefruitcontaining food or beverages.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>TAK-659</keyword>
	<keyword>Solid Tumors</keyword>
	<keyword>CLL</keyword>
	<keyword>DLBCL</keyword>
</DOC>