<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00577967</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate using the drug gabapentin to relieve the intense pruritic sensation associated with chronic renal failure patients undergoing peritoneal dialysis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gabapentin - A Solution to Uremic Pruritus?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pruritus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gabapentin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>gamma-Aminobutyric Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult Chinese male and female patients aged &gt; 18 undergoing CAPD for at least 3 months and able to read and understand Chinese Patients experiencing moderate to severe pruritis, defined as persistent, treatmentresistant pruritis considerably impairing sleep or daytime activity. Treatment resistance is defined as no or only partial resolvement of pruritis under current antipruritis treatment regimens such as antipruritis lotions and antihistamines. Patients in stable clinical condition in terms of peritoneal dialysis and general health Patients able to understand and answer the SDS questionnaire Patients able to express the sensation of itchiness in the terms of the VAS and the SDS score Patients who are willing to give written informed consent and to participate in and comply with the study protocol Patients with a known history of pruritis or dermatologic disease antedating renal failure. Patients with skin disease other than the usual cutaneous findings of uraemia such as xerosis or ecchymosis. Patients under current treatment with systemic steroids Known history of allergy to Gabapentin Those patients already put on anticonvulsants Unable to give written informed consent for the study Pregnancy or female patients of childbearing age who are unwilling to use contraception Poor drug compliance Known HIV positivity Active neoplastic disease Those who do not want to participate the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Uremic pruritis</keyword>
</DOC>