<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00577629</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether using high-dose chemotherapy, monoclonal antibodies, and targeted radioimmunotherapy will slow the progression of disease in patients with high-risk Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma (NHL).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chemotherapy With Monoclonal Antibody and Radioimmunotherapy for High-Risk B-Cell Non-Hodgkins Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase II efficacy trial for patients with untreated, high-risk, B-cell Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma. The study will evaluate the efficacy and safety of high-dose chemotherapy combined with monoclonal antibodies and targeted radioimmunotherapy in previously untreated patients with high-risk NHL</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cytarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iodine-131 anti-B1 antibody</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Untreated, biopsy proven Bcell nonHodgkin's lymphoma Age &gt;/= 18 years No other prior malignancy except for adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, in situ cervical cancer, or other cancer for which the patient has been diseasefree for one year. The patient cannot have been exposed to chemotherapy to treat any of these diseases for at least 3 years prior to study entry. Meet staging studies and laboratory tests prior to induction, consolidation and radioimmunotherapy. Significant medical and/or psychiatric illness which may compromise planned treatment; Pregnant or lactating; HIVinfection. Patients with follicular lymphoma grade 1, 2 or 3A are not eligible for this trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>high risk non-hodgkins lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>NHL</keyword>
	<keyword>Bexxar</keyword>
	<keyword>high dose chemotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>