<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00357656</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the hemostatic efficacy and safety of continuous infusion versus intermittent bolus infusion in the peri- and post-operative setting, employing rAHF-PFM, a recombinant antihemophilic factor manufactured without added human or animal proteins, in previously treated patients with severe or moderately severe hemophilia A (baseline factor VIII level &lt;= 2% of normal) who are undergoing unilateral major orthopedic surgery that requires drain placement. The total study period per subject (from consent to study completion) will vary from approximately 9 to 26 weeks and will involve clinical and laboratory assessments.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 3/4 Study of a Recombinant Protein-Free Factor VIII (rAHF-PFM): Comparison of Continuous Infusion Versus Intermittent Bolus Infusion in Hemophilia A Subjects Undergoing Major Orthopedic Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Factor VIII</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The subject or the subject's legally authorized representative has provided signed informed consent. The subject is within 18 to 70 years of age. The subject has severe or moderately severe hemophilia A, defined by a baseline factor VIII level &lt;= 2% of normal, as tested at screening. A subset of 15 subjects per group must have baseline factor VIII levels &lt; 1% of normal. The aPTT must be within the range of normal after administration of FVIII concentrate, as determined in the preoperative pharmacokinetic evaluation, or as documented in the medical history, if available. The subject is scheduled to undergo an elective unilateral major orthopedic surgery that requires drain placement. The subject was previously treated with factor VIII concentrate(s) for a minimum of at least 150 exposure days (as estimated by the investigator) prior to study entry. Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) positive subjects must be immunocompetent as determined with a CD4 count &gt;= 200 cells/mm³ (CD4 count at screening), but HIV negative subjects with a CD4 count &lt; 200 cells/mm³ qualify, if immunocompetency is documented. The subject has a life expectancy of at least 28 days from the day of surgery. The subject has a detectable factor VIII inhibitor at screening, with a titer &gt;= 0.4 BU (Nijmegen modification of the Bethesda assay) in the central laboratory. The subject has a history of factor VIII inhibitors with a titer &gt;= 0.4 BU (by Nijmegen assay) or &gt;= 0.5 BU (by Bethesda assay) at any time prior to screening. The subject is scheduled to undergo any other concurrent minor or major surgery during the course of the study. The placement of central venous lines and the performance of fine needle aspiration biopsies are permitted. Excluding hemophiliarelated physical impairments, the subject is assigned to NYHA class &gt;= III according to the New York Heart Association (NYHA). The subject has an abnormal renal function (serum creatinine &gt; 1.5 mg/dL). The subject has active hepatic disease (alanine aminotransferase [ALT] or aspartate aminotransferase [AST] levels &gt; 5 times the upper limit of normal). The subject has severe chronic liver disease as evidenced by, but not limited to, any of the following: International Normalized Ratio (INR) &gt; 1.4, hypoalbuminemia, portal vein hypertension including presence of otherwise unexplained splenomegaly and history of esophageal varices. The subject has clinical and/or laboratory evidence of abnormal hemostasis from causes other than hemophilia A (e.g., latestage chronic liver disease, immune thrombocytopenia purpura). The subject is currently receiving, or is scheduled to receive during the course of the study, an immunomodulating drug other than antiretroviral chemotherapy (e.g., alphainterferon, corticosteroid agents at a dose equivalent to hydrocortisone greater than 10 mg/day). The subject has a known hypersensitivity to mouse or hamster proteins. The subject has received another investigational drug study within 30 days prior to screening and/or is scheduled to receive additional investigational drug during the course of the trial in the context of another investigational study. The subject is identified by the investigator as being unable or unwilling to cooperate with study procedures.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hemophilia A (severe or moderately severe)</keyword>
</DOC>