<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00357994</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study was to demonstrate the superiority of levodopa - carbidopa intestinal gel over treatment with optimized oral levodopa/carbidopa during 12 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Efficacy, Safety and Tolerability of Levodopa-Carbidopa Intestinal Gel in Levodopa-Responsive Parkinson's Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study S187.3.001 (NCT00357994) and Study S187.3.002 (NCT00660387) were 2 identically designed, Phase 3, 12-week, randomized, double-blind, double-dummy, parallel-group, multicenter studies recruiting subjects from distinct sites. These studies evaluated the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of levodopa-carbidopa intestinal gel (LCIG) in the treatment of levodopa-responsive subjects with advanced PD who had persistent severe motor fluctuations, despite optimized treatment with oral levodopa-carbidopa, concomitant with other available antiparkinsonian medications. Participants were randomized to either LCIG active gel + placebo capsules or levodopa-carbidopa immediate release (IR) active capsules + placebo gel. Both treatment arms received the percutaneous endoscopic gastrostomy with jejunal extension (PEG-J) procedure for gel administration, active LCIG or placebo gel. Data from these 2 studies were combined for analysis. The decision to combine the study data for analysis was made before enrollment was completed for both studies.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carbidopa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carbidopa, levodopa drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levodopa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Idiopathic Parkinson's disease (PD) according to United Kingdom Parkinson's Disease Society (UKPDS) Brain Bank Criteria Levodoparesponsive participants who demonstrate some identifiable 'on response,' established by Investigator observation Demonstrate severe motor fluctuations in spite of individually optimized treatment and where therapy options are indicated Diagnosis is unclear or a suspicion of other parkinsonian syndromes exists such as secondary parkinsonism Undergone surgery for the treatment of PD Contraindications to levodopa Subjects with any neurological deficit that may interfere with the study assessments</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>carbidopa</keyword>
	<keyword>levodopa-carbidopa</keyword>
	<keyword>levodopa</keyword>
	<keyword>levodopa/carbidopa suspension</keyword>
	<keyword>dyskinesia</keyword>
	<keyword>Duodopa</keyword>
	<keyword>levodopa-carbidopa intestinal gel</keyword>
	<keyword>Severe Motor Fluctuations</keyword>
	<keyword>DUOPA</keyword>
</DOC>