<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00357331</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Skeletal buffering of chronic acid loads may contribute to a significant amount of bone loss over time. Evidence from a few small short-term studies suggests that basic compounds, namely potassium citrate and potassium bicarbonate may reduce bone loss and improve bone density. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effects of potassium citrate on bone metabolism. We hypothesize that administration of potassium citrate to postmenopausal women with osteopenia will reduce bone resorption and improve bone mineral density. Postmenopausal women with osteopenia (T score between -1.0 and -2.5) and no history of fracture will be randomized to either daily potassium citrate or placebo for one year. Primary outcomes will be markers of bone turnover, which will be measured over 12 months. Secondary outcomes will be bone mineral density, compliance, and adverse events.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effects of Potassium Citrate on Bone Metabolism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bone Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis, Postmenopausal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bone Diseases, Metabolic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Potassium Citrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citric Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Postmenopausal women, more than 2 years post menopause Osteopenia, defined as a T score at the lumbar spine or total hip between 1.0 and 2.5 No history of prior fragility fracture Exclusion criteria: Renal insufficiency Use of potassium sparing diuretics Use of potassium supplements Hyperkalemia Secondary causes of osteoporosis or metabolic bone disease Delayed gastric emptying esophageal compression, intestinal obstruction or stricture use of anticholinergic medication active urinary tract infection.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>postmenopausal osteopenia</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>bone loss</keyword>
</DOC>