<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01205828</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is for people with liver cancer (also called hepatocellular carcinoma, or HCC in abbreviation). The purpose of this study is to test the efficacy (effectiveness) of a new combination of drugs, ABT-888 and temozolomide for patients with liver cancer. Temozolomide acts by damaging deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) in rapidly dividing cells, in other words, cancer cells. ABT-888 inhibits an enzyme called "PARP" which helps to fix damaged DNA. By inhibiting this enzyme, ABT-888 prevents cancer cells from repairing the damage caused by the temozolomide and will hopefully increase the killing of cancer cells, and decrease the tumors in the body. ABT-888 is an investigational or experimental anti-cancer agent that has not yet been approved by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for use in liver cancer. This study will help find out what effects (good and bad) the combination of drugs, temozolomide and ABT-888, has on liver cancer. This research is being done because it is not known if ABT-888 will increase the effectiveness of temozolomide in liver cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ABT-888 and Temozolomide for Liver Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with hepatocellular carcinoma seen at Lombardi Cancer Center were evaluated for the eligibility of this study. The Georgetown Lombardi Comprehensive Cancer Center was responsible for the data and safety monitoring of this trial. As this study is an investigator initiated study Phase II study utilizing a non-FDA approved drug for which the PI held the IND it was considered a high risk study which had real-time monitoring by the PI and study team and quarterly reviews by the LCCC Data and Safety Monitoring Committee (DSMC).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Veliparib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pathological confirmation of HCC or noninvasive criteria following AASLD guidelines Measurable or evaluable disease based on RECIST criteria Progressive disease on sorafenib or intolerance to sorafenib ECOG performance status 02 Child Pugh Class A or B Adequate hepatic, bone marrow, and renal function Prior ABT888 or other PARP inhibitor treatment Anticipation of need for major surgery during the study Any of the following within 6 months before enrollment: myocardial infarction, severe/unstable angina, congestive heart failure, or severe pulmonary disease Women who are pregnant or lactating Women and men of childbearing potential who are not using a reliable form of contraception History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition to ABT888 and temozolomide Concurrent malignancy (i.e. malignancy other than hepatocellular cancer) unless 1) the subject has been curatively treated and disease free for at least 2 years or 2) the cancer was nonmelanoma skin cancer or early cervical cancer. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection (excluding active hepatitis B or C) or psychiatric illness/ social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>liver cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>hepatocellular</keyword>
	<keyword>temozolomide</keyword>
	<keyword>veliparib</keyword>
</DOC>