<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01205230</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine how dosing with ketoconazole (Nizoral) or esomeprazole (Nexium) affects the pharmacokinetics of oral pazopanib. The study will also test for safety of pazopanib when administered with ketoconazole or esomeprazole.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>VEG113971: An Open-Label Study of the Effects of Ketoconazole or Esomeprazole on Pazopanib PK</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is a 2-arm, open-label, repeat-dose, single sequence, crossover, study designed to evaluate the effects of ketoconazole (Arm A) and esomeprazole (Arm B) on the pharmacokinetics (PK) of oral pazopanib in subjects with solid tumor malignancies. This study will compare the PK parameters of oral pazopanib and its metabolite concentrations when given alone and when co-administered with either ketoconazole (Arm A) or esomeprazole (Arm B). Safety assessments (physical examinations, vital signs, 12-lead electrocardiograms, Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status, clinical laboratory assessments, and monitoring of adverse events) will also be evaluated during the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ketoconazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esomeprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed, written informed consent 18 years of age or legal age of consent if greater than 18 years at the time of signing consent Histologically confirmed diagnosis of refractory or relapsed advanced solid tumor malignancy after standard therapy OR for which there is no standard therapy OR for which subject opts not to receive standard therapy Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1 Adequate baseline organ function Subjects may not have had a transfusion within 7 days of screening assessment. Subjects receiving anticoagulant therapy are eligible if their INR is stable and within the protocol recommended range. Male OR Female of nonchildbearing potential (i.e., physiologically incapable of becoming pregnant), including any female who has had: a hysterectomy, a bilateral oophorectomy (ovariectomy), a bilateral tubal ligation, or is postmenopausal OR Nonpregnant Female of childbearing potential, including any female who has had a negative serum pregnancy test within 14 days prior to the first dose of study treatment, agrees to use acceptable contraceptive methods, used consistently and in accordance with both the product label and the instructions of the study physician. OR Female, if lactating, agrees to stop nursing prior to first dose until 14 days after last dose of study drug Able to swallow and retain orally administered medication History or clinical evidence of central nervous system (CNS) metastases or leptomeningeal carcinomatosis, except for individuals who have previouslytreated CNS metastases, are asymptomatic, and have had no requirement for steroids or antiseizure medication for 2 months prior to first dose of study drug Clinically significant GI abnormalities that may increase the risk for GI bleeding including, but not limited to: active peptic ulcer disease, known intraluminal metastatic lesion/s with risk of bleeding inflammatory bowel disease (e.g., ulcerative colitis, Crohn's disease), or other GI conditions with increased risk of perforation, history of abdominal fistula, GI perforation, or intra abdominal abscess within 28 days prior to beginning study treatment. Clinically significant GI abnormalities that may affect absorption of investigational product including, but not limited to: malabsorption syndrome, major resection of the stomach or small bowel. Presence of uncontrolled infection. Corrected QT interval (QTc) &gt;480 msec. History of any one or more of the following cardiovascular conditions within the past 6 months: cardiac angioplasty or stenting, myocardial infarction,unstable angina,coronary artery bypass graft surgery, symptomatic peripheral vascular disease, Class III or IV congestive heart failure, as defined by the New York Heart Association (NYHA). Poorly controlled hypertension Note: Initiation or adjustment of antihypertensive medication(s) is permitted prior to study entry. History of cerebrovascular accident including transient ischemic attack, pulmonary embolism or untreated deep venous thrombosis (DVT) within the past 6 months. Note: Subjects with recent DVT who have been treated with therapeutic anticoagulating agents for at least 6 weeks are eligible. Prior major surgery or trauma within 28 days prior to first dose of study drug and/or presence of any nonhealing wound, fracture, or ulcer (procedures such as catheter placement not considered to be major). Evidence of active bleeding or bleeding diathesis. Known endobronchial lesions and/or lesions infiltrating major pulmonary vessels. Hemoptysis in excess of 2.5 mL (or onehalf teaspoon) within 8 weeks of first dose of study drug. Any serious and/or unstable preexisting medical, psychiatric, or other condition that could interfere with subject's safety, provision of informed consent, or compliance to study procedures. Treatment with any of the following anticancer therapies: radiation therapy, surgery or tumor embolization within 14 days prior to the first dose of pazopanib OR chemotherapy, immunotherapy, biologic therapy, investigational therapy or hormonal therapy within 14 days or 5 halflives of a drug (whichever is longer) prior to the first dose of pazopanib. Any ongoing toxicity from prior anticancer therapy that is &gt; Grade 1 (graded by NCICTCAE, version 4.0), at the time of enrollment and/or that is progressing in severity, except alopecia as well as stable (&gt;4 weeks) ≤Grade 2 neuropathy or rash. Unable or unwilling to discontinue use of protocolprohibited medications for at least 14 days or 5 half lives of a drug (whichever is longer) prior to the first dose of study drug and for the duration of the study. Use of HRT prior to study enrollment due to the potential for inhibition of cytochrome P450 enzymes that metabolize estrogens and progestins (Arm A female subjects only).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Esomeprazole</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacogenetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Ketoconazole</keyword>
	<keyword>Pazopanib</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Interaction</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Solid Tumors</keyword>
</DOC>