<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01205737</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective international, multi-center, randomized, double-blind controlled study designed to assess and compare the pharmacokinetics, pharmacodynamics and the safety of MabThera® and TL011, in combination with CHOP in previously untreated patients with diffuse large B cell lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Double-blind, Randomized Controlled Study in CD20-positive Diffuse B Cell Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Newly diagnosed subjects with a confirmed pathologic diagnosis of diffuse large B cell nonHodgkin's lymphoma (DLBCL) based on the 2008 World Health Organization classification. 2.CD20+ lymphoma cells at screening 1880 (inclusive) years of age at screening Ann Arbor Stages IIV at screening Any IPI score at screening ECOG good performance status (02) at screening Willing and able to provide written informed consent prior to performing study procedures Women of childbearing potential must use effective contraceptive methods starting from screening and until 12 months following the last infusion.. 1. Any lymphoma other than CD20+ DLBCL 2. History of indolent lymphoma 3. DLBCL with central nervous system or meningeal involvement 4. Primary gastrointestinal (MALT) lymphoma 5. Bulky disease&gt;10 cm diagnosed by imaging at screening 6. Bone marrow involvement &gt; 25% according to bone marrow biopsy at screening 7. Subjects previously treated with chemotherapy, radiotherapy, immunotherapy or experimental therapies for lymphoma or other malignancy 8. Hypersensitivity to active ingredients, excipients (sodium citrate, polysorbate 80, sodium chloride, sodium hydroxide, hydrochloric acid, water for injections) and murine proteins 9. Active uncontrolled infection (viral, bacterial or fungal infection) requiring systemic therapy at screening and/or at baseline visit. 10. A documented history of recurrent or chronic clinically significant infection (viral, bacterial or fungal infection) 11. Subjects with a history of tuberculosis or active tuberculosis at screening. 12. Immunodeficiency syndrome or Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) seropositivity 13. Positive Hepatitis B surface antigen or antibodies to Hepatitis C 14. History of other cancer within the past 5 years except curatively treated nonmelanoma skin cancer or in situ carcinoma of uterine cervix 15. Any major surgical procedure within 12 weeks prior to screening and between screening and baseline 16. Immunization with live viral vaccines less than 4 weeks prior to first study drug infusion, and/or planned live viral vaccination during study period. 17. Known allergic reactions against foreign proteins 18. Subjects for whom 8 cycles of CHOP might be problematic, and have the following findings/conditions, should not be enrolled: Cardiac contraindication to doxorubicin: Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt; 50% according to multiacquisition gated (MUGA) scan or 2D Echocardiogram at screening Neurologic contraindication to vincristine: (e.g., peripheral neuropathy) Abnormal hepatic function at screening and/or baseline AST/ALT ≥ 3 x upper normal value (ULN) or ≥ 5 x ULN in the presence of DLBCL involvement of the liver Bilirubin ≥ 2 x ULN or ≥ 5 x ULN in the presence of DLBCL involvement of the liver Abnormal renal function at screening and/or baseline Serum creatinine ≥ 2 x ULN Abnormal bone marrow function at screening and/or baseline Platelets &lt; 100x109/L Neutrophils &lt; 1.5x109/L Hb &lt; 9g/dL 19. Any other serious active disease or comorbid medical condition (according to the investigator's decision and information provided in the Investigator Brochure of TL011) 20. Subjects who, according to the investigator, are likely to be noncompliant or uncooperative during the study. 21. Pregnant or lactating women or women that intend to get pregnant during study or within 12 months following the last infusion. 22. Treatment with any investigational drug within 90 days before planned first cycle of chemotherapy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>DLBCL</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacodynamics</keyword>
</DOC>