<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01340352</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Working hypothesis and aims: To investigate the association between cervical length in non-pregnant women, and the risk of premature birth. The participants will be recruited from the HaEmek Medical Center delivery room registration. Women delivered between 24-37 pregnancy weeks will be allocated to the study group. The investigators will invite them 3 month or more after delivery to ultrasound examination of the cervical length. The participants in the control group will be the women whom term delivery follows by chronological manner to those in study group. Data of the cervucal length will be collected at the time of the examination.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Is It Possible to Predict Pre Term Labor by Measuring Cervical Length in the Non-pregnant Uterus?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Women will be invited to undergo an examination in Ultrasound Unit of Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, HaEmek Medical Center. Ultrasound examination will be performed using the Voluson E8 device, General Electric. The cervical length,between the external and internal orifice will be measured using conventional technologies available including: Doppler, three dimensional and two dimensional ultrasound.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obstetric Labor, Premature</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Nonpregnant women aged 1840 years. Singelton last pregnancy. Last birth, spontaneous premature (2437 week) Last birth at least 3 months ago. Presence of uterine malformations. Sonographic pathologic findings. Technical failure (failed appropiate sonographic visualisation) Presence of fetal malformations ( in preterm delivery ) Presence of comorbidities including diabetes, hypertension, collagen disease, thrombophilia Presence of risk factors for premature delivery (amniotic fluid infection, cervical surgical treatments conization, polyhydramnios, etc.).</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>