<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01340911</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose of the study is to see how safe SRT3025 (study drug) is when given at different doses. The study will also investigate how the study drug is taken up, metabolised (chemically broken down), distributed through the body and excreted. A further aim is to look at how taking the study drug after eating might change this process.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study in Healthy Male Volunteers to Investigate Different Doses of a New Drug for the Treatment of Metabolic Diseases</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>SRT3025 is being developed for the treatment of metabolic diseases. This study is the first administration of SRT3025 in humans and seeks to establish the initial safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetic (PK) profile of SRT3025 (and any metabolites, if analyzed) before proceeding to future Phase 1 studies or Phase 2 patient studies. This protocol details a Phase 1, randomized, placebo-controlled, single-blind, dose escalation study to determine the safety, tolerability, and PK profile of SRT3025 in healthy male subjects. The study will be conducted in two parts. In Part 1A, 6 Cohorts of subjects will receive single escalating doses of SRT3025. In Part 1B, an additional one to two cohorts may be enrolled to investigate the effect of a moderate fat/calorie meal on single dose PK endpoints. In Part 2A, up to three cohorts may be enrolled to receive 14-day repeat doses of SRT3025 chosen from the Part 1A safety, tolerability, and PK data. In Part 2B, one to two additional cohorts may receive 14-day repeat doses of SRT3025 in combination with a moderate fat/calorie meal.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy as determined by a responsible and experienced physician, based on a medical evaluation including medical history, physical examination, laboratory tests and cardiac monitoring. A subject with a clinical abnormality or laboratory parameters outside the reference range for the population being studied may be included only if the Investigator and the Sirtris Medical Monitor agree that the finding is unlikely to introduce additional risk factors and will not interfere with the study procedures. Male between 18 and 55 years of age, inclusive, at the time of signing the informed consent. Male subjects with female partners of childbearing potential must agree to use one of the contraception methods that is permitted in the study. This criterion must be followed from the time of the first dose of study medication until the End of Study Safety Followup Visit. Body weight ≥50 kilogram (kg) and body mass index (BMI) within the range 1829.9 kg/m^2 (inclusive). Capable of giving written informed consent, which includes compliance with the requirements and restrictions listed in the consent form. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST), alanine transaminase (ALT), alkaline phosphatase and bilirubin ≥ 1.5x upper limit normal (ULN) (isolated bilirubin &gt;1.5x ULN is acceptable if bilirubin is fractionated and direct bilirubin &gt;35%). Have an abnormal 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG) or an ECG with abnormality considered to be clinically significant in the opinion of the Investigator. Specifically, single QTcB &gt; 450 msec; or QTc &gt; 480 msec in subjects with Bundle Branch Block. A positive prestudy Hepatitis B surface antigen or positive Hepatitis C antibody result within 3 months of screening Current or chronic history of liver disease, or known hepatic or biliary abnormalities (with the exception of Gilbert's syndrome or asymptomatic gallstones). A positive prestudy drug/alcohol screen. A positive test for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antibody. History of regular alcohol consumption within 6 months of the study defined as an average weekly intake of &gt;21 units. One unit is equivalent to 8 gram (g) of alcohol: a halfpint (~240 ml) of beer, 1 glass (125 ml) of wine or 1 (25 ml) measure of spirits. The subject has participated in a clinical trial and has received an investigational product within the 3 months prior to the first dosing day in the current study. Exposure to more than four new chemical entities within 12 months prior to the first dosing day. Use of prescription or nonprescription drugs, including vitamins, herbal and dietary supplements (including St John's Wort) within 7 days (or 14 days if the drug is a potential enzyme inducer) or 5 halflives (whichever is longer) prior to the first dose of study medication, unless in the opinion of the Investigator and Sirtris Medical Monitor the medication will not interfere with the study procedures or compromise subject safety. History of sensitivity to any of the study medications, or components thereof or a history of drug or other allergy that, in the opinion of the Investigator or Sirtris Medical Monitor, contraindicates his/her participation. History of sensitivity to heparin or heparininduced thrombocytopenia. Subjects who have asthma, history of asthma, are experiencing flulike symptoms, or have had an upper respiratory tract infection within two weeks of screening. Urinary cotinine levels indicative of smoking or history or regular use of tobacco or nicotinecontaining products within 6 months prior to screening. Consumption of red wine, seville oranges, grapefruit or grapefruit juice and/or pummelos, exotic citrus fruits, grapefruit hybrids or fruit juices from 7 days prior to the first dose of study medication.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>