<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01340014</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to assess patient preference regarding ocular comfort of AZARGA® compared to COSOPT® after one week instillation of each study medication.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Patient Preference Comparison of AZARGA Versus COSOPT</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>At the Screening Visit, each intervention was instilled in one eye in a contralateral fashion to establish baseline ocular comfort prior to randomization. A 48-hour washout period separated the two treatment periods.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma, Open-Angle</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ocular Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Timolol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dorzolamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brinzolamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of ocular hypertension, openangle with or without pseudoexfoliation or pigment dispersion glaucoma in both eyes. On a stable regimen of intraocular pressurelowering (IOP) medication within 30 days of Screening Visit. IOP considered safe (in the opinion of the Investigator) in both eyes in such a way that assures clinical stability of vision and the optic nerve throughout the study period. IOP between 19 and 35 millimeters mercury (mmHg) in at least one eye (study eye). Willing to discontinue the use of all other ocular drugs (prescribed and overthecounter) prior to receiving the screening dose during the Screening Visit and for the entire course of the study. Able to follow instructions and willing and able to attend all study visits. Read, sign, and date an Ethics Committee reviewed and approved Informed Consent Form. Other protocoldefined inclusion criteria may apply. Known medical history of allergy, hypersensitivity or poor tolerance to any component of the preparations to be used in this study that is deemed clinically significant in the opinion of the Principal Investigator. Best corrected visual acuity worse than 20/80 Snellen in either eye. Any abnormality preventing reliable applanation tonometry in either eye. Intraocular conventional surgery or laser surgery in either eye less than 3 months prior to the Screening Visit. Risk of visual field or visual acuity worsening as a consequence of participation in the study, in the Investigator's best judgment. Progressive retinal or optic nerve disease from any cause. History of ocular herpes simplex. Severe allergic rhinitis or bronchial hypersensitivity that would preclude the safe administration of a topical betablocker. Bronchial asthma, a history of bronchial asthma, or severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease that would preclude the safe administration of a topical betablocker. Women who are pregnant, lactating, or of childbearing potential and not using a reliable means of birth control. Participation in any other investigational study within 30 days prior to the Screening/baseline Visit. Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Glaucoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Intraocular pressure</keyword>
	<keyword>Tonometry, ocular</keyword>
</DOC>