<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00464633</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Multicenter, open-label, study of alvocidib in previously treated chronic lymphocytic leukemia patients. Primary objective is to determine overall response rate. The secondary objectives are: - to assess overall safety, - to assess duration of response, progression free survival, and overall survival. Clinical benefit and pharmacokinetics parameters are also evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Alvocidib in Patients With Previously Treated Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia or Prolymphocytic Leukemia Arising From Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Treatment until disease progression or no evidence of treatment response; occurrence of unacceptable toxicity, intercurrent medical problem, or adverse event (AE); or a maximum of 6 cycles. Follow-up of 6 months after the last treatment with alvocidib. The maximum duration of the study participation for patient will be about 15 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Prolymphocytic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alvocidib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient must have documentation of histologically confirmed and measurable Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL) or Prolymphocytic Leukemia (PLL) arising from CLL; Patient must have symptomatic and progressive disease; Patient must have received prior alkylating agent(s) and be fludarabine refractory; Patient must have the adequate organ functions; Patient's Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance (ECOG) status must be 02; Patient with de novo PLL; Patient with secondary malignancy that will limit survival ≤5 years; Patient with prior allogenic or autologous bone marrow transplant or peripheral blood stem cell transplant ≤12 months; Patient receiving an investigational agent or an approved agent for an investigational purpose within last 4 weeks prior to study entry; Patient with known history of glucose6phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency; Patient with autoimmune hemolytic anemia; Patient with known Central Nervous System involvement; Patient with active, uncontrolled serious bacterial, viral or fungal infections The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>CLL</keyword>
	<keyword>PLL</keyword>
	<keyword>flavopiridol</keyword>
</DOC>