<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00464347</DOC>
	<brief_summary>VERTACL will investigate whether a triple therapy, Avastin®, half fluence verteporfin photodynamic therapy (PDT), and triamcinolone acetonide-preservative free (TAC- PF), results in improved 12-month vision outcome compared to Avastin® alone in participants with neovascular AMD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TAC-PF, Avastin® in Combination With Photodynamic Therapy to Treat Age Related Macular Degeneration</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The VERTACL study is a multi-center, randomized, Phase II trial to investigate whether a triple therapy, Avastin®, half fluence verteporfin PDT, and TAC- PF, results in improved 12-month vision outcome compared to Avastin® alone in participants with neovascular AMD. Participants will be randomized (similar to the flip of a coin) in a 1:1 ratio to one of the two study groups: single therapy (Avastin®), or triple therapy (Avastin®, half fluence verteporfin PDT, and TAC- PF). Participants in the Avastin® alone arm will receive 1.25 mg intravitreal Avastin®, at every study visit. Participants in the triple-therapy arm will receive all treatments (Avastin®, half fluence verteporfin PDT, and TAC- PF) at baseline. Following baseline, participants in the triple therapy study arm will receive study treatment on an as-needed (PRN) basis if protocol-specific re-treatment criteria are met. After randomization, participants will return to the clinic approximately every six weeks for one year for study assessments and possible re-treatment. Participants will return to the clinic at month 24 for a final study assessment. Study assessments include: visual acuity, optical coherence tomography, and fundus photography.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone hexacetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone Acetonide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triamcinolone diacetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Includes: Drusen &gt; 63 mm Choroidal neovascularization under the fovea (Predominantly Classic, Minimally Classic, and Occult lesions acceptable) Greatest linear dimension (GLD) of entire lesion &lt; 5400 µm (no reading center confirmation required) ETDRS best corrected visual acuity of 20/40 20/320 (73 24 letter score) Total area of lesion must &lt; 9 MPS DA 03 intravitreal injections of antiVEGF monotherapy within 6 months of randomization with continuing evidence of exudative activity confirmed by FA or OCT within 48 weeks after the last injection Exclusion Criteria Includes: Oral steroid use within 6 months Prior complications from steroid therapy Prior stroke, myocardial infarction, or endstage malignancy Study Eye Exclusion Criteria Geographic atrophy or fibrosis under the fovea Fibrosis, hemorrhage, pigment epithelial detachments and other hypofluorescent lesions obscuring more than 50% of total lesion Prior treatment with verteporfin within 12 months IOP is &gt;25 mmHg and the participant is on Cosopt Intraocular surgery within 6 weeks Prior vitrectomy Peribulbar steroid injection within 6 months Poor reactions to topical or periocular steroid treatment including elevated IOP</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>AMD</keyword>
	<keyword>wet AMD</keyword>
	<keyword>verteporfin PDT</keyword>
	<keyword>Avastin</keyword>
	<keyword>TAC-PF</keyword>
</DOC>