<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01570998</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study proposes to study the efficacy and toxicity of breast radiotherapy given intra-operatively as a single dose after breast conserving surgery, with or without whole breast radiation as indicated by pathologic risk factors, in women with early stage breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Targeted Intraoperative Radiotherapy United States (TARGIT-US) Registry Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A pragmatic registry trial has been designed and modeled after the original successful, international TARGIT-A protocol, to continue the use of intraoperative radiotherapy for a select population of women, and to follow outcomes with regards to local and regional control, toxicity and morbidity. Within this pragmatic single arm registry trial is a more selective approach that may be employed in some centers for some or all patients. Patients selected for breast conserving surgery who are considered to have a low risk of local recurrence are eligible for the registry trial once given their informed consent.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ductal, Breast</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Breast Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All patients aged 45 years or older with operable invasive breast cancer, T1 and T2 (&lt; 3.5 cm), N01, M0, confirmed by cytological or histological examination, who are suitable for breast conserving surgery are eligible as long as they have had an ipsilateral diagnostic mammogram within 12 months of enrollment. Those with previously diagnosed and treated contralateral breast cancer may be entered. It is recommended that patients meet an ECOG performance status of 03, however, grade 4 patients can be treated at the discretion of the participating center. Individual centers may wish to restrict entry to a more exactly defined subset of patients in which case only patients with these characteristics may be entered by the particular center. For example, centers may decide at outset to recruit only women over the age of 50 or possibly only postmenopausal women. Before entering any patient into the trial, the local investigator should confirm that the patient would be available for regular followup for at least 5 years. Age &lt; 45 years Axillary lymph node positive breast cancer Invasive lobular cancer Tumor size &gt; 3.5 cm Extensive Intraductal Component (EIC= &gt; 25% of the lumpectomy specimen involved with ductal carcinoma in situ, DCIS) as assessed on surgical pathologic lumpectomy specimen Multicentric cancer in the same breast as diagnosed by clinical examination, mammography, ultrasound. MRI or pathologic assessment, not amenable to excision with negative margins with a single lumpectomy. Inability to assess pathologic margin status Bilateral breast cancer at the time of diagnosis. Ipsilateral breast had a previous cancer and/or prior infield radiation. Patients known to have BRCA1/2 gene mutations (testing for gene mutations is not required). Patients undergoing primary systemic treatment (hormones or chemotherapy) as initial treatment with neoadjuvant intent of reducing tumor size. No more than 30 days can have elapsed between the last breast cancer surgery (not axillary) and entry into the trial for patients in the postpathology stratification. Previous history of malignant disease does not preclude entry if the expectation of relapsefree survival at 10 years is 75% or greater Any factor included as exclusion criteria in the participating center's Treatment Policy Statement.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Disease-Free Survival</keyword>
	<keyword>Female</keyword>
	<keyword>Humans</keyword>
	<keyword>Intraoperative Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Mastectomy Segmental</keyword>
	<keyword>Middle Aged</keyword>
	<keyword>Neoplasm Recurrence Local</keyword>
	<keyword>Radiotherapy Dosage</keyword>
	<keyword>Radiotherapy Adjuvant</keyword>
</DOC>