<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00291876</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to evaluate the persistence of hepatitis A antibodies at 138, 150, 162, 174,186, 198, 210, 222, 234 and 246 months after subjects received their first dose of a 2 dose vaccination schedule of hepatitis A vaccine. This protocol posting deals with objectives &amp; outcome measures of the extension phase at year 11 to 20. No additional subjects will be recruited during this long-term follow-up.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-Term Immune Persistence of GlaxoSmithKline Biologicals' Inactivated Hepatitis A Vaccine Injected According to a 0, 12-month Schedule</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a long-term follow-up study at Years 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19 and 20 after primary vaccination with GSK Biologicals' hepatitis A vaccine (two-dose schedule). To evaluate the long-term antibody persistence, volunteers will donate a blood sample at Years 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19 and 20 after the first vaccine dose of the primary vaccination course to determine their anti-hepatitis A (anti-HAV) antibody concentrations. If a subject has become seronegative for anti-HAV antibodies during any of the long-term blood sampling time point (i.e. Months 138, 150, 162, 174,186, 198, 210, 222, 234 and 246), he/ she will be offered an additional vaccine dose. A blood sample will be taken on the day of the additional vaccination 14 days and one month after additional vaccination to evaluate the immune response following this vaccination. The Protocol Posting has been updated in order to comply with the FDA Amendment Act, Sep 2007 and to extend the follow up until Year 20. The study has 10 phases: 100571, 100572, 100573, 100574, 100575, 110677, 110678, 110679, 110680, 110681.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who had received at least one dose of the study vaccine in the primary study Written informed consent will have been obtained from the subjects before the blood sampling visit of each year.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>29 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HAVRIX™</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis A</keyword>
</DOC>