<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00325663</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study was to evalute three different acupuncture techniques, including one sham control, in its effect on osteoarthitis of the knee</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acupuncture in Osteoarthritis of the Knee</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: Acupuncture is one of the most frequently used complementary therapeutic approaches in the treatment of osteoarthritis of the knee. Due to methodological shortcomings of previous randomized controlled studies, controversy persists whether the observed effects are specific to acupuncture or non-specific consequences of needling. Objective: To compare classical Chinese acupuncture, semi-standardized modern acupuncture and non-specific needling by means of a double-blinded repeated measures cross-over design. Intervention: Within three weeks all patients receive three treatment modalities in a random order in a double-blind study design. Main outcome measures: Improvement in knee flexibility according to the neutral-zero method, defining a success as improvement by 10 degrees or more. Secondary parameter: improvement in pain according to the reduced WOMAC score by 50 percent or more.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients above age 35 knee osteoarthritis grade II or III according to the Kellgren classification. orthopedic deformations of the knee, malignant disease autoimmune disorders surgery including arthroscopy during the past 12 months pain medication with steroids physical therapy or acupuncture within the last for weeks no or a pain medication in continuous dosage</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2004</verification_date>
	<keyword>acupuncture</keyword>
	<keyword>double-blind</keyword>
	<keyword>sham control</keyword>
	<keyword>osteoarthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
</DOC>