<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00325039</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim of this clinical trial is to compare treatment success for two minimally invasive surgical procedures to treat stress urinary incontinence in women. These procedures are called mid-urethral slings. The secondary aims of the trial are to compare other outcomes for the two surgical procedures, including quality of life, sexual function, satisfaction with treatment outcomes, complications, and the need for other treatments(s) after surgery. Follow-up will be a minimum of two years.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TOMUS-Trial Of Mid-Urethral Slings</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Enuresis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female Stress urinary incontinence (SUI) as evidenced by all of the following: Selfreported stresstype urinary incontinence symptoms, of duration ≥ 3 months Medical, Epidemiological and Social Aspects of Aging (MESA) stress symptom score (percent of total possible stress score) greater than MESA urge symptom score (percent of total possible urge score) Observation of leakage by provocative stress test at a bladder volume ≤ 300ml Bladder capacity ≥ 200ml by stress test Postvoid residual (PVR) ≤ 100cc with pelvic organ prolapse (POP) Stage I or lower. If POP is Stage IIIV, PVR &gt;100cc but ≤ 500cc is allowed Eligible for both retropubic and transobturator procedures No medical contraindications, e.g., current urinary tract infection (UTI), history of pelvic irradiation, history of lower urinary tract cancer American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) class I, II, or III No current intermittent catheterization Available for 24months of followup and able to complete study assessments, per clinician judgment Signed consent form Age &lt;21 years Nonambulatory (ambulatory with assistive devices does not exclude the patient) Pregnancy by selfreport or positive pregnancy test, or selfreported intention to ever become pregnant Current chemotherapy or current or history of pelvic radiation therapy Systemic disease known to affect bladder function (i.e., Parkinson's disease, multiple sclerosis, spina bifida, spinal cord injury or trauma) Urethral diverticulum, current or previous (i.e. repaired) Prior augmentation cystoplasty or artificial sphincter Implanted nerve stimulators for urinary symptoms History of synthetic sling for stress urinary incontinence &lt;12 months postpartum Laparoscopic or open pelvic surgery &lt;3 months* Current evaluation or treatment for chronic pelvic pain (painful bladder syndrome) Participation in another treatment intervention trial that might influence the results of this trial Need for concomitant surgery requiring an abdominal incision, use of graft material in the anterior compartment, or any use of synthetic graft material Enrollment in other urinary incontinence trials including SISTEr/ESISTEr or BEDRI/EBEDRI</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Urinary Incontinence, Stress</keyword>
	<keyword>Surgery</keyword>
</DOC>