<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01317693</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Low intensity shockwaves (1/10 the ones used in Lithotripsy) are delivered to the penile tissue. Shockwaves are created by a special generator and are focused using a specially designed shockwave applicator apparatus. The shockwaves are delivered through the applicator covering the corpora cavernosa of the penis. In previous studies the investigators used a medium focused probe and in this study the investigators are evaluating results of this therapy using a wider focus probe in the aim of improving results of treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Extracorporeal Shock Wave Therapy With a Wide Focus Probe for the Treatment of Erectile Dysfunction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Erectile Dysfunction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ED of more than 6 months At least 50% unsuccessful to attempt sexual intercourse for 4 times at 4 different days Positive response to PDE5 inhibitors IIEF5 domain score of 1220 denoting mild to severe ED NonNeurological pathology Stable heterosexual relationship for more than 3 months NPT normal/flat Prior prostatectomy surgery Any cause of ED other than vascular related Any unstable medical, psychiatric, spinal cord injury, penile anatomical abnormalities Clinically significant chronic hematological disease Cardiovascular conditions that prevent sexual activity History of heart attack, stroke or lifethreatening arrhythmia within the prior 6 months. Cancer within the past 5 years. Antiandrogens, oral or injectable androgens Use of any treatment for ED within 7 days of screening including oral medications, vacuum devices, constrictive devices, injections or urethral suppositories</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>LI-ESWT</keyword>
	<keyword>Erectile Dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>ED</keyword>
	<keyword>Shock waves</keyword>
	<keyword>Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>