<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02928939</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Clinical practice guidelines do not take into account multimorbidity and various potential therapeutic conflicts. Identifying and quantifying therapeutic conflicts is crucial in multimorbid patients having more than two acute or chronic diseases. Guidance should be available for frequent encountered situations, e.g. gastrointestinal bleeding or exacerbation of diabetes mellitus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Therapeutic Conflicts and Multimorbidity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study investigates multimorbidity in view of the occurrence of two different therapeutic conflicts or dilemma situations, respectively. The first concerns patients with diagnosis of gastrointestinal bleeding and prescription of anticoagulants or/and antiplatelet drugs (e.g., warfarin, clopidogrel and acetylsalicylic acid) as a risk factor for bleeding events. The second concerns patients with diagnosis of exacerbated diabetes mellitus and prescription of corticosteroids as a risk factor for worsening of blood glucose.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Complications</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inpatients at the University Hospital Zurich, USZ Male and female patients, aged 18 years or older Fulfilling the criteria for Use Case A or B (i.e. patients with gastrointestinal bleeding and anticoagulants or antiplatelet drugs, Use Case A or patients with diabetes mellitus and/or systemic corticosteroids, Use Case B) If potential participants have a statement in the electronic medical record or elsewhere to refuse study participation, this represents exclusion criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>multimorbidity</keyword>
	<keyword>multiple chronic conditions</keyword>
	<keyword>drug-drug interactions</keyword>
	<keyword>drug-disease interactions</keyword>
	<keyword>polypharmacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Oral anticoagulants</keyword>
	<keyword>Steroids</keyword>
</DOC>