<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01010269</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare Vanguard High Flex Rotating Platform to Vanguard Complete Knee System in Asian population in terms of early range of motion (ROM), clinical outcomes, and kinetic and kinematic characteristics in relation to healthy knees.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vanguard Complete Knee Versus Vanguard High Flex Rotating Platform (RP) Knee Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objectives of this clinical study include: - Evaluate size fit and long term performance of Vanguard Complete Knee ("Fixed") System in Asian and Latino population in comparison to competitor's similar product. - Evaluate efficacy of Vanguard Complete Knee with Microplasty Tibial Tray. - Compare Vanguard High Flex Rotating Platform ("High Flex") Knee System to Vanguard Complete Knee System in Asian population in terms of: - Early ROM - Clinical outcomes - Kinetic and Kinematic characteristics in relation to Healthy Knees. o - Compare current design to new design of Vanguard High Flex Rotating Platform Knee System in terms of : - Early ROM - Clinical outcomes - Kinetic and Kinematic characteristics</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Painful and disabled knee joint resulting form osteoarthritis, rheumatoid arthritis, traumatic arthritis where one or more compartments are involved. Correction of varus, valgus, or posttraumatic deformity. Correction or revision of unsuccessful osteotomy, or arthrodesis. Need to obtain pain relief and improve function. Ability and willingness of the patient to follow instructions, including control of weight and activity level. Good nutritional state of the patient. Patient must have reached full skeletal maturity. Infection, sepsis, osteomyelitis, and failure of previous joint replacement. Uncooperative patient or patients with neurologic disorders who are incapable of following directions. Osteoporosis Metabolic disorders which may impair bone formation Osteomalacia Distant foci of infections which may spread to the implant site Rapid joint destruction, marked bone loss or bone resorption apparent on roentgenogram Vascular insufficiency, muscular atrophy, neuromuscular disease Incomplete or deficient soft tissue surrounding the knee</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>