<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01010802</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether recombinant human Erythropoietin (EPOrh) is safe in the treatment of patients with Parkinson's Disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of Erythropoietin (EPO) in Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After onset of Parkinson's Disease (PD)- in spite of the use of medications that constitute the symptomatic treatment- the disease is worsens with an inevitable progression, thus causing complications that lead to the loss of patient´s manual skills and independent gait. At present, the treatment of PD with the use of medications is based on dopamine precursors and dopaminergic agonists but as the disease advances, other symptoms that do not respond to dopaminergic stimulation do appear. For this reason, it is a priority to find a way to focus on neuroprotection during the course of the disease. There are evidences of neuroprotecting therapeutic alternatives in such substances as erythropoietin (EPO). Positive results on the neuroprotective/neurotrophic efficacy of EPO in neurological and psychiatric diseases have been obtained from treatment trials, but nevertheless, it is indispensable demonstrate that with the proposed medication doses it's well tolerated by PD patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Hohen and Yahr´s Scale between I and III One or more years of evolution of PD, Good response to levodopa (more that 30 % of change)valued in motor UPDRS An acceptable general health status, Chronic psychiatric or other neurological diseases. Previous polyglobulin Hematocryte, same or inferior to 50</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neuroprotection</keyword>
	<keyword>Parkinson Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Erythropoietin</keyword>
</DOC>