<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02020239</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators goal is to optimise physical activity interventions to help previously inactive women improve their body shape and composition. Many people seeking to lose weight or improve body composition initiate an exercise programme. The most common recommendation of an exercise intervention for someone attempting to manage their weight, has been to 'prescribe' the recommended 150 minutes of exercise per week (World Health Organisation), often using one mode of exercise. An alternative approach might be to offer a portfolio of activities, from which the exerciser can pick and choose, to facilitate greater amounts of physical activity. The problem with this is how do you account for the different intensities of walking, washing the car, playing badminton, cycling, jogging, etc? In this study, the investigators will try to overcome this barrier by allocating a number of "physical activity points" to each activity. Using this physical activity points system, participants will be provided with a points target that they can meet using any combination of activities. The investigators research aim is therefore to compare this points-based system against the traditional 5x30minute prescription (and sedentary control) for their ability to help previously inactive women to drop a dress size, increase fat burning, positively change their body composition and tone their tummy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Physical Activity Intervention Flexibility on the Time Course of Changes in Body Composition and Metabolism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female Aged 2550 years old Inactive (less than 150 minutes of moderateintensity aerobic physical activity per week) BMI 2535 kg/m2 Good general health, as assessed by the School of Sport, Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences' General Health Questionnaire Willing to strictly comply with all study procedures and restrictions Willing to participate, as demonstrated by voluntary written informed consent Positive result from the urine sample pregnancy test Currently breast feeding Currently participating in another clinical trial deemed to potentially interfere with this study Current or recent (within the last 30 days) smoker Currently taking prescription or nonprescription medication that may interfere with metabolism (including betablockers, insulin, bronchodilators, antiinflammatory agents, thyroxine and medication/supplements that in the opinion of the investigators may affect metabolism).</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>females</keyword>
	<keyword>body composition</keyword>
</DOC>