<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02020473</DOC>
	<brief_summary>End-of- life care is a major issue in medical ethics with life support technology progress. Intensive care may prolong the dying process in patients who have been unresponsive to the treatment already provided. Withholding or withdrawing of life support (WLS) care was introduced to avoid the suffering of critically ill patients. Decision to WLS is a difficult and affected by several factors including not only disease severity but also ethics, religion, culture, and legal background. In western countries, advance directives had an important role to WLS for dying patients and honor patient autonomy. However, the illegality of advance directives in Korea and Korean culture under Confucianism, requiring children to do the best to treat their parents in the name of filial piety make physicians and family members difficult to WLS in terminally ill patients. Additionally, WLS in intensive care unit had been usually decided without official documentation before the final legal decision by Supreme Court in Korea. Scanty information exists about end-of-life practices because informed consents of WLS were taken after the legal decision. Thus, we aimed to investigate the current status of informed consent at the time of decision to WLS and difference between WLS group and non-WLS group in Korea.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Informed Consents for Withholding/Withdrawing Life Support in Intensive Care Units</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>patients who died from January 2012 to December 2012 in the surgical or medical Intensive Care Unit (ICU) at Severance Hospital, Yonsei University Health System, in Seoul, Korea. Patients diagnosed with brain death</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>92 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Informed consents</keyword>
	<keyword>Withholding/withdrawing life support (WLS)</keyword>
	<keyword>Intensive care unit (ICU)</keyword>
</DOC>