<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01546337</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Anemia is common among cancer patients and the treatment of choice is now Erythropoiesis-Stimulating Agents (ESAs). However, some patients do not respond to treatment. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the predictive value of endogenous erythropoietin rate on the response to erythropoietin beta. First, by confirming the predictive value of endogenous erythropoietin observed / predicted ratio on this response. Then if it is confirmed by establishing the optimal value of this ratio.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Search for Predictive Markers of Efficacy of ESAs in Patients With Non-myeloid Malignancies or Myelodysplastic Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Anemia is common among cancer patients and the treatment of choice is now Erythropoiesis-Stimulating Agents (ESAs). However, some patients do not respond to treatment. Thus, only 50-60% of patients with multiple myeloma or non-Hodgkin lymphoma respond to ESAs. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the predictive value of endogenous erythropoietin rate on the response to erythropoietin beta. First, by confirming the predictive value of endogenous erythropoietin observed / predicted ratio on this response. Then if it is confirmed by establishing the optimal value of this ratio.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients over 18 patients with nonmyeloid haemopathy receiving chemotherapy or myelodysplastic syndrome indication of ESAs therapy with Hb &lt; 11g/dl uncontrolled hypertension anemia due to deficiency pregnant and lactating women patient who received treatment with erythropoiesisactivating factors in the two months preceding inclusion</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>non-myeloid haemopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>myelodysplastic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Erythropoiesis stimulating agents</keyword>
	<keyword>predictive markers</keyword>
</DOC>