<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03031093</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study has the objective to clarify the factors that directly influence the effectiveness of inhaled drug deposition in obese patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and suggest the use of epap valve during their inhalation therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aerosol Therapy in Obese COPD Patients.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study has the objective to clarify the factors that directly influence the effectiveness of inhaled drug deposition in obese patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and the formulate specific strategies that potentiate the control of the evolution of this disease. The suggested strategy in order to implement the aerosol therapy is the use of epap valve during these patient´s inhalation therapy. It will consist in a cross-over clinical trial. The population will be composed by volunteers of both genders, aged between 45-70 years old. Four distinct groups will be formed: obese participants without copd; obese participants with copd; non obese participants without copd; non-obese participants with copd.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fenoterol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ipratropium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bronchodilator Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bromides</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pentetic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Edetic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinol acetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HEALTHY, non obese no history of respiratory disease non smokers self declared sedentary Forced expiratory volume at first second (FEV1) equal or higher than 80% of predicted Forced Vital capacity (FVC) equal or higher than 80% of predicted; FEV1/FVC higher than 70% of predicted. BMI lower than 30 kg/m2 HEALTHY, obese no history of respiratory disease non smokers self declared sedentary Forced expiratory volume at first second (FEV1) equal or higher than 80% of predicted Forced Vital capacity (FVC) equal or higher than 80% of predicted FEV1/FVC higher than 70% of predicted. BMI equal or higher than 30 kg/m2 COPD participants, non obese ex smokers clinical stability (six previous weeks) FEV1 lower than 80% of predicted. FEV1/FVC lower than 70 % post bronchodilator. No cardiopulmonary diseases (self declared) BMI lower than 30 kg/m2 COPD participants, obese ex smokers clinical stability (six previous weeks) FEV1 lower than 80% of predicted. FEV1/FVC lower than 70 % post bronchodilator. No cardiopulmonary diseases (self declared) BMI equal or higher than 30 kg/m2 Difficulty to understand verbal commands exacerbations during the study period</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>aerosol therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>pulmonary scintigraphy</keyword>
	<keyword>upper airways anatomy</keyword>
</DOC>