<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01026610</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to investigate the safety and the antiviral activity of two doses of LB80380 for 48 weeks in treatment-naive patients with chronic hepatitis B infection compared to entecavir 0.5 mg.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of LB80380 in the Treatment-naive Patients of Chronic Hepatitis B</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>LB80380, an oral prodrug, is a promising candidate nucleotide analogue with antiviral activity against wild-type HBV. LB80380 is undergoing clinical development by LG Life Sciences for use in the treatment of chronic HBV infection. In this study, the treatment period is 48-week with 24-week of follow-up period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Entecavir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female or male, 18 to 65 years of age, inclusive Chronic hepatitis B Not treated with antiviral therapeutics including interferon or pegylated interferons for more than 12 weeks before Screening Not treated with antiviral therapeutics including interferon or pegylated interferons 6 months within Screening Compensated chronic hepatitis B HBeAg positive or HBeAg negative Elevated serum ALT level (1.210 X ULN, inclusive) Coinfection with hepatitis C or D virus (HCV or HDV) or HIV Decompensated liver disease Creatinine clearance (calculated by CockroftGault formula) less than 50 ml/min Screening alphafetoprotein (AFP) value greater than or equal to 50 ng/mL, and a followup ultrasonography performed prior to baseline shows findings indicative of HCC Treatment with immunomodulatory agent or corticosteroids within 6 months prior to study entry. Pregnancy or breastfeeding Patient is currently abusing alcohol or illicit drugs Significant systemic illnesses other than liver diseases Presence of other causes of liver disease A history of organ transplantation Presence of antiHBs at screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic hepatitis B</keyword>
	<keyword>LB80380</keyword>
	<keyword>treatment-naive</keyword>
	<keyword>entecavir</keyword>
</DOC>