<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01797458</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this randomized clinical trial is to compare the clinical effectiveness of three treatments involving different caries management strategies (conventional restorations, Hall technique, and a non-restorative treatment of dental caries) to the management of class II carious primary molar in children 3-8 year-old from three different countries (Scotland, Lithuania, and Germany).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>European Study on Three Different Approaches to Managing Class 2 Cavities in Primary Teeth</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>At present, many materials and techniques are used to treat carious primary teeth. All of these have their proponents who claim they provide the best performance in terms of longevity, aesthetics, bio-compatibility, etc (Qvist, 2010; Yengopal et al., 2009). However, despite the great variety of techniques and materials, there is no definite evidence for the most effective approach when dental caries in primary molars is concerned, as yet. On the other hand, there is conclusive evidence that shows that glass-ionomer cement is an inappropriate material for class II restorations in primary teeth, due to its significant shorter longevity compared with other restorative materials like compomer and amalgam. Recently, there is re-surging interest in "old" techniques: such as opening-up cavities used in Denmark and Netherlands (Peretz &amp; Gluck, 2006; Gruythuysen et al., 2010) or stainless steel crowns with the advent of the Hall technique in Scotland (Innes et al., 2007). However, there is lack of comparative evidence from high quality clinical trials leading to uncertainty in the effectiveness of these techniques. In addition, these techniques are rarely compared with standard fillings.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dental Caries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children aged 38 years (Germany: children who attend the Präventive Zahnmedizin und Kinderzahnheilkunde department at ErnstMoritzArndtUniversität Greifswald; Scotland: children who attend the paediatric dentistry department, School of Dentistry at University of Dundee; Lithuania: children who attend the paediatric dentistry department, Dental Faculty, Lithuanian University of Health Sciences) At least one primary molar tooth with caries into dentine involving two dental surfaces (diagnosed according to International Caries Detection and Assessment System ICDAS, codes 3 to 5) Willing to be examined Clinical or radiographic signs of pulpar or periradicular pathology Patients with a systemic disease requiring special considerations during their dental treatment. Parents/children who refuse to participate in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>8 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>class II carious primary molar</keyword>
	<keyword>Opening-up cavities</keyword>
	<keyword>Hall Technique</keyword>
	<keyword>Conventional restorations</keyword>
</DOC>