<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02679703</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the effect of the polarity of the electric current in healing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Polarity Action in Electrical Stimulation Transcutaneous Donors for Treatment Areas Burned Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of this study is to evaluate the effect of the polarity of the current in healing. Both will be compared to the effects of electrical stimulation of high voltage (HVES) and neuromuscular transcutaneous electrical stimulation (TENS) in the treatment of donor sites (DA) of burn patients. It is a prospective, controlled clinical, randomized, blinded. Will be assessed 60 subjects aged 18-59 years, of both sexes, underwent the surgical procedure of grafting (PCE) were randomly divided into small blocks 5:5:5 three groups: undergoing therapeutic procedure with HVES undergoing therapeutic procedure with TENS and control. Therapeutic procedures will be applied around the DA, thigh or scalp, after 24 hours of PCE until complete healing. The variables will be the healing time estimated by the removal of the dressing rayon, clinical evaluation, scar quality, the Vancouver scale; pain, the pain numerical scale evaluation (PNS); blood perfusion by thermography; quality of healing by digital imaging, quantification of areas of crusts by the software Image J; skin biomechanical aspects as firmness, the durometer being performed reassessment at the end of treatment. Data will be submitted to analysis of normality by the Shapiro-Wilk test and the effect of behavior among groups and pre- and post-intervention will be evaluated by ANOVA-two way followed by post-hoc (Bonferroni) or Friedman, with p &lt;0.05. Comparing groups, before a normal distribution is applied ANOVA followed by Tukey, and otherwise will be applied the Kruskal-Wallis test and post-hoc Dunn, p&lt;0.05.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Victims of second deep degree and third degree burns, aged between 18 and 59 years Both sexes Underwent the surgical procedure of grafting (PCE) with donor area of the scalp or thigh thick standardized mean (0.20 mm). Diabetes, Infectious processes Use of medications that alter the healing process (corticosteroids, chemotherapy, radiotherapy, among others) Cognitive impairment Agreeing not to sign the Consent Form and Clarified or that do not fit the inclusion criteria described.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>59 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>