<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02679742</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel study to assess the effects of β-hydroxymethylbutyrate (β-HMB) combined with a resistance training program, after an acute process in older patients with sarcopenia in terms of muscle mass, muscle strength and physical performance. Treatments compared will be β-hydroxymethylbutyrate (β-HMB) with a resistance training program or placebo with a resistance training program.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Postacute Sarcopenia: Supplementation With β-hydroxyMethylbutyrate After Resistance Training</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Sarcopenia is a geriatric syndrome characterized by the loss of skeletal muscle mass and strength that occurs with advancing age; it is related to frailty, falls, worsening quality of life, and death in chronic and elderly patients. Diagnosis of sarcopenia is based on clinical criteria: presence of low muscle mass and the presence of low muscle function and/or low physical performance. The latest developments indicate that dietary supplementation combined with resistance exercise could be an option to improve muscle mass and function. The objective of the study is to assess the effects of β-hydroxymethylbutyrate (β-HMB) combined with a resistance training program, after an acute process in older patients with sarcopenia in terms of muscle mass, muscle strength and physical performance. Design: A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel study with two intervention groups. The investigators shall compare placebo against an intervention with β-HMB in patients performing a resistance training program after an acute process (post-acute period) during 12 weeks. There will be 20 patients in each arm of the study. Additionally a one year follow up visit will be performed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcopenia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>male or female ≥60 years old sarcopenia diagnosis and casefinding criteria following European Working Group On Sarcopenia in Older People (EWGSOP) being discharged from postacute care geriatric unit for rehabilitation treatment ambulatory prior to the recent acute process cognitive situation that let them to understand and follow an active physical rehabilitation program (MiniMental Status Examination ≥21/30) voluntary participation and being able and willing to provide an informed consent potential participants will be excluded if they have active malignancy (exception basal or squamous cell skin carcinoma or carcinoma in situ of the uterine cervix) major lower limb surgery over the past 6 months (knee or hip arthroplasty) contraindication for resistance training performed regular exercise in the last 6 months use of any medications interfering with the nutritional intervention serious clinical conditions that compromises and endanger the patient's life contraindication, intolerance or allergy to βhydroxymethylbutyrate</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>beta hydroxy beta methylbutyrate</keyword>
	<keyword>older people</keyword>
	<keyword>muscle mass</keyword>
	<keyword>muscle strength</keyword>
	<keyword>post-acute</keyword>
</DOC>