<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02679716</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Retinal artery occlusions (RAO) cause deterioration in visual acuity and visual fields. In computational fluid dynamics (CFD) studies [Kaufmann et al. 2012] 10% of ascending emboli caused RAO, the residual 90% embolized into the cerebral arteries. As only 20% of patients with RAO had a history of stroke [Wang et al 2006, Leisser et al 2010-2014], there is a discrepancy between CFD-studies and clinical observations. Mead et al. [7] postulated small emboli being washed into the cerebral arteries without causing clinical symptoms of stroke, whereas similar emboli being washed into the ophthalmic artery would cause RAO. There is a discrepancy between CFD-study results and clinical observations in RAO patients, indicating that there could be a high number of RAO-patients having had cerebral ischemies without symptoms of stroke (as postulated by Mead et al. 2002). Purpose of the present study is to evaluate hemodynamic pathological changes at the ophthalmic artery origin in patients with RAO detected with an already existing CFD-model</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Reconstruction of Pathological Changes of the Ophthalmic Artery in Patients With Retinal Artery Occlusion</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Retinal artery occlusions (RAO) cause deterioration in visual acuity and visual fields. Emboli from plaques of the carotid artery, aortic arch or vegetations of the cardiac valves are the main reasons for RAO. In computational fluid dynamics (CFD) studies [Kaufmann et al. 2012] 10% of ascending emboli caused RAO, the residual 90% embolized into the cerebral arteries. As only 20% of patients with RAO had a history of stroke [Wang et al 2006, Leisser et al 2010-2014], there is a discrepancy between CFD-studies and clinical observations. Mead et al. [7] postulated small emboli being washed into the cerebral arteries without causing clinical symptoms of stroke, whereas similar emboli being washed into the ophthalmic artery would cause RAO. Hayreh et al. (2009) reported plaques of the carotid artery to be the main reason for emboli causing RAO. There is a discrepancy between CFD-study results and clinical observations in RAO patients, indicating that there could be a high number of RAO-patients having had cerebral ischemies without symptoms of stroke (as postulated by Mead et al. 2002). A recently published report showed ischemic cerebral lesions in 38% of patients with RAO without neurological symptoms [Lee et al. 2014]. The fact, that the 3-year risk of patients with RAO to develop stroke is doubled [Chang et al. 2012], underlines further associations between RAO and stroke. Purpose of the present study is to evaluate hemodynamic pathological changes at the ophthalmic artery origin in patients with RAO detected with an already existing CFD-model</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arterial Occlusive Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Artery Occlusion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Newly diagnosed RAO Older than 21 years Informed consent Women in reproductive age</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>