<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02679911</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to compare subject's compliance and satisfaction for two modes of treatment of toenails infection (Onychomycosis) with Loceryl Nail Lacquer (Loceryl NL) and Ciclopirox Nail Lacquer (Ciclopirox NL).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Onychomycosis With Loceryl (Amorolfine) Nail Lacquer 5% Versus Ciclopirox Nail Lacquer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A total of 20 subjects are to be included in 1 site in Germany. Methodology: Subjects will receive the following treatments on the right or left toenails: - Loceryl Nail Lacquer to be applied once weekly for 12 weeks on all affected toenails of one foot. - Ciclopirox Nail Lacquer to be applied once daily for 12 weeks on all affected toenails of the opposite foot.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Onychomycosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Skin Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Foot Dermatoses</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amorolfine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ciclopirox</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject with clinically Distal and Lateral Subungual Onychomycosis (DLSO) due to dermatophytes and/or yeast (including Candida) on at least one toenail of each foot at screening visit, Subject with less than 80% of the nail surface area with disease involvement and without matrix involvement, no dermatophytoma, streaks (spikes) or subungual hyperkeratosis &gt; 2mm, Subjects with positive mycological results (direct microscopy and culture) for dermatophytes and/or yeasts (including Candida) at baseline, Subjects with same number of affected toenails on both feet or no more than one additional affected toenail on one of the feet, Subject with a surgical, medical condition or clinically important abnormal physical findings, which, in the judgement of the investigator, might interfere with interpretation of the objectives of the study (i.e. lack of autonomy), Subjects with posttraumatic nail, lichen planus, eczema, psoriasis, or other abnormalities of the nail unit, which could affect/influence the subject's compliance of the investigational products, or mask the effects of treatment (cure), Subjects with known immunodeficiency, radiation therapy, immune suppressive drugs.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Onychomycosis</keyword>
</DOC>