<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01115075</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to understand the mechanisms for oscillations of dietary fat/carbohydrate intake and how fat intake affect insulin resistance and liver fat over interval of 3 to 4 days.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Oscillations of Dietary Fat/Carbohydrate Intake Over Interval of 3 to 4 Days</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>You will be expected to keep diet records for 17 consecutive days. You will start with a fasting screening visit (only water allowed). A physical exam and Medical history it taken at screening visit. Your body composition will be gathered by CT and Dexa Scan. Blood and urine will be collected for a chemical profile and other determinations. Questionnaires will be administered along with an accelerometer to be worn for the remainder of the study. The final day you will return the dietary records, accelerometer, and a few procedures will be performed as weight.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>You are a dietitian or a senior level or graduate level dietetics student You are between the ages of 2155 years inclusive and a nonsmoker you are not a restrictive diet or strenuous exercise regimen You typically eat several meals per day You have an eating disorder or history You abuse alcohol or other substances, and consume no more than 3 alcoholic drinks per day You have no current regular use of some overthecounter medication or prescription medication, excluding headache medicines, blood pressure medications, etc. You have gained/lost more than 10 pounds of body weight in the last year You have recently had or anticipating significant life changes during the course of your participation in the study. You have an eating disorder or history You have a major psychiatric illness or history You have no serious current clinical disease or surgical condition that may interfere with the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Leptin</keyword>
	<keyword>Changes in leptin may precede the</keyword>
	<keyword>phasing of oscillations of dietary fat intake</keyword>
</DOC>