<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02264990</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a 2-arm, Phase 3 study to evaluate the safety and efficacy of veliparib plus carboplatin and paclitaxel versus the Investigator's choice of standard chemotherapy in current or former smokers who are receiving their first cytotoxic therapy for metastatic or advanced non-squamous non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Comparing Veliparib Plus Carboplatin and Paclitaxel Versus Investigator's Choice of Standard Chemotherapy in Subjects Receiving First Cytotoxic Chemotherapy for Metastatic or Advanced Non-Squamous Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Who Are Current or Former Smokers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Veliparib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject must be ≥ 18 years of age. Life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks. Subject must have cytologically or histologically confirmed advanced or metastatic nonsquamous NSCLC and are current or former smokers. Subject must have NSCLC that is not amenable to surgical resection or radiation with curative intent at time of screening. Subject must have at least 1 unidimensional measurable NSCLC lesion on a CT scan as defined by RECIST (version 1.1). Subject has a known hypersensitivity to paclitaxel or to other drugs formulated with polyethoxylated castor oil (Cremophor). Subject has a known hypersensitivity to platinum compounds. Subject has peripheral neuropathy ≥ grade 2. Subject has squamous NSCLC, or an untreated known EGFR mutation of exon 19 deletion or L858R mutation in exon 21, or a known ALK gene rearrangement. Subject has received prior cytotoxic chemotherapy or chemoradiotherapy for NSCLC.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>cisplatin</keyword>
	<keyword>paclitaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>Poly Adenosine diphosphate (ADP)-ribose Polymerase (PARP)</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-squamous</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>pemetrexed</keyword>
	<keyword>carboplatin</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic</keyword>
	<keyword>veliparib</keyword>
</DOC>