<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02264210</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II trial studies how well icotinib works in treating patients with completely resected stage IB NSCLC harboring EGFR mutation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Icotinib for Completed Resected IB NSCLC With EGFR Mutation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Adjuvant chemotherapy have shown little evidence of survival benefit in patients with stages IB non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) after complete resection. Epidermal growth factor receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitors (EGFR-TKIs) show great efficacy in patients with EGFR mutant non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). Icotinib is a novel EGFR-TKI developed by a group of Chinese scientists and clinician. In the phase III ICOGEN trial, icotinib had non-inferiority efficacy to gefitinib with better safety. This study is studying icotinib to see how well it works in treating patients with fully resected stage IB NSCLC harboring EGFR mutation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bronchial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent provided. Males or females, Aged 1875 years. Able to comply with the required protocol and followup procedures, and able to receive oral medications. Had completely resected pathological confirmed stage IIAIIIA NSCLC. EGFR activating mutation in exon 19 or 21. Patient who can start the investigational therapy within 36 weeks after the complete resection. ECOG performance status of 01. Had a life expectancy of 12 weeks or more. Adequate hematological function, adequate liver function and renal function. Female patients, except those who are postmenopausal or surgically sterilized, must have a negative prestudy serum or urine pregnancy test. Had had previous chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or agents directed at the HER axis (e.g. erlotinib, gefitinib, cetuximab, trastuzumab). Inability to comply with protocol or study procedures. Had a history another malignancy in the last 5 years with the exception of cured basal cell carcinoma of the skin, cured in situ carcinoma of the uterine cervix and cured epithelial carcinoma of the bladder. Any evidence confirmed tumor recurrence before investigational therapy. Known severe hypersensitivity to icotinib or any of the excipients of this product. Evidence of clinically active interstitial lung disease. Eye inflammation not fully controlled or conditions predisposing the subject to this. Any unstable systemic disease (including active infection, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable angina, congestive heart failure, myocardial infarction within the previous 6 months, serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring medication, hepatic, renal, or metabolic disease). Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. Pregnancy or breastfeeding women. Ingredients mixed with small cell lung cancer patients. History of neurologic or psychiatric disorders.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>