<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00638378</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a clinical trial of orally administered Ruxolitinib (INCB018424) in patients whose disease has progressed following 1 prior chemotherapy regimen (not including anti-androgens or ketoconazole) for metastatic, androgen-independent prostate cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Ruxolitinib (INCB018424) Administered Orally to Patients With Androgen Independent Metastatic Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosed with radiographicallydocumented metastatic prostate cancer that has progressed while receiving androgensuppressive therapy in the form of a bilateral orchiectomy or GonadotropinReleasing Hormone (GnRH) agonist (eg, leuprolide, goserelin). Patients must demonstrate evidence of progressive disease based on 1 of the following criteria: 1) Progressive measurable disease, or 2) Progressive rise in prostatespecific antigen (PSA) level (2 consecutive rises from a prior reference level), or 3) Development of new lesions on bone scan. If receiving a GnRH agonist as primary hormonal therapy, the serum testosterone level must be ≤ 50 ng/mL. Must have received and progressed during or following 1 prior chemotherapy regimen for metastatic disease (not including an antiandrogen or ketoconazole); or, must have discontinued prior systemic therapy because of poor tolerance or other adverse effects; or, must have refused chemotherapy treatment. Patients having undergone more than 1 prior chemotherapy regimen may be admitted at the discretion of the sponsor. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 to 2. Baseline serum PSA level of ≥ 10 ng/mL Received any anticancer medications in the 30 days before receiving their first dose of study medication except for GnRH agonists and bisphosphonates. Any unresolved toxicity greater than or equal to Grade 2 from previous anticancer therapy, except for stable chronic toxicities not expected to resolve, such as peripheral neurotoxicity.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prostate Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>