<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02795819</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase 1 study will identify recommended phase 2 doses (RP2Ds) of AR-42 and pazopanib when given in combination for subsequent clinical trials and may potentially identify candidate pharmacodynamic and predictive biomarkers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Pan-DAC Inhibitor AR-42 and Pazopanib in Advanced Sarcoma and Kidney Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a single-arm, open-label, phase 1 trial to determine the RP2Ds of AR-42 and pazopanib when given in combination to patients with advanced Renal Cell Carcinoma (RCC) or Soft Tissue Sarcoma (STS). Eligible patients will have recurrent, unresectable, or metastatic RCC or STS for which pazopanib is an appropriate therapy. AR-42 will be taken orally once per day on 3 non-consecutive days each week during the first 3 weeks of each 4-week cycle. Pazopanib will be taken by mouth once daily continuously during each cycle. A modified 3+3 dose-escalation design will be followed until the maximum tolerated doses (MTDs) have been determined. Additional patients will be enrolled until a total of 12 patients have been treated at the MTDs. The maximum number of patients needed is 51 with an expected sample size of 29-35 patients enrolled over a period of about 15-35 months. Correlative studies will be conducted using samples of tumor that were archived following the most recent surgery or biopsy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Recurrent, unresectable, or metastatic Renal Cell Carcinoma (RCC) or Soft Tissue Sarcoma (STS) (any histologic type) for which pazopanib is an appropriate therapy Measurable or evaluable disease by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors Version 1.1 (RECIST v1.1) Age ≥ 18 years Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1 Adequate bone marrow function as defined below: Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1200/mm3 Platelets ≥ 120,000/mm3 Hemoglobin ≥ 9.5 g/dL Adequate renal function as defined below: Creatinine ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) for the laboratory or calculated or actual creatinine clearance ≥ 60 mL/min Proteinuria ≤ 2+ [100 mg/dL] (using a random urine sample or &lt; 3.0 gm using a 24hour sample) (Note: If urine sample indicates ≥ 2+ [100 mg/dL]), a 24hour urine sample must be collected and tested; urine protein in the 24hour sample must be &lt; 3.0 gm/24 hours.) Adequate hepatic function as defined below: Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN for the laboratory (Note: Patients with known Gilbert's Syndrome are not eligible for this study) Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 2.5 x ULN for the laboratory Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤ 2.5 x ULN for the laboratory Nonhematologic toxicities from previous cancer therapies resolved to ≤ grade 1 International normalized ratio (INR) ≤ 1.5 Activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) ≤ 1.5 x ULN for the laboratory Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) assessment (eg, echocardiogram, MUGA scan, firstpass technique) performed within 3 months prior to initiation of study treatment indicates an LVEF of ≥ 50% A woman of childbearing potential (WCBP), defined as a woman who is &lt; 60 years of age and has not had a hysterectomy, must have a documented negative serum pregnancy test within 7 days prior to initiating study treatment A WCBP and a male patient with a partner who is a WCBP must agree to use a medically accepted method for preventing pregnancy for the duration of study treatment and for 2 months following completion of study treatment Ability to understand and willingness to sign the consent form Symptomatic or untreated brain metastasis Leptomeningeal metastasis Any investigational agent within 4 weeks prior to initiating study treatment Previous therapy with pazopanib Inability to swallow medication Known or suspected malabsorption condition or obstruction Contraindication to antiangiogenic agents, including: Serious nonhealing wound, nonhealing ulcer, or bone fracture Major surgical procedure or significant traumatic injury within 4 weeks prior to initiating study treatment; other surgical procedures within 2 weeks prior to initiating study treatment Pulmonary hemorrhage/bleeding event ≥ grade 2 within 12 weeks prior to initiating study treatment Any other hemorrhage/bleeding event ≥ grade 3 within 12 weeks prior to initiating study treatment History of organ allograft including corneal transplant Evidence of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy Documented Gilbert's Syndrome Resting systolic blood pressure (BP) &lt; 100 mmHg Hypertension defined as systolic BP ≥ 140 mmHg or diastolic BP ≥ 90 mmHg despite optimal medical management QTc interval &gt; 450 ms on screening 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG) If baseline QTc on screening ECG meets exclusion criteria: Check calcium, potassium, and magnesium serum levels. Correct any identified hypocalcemia, hypokalemia, and/or hypomagnesemia and repeat ECG to confirm exclusion of patient due to prolonged QTc interval. For patients with heart rate (HR) 60100 bpm, manual read of QTc is not required. For patients with a baseline HR &lt; 60 bpm or &gt; 100 bpm, manual read of the QT interval by a cardiologist is required, with Fridericia correction applied to determine QTc (ie, QTcF). Active or clinically significant cardiac disease including any of the following: Unstable angina (eg, anginal symptoms at rest) or onset of angina within 3 months prior to initiating study treatment Myocardial infarction within 6 months prior to initiating study treatment Cardiac arrhythmias currently requiring antiarrhythmic therapy other than beta blockers Any documented history of clinically significant thrombotic, embolic, venous, or arterial events, such as cerebrovascular accident, transient ischemic attack, deep vein thrombosis, or pulmonary embolism necessitating therapeutic anticoagulation within 6 months prior to initiating study treatment (Note: Patients with a tumorassociated thrombus of locallyinvolved vessels should not be excluded from participating in the study.) Active infection requiring treatment or chronic infection requiring suppressive therapy Chronic or active hepatitis B or C infection requiring treatment with antiviral therapy Pleural effusion or ascites that causes respiratory compromise (eg, ≥ grade 2 dyspnea) Required ongoing treatment with other drugs thought to potentially have adverse interactions with either of the medications included in the study treatment; if such medications have been used, patients must have discontinued these agents at least 1 week prior to initiating study treatment. Examples include: Strong CYP3A4 inhibitors and/or strong CYP3A4 inducers; the reference list of CYP isozymes and classification of strong, moderate, and weak interactions are available through the Food and Drug Administration (FDA website. Strong inhibitors of Pglycoprotein (Pgp) and/or breast cancer resistance protein (BCRP); the reference list of strong inhibitors of Pgp and BCRP. Simvastatin and other HMGCoA reductase inhibitors (ie, statins) Drugs that raise gastric pH including proton pump inhibitors and H2blockers (Note: Shortacting antacids, in place of PPIs and H2blockers, are permitted.) HDAC inhibitors Pregnancy or breastfeeding Medical, psychological, or social condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, may increase the patient's risk or limit the patient's adherence with study requirement</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>