<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02795767</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This single-arm study will enroll children (less than [&lt;] 12 years of age) and adolescents (12 to 17 years of age) with hemophilia A and FVIII inhibitors who are currently receiving treatment with bypassing agents. Participants will receive weekly subcutaneous (SC) doses of emicizumab for a designated period of 52 weeks. All participants will continue to receive standard of care/background treatment with their usual episodic bypassing agent therapy to treat breakthrough bleeds as needed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Once-Weekly Emicizumab in Children and Adolescents With Hemophilia A and Factor VIII (FVIII) Inhibitors (HAVEN 2)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Factor VIII</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children &lt;12 years of age, with allowance for participants 12 to 17 years of age who weigh &lt;40 kilograms (kg) and participants &lt;2 years of age after protocoldefined interim data review criteria are met Diagnosis of hemophilia A of any severity and hightiter FVIII inhibitor (that is, greater than or equal to [&gt;/=] 5 Bethesda units [BU]) Requirement for treatment with bypassing agents Adequate hematologic, hepatic, and renal function Inherited or acquired bleeding disorder other than hemophilia A Ongoing (or planning to receive during the study) immune tolerance induction (ITI) therapy or prophylaxis treatment with FVIII Previous (in the past 12 months) or current treatment for thromboembolic disease or signs of thromboembolic disease Other disease that may increase risk of bleeding or thrombosis Hypersensitivity to monoclonal antibodies or components of the emicizumab injection Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or hepatitis B or C Use of systemic immunomodulators Planned surgery during study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>