<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02795377</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Membrane microparticles are submicron fragments of membrane vesicles shed from various cell types. Circulating endothelial microparticles have been proposed as markers of endothelial injury. However, which mechanical forces contribute to their release is not clear.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hypertension and Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In a first series subjects (50% hypertensives) with and without arterial hypertension and no Coronary Artery Disease (CAD) (n=50) will be recruited. MP subpopulations will be discriminated by flow cytometry according to the expression of established surface antigens including CD31+/41-, CD144+, and CD62e+. Besides office and ambulatory 24h blood pressure measurements, pulse wave analysis will be performed to determine central blood pressure, augmentation index (AIX), and pulse wave velocity. Endothelial function (Flow-mediated dilation, FMD), arterial pulsatile stretch (fractional diameter changes, FDC), and wall-shear-stress (WSS) will be measured in the same segment of the brachial artery (BA) by ultrasound. In a second series, the investigators will take measurements in subjects with hypertensive crises (SBP&gt;180 mmHg) (n=20) before and after 4h and normalization of arterial BP by urapidil. In a third series, the investigators will take measurement in subjects with stable CAD (n=10) before and after transfemoral coronary diagnostic angiography.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<criteria>male subjects with or without arterial hypertension, hypertensive crises, stable CAD written informed consent subjects with manifest peripheral artery, or cerebrovascular disease, acute inflammation (CRP&gt;0.6 mg/dl), malignancies, arrhythmias</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>arterial hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>microparticle</keyword>
	<keyword>endothelial function</keyword>
</DOC>