<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02896231</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase I, first-in-human dose-escalation study was conducted to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD), recommended phase II dose (RP2D), dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs), pharmacokinetics (PK) profile, and preliminary antitumor activity of PLB1001.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>First-in-human Phase I Study of a Selective c-Met Inhibitor PLB1001</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase I, open-label, multicentre study of PB1001 administered orally to patients with Met-positive (Met+) advanced NSCLC. The study includes a Dose-escalation Part (part A)and a Dose Expansion Part(part B). The aim of the part A is to estimate the MTD and to identify the dose limited toxicity(DLT) and the recommended phase II dose (RP2D) for PLB1001 single agent as well as to determine the PK/PD profile .Once response has been observed in certain dose level ,then followed by the expansion part to further assess the clinical efficacy and safety of PLB1001 single agent. Aprox. 40 patients will be enrolled in PART A, while 20-30 patients for expansion cohort . PLB1001 is a potent selective c-Met inhibitor. PLB1001 acts on cancer by blocking abnormal cmet-mediated signalling, leading to profound tumour growth inhibition in xenografts of non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) tumours. Preliminary data from a c-Met inhibitor INC 280 has provided possibility on the safety and clinical activity of PLB1001 monotherapy in this patient population.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed Informed Consent Form Age≥18 years Histologically or cytologically confirmed advanced nonsmall cell lung cancer Must have evidence of cMet positivity from the results of molecular prescreening evaluations At least one measurable lesion as per RECIST v1.1 Patients must have recovered from all toxicities related to prior anticancer therapies to grade ≤ 1 ECOG Performance Status of 02 Previous or current treatment with a cMet inhibitor or HGFtargeting therapy Symptomatic central nervous system (CNS) metastases that are neurologically unstable or requiring increasing doses of steroids to control, and patients with any CNS deficits. Clinically significant, uncontrolled heart diseases. Unstable angina History of documented congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association functional classification &gt; II) Uncontrolled hypertension defined by a Systolic Blood Pressure (SBP) ≥ 145 mm Hg and/or Diastolic Blood Pressure (DBP) ≥ 85 mm Hg Arrhythmias Active peptic ulcer disease or gastritis Adverse events from prior anticancer therapy that have not resolved to Grade ≤ 1, except for alopecia Major surgery within 4 weeks prior to starting PLB1001 Previous anticancer and investigational agents within 4 weeks before first dose of PLB1001. If previous treatment is a monoclonal antibody, then the treatment must be discontinued at least 6 weeks before first dose of PLB1001. Pregnant or nursing women Involved in other clinical trials &lt; 30 days prior to Day 1</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>