<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00606112</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and tolerance of a single intravenous (through a vein) dose of trodusquemine (MSI-1436) in obese, type 2 diabetics. Different amounts of trodusquemine (MSI-1436) will be given to each volunteer group throughout the study. Another purpose is to evaluate the pharmacokinetics (PK - the study of the way the drug enters and leaves the blood and tissues over time) of trodusquemine (MSI-1436). Finally, this study will also determine whether trodusquemine (MSI-1436) has any effect on appetite, mood or behavior, and selective biomarkers (substances in your blood that may change in response to the study drug).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Single Dose, Tolerance and Pharmacokinetic Study in Obese or Overweight Type 2 Diabetic Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. male or female obese or overweight type 2 diabetic subjects, between 18 and 55 years old (inclusive) 2. either treatment naive or who are inadequately controlled on either metformin alone or metformin in combination with a sulfonylurea. Subjects on metformin in combination with a sulfonylurea will be allowed a 2 week period to wash out the sulfonylurea before dosing. 3. have a fasting blood sugar of ≥ 100 mg/dL, hemoglobin A1C ≥ 7.5% (but ≤ 11.0%). Subjects on a combination of metformin and sulfonylurea must have a hemoglobin A1C ≥ 7.5% (but ≤ 10.0%); 4. nonsmoker 5. body mass index (BMI) of 2740 kg/m2 1. likely allergy or sensitivity to any components of Trodusquemine (MSI1436) for Injection based on known allergies to drugs of the same class; 2. any subject with a history of allergy (rash, hives, breathing difficulty, etc.) to any medications, either prescription or nonprescription, including dietary supplements or herbal medications; 3. any subject with a history of severe allergy or bronchial asthma; 4. a clinically significant history of or current abnormality or disease of any organ system, including renal, hepatic, gastrointestinal, cardiovascular (except hyperlipidemia or controlled hypertension), pulmonary (including chronic asthma), endocrine (except diabetes), central nervous, or hematologic systems, or recent clinically significant surgery;</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2009</verification_date>
</DOC>