<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01639378</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The REACH study, is a prospective, double-blinded, randomised, controlled study of the safety and effectiveness of renal denervation in subjects with chronic systolic heart failure. Bilateral denervation will be performed using the Symplicity Catheter - a percutaneous system that delivers radio frequency (RF) energy through the luminal surface of the renal artery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Renal Artery Denervation in Chronic Heart Failure Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Interventional study Allocation: Randomised Endpoint Classification: Safety / Efficacy Study Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment Masking: Double blind (Subject / CHF team). The interventional operator, will have no role in care of the patient following randomisation. Primary Purpose: Treatment Chronic Systolic Heart Failure Device: Renal denervation (Symplicity Catheter System) Symplicity Catheter System -Intervention: Device: Renal denervation (Symplicity Catheter System) Patients are randomised in the cath lab to receive either renal denervation or sham procedure. Experimental arm: Renal Denervation Control arm: No renal denervation (sham procedure) In both arms, aftercare is provided by clinicians who are blinded to the randomised allocation arm. Subjects will have been recruited on stable heart failure therapy, and the intention is to maintain this therapy steady during followup.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure, Systolic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronic heart failure due to systolic dysfunction New York Heart Association class II or higher Maximal pharmacological therapy including (where clinically indicated and tolerated), bblocker, ACE inhibitors /A2 blocker, Aldosterone blockade. Ejection fraction less than 40% Estimated GFR&lt;35ml/hr Unfavourable renal anatomy (renal artery stenosis) Unable to walk on a treadmill for cardiopulmonary exercise test Significant valvular disease (moderate or more aortic regurgitation/stenosis or mitral stenosis; severe mitral/tricuspid regurgitation) Severe lung disease Symptomatic orthostatic dizziness Unable to consent Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>