<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01639885</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study investigates the feasibility and immunogenicity of the triple combination of gemcitabine, Peg-Intron and p53 SLP vaccination in patients with platinum-resistant ovarian cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chemo-immunotherapy (Gemcitabine, Interferon-alpha 2b and p53 SLP) in Patients With Platinum-resistant Ovarian Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Recurrent ovarian cancer has a dismal prognosis and there is a pressing need to identify more efficient therapies. Ovarian cancer is highly immunogenic and good survival is tightly linked to the presence of tumor-infiltrating T cells and the absence of immunosuppressive immune cells. This anti-tumor immune response might be primed by chemotherapy. Gemcitabine has immune-modulatory properties in addition to its direct cytotoxic effect in platinum resistant ovarian cancer. Additionally, Peg-Intron allows the full maturation of dendritic cells, thereby enhancing the anti-tumor response. Moreover, the tumor-associated self-antigen p53 is commonly over-expressed in ovarian cancer and can serve as a target for immunotherapy. Therefore, chemo-immunotherapy with gemcitabine and Peg-Intron plus/minus p53 SLP vaccination seems an attractive treatment for recurrent, p53+ ovarian cancer patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histological proven epithelial ovarian cancer, peritoneal cavity or fallopian tube cancer (inclusive mucinous or clear cell tumors) Tumor overexpressing p53 Progression of disease or relapse after previous therapy with platinum Measurable disease (RECIST 1.1) or elevated CA125 &gt; 2 times the upper limit of normal within 3 months and confirmed Age ≥ 18 years WHO performance status 02 Adequate bone marrow function: WBC ≥ 3.0 x 109/l, neutrophils ≥ 1.5 x 109/l, platelets ≥ 100 x 109/l Adequate liver function: bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (UNL) range, ALAT and/or ASAT ≤ 2.5 x UNL, Alkaline Phosphatase ≤5 x UNL Adequate renal function: the calculated creatinine clearance should be ≥ 50 mL/min Survival expectation &gt; 3 months Patients must be accessible for treatment and followup Written informed consent according to the local Ethics Committee requirements Previous malignancy within 5 years, with exception of a history of a previous basal cell carcinoma of the skin or preinvasive carcinoma of the cervix. Serious other diseases as recent myocardial infarction, clinical signs of cardiac failure or clinically significant arrhythmias Known hypersensitivity reaction to any of the components of the treatment Pregnancy or lactating Medical or psychological condition which in the opinion of the investigator would not permit the patient to complete the study or sign meaningful informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>p53 overexpression</keyword>
	<keyword>platinum-resistant</keyword>
</DOC>