<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00466674</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Donor mobilization : Donor will be mobilized with G-CSF (Granocyte) sub-cutaneous 10 µg/kg/day during 5 to 6 days. Hematopoïetic Stem Cell Harvest: By 1, 2, or 3 aphaeresis, a number of 4 x 106 cellules CD34+ /kg is required. If the CD34+ &gt;= 2 and &lt;= 4x106/kg: the center must decide on the strategy Decision. In case of insufficient graft : a Bone Marrow Harvest is recommended Conditioning : Fludarabine - Busulfan - ATG - D-5 : Fludarabine (30 mg/m²) - D-4 : Fludarabine (30 mg/m²)+ Busilvex (0,8 mg/kg every 6 h) - D-3 : Fludarabine (30 mg/m²)+ Busilvex (0,8 mg/kg every 6 h) - D-2 : Fludarabine (30 mg/m²) + ATG (Genzyme) (2.5 mg/Kg) - D-1 : Fludarabine (30 mg/m²) + ATG (Genzyme) (2.5 mg/Kg) GVHD Prophylaxis: CsA alone at 3 mg/ kg + Methotrexate D1, D3 and D6 only in case of minor ABO incompatibility and with an anti A/B antibodies titer&gt; 1/32. Transplant : HSC at D0 • 3 months after Transplantation : Disease Evaluation : - If CR : Supervision. Then if progression: 4 cycles of Bortezomib. - If no CR : Bortezomib (4 cycles) • Evaluation after Bortezomib cycles - If CR : Supervision. Then, if progression and no GvHD : DLI If no RC and no GVHD : DLI</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Myeloma in Patients &lt;= 65 Years Old With Response &gt;= 50% After HSC Autotransplant by Allogenic Transplant Genoidentical or Phenoidentical After Reduced Intensity Conditioning</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Major patients not under guardianship Myeloma with high b2 microglobulin level (&gt; 3 mg/l) and/or chromosome 13 deletion, and/or translocation t(4;14) stage I DS with high evolutive potential or stage II, III DS. AND With response &gt;= 50% and &lt;= 90% after the first AutoHSCT (IFM 2005 01). The evaluation must be performed within 2 months after the first AutoHSCT. with an HLA identical related or unrelated donor ( match 10/10). Donor and recipient must have signed a written informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>RICT</keyword>
	<keyword>conditioning</keyword>
	<keyword>allograft</keyword>
</DOC>