<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01206764</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Renal cell carcinoma (RCC) accounts for more than 200,000 new cases of cancer and over 100,000 cancer deaths annually in the World (Ferlay, et al., 2004). It is estimated that there were about 15,000 new cases of RCC in the region that excludes the Americas, European Union and Japan. Renal cell carcinomas arise from the proximal tubal epithelium are more common in males than in females with an overall lifetime risk of 1 in 75 and a median age of diagnosis of 65 years. Everolimus (Certican®) has been approved since 2003 in more than 60 countries for the prevention of organ rejection in patients with renal and cardiac transplantation. Everolimus (RAD001) is a derivative of rapamycin, which acts as a signal transduction inhibitor. It targets mTOR, a key protein kinase regulating cell growth, proliferation, and survival. The mTOR pathway activity is modulated by the phosphatidylinositol-3-kinase (PI3K)/protein kinase B AKT (AKT) pathway, a pathway known to be deregulated in numerous human cancers. RAD001 (Afinitor®) has been investigated as an anticancer agent based on its potential to act: - directly on the tumor cells by inhibiting tumor cell growth and proliferation; - indirectly by inhibiting angiogenesis leading to reduced tumor vascularity (via potent inhibition of tumor cell hypoxia-inducible factor 1 (HIF-1) activity, VEGF production, and VEGF-induced proliferation of endothelial cells). Primary: To evaluate the PFS rate over time. Secondary: - To evaluate the disease control rate (stable disease [SD] + partial response [PR] + complete response [CR]); - To evaluate the objective response rate (ORR; where ORR = CR + PR) and duration; - To describe the safety profile of RAD001.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Trial of Everolimis in Patients With Advanced Renal Cell Carcinoma.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients may be entered in the study only if they meet all of the following criteria: Age ≥18 years old; Patients with advanced renal cell carcinoma with confirmed clear or nonclear cell histology, with or without nephrectomy, and with any MSKCC prognosis; Prior cytokine therapy is permitted; Patients with at least one measurable lesion at baseline as per the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) criteria. If skin lesions are reported as target lesions, they must be documented (at baseline and at every physical exam) using color photography and a measuring device (such as a caliper) in clear focus to allow the size of the lesion(s) to be determined from the photograph; Life expectancy ≥3 months. Life expectancy should be judged in relation to other determining patient eligibility factors such as laboratory results, Karnofsky Performance Status, etc.; Patients with a Karnofsky Performance Status ≥70%; Adequate bone marrow function as shown by: absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1.5 x 109/L, platelets ≥100 x 109/L, hemoglobin (Hb) &gt;9 g/dL; Adequate liver function: serum bilirubin ≤1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN), alanine transaminase (ALT), and aspartate transaminase (AST) ≤2.5 x ULN; Adequate renal function: serum creatinine ≤1.5 x ULN; Females of childbearing potential must have had a negative serum or urine pregnancy test 7 days prior to the administration of the study treatment start; Patients who give a written informed consent obtained according to local guidelines. Patients may not be entered into the study if they meet any of the following criteria: Patients within 2 weeks postminor surgery (e.g., herniorrhaphy), 4 weeks postmajor surgery (e.g., intrathoracic, intraabdominal, or intrapelvic) to avoid wound healing complications. Percutaneous biopsies require no waiting time prior to study entry; Patients with a recent history of hemoptysis, ≥0.5 teaspoon of red blood; Patients who have received prior systemic treatment for their metastatic RCC other than with cytokine therapy; Patients who received prior therapy with a VEGF pathway inhibitor, such as sunitinib, sorafenib, and bevacizumab; Patients who have previously received mTOR inhibitors (sirolimus, temsirolimus, everolimus, deferolimus); History or clinical evidence of central nervous system (CNS) metastases. Note: Subjects who have previouslytreated CNS metastases (surgery ± radiotherapy, radiosurgery, or gamma knife) and meet all 3 of the following criteria are eligible: Are asymptomatic; Have had no evidence of active CNS metastases for ≥6 months prior to enrollment and; Have no requirement for steroids or enzymeinducing anticonvulsants (EIAC); • Clinically significant gastrointestinal abnormalities including, but not limited to: Malabsorption syndrome; Major resection of the stomach or small bowel that could affect the absorption of study drug; Active peptic ulcer disease; Inflammatory bowel disease; Ulcerative colitis, or other gastrointestinal conditions with increased risk of perforation; History of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation, or intra abdominal abscess within 28 days prior to beginning of study treatment; Patients receiving chronic systemic treatment with corticosteroids (dose of ≥10 mg/day methylprednisone equivalent) or another immunesuppressive agent. Inhaled and topical steroids are acceptable, as well as opotherapy after bilateral adrenal gland removal; Patients with a known history of human immunodeficiency virus seropositivity; Patients with autoimmune hepatitis; Patients with an active, bleeding diathesis. Patients may use coumadin or heparin preparations; Patients who have any severe and/or uncontrolled medical conditions or other conditions that could affect their participation in the study; Patients who have a history of another primary malignancy ≤3 years, with the exception of nonmelanoma skin cancer and carcinoma in situ of uterine; Female patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding, or adults of reproductive potential who are not using effective birth control methods. If barrier contraceptives are being used, these must be continued throughout the study by both sexes. Oral contraceptives are not acceptable; Patients who are using other investigational agents or who had received investigational drugs ≤4 weeks prior to study treatment start; Patients unwilling or unable to comply with the protocol. Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>RCC,</keyword>
	<keyword>mTOR pathway,</keyword>
	<keyword>angiogenesis,</keyword>
	<keyword>PFS,</keyword>
	<keyword>partial response [PR] + complete response [CR])</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic recurrent renal cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic unresectable renal cell carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>