<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01550211</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims to identify electrophysiological correlates of impaired perceptual and linguistic processes in chronic schizophrenic patients, un-medicated first-episode schizophrenic patients and their healthy relatives. Following administrating some questionnaires (demographic details and psychiatric history questionnaire, handedness questionnaire, reading abilities test and positive and negative symptoms questionnaire) and performing a perception test and a verbal abstract intelligence test, participants will conduct a brain scan during a series of perceptual and linguistic tasks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Changes in Brain Synchronization During Perceptual and Linguistic Tasks in Schizophrenic Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for chronic patients: Hebrew native speakers. Diagnosis of schizophrenia with a history of more than one episode. Capable and willing to provide informed consent. Inclusion criteria for naive patients: Hebrew native speakers. Diagnosis of schizophrenia with a history of only one episode and unmedicated. Capable and willing to provide informed consent. Inclusion criteria for patients' relatives (control group 1): Hebrew native speakers. Without any psychiatric history. Have a child and/or a sibling with schizophrenia. Inclusion Criteria for students (control group 2): Hebrew native speakers. Without any psychiatric history. Exclusion Criteria for patient groups (chronic and "naïve"): Left handedness. Reading disability. Visual perception disability. Brain damage and/or a history of seizures. Impaired intelligence. Metal implants. Exclusion Criteria for control groups (family members and students): Psychiatric history. Left handedness. Reading disability. Visual perception disability. Brain damage and/or a history of seizures. Impaired intelligence. Metal implants.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>