<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01484028</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will serve to evaluate and compare the performance of two new lenses to a marketed lens.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Performance of Two Contact Lenses Compared to a Marketed Lens</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Refractive Errors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy, female adult, at least 18 years of age, and no more than 34 years of age The subjects must be female, light eye Caucasian, NonHispanic, habitual soft contact lens wearer (both eyes) with light or dark eyes Must have rated the Concept Statement positively (i.e., a rating of 4 or 5). Optimal vertexed spherical equivalent distance correction must be between 1.00 and 4.00 diopters (D) Any cylinder power must be: &lt;=0.75D Visual acuity must be best correctable to 20/25 or better for each eye Must have normal eyes (no ocular medications or ocular infection of any type) Must read and sign the Statement of Informed Consent Must appear able and willing to adhere to the instructions set forth in this clinical protocol. Ocular or systemic allergies or disease which might interfere with contact lens wear Systemic disease, autoimmune disease, or use of medication which might interfere with contact lens wear Clinically significant (grade 3 or worse) corneal edema, corneal neovascularization, corneal staining, or any other abnormalities of the cornea which would contraindicate contact lens wear Clinically significant (grade 3 or 4) tarsal abnormalities or bulbar injection which might interfere with contact lens wear Any ocular infection Any corneal distortion resulting from previous hard or rigid gas permeable contact lens wear Any color deficiencies (colorblindness) to the best of the subject's knowledge Pregnancy or lactation Diabetes Infectious diseases (e.g. hepatitis, tuberculosis) or an immunosuppressive disease (e.g. HIV) Habitual contact lens type is toric, multifocal, or is worn as extended wear. Subject presents with one dark iris color and one light iris color. Subject has heterochromia iridis (a difference in color between parts of one iris). The subject must not be an employee or family member of the clinical study site.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>34 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>