<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01484717</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cigarette smoking remains the most common source of preventable morbidity and mortality in the United States, with in excess of $167 billion in economic costs per year. Contingency management (CM), in which tangible incentives are provided contingent on a target behavior like abstinence, is highly efficacious in improving substance abuse treatment outcomes and is receiving increased attention for smoking cessation. Expired carbon monoxide (CO) is the most common objective smoking status test used in smoking research and treatment. Unfortunately, multiple CO tests/day are typically required to detect all smoking and reinforce sustained abstinence. The resulting logistical and resource limitations greatly limit the application of this potentially powerful quit smoking toolset. This study addresses these limitations by examining the effectiveness of using interactive voice response technology (IVR) to implement CM. Smokers who want to quit (N = 90 randomized) will receive 2 quit preparation sessions based on public health guidelines for smoking cessation and set a target quit date. Participants will be randomly assigned to 1 of 2 treatment conditions: (a) IVR-S consisting of objective smoking status monitoring using IVR, telephone counseling and transdermal nicotine and (b) IVR-CM, consisting of the same monitoring, telephone counseling and transdermal nicotine plus IVR-based CM for smoking abstinence. It is hypothesized that abstinence rates will be higher in the IVR-CM condition compared to the IVR-S, supporting a combined IVR CM approach, and thereby greatly increasing the applicability of these powerful smoking cessation tools.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Interactive Voice Response Technology to Mobilize Contingency Management for Smoking Cessation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Nicotine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>regular cigarette smoker age ≥ 18 mailing address &amp; valid photo I.D. want transdermal nicotine not English speaking in recovery for pathological gambling contraindication for transdermal nicotine female who is pregnant, nursing a child, or not using effective contraception</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>