<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02103764</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objectives of the present study is to determine the effectiveness of cyclic desogestrel (DSG) compared with cyclic medroxyprogesterone acetate for the treatment of anovulatory dysfunctional uterine bleeding (DUB) in the following aspects: 1. Endometrial histopathology changes 2. Menstrual cycle control.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Cyclic DSG Compared With Cyclic MPA for the Treatment of Anovulatory DUB</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Anovulatory dysfunctional uterine bleeding (DUB) is the most common cause of abnormal uterine bleeding especially in postmenarcheal adolescent, perimenopausal women, patient with polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) and in obese women. Aims of treatment in women with anovulatory DUB are to restore the natural control mechanism of endometrium (introduce normal synchronous growth, development, shedding of a structural stable endometrium) and to prevent endometrial hyperplasia. The two main treatment options are estrogen-progestin therapy and progestin therapy. Women who are sexually active and not immediately prepared to pursue pregnancy are best manage by estrogen-progestin treatment especially combined oral contraceptive pills (COCs) but in perimenopausal women, obese women or women who can't tolerate COCs or have contraindications in using COCs, cyclic progestin will be the treatment of choice. Common used progestin in anovulatory DUB is medroxyprogesterone acetate (MPA) 5-10 mg/day for 10-14 days each month. This progestin has strong progestogenic effect but has some undesirable effect such as glucocorticoid effect, mineralocorticoid effect and androgenic effect. Long term using this progestin especially in obese women or perimenopausal women who have risk for diabetes mellitus and dyslipidemia may be negative effect to glucose and lipid metabolism. DSG is the third generation progestin with no glucocorticoid, mineralocorticoid effect and low androgenic effect may be the better choice of treatment but the data of DSG in treatment of anovulatory DUB us scanty. So this study will evaluate the effect of cyclic DSG in endometrial histology changing and lipid, glucose metabolism in patient with anovulatory DUB. Comparison : Women with anovulatory DUB are randomized into two groups, receiving a course of either cyclic DSG or cyclic MPA. The main outcome measured is to compare the effect of both interventions on endometrial histology changing.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metrorrhagia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Medroxyprogesterone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Desogestrel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Medroxyprogesterone Acetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Premenopausal women with anovular DUB (proved by endometrial histology) Age &gt; 18 yr. Any uterine pathology that might cause abnormal uterine bleeding Contraindication to progestin treatment (such as breast cancer) Severe drug allergy towards a progestogen Intake of any hormonal treatment in the previous 3 months</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anovulatory Dysfunctional Uterine Bleeding</keyword>
	<keyword>cyclic desogestrel</keyword>
	<keyword>cyclic medroxyprogesterone acetate</keyword>
	<keyword>lipid metabolism</keyword>
	<keyword>glucose metabolism</keyword>
	<keyword>endometrial histology changing</keyword>
</DOC>