<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02103036</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is determine whether the Core Stability Exercise is more effective than the traditional Back School for low back pain (LBP) in women.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Valuation of the Low Back Pain Treated With Different Types of Active Exercises in Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of this study is to check what kind of exercises are the best to treat LBP with regard to clinical improvements. The secondary objectives are: to determine which treatment is more effective in improving pain in the fewest sessions possible, to determine the involvement of inflammatory biomarkers in the development of pain and revalue the results after one month of having finishing treatment. The project is a longitudinal, single-blind and randomized study with two treatment groups: GROUP 1: Infrared light+ Transcutaneous Electrical Nerve Stimulation (TENS) + Core Stability Exercises. GROUP 2: Infrared light + Transcutaneous Electrical Nerve Stimulation (TENS) + Traditional Back School. Duration of treatment: 4 weeks. The participants will performe the exercises in 20 daily sessions (Monday to Friday) guided by a physiotherapist. Following treatment with the physiotherapist, the participants should perform the exercises at home for 4 weeks at a rate of three times per week.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women aged 18 to 70 years. Diagnosis of back pain from a trauma. Untreated pain (except acetaminophen). Informed consent. Algic process in the lumbar spine of infectious, neoplastic, metastasis, osteoporosis, inflammatory arthritis or fractures. Cognitive impairment of any etiology. Exercise intolerance for any reason. Patients who have completed physical therapy in the last 3 months. Patients who have received infiltration injections in the last 6 weeks.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Low Back Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Core stability exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Back school</keyword>
	<keyword>TENS</keyword>
	<keyword>Infra- red light</keyword>
</DOC>