<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02062346</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients with vasculitis commonly develop high blood pressure (hypertension) and this is associated with an increased risk of heart disease. It is thus important to lower blood pressure in those with hypertension. However, hypertension in vasculitis is inadequately controlled with many currently available blood pressure lowering agents. Endothelin is a chemical produced by blood vessels that contributes to the development of hypertension. Higher than normal levels of endothelin are seen in patients with vasculitis. By using drugs that block the effects of endothelin ('endothelin receptor antagonists') the investigators can hopefully treat hypertension in patients with vasculitis. The purpose of the study is to ascertain whether endothelin receptor antagonists lower blood pressure and improve blood vessel function more effectively in patients with vasculitis than those without it.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Endothelin Antagonism in ANCA Vasculitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Vasculitis patients - matched for age, BP and renal function - will be recruited into 3 groups defined by their induction immunosuppression: (i) Azathioiprine, (ii) Mycophenolate mofetil, (iii) Rituximab. A 4th group will comprise control healthy subjects (n=10 for each). Subjects will attend for 4 study days &gt;1 week apart. Circulating Mφ and other immune cells will be confirmed using FACS prior to each study. Day 1: assessment of vascular function. Days 2, 3 &amp; 4 (randomised &amp; infusions given in a double-blind method): comparison of the effects of selective ETA receptor antagonism (BQ123; 1000nmol/min for 15min iv), mixed ETA/B antagonism (BQ123/788; 1000 nmol/min &amp; 300 nmol/min for 15 min), and placebo on systemic haemodynamics. Outcome measures - Forearm blood flow - tPA release - Blood pressure - Aix &amp; PWV</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vasculitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>cyclo(Trp-Asp-Pro-Val-Leu)</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female Age 1880 Body mass index ≤35 Normal serum albumin Subject is below the age of legal consent, or is mentally or legally incapacitated History of multiple and/or severe allergic reactions to drugs (including study drugs), or food The subject has donated blood (450 ml) within the last 4 weeks Past or present drug or alcohol abuse including intravenous drug abuse at any time Participation in another clinical trial within 1 month Considered to be at high risk of HIV or hepatitis B Women of childbearing potential (only women who are postmenopausal or surgicallysterilised will be included in the study)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>endothelin;</keyword>
	<keyword>blood pressure;</keyword>
	<keyword>vasculitis</keyword>
</DOC>