<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02062229</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Infertility is a common problem, affecting perhaps one couple in six, the majority of whom now seek medical care. It is becoming a social challenge because it is responsible for personal and interpersonal discomfort and anxiety. A major obstacle to meaningful study of the epidemiology of male infertility is the difficulty in accurate diagnosis of the presence or absence of a problem. Traditionally, the diagnosis of male infertility is facilitated by the conventional assessment of the semen profile - constructed according to recognized guidelines (i.e. WHO) and including pH, cell count and motility - but no specific biomarkers are available. We sought to determine the oxysterol and fatty acid lipidome with the ai of finding a lipid biomarker useful for the diagnosis of male infertility.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Oxidative Stress and Lipidomics in Male Infertility</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Subjects referring to an outpatient infertility laboratory will be enrolled in the study. A complete clinical record is collected as well as a sperm and a fasting blood sample. Patients are stratified according to current guidelines focusing on sperm and anatomical characteristics. Sperm characteristics will be studied on fresh samples immediately after collection; blood samples will be centrifuged and plasma stored at -80°C until analysis that include routine glucose and lipid profile by commercial kits. Vitamin E (alpha- and gamma-tocopherol), oxysterols profiling, and fatty acids profiling is analyzed by state of the art gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC/MS) using isotope dilution methods.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infertility, Male</mesh_term>
	<criteria>clinically healthy subjects and clinical healthy subjects with infertility subjects with endocrine, cardiovascular, metabolic, inflammatory and neurologic diseases or cancer subjects taking medicines and/or supplements</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>oxidative stress</keyword>
	<keyword>oxysterols</keyword>
	<keyword>fatty acids</keyword>
	<keyword>seminal fluid</keyword>
</DOC>