<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02062918</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objectives: To assess the effectiveness of an abdominal belt in the treatment of chronic mechanical-postural low back pain. Methods: A randomized controlled trial was carried out, involving 60 consecutively selected patients with chronic low back pain randomly allocated to an intervention group (use of abdominal belt) and control group (non-use of abdominal belt). Patients were evaluated at the baseline of the study (T0) as well as 1 (T1), 3 (T3) and 6 months (T6) after the inclusion. The patients were assessed for: pain (VAS); functional capacity (Roland Morris), patient satisfaction (Likert scale); and number of anti-inflammatory pills ingested. Intention-to-treat analysis was also used. Hypothesis - abdominal belt will improve pain in chronic low back pain patients</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Abdominal Belt Use to Treat Low Back Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients from both genders, between 18 and 65 years of age, who sought medical care for a complaint of lumbar pain, diagnosed with Chronic low back pain, with VAS for pain between 4 and 8 cm (010), who agreed to participate in the study and signed terms of informed consent. diagnosis or under diagnostic investigation of low back pain from secondary causes (spondyloarthopathy, infection, neoplasm, complete sciatica), fibromyalgia, previous spinal surgery, litigation (patients on leave from work or in work leave processes due to low back pain); having changed physical activity in previous three months; body mass index (BMI) higher than 30; acupuncture treatment or physiotherapy in the previous three months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Abdominal belt</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic low back pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Functional capacity</keyword>
</DOC>