<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02062242</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of transvaginal electrical stimulation, vaginal palpation, and vaginal palpation associated with posterior pelvic tilt and contraction of accessory muscles in the acquisition of ability to contract the pelvic floor muscles (PFM), as well as to evaluate the sexual function of women studied.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Electrical Stimulation and Vaginal Palpation in Pelvic Floor Muscles Awareness</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Many women does not know to contract the PFM voluntarily favoring the development of disorders such as urinary and fecal incontinence, pelvic organ prolapse and sexual disorders. However there are no studies in the literature that address the application of therapeutic resources available to improve the PFM awareness. The objective of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of transvaginal electrical stimulation, vaginal palpation, vaginal palpation associated with posterior pelvic tilt and contraction of accessory muscles in the acquisition of ability to contract the PFM, as well as to evaluate the sexual function of women studied. One hundred twenty women with PFM function graded 0 and 1 measured by Oxford Modified Scale will be submitted at random to physical therapy with transvaginal electrical stimulation, vaginal palpation, vaginal palpation associated with posterior pelvic tilt and contraction of accessory muscles (glutes and hip adductors) and the control group who receive verbal instructions related to the pelvic floor and its contraction. For the evaluation of the sexual function will be applied the Female Sexual Function Index (FSFI). The patients will be assessed by vaginal palpation, perineometry and surface electromyography before and after the intervention.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pelvic Floor Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women with age greater than or equal 18 years; Women with pelvic floor muscle function graded 0 and 1 measured by Oxford Modified Scale; Women who voluntarily consente to participate in research. Women with associated neurological pathologies; Women with symptoms of vaginal or urinary tract infection; Women with pelvic organs prolapse graded greater than 2; Pregnancy suspected or confirmed; Cognitive deficit that impedes or impair the procedure.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pelvic Floor</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical Therapy Specialty</keyword>
	<keyword>Awareness</keyword>
	<keyword>Electric Stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Palpation</keyword>
</DOC>