<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02708030</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomised trial is undertaken to assess whether MAD or LGIT is non-inferior to KD with regard to seizure control at twenty-four weeks among children with drug resistant epilepsy. The hypothesis of the study is that in 1 to 15-year-old children with drug resistant epilepsy, use of Modified Atkins Diet (MAD) or Low Glycemic Index Therapy (LGIT) as an add on to the ongoing anti-epileptic drugs would not be inferior to ketogenic diet by &gt;15% in terms of seizure reduction from baseline seizure frequency at 24 weeks. The primary outcome of the study is to determine the efficacy of MAD as compared to KD and LGIT as compared to KD for seizure reduction in drug resistant epilepsy following 24 weeks of dietary therapy in 1 to 15-year-old children on anti-epileptic drugs. The change in seizure frequency will be estimated as percentage change in seizure reduction at 24 weeks as compared to baseline.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dietary Therapy In Epilepsy Treatment (DIET-Trial): A Randomised Non Inferiority Trial Comparing KD, MAD &amp; LGIT for Drug Resistant Epilepsy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Drug Resistant Epilepsy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Children aged 115 years with drug resistant epilepsy (Drug resistant epilepsy for the study will be defined as seizure frequency &gt;4 seizures per month, and treatment failure of ≥2 prescribed antiepileptic drugs). 2. Willing to come for regular follow up 1. Surgically remediable cause for drug resistant epilepsy 2. Proven inborn error of metabolism except those in which KD is indicated (i.e., Pyruvate Carboxylase deficiency and GLUT1 Deficiency) 3. Previously received KD, MAD or LGIT 4. Known case of 1. Chronic kidney disease 2. Chronic liver disease/ GI illness 3. Chronic heart disease (congenital and acquired) 4. Chronic respiratory illness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>