<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02708940</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research project aims to evaluate the feasibility and effectiveness of a new approach to tailored mobile applications using the Chorus Participatory Mobile Framework. PHP and IOP program participants—patients and therapists--will be consented and enrolled by study staff. Study participants will be invited to workgroups specific to their program to discuss the usability of Chorus and be asked to complete surveys on demographics, satisfaction, self-efficacy, and involvement with Chorus and usability of the tool.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Participatory Messaging in the UCLA Psychiatry Partial Hospitalization and Intensive Outpatient Programs</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Partial Hospitalization Program (PHP) and Intensive Outpatient Program (IOP) in the Neuropsychatric Hospital at UCLA provide psychiatric services for adults and children with acute mental illness. These include voluntary programs that support individuals in their recovery with the goal to assist patients in achieving the highest level of independence. Most programs operate Monday through Friday between four to eight hours a day. Recently, the PHP and IOP programs have decided to start including mobile messaging as a part of care, helping patients to feel supported even after they have left the hospital for the day. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the feasibility and effectiveness of their ongoing use of the Chorus Participatory Mobile Framework to support clinical care. Chorus is a framework and web application that allows users to rapidly create a broad range of automated text messaging (SMS), interactive voice (IVR), or mobile web applications using a simple and accessible visual interface without requiring any server programming. There will be two broad populations using Chorus: (1) programs (e.g. OCD Intensive Treatment Program) in which all participants will receive participatory mobile messaging and (2) programs (e.g. Adult Acute PHP) in which patients will be randomized to receive either participatory mobile messaging or no mobile messaging. Across all programs, Kandace Whiting and Armen Arevian will train PHP and IOP therapists starting with creating simple, basic, useful messaging content in Chorus to support patients in achieving program goals. Examples of messages include Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT), symptom management, and stress management cues to patients in the Obsessive Compulsive Disorder Clinic, patients in the Adult Eating Disorder Clinic, and parents from The Achievement, Behavior, Cognition (ABC) Child Programs. All participating patients receiving participatory mobile messaging will work with program staff one-on-one to tailor SMS and IVR content and design based on their own preferences. By being able to personalize the messaging, the Chorus Participatory Mobile Framework meets the capacities and preferences of the users rather than a "one-size" approach requiring adaptation of the users to the technology. Both therapists and patients will be invited to up to bi-weekly, in-person workshops specific to their program to provide feedback and input. The goal of these workshops is to further develop and refine the novel mobile interventions based on stakeholder input. The Chorus Participatory Framework will be used during the workshops to develop and test the application in real-time. Workshops will be audio and/or video recorded to document the process.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Patients (over the age of 18) or parents of patients who are minors (between the ages of 6 and 17) Enrolled in PHP or IOP programs at Resnick Neuropsychiatric Hospital Agree to participate (minors will be required to have parental consent) Patient participants will need to be English speaking because text and IVR messages and workshops will be conducted in English. Patient must have cellular phone that can receive text messages All PHP and IOP staff are eligible and will be invited to participate in workshops and complete surveys. Declines consent or is unwilling to participate in the study Does not speak English. Language other than English is an exclusion given resources and capacity of the study Patients without a cellular phone that can receive text messages Not receiving texts or IVR messages from their program is an exclusion given that it is the intervention we are evaluating Patients under the age of 6.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>