<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="63967">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02273167</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NER1006-02/2014 (MORA)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02273167</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Multicenter Randomized Parallel Group Phase III Study Comparing the Bowel Cleansing Efficacy, Safety and Tolerability of NER1006 Versus MOVIPREP® Using a 2-Day Split-Dosing and 1-Day Morning Split-Dosing Regimens in Adults.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter Randomized Parallel Group Phase III Study Comparing the Bowel Cleansing Efficacy, Safety and Tolerability of NER1006 (a Low Volume Bowel Cleansing Solution) Versus MOVIPREP® Using a 2-Day Split-Dosing and 1-Day Morning Split-Dosing Regimens in Adults.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Norgine</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Norgine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study evaluates the efficacy, safety and tolerability of NER1006 compared with MOVIPREP
      in adult patients requiring bowel cleansing prior to any procedure that requires a clean
      bowel, using a 2-Day Split-Dosing and 1-Day Morning Split-Dosing regimens. Approximately 810
      patients will be randomised with the aim of achieving a minimum of 245 patients in each of
      the 3 groups.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single Blind (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Use of Harefield Cleansing Scale to grade bowel cleansing efficacy</measure>
    <time_frame>Day of colonoscopy (Day 2)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the overall bowel cleansing efficacy and the 'Excellent plus Good' cleansing rate in the colon ascendens of 2-day split-dosing and 1-day morning of colonoscopy split-dosing regimens with NER1006 compared to a 2-day split-dosing regimen with MOVIPREP®, graded according to the Harefield Cleansing Scale© (HCS©) in patients undergoing screening, surveillance or diagnostic colonoscopy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adenoma Detection Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Day of colonoscopy (Day 2)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the overall adenoma detection rate with NER1006 compared to MOVIPREP.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Polyp Detection Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Day of colonoscopy (Day 2)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the overall polyp detection rate with NER1006 compared to MOVIPREP.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Use of Boston Bowel Preparation scale to evaluate bowel cleansing efficacy</measure>
    <time_frame>Day of colonoscopy (Day 2)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>BOCLIR questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of dosing until the time of the colonoscopy procedure (day 2)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient compliance and acceptability using the validated patient rating scale &quot;PRO&quot; (patient reported outcomes)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the time of dosing until the time of the colonoscopy procedure (day 2)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients experiencing adverse events while receiving NER1006 compared with MOVIPREP</measure>
    <time_frame>After colonoscopy procedure (Day 2)</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">849</enrollment>
  <condition>Colorectal Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NER1006, 2-Day Split-Dosing</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>NER1006: 2-Day Split-Dosing Regimen (to commence in the evening of the day before colonoscopy).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NER1006,1-Day Morning Split-Dosing</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>NER1006: 1-Day Morning Split-Dosing Regimen (to commence in the morning of the day of colonoscopy).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MOVIPREP, 2-Day Split-Dosing</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>MOVIPREP®: 2-Day Split-Dosing Regimen (to commence in the evening of the day before colonoscopy).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NER1006, 2-Day Split-Dosing</intervention_name>
    <description>The subject will self-administer the first dose of the assigned investigational product in the evening prior to the scheduled colonoscopy and take any mandatory additional clear fluid. Subject will take the second dose together with any required additional clear fluids on the morning of the colonoscopy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NER1006, 2-Day Split-Dosing</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NER1006,1-Day Morning Split-Dosing</intervention_name>
    <description>The subject will self-administer the first dose of the investigational product on the morning of the colonoscopy and take any mandatory additional clear fluid.
After a 1-2 hour break the subject will self-administer the second dose plus any additional clear mandatory fluid.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NER1006,1-Day Morning Split-Dosing</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MOVIPREP, 2-Day Split-Dosing</intervention_name>
    <description>The subject will self-administer the first dose of the assigned investigational product in the evening prior to the scheduled colonoscopy and take any mandatory additional clear fluid. Subject will take the second dose together with any required additional clear fluids on the morning of the colonoscopy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MOVIPREP, 2-Day Split-Dosing</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients must provide written informed consent.

          -  Male and female outpatients and inpatients aged: ≥18 to ≤85 years undergoing a
             screening, surveillance or diagnostic colonoscopy.

          -  Females of child-bearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test at Screening
             and must be practising one of the following methods of birth control and agree to
             continue with the regimen throughout the study period (unless post-menopausal or
             surgically sterile):

               -  Oral, contraceptives (for a minimum of three months before study entry) in
                  combination with a condom;

               -  Intrauterine device in combination with a condom;

               -  Double barrier method (condoms, sponge diaphragm, or vaginal ring with
                  spermicidal gels or cream.

          -  Willing and able to complete the entire study and to comply with instructions.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients with past history within last 12 months or current episode of severe
             constipation (requiring repeated use of laxatives/enema or physical intervention
             before resolution), known or suspected ileus, gastrointestinal obstruction, gastric
             retention, bowel perforation, toxic colitis or megacolon.

          -  Patients with ongoing severe acute Inflammatory Bowel Disease.

          -  Patients who have had previous significant gastrointestinal surgeries, including
             colonic resection, sub-total colectomy, abdomino-perineal resection, de-functioning
             colostomy, Hartmann's procedure and de-functioning ileostomy or other similar
             surgeries involving structure and function of the small or large colon.

          -  Regular use of laxatives or colon motility altering drugs in the last month (i.e.
             more than 2-3 times per week) and/or laxative use within 72 hours prior to
             administration of the preparation.

          -  Patients with active intestinal bleeding episodes or with a clinically significant
             low hemoglobin level &lt;9 g/dL for women and &lt;11 g/dL for men at screening.

          -  Known glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency.

          -  Known phenylketonuria.

          -  Known hypersensitivity to polyethylene glycols, ascorbic acid and sulfates

          -  Past history within the last 12 months or evidence of any on-going clinically
             relevant electrocardiogram (ECG) abnormalities (e.g. arrhythmias).

          -  History of uncontrolled hypertension with systolic blood pressure &gt;170 mmHg and
             diastolic blood pressure &gt;100 mmHg.

          -  Patients with cardiac insufficiency NYHA grades III or IV.

          -  Patients with severe renal insufficiency (i.e. with GFR, &lt;30 mL/min/1.73m2).

          -  Patient with serum albumin &lt;3.4 g/dL.

          -  Patients with liver disease of grades B and C according to the Child Pugh
             classification.

          -  Patients suffering from dehydration at screening as evaluated by the Investigator
             from physical examination and laboratory investigations.

          -  Patients with clinically significant electrolyte abnormalities, whether pre-existing
             or noted at screening, such as hypernatremia, hyponatremia, hyperphosphatemia,
             hypermagnesemia, hypokalemia, hypocalcaemia dehydration, or those secondary to the
             use of diuretics or angiotensin converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitors.

          -  Patients with any other clinically significant hematological parameters including
             coagulation profile at screening.

          -  Patients with impaired consciousness that might predispose them to pulmonary
             aspiration.

          -  Patients undergoing colonoscopy for foreign body removal and/or decompression.

          -  Patients who are pregnant or lactating, or intending to become pregnant during the
             study.

          -  Clinically relevant findings on physical examination based on the Investigator's
             judgment.

          -  History of drug or alcohol abuse within the 12 months prior to dosing.

          -  Concurrent participation in an investigational drug or device study or participation
             within three months of study entry.

          -  Patients who are ordered to live in an institution on court or authority order
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Raf Bisschops, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UZ Leuven</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ Leuven</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leuven</city>
        <zip>3000 Leuven</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 18, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>October 16, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
