<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="116395">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01587898</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>116581</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01587898</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>4 Week Correction Study in Subjects With Anemia Associated With Chronic Kidney Disease Who Are Not Undergoing Dialysis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Four-week Phase IIa, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled, Parallel-group, Multi-center Study to Evaluate the Safety, Efficacy and Pharmacokinetics of GSK1278863 in Subjects With Anemia Associated With Chronic Kidney Disease Who Are Not Taking Recombinant Human Erythropoietin and Are Not Undergoing Dialysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>PPD</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GlaxoSmithKline</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a four-week Phase IIa, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group,
      multi-center study to evaluate the safety, efficacy and pharmacokinetics of GSK1278863 in
      approximately 68 subjects with anemia associated with chronic kidney disease who are not
      taking rhEPO and are not undergoing dialysis. The range of Hgb values for study eligibility
      is 8.5-11.0 g/dL. Eligible subjects will be randomized in equal proportions to receive once
      daily (QD) placebo or GSK1278863 0.5 mg, 2 mg or 5 mg in a double-blind fashion.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a four-week Phase IIa, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group,
      multi-center study to evaluate the safety, efficacy and pharmacokinetics of GSK1278863 in
      approximately 68 subjects with anemia associated with chronic kidney disease who are not
      taking rhEPO and are not undergoing dialysis. The study consists of a screening phase of up
      to 2 weeks, a 4-week treatment phase and a 2-week follow-up phase. The range of Hgb values
      for study eligibility is 8.5-11.0 g/dL. Eligible subjects will be randomized in equal
      proportions to receive once daily (QD) placebo or GSK1278863 0.5 mg, 2 mg or 5 mg in a
      double-blind fashion. Study treatment will be stopped if Hgb values fall outside of the
      range pre-specified in the protocol.

      This study aims to estimate the relationship between dose of GSK1278863 and Hgb response for
      correcting anemia in non-dialysis subjects with CKD who are not taking rhEPO (NDD). In
      addition, the study will characterize the effect of GSK1278863 on various
      pharmacokinetic/pharmacodynamic (PK/PD) markers, and will investigate the safety and
      tolerability of GSK1278863.

      An early interim analysis of the Hgb data is planned after approximately 20 subjects from
      cohort 1 have completed 3 weeks of treatment. Depending upon the interim findings, a second
      cohort of subjects may be added to investigate an additional GSK1278863 dose arm.
      Recruitment to the first cohort will continue during the interim analysis.

      A second interim analysis is planned after approximately 48 subjects from cohort 1 have
      completed 4 weeks treatment. The purpose of this interim is three-fold, to investigate
      whether a second cohort of subjects may be added, to facilitate early development of
      dose-response and PK/PD statistical models, and to generate interim results to facilitate
      design and dosing decisions for the next trial.

      Subject completion is defined as completion of all study phases including the follow-up
      phase.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Participant, Investigator</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Modelled hemoglobin change from baseline over 4 weeks of treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Modelled Hgb change from baseline over 4 weeks of treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Hgb changes over 4 weeks.</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum Hgb changes over 4 weeks, the number and percentage of subjects who achieve an Hgb response (defined as achieving an increase of at least 0.5 g/dL, 1.0 g/dL, 1.5 g/dL and 2.0g/dL in Hgb during the trial) and the number of subjects who have reached Hgb stopping criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants achieving an increase of 0.5 g/dL, 1.0 g/dL, 1.5 g/dL and 2.0g/dL in Hgb</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of population pharmacokinetic parameters of GSK1278863 and relevant metabolites. These include fixed-effect (clearance, volumes, covariate effects) and random-effect (within and between subject variability, residual variability) parameters.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety markers</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Discontinuation for safety related reasons, e.g. pre-specified stopping criteria or AE, incidence and severity of AEs and SAEs, absolute values and changes from baseline over time in laboratory parameters, ECGs and vital signs</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Markers of iron metabolism and utilization</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of change in hepcidin, ferritin, transferrin, transferrin saturation, total iron, total iron binding capacity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>High sensitivity C-reactive protein (hsCRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of change in hsCRP</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Erythropoietin</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of change in erythropoietin levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hematologic measures</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of change in hematocrit, red blood cells and reticulocytes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor (VEGF)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of change in VEGF levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">74</enrollment>
  <condition>Anaemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>0.5mg GSK1278863</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Once daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2mg GSK1278863</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Once daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>5mg GSK1278863</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Once daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Once daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GSK1278863</intervention_name>
    <description>Tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>0.5mg GSK1278863</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>5mg GSK1278863</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>2mg GSK1278863</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Age and weight: &gt;/= 18 years of age and &gt;/= 45 kg.

          2. Not routinely undergoing dialysis, regardless of the modality (either hemodialysis or
             peritoneal dialysis) or dialysis planned during the time the subject would be
             enrolled in the study.

          3. No current or prior rhEPO use within the past 7 weeks; e.g., epoetins (or their
             biosimilars), darbepoetin, Mircera (methoxy polyethylene glycol epoetin beta),
             peginesatide or their biosimilars..

          4. KDOQI CKD stages 3/4/5 defined by eGFR using the Modification of Diet for Renal
             Disease (MDRD).

          5. Hgb: Hgb concentrations 8.5-11.0 g/dL (inclusive) as outlined in Section 4.2.

          6. Vitamin B12: Above the lower limit of the reference range (may rescreen in 2 months).

          7. Folate: &gt;/=2.0 ng/mL at Screening. May rescreen in a month.

          8. Ferritin: &gt;/=40 ng/mL with the absence of microcytic or hypochromic RBCs.

          9. TSAT within the reference range.

         10. Iron replacement therapy: Stable maintenance dose of oral iron replacement therapy,
             if required, that will be maintained throughout the study. NOTE: IV iron replacement
             therapy is not allowed the two weeks prior to Screening through the end of the study
             (Week 6).

         11. QTc: QTcB &lt;470 msec or QTcB &lt;480 msec in subjects with bundle branch block obtained
             at Screening Visit, based on Central Reader's interpretation.

         12. Females: Eligible to participate if she is of childbearing potential, and must agree
             to use approved contraception methods from Screening until completion of the
             Follow-up Visit OR of non-childbearing potential defined as pre-menopausal females
             with a documented tubal ligation of hysterectomy; or postmenopausal defined as 12
             months of spontaneous amenorrhea [in questionable cases a blood sample with
             simultaneous follicle stimulating hormone (FSH)&gt;40 MIU/ml and estradiol &lt;40 pg/ml is
             confirmatory]. Females on hormone replacement therapy (HRT) whose menopausal status
             is in doubt will be required to use one of the approved contraception methods if they
             wish to continue their HRT during the study. Otherwise they must discontinue HRT to
             allow confirmation of post-menopausal status prior to study enrollment. For most
             types of HRT, at least 2 weeks will elapse between the cessation of therapy and the
             blood draw; this interval depends on the type and dosage of HRT. Following
             confirmation of their post-menopausal status, they can resume use of HRT during the
             study without use of a contraceptive method.

         13. Males: Must agree to use approved contraceptive methods from the time of Screening
             until completion of the Follow-up Visit.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Dialysis: Planning to initiate dialysis during the study or who have a high potential
             for initiating dialysis during study participation.

          2. Renal transplant: Renal transplant anticipated or scheduled within the study time
             period or subjects with a functioning renal transplant.

          3. Total CPK: &gt;5x the upper limit of the reference range.

          4. HIV: Positive HIV antibody.

          5. History of myocardial infarction or acute coronary syndrome within the prior 6
             months.

          6. History of stroke or TIAs.

          7. Heart failure: Class III/IV heart failure, as defined by the New York Heart
             Association (NYHA) functional classification system.

          8. Hypertension: Poorly controlled hypertension, whether due to inadequate treatment, or
             lack of treatment, defined as DBP &gt;100 mmHg or SBP&gt;160 mmHg.

          9. Thrombotic disease: History of thrombotic disease (e.g., venous thrombosis such as
             deep vein thrombosis or pulmonary embolism, or arterial thrombosis such as new onset
             or worsening limb ischemia requiring intervention), or other thrombosis related
             condition) within the prior 6 months.

         10. Pulmonary hypertension: Known pulmonary hypertension and those at higher risk (than
             normally associated with CKD) for pre-existing elevation in pulmonary pressure (e.g.,
             significant heart failure or lung disease requiring supplemental oxygen, or those
             with connective tissue diseases).

         11. Inflammatory disease: Chronic inflammatory disease that could impact erythropoiesis
             (e.g., scleroderma, systemic lupus erythematosis, rheumatoid arthritis, celiac
             disease).

         12. Hematological disease: Any hematological disease including those affecting platelets,
             the coagulation disorders (e.g., Protein C or S deficiency) or red blood cells (e.g.
             sickle cell anemia, myelodysplastic syndromes, hematological malignancy, myeloma,
             hemolytic anemia) or any other cause of anemia other than renal disease.

         13. Liver disease: Current liver disease, known hepatic or biliary abnormalities (with
             the exception of Gilbert's syndrome or asymptomatic gallstones) or evidence at
             Screening of abnormal liver function tests [alkaline phosphatase, ALT or AST &gt; 2.0 x
             upper limit of normal (ULN) or total bilirubin &gt; 1.5 x ULN]; or other hepatic
             abnormalities that in the opinion of the investigator would preclude the subject from
             participation in the study.

         14. Major surgery: Within the prior 12 weeks or planned during the study.

         15. Transfusion: Blood transfusion within the prior 12 weeks or an anticipated need for
             blood transfusion during the study.

         16. Ulcer and Active GI Bleeding: Evidence of active peptic, duodenal, or esophageal
             ulcer disease or active GI bleeding within the prior 12 weeks.

         17. Acute infection: Clinical evidence of acute infection or history of infection
             requiring intravenous (IV) antibiotic therapy the eight weeks prior to Screening
             through Day 1 (randomization).

         18. Malignancy: History of malignancy within 5 years of Screening or are receiving
             treatment for cancer or those with a strong family history of cancer (e.g., familial
             cancer disorders), with the exception of squamous cell or basal cell carcinoma of the
             skin that has been definitively treated.

         19. Hyperparathyroidism: Clinically significant hyperparathyroidism in the opinion of the
             Investigator, including subjects with parathyroid hormone (PTH) values ≥600 pg/mL.

         20. Eyes: History of proliferative retinopathy requiring treatment within the prior 12
             months, or macular edema requiring treatment.

         21. Severe reactions: History of severe allergic or anaphylactic reactions or
             hypersensitivity to excipients in the investigational product.

         22. Drugs and supplements: Use of any prescription or non-prescription drugs or dietary
             supplements that are prohibited from Screening until the Follow-up Visit.

         23. Androgens: New androgen therapy or changes to pre-existing androgen regimen within
             prior 12 weeks.

         24. Prior investigational product exposure: The subject has participated in a clinical
             trial and has received an experimental investigational product within prior 30 days.

         25. Protocol compliance: Unwillingness or inability to follow the procedures, or
             lifestyle and/or dietary restrictions outlined in the protocol.

         26. Other conditions: Any condition which in the investigators opinion should exclude the
             subject from participating in the study.

         27. Pregnancy and lactation: Pregnant females as determined by positive urine hCG test,
             OR women who are lactating at Screening or during the trial.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GSK Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>GlaxoSmithKline</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Azusa</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91702</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bakersfield</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>93309</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chino</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90022</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90025</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90057</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>North Hollywood</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91606-1559</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orange</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92868</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Riverside</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92505</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Dimas</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91773</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>West Hills</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91307</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Yuba City</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Denver</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80230</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Daytona Beach</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32117</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edgewater</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32132</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Lauderdale</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33308</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jacksonville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32258</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33145</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33150</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33173</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ocala</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>34471</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pembroke Pines</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33028</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Port Charlotte</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33952</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Savannah</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>31406</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Evanston</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gurnee</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60031</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48236</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Asheville</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28801</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlotte</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wilmington</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28401</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winston Salem</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oklahoma City</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>73116</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethlehem</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>18017</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Erie</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>16507</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Uniontown</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15401</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Arlington</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>76011</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78751</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Corsicana</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Greenville</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75402</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77054</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77099</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Temple</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>76502</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Silverdale</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98383</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Calgary</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T2R 0X7</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brampton</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>L6T 0G1</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>N6A 5A5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sudbury</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>P3E 5J1</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heidelberg</city>
        <state>Baden-Wuerttemberg</state>
        <zip>69120</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aschaffenburg</city>
        <state>Bayern</state>
        <zip>63741</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Demmin</city>
        <state>Mecklenburg-Vorpommern</state>
        <zip>17109</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lehrte</city>
        <state>Niedersachsen</state>
        <zip>31275</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>22297</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</url>
    <description>Researchers can use this site to request access to anonymised patient level data and/or supporting documents from clinical studies to conduct further research.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 23, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 19, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_disposition_date>April 27, 2015</firstreceived_results_disposition_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Anemia</keyword>
  <keyword>Prolyl hydroxylase inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>Hemoglobin</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic kidney disease</keyword>
  <keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
  <keyword>recombinant human erythropoietin</keyword>
  <keyword>GSK1278863</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Patient-level data for this study will be made available through www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com following the timelines and process described on this site.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <study_docs>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>116581</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>116581</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Dataset Specification</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>116581</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Study Protocol</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>116581</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Annotated Case Report Form</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>116581</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Clinical Study Report</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>116581</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Individual Participant Data Set</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
    <study_doc>
      <doc_id>116581</doc_id>
      <doc_type>Informed Consent Form</doc_type>
      <doc_url>https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com</doc_url>
      <doc_comment>For additional information about this study please refer to the GSK Clinical Study Register</doc_comment>
    </study_doc>
  </study_docs>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted, but a results disposition has been submitted -->
</clinical_study>
