<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00408681</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Lithium carbonate may be an effective treatment for intestinal graft-versus-host disease caused by a donor stem cell transplant. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is studying lithium carbonate in treating patients with acute intestinal graft-versus-host-disease after donor stem cell transplant.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lithium Carbonate in Treating Patients With Acute Intestinal Graft-Versus-Host-Disease (GVHD) After Donor Stem Cell Transplant</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To evaluate the effects of lithium on functional and mucosal anatomic recovery in the small or large bowel of patients with acute GVHD. II. Functional recovery will be evaluated according to changes in clinical manifestations of gastrointestinal GVHD. III. Mucosal anatomic recovery will be evaluated by review of results from clinically indicated endoscopic evaluations. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the tolerability of lithium administration in allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplant recipients. OUTLINE: Patients receive oral lithium carbonate once or twice daily. Treatment continues for up to 8 weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Follicular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Burkitt Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large-Cell, Immunoblastic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Plasmablastic Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Mantle-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelogenous, Chronic, BCR-ABL Positive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell, Marginal Zone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Germ Cell and Embryonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Glandular and Epithelial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Graft vs Host Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycoses</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycosis Fungoides</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Primary Myelofibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sezary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelomonocytic, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelomonocytic, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Cutaneous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Germinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Hairy Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myeloproliferative Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Chronic-Phase</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhabdomyosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testicular Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic-Myeloproliferative Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Chronic, Atypical, BCR-ABL Negative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypereosinophilic Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Wilms Tumor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Blast Crisis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhabdomyosarcoma, Embryonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Accelerated Phase</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelomonocytic, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Neutrophilic, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trophoblastic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gestational Trophoblastic Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lithium Carbonate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient with a diagnosis of severe intestinal GVHD that is not improving at any time after initial treatment with glucocorticoids for at least 7 days are eligible for enrollment; measures indicating severity of GVHD will include: a) persistent diarrhea with average daily stool volumes &gt; 500 mL per day; or b) persistent hemorrhage that is detectable by visual inspection of the stool Patients with denuded mucosa caused by GVHD are eligible for enrollment, regardless of prior treatment for acute GVHD; denuded mucosa is defined as loss (i.e., erosion or sloughing) of the epithelium in: a) at least onethird of the surface area in a 30 cm colonic segment (i.e., rectosigmoid, descending or transverse colon); or b) at least one fifth of the surface area of the second portion of the duodenum, as estimated by endoscopic evaluation; denuded mucosa must be documented by images of the duodenum and colon and by histologic evaluation of the colon All subjects must provide written informed consent with the use of forms approved by the Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center (FHCRC) Institutional Review Board (IRB) Significant renal dysfunction (estimated creatinine clearance &lt; 30 mL/min) Persistent or recurrent malignancy Secondary malignancy Patients who had autologous or syngeneic marrow transplantation Presence of any cause of intestinal symptoms or ulceration other than GVHD Patients with any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially hampering compliance with the study protocol will be excluded</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>