<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00076622</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will examine therapeutic and adverse effects of continuing versus discontinuing antidepressant medication in nursing home residents who have had no more than a single episode of depression and who no longer have depressive symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Medication Treatment for Depression in Nursing Home Residents</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There are approximately 1.6 million nursing home residents in the United States. More than one third of these residents are taking antidepressant medications (ADs). Although ADs are effective, evidence suggests that they can lead to significant adverse events, including an increased risk of falls and bone fractures. Many depressed nursing home residents suffer from an initial episode of late-life depression and do not meet guideline-based recommendations for maintenance treatment. This study will examine the benefits and risks of long-term AD treatment in depressed nursing home residents whose single episode of depression has been in continuous remission for at least six months. Participants will be randomly assigned to either continue or discontinue AD treatment. Participants will be monitored over a period of one year for recurrence of depression and related symptoms, as well as for the occurrence of falls, fractures, and other adverse events. Medical chart review, self-reported mood symptoms, and depression scales will be used to assess participants.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antidepressive Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Current use of antidepressant medication Have been in remission from first episode of depression for 6 months or longer Currently residing in a long term care or assisted living facility Bedridden Severe cognitive impairment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Antidepressant drugs</keyword>
	<keyword>Nursing Homes</keyword>
</DOC>