<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02188017</DOC>
	<brief_summary>An randomized trial of two maintenance doses of Acthar Gel for patients with chronic pulmonary sarcoidosis. Patients will be observed for 24 weeks of treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acthar Gel for Chronic Pulmonary Sarcoidosis (ACPS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multi-center double-blind trial to determine dose and effect size. A total of 20 chronic pulmonary sarcoidosis patients will be recruited at eight clinical sites across the United States. After initial evaluation, including pulmonary function, CT and PET scanning, patients will be randomized to receive 80 Units if Acthar gel daily for 10days, followed by either 40 or 80 units of Acthar gel twice a week for an additional 22 weeks. At the end of total 24 weeks of treatment, they will undergo repeat evaluation including pulmonary function, CT, and PET scanning.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoidosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoidosis, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adrenocorticotropic Hormone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient with biopsy confirmed sarcoidosis meeting American Thoracic Society criteria 23 Patient on &gt;5 mg prednisone for pulmonary indications FVC &lt;85% predicted Prednisone dose not reduced in prior 3 months Deterioration of pulmonary disease over the past year Decrease in FVC &gt;5% Age: 18 through 90 (i.e., candidates must have had their 18th birthday, but not had their 91st birthday). adrenal insufficiency (Addison's disease) Scleroderma a fungal infection herpes infection of the eyes osteoporosis a stomach ulcer congestive heart failure high blood pressure recent surgery if you are allergic to pork proteins Do not receive a smallpox vaccine or any "live" vaccine while you are using corticotropin. Patients receiving antiTumor Necrosis Factor antibody (e.g. infliximab, adalimumab) in prior six months Uncontrolled diabetes, hypertension, or other contraindication to increased dosage of glucocorticoids Patients requiring therapy for pulmonary hypertension Females of childbearing potential who are known to be pregnant and/or lactating or who have a positive urine pregnancy test on screening. Current participation in another research drug treatment protocol (patient cannot start another experimental agent until after 90 days) Any other condition that the investigator feels would pose a significant hazard to the patient if Acthar Gel therapy is initiated.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>prednisone, methotrexate, sarcoidosis, azathioprine</keyword>
</DOC>