<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02265458</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Non-invasive ventilation (NIV) might be associated with anxiety, thus leading to NIV failure, and intubation. Music therapy has been used in various clinical context, including in ICU patients under mechanical ventilation. We aim to evaluate the effect of a musical intervention on respiratory comfort during NIV for acute respiratory failure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Musical Intervention in Non-invasive Ventilation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We plan a randomized controlled trial with 3 different arms, in ICU patients requiring NIV for acute respiratory failure : "usual care", "sensory isolation" and "sensory isolation and musical intervention".At the onset of respiratory failure, each patient will be randomized in one of the 3 arms. "Usual care" assigned patients will receive NIV according to each unit protocol; "sensory isolation" assigned patients will receive NIV associated with a mask obscuring the eyes and a noise-reducing headset."musical intervention patients" will receive a 30 minutes musical intervention during each NIV session. Respiratory discomfort will be blindly assessed before, immediately after NIV is correctly set (5 minutes), at 30 minutes, and at hours 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 12, 16, 20, 24 according to NIV session length, and at the end of NIV session during each NIV session.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>respiratory distress requiring NIV Glasgow coma score above 12 NIV contraindication : Hemodynamic failure, neurologic failure, head trauma, vomiting Severe hypoacusis people without hearing device Decision to limit active treatment with an estimated life expectancy of less than 48 hours</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Respiratory failure</keyword>
	<keyword>NIV</keyword>
	<keyword>Musical intervention</keyword>
</DOC>