<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00022087</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Zoledronate plus calcium and vitamin D may prevent bone loss in patients receiving adjuvant chemotherapy for breast cancer. It is not yet known which regimen is more effective in preventing bone loss. PURPOSE: This randomized phase III trial is comparing two regimens of zoledronate plus calcium and vitamin D to see how well they work in preventing bone loss in women who are receiving adjuvant chemotherapy for breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Zoledronate, Calcium, and Vitamin D in Preventing Bone Loss in Women Receiving Adjuvant Chemotherapy for Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Compare the bone mineral density in the lumbar spine after 12 and 36 months of therapy with zoledronate, calcium, and cholecalciferol (vitamin D) in women with breast cancer receiving adjuvant chemotherapy. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, open-label, multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to intent to treat with tamoxifen (yes vs no) and node status (negative vs positive vs unknown [for patients receiving neoadjuvant therapy]). Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. - Arm I: Beginning on the first day of adjuvant chemotherapy (or within 3 months after the first day), patients receive zoledronate IV over at least 15 minutes once every 3 months during months 1-24 and oral calcium and oral cholecalciferol (vitamin D) daily during months 1-36. - Arm II: Beginning on the first day of adjuvant chemotherapy (or within 3 months after the first day), patients receive oral calcium and oral vitamin D daily during months 1-36 and zoledronate IV over at least 15 minutes once every 3 months during months 13-36. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: Approximately 400 patients (200 per treatment arm) will be accrued for this study within 24 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Zoledronic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diphosphonates</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the breast by fine needle aspirate, biopsy (trucut, core, stereotactic), lumpectomy, or modified radical mastectomy Stage IIII (any T, any N, M0) Stage IV due solely to supraclavicular node involvement allowed Plan to use adjuvant chemotherapy* with or without adjuvant endocrine therapy* Subsequent adjuvant hormonal therapy with an aromatase inhibitor allowed in women rendered postmenopausal by adjuvant chemotherapy NOTE: *Must be specified prior to study entry Hormone receptor status: Not specified PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 40 and over Sex: Female Menopausal status: See Disease Characteristics Premenopausal, defined as actively menstruating or last menstrual period occurred within 6 months prior to study entry Prior hysterectomy without bilateral oophorectomy and estradiol and folliclestimulating hormone within premenopausal range prior to the initiation of chemotherapy allowed Performance status: Not specified Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Other: Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: See Disease Characteristics No more than 3 months since prior adjuvant chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: See Disease Characteristics Radiotherapy: Not specified Surgery: See Disease Characteristics See Menopausal status Other: No other concurrent bisphosphonates No concurrent digoxin No concurrent tetracycline Concurrent neoadjuvant therapy allowed Concurrent enrollment on therapeutic adjuvant clinical trials allowed provided the therapeutic trial does not preclude participation in this trial</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>osteoporosis</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIA breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIB breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIC breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>