<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00681655</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will study the presence of a particular form of a gene, GABRA2, to characterize functional responses of the human brain to alcohol administration and will evaluate that relationship in the context of factors known to increase the risk for future alcoholism.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>GABRA2 and the Pharmacokinetics of Risk for Alcoholism (GPRA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>European American male and females between 2127 years of age. Good health as determined by medical history, physical exam, and laboratory tests. Females must have a negative urine pregnancy (hCG) test at the start of each study session. People who consume 0.10 standard drinks per week (12 gethanol) per liter of total body water when averaged over the preceding month, or more, OR who have consumed more than 0.10 standard drinks per liter of total body water on any one occasion in the last month. Inability to read or comprehend eighth grade English. Inability to hear or comprehend verbal instructions, or inability or unwillingness to cooperate with the procedures required for the study. Inability to resolve 2 dots, each 2 mm in diameter with centers placed 5 mm apart on a card placed 20 inches from the bridge of the nose, or the need to wear eyeglasses to do so. Current or prior history of any serious disease, including head trauma causing loss of consciousness, cancer, CNS, cardiovascular, respiratory, gastrointestinal, hepatic, renal, endocrine, or alcohol or drug dependence, but not alcohol abuse or nicotine dependence. Positive hepatitis or HIV test at screening, provided subject consented to these tests. Current or prior history of alcoholinduced flushing reactions. Current diagnosis of AxisI psychiatric illness. Positive result on urine drug screen obtained at the facetoface interview. Pregnancy, as determined by urine HcG on each day of laboratory testing, or intention to become pregnant for women. Use of medications known to interact with alcohol within 2 weeks of the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>27 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>