<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01323790</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effect and safety of NKTR-118 treatment of opioid-induced constipation in patients with non-cancer-related pain, including those patients that have inadequate response to laxative therapy (LIR).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of Efficacy and Safety in Patients With Non-cancer-related Pain and Opioid-induced Constipation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Constipation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Analgesics, Opioid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Naloxegol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Provision of written informed consent prior to any studyspecific procedures. Selfreported active symptoms of OIC at screening (&lt;3 SBMs/week and experiencing ≥1 reported symptom of hard/lumpy stools, straining, or sensation of incomplete evacuation/anorectal obstruction in at least 25% of BMs over the previous 4 weeks); and Documented confirmed OIC (&lt;3 SBMs/week on average over the 2week OIC confirmation period. Receiving a stable maintenance opioid regimen consisting of a total daily dose of 30 mg to 1000 mg of oral morphine, or equianalgesic amount(s) of 1 or more other opioid therapies for a minimum of 4 weeks prior to screening for noncancerrelated pain with no anticipated change in opioid dose requirement over the proposed study period as a result of disease progression. Willingness to stop all laxatives and other bowel regimens including prune juice and herbal products throughout the 2week OIC confirmation period and the 12week treatment period, and to use only bisacodyl as rescue medication if a BM has not occurred within at least 72 hours of the last recorded BM. Patients receiving Opioid regimen for treatment of pain related to cancer. History of cancer within 5 years from first study visit with the exception of basal cell cancer and squamous cell skin cancer. Medical conditions and treatments associated with diarrhea, intermittent loose stools, or constipation. Other issues to the gastrointestinal tract that could impose a risk to the patient. Pregnancy or lactation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>84 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-Cancer-Related Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Opioid-Induced Constipation</keyword>
</DOC>