<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01323283</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study hypothesizes that supplementation of omega-3 fatty acids (OM3) can increase physical activity, inhibit rapid gain in body weight and BMI in both sedentary and normally active 8 year old children. The purpose is secondarily to explore patterns of associations between OM3 supplementation, baseline and follow-up levels in all studied parameters. The study also aims to study if basal levels of OM3 are correlated with physical activity and to study if there is an association between basal levels of OM3 and the effect of OM3 supplementation on physical activity. To study if there is an effect of OM3 supplementation on triglyceride and LDL cholesterol levels and to study if there are more pronounced effects on children with higher levels. To study if OM3 supplementation, compared with placebo reduce weight increase among children at risk to become overweight. To study if there is an association between effects of OM3 on physical activity, weight and risk markers in blood. To study if there are any gender differences.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Omega-3 Fatty Acids Regarding Ergogenic, Anti-inflammatory and Obesity Inhibitory Effects in 8 Year Old Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Stimulants</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children in second grade of Swedish primary school willing to participate Any morbidity affecting ambulatory physical activity, studied blood parameters and selfreport parameters (i.e. perceived motor skill, quality of life and physical activity) Knowing beforehand participant will not be able to complete the intervention and/or the 0 and 15 week assessments/clinics.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>9 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Omega-3</keyword>
	<keyword>physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>children</keyword>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>sedentary</keyword>
	<keyword>accelerometry</keyword>
	<keyword>BMI</keyword>
	<keyword>fatty acids</keyword>
	<keyword>inflammatory markers</keyword>
	<keyword>intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>randomized</keyword>
	<keyword>double blind</keyword>
</DOC>