<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT02510547</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>CrossBoss First single-blind randomized control trial randomize 246 patient undergoing clinically-indicated Chronic Total Occlusion Percutaneous Coronary Intervention , upfront use CrossBoss catheter vs. antegrade guidewire escalation strategy The `` CrossBoss First '' study two primary objective . The primary efficacy objective compare procedure time require cross CTO abort procedure CrossBoss first vs. antegrade wire escalation strategy . The investigator hypothesize upfront use CrossBoss catheter associate short procedure time require CTO cross compare antegrade wire escalation strategy . The primary safety objective compare frequency procedural major adverse cardiovascular event ( MACE ) upfront use CrossBoss vs. guidewire escalation strategy . The investigator hypothesize upfront use CrossBoss catheter associate similar incidence MACE compare antegrade wire escalation strategy . The secondary endpoint : ( 1 ) technical procedural success4-6 ; ( 2 ) total procedure time ( define interval administration local anesthesia obtain vascular access removal last catheter ) ; ( 3 ) fluoroscopy time cross CTO total fluoroscopy time ; ( 4 ) total air kerma radiation exposure ; ( 5 ) total contrast volume ; ( 6 ) number wire , microcatheters , balloon , stent use .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison CrossBoss First Versus Standard Wire Escalation Strategy Crossing Coronary Chronic Total Occlusion : `` CrossBoss First '' Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arteriosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 year great Willing able give inform consent Undergoing clinicallyindicated CTO PCI plan antegrade cross approach Plan primary retrograde approach CTO cross Ostial CTOs ( within 5 mm vessel ostium )</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>