<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01027351</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The proposed study V72P6E1 is an Extension Study of V72P6 (NCT00381615). The objectives of this extension study will be to explore antibody persistence at approximately 40 months of age and to evaluate the safety, tolerability and immunogenicity of booster doses of rMenB±OMV NZ administered to subjects at approximately 40 months of age. Antibody persistence will be subsequently measured at 18-20 months after these booster doses when the subjects are 60 months of age. Two groups of naïve subjects, aged approximately 40 and 60 months, will be recruited in the study to serve as a baseline comparator for assessing antibody persistence at these ages. These subjects will receive a two-dose catch-up regimen with rMenB+OMV NZ. Subjects who are enrolled at 40 months of age are offered DTaP/IPV and MMR vaccinations, if they have not already received these vaccines prior to enrollment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Extension Study Evaluating Antibody Persistence and Safety, Tolerability and Immunogenicity of Booster Doses of Novartis rMenB±OMV NZ Vaccine in Healthy UK Children Who Previously Received One or Four Doses of the Same Vaccine</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Meningococcal Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lactitol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy 40 to 44monthsold children, who participated and completed the study V72P6 (NCT00381615; followon subjects) Healthy 40 to 44months or 60 to 62monthsold children (naïve subjects) Previous ascertained or suspected disease caused by N. meningitidis History of severe allergic reaction after previous vaccinations or hypersensitivity to any vaccine component Any serious chronic or progressive disease Known or suspected impairment/alteration of the immune system Receipt of, or intent to immunize with another vaccine, within 30 days prior and after vaccination with the investigational vaccines (within 14 days for licensed flu vaccines)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>62 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
	<keyword>Pre-school</keyword>
	<keyword>Meningococcal disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>Vaccination</keyword>
</DOC>