<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01027949</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study provides, or continues to provide, UT-15C SR (treprostinil diethanolamine) to eligible patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension who have completed protocols TDE-PH-202, TDE-PH-203, TDE-PH-205, TDE-PH-301, TDE-PH-302, TDE-PH-308 studies or any additional UT-15C SR clinical protocols evaluating subjects with PAH. The study assesses the long term safety of UT-15C and the effect of continued treatment with UT-15C on exercise capacity after one year of treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Open-Label Extension Trial of UT-15C SR in Subjects With Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label study. Each subject's visit schedule will allow assessments after defined periods of exposure to UT-15C SR (3, 6, 12, 24 and 36 months total exposure). The study will continue with yearly visits beyond 36 months until either UT-15C SR is approved by the appropriate regulatory authorities or the study is discontinued by the sponsor. Therefore, the actual date of each visit will be determined by the date on which the subject first received UT-15C SR (e.g., the date of study drug initiation in TDE-PH- 301, TDE-PH-302, or TDE-PH-308 for subjects who were randomized to active therapy in those trials,and the date of UT-15C SR initiation in this study for subjects who were randomized to placebo in the previous controlled trial). Note that the TDE-PH-202, TDE-PH-203, TDE-PH-205 studies are open-label design and therefore will follow the regimen for subjects receiving UT-15C SR.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Familial Primary Pulmonary Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Treprostinil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participation in study TDEPH202, TDEPH203, TDEPH205, TDEPH301, TDEPH302,TDEPH308 or any additional UT15C SR clinical protocol is required. Subjects must complete all assessments in one of these studies to be eligible.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>