<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02392104</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the feasibility, safety, and acceptability of implementing an extended interval of INR follow-up in Veterans on a stable dose of warfarin in the Anticoagulation Clinic at the William S. Middleton Memorial Veterans Hospital. All participants will be provided usual care from the anticoagulation clinic, except for the interval between INRs. If the participant continues to be on a stable dose of warfarin and the INRs are within the goal range of 2-3 (including lab variation), follow-up visits will be scheduled following an extended interval protocol. Patient satisfaction will be evaluated at various points throughout the study. Additionally provider satisfaction, confidence, and knowledge of the extended interval protocol will be analyzed. Bleeding and thromboembolic events will be evaluated to ensure the safety of an extended follow-up interval.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Evaluation of an Extended Interval of INR Follow-up in a VA Anticoagulation Service</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Warfarin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years of age or older requirement for indefinite warfarin therapy target INR of 23 stable weekly warfarin dose for the past 6 months (not more than a single, onetime adjustment (boost/omission) in the past 6 months, planned interruption for a procedure or surgery with INR(s) out of range in the past 6 months would not exclude a patient) a patient of the Madison VA anticoagulation clinic for the previous 12 months consistently drink ≥4 alcoholic beverages/day or a documented episode of alcohol binging in the past 6 months diagnosis of cancer and on active chemotherapy/radiotherapy in the past 3 months life expectancy of &lt; 1 year enrolled in other investigational drug protocols only receiving anticoagulation care at the Madison VA for part of the year (e.g. snowbirds) receiving visiting nurse services for INR monitoring thrombocytopenia (&lt;100K) within past 12 months history of bleeding or thromboembolism requiring medical intervention within past 6 months treatment for active liver disease (e.g. hepatitis) diagnosis or documentation in EMR suggesting cognitive impairment activated power of attorney inability to provide informed consent nonEnglish speaking unstable mental health disorder that impairs judgment history of nonadherence to anticoagulation clinic policies and procedures (i.e. missed appointments, selfadjustment of warfarin dose, nonadherence, etc.).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>International Normalized Ratio</keyword>
	<keyword>Warfarin</keyword>
</DOC>