<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02392520</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study aims to compare the novel method of GnRH antagonist administration in the luteal phase versus conventional treatment in IVF patients who develop severe early ovarian hyperstimulation syndrome and have all their embryos cryopreserved.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Luteal Antagonist Versus Conventional Treatment in Women With Severe Early Ovarian Hyperstimulation Syndrome (OHSS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>GnRH antagonist administration in the luteal phase has been proposed as a strategy for the treatment of established severe early OHSS, causing rapid regression of the syndrome on an outpatient basis. The approach has been described as tertiary OHSS prevention, thereby complementing the primary prevention (GnRH antagonist protocol) and secondary prevention (GnRH agonist trigger) that constitute the OHSS-free clinic concept. No randomized controlled trials (RCT) exist to date comparing luteal GnRH antagonist administration versus conventional treatment. The aim of the present study is to compare the novel method of GnRH antagonist administration in the luteal phase versus conventional treatment with primary outcome time to severe OHSS regression, in IVF patients who develop severe early OHSS and have all their embryos cryopreserved.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Hyperstimulation Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cetrorelix</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women with established severe early OHSS. Criteria for the diagnosis of severe OHSS require: the presence of moderate (or higher) ascites and at least two of the following: enlarged ovaries (&gt;100 mm maximal diameter), haematocrit (Ht) &gt;45%, white blood cell count (WBC) &gt;15,000/mm3. Women not fulfilling the above criteria</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>severe OHSS</keyword>
	<keyword>antagonist administration</keyword>
	<keyword>conventional treatment</keyword>
</DOC>