<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00189059</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The acute and subchronic effects of amitriptyline were compared to placebo in a double-blind crossover randomized study on driving ability and driving-related skills in chronic neuropathic pain patients.It was hypothesized that nocturnally administered 25 mg amitriptyline might affect driving performance negatively after acute, but not after subchronic treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Amitriptyline for the Treatment of Pain on Driving Performance and Cognition.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The present study was designed to determine the effects of nocturnally administered 25 mg amitriptyline, compared to placebo, after single (Day 1, acute effects) and repeated (Day 15, subchronic effects) administration on driving performance in neuropathic pain patients. In addition to the on-the-road driving test, laboratory tests measuring driving-related skills were administered. Moreover, effects of amitriptlyine on an attentional capacity task were tested using Event-Related Potentials (ERPs). It was hypothesized that nocturnally administered 25 mg amitriptyline might affect driving performance negatively after acute, but not after subchronic treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amitriptyline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amitriptyline, perphenazine drug combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age, amitriptyline responder, adequately treated with amitriptyline in studied dose before study participation, pain intensity score (VAS) of at least 4 cm on a 10 cm scale, driving licence, driving experience, speak fluently Dutch, normal vision, righthanded psychological or physical disorder other than pain(related), other psychotropic medication use, excessive drinking or smoking, alcohol or drug dependence, illigal drug use</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2005</verification_date>
	<keyword>neuropathic pain</keyword>
	<keyword>erp</keyword>
	<keyword>driving</keyword>
	<keyword>attention</keyword>
	<keyword>amitriptyline</keyword>
</DOC>