<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02156934</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study was designed to provide confirmation of efficacy of muscle derived stem cells (MDCs) for the treatment of SUI in women.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Paraurethral Transplantation of Autologous Muscle Derived Stem Cells for Treatment of Stress Incontinency</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators will be assessed the 12-month potential efficacy of autologous muscle derived cells as therapy for stress urinary incontinence. A total of 20 women in whom stress urinary incontinence had not improved underwent intra-sphincter injection of low doses 50×106 of autologous muscle derived cells, which will be derived from biopsies of their deltoid muscle. Assessments will be made at 1, 3, 6 and 12 months after cell injection. Changes in stress urinary incontinence severity were evaluated by pad test, diary of incontinence episodes and quality of life surveys.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Female Stress Urinary Incontinence symptoms Urodynamic stress incontinence confirmed with multichannel urodynamic testing positive cough stress test urgency score &lt; stress score Patient's age between 40 65 years Desire to surgical correction of stress urinary incontinence or inadequate response to conservative treatment of SUI Postvoid residual volume &gt;100cc Detrusor overactivity on preoperative multichannel urodynamic testing History of previous synthetic, biologic or fascial suburethral sling or any other surgery on external genitalia, bladder neck, bladder or urethra Desires future childbearing Chronic inguinal or vulvar abscess or history of Hidradenitis Suppurative History of bleeding diathesis or current anticoagulation therapy Inguinal lymphadenopathy or inguinal/vulvar mass Current genitourinary fistula or urethral diverticulum Current sever cystocele or rectocele Active urinary infection Nontreated urge incontinency or any significant voiding dysfunction Neuromuscular disorders Uncontrolled Diabetes Reversible cause of incontinence (i.e. drug effect) Contraindications for surgery</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>autologous stress urinary incontinence muscle derived cells</keyword>
</DOC>