<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02156401</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Venous thromboembolism (VTE) with its two clinical manifestations deep vein thrombosis (DVT) and pulmonary embolism (PE) is a life-threatening disease that is associated with considerable morbidity and mortality. The incidence of VTE increases with age and it - as the third most common cardiovascular disease after ischemic heart disease and stroke - represents an important public health problem in industrialized countries with several aspects in need to be addressed. VTEval Project includes three long-term prospective observational studies to evaluate and improve VTE diagnostics and management, treatment and outcome. The aims of the project include a systematic assessment of VTE, i.e. disease status (symptoms, clinical and subclinical aspects) and risk profiles (classic, psychosocial and environmental factors), using a system-oriented approach. VTEval collects three large prospective cohorts of patients with suspected and incident VTE consisting of individuals with a clinical suspicion of acute PE, individuals with a clinical suspicion of acute DVT, and individuals with incidental diagnosis of VTE). The standardized and harmonized data acquisition of the study establishes a sustainable resource for comprehensive research on VTE, thus providing the basis for both short- and long-term analysis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>VTEval Project - Prospective Cohort Studies to Evaluate and Improve Diagnostics, Management Strategies and Risk Stratification in VTE</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Embolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Embolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥18 years and Informed written consent Clinical condition: Cohort 1: Clinical suspicion of acute PE (with or without DVT) Cohort 2: Clinical suspicion of acute DVT (without symptomatic PE) Cohort 3: Incidentally diagnosed VTE</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Venous thromboembolism</keyword>
	<keyword>Deep vein thrombosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulmonary embolism</keyword>
	<keyword>Cohort study/epidemiology</keyword>
	<keyword>Outcome</keyword>
	<keyword>Prognosis</keyword>
</DOC>