<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02156271</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to help scientist better understand the effect of a 12-week single daily evening dose of ramelteon (Rozerem ©), a drug that has been approved by the U. S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for the treatment of insomnia (trouble falling asleep or staying asleep). The study will measure levels of inflammation, fasting insulin and fasting glucose (sugar) in subjects who are taking either ramelteon (8 mg) or placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mechanisms of Sleep Latency and Health: The Effect of a Melatonin Receptor Agonist in Inflammation and Insulin Resistance</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Melatonin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At screening visit: aged 1865 nonsmokers for women: oral contraceptive (OC) or hormone replacement therapy (HRT) nonusers To schedule the baseline PSG (Visit 2), subjects must meet the following inclusion criteria: ages 1865 inclusive; PSQIComponent 2 (sleep latency) score of greater than 1; nonsmoker (e.g., less than 20 cigarettes in the past 5 years); habitual bedtime between 8:30 pm and midnight For premenopausal women: regular menstrual cycles determined by Framingham Study criteria; not pregnant and no history of oral contraceptive (OC) usage in last 6months. For postmenopausal women: no recent (&lt; 6 months) use of Hormone Replacement Therapy (HRT) no surgical menopause positive urine drug screen Potential subjects with hypersensitivity to ramelteon or any components of the formulation will be excluded from participation. Given that ramelteon should not be used by individuals with severe hepatic impairment, or in patients in combination with fluvoxamine, individuals who report liver problem or use of fluvox will be excluded. use of rifampin (Rifadin ©); ketoconazole (Nizora ©l); or fluconazole (Diflucan ©). Ramelteon has not been studied in children or adolescents, and the effects in these populations are unknown, thus only individuals above 18 years will participate.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Insomnia</keyword>
</DOC>