<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00378495</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Miltefosine will be administered to Brazilian patients with kala azar</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Miltefosine for Brazilian Visceral Leishmaniasis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Miltefosine will be administered to Brazilian patients with kala azar. Both pediatric and adult patients will be studied. Patients will be followed for 6 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leishmaniasis, Visceral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leishmaniasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Miltefosine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Newly diagnosed (untreated) visceral leishmaniasis with symptomatic disease and visualization of amastigotes in tissue samples or a positive culture. Age: Group 1: 2 to 12 years; Group 2: 13 to 60 years Sex: male and female patients eligible (no effort to be made to balance the study for gender) Exclusion criteria Safety concerns: Thrombocyte count &lt;30 x 109/l; Leukocyte count &lt;1 x 109/l; Hemoglobin &lt;5 g/100 ml; ASAT, ALAT, AP &gt;3 times upper limit of normal range; Serum creatinine or BUN &gt;1.5 times upper limit of normal range; Evidence of serious underlying disease (cardiac, renal, hepatic or pulmonary); Immunodeficiency or antibody to HIV; Severe protein and/or caloric malnutrition (Kwashiorkor, Marasmus); Any noncompensated or uncontrolled condition; Lactation, pregnancy (to be determined by adequate test) or inadequate contraception in females of childbearing potential for treatment period plus 2 months. Lack of suitability for the trial: Negative bone marrow aspirate (smear); Any history of prior antileishmania therapy; Any condition which compromises ability to comply with the study procedures; Concomitant serious infection other than visceral leishmaniasis (this would include evidence of other conditions associated with splenomegaly such as schistosomiasis or malaria). Administrative reasons: Lack of ability or willingness to give informed consent (patient and/or parent / legal representative); Anticipated nonavailability for study visits/procedures.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>miltefosine</keyword>
	<keyword>kala azar</keyword>
	<keyword>Brazil</keyword>
</DOC>