<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00378599</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an exploratory study and is a Phase 3, single-arm, multi-center, open-label study of pegylated interferon alfa-2b, PEG-IFN alpha-2b (PEG-Intron) and ribavirin (RBV) to determine the sustained virologic response (SVR) at 24-week follow-up to 48 week in subjects after orthotopic liver transplantation (OLT) with chronic hepatitis C (HCV) recurrence.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Pegylated Interferon Alfa-2b and Ribavirin After Orthotopic Liver Transplantation in Subjects With Chronic Hepatitis C Recurrence (P04590AM3)(COMPLETED)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must confirm that all prior medication washout times have been observed. Subject must be 18 70 years of age of either gender and of any race. Subject must be transplanted for endstage hepatitis C or fulminant hepatitis C. Subject must have documented: persistent HCV viremia after OLT as defined by plasma positive for HCV RNA by quantitative reverse transcriptionpolymerase chain reaction (RTPCR), A liver transplant performed at least 3 months prior to screening but not more than 3 years prior to screening. Subject must be on stable doses of immunosuppression for at least 1 month. Compensated liver disease with minimum hematologic, biochemical, and serologic criteria at the (Day 1) baseline visit. Alphafetoprotein value (AFP) less than or equal to 250ng/mL. If AFP greater than 100 ng/mL, patient will need evidence of normal liver (magnetic resonance imaging) MRI and normal chest computerized tomography (CT) scan within the last 3 months or during the screening period. For subjects with a history of diabetes or hypertension, clearance from an ophthalmologist has to be obtained prior to treatment start (Day 1/Visit 2). Subjects with a history of mild depression may be considered for entry into this study. Female subjects cannot be pregnant or breastfeeding and must be either postmenopausal, surgically sterile or using 2 methods of birth control. Sexually active male subjects are practicing an acceptable, method of contraception. Contraceptive measures will be reviewed with female subjects at each visit. Dual methods of contraception must be used for 1 month prior to the start of treatment and 6 months after treatment discontinuation. Pregnancy tests obtained at Screen Visit and Day 1 Visit prior to the initiation of treatment must be negative. Pregnant women, women who plan to become pregnant, male subjects whose partner wants to become pregnant, and breastfeeding women (during study and up to 6 months after study completion). Subject has used any investigational product within 30 days prior to Screening or is participating in any other clinical study. Prior treatment for chronic hepatitis C postliver transplant, including but not limited to antiviral or immunomodulatory product, any interferon product, or RBV, either as monotherapy or in combination. Subjects with other organ transplants. Any subject who received a positive hepatitis C core antibody (HBcAb) or HCV positive donor liver graft. Retransplantation of the liver for rejection or graft failure. Evidence of decompensated liver disease. Known coagulopathies including hemophilia. Known hemoglobinopathies. Known glucose6phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency. Hypersensitivity to alpha interferon and/or RBV. Coinfection with hepatitis B virus (HBV) and/or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). Evidence of active or suspected malignancy or a history of malignancy within the last 5 years (with the exception of pretransplant hepatocellular carcinoma histologically within the Milan criteria, and adequately treated basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin). Any known preexisting medical condition that could interfere with the subject's participation in and completion of the study. Subject is or was a substance abuser. Subjects treated with buprenorphine (Subutex) who have been stable for 6 months may be included. Patients weighing over 135 kg; Is participating in any other clinical study(ies); Is allergic to or has sensitivity to the study drug or its excipients.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>