<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01804790</DOC>
	<brief_summary>National, multi-center, open-label,randomized, 2-arm phase III superiority trial, comparing neoadjuvant chemotherapy (CT) with mFolfirinox followed by preoperative chemoradiotherapy (CRT), versus preoperative CRT in patients with locally advanced rectal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase III Study Comparing Preoperative Chemoradiotherapy Alone Versus Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy With Folfirinox Regimen Followed by Preoperative Chemoradiotherapy for Patients With Resectable Locally Advanced Rectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Methodology This is a biomedical research, national, multicenter, open-label randomized, 2-arm phase III superiority trial, comparing neoadjuvant CT with mFolfirinox then preoperative CRT, versus immediate preoperative CRT, in patients with locally advanced rectal cancer Randomized Phase III study with stopping rules Stratification : center, gender, tumor location in the rectum (&lt; 6 cm from anal verge versus ≥ 6 cm), initial stage (cT3 vs cT4, and cN0 vs cN+)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leucovorin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histogically proven rectal adenocarcinoma Stages cT3 with risk of local recurrence or cT4, M0 and for which a multidisciplinary meeting recommend preoperative CRT Resectable tumor, or considered as potentially resectable after CRT No distant metastases Patient eligible for surgery Patient aged from 18 to 75 years WHO/ECOG performance status 0/2. No heart failure or coronary heart disease symptoms (even controlled). No peripheral neuropathy &gt; grade 1 No prior radiotherapy of the pelvis for any reason and no previous CT No major comorbidity that may preclude the delivery of treatment and no active infection (HIV or chronic hepatitis B or C). Adequate contraception in fertile patients. Adequate hematologic function Adequate hepatic function Signed written informed consent Metastatic disease Unresectable rectal cancer, including prostatic involvement or extension to pelvic floor muscles Contraindication to 5FU, or to oxaliplatin or to irinotecan, including Gilbert disease or genotype UGT1A1 Medical history of chronic diarrhea or inflammatory disease of the colon or rectum Medical history of angina pectoris or myocardial infarction Progressive active infection or any other severe medical condition that could jeopardize treatment administration Other concomitant cancer, or medical history of cancer other than treated in situ cervical carcinoma or basocellular carcinoma or spinocellular carcinoma Patient included in another clinical trial testing an investigational agent. Pregnant or breastfeeding woman. Persons deprived of liberty or under guardianship or incapable of giving consent Any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially hampering compliance with the study protocol or followup schedule.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>rectum</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>locally advanced</keyword>
</DOC>