<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01804400</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess the safety and efficacy of QAW039 alone and in combination with Montelukast in patients with allergic rhinitis (hay fever) using an environmental exposure chamber.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Trial to Test How Well Two Drugs, QAW039 and Montelukast Work Both Individually and Together, to Target Allergic Rhinitis Using an Environmental Exposure Chamber</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Montelukast</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female aged 1865 years inclusive, with a clinical history of intermittent allergic rhinitis with seasonal onset and offset of nasal allergy symptoms during each of the last two grass pollen allergy seasons. A positive skin prick test at Visit 1 to dactylis glomerata with a wheal diameter equal to or greater than 3 mm and a negative control with a wheal diameter of zero. A positive skin prick test within 12 months prior to Visit 1 is also acceptable. FEV1 measured by spirometry must be ≥80% of their predicted value at screening. If the patient does not achieve ≥80% of their predicted value this may be repeated prior to the EEC challenge at visit 2. TNSS score ≥6 on at least one assessment during the 2h EEC challenge at Screening. Use of other investigational drugs at the time of enrollment, or within 30 days or 5 halflives of enrollment, whichever is longer; or longer if required by local regulations, and for any other limitation of participation in an investigational trial based on local regulations. Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women, Women of childbearing potential, defined as all women physiologically capable of becoming pregnant, unless they are using effective methods of contraception during dosing of study treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>