<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01804959</DOC>
	<brief_summary>SSc-associated gastrointestinal (GI) involvement is common, with no effective treatment. Probiotics may have beneficial effects on symptoms as supported by one small open-label study (n=10) that demonstrated decreased bloating symptoms in SSc patients after 2 months of probiotics. This study aims to determine (i) whether 60 days of VSL#3 probiotics result in greater GI symptom improvement than placebo in SSc outpatients, assessed using an interview-administered 34-item Gastrointestinal Tract (GIT) questionnaire and (ii) whether 60 days versus 120 days of probiotics result in greater GI symptom improvement in SSc outpatients, assessed using the GIT questionnaire.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trial of Probiotics in Systemic Sclerosis Associated Gastrointestinal Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Scleroderma, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Scleroderma, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Digestive System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>SSc that fulfills the American College of Rheumatology (ACR, 1990) classification criteria or the proposed European League Against Rheumatism (EULAR) criteria for very early diagnosis of systemic sclerosis. SSc overlap syndromes (ie SSc occurring in overlap with other connective tissue diseases) SScassociated GI symptoms (heartburn, dysphagia, vomiting, bloating/distension, faecal soilage, diarrhoea, constipation) not due to other causes as determined by clinical evaluation, with a total GIT score of at least 0.10 Stable doses of immunosuppressive treatment, corticosteroids, and GI medications for 30 days. On antibiotics or probiotics within the last 30 days Current serious infections requiring hospitalization Longterm indwelling catheter, including patients on total parenteral nutrition Females who are lactating or pregnant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>