<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03090113</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized, double blind, placebo-controlled, parallel, multicenter research in order to evaluate the effect of Shuxuetong injection in prevention of symptomatic or asymptomatic new cerebral infarction within 10 days. Subgroup study：Evaluate the role of advanced diagnostic technique in identifying potential causes of Embolic Stroke of Undetermined Source (ESUS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Shuxuetong for Prevention of Recurrence in Acute Cerebrovascular Events With Embolism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Shuxuetong injection or Placebo injection for 10days. About 2416 patients randomized at 80 centers all over China with 20 subgroup study centers. Face to face interview at baseline, 10 days, and 90 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Embolism</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria 1. More than or equal to 18 years old and less than 80 years old; 2. Acute ischemic stroke, brain magnetic resonance imaging showed non lacunar infarction (subcortical infarction less than or equal to 1.5 cm); 3. Firstever stroke; 4. Onset within 72 hours; 5. Patients or their family members are willing to sign the informed consent. Exclusion criteria 1. Intracranial hemorrhage: cerebral hemorrhage, subarachnoid hemorrhage, etc.; 2. Transient ischemic attack; 3. Lacunar infarction; 4. Clear diagnosis of other causes of ischemic stroke (arterial dissection, arteritis, vasospasm, etc.); 5. ASPECTS less than or equal to 7 or posterior circulation ASPECTS less than or equal to 7； 6. modify Rankin Scale (mRS) more than or equal to 2 before stroke; 7. Cumulative usage of traditional Chinese medicine which activating blood circulation more than 3 times after onsite, including but not limited to: Danhong, Xueshuantong, Xuesaitong, Ginkgo biloba, sodium ozagrel, Salvia miltiorrhiza, ligustrazine, Erigeron breviscapus, etc; 8. Chronic liver disease, liver and kidney dysfunction, lifted alanine aminotransferase (3 times greater than the ULN), lifted serum creatinine (2 times greater than the ULN); 9. History of Coagulopathy, systemic bleeding, thrombocytopenia or neutropenia; 10. Blood pressure less than or equal to 90/60 mmHg or blood pressure more than or equal to 220/120 mmHg after treatment; 11. Serious heart or lung disease, researchers deemed not suitable for the study; 12. Patients with atrial fibrillation who were scheduled or likely to receive anticoagulant therapy with unfractionated heparin or low molecular weight heparin within 2 weeks after randomization 13. Life expectancy less than 3 months or cannot fulfill study for other reasons; 14. Known allergies for ingredients of the drug, allergy history for food or drug; 15. Women of childbearing age who had negative Pregnancy test result but refuse to take effective contraceptive measures, pregnant women or lactating women; 16. Joined other clinical studies in the last 30 days; 17. Unable to understand and/or comply with the study procedures and/or followup studies due to mental illness, cognitive or emotional disorders. Subgroup Exclusion Criteria 1. History of atrial fibrillation 2. Atrial fibrillation in 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG); 3. Heart rate monitoring (dynamic electrocardiogram telemetry) up to 20 hours or more detected atrial fibrillation for 6 minutes or more; 4. Intracardiac thrombosis in thoracic or esophageal echocardiography; 5. Occlusion or proximal vessel infarction for more than 50%.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Embolic Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Shuxuetong</keyword>
	<keyword>Recurrence</keyword>
	<keyword>Symptomatic New Cerebral Infarction</keyword>
	<keyword>Asymptomatic New Cerebral Infarction</keyword>
</DOC>