<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00031642</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Monoclonal antibodies such as rituximab can locate cancer cells and deliver cancer-killing substances to them without harming normal cells. Radiolabeled monoclonal antibodies can locate and deliver radioactive cancer-killing substances. PURPOSE: Phase I/II trial to study the effectiveness of combining radiolabeled monoclonal antibodies with rituximab in treating patients who have non-Hodgkin's lymphoma that has not responded to high-dose chemotherapy and autologous stem cell transplantation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Monoclonal Antibody Therapy in Treating Patients With Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma That Has Relapsed After High-Dose Chemotherapy and Autologous Stem Cell Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the maximum tolerated dose of yttrium Y 90-labeled ibritumomab tiuxetan when administered with rituximab in patients with B-cell non-Hodgkin's lymphoma who have relapsed after high-dose chemotherapy and autologous hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. - Determine the safety and efficacy of this regimen in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study of yttrium Y 90-labeled ibritumomab tiuxetan (IDEC-Y2B8). - Phase I: Patients receive rituximab IV over 4-6 hours followed by indium In 111-labeled ibritumomab tiuxetan (IDEC-In2B8) IV over 10 minutes on day 0. Patients receive rituximab IV again on day 7 followed by IDEC-Y2B8 IV over 10 minutes. Cohorts of 3-6 patients receive escalating doses of IDEC-Y2B8 until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose at which 3 of 6 patients experience dose-limiting toxicity. - Phase II: Once the MTD is determined, 58 additional patients are treated at that dose level as in phase I. Patients are followed at 6 weeks, every 3 months for 1 year, every 6 months for 2 years, and then annually thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: Approximately 78 patients (20 for phase I and 58 for phase II) will be accrued for this study within 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of relapsed Bcell nonHodgkin's lymphoma (NHL) after highdose chemotherapy and autologous stem cell transplantation Less than 25% bone marrow involvement with NHL as evidenced by unilateral or bilateral biopsy within the past 6 weeks Bone marrow biopsy should demonstrate 1520% of cellular space occupied by normal hematopoiesis CD20 antigen expression in tumor tissue within the past year as evidenced by 1 of the following: Immunoperoxidase stains of tissue showing positive reactivity with L26 antibody Flow cytometry studies Measurable disease More than 2 cm bidimensionally No active CNS lymphoma No HIV or AIDSrelated lymphoma PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 19 and over Performance status: WHO 02 Life expectancy: At least 3 months Hematopoietic: Absolute neutrophil count greater than 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count greater than 150,000/mm^3 No transfusion dependency Hepatic: Bilirubin less than 2.0 mg/dL SGOT or SGPT no greater than 2.5 times upper limit of normal (unless due to lymphomatous infiltration of the liver) Renal: Creatinine less than 2.0 mg/dL No active obstructive hydronephrosis Other: Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 6 months after study therapy HIV negative No active infection requiring oral or IV antibiotics No human antimurine antibody positivity No other major medical problems PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: See Disease Characteristics At least 4 weeks since prior growth factors At least 4 weeks since prior biologic therapy No dependency on hematopoietic growth factors (e.g., epoetin alfa, interleukin11, filgrastim [GCSF], or sargramostim [GMCSF]) No prior radioimmunotherapy No other concurrent biologic therapy of any kind Chemotherapy: See Disease Characteristics At least 4 weeks since any prior cytotoxic chemotherapy (6 weeks for nitrosoureas) No prior fludarabine No concurrent chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: No concurrent steroids except as maintenance for noncancerous disease Radiotherapy: See Biologic therapy At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy No prior pelvic radiotherapy No prior radiotherapy to more than 25% of estimated bone marrow reserve No concurrent external beam radiotherapy Surgery: Not specified Other: Recovered from all prior therapy At least 4 weeks since prior immunosuppressants No other concurrent investigational drugs No other concurrent anticancer therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 1 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 2 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent grade 3 follicular lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult diffuse small cleaved cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult diffuse mixed cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult immunoblastic large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult Burkitt lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent mantle cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent small lymphocytic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>extranodal marginal zone B-cell lymphoma of mucosa-associated lymphoid tissue</keyword>
	<keyword>nodal marginal zone B-cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>splenic marginal zone lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>