<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01288300</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Main objective: To improve diabetes outcomes among Mexican-Americans with diabetes through church-based, culturally tailored, diabetes self-management interventions linked to the local healthcare system. Specific Aim: To pilot test a church-based, culturally tailored diabetes self-management intervention to improve diabetes outcomes among low-income Mexican-American with diabetes H1 A church-based diabetes self-care management curriculum partnered with the local healthcare system will improve glycosylated hemoglobin. H2 A church-based diabetes self-care management curriculum partnered with the local healthcare system will improve systolic blood pressure and low-density lipids. H3 A church-based diabetes self-care management curriculum partnered with the local healthcare system will improve diabetes related self-efficacy, self-empowerment and self-care management.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Health and Faith (Salud y Fe): Community-Based Diabetes Pilot Intervention</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Diabetes is a very prevalent and morbid condition affecting Latinos, especially Mexican-Americans in the United States. South Lawndale, a predominately-Mexican neighborhood of Chicago, has a disproportionately high diabetes related mortality rate in comparison to the rest of Chicago and the U.S. Many church-based interventions have shown promise improving health outcomes among minority populations; but data on church-based interventions for Latino populations is scarce. Mobilizing community resources to develop church-based, diabetes self-management interventions may lead to sustainable, culturally tailored interventions, and improve outcomes in Latinos with diabetes. Considering the growth of the Hispanic population and their disproportionate burden of chronic diseases, developing programming aimed at decreasing the health disparities in this population is crucial. Our study proposes to fill this gap.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>over the age of 18 able to speak either English or Spanish selfreport of diagnosis of diabetes by a doctor cannot give informed consent (e.g. due to intoxication or dementia) do not speak English or Spanish younger than 18 years old. pregnant women undergoing hemodialysis or treatment for cancer unable to attend 3 and 6month follow up appointments</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>