<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02005302</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Multi-center, prospective, randomized, controlled study to verify the clinical effectiveness of K / DOQI guidelines. The efficiency and safety of Vitamin D2 and low protein diet treatment for prevention and treatment of CKD-MBD and malnutrition in CKD3-5 (ND) patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Optimizing Treatment Programs for Chronic Kidney Disease-mineral and Bone Disorder and Malnutrition</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will enroll chronic kidney disease patients, stage 3 to 5ND, who have chronic kidney disease mineral and bone disease (CKD-MBD) and malnutrition as defined by Kidney Disease Improvement Global Outcome (KDIGO) Guidelines. Patients in five centers will be randomized. A total of 600 patients will be enrolled, 150 patients receiving Vitamin D2 treatment virus 150 patients receiving calcitriol treatment, and another 150 patients receiving low protein diet virus 150 patients receiving normal protein diet. Outcomes will be assessed as proportion of patients achieving target blood levels on calcium, phosphorus, parathyroid hormone, 25 hydroxyvitamin D, albumin and hemoglobin. Other outcomes will also be assessed, which include secondary hyperparathyroidism (sHPT), vascular calcification, cardiovascular diseases, nutritional status and quality of life.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin A</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with age between 1880 years. Patients with chronic kidney disease stage 3 to 5, and concurrent chronic kidney disease mineral and bone disorder and malnutrition Renal artery stenosis, inherent renal malformation, solitary kidney, or malignancy in urinary system. Active system immunity diseases. History of liver failure History of intestinal malabsorption or chronic diarrhea Treatment with phenobarbital, phenytoin, rifampicin, sucralfate, steroids, digoxin, or other medications that could affect vitamin D metabolism Primary hyperparathyroidism Treatment with cinacalcet or other calcimimetic within the past 6 months Anticipated dialysis within 6 months after randomization Have an unstable medical condition, defined as having been hospitalized within 30 days before screening, the expectation of recurrent hospital admissions or life expectancy of less than 6 months in the judgment of the investigator Subject is currently enrolled in, or fewer than 30 days have passed since subject has completed another investigational device or drug study(s); or subject is receiving another investigational agent(s). Current treatment with vitamin D 50,000 IU Using glucocorticoid or immunosuppressive agents. Acute renal dysfunction. The expected live time is less than 2 years. Pregnant or lactating woman. Suffered from acute myocardial infraction, acute congestive heart failure, or stroke in last 6 months. Patients whose concurrent illnesses, disability, or geographical residence would hamper attendance at required study visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>chronic kidney disease</keyword>
	<keyword>mineral and bone disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Malnutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>low protein diet</keyword>
</DOC>