<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00760916</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is an international, multi-center, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study in subjects with PAH who are currently receiving approved therapy for their PAH (i.e., endothelin receptor antagonist and/or phosphodiesterase-5 inhibitor)or as a monotherapy treatment. Study visits will occur at 4 week intervals for 12 weeks with the key measure of efficacy being the 6-minute walk test. Study procedures include routine blood tests, medical history, physical exams, disease evaluation, and exercise tests. At the end of the first 12-weeks, the patient will be un-blinded. Patients will continue with another 12-Week open label portion with visits occuring at 4-week intervals. Patients who complete all assessments for 24-weeks will also be eligible to enter a 36 month open-label, extension phase study (FREEDOM - EXT).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>FREEDOM DR: Oral Treprostinil in Combination With an Endothelin Receptor Antagonist (ERA) and/or a Phosphodiesterase-5 (PDE-5) Inhibitor or as Monotherapy for the Treatment of Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension (PAH)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is an international, multi-center, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study in subjects with PAH who are currently receiving approved therapy for their PAH (i.e., endothelin receptor antagonist and/or phosphodiesterase-5 inhibitor)or as a monotherapy treatment. Study visits will occur at 4 week intervals for 12 weeks with the key measure of efficacy being the 6-minute walk test. Study procedures include routine blood tests, medical history, physical exams, disease evaluation, and exercise tests. At the end of the first 12-weeks, the patient will be un-blinded. Patients will continue with another 12-Week open label portion with visits occuring at 4-week intervals. Patients who complete all assessments for 24-weeks will also be eligible to enter a 36 month open-label, extension phase study (FREEDOM - EXT).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endothelin Receptor Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Treprostinil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phosphodiesterase 5 Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Between 18 and 70 years of age, inclusive Body weight at least 50 kilograms PAH that is either idiopathic/familial; associated with repaired congenital systemictopulmonary shunts (repaired ≥ 5 years); associated with collagen vascular disease; associated with HIV. Currently receiving an approved endothelin receptor antagonist and/or an approved phosphodiesterase5 inhibitor for at least 90 days and on a stable dose for at least the last 30 days or not currently receiving approved PAH therapy. Previous testing (e.g., right heart catheterization, echocardiography) consistent with the diagnosis of PAH. Reliable and cooperative with protocol requirements. Nursing or pregnant. Received a prostacyclin within the past 30 days. PAH due to conditions other than noted in the above inclusion criteria. History of uncontrolled sleep apnea, renal insufficiency, anemia, left sided heart disease, uncontrolled systemic hypertension, or parenchymal lung disease. Use of an investigational drug within 30 days of Baseline</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</keyword>
</DOC>