<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03002857</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The most used airway management strategies are different types of supraglottic airway devices (SAD) for transurethral resection of bladder and ureteroscopy in urological surgery . Classical laryngeal mask airway (LMA-C) and I-Gel SADs are being used already. The aim of this study was to evaluate and compare the performance of a new type of SAD the Baska Mask® with I-gel and LMA-C regarding their insertion times, durations, perioperative complications and effects on hemodynamic parameters, peak airway pressures (Paw) and airway plato pressures in urological surgery as well.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of I-gel LMA, Classical LMA With a New Supraglottic Airway the Baska Mask® in Urological Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The most used airway management strategies are different types of supraglottic airway devices (SAD) for transurethral resection of bladder and ureteroscopy in urological surgery . Classical laryngeal mask airway (LMA-C) and I-Gel SADs are being used already. The aim of this study was to evaluate and compare the performance of a new type of SAD the Baska Mask® with I-gel and LMA-C regarding their insertion times, durations, perioperative complications and effects on hemodynamic parameters, peak airway pressures (Paw) and airway plato pressures in urological surgery as well. The main suggestion about the Baska Mask® is that it's the most appropriate airway device with high Paws. In high Paws, higher air leaks may occur from the sides of cuff and this causes hypoventilation. So the main aim of this study is to evaluate and compare effects of three types -I-gel, ,the Baska Mask® LMA-C- of SADs regarding their effects on Paw, Airway plato pressures, Tidal volume, air leak volumes. The secondary aim was to observe and compare their effects on hemodynamic parameters,insertion times, ease of insertion and perioperative complications.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Polystyrene sulfonic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>(ASA) 123 physical status scheduled for elective surgical procedure for transurethral resection of bladder and ureteroscopy. Under the age of 18, history of hiatus hernia, gastroesophageal reflux, body mass index (BMI) &gt; 30 kg m2, ASA physical status 4 or over and patients who met the difficult intubation criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Laryngeal Mask Airway</keyword>
	<keyword>Urologic Surgical Procedure</keyword>
</DOC>