<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01879072</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this protocol is to establish a cohort of at least 1500 biologic samples collected prospectively from patients treated in BMT CTN centers that will be a shared bio specimen resource for conducting future allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HCT) correlative studies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Cohort for the Evaluation of Biomarkers Following HCT (BMT CTN 1202)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The goal of this protocol is to establish a cohort of biologic samples collected prospectively from patients treated in BMT CTN centers that will be a shared bio specimen resource for conducting future allogeneic HCT correlative studies. This resource is designed to allow genomic, proteomic and transcriptional data to be integrated with high quality clinical phenotype and outcomes data to identify risk factors for development and severity of acute GVHD, chronic GVHD, organ toxicity, relapse, mortality, infection and other clinically significant complications occurring after allogeneic HCT. To achieve this goal, patients and donors will be recruited and consent obtained at the time that they enroll on BMT CTN protocols where enrollment occurs at or before transplantation or prior to start of conditioning for patients enrolled on non-BMT CTN studies or treated as standard of care. Samples will be collected: (1) from patients and donors pre-transplant; and, (2) from patients post-transplant on a calendar schedule through the first 3 months post-HCT. For patients co-enrolled on BMT CTN studies, clinical data will be collected in the context of the primary transplant protocols. For patients not enrolled on BMT CTN protocols, clinical data on early post-transplant events will be collected using the same data collection forms and systems that are used on BMT CTN trials. Additional clinical data for both BMT CTN and non-BMT CTN patients will be available from data submitted to the Center for International Blood and Marrow Transplant Research (CIBMTR) using the CIBMTR Comprehensive Report Forms. This protocol also leverages ongoing pre-transplant donor-recipient sample collection performed by the CIBMTR and National Marrow Donor Program (NMDP). Success in establishing this shared resource will inspire future investigator initiated research proposals and will allow investigators to take advantage of National Institutes of Health (NIH) funding initiatives.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Recipients of first allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplants that are transplanted in U.S. centers that participate in the NMDP/CIBMTR's "Protocol for a Research Sample Repository for Allogeneic Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation and Marrow Toxic Injuries" and receive a cord blood graft or receive a bone marrow or peripheral blood graft from a related donor or from an unrelated donor in an NMDPaffiliated Donor Center or Registry participating in that same protocol. This transplant and donor center restriction is to allow linkage with pretransplant donor specimens collected under the NMDP/CIBMTR protocol. Current data indicate that &gt;90% of donors approached under this protocol agree to provide samples 2. Patients with any malignant or nonmalignant hematologic disorder will be eligible for enrollment on this protocol. A subset of 240 sequential patients with acute leukemia in first or second remission will also provide research samples for gene expression studies. 3. Children may participate in this study but must weigh at least 20 kilograms given the volume (100ml) and number of blood draws during this study. Subjects must weigh at least 30 kg to provide research samples for gene expression studies (additional 40 ml). 4. All participants or parent/legal guardian must sign an informed consent for this study. Because studies using this resource will require linking with clinical data collected by CIBMTR, all participants or parent/legal guardian must also consent to participate in "Protocol for a Research Database for Hematopoietic Cell Transplantation and Marrow Toxic Injuries".</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
	<keyword>Hematopoietic stem cell transplant</keyword>
</DOC>