<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00900302</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Studying protein expression in sentinel lymph node tissue from patients with cancer in the laboratory may help doctors identify and learn more about biomarkers related to cancer. It may also help the study of cancer in the future. PURPOSE: This laboratory study is evaluating OX-40 protein expression in the sentinel lymph nodes of patients with cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>OX-40 Protein Expression in the Sentinel Lymph Nodes of Patients With Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the qualitative and quantitative expression of OX-40 and related markers in sentinel lymph nodes previously removed from patients with cancer. - Determine the qualitative and quantitative expression of OX-40 and related markers in sentinel lymph nodes freshly removed from patients with cancer. - Correlate the expression of OX-40 and related markers in sentinel lymph node tissue with expression in nonsentinel tissue from primary tumors and nonsentinel lymph nodes, tumor stage, and patient outcomes. OUTLINE: Sections of primary tumors, nonsentinel lymph nodes, and sentinel lymph nodes will be analyzed for expression of OX-40 by immunohistochemistry. Sections of negative (no tumor metastases) lymph nodes will be used as internal controls. Fresh tissue and blood will be tested for marker analysis and in vitro assays of immune function. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 100 specimens from sentinel lymph nodes previously removed from cancer patients and 100 specimens from sentinel lymph nodes freshly removed from cancer patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed cancer, including, but not limited to, the following: Melanoma Breast cancer Invasive squamous cell cancer Other cancers for which patients underwent or will undergo the following: Adequate archived paraffinembedded tissue for making slides for immunostaining Adequate freshly removed sentinel lymph node (and primary tumor, if available) tissue for laboratory assays Clinical data and date of last followup on tumor stage and status must be available Hormone receptor status not specified PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Not specified PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>male breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IA breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IB breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIA breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIB breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIC breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>unspecified adult solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
	<keyword>unspecified childhood solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell carcinoma of the anus</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell carcinoma of the bladder</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell carcinoma of the esophagus</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell carcinoma of the gallbladder</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell carcinoma of the skin</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell carcinoma of the vulva</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>vaginal squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I verrucous carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II verrucous carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III verrucous carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV verrucous carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent verrucous carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I verrucous carcinoma of the oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II verrucous carcinoma of the oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III verrucous carcinoma of the oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV verrucous carcinoma of the oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent verrucous carcinoma of the oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic squamous neck cancer with occult primary squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent metastatic squamous neck cancer with occult primary</keyword>
	<keyword>untreated metastatic squamous neck cancer with occult primary</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I squamous cell carcinoma of the paranasal sinus and nasal cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II squamous cell carcinoma of the paranasal sinus and nasal cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the paranasal sinus and nasal cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the paranasal sinus and nasal cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the paranasal sinus and nasal cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>salivary gland squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I salivary gland cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II salivary gland cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III salivary gland cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV salivary gland cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent salivary gland cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell carcinoma of unknown primary</keyword>
	<keyword>cervical squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>penile squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent anal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I anal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II anal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIA anal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIB anal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV anal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent esophageal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I esophageal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II esophageal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III esophageal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV esophageal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>localized gallbladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent gallbladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>unresectable gallbladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent vulvar cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I vulvar cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II vulvar cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III vulvar cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV vulvar cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IA cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IB cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIA cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIB cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IVA cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IVB cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIB non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent skin cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>newly diagnosed carcinoma of unknown primary</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent carcinoma of unknown primary</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent penile cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I penile cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II penile cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III penile cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV penile cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IA melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IB melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIA melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIB melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIC melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIA melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIB melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIIC melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV melanoma</keyword>
</DOC>