<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00900380</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Studying samples of tissue from patients with cancer in the laboratory may help doctors learn more about cancer and the development of drug resistance in patients. PURPOSE: This laboratory study is examining tissue samples from patients with acute myeloid leukemia to learn more about drug resistance in these patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Studying Tissue Samples to Learn More About Drug Resistance in Patients With Acute Myeloid Leukemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Ascertain whether assessments of P-glycoprotein (P-gp) status using the accumulation assay find greater than 10% positive specimens among 30 specimens (collected from patients with acute myeloid leukemia enrolled on clinical trial ECOG-E3999) found to be negative using only the efflux assay. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Cryopreserved bone marrow specimens are examined for P-glycoprotein (P-gp) by the accumulation assay and the efflux assay using DiOC_2 dye. Flow cytometry is used for measuring activity in both assays. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 40 specimens will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Cryopreserved bone marrow specimens collected from patients with acute myeloid leukemia enrolled on clinical trial ECOGE3999 meeting the following criteria: Appreciable levels of either CD34+ OR CD117+ blasts Appreciable staining with antiPgp antibodies 30 specimens must exhibit low to moderate dye loading for the Rh123 efflux assay 10 specimens must exhibit positive Rh123 efflux activities PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Not specified PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult acute monocytic leukemia (M5b)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute megakaryoblastic leukemia (M7)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloblastic leukemia with maturation (M2)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloblastic leukemia without maturation (M1)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myelomonocytic leukemia (M4)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute monoblastic leukemia (M5a)</keyword>
	<keyword>secondary acute myeloid leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>untreated adult acute myeloid leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute minimally differentiated myeloid leukemia (M0)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with 11q23 (MLL) abnormalities</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with inv(16)(p13;q22)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with t(16;16)(p13;q22)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult acute myeloid leukemia with t(8;21)(q22;q22)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult erythroleukemia (M6a)</keyword>
	<keyword>adult pure erythroid leukemia (M6b)</keyword>
</DOC>