<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01650714</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The proposed study will assess the efficacy and safety of the innovative endoscopic technique for the acquisition of full thickness gastric muscle wall biopsies. Having access to full thickness biopsies will allow an increased understanding of the pathophysiology of gastrointestinal diseases such as functional gastrointestinal disorders, gastroparesis, pseudoobstruction and other motility disorders. This information is essential to development of more targeted and effective therapy than currently available. Despite the high prevalence of functional gastrointestinal disorders and its significant impact on social and health care costs, the underlying cause is not well understood and there is no effective specific treatment to successfully alleviate patient symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Endoscopic Full Thickness Biopsy, Gastric Wall.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Our group has studied a new endoscopic method using a submucosal endoscopy with mucosal flap (SEMF) technique to acquire full thickness gastric tissues successfully and safely in preclinical studies. The proposed study will assess the efficacy and safety of the innovative endoscopic technique for the acquisition of full thickness gastric muscle wall biopsies. Having access to full thickness biopsies will allow an increased understanding of the pathophysiology of gastrointestinal diseases such as functional gastrointestinal disorders, gastroparesis, pseudoobstruction and other motility disorders. This information is essential to development of more targeted and effective therapy than currently available. Despite the high prevalence of functional gastrointestinal disorders and its significant impact on social and health care costs, the underlying cause is not well understood and there is no effective specific treatment to successfully alleviate patient symptoms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Gastroparesis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Symptomatic refractory idiopathic gastroparesis: 1. The refractory nature of symptoms (e.g. based on nutritional failure, consideration for enteral or parenteral nutrition) will be determined by the physician/gastroenterologist who is the primary care provider for the patient's gastroparesis. 2. Patients will have documentation within the last 2 years of delayed gastric emptying with &gt;30% retained gastric contents at 4 hours based on 296 kcal solidliquid, fatcontaining standard meal gastric emptying test. 3. The patient's physician will determine if this procedure may potentially provide prognostic and therapeutic options. 2. Age &gt; 18 and &lt; 70 years old 3. Hemoglobin (Hb) &gt; 10g, platelets &gt;150,000 and prothrombin time international normalized ratio (INR) &lt;1.5 4. Ability to give informed consent 1. Prior oropharyngeal, esophageal, gastric or small bowel surgery 2. Esophageal stricture 3. Prior abdominal radiation therapy 4. Prior feeding tube placement 5. Coagulopathy 6. Use of Coumadin or antiplatelet drugs e.g. Plavix, steroids or immunosuppressive drugs 7. Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>