<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00572767</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to evaluate the effect of Dextro-amphetamin added to physiotherapy on motor recovery in patients after stroke. The study is a double-blinded placebo-controlled randomised controlled trial. Patients after a first-ever ischemic stroke will receive Dexamphetamine (10mg) twice per week for a duration of five weeks after a baseline phase of two weeks. The outcome measure focuses on motor recovery and will be assessed: - one and two weeks before study intervention (baseline phase) - five times during the study intervention - one week after study intervention (follow-up) - once after six and twelve months after start of the study intervention (follow-up).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Effect of Dextro-Amphetamin Added to Physiotherapy in Patients After Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amphetamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients after firstever ischemic stroke with a clinical relevant paresis of the upper and lower limb (general clinical muscle testing below level four) correlation of clinical symptoms with a brain imaging (CT or MRI) able to communicate with the neurological examiner and understand the aim/matter of the study (with or without aphasia) start of the first oral application of the study drug between the fourteenth and 60th day after stroke onset older than 13 years given written informed consent (or two independent witnesses) intracranial or (chronic) subdural hemorrhages any additional neurological or psychiatric illnesses instable arrythmia not controlled or treated arterial hypertension ensured cardioembolic event anxiolytica, neuroleptica, or alphaadrenergic antagonists or agonists respectively certain anticonvulsiva or antihypertonica manifest hyperthyreosis dementia or terminal illnesses epilepsy, phaeochromocytoma or glaucoma women known to be pregnant or lactating</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>randomised-controlled trial</keyword>
	<keyword>ischemic stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>motor recovery</keyword>
	<keyword>amphetamine</keyword>
	<keyword>motor recovery of patients after a first-ever ischemic stroke</keyword>
</DOC>