<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03074643</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the effects of diet composition (i.e., amount of protein and carbohydrate) during a 6-month weight loss intervention and 12-months of follow-up on physical function, muscle mass, and weight loss maintenance in obese older adults. Participants will receive either a protein or carbohydrate supplement along with a behavioral weight loss intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Utilizing Protein During Weight Loss to Impact Physical Function</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will use a 3-group design in 225 obese (BMI 30-45 kg/m2), older (65-79 years) men and women at risk for disability (SPPB ≤10) who will undergo a 6-month weight loss intervention followed by a 12-month follow-up phase to test the overall hypothesis that a higher protein (1.2 g/kg body wt/d) / lower carbohydrate (CHO) diet during a 6-month weight loss intervention improves physical function compared with an isocaloric lower protein (the current Recommended Dietary Allowance (RDA), 0.8 g/kg body wt/d) / higher CHO diet, and whether continuing a higher protein / lower CHO diet for 12-months following weight loss will result in better maintenance of improved physical function. All participants will undergo a 6-month weight loss intervention involving caloric restriction and supervised exercise followed by 12 months of follow-up with randomization to one of three groups (n=75/group): 1) Lower protein / higher CHO diet for the 6-month weight loss phase only (RecProt); 2) Higher protein / lower CHO diet for the 6-month weight loss phase only (6-mo HiProt); or 3) Higher protein / lower CHO diet for the 6-month weight loss and 12-month follow-up phases (18-mo HiProt). Physical function (primary aim) will be assessed by the expanded Short Physical Performance Battery (primary outcome) and lower extremity muscle strength and power at baseline, 6-, 12- and 18-months. Weight loss maintenance and body composition (secondary aim) will be assessed by dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) and computed tomography (CT) at baseline, 6- and 18-months. Bone mineral density (DXA) and cardiometabolic risk factors will also be measured at baseline, 6- and 18-months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Body Weight Changes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>6579 years BMI: 3045 kg/m2 No regular resistance training and/or aerobic exercise (&gt;20 mins/d) for past 6 months SPPB ≤10 No contraindications for safe and optimal participation in exercise training Approved for participation by Medical Director (Dr. Lyles) Willing to provide informed consent Agree to all study procedures and assessments Willing to consume protein/CHO supplements for up to 18 months Able to provide own transportation to study visits and intervention sessions Weight loss (≥5%) in past 6 months Dependent on cane or walker Cognitive impairment (MoCA score &lt;22) Severe arthritis, or other musculoskeletal disorder Joint replacement or other orthopedic surgery in past year Bilateral knee replacement Uncontrolled resting hypertension (&gt;160/90 mmHg); Insulindependent or uncontrolled diabetes (HbA1c ≥7.5%) Current or recent past (within 1 year) severe symptomatic heart disease, uncontrolled angina, stroke, chronic respiratory disease requiring oxygen; uncontrolled endocrine/metabolic disease; neurological or hematological disease; cancer requiring treatment in past year, except nonmelanoma skin cancers; liver or renal disease; or clinically evident edema Depression Serious conduction disorder, uncontrolled arrhythmia, or new Q waves or STsegment depressions (&gt;3 mm at rest or ≥2 mm with exercise) Abnormal kidney function (eGFR &lt;45 based on serum creatinine, age, gender, and race) Anemia (Hb&lt;14 g/dL in men; &lt;12.3 g/dL in women) Drug abuse or excessive alcohol use (&gt;7 drinks/week women; &gt;14 drinks/week men) Use of any tobacco or nicotine products in the past year Milk allergy / lactose intolerance Osteoporosis (Tscore &lt; 2.5 on hip or spine scan) Regular use of growth/steroid hormones, sex steroids or corticosteroids, osteoporosis medication, or protein supplements Weight loss medications or procedures Current participation in another intervention study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>