<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03074019</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical trial is to assess the efficacy of a novel prebiotic, XOS95, at two different dosages, in comparison to a placebo by assessing shifts in microbial populations after 8 weeks of supplementation, assessed as changes in abundance of microbial populations.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Study on the Effect of a XOS95 on the Human Gut Microbiome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Male or female adults aged 18 60 (inclusive) Healthy as determined from medical history Nonsmoker, or exsmoker ≥6 months Body mass index 18.5 27.5kg/m2 (inclusive) Female subjects of childbearing potential [i.e. not surgically sterilized or postmenopausal (greater than one year since last menses)] must have negative urine pregnancy test and must be using an effective birth control method , defined as: Continuous use of oral or long acting injected contraceptive for at least 2 months prior to study entry , or Use of an intrauterine device or implantable contraceptive, or Use of double barrier methods of birth control, or Abstinence from heterosexual intercourse Willing to avoid alcohol consumption for 24 h prior to every clinic visit Willing to maintain their regimens of medications and supplements known to alter GI function (including, but not limited to, iron supplements, calcium, and antidepressants) Willing to maintain a stable body weight, activity level and dietary pattern except for use of the study products, as directed Willing and able to provide informed written consent Pregnancy or lactation, or subject unwilling to take appropriate contraceptives for the duration of the study Use of prescription nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (or daily use of over the counter nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs &gt;1month), steroids, corticosteroids, or any other prescription antiinflammatory drugs within 3 months prior to visit 1 Individuals taking any over the counter or prescription medications, including natural health products, that may alter lipid profiles including, but not limited to fish oil (omega3 fatty acids), statins, fibrates, bile acid exchanger resin, phytosterols, niacin or its analogues, carnitine, polyglucosamines (Chitosan) or other lipidbinding ingredients within the 3 months prior to visit 1 Individuals taking any over the counter or prescription medications, including natural health products that may alter blood glucose (e.g. biguanides (Metformin), Alphalipoic Acid (ALA), Gymnema sylvestre) or insulin modulating medications (e.g. sulfonylureas, meglitinides, Dphenylalanine derivatives, thiazolidinediones, DPP4 inhibitors, alphaglucosidase inhibitors, bile acid sequestrants within 3 months prior to visit 1 Use of proton pump inhibitors or medications which inhibit peristaltic movement (e.g. opioids, loperamide) Unstable use (i.e. initiation or change in dose) of antihypertensive medications or thyroid hormone replacement medications within 3 months prior to visit 1 Use of any weightloss programs or weightloss medications (prescription or overthe counter) including, but not limited to, lipase inhibitors, within 3 months prior to visit Use of over the counter or prescription laxatives or stool softeners within 1 month prior to baseline (V2) Use of antibiotics (other than topical) within 2 months prior to baseline (V2) Use of prebiotic or fiber supplements (e.g. fructans and galactooligosaccharides (FOS, GOS), psyllium, fiber, inulin, glucomannan, acacia fiber/gum) or probiotic supplements (i.e. live microorganisms) within 4 weeks of baseline (V2) Consumption of specific functional prebiotic or probioticrich foods within 4 weeks of baseline (V2) (Appendix 3) History of blood clotting disorders or use of coagulationinhibiting drugs (e.g. warfarin) Individuals with achlorhydria Presence of major diseases such as diabetes, gastrointestinal, endocrine, cardiovascular, pancreatic, renal, or liver disease Chronic diarrhea or constipation, irritable bowel syndrome, celiac disease, glutensensitive enteropathy, or inflammatory bowel disease Abdominal or gastrointestinal surgery within the previous 12 months or planned abdominal or gastrointestinal surgery or procedures such as colonoscopy in the next 4 months Recent gastrointestinal foodborne illness (within 1 month prior to visit 1) History of neurological disease (e.g. Parkinson's disease, stroke, traumatic brain injury, etc.) History of cancer (excluding nonmelanoma skin cancer and basal cell carcinoma) in the past 5 years Uncontrolled hypertension defined as a seated resting systolic blood pressure ≥140 mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure ≥90 mmHg Abnormal laboratory test results of clinical significance, including, but not limited to ALT or AST ≥1.5X the upper limit of normal at screening (visit 1) Presence or history (past 6 months) of alcohol or drug abuse; alcohol use of &gt;2 standard alcoholic drinks per day Extreme dietary habits (e.g. vegan or very low carbohydrate diets, glutenfree diet, low FODMAP diet) Subject has a known allergy or intolerance to the test products or placebo Subject is unwilling or unable to abide by the requirements of the protocol Any condition that would interfere with the subject's ability to comply with study instructions, might confound the interpretation of the study, or put the subject at risk Subject has taken an investigational health product or has participated in a research study within 30 days prior to first study visit</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>