<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03074357</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This biomarker study is a follow-up to CPLATFRM2201. The goal of CBASICHR0005 is to collect another urine sample, interval clinical information, and an optional DNA sample from as many of the original 80 patients as possible. This new information will transform the data obtained in PLATFRM2201 from a cross-section to a temporal profile, which will (a) further enable the identification of biomarkers predictive of faster progression, and (b) satisfy the FDA's recommendation to perform "natural history studies" in rare diseases.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Urine, DNA and Clinical Information Collection From Patients With Alport Nephropathy.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>• Able to communicate well with the investigator, to understand and comply with the requirements of the study and able to provide written informed consent (parent or legal guardian for pediatric and adolescent subjects), which must be obtained before any assessment is performed. Alport SubjectSpecific Participation in CPLATFRM2201 Physically able to provide a single firstmorning urine sample of at least 30 mL (one ounce). Alport patients who have initiated dialysis therapy since participation in CPLATFRM2201 are exempt from this criterion and may still participate in this study. Healthy VolunteerSpecific • Male and Female Volunteers (may include healthy siblings of Alport patients) aged 5 to 15 years. Alport SubjectSpecific • None Healthy VolunteerSpecific Use of investigational drugs at the time of enrollment, or within 30 days or 5 halflives of enrollment, whichever is longer; or longer if required by local regulations, and for any other limitation of participation in an investigational trial based on local regulations. Known history of one of more of (a) hematuria (gross or microscopic), (b)audiological deficits, (c) fixed (nonorthostatic) proteinuria, or (d) reduced renal filtration function with serum creatinine (Cr) above the upper limit of the normal agespecific reference range, on at least 2 prior occasions (serum Cr need not be measured specifically for eligibility). Any other clinically significant underlying medical conditions as judged by the PI.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>