<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03074526</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the efficacy of Lyophilized amniotic fluid as compared to the Saline Injection, placebo control in the treatment of moderate osteoarthritis of the knee.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Protocol for the Clinical Evaluation of Lyophilized Amniotic Fluid in the Treatment of Knee Osteoarthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Approximately 180 subjects will be enrolled in one of three dose arms ( 4ml, Saline Placebo and 4ml 2x). The estimated enrollment period is 6 months. Each subject will receive 1 injection and be evaluated for efficacy and safety during a 6 month observation period. The study is expected to be completed within 12 months, inclusive of enrollment and follow-up for all subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subject is 30 years or older. 2. Subject has a diagnosis of osteoarthritis (OA) defined as Grade 1 to 3 on the Kellgren Lawrence grading scale. 3. Subject is willing and able provide informed consent and participate in all procedures and followup evaluations necessary to complete the study. 4. Subject must have a VAS pain scale greater than 30. 1. Subject has active infection at the injection site. 2. Subject has rheumatoid arthritis, psoriatic arthritis, or have been diagnosed with any other autoimmune disorders that could be the cause of their knee pain. 3. BMI greater than 45 kg/m2 4. Subject has received an intraarticular hyaluronic acid (HA) injection for the treatment of OA of the target knee within 12 weeks prior to screening. 5. Subject has received a steroid or platelet rich plasma (PRP) injection for the treatment of OA of the target knee within 12 weeks prior to screening. 6. Subject has had major surgery or arthroscopy in the target knee within 26 weeks of treatment or plans to have surgery in the target knee within 180 days of treatment. 7. Subject is pregnant or plans to become pregnant within 180 days of treatment. 8. Subject has used an investigational drug, device or biologic within 12 weeks prior to treatment. 9. Subject has any significant medical condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would interfere with protocol evaluation and participation. 10. Subject has a history of immunosuppressive or chemotherapy in the last 5 years 11. Subject has autoimmune disease or a known history of having Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndromes (AIDS) or HIV 12. Subject has had prior radiation at the site 13. Subject is currently taking anticoagulant therapy (excluding Plavix or Aspirin) 14. New diagnosis of gout in the past 6 month 15. Subject has a diagnosis of osteoarthritis (OA) defined as Grade 4 on the Kellgren Lawrence grading scale. 16. Subject has a diagnosis of Osteonecrosis of the knee. 17. Subject has had a total knee replacement.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>