<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03074578</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There is a need for quantify the emotional and neurophysiological perception of verbal violence, in order to understand the impact it might have on a subject. This project aims at assessing the influence of time, sleep, and people interaction on the perception of verbal violence.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Is There a Desensitization During Sleep After Exposure to a Violent Verbal Input ?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There are many processes involved in the perception of verbal violence. There is a need for quantified data to have a better understanding the physiological and neurological perception of verbal violence, in order to understand the impact it might have on a subject. This project aims at assessing the influence of time, sleep, and people interaction on the perception of verbal violence. The "cognitive replay" will also be assessed through dreams. The investigators think that sleep plays a role in desensitization to negative emotions and to memory consolidation. However, the role of sleep in verbal violence remains unknown.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adrenocorticotropic Hormone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Melanocyte-Stimulating Hormones</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>beta-Endorphin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject fully understands French Subject willing to consent to the study and signed the written consent Subject is afiliated to the Freanch national health care system (Sécurité Sociale) Subject level of education superior to "Brevet des collèges" (an equivalent would be the general certificate of secondary education) The subject is not able to understand the protocol The subject has a language disorder The subject has a psychiatric or neurological disorders The subject does not use psychotropic drugs The subject has watched the advertidement : "stop djihadisme", broadcasted on television by the french government</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>sleep</keyword>
	<keyword>verbal abuse</keyword>
	<keyword>polysomnography</keyword>
	<keyword>perception</keyword>
	<keyword>neuropsychological tests</keyword>
</DOC>