<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03074890</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Massive haemorrhage is defined as the necessity of 3 or more packed red blood cells in one hour, the transfusion of 10 packed blood cells, the loss of the half of the blood volume, the loss of 4-5 cc/kg/h or more, and haemorrhage shock. Haemorrhage shock provokes changes in the bloodstream with celular and organic disfunction. In many cases massive transfusion is needed to stabilize the vital function. This massive transfusion can have serious side effects (infectious and immunologic and no immunologic reactions) and increase the morbidity and mortality. Massive transfusion protocols improve the survival in severe trauma injury patients. The transfusion of fixed rate of packed red blood cells, fresh frozen plasma and platelet concentrates have decreased the severity of trauma induced coagulopathy. Recently several studies have shown the benefit of massive transfusion protocols with high transfusion ratios (1:1:1 RBC:FFP:PLT) in mortality after severe trauma. So early and aggressive transfusion improve the outcomes and the resources. Massive Transfusion Protocol have been elaborated in the Hospital Universitario de Canarias with high transfusion ratios (1:1:1 RBC:FFP:PLT) . The goals of this protocol is to reduce the variability in the clinic experience, to reduce the transfusion necessities and to assure an safe treatment with blood products. So with this study the investigators will evaluate if the goals of this Protocol are followed and if the use of this Protocol is really safe and efficient.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluating of the Hospital Universitario de Canarias Massive Transfusion Protocol</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with massive haemorrhage and surgery Informed consent &lt;18 years old patients Patients didn´t want to participate in this study Patients were participated in other studies</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>