<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02152254</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this research study is to compare the effects of treatment based on molecular profiling to those of the standard-of-care. Treatment Assignment: From a tumor biopsy, a molecular profile of the disease is established. Based on genetic profiling, the following interventions will follow: A) If there is no abnormality, patients will be treated according to the patient's doctor as to what is in their best interest. B) If there is an abnormality and there is an FDA-approved drug for the tumor type, patients will be offered that treatment. C) If there is an abnormality and there is no FDA-approved drug for the abnormality and the tumor type, patients will be randomly assigned to Arm A (targeted therapy) or Arm B (standard-of-care therapy).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>IMPACT 2: Randomized Study Evaluating Molecular Profiling and Targeted Agents in Metastatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients whose tumors progress on protocol-assigned treatment will have achieved the primary study endpoint and have the option of crossing over to the other treatment arm. Imaging studies will be repeated every 2 cycles after initiation of treatment in both randomized arms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Second Primary</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients with metastatic cancer. 2. Patients may have received unlimited lines of prior therapy. 3. Prior to randomization, patients with metastatic disease must have been treated with established standardofcare therapy, or physicians have determined that such established therapy is not sufficiently efficacious, or patients have declined to receive standardofcare therapy. 4. The patient has measurable disease. 5. The patient has Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 01. 6. The patient has biopsyaccessible tumor. For patients who had no prior anticancer therapy and had surgical resection within a year and tumor tissue is immediately available, that tumor will be analyzed and no biopsy will be needed. 7. The patient has normal organ and marrow function, defined as absolute neutrophil count&gt;/= 1,000/µl; platelets &gt;/=100,000/µl (unless these abnormalities are due to bone marrow involvement). 8. The patient has adequate hepatic function as defined by a total bilirubin level&lt;/=1.5 x the upper limit of normal (ULN), unless the patient has known Gilbert's disease, and alanine aminotransferase (ALT)/ serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase levels (SGPT) &lt;/= 2.5 X ULN (unless the patient has liver metastases). 9. The patient has serum creatinine clearance &gt;/= 50 ml/min by the CockcroftGault formula. 10. If the patient has brain metastasis, they must have been stable (treated and/or asymptomatic) and the patient must have been off steroids for at least 2 weeks. 11. The patient is &gt;/=18 years of age. 12. The patient has provided signed informed consent. 13. Patients with a previous malignancy (other than the patients' known cancer) that were treated successfully and are diseasefree for at least 3 years are allowed. 14. Patients with a history of basal cell carcinoma of the skin or preinvasive carcinoma of the cervix are eligible. 15. Women of childbearing potential must agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry and for the duration of study participation. Childbearing potential will be defined as women who have had menses within the past 12 months and who have not had a tubal ligation, hysterectomy, or bilateral oophorectomy. Should a woman become pregnant or suspect that she is pregnant while participating in this study, she should inform her treating physician immediately. 16. Male subjects must agree to use effective contraception or abstinence while on study and for 90 days after last dose of study drug. 1. Patients who are randomized to the control arm must not receive therapy based on prior molecular profiling. 2. The patient has received chemotherapy, surgery, or radiotherapy (for therapeutic purposes) within 3 weeks of initiating study treatment (4 weeks for bevacizumab or investigational drugs) or the patient has not recovered (grade ≥2 from side effects of the previous therapy). Patients who receive palliative radiation therapy can be treated immediately after completion of radiation therapy. 3. The patient has cardiac conditions as follows: uncontrolled hypertension (BP &gt; 160/100) despite optimal therapy, uncontrolled angina, ventricular arrhythmias, congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association Class II or above), prior or current cardiomyopathy, atrial fibrillation with heart rate &gt;100 bpm, unstable ischaemic heart disease (MI within 6 months prior to starting treatment or angina requiring use of nitrates more than once weekly). 4. The patient has peripheral neuropathy &gt;/= grade 2. 5. The patient is pregnant (confirmed by serum bHCG, if applicable) or is breastfeeding. 6. The patient has concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled medical disease that could compromise participation in the study (i.e., uncontrolled diabetes, severe infection requiring active treatment, severe malnutrition, chronic severe liver or renal disease). 7. The patient has refractory nausea and vomiting or chronic gastrointestinal diseases (e.g., inflammatory bowel disease) or has had significant bowel resection that would preclude adequate absorption (for oral therapy only). 8. The patient is unable to swallow capsules and/or has a surgical or anatomical condition that precludes swallowing and absorbing oral medication on an ongoing basis (for oral therapy only). 9. Any other condition that would, in the investigator's judgment, contraindicate the patient's participation in the clinical study due to safety concerns or compliance with clinical study procedures.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Molecular Profiling</keyword>
	<keyword>Genomic alteration analysis of the tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>Advanced Cancer Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Gene mutations</keyword>
	<keyword>Tumor biopsy</keyword>
	<keyword>Personalized medicine</keyword>
</DOC>