<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02152085</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the capacity of a 6-week treatment with neuromuscular electrical stimulation to improve walking in individuals whose mobility has been compromised by multiple sclerosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neuromuscular Electrical Stimulation and Mobility in Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants will be randomly assigned to one of two study arms. Those in one arm will receive a treatment with narrow stimulus pulses (0.4 ms) and those in the other arm will receive wide stimulus pulses (1 ms). The electrical stimulation will be delivered with a Vectra Genisys System.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Able to read, understand, and speak English to ensure safe participation in the project Difficulties with walking On stable doses of Ampyra, provigil, or other symptomatictreating medications No systemic steroids within the last 30 days Not currently exercising more than 2x/wk Able to arrange own transportation to and from the laboratories Provide informed consent, including willingness to be randomly assigned to one of the two groups Documented MSrelated relapse in the last 3 months Medical diagnosis or condition that is considered to be an absolute or relative contraindication to participating in exercise training, such as major renal, pulmonary, hepatic, cardiac, gastrointestinal, HIV, cancer (other than treated basal cell cancer), other neurological disorders, or pregnancy Poorly controlled diabetes mellitus or hypertension History of seizure disorders Alcohol dependence or abuse (≥2 drinks/day), or present history (last 6 months) of drug abuse Inability to attend exercise sessions 3 days per week for 6 weeks</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Walking</keyword>
	<keyword>Mobility</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuromuscular electrical stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiple sclerosis</keyword>
</DOC>