<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00406848</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the efficacy and safety of duloxetine 60 mg once daily to placebo on depression in elderly patients (greater than or equal to 65 years of age). Patients who do not respond in the first 13 weeks will be eligible for rescue using pre-defined criteria. Patients randomized to duloxetine 60 mg/day meeting the rescue criteria will be increased to 120 mg/day. Patients randomized to the placebo arm meeting the rescue criteria will be assigned to duloxetine 60 mg/day.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Comparing the Efficacy and Safety of Duloxetine and Placebo for the Treatment of Depression in Elderly Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Duloxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Are male or female outpatients at least 65 years of age who meet the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders Fourth Edition Text Revision (DSMIVTR) diagnostic criteria for Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) Have a Mini Mental Score Exam (MMSE) score of at least 20 at Visit 1 Have a degree of understanding such that the patient can communicate intelligibly with the investigator and study coordinator Patients judged clinically to be at serious suicidal risk in the opinion of the investigator Have any prior history of bipolar disorder, panic disorder, psychosis, schizophrenia, or obsessivecompulsive disorder Have any current (within the past 12 months) DSMIVTR primary Axis I diagnosis other than MDD Have moderate to severe dementia Have a serious medical illness, including any cardiovascular (CV), hepatic, renal, respiratory, hematologic, endocrinologic, or neurologic disease, or clinically significant laboratory abnormality that is not stabilized or is anticipated to require hospitalization within 6 months, in the opinion of the investigator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>