<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02368405</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized controlled trial to study a nutrition education intervention in individuals with spinal cord injuries both in the acute rehabilitation setting (n = 100) and the community setting (n = 100). Participants in the treatment group will receive six interactive nutrition lectures based upon a successful program that has been used in older adults titled "Eat Smart, Stay Well". The goals of intervention are to improve whole-grain, fruit and vegetable, and low-fat dairy intake and reduce fat and saturated fat intake. Secondary outcomes will include improvements in waist circumference of body mass index and some biomarkers such as cholesterol and blood sugar.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nutrition Education for Cardiovascular Disease Prevention in Spinal Cord Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The prevalence of SCI is significant. Obesity, diabetes, and CVD are more prevalent in the SCI population. Many individuals with SCI are unable or have a limited capacity to exercise. This reality makes good nutrition even more urgent. This study will be the first to test whether additional nutrition education can improve nutrition behavior and knowledge, diet quality, adiposity, and metabolic CVD risk factors in individuals with SCI and to determine the best setting to deliver nutrition education to individuals with SCI.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>American Spinal Injury Association classification A, B, C as long as they are not functional ambulators Stage III or IV pressure ulcers, pregnancy, endstage renal disease, treatment for cancer except for nonmelanoma skin cancer within the past five years, and chronic, nontobacco substanceabuse, cognitive impairment with inability to learn</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>