<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00208468</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This post-market clinical follow-up study was designed to compare hip replacement outcomes of the European Hip against 3 controls (Omniflex, Zweymuller, and Spotorno), however Omniflex did not end up being used. The first patient had surgery on February 18, 2000 and the final patient had surgery on September 2, 2005. There were 317 subjects consented but only 301 had hip replacement surgery (subjects received: 220 European hips, 33 Zweymuller, and 48 Spotorno). The study took place at three sites. Each site used their standard device as the control. The Austrian site enrolled 69 European hips and 33 Zweymuller hips. 92 European hips and 48 Spotorno hips were enrolled in Germany. Finally, the site in Italy enrolled 59 European hips. Although the study protocol intended collecting DEXA and RSA outcomes, the data collected by the sites did not include these outcomes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomised Multi-centre Study to Compare the Long-term Performance of the Future Hip to 3 Other Implants in Primary Total Hip Replacement</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Necrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Femoral Fractures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Dislocation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Dislocation, Congenital</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Legg-Calve-Perthes Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Slipped Capital Femoral Epiphyses</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Collagen Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rheumatic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>i) Administrative The subject is able to understand the study, is willing to give voluntary, written, informed consent, will cooperate with assessment procedures and is geographically able to comply with the postoperative followup regime. ii) Age The subject's age is between 18 and 75 years inclusive. iii) Sex Male or female subjects may be recruited to the study. iv) Diagnosis Subjects must be undergoing primary THR surgery for noninflammatory degenerative joint disease including osteoarthritis, avascular necrosis, posttraumatic arthritis, fractured neck of femur and nonunion of fractured neck of femur, SUFE or Perthes disease. v) Suitability Subjects who in the opinion of the Investigator are considered to be suitable for treatment with the devices involved in the study. i) Subjects undergoing revision procedure to the operative hip. ii) Subjects who have had a previous femoral osteotomy to the operative hip. iii) Subjects who have a history of active sepsis in the joint. iv) Subjects who have been diagnosed with primary or secondary carcinomas in the last five years (excluding basal cell carcinoma or cervical carcinoma). v) Subjects with any condition which may, in the opinion of the Investigator, interfere with the total hip replacement's survival or outcome, e.g. Paget's disease, Charcot's disease. vi) Subjects with psychosocial disorders which, in the opinion of the Investigator would limit rehabilitation. vii) Subject's whose weight is &gt; 100kg. viii) Subjects with femoral head necrosis on the nonoperated side (RSA and DEXA subjects only). ix) Subjects who have a fracture of the femur &gt; 6 months old (RSA and DEXA subjects only). x) Subjects diagnosed as having ankylosing spondylitis (RSA and DEXA subjects only) xi) Subjects with a known history of poor compliance to medical treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hip</keyword>
	<keyword>Cementless</keyword>
</DOC>