<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02925702</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Prospective Multi-centre Study of Prognostic Factors in Castration Resistant PROState Cancer Treated With Radium 223</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PRORADIUM: Prospective Multi-centre Study of Prognostic Factors in CRPC Treated With Radium-223</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Observational study to analyze prognostic factors in castration resistant prostate cancer patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Radium Ra 223 dichloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Provision of informed consent. 2. Eighteen years of age or older. 3. General health status acceptable and compatible with active treatment: ECOG ≤02. 4. Histological confirmation of prostate cancer diagnosis. 5. Prior resistance to biochemical castration with an LHRH agonist (or surgical castration through bilateral orchiectomy) and progression to an antiandrogen drug (e.g. bicalutamide, nilutamide or cyproterone acetate). 6. Biochemical progression upon prior treatment in agreement with PSAWG2 criteria, confirmed by a second PSA test. 7. Castrate levels of testosterone in peripheral blood: testosterone &lt;0.5 ng/ml. 8. Candidates for standard treatment with Radium223 (55 kBq/kg each 28 days during 6 cycles) 9. Availability of anatomopathological tumour material (e.g. a paraffin block of the prostatectomy or initial biopsy of the metastasis). 10. Acceptable hematological, hepatic and renal functions and without contraindications for the administration of abiraterone in agreement with its respective summary of products characteristics. 1. Previous cancer diagnosis, except those patients who had a localized malignant tumour and who are five years cancerfree, as well as subjects with a history of skin cancers (of nonmelanoma type) or excised in situ carcinomas. 2. Medical histories, be they psychiatric or of any other character, which, according to the judgement of the investigator, might interfere with the subject's granting of informed consent or the safe execution of the procedures required in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>