<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02925923</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the inhibition of platelet aggregation (i) ticagrelor and bivalirudin/heparin versus (ii) clopidogrel, eptifibatide and heparin in patients with unstable angina undergoing coronary intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ticagrelor Versus Clopidogrel and Eptifibatide Bolus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The first 30 minutes of PCI procedure is of outmost importance when plaque ruptures and platelet activation occurs. Platelet activation and accumulation causes the formation of blood clots that may cause heart attack. As a standard of care, the doctor can prescribe medications such as are ticagrelor, eptifibatide, clopidogrel, to prevent the formation of blood clots. 100 patients with stable or unstable angina, both male and female, will be randomized to either Group A- Ticagrelor and bivalirudin/heparin or Group B- Clopidogrel, eptifibatide and heparin administrated immediately before PCI. Platelet function testing and ECG will be performed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Angina Pectoris</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angina, Unstable</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angina, Stable</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clopidogrel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eptifibatide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ticlopidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ticagrelor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium heparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bivalirudin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with stable or unstable angina. 1. need for oral anticoagulation therapy (Warfarin, Dabigatran, Rivaroxaban, Apixaban, Edoxaban) 2. increased risk of bradycardia, and the associated therapy with a strong cytochrome P450 inhibitors (antiretroviral agents, antifungal agents and some antibiotics eg. Indinavir, Nelfinavir, Lopinavir, Ritonavir, Itraconazole, Ketoconazole, Voriconazole, Clarithromycin, Telithormycin) 3. surgery&lt;4 weeks 4. use of any thienopyridines (Clopidogrel, Prasugrel) 7 days prior to randomization 5. administration of GP IIb/IIIa inhibitors 6. bleeding diathesis or major bleeding episode within 2 weeks 7. thrombocytopenia (Platelet count &lt; 100000) 8. incessant chest pain 9. hemodynamic instability (Mean arterial pressure &lt; 65 mm Hg; need for vasopressor or inotropic agents; need for mechanical circulatory support for coronary intervention), NSTEMI as evidenced by elevation of troponin levels (Troponin &gt; 0.034 ng/ml); renal failure with a serum creatinine &gt;2.0 mg/dL 10. anemia with HCT&lt;30%.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>