<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02337231</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A randomized, controlled, cross-over clinical trial of borage oil vs soybean oil to determine whether the metabolism and/or impact of medium chain-polyunsaturated fatty acids (MC-PUFAs) in botanical oil supplements are changed in relationship to specific genotypes in a SNP (rs174537) strongly associated with FADS1 activity and PUFA metabolism.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Botanical Oils Study to Determine Genetic Differences in the Way Your Body Processes Fats in Edible Oils</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will be a randomized, controlled, cross-over clinical trial of borage oil and soybean oil to determine whether the metabolism and/or impact of MC-PUFAs in botanical oil supplements are changed in relationship to specific genotypes in a SNP (rs174537) strongly associated with FADS1 activity and PUFA metabolism. Subjects previously genotyped at rs174537 will be given supplements and both blood PUFA (serum and erythrocyte membranes), urinary eicosanoids and eicosanoid release from whole blood (leukocyte generation) will be measured as biochemical determinants of genotype impact on supplement metabolism. To evaluate the effect of genotype at the rs174537 locus on the metabolism of MC-PUFAs in borage and soybean oil to long chain polyunsaturated fatty acids (LC-PUFAs), including arachidonic acid, the investigators will utilize a double blind, randomized, crossover design. There will be three study groups based on the genotype of the healthy volunteer at rs174537. Individuals within each genotype will be consented and screened up to 8 weeks prior to randomization and the start of the intervention. Subjects will be randomized to begin with 4 weeks of either borage oil or soybean oil followed by an 8 week washout period, and then another 4 week period in which they take the second oil. Study visits will occur at 0, 2, and 4 weeks during each oil supplementation period, in addition to the consenting visit, for a total of 7 visits during the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Borage oil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Able to give informed consent Must agree to adhere to dietary requirements during the entire study Be willing to participate for the whole study Be willing to not take PUFA supplements outside of those provided by the study Agree not to take interfering medications during the duration of the study Agree to allow samples to be stored for future use May not have diabetes, cancer, heart attack or vascular surgery within the past year, be diagnosed with heart disease, have uncontrolled high blood pressure, history of stroke, atherosclerosis, asthma, multiple sclerosis or chronic joint disease Gallbladder removal or gallbladder disease Use of tobacco products within the last six months Pregnancy or lactation Fasting triglycerides greater than 150 mg/dl Blood pressure greater than 130/90 BMI equal to or greater than 30 or less than 19 Fasting glucose greater than 125 mg/dl Have liver function values in the normal range Taking greater than 100 mg aspirin/day Taking NSAIDS or oral corticosteroids Taking montelukasttype allergy medications Having a pacemaker or a defibrillator Taking lipid lowering medications</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>