<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00639015</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present study was conducted as a prospective, randomized, controlled study to compare: - the effects of norepinephrine and phenylephrine on systemic and regional hemodynamics in patients with catecholamine-dependent septic shock - to test the hypothesis that norepinephrine may likewise better preserve hepatosplanchnic perfusion versus phenylephrine in patients suffering from septic shock</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phenylephrine in Septic Shock</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Thirty two septic shock patients requiring vasopressor support to maintain mean arterial pressure between 65 and 75 mmHg despite adequate volume resuscitation will be enrolled in the study. Patients will be randomly allocated to be treated with either a) titrated phenylephrine, b) titrated norepinephrine (control; each n = 16), to achieve a mean arterial pressure (MAP) between 65 and 75 mmHg, if necessary. Data from right heart catheterization, thermo-dye dilution catheter, gastric tonometry as well as data from organ function, will be obtained at baseline and after 12 hours.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Shock</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Shock, Septic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phenylephrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxymetazoline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Norepinephrine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of Septic shock Vasopressor support to maintain mean arterial pressure (MAP) between 65 and 75 mmHg despite adequate volume resuscitation (pulmonary artery occlusion pressure = 1318 mmHg and central venous pressure = 812 mmHg) Pregnancy Age &lt; 18 years Present cardiac dysfunction Present or suspected acute mesenteric ischemia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sepsis</keyword>
	<keyword>Septic Shock</keyword>
	<keyword>phenylephrine</keyword>
	<keyword>norepinephrine</keyword>
	<keyword>catecholamine</keyword>
</DOC>