<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01761487</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There is an urgent need to control the current national outbreak of Carbapenem-resistent Klebsiella pneumonia (CRKP). In Israel, the death rate among CRKP carriers is 3.5 times higher than in Carbapenem-sensitive Klebsiella pneumonia carriers (44% vs. 12.5%, respectively). In the investigators' previous study: A Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Trial of Selective Digestive Decontamination (SDD) Using Oral Gentamicin and Oral Polymyxin E for Eradication of CRKP Carriage (Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2012;33:14-19) the investigators have shown that the investigators' SDD regimen is effective for decolonization patients colonized with CRKP. The investigators' assumption is that a higher dose of polymyxin E together with gentamicin (SDD drugs) for a prolonged period is needed to overcome the likelihood of a high rate of drug inactivation in the gut, thereby reaching CRKP carriage eradication.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SDD for Eradicating CRKP Carriage</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Klebsiella Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gentamicins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polymyxins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colistin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Provide a sighed and dated written informed consent document indicating that the subject (or a legally accepted representative) has been informed of all pertinent aspects of the study Hospitalized men or women at least 18 years of age Rectal swab culture positive for CRKP in the last week Will be willing to initiate and remain on treatment, except for adverse events occurring Age less than 18 years. Pregnant women, lactating women. A know allergy to one of the study drugs. Renal failure with creatinine clearance less than 50mL/min. Current Treatment with IV gentamicin and/or IV polymyxin E Any safety, behavioral, clinical, or administrative reasons that, in the Investigator's judgment, would potentially compromise study compliance or the ability to evaluate safety/efficacy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>