<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01761006</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to determine whether exhaled nitric oxide (FeNO) goes up during an acute exacerbation of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (AECOPD) and whether the level of exhaled nitric oxide returns to normal in the weeks after an exacerbation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of FeNO During and Following Acute COPD Exacerbation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this research study is to determine whether exhaled nitric oxide (FeNO) goes up during an acute exacerbation of COPD and whether the level of exhaled nitric oxide returns to normal in the weeks after an exacerbation. FeNO is measured with a medical device called the NIOX MINO®. The NIOX MINO® device has been cleared by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for use in children and adults age 7 and older to measure Fractional Exhaled Nitric Oxide (FeNO) in human breath.This information will be useful for determining whether FeNO may help predict the development of a COPD exacerbation and/or be useful for identifying patients who will have a beneficial therapeutic response to inhaled or systemic corticosteroids during a COPD exacerbation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: 40 years and above, inclusive Sex: Males and Females Smoking History: ≥20 pack years. COPD Defined as an FEV1/ FVC or FEV1/SVC ratio &lt;70% predicted. AECOPD defined as a clinically significant worsening of COPD symptoms requiring treatment with antibiotics and/or systemic steroids and/or hospitalization for same. Use of Systemic Corticosteroids for more than 48 hours prior to Visit 1. AECOPD requiring mechanical ventilation Study Participation Outside of This Protocol: Patients currently enrolled in studies of Investigational or nonInvestigational Drugs or Medical Devices and/or who participated in these studies within 30 days prior to this study are excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Exhaled Nitric Oxide</keyword>
	<keyword>NIOX MINO</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute COPD exacerbation</keyword>
</DOC>