<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01761500</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma is an aggressive malignance disease in children and adolescents. This study was designed to evaluate the efficacy and toxicity of the modified NHL-BFM-90 protocol in Chinese children and adolescents with Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improve the Survival Rate of Chinese Children and Adolescents With Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma (NHL) in children and adolescents include Burkitt's lymphoma (BL), diffuse large B cell lymphoma (DLBL), anaplastic large cell lymphoma (ALCL) and lymphoblastic lymphoma (LBL). These subtypes of NHL are an aggressive group of diseases. At present, in developed countries, 80 to 90% of children with NHL are cured by intensive, risk-adapted chemotherapy.The best protocols include BFM-90, LMB-89 and FAB/LMB/96. However, in developing countries, such as those with low and moderate incomes, the limited availability of resources is an obstacle for using these complicated and intensive protocols.As such, very simple protocols, such as the CHOP protocol, were often used to treat children and adolescents with NHL, thus resulting in poor survival rates. To improve the survival rate of Chinese children and adolescents with NHL, This study was designed to evaluate the efficacy and toxicity of this modified NHL-BFM -90 protocol in Chinese children and adolescents with NHL.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Untreated children and adolescents with NonHodgkin's lymphoma 2. Age ≤ 20 years 3. The informed consent of their guardians was obtained. 1. Recurrence NonHodgkin's lymphoma 2. Age ＞20 years 3. No abide by the protocol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>20 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma;</keyword>
	<keyword>Childhood and adolescence;</keyword>
	<keyword>Survival Rate</keyword>
</DOC>