<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00471588</DOC>
	<brief_summary>3 groups of subjects (healthy controls, OCD subjects and stimulant-dependent subjects) will receive pramipexole (1.5 mg, single dose), amisulpride (400 mg, single dose) or placebo in a cross-over, double-blind, placebo-controlled design. Effects of compulsive behaviour will be assessed using fMRI and cognitive testing. Assess biomarkers including cardiovascular responses and plasma levels. All groups studied on 3 separate occasions following screening, with at least a week intervening between consecutive assessments. The procedures to be adopted for study assessment will be identical on each occasion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Characterize The Modulatory Effects Of Dopamine D2/D3 Receptor Agonist And Antagonist Drugs On Compulsive Behaviors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Behavior</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pramipexole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dopamine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dopamine Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sultopride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sulpiride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female, between 18 55 years of age; the groups will be matched for either handedness. Participants must have the ability to comprehend the key components of the consent form and provide informed consent. Participants must lead and write (in English) at a level sufficient to complete study related assessments. Assessment by a psychiatrist or psychologist, which includes a facetoface evaluation of the individual using the DSMVI diagnosis. No history of neurological disorder, head/brain injury, hepatitis, or visual impairment. No MRI contraindications (metal in body, claustrophobia) and able to provide blood samples (venous accessibility, especially relevant for drug users). Patients with obsessivecompulsive disorder will have a minimum 2year history of compulsive behaviours satisfying DSMIVTR criteria for OCD. Participants with chronic stimulant use will have a minimum 2year history of dependence on class A stimulants, with age of drug abuse onset before 20 years, and will satisfy DSMIVTR criteria for dependence on stimulant drugs. Control volunteers have to be in good mental and physical health. A personal history of psychiatric or neurological disorders, as defined by the DSMIV (except OCD in patients with OCD and substance dependence in drug users) A history or presence of alcohol / substance abuse or dependence (other than nicotine), as defined by the DSMIVTR (except drug dependence group). A BDIII total score greater than 14 will lead to exclusion from the study. Treatment with methadone or buprenorphine may interfere with the experimental tasks, and therefore, will lead to exclusion from the study. Participants who have any laboratory abnormality that in the investigator's judgement is considered to be clinically significant and could potentially affect subject safety or study outcome. History of clinically significant or current renal dysfunction. Clinically significant abnormalities in hematology, blood chemistry, MRI, urinalysis or physical examination not resolved by baseline visit. Impaired liver function at baseline or history of liver dysfunction. Female participant is pregnant or currently breastfeeding. Any serious medical disorder or condition that would in the Investigator's opinion, preclude the administration of study medication and or a history of clinically significant hepatic, cardiac, renal, neurologic, cerebrovascular, metabolic or pulmonary disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dopamine</keyword>
	<keyword>OCD</keyword>
	<keyword>MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>stimulant users</keyword>
</DOC>