<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01247974</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multi-center, prospective, randomized and controlled clinical trial comparing the safety and efficacy of the CorMatrix ECM for Pericardial Closure to reduce the incidence of new onset postoperative atrial fibrillation by circumferentially reconstructing the normal pericardial anatomy following isolated, first-time, CABG procedures compared to subjects that do not undergo pericardial closure. This trial will be conducted at up to 20 clinical sites in the U.S.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation Of New Onset Postoperative Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of this prospective clinical trial is to demonstrate the safety and efficacy of the CorMatrix ECM for Pericardial Closure to reduce the incidence of new onset postoperative atrial fibrillation by circumferentially reconstructing the normal pericardial anatomy following isolated, first-time, coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) procedures as compared to subjects who did not undergo pericardial closure. Safety will be established by demonstrating that the composite clinical event rate for the ECM treatment group is not worse than the control group that did not undergo pericardial closure. The efficacy will be established by demonstrating a reduced incidence of new onset postoperative atrial fibrillation in the ECM treatment group as compared to the control group.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The subject is 18 years of age or older This cardiac operation is the subject's first or primary cardiac operation The subject must be undergoing an isolated CABG procedure using a median sternotomy approach The subject must possess the ability to provide written Informed Consent The subject must express a willingness to fulfill all of the expected requirements of this clinical protocol Prior history of atrial fibrillation Prior history of open heart surgery Prior history of pericarditis Prior history of antiarrhythmia drug treatment (e.g., amiodarone, dronedarone or sotalol) in the past six months The subject has an implantable cardiac device (i.e., cardiac resynchronization therapy devices with and without defibrillator capabilities (CRTs and CRTDs), implantable cardioverterdefibrillators (ICD) and pacemakers) Concomitant procedure planned In the investigator's opinion, the subject may require prophylactic treatment with antiarrhythmia drugs or temporary pacing postoperatively</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting</keyword>
	<keyword>New Onset Postoperative Atrial Fibrillation</keyword>
</DOC>