<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01247675</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study investigates the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetic profile (PK), and pharmacodynamic response (PD) of three different doses of ACP-001 given once-a-week compared to one dose-level of an approved daily human growth hormone product over a period of 4 weeks (4 weekly administrations versus 28 daily administrations) in adults with Growth Hormone Deficiency.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Safety, Pharmacokinetic and Pharmacodynamic Study of ACP-001 (TransCon hGH) in Adults With Growth Hormone Deficiency</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Endocrine System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dwarfism, Pituitary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female between 20 to 70 years Body Mass Index (BMI, kg/m2) of 19.0 to 36.0 kg/m2, both inclusive Adult Growth Hormone Deficient (AHGD) patients with documented growth hormone deficiency as defined in the Consensus guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of adults with GH deficiency II (Consensus Guidelines 1998 and 2007) Fertile females must agree to use appropriate contraceptive methods and have a negative pregnancy test at inclusion GH replacement therapy for at least 3 months Willing to maintain current activity level during the trial Subjects are able and willing to provide written informed consent and authorization for protected health information disclosure in accordance with Good Clinical Practice (GCP) History of hypersensitivity and/or idiosyncrasy to any of the test compounds or excipients employed in this study. Females of childbearing potential who are pregnant, breastfeeding or intend to become pregnant or are not using adequate contraceptive methods. Reliable methods for women are orally administered hormonal contraceptives, surgical intervention (e.g. tubal ligation), intrauterine device (IUD) and sexual abstinence. Active malignant disease or malignant disease within the last 5 years Proliferative retinopathy judged by retinaphoto within the last year Heart insufficiency as judged by the investigator and/or NYHA 3 or greater (NYHA criteria for diagnosis of diseases of the heart, 1994) Subjects with uncontrolled diabetes with an HbA1c above 8.0% and/or insulin treatment Stable pituitary hormone replacement therapy for less than 3 months Impaired liver function as judged by the investigator or hepatic transaminases &gt; 2 times the upper limit of normal Impaired kidney function as judged by the investigator and/or creatinine clearance &lt;50 mL/min and/or serum creatinine &gt; 1.4 mg/dL Participation in another interventional clinical study involving an investigational compound within 3 months prior to enrolment in this study or participation in another interventional clinical study involving an investigational compound during this study. Subjects who are unable to comply with the requirements of the study or who in the opinion of the investigator should not participate in the study. History or presence of alcohol abuse or drug abuse. Patients with known history for, or presence of, antihGH and / or antiPEG antibodies</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>