<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00326027</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to evaluate the effect of pantoprazole on fast symptom reduction in hospitalized patients with NERD (non-erosive reflux disease) or GERD (gastroesophageal reflux disease, Los Angeles [LA] Grade A-D). During the study, the patients will complete a patient-orientated, self-assessed reflux questionnaire (ReQuest™). The study duration consists of a treatment period of 7 days ± 3 days. Pantoprazole (tablet) will be administered once daily in the morning to patients with NERD or GERD at one dose level for each indication. The study will provide further data on the safety and tolerability of pantoprazole.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Pantoprazole in Patients Older Than 18 Years Who Have Symptoms of Non-erosive Reflux or Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease (BY1023/DE-004)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Gastroesophageal Reflux</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pantoprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Main Written informed consent Inpatients (hospitalization during the entire study period is mandatory) Symptomatic (heartburn, acid regurgitation or dysphagia for at least 1 day since admission to the hospital) nonerosive reflux disease (NERD) or erosive gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD, LA Grade AD) Main Known ZollingerEllison syndrome or other gastric hypersecretory condition Previous acidlowering surgery or other surgery of the esophagus and/or upper gastrointestinal tract (exception: polypectomy and cholecystectomy) On initial endoscopy, presence of obstructive esophageal strictures, Schatzki's ring, esophageal diverticula, esophageal varices, achalasia or Barrett's esophagus with known highgrade dysplasia or longer than 3 cm Acute peptic ulcer and/or ulcer complications Pyloric stenosis Known inflammatory bowel diseases</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>GERD</keyword>
	<keyword>Pantoprazole</keyword>
	<keyword>NERD</keyword>
</DOC>