<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02516449</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether the use of shared decision making aids is more effective than usual care in improving asthma knowledge, lessening decisional conflict, and enhancing adherence to treatments and asthma control in adult patients with mild to severe asthma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of Shared Decision Making Aids in Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Men or women, aged 18 to 65 years; 2. Current diagnosis of mild to severe asthma; 2.1) Asthma diagnosis will be made upon one of the following criteria: 2.1.1) Forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV1) increases by at least 12% after the use of a bronchodilator (and a minimum ≥ 200 mL); 2.1.2) Current asthma symptoms and a positive methacholine challenge test (20% fall in FEV1 after inhalation of a provocative dose of methacholine 16 mg/mL); 2.1.3) A respirologist's current diagnosis of asthma found in the patient's medical report. 2.2) Severity of asthma will be assessed according to prescribed pharmacotherapy, as suggested by the 2012 Canadian Thoracic Society Guidelines: 2.2.1) Patients with mild asthma using SABA as well as low doses (≤250 mcg/day beclomethasone or equivalent) of inhaled glucocorticosteroids; 2.2.2) Patients with moderate asthma using SABA as well as low to moderate doses (250mcg/day &lt; dose ≤500 mcg/day beclomethasone or equivalent) of inhaled glucocorticosteroids, with or without additional therapy (LABA or LTRA); 2.2.3) Patients with severe asthma using high doses (&gt;500 mcg/day beclomethasone or equivalent) of inhaled glucocorticosteroids, and additional pharmacotherapy (LABA, LTRA, or Prednisone), and SABA. 1. Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD); 2. Education on asthma in the last 6 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>