<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02516202</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a new application from the Menopause Strategies: Finding Lasting Answers for Symptoms and Health (MsFLASH) Clinical Trials network. Here we propose to conduct a large multicenter trial comparing two common treatments, a vaginal hormone tablet and an over-the-counter gel, with placebo to evaluate their effects on bothersome vaginal symptoms and sexual function, and to create a biorepository of specimens for future translational, mechanistic research on the etiology of vaginal symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Vaginal Health Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Menopause Strategies: Finding Lasting Answers for Symptoms and Health (MsFLASH) Clinical Trials network was established in 2009. By the end of 2014, the network completed 4 clinical trials testing 7 interventions in approximately 1000 women ages 40-62 with vasomotor (VMS) and other menopause symptoms. The current trial will evaluate a relatively understudied area of menopause - vaginal health and sexual function. This is a 3-arm, randomized, controlled, double-blind, clinical trial among postmenopausal women ages 45-70. Our primary aim is to evaluate the effectiveness of ultra-low dose vaginal estradiol (Vagifem 10 mcg), non-hormonal hydrophilic non-prescriptive vaginal gel (Replens) and placebo in reducing the Most Bothersome vaginal Symptom (MBS). Secondary aims include an evaluation of a composite score of vaginal symptoms (dryness, itching, irritation or soreness), sexual function, quality of life and genitourinary atrophy. We will also create a biorepository of vaginal and blood specimens. In a subset of women, we will examine whether treatment response is related to: a) the post-menopausal vaginal microbiome; b) vaginal mucosal inflammation; and c) reproductive hormone profiles. The in-depth focus on the mechanisms associated with postmenopausal vaginal symptoms will use state of the art microbiologic techniques on longitudinally collected biologic specimens and will guide future translational studies.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyspareunia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaginal Discharge</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polyestradiol phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol 3-benzoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol 17 beta-cypionate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol valerate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psyllium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium polycarbophil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Females aged 4570 years 2 or more years since last natural menstrual period, or surgical menopause (bilateral oophorectomy) At least 1 vaginal symptom (inside or outside the vagina) reported from the following list, experienced in the past 30 days which is moderate or severe: Dryness at least once a week Itching at least once a week Irritation at least once a week Soreness/Pain at least once a week Pain associated with sexual activity at least once Signed informed consent Exclusion Criteria Current unexplained abnormal genital bleeding (or any unevaluated bleeding since menopause) Currently pregnant, attempting pregnancy or breast feeding Current acute vaginal infection (as indicated by wet mount at V1) Pelvic or vaginal surgery in prior 60 days Antibiotic use in the past 30 days Women under age 55 with endometrial ablation Women under age 55 with hysterectomy and at least one ovary Current cancer treatment (exception basal or squamous skin cell cancers) Current or past thromboembolic disease (pulmonary embolus or deep vein thrombosis, not including thrombophlebitis), myocardial infarction or stroke Current severe liver disease Current or past breast or endometrial cancer or precancer Blood clotting disorder (e.g., Factor V Leiden, prothrombin mutation, protein C, protein or antithrombin deficiency) Porphyria Current or past lichen sclerosus or lichen planus History of adverse reaction to vaginal estrogen or Replens Use of any systemic reproductive hormones (hormonal contraception, postmenopausal hormone therapies, SERMS) in the past 2 months Use of hormonal contraception in the past year Use of any type of vaginal estrogen product (however interested women will be allowed to join the study if they abstain from use during the month preceding enrollment) Use of any type of vaginal moisturizer, douche, vaginal prebiotic or probiotic, or soap in the vagina in the past month (however interested women will be allowed to join the study if they abstain from use during the month preceding enrollment) Unwilling to abstain from use of any nonstudy vaginal moisturizer, vaginal estrogen, douche, or soap in the vagina throughout the trial Unable to follow instructions, complete questionnaires, or physically unable to place product in the vagina Current participation in another drug trial or intervention study Chronic vulvovaginal symptoms in the 5 years before menopause (defined as a vaginal or vulvar condition requiring more than 4 visits to a health care provider in a given year)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>