<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02516163</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective, non-randomized, study of the clinical outcomes of participants that receive the Stryker Triathlon® Total Knee System for Total Knee Arthroplasty implanted using ShapeMatch® Cutting Guides.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Stryker Triathlon Total Knee System for Total Knee Arthroplasty Implanted Using Shapematch Cutting Guides:Sub-Study A</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, non-randomized, study of the clinical outcomes of participants that receive the Stryker Triathlon® Total Knee System for Total Knee Arthroplasty implanted using ShapeMatch® Cutting Guides. Sub-study A aims to quantify the reproducibility of intra-operatively positioning the cutting guides onto the affected femoral and tibial joint surfaces.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>The patient is a male or nonpregnant female between the ages of 5090. The patient requires a primary total knee replacement and is indicated for computerassisted surgery. The patient has a primary diagnosis of osteoarthritis (OA). The patient has intact collateral ligaments. The patient is able to undergo MRI scanning of the affected limb. The patient has signed the study specific, HRECapproved, Informed Consent document. The patient is willing and able to comply with the specified preoperative and postoperative clinical and radiographic evaluations. The patient has a history of total, unicompartmental reconstruction or fusion of the affected joint. The patient has had a high tibial osteotomy or femoral osteotomy. The patient is morbidly obese (BMI ≥ 40). The patient has a deformity which will require the use of stems, wedges or augments in conjunction with the Triathlon Total Knee System. The patient has a varus/valgus malalignment ≥ 15° (relative to mechanical axis). The patient has a fixed flexion deformity ≥ 15°. The patient has a neuromuscular or neurosensory deficiency, which would limit the ability to assess the performance of the device. The patient has a systemic or metabolic disorder leading to progressive bone deterioration. The patient is immunologically suppressed or receiving steroids in excess of normal physiological requirements. The patient has a cognitive impairment, an intellectual disability or a mental illness. The patient is pregnant. The patient has metal hardware present in the region of the hip, knee or ankle (as this is known to create geometrical distortion in the region of the implant). The patient has any known contraindications for undergoing assessment by MRI (e.g. ferrous implants, metallic clips, magnetically activated implanted devices such as cardiac pacemakers, etc).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>