<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02516540</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The hypothesis of this 3 year, prospective randomized multicenter efficacy trial is that a structured life-style intervention program with exercise training and mediterranean diet is effective regarding increased adherence to a mediterranean diet, reduction of body mass index, and increase of physical fitness.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Lifestyle Intervention in BRCA1/2 Mutation Carriers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>BRCA1/2 mutation carriers have a considerably increased risk to develop breast and ovarian cancer during their lifetime. There is evidence from the literature that for sporadic breast cancer disease risk and the course of disease can be significantly influenced by physical activity, nutrition and weight. The hypothesis of this 3 year, prospective randomized multicenter efficacy trial is that a structured life-style intervention program with exercise training and mediterranean diet is effective regarding increased adherence to a mediterranean diet, reduction of body mass index, and increase of physical fitness.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hereditary Breast and Ovarian Cancer Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>proven pathogenic BRCA1/2 mutation age &gt;=18 written informed consent current chemotherapy of radiotherapy (inclusion 6 weeks after CTX or RX possible) metastatic tumor disease life expectancy &lt;3 years clinically limiting cardiovascular or respiratory disease (instable CVD, heart failure stage IV, COPD GOLD IV, maximum resting blood pressure 160/100 mmHg) significant orthopedic disability which prevents from participating in the group interventions severe concomitant diseases which prevents from participating in the group interventions Karnofsky index &lt;60 maximum exercise capacity &lt;50 W food allergies which prevent from mediterranean diet vegan diet body mass index &lt;15 kg/m2 pregnancy insufficient knowledge of German language insufficient compliance active participation in other interventional trials</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>hereditary breast and ovarian cancer (HBOC)</keyword>
	<keyword>BRCA1/2 mutation carriers</keyword>
	<keyword>Mediterranean diet</keyword>
	<keyword>Structured exercise training</keyword>
	<keyword>prevention</keyword>
</DOC>