<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02237703</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study uses positron emission tomography (PET) imaging to measure kappa opioid receptors (KOR) in the brains of individuals with and without post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). The investigators propose to recruit 45 drug-naïve individuals, N=15 patients with PTSD, N=15 trauma-exposed, but asymptomatic healthy control subjects (TC) and N=15 non-trauma exposed healthy control subjects (HC) to participate in one magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and one PET study. The investigators will also carefully document trauma history, and collect behavioral and neuroendocrine measures to provide a more integrative view on the neurobiology of PTSD and its phenotype. The investigators predict PTSD will show greater carbon - 11 (11C)[11C]LY2795050 volume of distribution (VT) (i.e. KOR binding) values than control populations in an a priori defined PTSD circuit.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Kappa Opioid Receptor Imaging in Post-traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Analgesics, Opioid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for patients with PTSD: 1. age 1855 years old 2. currently diagnosed with PTSD and symptomatic with a ClinicianAdministered PTSD Scale (CAPS) score &gt; 50. Exclusion criteria for patients with PTSD: 1. any primary Axis I disorder other than PTSD (e.g. psychosis) 2. medical or neurological illnesses likely to affect physiology or anatomy, i.e. uncontrolled hypertension, cardiovascular disorders 3. a history of drug (including benzodiazepines (BZD)) dependence (Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM IV) criteria) within 1 year of the study and lasting longer than 2 years, except for alcohol dependence 4. current pregnancy (as documented by pregnancy testing at screening or on the day of PET imaging study) 5. current breast feeding 6. use of tobacco or nicotinecontaining products in excess of the equivalent of 5 cigarettes per day, or cannot abstain from smoking during the prescribed tests 7. acute suicidal ideation or behavior, as defined by suicidal ideation and behavior during the 3month period prior to enrollment in the study and while being enrolled in the study 8. general MRI exclusion criteria, i.e. pacemakers, metals in the body 9. Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) (due to possible neuropsychiatric effects); 10. use of opioid medications within 2 weeks of the PET study 11. having an abnormality in the 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG) that, in the opinion of the investigator, increases the risks associated with participation in the study 12. seriously claustrophobic 13. blood donation within 8 weeks prior to the study. Inclusion criteria for Healthy Subjects: 1. age 1855 years old 2. no personal or firstdegree family history of any Axis I diagnosis. Exclusion criteria for Healthy Subjects: 1. any history or current primary Axis I disorder 2. medical or neurological illnesses likely to affect physiology or anatomy, i.e. uncontrolled hypertension, cardiovascular disorders 3. a history of drug (including benzodiazepines [BZD]) dependence (DSM IV criteria) within 1 year of the study and lasting longer than 2 years, except for alcohol dependence 4. current pregnancy (as documented by pregnancy testing at screening or on the day of PET imaging study) 5. current breast feeding 6. use of tobacco or nicotinecontaining products in excess of the equivalent of 5 cigarettes per day, or cannot abstain from smoking during the prescribed tests 7. acute suicidal ideation or behavior, as defined by suicidal ideation and behavior during the 3month period prior to enrollment in the study and while being enrolled in the study 8. general MRI exclusion criteria, i.e. pacemakers, metals in the body 9. HIV (due to possible neuropsychiatric effects) 10. use of opioid medications within 2 weeks of the PET study 11. having an abnormality in the 12lead ECG that, in the opinion of the investigator, increases the risks associated with participation in the study 12. seriously claustrophobic 13. blood donation within 8 weeks prior to the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Post-traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Positron emission tomography (PET)</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuroimaging</keyword>
	<keyword>Kappa opioid receptor (KOR)</keyword>
</DOC>