<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01189630</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Observational Study in the "Real World" of Implantable Electronic Cardiac Devices will enable the construction of an electronic database with local access to clinical information, which will collect and disseminate epidemiologic data on demography, cardiovascular mortality and morbidity, and potential risk factors for a selected group of patients. These clinical variables will be analyzed against the data, as based in the programming of devices and the diagnostics. Approved descriptive statistics and analyses will be made available via Internet. The study will describe statistical indexes on sub-groups representing more than 10% of total of datasets. The study will be open to include any patient that had a Medtronic electronic device implanted, pacemakers, ICD, ICD with CRP. The study will be also adapted for devices implanted in the present and for devices to be implanted in patients in the future.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Medtronic Observational Study in the "Real World" of Implantable Electronic Cardiac Devices</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a Prospective, Multicenter Observational Post Market Release Study. It shall involve around 2,000 patients that are eligible for Implantable Cardiac Pacemakers (IPG) implantation, 500 patients eligible for Cardiac Resynchronization Pacemakers (CRT-P) implantation, 1,000 patients eligible for the implantation of Implantable Cardioverter Defibrillators with or without Cardiac Resynchronization Pacemakers (CDI, CRT-D), and around 20 centers in Brazil. Patients will be consecutively enrolled in centers among those selected for the implantation of a Medtronic device in accordance with indications approved.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients older than18 years of age Patient agrees to participate in the study and is able to sign the Data Release Form High probability of adherence to followup requirements Patients who want to be enrolled in another clinical study during at the same time that he/she is part of OBSERVE study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>95 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>"Real World" Electronic Database with clinical information</keyword>
	<keyword>related to Implantable Cardiac devices.</keyword>
</DOC>