<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01189682</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Catheter related infection is a frequent and life threatening event in ICU. A chlorhexidine impregnated sponge has been proven to reduce the rate of major catheter related infections in ICU patients (HR=0.39, p=0.03) (Timsit Jama 2009). However, dressings are detached in 40% of cases before planned changes and the rate of unplanned dressing is significantly associated with the major catheter related infections. Primary objective: To demonstrate that Tegaderm CHG, a new CHG impregnated dressing decrease the rate of major catheter related infection as compared to non impregnated dressings and to demonstrate that highly adhesive dressing decrease the rate of detached dressings. Secondary objectives: - To demonstrate that the use of high performance dressing decrease the rate of unstuck dressing and the rate of catheter infections. - To evaluate the tolerance of CHG impregnated gel dressings (Tegaderm CHG). - To calculate the cost saving of each dressings</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Tegaderm HP and CHG in Major Catheter Related Infections and Dressing Detachment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Inclusion criteria: Patients older than 18 years old with central venous who need a central vein and/or an arterial catheter for an expected duration of more than 48 hours.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Catheter-Related Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients older than 18 years old with a central venous catheter or arterial catheter installed in the study departement for a maximum for 24 hours pulmonary arterial catheter antisepticimpregnated catheter hemodialysis catheter chlorhexidine allergy emergency catheter without surgical asepsis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>catheter</keyword>
	<keyword>dressing</keyword>
	<keyword>chlorhexidine</keyword>
	<keyword>Patient admitted in ICU with a CVC or art. catheter</keyword>
</DOC>