<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01006798</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the safety and immunogenicity over a 9-month period of five different dosages of Ad4-H5-Vtn in volunteers (Vaccinees) who receive three doses of the study vaccine or placebo. In addition, transmission of Ad4-H5-Vtn will be evaluated in all Household Contacts residing with the vaccinated volunteers. Vaccinees also may participate in a substudy in which they receive a booster vaccination with the licensed Influenza Virus Vaccine, H5N1 (Sanofi Pasteur).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Immunogenicity of Replication-Competent Adenovirus 4-vectored Vaccine for Avian Influenza H5N1</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>At least 160 healthy Vaccinees will be randomized into 5 ascending dosage cohorts each consisting of at least 32 volunteers. In each dosage cohort Vaccinees will be randomly assigned to receive 3 doses of either Ad4-H5-Vtn or placebo separated by approximately 56 days. Volunteers will be followed for 168 days post-third vaccination.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy adults and their healthy adult household contacts. Healthcare workers who have direct contact with patients who are immunodeficient, are HIVpositive, have an unstable medical condition, or are under the age of 18. Childcare workers who have direct contact with children 5 years old and younger. Resides with Household Contacts who are under the age of 18 or over the age of 65. Received or plans to receive licensed inactivated 2009 H1N1 influenza vaccine from 14 days prior to 14 days after any study vaccination. Received or plans to receive any other licensed vaccines from 30 days prior to the first study vaccination until 30 days after the third study vaccination.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Virus Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Respiratory Tract Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Vaccine</keyword>
</DOC>