<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01006811</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Infantile spasms constitute a type of catastrophic epilepsy syndrome occuring in young children. The ketogenic diet has been shown to be very effective in these children. The modified Atkins diet is a less restrictive option than the ketogenic diet, which has been effective in preliminary studies on refractory epilepsy in children, adolescents and adults. Modified Atkins diet may be of special importance in infants, as proteins are not restricted, hence no problems with growth are expected. Hence this pilot study has been planned to evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of the modified Atkins diet in infantile spasms refractory to conventional treatment (ACTH, vigabatrin, and anti-epileptic drugs).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of the Modified Atkins Diet in Infantile Spasms</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Spasm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spasms, Infantile</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age: 6 months to 3 years. 2. Presence of epileptic spasms in clusters, with electroencephalographic evidence of hypsarrhythmia or its variants), having at least one cluster per day. 3. Treatment with at least corticosteroid/ ACTH or Vigabatrin and one other AED( sodium valproate, pyridoxine, topiramate, zonisamide, benzodiazepines (clobazam, clonazepam, nitrazepam). 1. Known or suspected inborn error of metabolism, as evidenced by: Clinical suspicion of metabolic disorder as evidenced by 2 or more of the following a history of parental consanguinity, prior affected siblings, unexplained vomiting, intermittent worsening of symptoms, recurrent episodes of lethargy, altered sensorium, or ataxia, hepatosplenomegaly on examination And/ or 2 or more of the following biochemical abnormalities High blood ammonia (&gt;80mmol/L), High arterial lactate (&gt;2 mmol/L), metabolic acidosis (pH &lt;7.2), hypoglycaemia (blood sugar &lt;40 mg/dl), abnormal urinary aminoacidogram, presence of reducing sugars or ketones in urine, and positive results on urine neurometabolic screening tests. 2. Motivational or psychosocial issues in the family which would preclude compliance 3. Systemic illness chronic hepatic, cardiac, renal or pulmonary disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>3 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>West syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypsarrhythmia</keyword>
</DOC>