<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02827383</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot study seeks to demonstrate feasibility to conduct data collection and illustrate potential for effect of fractionalized bouts of stair climbing on glucose control in adults at risk for type 2 diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Stair Climbing Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objective: Compare the short-term effects of two different fractionalized stair climbing bout protocols on glucose control among adults at risk for type 2 diabetes. Rationale: Fractionalized physical activity is associated with reduced BMI, glycated hemoglobin, lower 2-hr plasma glucose and insulin sensitivity in cross-sectional studies. Yet, few studies have examined the effects of fractionalized or intermittent physical activity in a prospective manner. Furthermore, the research is limited to patients with diagnosed type 2 diabetes, or using exercise of a moderate intensity. The hypothesis is that stair climbing, a vigorous-intensity activity, may have a greater health effect. However, this has not been tested in short bouts of activity that are spread out during a day. Implications: Fractionalized physical activity may be more feasible for adults at risk for, or with diagnosed type 2 diabetes who are not currently active. These short bouts can increase energy expenditure throughout the day, rather than in one long continuous bout as currently recommended.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prediabetic State</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age greater than 40 years but less than 65 years (working age adult with reduce physiologic capacity to regulate glucose) BMI of overweight or obese (25.0 to 35.0) Answered "No" to all questions on the Physical Activity Readiness Questionnaire, or has physician approval to participate Hemoglobin A1C% value in the atrisk range of 5.7 to 6.4 Unable to physically perform stair climbing Currently exercising for 60 or more minutes weekly. Weight over 275 lbs (because stair climbing machine has a weight limit)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>