<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02827825</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to describe the population of patients admitted to the ICU in neurosurgery for stroke requiring secondary care in intensive care and their future.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Patients Undergoing Strokes Admitted in Intensive Care Requiring Neurosurgical ICU Crossing: Patient Profile and Prognosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Methodology : DESIGN: Retrospective observational study single center, non-interventional Term study over 2 years, retrospectively Acquisition of data: - Study of computer file: report available on DxCare hospital and Cora - Collection of data as excel spreadsheet - Statistical analysis: local management - Anonymity of data: - For each subject will be awarded an identifier (original name and surname - year of birth) and the data will be entered on a computer file which will be sent to the statistician in charge of analyzing the GHPSJ site. There will be no exchange of personal data for this study is single center on the site GHPSJ. Development of the study: - Procedure: - Series includable patients from the PMSI data - Select folders according the inclusion criteria - Collecting information from files on Excel spreadsheet by the internal charge of data collection (Sylvain CHAWKI) - Statistical Analysis - Writing Article - Expected duration of patient recruitment: Retrospective of 2 and a half years from January 1, 2013 to April 31, 2015</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Admitted USINV for ischemic or hemorrhagic stroke Admitted secondarily in ICU Admission in ICU in first Administrative Admission in Intensive Care Requiring Neurosurgical within the thrombolysis alert regulated by the neurovascular guard but going directly to ICU imaging waning Subarachnoid hemorrhage</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neurosurgical</keyword>
	<keyword>Intensive Care</keyword>
</DOC>