<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03006731</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the effects of an exercise training strategy called high-intensity interval training (HIIT) to moderate intensity continuous exercise (MICE), on walking function and cardiovascular fitness in stroke patients. Hypothesis: HIIT will result in significantly greater benefit to fitness and mobility than MICE.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>High Intensity Interval Training for People With Stroke Deficits</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Using a randomized design, the study will evaluate the effects of 3 HIT sessions combined with 2 MICE sessions per week on cardiovascular fitness and mobility compared to MICE training 5 days/week. Participants post-stroke will be randomly assigned to either MICE (5 days per week (d∙wk-1)) or combined HIIT (3 d∙wk-1) with MICE (2 d∙wk-1). Both groups will be exercising 5 times per week (walking on a treadmill with harness for fall protection); 3 times at the centre and 2 times at home. Outcome measures will be conducted before and after 24 weeks of training.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<criteria>clinical diagnosis of stroke (hemorrhagic or ischemic), ability to walk at least 100 m independently with or without an assistive device with no severe limitations due to pain, living in the community at least 10 weeks post stroke (no upper limit) with a strokerelated motor impairment score of &lt;7 on the ChedokeMcMaster Stroke Assessment scale of the leg or foot or with hemiparetic gait pattern, no severe communicative aphasia or comprehensive aphasia as noted in in clinical reports or referral form no orthopedic issues that may be aggravated by HIT ability to provide informed consent severe uncontrolled hypertension or orthostatic blood pressure decrease of &gt;20 mmHg other cardiovascular morbidities which would limit exercise tolerance (e.g. horizontal or downsloping STsegment depression &gt;2 mm, symptomatic aortic stenosis, complex arrhythmias), unstable angina, severe proliferative retinopathy or uncontrolled blood glucose, hypertrophic cardiomyopathy lower extremity claudication cognitive and/or behavioral issues limiting participation in exercise testing and training, prior unrelated neurological disorders or psychiatric illness abdominal or inguinal hernia causing discomfort with routine activities. Other issues will be considered casebycase.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>