<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03006575</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This Phase II randomized study is to determine the efficacy of consolidation chemotherapy after split irradiation with concurrent chemotherapy in locoregional recurrence of non-small cell lung cancer after surgical resection</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Consolidation Chemotherapy For Locoregional Recurrence Of Non-small Cell Lung Cancer After Surgical Resection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This Phase II randomized study is to determine the efficacy of consolidation chemotherapy (CC) after split-course chemoradiotherapy (CCRT) in locoregional recurrence of non-small cell lung cancer after surgical resection. Patients were randomly assigned to either CCRT alone (observation arm) or CCRT followed by CC (consolidation arm). All patients received four cycles of weekly docetaxel (25mg/㎡) and nedaplatin (25mg/㎡)(DP), each of 1 day's duration, combined with split-course thoracic radiotherapy of 51 Gy/17 fractions and 15 Gy/5 fractions administered in the first and second courses, respectively, with one-month break. In the consolidation arm, patients were further treated with two cycles of pemetrexed (500mg/㎡) in non-squamous lung cancer or docetaxel (60mg/㎡) in squamous lung cancer, each of 3 days' duration, every 3 weeks. The primary end point is progression-free survival, which is the time that passes from the first day of radiotherapy to the date on which disease progresses. Progression-free survival will be calculated and compared using the Kaplan-Meier method. Toxicities will be graded according to CTCAE v. 4.0.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pathologic confirmation of NSCLC. Patients have measurable or evaluable lesions based on the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) criteria. Postoperative locoregional recurrence including ipsilateral hemithorax and the mediastinum. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 01. Previously treated with chemotherapy or treatmentnaive No previous chest radiotherapy, immunotherapy or biotherapy Hemoglobin≥10 mg/dL, platelet≥100000/μL,absolute neutrophil count ≥1500/μL Serum creatinine ≤1.25 times the upper normal limit(UNL), or creatinine clearance≥60 ml/min Bilirubin ≤1.5 times UNL, AST（SGOT）≤2.5 times UNL ,ALT（SGPT）≤2.5 times UNL,alkaline phosphatase ≤5 times UNL Forced expiratory volume at one second (FEV1) &gt;0.8 L Coagulation tests within normal limits patients and their family signed the informed consents Previous or recent another malignancy, except nonmelanoma skin cancer or cervical cancer in situ Second primary carcinoma of the lung Contraindication for chemotherapy Malignant pleural or pericardial effusion. Women in pregnancy, lactation period, or no pregnancy test 14 days before the first dos Women who has the probability of pregnancy without contraception Tendency of hemorrhage In other clinical trials within 30 days Addicted in drugs or alcohol, AIDS patients Uncontrollable seizure or psychotic patients without selfcontrol ability Severe allergy or idiosyncrasy Not suitable for this study judged by researchers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Split-course Chemoradiotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Locoregional recurrence</keyword>
	<keyword>Postoperative recurrence</keyword>
	<keyword>Consolidation chemotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>