<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01982578</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Genistein is an isoflavone that has antioxidant and neuroprotective effects on Alzheimer's disease (AD). A few years ago our group reported that genistein increased PPARg (peroxisome proliferator activated receptor gamma) levels. By the way, activation of retinoid X receptor (RXR)-PPARg dimer, will make overexpressing apolipoprotein E (apoE), which mediates the degradation of amyloid beta (AB). Therefore, we believe that if this phytoestrogen administration increases the availability of the transcription factor, it can increase apoE, and also AB degradation. The main aim of this study is to determinate the effect of 60 mg BID of genistein administration, during 180 days, compared to placebo group, in AD patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Genistein as a Possible Treatment for Alzheimer's Disease.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Alzheimer's disease is devastating in terms of personal wellbeing as well as for society. Any effort to prevent and/or treat this disease is always sought after. Recently, an exciting new possibility was opened by modulating a cellular component called RXR-PPARG. A successful experimental treatment for Alzheimer's was found by activating RXR. But we previously showed that a component of soya, i.e., genistein, is able to activate the other part of the RXR-PPARG molecule, i.e., the PPARG moiety. Genistein, moreover, does not have the undesirable effect of bexarotene and is a food component. Our preliminary results in animals indicate that genistein is effective in the treatment of experimental Alzheimer's in mice. Epidemiological evidence shows that individuals who live in Eastern societies who have a high genistein intake (because they eat a lot of soya) have lower rates of Alzheimer's disease. Thus we propose a controlled clinical trial to test if administration of the food component genistein is able to prevent or cure, at least partially, Alzheimer's disease.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Genistein</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with mild cognitive impairment (MCI) compatible with prodromal AD. MiniMental State Examinations (MMSE) score between over 24 inclusive. CSF levels of AB, pTAU compatible with AD. 18 years or older. Must have a study partner who is able and willing to comply with all required study procedures. Willing and able to provide informed consent by either the subject or subject's legal representative. Patient who does not meet the inclusion criteria. Thyroid abnormalities with or without treatment. Immune abnormalities in blood analyses. Patient suffers hormone dependent neoplasia. Take a diet rich on isoflavones.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Genistein</keyword>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Cerebrospinal fluid</keyword>
	<keyword>Amyloid beta</keyword>
</DOC>