<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02330406</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether Anagliptin or Sitagliptin are effective in reducing the low-density lipoprotein cholesterol in patients with type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular risk factors on statin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized Evaluation of Anagliptin Versus Sitagliptin On Low-density lipoproteiN Cholesterol in Diabetes Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Diabetes is a significant cause of cardiovascular and cerebrovascular events. Especially, diabetic patients with cardiovascular risk factors were significantly higher risk for cardiovascular and cerebrovasculara event. Therefore, several medical management strategies including anti-diabetic medications and statins were considered for those patients. However, in spite of such treatment, still many patients have cardiovascular and cerebrovascular events. One of the hypothesis is the residual risk such as elevated low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDLC) even with statin therapy. Anagliptin, one of the dipeptidyl peptidase-4 (DPP4) inhibiors, was reported to reduce LDLC and may have pontential to decrease the cardiovascular and cerebrovascular risk for such patients on statins. We, thus, conduct a randomized controlled trial to compare Anagliptin or Sitagliptin in terms of change of LDLC for 52 weeks as well as glycemic control.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sitagliptin Phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with type 2 diabetes with cardiovascular risk factors (*) who treated with diet, exercise or antidiabetic medications Patients who were treated with statins for 8 weeks or longer Patients with lowdensity lipoprotein cholesterol equal to or greater than 100 mg/dL in the at least one of three measurements after the administration of statins Patients with glycerated hemoglobin (HbA1c, NGSP) equal to or greater than 6.0 % (7.0 % if patients were not treated with dipeptidylpeptidase 4 inhibitors) and lesser than 10.5 % (*) cardiovascular risk factors were any of following conditions 1. Presence of stenosis (&gt;=25%) or plaque on the previous coronary angiography or coronary CT 2. Presence of coronary calcification on the previous coronary CT 3. History of acute coronary syndrome 4. History of percutaneous coronary intervention or coronary artery bypass graft 5. History of stroke (ischemic stroke or hemorrhagic stroke) 6. History of transient ischemic attack 7. History of peripheral artery diseases or aortic disorders 8. AnkleBrachial Index (AMI) equal to or less than 0.9 in the past measurement 9. Presence of carotid artery plaque (including Max IMT &gt;=1.1mm) on carotid ultrasonography in the past Patients with type 1 diabetes Patients with triglyceride equal to or greater than 400 mg/dL in the previous fasting measurements Patients with pregnancy, possible pregnancy, or on breastfeeding Patients with severe infections, perioperative status, or severe trauma Patients with renal dysfunction (creatinine &gt;= 2.4 mg/dl for men, &gt;= 2.0 mg/dl for women) Patients who were received glucagonlike peptide1receptor agonists Patients whom physician in charge considered inappropriate for the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dipeptidyl-Peptidase 4 Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>LDL Cholesterol</keyword>
	<keyword>Glycosylated Hemoglobin</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary Disease</keyword>
</DOC>