<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01367067</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of the study is to search for possible predictors for claustrophobia during magnetic resonance (MR) imaging. A claustrophobic event shall be defined by an incomplete examination, or a complete examination that requires coping actions by the staff. Coping actions may consist of the administration of sedatives, prism glasses, an MR imaging test run with the patient, a pause, the prone position, an escort in the scanner room, and supportive communication. The investigators hypothesize that there is a difference between patients with and without events in their scores on the Claustrophobia Questionnaire and several further psychometric questions. Other factors may also favour events like patient characteristics, examined region, duration of the examination and scanner type. Therefore, predictors could identify patients who are likely to experience claustrophobia during MR imaging so that they can receive the appropriate support by the staff to complete their examination. Thus a larger patient population could benefit from MR imaging.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prediction of Claustrophobia During MR Imaging</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Phobic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inpatients and outpatients referred to MR imaging with a clinical indication of any part of the body Mentally and physically able to fill out a questionnaire Sufficient German language skills Age under 18 years Patients from the Intensive Care Unit Severe emergencies Surgery during MR imaging Participation in other studies Fetal and prenatal examinations Referral from medical jurisprudence</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>claustrophobia</keyword>
	<keyword>magnetic resonance imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>anxious patients</keyword>
	<keyword>phobic disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>anxiety disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>mental disorders</keyword>
</DOC>