<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01504204</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare adherence to treatment and efficacy with Epiduo® Gel in patients with mild to moderate acne who receive a medication sample and instructions on proper application with their stock size medication tube versus patients who receive only the stock size medication tube.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Samples on Acne Treatment With Epiduo® Gel</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Acne Vulgaris</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adapalene</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adapalene, Benzoyl Peroxide Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Benzoyl Peroxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subject with mild to moderate acne, aged 12 and older, who agrees to participate and provides written consent. Have an Acne Global Assessment (AGA) of mild to moderate acne (an AGA score of 2 or 3) Presence of a concurrent medical condition or skin condition, which is determined by the investigator to potentially interfere with study outcomes or patient assessments. Subjects with known allergy or sensitivity to Epiduo® Gel (or Benzoyl Peroxide Gel) or components therein, including adapalene or benzoyl peroxide Female subjects who are not postmenopausal for at least 1 year, surgically sterile, or willing to practice effective contraception during the study. Reliable methods of birth control are: abstinence (not having sex), oral contraceptives, intrauterine device (IUD), DepoProvera, tubal ligation, or vasectomy of the partner (with confirmed negative sperm counts) in a monogamous relationship (same partner). An acceptable, although less reliable, method involves the careful use of condoms and spermicidal foam or gel and/or a cervical cap or sponge. Nursing mothers, pregnant women and women planning to become pregnant while on study are to be excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>adapalene</keyword>
	<keyword>benzoyl peroxide</keyword>
	<keyword>sample</keyword>
	<keyword>topical treatment</keyword>
</DOC>