<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02200510</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to develop patient-provider clinical support tools to improve clinical practice, patient self-management, and disease outcomes in sickle cell disease during transition to adult care. The investigators hypothesize that these clinical support tools (patient tool, provider tool, and patient/parent web-based portal) will be feasible, user friendly, and beneficial. The investigators hypothesize that participants will demonstrate better disease self-efficacy at the end of the 6 week intervention and maintain these gains during the follow-up period (up to 1 year post-intervention).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Patient-Provider Tools to Improve the Transition to Adult Care in Sickle Cell Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of the study is to develop patient-provider clinical support tools to improve clinical practice, patient self-management, and disease outcomes in sickle cell disease during transition to adult care.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have sickle cell disease (SCD) Between the ages of 13 and 24 Receive care at Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center, University Hospital, University of Cincinnati Med Peds Practice, a practice in the Ohio Valley SCD Network, or another local provider Parent/caregiver of a patient with SCD age 1324 years Below age 13 Have significant health complication(s) that would interfere with completion of the intervention (by physician report) Have significant cognitive or developmental disabilities (by parent or physician report) due to high demand on participants to understand questions Are not a patient at Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center, University Hospital, University of Cincinnati Med Peds Practice, a practice in the Ohio Valley SCD Network, or another local provider Are not a parent/caregiver of a patient with SCD age 1324 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anemia, Sickle Cell</keyword>
	<keyword>Transition to Adult Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Self Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Personal Electronic Health Records</keyword>
	<keyword>Adolescent</keyword>
	<keyword>Young Adult</keyword>
	<keyword>Disease Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Physician-Patient Relations</keyword>
</DOC>