<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02948036</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Specific Aim 1: Finalize development of the closed-loop strategy in the Moodify application. Specific Aim 2: Evaluate the acceptability and feasibility of the Moodify application with the target population to prepare for a large-scale efficacy trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Closed-loop Assessment and Treatment Platform for Mood Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Specific Aim 1: Investigators have recently constructed a beta version of the Moodify application, comprised of the multi-modal assessment modules, several treatment modules and an initial version of the closed-loop algorithm to control treatment delivery. Utilizing the extensive experience in developing mobile assessment and treatment tools at Posit Science Corporation, the investigators will employ an iterative development process incorporating feedback from users (focus groups of patients with mood disorders), clinicians and scientists (project consultants) to achieve the following development goals: (1) Finalize Moodify's closed-loop algorithm to incorporate all assessment modules and expand the existing triage approach; (2) Expand cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) functions within the app; and (3) Expand in-app bi-directional communication feature between the clinician and user. At the completion of Specific Aim 1, the investigators will have a mobile app suitable for evaluation in a feasibility trial (Specific Aim 2). Specific Aim 2: The investigators will conduct a single arm, open label feasibility field trial with 25 participants that meet criteria for Major Depressive Disorder (MDD). Participants will be asked to engage with the experimental cognitive treatment and spend up to six weeks engaged in 15 hours of cognitive training as an adjunct to their standard clinical treatment. The experimental cognitive treatment will be deployed as dictated by the closed loop predictive algorithm, with all patient data continuously accessible for remote monitoring by the attending clinicians and Posit Science Corporation (PSC) clinician and Principal Investigator, Dr. Thomas Van Vleet. Participants will be re-evaluated every two weeks during treatment use, and again at the expected time of completion of training, at 6 weeks, to evaluate changes in cognitive function. Participants will then stop using their assigned program for 6 weeks, and return for a follow-up assessment to evaluate the endurance of changes in cognitive function in the absence of further program use.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mood Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Participant meets Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM)5 diagnostic criteria for Major Depressive Disorder (MDD; confirmed by Structured Clinical Interview for DSM5 (SCID)) 2. Participants must be 18 to 60 years of age 3. Participant with a score ≥ 17 on Baseline Hamilton Rating Scale for Depression (HRSD, 17 item) 4. Participants taking antidepressants or engaged in psychotherapy will not be excluded; instead, their antidepressant treatment will be evaluated and entered as covariates in all statistical analyses 5. Participant must be a fluent English speaker from the age of 12 6. Participant must have adequate sensorimotor capacity to perform the program, including visual capacity adequate to read from a computer screen at a normal viewing distance, auditory capacity adequate to understand normal speech, and motor capacity adequate to control a computer mouse, in the judgment of the consenting clinician 7. Participant has access to wireless Internet connectivity 1. Participants with serious, unstable and/or untreated conditions that may affect cognition, including substance abuse/dependence disorders, cardiovascular, endocrine, neurologic diseases, brain injury, recent hospitalization, ongoing chemotherapy or other cancer treatment 2. Participants with history or current DSM5 diagnosis of organic mental disorder, schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder, delusion disorder, psychotic disorder not otherwise specific, bipolar disorder, substance abuse (&lt;1 year), and/or mood congruent or mood incongruent psychotic features or disorders 3. Participant with a history or current diagnosis of dementia and/or a scores within an abnormal range on the Mini Mental State Examination, based on age and education, at the time of screening 4. Participant with a history of seizure disorder 5. Participants that selfreport, or have clinical or laboratory evidence of hypothyroidism 6. Participant with a lifetime history of Electroconvulsive Therapy (ECT) or Vagus Nerve Stimulation (VNS) 7. Participant with active suicidal ideation or behaviors 8. Participants who shows signs of intoxication due to current substance abuse (including alcohol and/or illegal drugs) during any in person visit 9. Participant with problems performing assessments or comprehending or following spoken instructions, or those with behaviors during screening or baseline visits that, in the judgment of the screening clinician, are likely to present significant problems for the clinicians performing assessments or those supporting participants in the inresidence setting 10. Participant is enrolled in a concurrent clinical trial involving an investigational pharmaceutical, nutraceutical, medical device, or behavioral treatment that could affect the outcome of this study. However, participation in standard treatments (e.g., occupational therapy) or use of prescribed medications (e.g., antidepressants) is allowable. 11. Participant is using computerbased cognitive training programs or has used it within a month of the consent date</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>