<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00744744</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Gathering information about quality of life in patients with cancer may improve the ability to plan treatment and may help patients live more comfortably. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is studying health-related quality of life in patients with bladder cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Health-Related Quality of Life in Patients With Bladder Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - To identify aspects of survivorship experience that differ by clinical risk (low risk vs high risk) in patients with non-invasive bladder cancer. - To collect and examine data on health-related quality of life (HRQOL) and symptom management. - To analyze differences in outcomes between genders, stage and grade of disease, and recency of diagnosis (new diagnosis vs ≥ 6 month diagnosis). OUTLINE: Patients undergo a 45-minute telephone interview to assess their current medical condition and psychological functioning (i.e., bladder cancer treatment history, levels of depression and anxiety, quality of life, self-efficacy, and perceived social support). Patients complete a series of questionnaires including the Lepore social constraint measure; REACH social support measure; self-report inventories assessing patient communication, relationship style, illness intrusiveness, fear of recurrence, and social constraint; Impact of Events scale; Brief Symptom Index-18 and Global Severity Index; EORTC QLQ-C30 (general health-related quality of life); and EORTC QLC-BLS24 (disease-specific health-related quality of life).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of noninvasive bladder cancer within the past 4 years PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Not pregnant Able to read, speak, and understand English PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage 0 bladder cancer</keyword>
</DOC>