<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02054312</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators proposed a preliminary randomized control trial of Family Based Interpersonal Psychotherapy (FB-IPT), a family-based adaptation of Interpersonal Psychotherapy for Depressed Adolescents (IPT-A; Mufson et al., 2000). Forty-five preadolescent children (ages 8-12) diagnosed with a depressive disorder will be randomized to receive a 14-week course of FB-IPT or Client Centered Therapy (CCT), a supportive nondirective psychotherapy that closely approximates treatment at usual in community mental health clinics. In addition to assessing the feasibility and acceptability of randomization and each of the treatment conditions, this project will evaluate the effects of FB-IPT and CCT across multiple domains, including symptomatology and psychosocial functioning. Preadolescents will be assessed prior to treatment, during treatment (Weeks 3, 7, 11), one week post-treatment, and at 3 and 6 months post-treatment to compare changes in depressive symptoms, global, social, and family functioning. Data on psychosocial risk factors associated with onset and recurrence of preadolescent depression will be collected prior to treatment and at specified intervals post-treatment in order to conduct exploratory analyses on correlates of positive and negative treatment outcomes for Family Based IPT. This data will be used to generate future hypotheses about potential mediators and moderators that will be incorporated into an R01 application for an efficacy study of Family Based IPT.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Family Based Interpersonal Psychotherapy (FB-IPT) for Depressed Preadolescents</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<criteria>current depressive disorder one parent must be willing to participate in treatment bipolar disorder PTSD recent abuse developmental delay autism spectrum disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>