<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01543217</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to reduce the number of subsequent hospital admissions and/or emergency department (ED) visits for hospitalized patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) by utilizing a respiratory care practitioner-led disease management (RCP-DM) program compared to standard discharge instructions and planning.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Respiratory Disease Management</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators propose to carry out a prospective, randomized, trial at Barnes-Jewish Hospital (1250-bed urban academic hospital). Eligible patients will be identified by a senior study coordinator who will also obtain informed consent for study participation. Adults greater than 18 years of age and less than 65 years of age will be eligible for enrollment if the lead investigator and the treating physician agree that the patient meets the enrollment criteria which include the following: patients with spirometrically confirmed COPD at high risk for repeat hospitalization or ED visits as predicted by hospital admission or ED visit in the previous 12 months for a COPD exacerbation, chronic home use of oxygen, or a course of systemic corticosteroid therapy in the preceding 12 months. Exclusion criteria include patients not expected to survive their hospitalization, presence of metastatic cancer, bed-bound individuals, non-English speaking patients, and patients unable to provide informed consent.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults greater than 18 years of age and less than 64 years of age will be eligible for enrollment if the lead investigator and the treating physician agree that the patient meets the enrollment criteria which include the following: patients with spirometrically confirmed COPD at high risk for repeat hospitalization or emergency department (ED) visits as predicted by hospital admission or ED visit in the previous 12 months for a COPD exacerbation, chronic home use of oxygen, or a course of systemic corticosteroid therapy in the preceding 12 months. patients not expected to survive their hospitalization, presence of metastatic cancer, bedbound individuals, nonEnglish speaking patients, and patients unable to provide informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
</DOC>