<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01543412</DOC>
	<brief_summary>No validated second-line chemotherapy for the treatment of locally advanced/metastatic pancreatic cancer is actually available,after the failure of a gemcitabine(+/- Cisplatin or Oxaliplatin)-based regimen. Irinotecan seems to be a moderately active drug in the treatment of this disease Recently was reported some interesting results using a potentially non -cross resistant regimen (FOLFIRI) which could be useful even as second-line chemotherapy. An exploratory study in this setting seem warranted.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Second Line Chemotherapy for Advanced Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed written informed consent prior to beginning protocol specific procedures Previous chemotherapy with Gemcitabine plus or less Platinoids Previous gemcitabine delivered as a radiosensitizer for locally advanced disease, followed or not by a gemcitabine plus or less platinoids as maintenance or disease progression is allowed. Male or female less than 75 years of age Diagnosis of histologically or cytologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the pancreas Locally advanced (nonresectable) or metastatic pancreatic cancer Presence of at least one unidimensional indicator lesion measurable by CT scan or MRI in not an irradiated area ECOG performance status 0 to 1 at study entry Life expectancy: more than 3 months Neutrophils more than 1.5 x 109L, platelets more than 100 x 109L, and hemoglobin more than 10 gdL Bilirubin level either normal or less than 1.5 x ULN ASAT and ALAT normal or less than 2.5 x ULN (normal or less than 5 x ULN if liver metastasis are present) Serum creatinine less than 1.5 x ULN Amylase normal or less than 1.5 ULN Effective contraception for both male and female patients if the risk of conception exists Absence of any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially hampering compliance with the study protocol and followup schedule; those conditions should be assessed with the patient before registration in the trial Brain metastases Previous treatment with irinotecan or fluoropyrimidines Significant cardiovascular disease: clinically relevant coronary artery disease or a history of a myocardial infarction within the last 6 months Significant gastrointestinal abnormalities Gilbert's Syndrome Any uncontrolled infections Known HIV infection Radiotherapy within 4 weeks prior to study entry Any investigational agents 4 weeks prior to entry Known grade 3 or 4 allergic reaction to any of the components of the treatment Known drug abuse or alcohol abuse Medical or psychological condition which in the opinion of the investigator would not permit the patient to complete the study or sign meaningful informed consent Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding Any concurrent malignancy other than nonmelanoma skin cancer, or carcinoma in situ of the cervix. Legal incapacity or limited legal capacity</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>FOLFIRI</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastases</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreatic adenocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>locally advanced or metastatic pancreatic adenocarcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>