<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02530177</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see how many patients develop hair, skin and nail changes due to cancer treatments. The investigators would like to study the clinical factors, genetic markers, and impact on patients' health-related quality of life to learn more about who is at greater risk. We trust that the study will improve our understanding of how cancer patients feel about their skin, hair, and nail conditions. This information will help us determine the burden on breast cancer patients and survivors. It will also help us learn how to prevent these conditions and it may improve the way we treat them and counsel patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Chemotherapy-Induced Hair Changes and Alopecia, Skin Aging and Nail Changes in Women With Non-Metastatic Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alopecia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alopecia Areata</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women newly diagnosed with nonmetastatic breast cancer (stage 0III, any receptor type) at the time of starting chemotherapy (ddACT, CMF, Newer Combination Regimens) or endocrine therapy (tamoxifen, anastrozole, letrozole, exemestane) Women ≥ 18 years at the time of enrollment into the study Able to communicate in English and participate in the informed consent process Able to comply with the followup visits, assessments, answering questionnaires Metastatic breast cancer Followup care/visits not scheduled at MSKCC Any current alopecia especially due to an active scalp and/or hair disorder (e.g. alopecia areata), or a preexisting condition with sequelae (e.g. scarring alopecia) Currently active or uncontrolled medical condition [e.g. thyroid disorder, autoimmune connective tissue disease (e.g. SLE), BMT complications (GVHD)] or medication intake (e.g. HRT), affecting scalp hair Prior systemic treatment for any malignancy Active secondary cancer requiring cytotoxic chemotherapy Planned (or a history of) radiation therapy to the head Vulnerable populations [e.g. decisionally impaired (cognitive, psychiatric), terminally ill, prisoners], or patients who, in the opinion of the investigator have a condition that precludes their ability to provide an informed consent Men Volunteer Post menopausal women, with menopausal status defined as (per self report): Bilateral salpingooophorectomy independent of age If natural menopause, age ≥ 50 with cessation of menses for at least 12 months Or premenopausal women with premenopausal status defined as &lt;53 years of age with no cessation of menses Able to communicate in English and participate in the informed consent process Able to comply with the baseline assessments and answering questionnaires Women &gt;/= 18 years at the time of enrollment into the study</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alopecia</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Aging</keyword>
	<keyword>Nail Changes</keyword>
	<keyword>Hair Changes</keyword>
	<keyword>15-198</keyword>
</DOC>