<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02432027</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluate the effects of topical C-82 in a psoriasis plaque test.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial to Evaluate Topical C-82 in a Psoriasis Plaque Test</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective of this trial is to evaluate antipsoriatic efficacy of the C-82 topical gel compared with vehicle by measurement of the thickness of the Echo Lucent Band (ELB) of the psoriatic infiltrate using 20 MHz sonography. To gain additional information about possible efficacy the change of the test fields compared to untreated plaque will be clinically assessed by visual scoring.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcipotriene</mesh_term>
	<criteria>mild to moderate chronic stable plaque type psoriasis plaques thickness of at least 200 µm lesion(s) on the trunk or extremities (excluding palms/soles) skin must be without disease findings other skin disease psoriasis guttata, psoriasis punctata, psoriasis erythrodermatica, psoriasis arthropathica and pustular psoriasis treatment with any locally acting medications (including antipsoriatics like vitamin D analogues, dithranol) within 2 weeks preceding and during the trial treatment with any systemic medications (including antipsoriatics like corticosteroids, cytostatics or retinoids) or medications which are known to provoke or aggravate psoriasis (e.g. betablocker, antimalarial drugs, lithium) or phototherapy/PUVA within 4 weeks preceding and during the trial treatment with any biologics within 3 months preceding and during the trial known allergic reactions, irritations or sensitivity to the active ingredients or other components of the investigational products (e.g. Carbomere 940, propylene glycol) drug or alcohol abuse symptoms of a clinically significant illness within 4 preceding and during the trial participation another clinical trial within 4 weeks of this clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>