<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02432976</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A diminution of quality of life is often reported by patients after coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) surgery. A part of this diminution could be explain by postoperative left ventricular (LV) dysfunction. Exenatide (Byetta®) is an incretin mimetic, characterized by an anti-hyperglycemic effect that depends on the blood glucose level. Recent data have suggested that exenatide could improve LV function by an inotropic effect in patients suffering from cardiogenic shock or from congestive heart failure. Moreover, patients suffering from congestive heart failure reported a better quality of life when they were treated with exenatide compared to placebo. The investigators hypothesize that perioperative exenatide infusion could improve postoperative quality of life in CABG surgery patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Perioperative Exenatide Infusion on Quality of Life in Cardiac Surgery Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The ExeQOL study is an ancillary study of the ExSTRESS trial (www.clinicaltrials.gov identifier: NCT01969149). The ExSTRESS trial is a phase II/III randomized-controlled trial that aim at assessing intravenous exenatide versus insulin for perioperative glycemic control in CABG surgery. The phase II of the ExStress trial will assess the safety and the efficacy of a continuous intravenous infusion of exenatide for the management of post operative stress hyperglycemia after planned coronary artery graft bypass (CABG) surgery. The aim of the phase III of the ExSTRESS trial is to compare the efficacy of a continuous intravenous infusion of exenatide to the gold standard treatment, i.e the intravenous infusion of short-acting insulin, for the management of post operative stress hyperglycemia after planned CABG surgery.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Exenatide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Lispro</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Incretins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age over 18. Patient consent. Non insulin requiring type 2 diabetic patients. Non diabetic patients. Planned coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) surgery. ASA (American Society of Anesthesiologists) score 1, 2, or 3. Pregnancy and breast feeding. Pancreatectomy. Acute pancreatitis. Chronic pancreatitis. Type 1 diabetic patients. Insulin requiring type 2 patients. HbA1c&gt;8% Ketoacidosis. Hyperosmolar coma. Preoperative blood glucose level above 300 mg/dl [21]. Insulin or exenatide contraindication. History of renal transplantation or currently receiving renal dialysis or creatinine clearance below 60 ml/min. Emergency surgery. Planned non CABG cardiac surgery.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Bypass Graft Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Incretin mimetic</keyword>
	<keyword>Exenatide</keyword>
</DOC>