<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02762838</DOC>
	<brief_summary>BCD-055-3 is international multi-center comparative double-blind randomized clinical trial of efficacy and safety of BCD-055 (JSC "BIOCAD", Russia) and Remicade® in combination with methotrexate in patients with active rheumatoid arthritis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparative Clinical Trial of Efficacy and Safety of BCD-055 and Remicade® in Combination With Methotrexate in Patients With Active Rheumatoid Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infliximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin B Complex</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed informed consent Active rheumatoid arthritis according to criteria of American College of Rheumatologists (2010), that was diagnosed at least 6 months prior to screening. Active rheumatoid arthritis at screening despite of therapy with methotrexate for 3 last months. Use of methotrexate in stable dose for at least 4 weeks before screening (1025 mg per week). History of ineffective treatment with basic antiinflammatory drugs (including methotrexate). Previous therapy of rheumatoid arthritis with monoclonal antibodies (including antitumor necrosis factor drugs) Felty's syndrome Functional status class IV according to ACR classification (1991) Low activity of rheumatoid arthritis (DAS28CRP(4) index less than 3.2) Patient needs corticosteroids in a dose more than 10 mg (recalculated to prednisolone) before signing informed consent. Patients needs equal of less than 10 mg prednisolone but the dose was not stable for last 4 weeks prior to infliximab treatment Prior use of diseasemodifying antirheumatic drugs including methotrexate, sulfasalazin, chloroquine or hydroxychloroquine for up to 4 weeks before randomization. Prior use of alkylating agents for up to 12 months prior to signing informed consent. Intraarticular use of corticosteroids for up to 4 weeks before randomization. Prior use of live or attenuated vaccines for up to 8 weeks before signing informed consent. Diagnosis of tuberculosis. Body mass more than 130 kg.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>