<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02762721</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to estimate the frequency of FGFR2 fusions in archived intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma (iCCA) or mixed hepatocellular-cholangiocarcinoma (HCC-CCA) tumor samples</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Analysis of Oncogenes in Intrahepatic Cholangiocarcinoma or Mixed Hepatocellular-Cholangiocarcinoma in Tumor Tissue Samples</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a non-interventional, observational study of archived human tissue samples; no surgical procedures will be required and no treatment will be provided as part of this study. Approximately 150 archived tissue samples obtained from patients with iCCA or mixed HCC-CCA will be analyzed for somatic alteration status and will include cholangiocarcinoma-specific FGFR2 fusion isoforms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cholangiocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>If required by law or local regulations (i.e., the sample is from an identifiable subject), signed written informed consent should be granted prior to use of the sample in the study ≥ 18 years of age Histologically or cytologically confirmed iCCA or mixed HCCCCA, who are/were eligible for systemic therapy (samples collected prior to initiation of the systemic therapy may be submitted for testing) Have one or more formalin fixed and paraffin embedded blocks available. If blocks are not evaluable, 710 unstained, nonbaked slides with 5micron thick sections with at least 20% tumor tissue should be available. (Potential participants who are scheduled to undergo surgical treatment may agree to provide surplus of tissues not required for diagnosis and have to provide informed consent prior to the surgery.) Not applicable: Patients must meet all of the inclusion criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>FGFR2 fusion</keyword>
	<keyword>iCCA</keyword>
	<keyword>mixed HCC-CCA</keyword>
	<keyword>Intrahepatic Cholangiocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Mixed Hepatocellular Cholangiocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Cholangiocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>ArQule</keyword>
</DOC>