<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02072031</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Anlotibib (AL3818) is a kind of innovative medicines approved by State Food and Drug Administration（SFDA:2011L00661） which was researched by Jiangsu Chia-tai Tianqing Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Anlotinib is a kinase inhibitor of receptor tyrosine with multi-targets, especially for VEGFR2、VEGFR3、PDGFRβ and c-Kit. It has the obvious resistance to new angiogenesis. The trial is to compare the efficacy and safety profile between Anlotinib and Sunitinib in patients with advanced Renal Cell Carcinoma(RCC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II Study of Anlotinib Versus Sunitinib in Patients With Advanced Renal Cell Carcinoma（RCC）</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Maleic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sunitinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1.Patients with histologically confirmed advanced renal cell carcinoma including clear cell component and not available for surgery 2.Without drug treatment for RCC or chemotherapy/cytokine therapy failure or resistant patients) 3.With measurable disease (using RECIST1.1) 4.1875years,ECOG PS:01,Life expectancy of more than 3 months 5.Other cytotoxic drugs,radiation therapy,or surgery≥4 weeks 6.main organs function is normal 7.Signed and dated informed consent 1.Previously received targeted therapy of the metastatic renal cell carcinoma (such as sunitinib, Sorafenib) 2.patients has many influence factors toward oral medications 3.Known brain metastases 4.patients with severe and failed to controlled diseases,including: suboptimal blood pressure control;suffering from myocardial ischemia or above grade I myocardial infarction, arrhythmias and Class I heart failure;activity or failure to control severe infections;liver disease such as cirrhosis, decompensated liver disease, chronic active hepatitis;poorly controlled diabetes (FBG)&gt;10mmol/L);urine protein≥++,etc. 5.patients failed to heal wounds or fractures for Longterm 6.patients occurred venous thromboembolic events within 6 months 7.patients has HIVpositive or organ transplantation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anlotinib</keyword>
	<keyword>Sunitinib</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal Cell Carcinoma（RCC）</keyword>
</DOC>