<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02072356</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial studies radiolabeled glass beads (yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres) in treating patients with unresectable hepatocellular carcinoma. Internal radiation therapy uses radioactive material placed directly into or near a tumor to kill tumor cells. Using radiolabeled glass beads to kill tumor cells may be an effective treatment for liver cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Radiolabeled Glass Beads in Treating Patients With Liver Cancer That Cannot be Removed by Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Provide oversight to treatment with TheraSphere to eligible patients with hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) of the liver who are not surgical resection candidates. II. Evaluate patient experience, toxicities and overall survival associated with TheraSphere treatment. OUTLINE: Patients receive yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres intra-arterially (IA) on day 0, and may receive a second dose within 30-90 days of initial treatment. Patients may receive additional treatment 4-12 weeks after initial treatment at the discretion of the study physician. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 3-6 weeks and annually for 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methamphetamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of intrahepatic malignancy including but not limited to HCC; the histopathology confirmation criterion may be waived in patients with a radiographically identifiable liver mass, known laboratory or clinical risk factors for cancer or elevated tumor markers such as alphafetoprotein (AFP) and clinical findings Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status score 0 2 Life expectancy &gt;= 3 months &gt; 4 weeks since prior radiation, surgery or chemotherapy Able to comprehend and provide written informed consent in accordance with institutional and federal guidelines Ineligible for surgical resection Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt; 5 times upper limit of normal (UNL) Serum bilirubin &gt; 2.0 mg/dl (unless segmental infusion is planned) Any contraindications to angiography and hepatic artery catheterization such as: History of severe allergy or intolerance to any contrast media, narcotics, sedatives, or atropine that cannot be corrected or premedicated Bleeding diathesis, not correctable by usual forms of therapy Severe peripheral vascular disease that would preclude catheterization Evidence of potential delivery of greater than 16.5 mCi (30 Gy absorbed dose) of radiation to the lungs in a single treatment Evidence of pulmonary insufficiency Evidence of any detectable technetium99m macroaggregated serum albumin (Tc99m MAA) flow to the stomach or duodenum, not correctable by using established angiographic techniques to stop or mitigate such flow Significant extrahepatic disease representing an imminent lifethreatening outcome Active uncontrolled infection Significant underlying medical or psychiatric illness Comorbid disease of condition that would preclude safe delivery of TheraSphere treatment or, in the judgment of the physician, place the patient at undue risk Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Humanitarian Device</keyword>
	<keyword>Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>TheraSphere®</keyword>
	<keyword>HUD</keyword>
</DOC>