<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02089490</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The dermal substitute NEVELIA® has received CE marking in July 9, 2013. Its use in the NEVAL protocol will be in accordance with its leaflet, i.e. for the treatment of burns or in case of reconstructive plastic surgery. The matric implantation will be followed by autologous skin grafting when the neodermis formation will be observed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of NEVELIA® in Terms of Safety and Efficacy for Third-degree Burns Treatment or Reconstructive Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The NEVAL protocol is a descriptive study conducted in order to confirm the clinical evidence of safety and performance of NEVELIA®, as described in the literature on equivalent products. This dermal substitute consists of an inner biodegradable dermal substitute made of bovine collagen (collagen of type I), covered with an outer silicone membrane. Its porosity and the speed of degradation allow the act of recolonization by the fibroblasts and initiation of the vascularization process within 3 weeks. The application procedure requires removement of the silicone layer and wound covering with an ultra-thin epidermal graft, possibly meshed. This surgical procedure is well-known and permits an ultra-thin epidermal graft. All the patients will be treated with NEVELIA®, prior to autologous skin grafting within 3 weeks after its application. Then, three follow-up visits will be planned: post operatively, at 6 and 12 months. The objectives are: - Primary objective: To assess the type and frequency of complications - Secondary objectives: - To assess the take rate of NEVELIA® - To assess the take rate of skin graft - To assess the satisfaction rate of physician and patient, - To assess the quality of the healed skin, - To assess the rate of re-operation at 12 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Burns</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients aged 18 or older Patient geographically stable, Patient requiring dermal reconstruction after thirddegree burns, reconstructive surgery or trauma surgery; Patient who signed the nonopposition form; Patient able to be followed up to 12 months. Patient with clinical signs of wound infection; Allergic patient or with known allergy to bovine collagen or silicone; Patient with lifethreatening conditions; Patient receiving a treatment that may affect wound healing; Patient with an autoimmune or immunosuppressive disease; Patient with a suspected neurological disease as CreutzfeldtJakob disease; Patient simultaneously participating in another study; Pregnant or nursing woman.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>