<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02884037</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In Non-alcoholic fatty (NAFLD) liver disease patients, the investigators hypothesized that rifaximin might act on Gram-negative bacteria and IBO thereby inhibiting LPS-mediated proinflammatory cytokine production. This work evaluates the efficacy of 6 months administration of rifaximin in NAFLD patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rifaximin Modify the Pathogenesis of Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators aimed to study the effect of rifaximin on NAFLD. 126 patients with biopsy-proven NAFLD [42 steatosis, 84 non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH)] were enrolled in this open-label, prospective, multicentric cohort study. BMI, AST, ALT, gamma glutamyl transferase (γ-GGT), lipid profile, homeostatic model assessment (HOMA), serum endotoxin, Toll-like receptor 4 (TlR4), interleukin-6 (IL-6), IL-10, tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α) and cytokeratin-18 (CK-18) levels were measured before and after a 6 month administration of rifaximin (1100-1200 mg/day).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rifaximin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rifamycins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>women or men aged 1870 years, biopsy proven NAFLD and /or NASH with or without mild to moderate fibrosis (fibrosis stage 03), persistently abnormal ALT on 2 occasions, and participants have provided written informed consent prior to screening treatment with antibiotics during the 3 months before the beginning of the study, allergy to rifamycin or rifaximin, presence of other type of liver disease or pancreatic or biliary tract diseases, excessive alcohol intake (&gt;20 g/day), pregnant or lactating women, hypothyroidism, systemic inflammatory conditions (e.g. connective tissue diseases and inflammatory bowel diseases), bariatric surgery and blind loop, evidence of hepatic decompensation (ascites, hepatic encephalopathy, and varices), and history of myocardial infarction and/ or stroke within 6 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>NAFLD</keyword>
	<keyword>Rifaximin</keyword>
	<keyword>Endotoxin and Homeostatic Model Assessment</keyword>
</DOC>