<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00235859</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to assess the safety and efficacy of adalimumab compared to placebo in subjects with rheumatoid arthritis on methotrexate therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adalimumab Administered in Korean Rheumatoid Arthritis Subjects Treated With Methotrexate</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Meet ACR criteria for diagnosis of active RA and have at &gt;6 swollen joints and &gt;9 tender joints Subjects must have received at least one prior DMARD besides MTX, but may have had efficacy failures on no more than four standard DMARDs other than MTX Therapy with MTX for at least 6 months prior to screening and on a stable dose of MTX for at least 4 weeks prior to screening visit Age 18 years and older Prior treatment with any TNF antagonist, including adalimumab History of clinically significant drug or alcohol abuse in the previous year, iv drug abuse, active infection with listeria or tuberculosis (TB), lymphoma or leukemia,and any malignancy with the exception of successfully treated nonmetastatic basalcell carcinoma of the skin. Subjects may not have been administered a live vaccine within three months prior to study drug administration or during the study, treatment with any other investigational agent within 30 days or 5 halflives of the agent, whichever is longer, prior to the screening evaluation, treatment with any investigational biologic agent, including antiCD4 antibody, within 6 months prior to the screening evaluation, prior treatment with any TNF antagonist, including Adalimumab, prior exposure to alkylating agents such as chlorambucil or cyclophosphamide. Chest Xray with calcified granuloma and/or pleural scarring Positive TB skin test, RT23 dose skin test, &gt;5 mm at 48 to 72 hours Unstable ischemic heart disease, active inflammatory bowel disease, active peptic ulcer disease, recent stroke (within 3 months of the screening evaluation) or any poorly controlled medical condition Intraarticular, intramuscular or iv administration of corticosteroids within 4 weeks prior to screening evaluation Female who is pregnant or breastfeeding.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Rheumatoid Arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>adalimumab</keyword>
</DOC>