<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02825472</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Rationale: Regular physical activity and aerobic exercise training are related to decreased cardiovascular mortality in healthy individuals, as well as in individuals with cardiovascular risk factors and cardiac patients. Unfortunately, no such data is available on exercise training in adult patients with congenital heart disease. Objective: The objective of the ExTra GUCH trial is to assess whether encouragement of a six-month sports participation program in addition to usual care in symptomatic adult patients with congenital heart disease improves exercise capacity and quality of life, and lowers serum N-terminal prohormone brain natriuretic peptide (NT-proBNP) levels. Study design: International, multi-centre parallel randomized controlled trial. Study population: Adult patients with congenital heart disease, who are in New York Heart Association (NYHA) class II or III. Intervention (if applicable): The intervention group receives a six-month individualized exercise training program, the control group receives usual care. Main study parameters/endpoints: The primary outcome is the change in peakVO2 between patients in the sports participation group, and the control group. Secondary outcome measures are change in NYHA functional class, quality of life, and NT-proBNP levels. The primary safety outcome is the composite of all hospitalizations, and all deaths during, or within three hours after exercise. The secondary safety outcome is the composite of all exercise related injuries for which medical attention is sought.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Exercise Training in Grown-up Congenital Heart Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators intend to submit the trial design of this study for this purpose.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Defects, Congenital</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years Congenital heart disease of all complexities NYHA Class II or III Inability to give informed consent Inability to participate in an exercise training program Exerciseinduced arrhythmia and/or ischemia Cyanosis at rest Pregnancy Major cardiovascular event and/or procedure within three months previous to inclusion. Participation in interventional clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Congenital Heart Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Sport</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise training</keyword>
</DOC>