<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00844805</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study was to assess the proportion of participants in the infliximab plus naproxen arm versus the placebo plus naproxen arm, in a population of participants with moderate-to-severe active axial spondyloarthritis and disease duration of ≤3 years, who achieve the Assessment in Ankylosing Spondylitis (ASAS) partial remission criteria.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Infliximab for Treatment of Axial Spondyloarthritis (P05336 AM1)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In the 28-week treatment phase, participants were randomized to receive either infliximab plus naproxen or placebo plus naproxen. After 28-weeks of treatment, participants that achieved partial remission in the treatment phase were randomized to continued treatment with naproxen or to receive no treatment and were followed for an additional 24 weeks (follow-up phase).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Spondylitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spondylitis, Ankylosing</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spondylarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Naproxen</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infliximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participant must: be 18 to 48 years of age have diagnosis of active axial spondyloarthritis, with disease duration of less than or equal to 3 years. have active disease during trial enrollment have limited treatment history for axial spondyloarthritis (must meet certain criteria) agree to an acceptable method of contraception (for women of childbearing potential and all men) must meet certain tuberculosis screening requirements must meet certain laboratory screening safety requirements have an xray of the sacroiliac joints available from within the previous 12 months (or have one performed during the Screening visit if site is outside of Germany). Participant will be excluded: for certain medical conditions and/or recent history of certain medical disorders for current or recent treatment with certain other medications and certain vaccinations. for being a woman who is breastfeeding, pregnant, or intending to become pregnant. if known to have had a substance abuse problem within the previous 3 years prior to screening. if currently participating in any other clinical study. for other administrative reasons.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>48 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>