<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01876342</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sportsman's hernia causes chronic groin pain in physically active adults. Open hernia repair without mesh or laparoscopic technique with mesh have been advocated in the treatment of sportsman's hernia. The aim of this randomized study is to compare the effectiveness of open technique to laparoscopic technique for the treatment of Sportsman´s hernia. The hypothesis is that laparoscopic technique is less painfull than open surgery for repair of sportsman's hernia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TEP Versus Open Repair of Sportsman's Hernia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Sportsman's hernia is defined as a weakness or disruption of the posterior wall of the inguinal canal. Open hernia repair with or without mesh or laparoscopic techniques with mesh have been advocated in the treatment of sportsman's hernia and associated athletic pubalgia. The results of the operative treatment from single centers are reported to be good to excellent in between 70 - 90% of patients with the most promising results reported using an open minimal repair (OMR) technique. There are no randomized trials comparing open versus laparoscopic techniques regarding time for recovery and relief of pain. The aim of this randomized study is to compare the effectiveness of OMR technique in local or spinal anesthesia to endoscopic Total ExtraPeritoneal (TEP) technique in general anesthesia for the treatment of Sportsman´s hernia/athletic pubalgia. The primary endpoint is patient being free from intractable groin pain during sports activity or daily work four weeks after surgery.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hernia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>males/females professional or nonprofessional athletes age 1850 years unilateral or bilateral groin pain lasting &gt; 6 weeks physical examination and MRI indicating sportsman's hernia pain above inguinal ligament in the deep inguinal ring grade III edema at pubic symphysis on MRI scan is allowed patients not willing to participate inguinal or femoral hernia MRI reveals other major pathology former surgery to the actual groin allergy to polypropylene or other contraindication to surgery</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>sports hernia</keyword>
	<keyword>sportsman's hernia</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic groin pain</keyword>
	<keyword>open minimal repair</keyword>
	<keyword>totally extraperitoneal endoscopic technique</keyword>
</DOC>