<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00664274</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This project will explore the relationship between catechol-O-methyltransferase (COMT) Val158/108Met genotype and response to a 12-week computerized neurocognitive rehabilitation (CRT) given to chronic schizophrenic patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Relation of Catechol-O-methyltransferase (COMT) Genotype and Response to Cognitive Remediation Schizophrenia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cognitive deficits play a crucial role in both the pathogenesis and prognosis of schizophrenia. The COMT gene is functionally expressed in neural systems considered important in a range of healthy brain functions and brain disorders, including schizophrenia. The COMT Met allele has been shown to be associated with a lower activity form of COMT, and with better performance on neurocognitive tests, while the COMT Val allele is associated with poorer executive cognition. This study will investigate the relationship of COMT polymorphism in patients with chronic schizophrenia with the response to CRT targeting visuospatial processing, attention, and cognitive flexibility using MATRICS Consensus Cognitive Battery (MCCB) developed by the NIH-MATRICS initiative.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Participation in the active arm of the neurocognitive remediation program 2. Age 18 55 3. Inpatients 4. DSMIV diagnosis of schizophrenia (all subtypes) with illness duration &gt;5 years 5. Auditory and visual acuity adequate to complete cognitive tests 6. Stable dose of oral atypical antipsychotic for at least 4 weeks 7. Total PANSS score &gt; 60 8. RBANS total score ≤ 80 9. MMSE score of greater than or equal to 24 10. Good physical health determined by physical examination, laboratory tests 11. Capacity and willingness to give written informed consent 1. Inability to read or speak English 2. Documented disease of the central nervous system 3. History of intellectual impairment predating onset of symptoms of psychosis (e.g. mental retardation) 4. Clinically significant or unstable cardiovascular, renal, hepatic, gastrointestinal, pulmonary or hematologic conditions 5. HIV + 6. Patients diagnosed with substance dependence 7. Currently participating in another experimental study, except for the parent study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>