<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00664326</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a uncontrolled, open-label, non-randomized Phase II study of oral BAY73-4506 to evaluate the response rate of BAY73-4506 in previously untreated patients with metastatic or unresectable renal cell cancer (RCC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase II Uncontrolled Study of BAY73-4506 in Previously Untreated Patients With Metastatic or Unresectable RCC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The final analysis of efficacy will be performed after last patient has been treated for at least 6 months. Additional periodic safety and efficacy data reviews will be performed for any patients continuing to receive study drug afterwards.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patients &gt;/= 18 years of age. Patients, who suffer from unresectable and/or metastatic, measurable predominantly clear cell RCC (renal cell carcinoma histologically) or cytologically documented. Patients must be previously untreated for advanced disease. Prior palliative radiation therapy is allowed if the target lesion(s) are not included within the radiation field and no more than 30% of the bone marrow is irradiated. Patients who have at least one unidimensional measurable lesion by computed tomography (CTscan) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) according to Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST). Patients with "Intermediate" or "Low" risk per the Motzer score. Patients who have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1. Adequate bone marrow, renal and hepatic function as assessed by the following laboratory requirements to be conducted within 7 days prior to study drug treatment Patients who have received prior systemic treatment regimens for RCC. Uncontrolled/unstable cardiac disease Uncontrolled hypertension Active clinically serious infections (&gt; Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events [CTCAE] grade 2 ) History of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection or chronic hepatitis B or C. Known history or symptomatic metastatic brain or meningeal tumours Patients with seizure disorder requiring medication Patients with evidence or history of bleeding diathesis. Any hemorrhage or bleeding event &gt;/= CTCAE Grade 3 within 4 weeks of first dose of study. Pregnant or breastfeeding patients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Renal Cell Carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>