<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02613403</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized, multicenter, open-label trial of the combination regimen of MK-5172 (grazoprevir [GZR]) (100 mg), MK-3682 (450 mg) and MK-8408 (ruzasvir) (60 mg) for 16 weeks with ribavirin (RBV) or 24 weeks without RBV in cirrhotic (C) or non-cirrhotic (NC) hepatitis C virus (HCV) genotype (GT) 1 or GT3-infected participants who have previously failed a direct-acting antiviral regimen (DAA). The combination regimen will be administered as two fixed-dose combination (FDC) tablets, referred to as MK-3682B, given once-daily. The study will evaluate the efficacy of the combination regimen of MK-5172 (GZR), MK-3682 and MK-8408 (ruzasvir) with or without ribavirin as assessed by the proportion of participants achieving Sustained Virologic Response 12 weeks (SVR12) after the end of all study therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of MK-3682B (MK-5172 + MK-3682 + MK-8408) Fixed Dose Combination in Chronic HCV Participants Failing Prior Antiviral Treatment (MK-3682-021)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Prior to enrollment of GT3-infected subjects, the safety and efficacy data for GT3 subjects being dosed in Part B of MK-3682-012 (NCT02332720) will be reviewed. Participants in MK-5172-017 (NCT01667081) are eligible for enrollment in the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Digestive System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>RNA Virus Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Viral, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Flaviviridae Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antiviral Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Has HCV RNA ≥ 10,000 IU/mL in peripheral blood at enrollment. Has documented chronic HCV GT1 or HCV GT3 infection (with no evidence of nontypeable or mixed genotype) Has documented relapse, defined as having HCV RNA target not detected at endoftreatment, but HCV RNA quantifiable during followup, after treatment with one of the following DAA regimens either by approved dosage and duration or by completion of a clinical trial: GT1: SOF/LDV ± RBV; GT1: GZR/EBR ± RBV; GT3: SOF + RBV; GT3: SOF + PR; GT3: SOF + DCV ± RBV; GT3: SOF/LDV ± RBV. Participants who previously failed PR treatment, with or without simepravir (SIM), boceprevir (BOC), or telaprevir (TPV), prior to receiving DAA therapy, may also be enrolled. Is otherwise healthy. Has either absence of cirrhosis or presence of compensated cirrhosis. Is not of reproductive potential or is of reproductive potential and agrees to avoid becoming pregnant or impregnating a partner beginning at least 2 weeks prior to administration of the initial dose of study drug, through 6 months after taking the last dose of study drug (or longer if dictated by local regulations), by complying with one of the following: (1) practice abstinence from heterosexual activity OR (2) use (or have their partner use) two forms of acceptable contraception during heterosexual activity which may include oral contraceptives. For HIV coinfected participants additional criteria include: 1) documented HIV1 infection 2) either not currently on antiretroviral therapy (ART) without plans to initiate ART while participating in this study or has well controlled HIV on ART 3) at least one viable antiretroviral regimen alternative beyond their current regimen in the event of HIV virologic failure and the development of antiretroviral drug resistance. Is under the age of legal consent, is mentally or legally incapacitated, has significant emotional problems at the time of prestudy screening visit or expected during the conduct of the study or has a history of a clinically significant psychiatric disorder which, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with the study procedures. Has previously received a DAA containing regimen other than the permitted regimens listed above. Did not complete their prior DAA therapy due to intolerance to the DAA regimen or who failed the DAA regimen for reasons other than relapse (e.g., virologic breakthrough, rebound or nonresponse, noncompliance, lost to followup, withdrew consent). Has evidence of decompensated liver disease manifested by the presence of or history of ascites, esophageal or gastric variceal bleeding, hepatic encephalopathy or other signs or symptoms of advanced liver disease. Has cirrhosis classified as ChildPugh Class B or C or has a PughTurcotte (CPT) score &gt;6 Is coinfected with hepatitis B virus (HBV) For participants with HIV, has a history of opportunistic infection in the 6 months prior to screening. Has a history of malignancy ≤5 years prior to enrollment except for adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer or in situ cervical cancer or carcinoma in situ; or is under evaluation for other active or suspected malignancy. Has cirrhosis and liver imaging within 6 months of Day 1 showing evidence of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) or is under evaluation for HCC. Is currently participating or has participated in a study with an investigational compound within 30 days of signing informed consent and is not willing to refrain from participating in another such study during the course of this study. Participants participating in MK5172017 (NCT01667081) may be enrolled in this study, MK 3682021. Has clinicallyrelevant drug or alcohol abuse within 12 months of screening Is a female and is pregnant or breastfeeding or expecting to conceive or donate eggs from at least 2 weeks prior to Day 1 through at least 6 months after last dose of study drug, or longer if dictated by local regulations. Is a male whose female partner(s) is/are pregnant. Has organ transplants (including hematopoietic stem cell transplants) other than cornea and hair. Has history of gastric surgery or history of malabsorption disorders. Has current or history of any clinically significant cardiac abnormalities/dysfunction or personal or family history of Torsade de pointes. Has chronic pulmonary disease. Has an hemoglobinopathy. Has central nervous system (CNS) trauma requiring intubation, intracranial pressure monitoring, brain meningeal or skull surgery, or resulting in seizure, coma, permanent neurologic deficits, abnormal brain imaging, or cerebral spinal fluid (CSF) leak; prior brain hemorrhage and/or intracranial aneurysms (whether adequately repaired or not). Has current or history of seizure disorder unless seizure was &gt;10 years ago, a single isolated event, no history of or current use of antiseizure medications, and a documented normal neurological examination at Day 1. Has history of stroke or transient ischemic attack. Has medical/surgical conditions that may result in a need for hospitalization during the period of the study. Has a medical condition requiring, or likely to require, chronic systemic administration of corticosteroids, TNF antagonists, or other immunosuppressant drugs during the course of the study Has evidence of history of chronic hepatitis not caused by HCV. Participants with history of acute nonHCVrelated hepatitis, which resolved &gt;6 months before study entry, may be enrolled.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>