<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02613572</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Because of its iron-chelating and antioxidant properities, alpha lipoic acid may be a treatment for geographic atrophy secondary to age-related macular degeneration. There is ample published data about the safety and pharmacokinetics of alpha lipoic acid in adults. However, there is not much data on the safety and tolerability of higher doses of alpha lipoic acid in the elderly population. The purpose of Phase I of this protocol is to determine if there are safety/tolerability concerns seen when higher doses of alpha lipoic acid are taken by subjects 65 years of age or older. The objective of Phase 2 of this protocol is to determine the effects of ALA on the progression of GA in subjects with AMD. The central hypothesis, based on the existing literature, is that oral ALA reduces the rate of enlargement of GA in AMD subjects. The rationale is that the antioxidant and iron chelating effects of ALA will slow down one of the major pathways responsible for GA progression.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Alpha Lipoic Acid in Geographic Atrophy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Phase I (Apr 2016 completed): 15 subjects, 65 years of age or older will take alpha lipoic acid on the following schedule: 600 mg once daily with a meal for 5 days. If tolerated, then the subject will then take 800 mg once daily with a meal for 5 days. If tolerated, then the subject will then take 1200 mg once daily with a meal for 5 days. Phase II: Randomized, double-blind placebo controlled pilot trial. Upon the completion of the dose tolerability test, we plan to enroll 50 subjects into a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Subjects will be randomized (1:1) into one of two study arms: placebo capsules and ALA 1200 mg orally once daily, assuming that 1200 mg is well tolerated by subjects in Phase 1. If 1200 mg is not well-tolerated based on Phase 1 data, then the highest tolerable dose will be used. Four clinical sites are planned and the enrollment period is estimated to be 6 months. The primary endpoint is the mean rate of change of the area of GA in the study eye from baseline to 18 months as evaluated by fundus autofluorescence. Subjects will have a refracted electronic visual acuity and dilated exam at baseline, 6 months, 12 months, and 18 months. The study will be conducted on an outpatient basis and study visits will last approximately 2-3 hours. Two weeks after the 18 months study visit, the subject will be contacted to share with the investigators adverse events that developed after completing the 18 month visit. The Investigator shall ensure each subject has a follow-up eye exam scheduled within 6 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Geographic Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thioctic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Phase I Ages 6590 Female participants must be menopausal. Male participants are required to use contraception. Able to give informed consent For the study duration (15 days), the subject must remain in the country, remain within 4 hours of travel time (by car or airplane), have access to medical care if needed, and provide contact information so the subject can be reached as needed. Blood Pressure greater than 190/100 at the baseline visit Pulse greater than 100 at the baseline visit Acute and ongoing systemic infection History of dementia Participant has a condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, gives them an unstable medical status. Participant has geographic atrophy and the investigator believes the participant is a candidate for enrollment into the planned Phase 2 trial for geographic atrophy. Phase II Inclusion Criteria Age 5590 • Diagnosis of geographic atrophy from agerelated macular degeneration in the study eye. The largest GA lesion must be a minimum of 0.5 DA (1.25 mm2) and no more than 6 DA in size (15.0 mm2). GA is defined as one or more welldefined, usually more or less circular patches of loss of the RPE, typically with exposure of underlying choroidal blood vessels. If the GA is multifocal and the largest lesion is &lt; 0.5 DA, then there should be at least 3 lesions ≥ 250 microns in greatest linear diameter. BCVA between 20/20 and 20/400 in the study eye. Female participants must be menopausal. Male participants are required to use contraception and cannot donate sperm during study participation. Presence of hyperfluorescence at the edge of GA on autofluorescence imaging. Ability to give informed consent. If a subject has two eligible eyes, then both eyes can be enrolled into the study. Subject must have mailed back the medication bottle after the 10 day runin phase, demonstrating that they have taken ≥ 80% of the capsules. Exclusion Criteria Evidence of ocular disease other than AMD in the study eye that may confound the study outcomes (e.g., History of myopic degeneration, choroidal neovascularization, central serous chorioretinopathy, severe diabetic retinopathy, uveitis, vitelliform dystrophy, or macular edema). Presence of geographic atrophy that is already touching clearly defined beta peripapillary atrophy or is already touching the optic disc. Beta peripapillary atrophy is defined as peripapillary atrophy in which either the sclera or choroidal vessels are clearly visible. Any history of intravitreal injection in the study eye for AMD or choroidal neovascularization. However, if a subject develops choroidal neovascularization in the study eye during the study, then the subject will receive the standard of care intravitreal injection treatments per the investigator. The subject will continue to stay in the study. Treatment of CNV or other diseases in the nonstudy eye is at the investigator's discretion. History of intravitreal injection of any agent (e.g., triamcinolone) other than antiVEGF in the study eye within the last four months prior to study enrollment. History of laser treatment (including photodynamic therapy) to the macula for the study eye. History of intraocular surgery within 90 days. for the study eye. History of anterior segment laser (laser peripheral idotomyiridotomy, laser to trabecular meshwork, YAG capsulotomy) within 90 days for the study eye. Media opacity (corneal scar, cataract) that would prevent adequate fundus imaging for the study eye. Any history of participation in another therapeutic clinical trial for GA. Participation currently or within the past 30 days in another therapeutic clinical trial in which a systemic or ocular study medication is received by the subject. GA in the study eye due to a cause other than AMD History of prior use of ALA. AREDS (Age Related Eye Disease Study) vitamins taken at standard doses are not considered an exclusion criterion. Taking a standard multivitamin is not considered an exclusion criterion. However, the multivitamin should not contain alpha lipoic acid (also known as thioctic acid). Taking antioxidant supplements (other than a standard multivitamin (such as bilberry, ALA, vitamin C that is not part of a multivitamin, vitamin E that is not part of a multivitamin, or other similar antioxidants) within one month of enrollment is an exclusion criteria; these patients should discontinue the antioxidant supplement one month before enrollment in order to participate. Study subjects should not be on any antioxidant supplements during the study except for AREDS vitamins or ALA (if the study subject is randomized to the ALA intervention arm). Participant has a condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would preclude participation in the study for 18 months (e.g., unstable medical status including blood pressure and glycemic control, unstable psychiatric history, moving and not able to return for all planned study visits).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>