<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01915446</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims to investigate the predictive value of novel biomarkers and contrast-enhanced ultrasonography for early detection of abdominal end-organ (kidney and intestinum) hypoperfusion and ischemia in patients undergoing endovascular aortic repair (EVAR) for aortic aneurysm or dissection. In this context, patients will be monitored for renal biomarkers (TIMP-2, IGFBP7) and intestinal biomarkers (plasmatic intestinal fatty acid binding protein (i-FABP)) and local tissue perfusion will be assessed using contrast-enhanced ultrasonography (CEUS). The ultimate goal of this study is an early identification of patients developing one or both of these complications, which may facilitate a timely intervention to improve outcome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Kidney and Intestinal Markers for Early Detection of Organ Injury After Endovascular Aortic Repair</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Existence of an aortic aneurysm with need of repair as indicated by the treating vascular surgeon Aortic stenting involving the origin of both mesenteric (i.e. superior and inferior mesenteric arteries) and kidney arteries Central line is present to perform repeated blood collections Written informed consent is obtained. Preexisting severe liver or kidney injury (defined as spontaneous international normalized ratio (INR) &gt;2 or creatinine &gt;2 mg/dl or renalreplacement therapy in the preoperative course.) Known allergy to ultrasound contrast media (exclusion for the CEUS but not for marker evaluation) Anemia with hemoglobin concentration &lt; 7g/dl Patients &lt; 18 years of age Patients not able to give written informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>EVAR</keyword>
	<keyword>endovascular aortic repair</keyword>
	<keyword>acute kidney failure</keyword>
	<keyword>mesenteric ischemia</keyword>
</DOC>