<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00908583</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To determine if deletional strategies will provide effective desensitization.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Desensitization in Kidney Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A prospective iterative trial of proteasome inhibitor (PI)-based therapy for reducing HLAantibody (Ab) levels was conducted in five phases differing in bortezomib dosing density and plasmapheresis timing. Phases included 1 or 2 bortezomib cycles (1.3mg/m2,6-8 doses), one rituximab dose and plasmapheresis. HLA Abs were measured by solid phase and flow cytometry (FCM) assays. Immunodominant Ab (iAb) was defined as highest HLA Ab level. Forty-four patients received 52 desensitization courses (7 patients enrolled in multiple phases): Phase 1 (n=20), Phase 2 (n=12), Phase 3 (n=10), Phase 4 (n=5), Phase 5 (n=5).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age between 18 and 65 Voluntary written informed consent Patient on deceased donor wait list with a current or peak cytotoxic or calculated panel reactive antibody (PRA) &gt; 20% Myocardial infarction within 6 months Patient received investigational drug within 14 days prior to initiation of study treatment Serious medical or psychological illness Diagnosed with malignancy within three years, except complete research of basal cell carcinoma or squamous cell carcinoma of skin, an insitu malignancy or low risk prostate cancer after curative therapy Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt; 1000 Receipt of live vaccine within 4 weeks of study entry Female subject that is breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alloantibody</keyword>
	<keyword>Desensitization</keyword>
	<keyword>Kidney Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Nephrology</keyword>
	<keyword>Plasma Cells</keyword>
	<keyword>Translational Research/Science</keyword>
</DOC>