<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00782301</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Confirm the safety of maraviroc when used as a component of combination antiretroviral therapy in HIV and Hepatitis co-infected patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Maraviroc Versus Etravirine In Combination With Antiretroviral Therapy In Drug Experienced HIV And Hepatitis Co-Infected Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Darunavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Maraviroc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Raltegravir Potassium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etravirine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HIV1 RNA viral load of ≥1000 copies/mL at the screening visit. Detectable HCV RNA levels or Hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) positive. Previous antiretroviral treatment experience with at least 2 antiretroviral drug classes for ≥3 months. Documented resistance to an NNRTI as well as documented resistance to another antiretroviral agent. CCR5 tropic virus detected by the TrofileTM assay. Suspected or documented active, untreated HIV1 related Opportunistic Infection (OI) or other condition requiring acute therapy at the time of randomization (subjects on a stable (&gt;1 month) secondary OI prophylaxis regimen are eligible for the study; subjects on a primary OI prophylaxis regimen of any duration are also eligible for the study). Prior treatment with darunavir/ritonavir, raltegravir, or another integrase inhibitor, etravirine, maraviroc or another CCR5 inhibitor for more than 14 days at any time. Subjects receiving treatment for chronic Hepatitis or the expected need to initiate HCV treatment within 48 weeks of randomization. (Subjects who were previously treated for Hepatitis C are eligible for the study). AST and/or ALT greater than 5 times the upper limit of normal (ACTG Grade 3).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV and Hepatitis co-infection</keyword>
</DOC>