<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00782093</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objectives of this study are to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetic profile of volociximab intravitreous injection in subjects with subfoveal choroidal neovascularization secondary to age-related macular degeneration (AMD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 1 Ascending and Parallel Group Trial to Establish the Safety, Tolerability and Pharmacokinetics Profile of Volociximab (Alpha 5 Beta 1 Integrin Antagonist) in Subjects With Neovascular Age- Related Macular Degeneration</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subfoveal choroidal neovascularization (CNV) due to AMD (i.e., predominantly classic, minimally classic or occult no classic) as documented by fluorescein angiogram. Any prior treatment for AMD or any intravitreal treatment for any indication in the study eye prior to the screening visit, except oral supplements of vitamins and minerals. Previous or concomitant therapy with intravitreous corticosteroids. Any of the following underlying diseases including: Diabetic retinopathy History or evidence of severe cardiac disease (e.g., NYHA Functional Class III or IV see Appendix 19.6), history or clinical evidence of unstable angina, acute coronary syndrome, myocardial infarction or revascularization within last 6 months, ventricular tachyarrythmias requiring ongoing treatment. History or evidence of clinically significant peripheral vascular disease, such as intermittent claudication or prior amputation. Clinically significant impaired renal (serum creatinine &gt;2.5 mg/dl or s/p renal transplant or receiving dialysis) or hepatic function. Patients with results outside these ranges may be enrolled in consultation with Ophthotech. Stroke (within 12 months of trial entry). Any major surgical procedure within one month of trial entry. Previous therapeutic radiation in the region of the study eye. Any treatment with an investigational agent in the past 60 days for any condition. Women who are pregnant or nursing. Known serious allergies to the fluorescein dye used in angiography, to the components of the ranibizumab formulation, or to the components of the volociximab formulation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>AMD</keyword>
</DOC>