<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00896337</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The ORION study is being conducted to determine whether the Epic™ Nitinol Stent for primary stenting of iliac atherosclerotic lesions shows acceptable performance at 9 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>EPIC Nitinol Stent System in the Treatment of Atherosclerotic Lesions in Iliac Arteries</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>ORION is a prospective, single arm, non-randomized, multicenter study. A subject could receive a maximum of 2 study stents for up to 2 target lesions. A maximum of 1 non-target lesion in 1 non-target vessel could be treated with a commercially approved treatment during the index procedure.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Documented chronic, symptomatic iliac artery atherosclerotic disease (Rutherford/Becker category 1, 2, 3 or 4) Lifestylelimiting claudication or rest pain De novo or restenotic lesions in the common and/or external iliac artery Subjects with bilateral disease may have only one target lesion treated per side Two target lesions may be treated with a maximum of two stents (if two target lesions are treated, each lesion must be covered with a maximum of one stent) Length of diseased segment(s) &lt;=13 cm and treatment is planned with no more than 2 overlapped Epic™ stents Baseline diameter stenosis &gt;= 50% (operator visual assessment) Reference vessel diameter &gt;= 5 mm and &lt;=11 mm At least one sufficient ipsilateral infrapopliteal runoff vessel Origin of profunda femoris artery is patent Target vessel with instent restenosis Acute critical limb ischemia Tissue loss (Rutherford/Becker category 5 or 6) Any major amputations to the target limb Any minor amputation of the target limb in the last 12 months. If a minor amputation occurred greater than 12 months, stump needs to be completely healed. Life expectancy less than 24 months due to other medical comorbid condition(s) that could limit the subject's ability to participate in the trial, limit the subject's compliance with the followup requirements, or impact the scientific integrity of the trial Known hypersensitivity or contraindication to contrast dye that, in the opinion of the investigator, cannot be adequately premedicated. Intolerance to antiplatelet, anticoagulant, or thrombolytic medications Platelet count &lt; 150,000 mm3 or &gt; 600,000 mm3 Serum creatinine &gt; 2.0 mg/dL Dialysisdependent end stage renal disease Pregnancy Current participation in another drug or device trial that has not completed the primary endpoint or that may potentially confound the results of this trial Known allergy to Nitinol Presence of arterial lesions (with the exception of renal, carotid or short, focal SFA lesions) requiring intervention within 30 days of the index procedure Superficial femoral artery occlusion in the limb supplied by target vessel Heavily calcified and/or excessively tortuous lesions in the target vessel as determined by angiography Target lesion is within or near an aneurysm Persistent, intraluminal thrombus of the proposed target lesion postthrombolytic therapy Perforated vessel as evidenced by extravasation of contrast media Vascular graft, aneurysm or postsurgical stenosis of the target vessel Multiple lesions in the same target vessel unable to be treated with a maximum of two stents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>iliac artery stenosis</keyword>
	<keyword>claudication</keyword>
	<keyword>atherosclerotic iliac disease</keyword>
	<keyword>peripheral vascular disease</keyword>
</DOC>