<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01798563</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study the investigators are looking at two subtypes of Parkinson Disease (PD); "tremor-dominant" (TD) and postural imbalance and gait disorder (PIGD). This study will use magnet resonance imaging (MRI) to see how the brain reacts while resting and doing a finger-tapping task while on and off PD medication. This study will look at the differences between the two sub-types of PD and healthy volunteers. The investigators will test the hypothesis that connectivity at rest within the motor cortex and between the motor cortex and motor-associated regions such as the supplementary motor area and the pre motor cortex will not be as strong in PIGD compared to TD (increased activity and functional connectivity in TD group)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Functional Connectivity Parkinson Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>English as their primary language Patients with Parkinson disease and healthy controls will be enrolled Parkinson patients must be on a dopaminergic medication (levodopa or dopamine agonist) and on a stable dose over the prior month If unable to provide informed consent Pregnancy Excess of 300lbs Claustrophobia Metal in body Untreated neurological or psychiatric condition, who are delusional or have hallucinations, with cognitive impairment (MOCA&lt;26), with a history of head injury sufficient to cause a concussion, or with significant systemic medical diseases (e.g. heart failure, liver failure, kidney failure, poorly controlled diabetes, etc.) Healthy control subjects will be excluded if taking any type of dopaminergic or antidopaminergic medication Subjects who are unable to demonstrate understanding of the study procedures and risks will be excluded</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Parkinson</keyword>
	<keyword>Parkinson Disease</keyword>
</DOC>