<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01589575</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to compare the rate of reported anxiety / depression (HADS &gt;= 8) among spouses and other family members in ICU patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Anxiety and Depression in Relatives of Critically Ill Patients: Spouses Versus Other Close Relatives</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The secondary objectives of this study are: - to assess symptoms of anxiety (HADS ≥ 8) and depression (HADS ≥ 8) among relatives of ICU patients three months after discharge - to assess what relatives felt vis-à-vis the information process - describe the number and duration of interviews with participants - to compare variables between the groups "spouses" and "other relatives". - satisfaction - number and duration of interviews - HADS questionnaire - The scale Edmunton - an internal questionnaire - IES-R score - level of mental well-being: WEMWBS - to describe the completeness of the study - to test the hypothesis that the development of symptoms related to physical manifestations of anxiety and depression predicts the development of post-traumatic stress at 3 months. - to assess the impact of the various forms of stress during hospitalization.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The relative must have given his/her informed and signed consent The relative must be insured or beneficiary of a health insurance plan The relative must be available for 3 months of followup The relative is under judicial protection, under tutorship or curatorship The relative refuses to sign the consent It is impossible to correctly inform the relative</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Intensive Care Unit</keyword>
</DOC>