<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01108614</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to reduce the HIV/HCV incidence among the clients attending community-based methadone maintenance treatment (MMT) , and to prevent the secondary sexual transmission from HIV+ clients to their spouse and sex partners, through intensified comprehensive intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Injecting Drug Use Community Intervention Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Even though National sentinel surveillance data show that the increase rate of HIV new infections among IDUs in China has become stabilized and slowed down, the new HIV infection is still on the rise, especially in the Yunnan, Guizhou, Guangxi, Xinjiang and Sichuan. This study attempts to further reduce the new infection among MMT clients, and particularly to prevent the transmission from HIV infected clients to their sexual partners with comprehensive intervention. The purposes of this study are: 1. To evaluate the effectiveness of comprehensive interventions to decrease the HIV/STIs incidence among MMT clients. 2. To prevent the sexual transmission between those HIV+ clients and their spouse/partners with intensified intervention.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Syphilis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methadone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>(1) For MMT clients: 20 years or above and have independent capacity of civil conduct. Those have enrolled in MMT clinics more than one month, and progressed to the phase of maintenance treatment. No mental and other physical diseases More than 6month stay at local places and registered at the designated clinics. Complete Informed consent Fail to complete Informed consent Temporarily transit in or out of the designated clinic. Those have enrolled in MMT clinics less than one month, and haven't progressed to the phase of maintenance treatment. With serious mental or other physical diseases For the spouse or sex partners of MMT HIV+ clients' 20 years or above and have independent capacity of civil conduct. Keep fixed sexual contact with HIV+ clients in the recent 6 month No mental and other physical diseases More than 6month stay at local places and be able to participate the 1 year follow up. Complete Informed consent The recent HIV test is negative Fail to complete Informed consent Temporarily transit in or out of the designated clinic. With serious mental or other physical diseases The recent HIV test is positive</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Methadone maintenance treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>drug users</keyword>
	<keyword>heroin</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV</keyword>
	<keyword>Syphilis</keyword>
	<keyword>HSV-2</keyword>
</DOC>