<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00729339</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD) is a very common disease in the Western World. In Taiwan, this disease is increasing gradually because the investigators' eating style is closing to Western world. Proton pump is the main drug for patients with GERD in the past two decades. Prokinetic agent is an important adjuvant to the therapy of GERD. This study aims to evaluate the role of prokinetic agent in the management of GERD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Role of Mosapride in Patients With Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, double-blind, cross-over study. FSSG is obtained at the beginning, one month and two months of the study. This study plans to enroll 100 patients with symptoms of GERD (acid regurgitation, belching, dysphagia). After receiving endoscopic examination, a frequent scale for the symptoms of gastroesophageal reflux disease (FSSG) is obtained from these patients. Fifty patients receive lansoprazole 30 mg once plus mosapride 5 mg tid daily in the first month; and lansoprazole 30 mg once plus placebo tid daily in the second month. Another fifty patients receive lansoprazole 30 mg once plus placebo tid daily in the first month; and lansoprazole 30 mg once plus mosapride 5 mg tid daily in the second month.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Gastroesophageal Reflux</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lansoprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexlansoprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mosapride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged between 18 and 90 years old Outpatients Characteristic GERD symptoms: acid regurgitation, heart burn, or belching Erosive esophagitis on upper digestive endoscopy, based on Los Angeles classification History of allergy to lansoprazole or mosapride Pregnant or lactating women Uremia Decompensated liver disease Age under 18 and over 90 yearsold Lack of informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gastroesophageal reflux disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Mosapride</keyword>
	<keyword>Lansoprazole</keyword>
</DOC>