<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00005118</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see if it is safe and effective to give indinavir plus ritonavir plus 2 NRTIs to HIV-infected patients who need early intervention treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Safety and Effectiveness of Indinavir Plus Ritonavir Plus Two NRTIs in HIV-Infected Patients Who Need Early Intervention Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients receive indinavir bid plus ritonavir bid, plus 2 NRTIs bid (2 new NRTIs or 1 new NRTI and 1 NRTI without evidence of resistance). CD4 cell counts and plasma viral RNA are measured every 4 weeks for the duration of the study. Physical examination and laboratory tests of blood and urine are performed every 4 weeks for the duration of the study. Chest x-ray and 12-lead ECG are done prestudy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Indinavir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients may be eligible for this study if they: Are HIVpositive. Are 18 years of age or older. Have a CD4 cell count of at least 50 cells/mm3. Have a viral load (level of HIV in the blood) of at least 400 copies/ml but no more than 20,000 copies/ml. Have had an initial response to protease inhibitor therapy with a viral load of less than 400 copies/ml in two consecutive tests at least 1 week apart. Have been on antiHIV (antiretroviral) treatment including indinavir or nelfinavir for at least 16 weeks. Have had virologic failure (two consecutive viral loads that were greater than or equal to 400 copies/ml and less than or equal to 20,000 copies/ml at least 1 week apart) that is not due to another infection, vaccination, or a temporary stop in treatment. Are naive to at least one of the selected NRTIs.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2001</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV-1</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy, Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Protease Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>Ritonavir</keyword>
	<keyword>Indinavir</keyword>
	<keyword>Reverse Transcriptase Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-HIV Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Viral Load</keyword>
	<keyword>Nelfinavir</keyword>
</DOC>