<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00005085</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of rebeccamycin analog in treating patients who have metastatic or locally recurrent colorectal cancer. Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rebeccamycin Analog in Treating Patients With Metastatic or Locally Recurrent Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the objective response rate of patients with metastatic or locally recurrent colorectal cancer treated with rebeccamycin analogue. II. Determine the toxicity of this regimen in this patient population. III. Determine the effect of this regimen on progression-free and overall survival in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients receive rebeccamycin analogue IV once on day 1. Treatment repeats every 21 days for a maximum of 12 courses in the absence of unacceptable toxicity or disease progression. Patients are followed every 3 months for 2 years, every 6 months for 3 years, and then annually thereafter.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed metastatic or locally recurrent adenocarcinoma of the colon or rectum No curable stage of disease At least 1 unidimensionally measurable lesion At 20 mm by conventional techniques OR at least 10 mm by spiral CT scan No tumor lesions in previously irradiated area except clearly measurable lesion documented histologically to be consistent with recurrent tumor in previously irradiated bed within pelvis The following are considered nonmeasurable disease: Bone lesions Leptomeningeal disease Ascites Pleural/pericardial effusion Inflammatory breast disease Lymphangitis cutis/pulmonis Abdominal masses not confirmed and followed by imaging techniques Cystic lesions No known brain metastases PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: ECOG 02 OR Karnofsky 60100% Life expectancy: More than 12 weeks WBC at least 3,000/mm3 Absolute neutrophil count at least 1,500/mm3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm3 Bilirubin normal AST/ALT no greater than 2.5 times upper limit of normal Creatinine normal OR creatinine clearance at least 60 mL/min No symptomatic congestive heart failure No unstable angina pectoris No cardiac arrhythmia Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 6 months after study Eligible for placement of a central venous catheter No prior allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition to rebeccamycin analogue No other uncontrolled concurrent illness No ongoing or active infection No psychiatric illness or social situation that would preclude study compliance PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: No concurrent prophylactic growth factors (e.g., epoetin alfa) except for clinically defined indication (e.g., filgrastim (GCSF) for febrile neutropenia) At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy (e.g., fluorouracil, oral fluoropyrimidines, irinotecan, or oxaliplatin) (6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin) No other concurrent chemotherapy No concurrent hormones except for clinically defined indication At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy (including to bony sites, whole pelvis, lung, liver, or spinal cord/brain) and recovered No prior total dose of radiotherapy more than 7,000 cGy No prior radiotherapy to 40% or more of total bone marrow No prior radiotherapy to only site of measurable disease No concurrent radiotherapy Recovered from prior therapy 1 prior adjuvant treatment allowed 1 prior treatment for advanced disease allowed At least 4 weeks since prior investigational agents No other concurrent investigational antineoplastic drugs No other concurrent investigational agents No concurrent commercial agents for colorectal cancer No concurrent combination antiretroviral therapy for HIVpositive patients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2002</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IV colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV rectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent rectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma of the colon</keyword>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma of the rectum</keyword>
</DOC>