<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00005617</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Vaccines made from peptides may make the body build an immune response to kill tumor cells. PURPOSE: Phase I/II trial to study the effectiveness of vaccine therapy in treating patients who have stage IV, or relapsed malignant melanoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vaccine Therapy in Treating Patients With Stage IV or Relapsed Malignant Melanoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the safety of administering MART-1 peptide-pulsed dendritic cells to patients with stage IV or relapsed malignant melanoma. - Determine the immunological and clinical responses in this patient population after this therapy. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study. Patients undergo leukapheresis between days -14 to -8. Mononuclear cells are isolated, used to generate dendritic cells (DC), and then pulsed with MART-1 peptide. Patients are vaccinated with MART-1 peptide-pulsed DC either IV or intradermally on days 0, 14, and 28. Cohorts of 3-6 patients receive escalating doses of MART-1 peptide-pulsed DC until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose preceding that at which 2 of 6 patients experience dose-limiting toxicity. Patients are followed until death. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 18-24 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults over the age of 18 with malignant melanoma. HLAA2.1 positive and express MART1, as assessed by either RTPCR or by immunohistochemistry Tumor stages T3N0M0 or greater are eligible for this trial according to the following: 1. I (&lt;.75 to 1.5 mm or Clark level IIIT12N0M0)—not eligible 2. II (1.5 to 4 mm or level IVT3N0M0)—eligible 3. III (limited nodal metastasis involving one regional lymph node basin, or fewer than 5 intransit metastasis TxN1M0)—eligible 4. IV (advanced regional metastasis TxN2M0 or any distant metastasis TxNxM1)—eligible 5. Relapsed melanoma—eligible Patients previously treated with any form of therapy for either metastatic, relapsed or primary melanoma are eligible for this trial, provided that previous treatment was completed &gt;30 days prior to enrollment Both male and females may be enrolled. Premenopausal females must have a negative pregnancy test prior to treatment Karnofsky Performance Status greater than or equal to 70 percent No previous evidence of class 3 or greater New York Heart Association cardiac insufficiency or coronary artery disease No previous evidence of opportunistic infection A minimum of 30 days must have elapsed since the completion of prior chemotherapy, immunotherapy or radiation therapy Adequate baseline hematological function as assessed by the following laboratory values within 30 days prior to study entry (day 30 to 0): 1. Hemoglobin &gt;9.0 g/dl 2. Platelets &gt; 100000/mm3 3. WBC &gt; 3000/mm3 4. Absolute Neutrophil Count &gt; 1000/mm3 Positive skin test to common antigens (tetanus and candida) Ability to give informed consent Lactating females and females of childbearing potential must have negative serum betaHCG pregnancy test Acute infection: any acute viral, bacterial, or fungal infection which requires specific therapy. Acute therapy must have been completed within 14 days of prior to study treatment HIVinfected patients Acute medical problems such as ischemic heart or lung disease that may be considered an unacceptable anesthetic or operative risk Patients with any underlying conditions which would contraindicate therapy with study treatment (or allergies to reagents used in this study) Patients with organ allografts Uncontrolled CNS metastasis. Patients with CNS metastasis will be eligible if they have received CNS irradiation to control local tumor growth</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IV melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent melanoma</keyword>
</DOC>