<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02081014</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to demonstrate that mini-doses of stable liquid glucagon (G-Pen Mini) produced by Xeris Pharmaceuticals are safe and effective as a treatment for mild to moderate hypoglycemia, a complication of diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of Mini-Dose Glucagon (G-Pen Mini) in Patients With Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypoglycemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon-Like Peptide 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male and female subjects on insulin infusion pump therapy for treatment of type 1 diabetes 2. Between the ages of 18 and 50 years of age, inclusive, at Screening. 3. Females of childbearing potential with a negative serum pregnancy test prior at screening and negative urine pregnancy tests prior to the Treatment visits, using an approved forms of contraception for the duration of participation in the study (i.e. until after last dose). 4. Male subjects are required to use a condom and another of the methods of contraception in #3 above starting at Randomization and for the duration of the study. 5. Hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) &lt; 9.0 %. 6. Evidence of a personally signed and dated informed consent document indicating that the subject has been informed of all pertinent aspects of the study. 7. Subjects must be willing and able to comply with scheduled visits, treatment, laboratory tests and study procedures. 1. Clinical evidence of microvascular complication(s) other than mild microalbuminuria or history of mild nonproliferative retinopathy 2. Any chronic diseases or illness that interferes with glucose metabolism, except for T1DM, or medications other than hypothyroidism on appropriate thyroid hormone replacement. 3. Blood pressure (BP) readings at Screening where Systemic BP &lt;90 or &gt;140 mm Hg, and Diastolic BP &lt;50 or &gt;90 mm Hg. 4. Cardiovascular event within 6 months prior to screening such as unstable angina, acute coronary syndrome, myocardial infarction, therapeutic coronary procedure (e.g., stent placement, Percutaneous Transluminal Coronary Angioplasty (PTCA), Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting (CABG)), stroke or transient ischemic attack. 5. Study participants who are pregnant at Screening. 6. Breast feeding must be discontinued if a subject wishes to participate in this study. 7. Positive test for hepatitis B, hepatitis C, or HIV found at Screening. 8. Positive urine drug test for illicit drugs at Screening. 9. History of allergies to glucagon, glucagonlike products or to any of the excipients in the investigational formulation. 10. Known presence of hereditary problems of glycogen storage disease, galactose and /or lactose intolerance 11. Administration of glucagon more than once within the three (3) months prior to Screening 12. Subjects with any of the following abnormalities in clinical laboratory tests at Screening, confirmed by a single repeat, if necessary: Hemoglobin (Hb) below the lower limits of normal for the laboratory Total bilirubin above the upper limits of normal for the laboratory Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) above the upper limits of normal for the laboratory Creatinine above the upper limits of normal for the laboratory 13. History of regular alcohol consumption as defined by alcohol intake in a quantity exceeding 7 drinks per week for females or 14 drinks per week for males, where 1 drink = 5 ounces (150 mL) of wine or 12 ounces (360 mL) of beer or 1.5 ounces (45 mL) of hard liquor. 14. Participation in other studies involving administration of an investigational drug or device within 30 days or 5 halflives, whichever is longer, before screening for the current study and during participation in the current study 15. Whole blood donation of 1 pint (500 mL) within 8 weeks prior to Screening. Donations of plasma, packed red blood cells, platelets or quantities less than 500 mL are allowed at investigator discretion. 16. Other severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory abnormality that may increase the risk associated with study participation or investigational product administration or may interfere with the interpretation of study results and, in the judgment of the investigator, would make the subject inappropriate for entry into this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hypoglycemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucagon</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
</DOC>