<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02081508</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to investigate whether minimizing interference improves memory in multiple sclerosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Consolidation &amp; Interference in Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The ability to form new long-lasting memories is important for successful independent living and a high quality of life. Roughly half of the individuals diagnosed with Multiple Sclerosis (MS) have difficulty remembering new information and this is likely associated with poor acquisition of new information. There are only a limited number of studies that have investigated memory consolidation in MS. The current study will investigate the role of interference during the consolidation time period of memory formation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>If you are between the ages of 1865. If you have a diagnosis of Multiple Sclerosis (MS) or are medically healthy. If you have MS, you have not had a flare up of MS symptoms in the past month. You do not have other neurological issues such as, Epilepsy or Stroke. You do not have a significant history of psychiatric problems or a current diagnosis of Major Depressive Disorder, Schizophrenia, Bipolar Disorder . You do not have a significant history of drug or alcohol abuse. You can read and speak English fluently. You are not currently taking steroids. You are younger than 18 years old. You are older than 65 years old. You have had a prior stroke or neurological disease other than MS. You have a history of significant psychiatric illness (for example, bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, or psychosis) or a current diagnosis of Major Depressive Disorder, Bipolar Disorder. You have a significant alcohol or drug abuse history. You are currently taking steroids.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Memory</keyword>
</DOC>