<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02081950</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a pilot, open-label study aimed at a preliminary evaluation of enoxaparin bioavailability following two administrations of Clexane s.c. at a dose of 80mg, in two different periods.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Single-Dose Study to Examine the Within Subject Variability of Clexane® in Healthy Adult Subjects Under Fasting Conditions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Enoxaparin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy male or female volunteer between 18 and 55 years of age. Female subject of child bearing potential with a negative pregnancy test at the Screening Visit and willing to use 2 effective methods of contraception from Day 1 until 3 months afterwards. Subject with no clinically significant abnormal serum biochemistry, haematology, coagulation factors and urine examination values within 14 days of the first dose. Female subject with weight &lt; 45 kg or male subject with weight &lt; 57 kg. Subject with clinically relevant abnormal physical findings which could interfere with the objective of the study. Subject with clinically relevant abnormal laboratory values indicative of physical illness; Hemoglobin &lt;13 g/dL; Absolute platelet count below 100 x 109/L. Subject with hypersensitivity or idiosyncratic reaction to enoxaparin and/or low molecular weight heparins, and/or pork products. Subject with a relevant history or presence of significant cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic, renal, hematologic, gastrointestinal, endocrine, immunologic, dermatologic, neurologic, or psychiatric disease. In addition, history or presence of: alcoholism or drug abuse within the past year; clotting disorders; gastric or duodenal ulcers; hypertension; retinopathy; deep venous thrombosis; pulmonary embolism; GI bleeding. Subject with any clinically significant illness within 4 weeks prior to dosing. Subject with recent use of NSAID and/or aspirin (within 4 weeks of first dose) or the use of any pharmacological agents known to significantly induce or inhibit drugmetabolizing enzymes within 30 days of the first dose. No subject may take any antibiotic agent known to interfere with intestinal microflora within 30 days of the first dose. Subjects with any medical condition requiring regular treatment with prescription drugs.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>