<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02369016</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Assess the efficacy and safety of copanlisib monotherapy</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase III Copanlisib in Rituximab-refractory iNHL</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Double blind copanlisib vs placebo with unblinding after centrally assessed progression and option to cross over to copanlisib for patients who progressed on placebo.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed diagnosis of indolent Bcell NHL, with histological subtype limited to the following: Follicular lymphoma (FL) grade 123a. Small lymphocytic lymphoma (SLL) with absolute lymphocyte count &lt; 5 x 109/L at the time of diagnosis and at study entry. Lymphoplasmacytoid lymphoma/Waldenström macroglobulinemia (LPL/WM). Marginal zone lymphoma (MZL) (splenic, nodal, or extranodal). Patients must have received two or more prior lines of treatment. A previous regimen is defined as one of the following: at least two months of singleagent therapy, at least two consecutive cycles of polychemotherapy, autologous transplant, radioimmunotherapy. Prior therapy must include rituximab and alkylating agents. Prior exposure to idelalisib or other PI3K (Phosphatidylinositol 3kinase) inhibitors is acceptable (except to copanlisib) provided that there is no resistance. Patients must be refractory to the last rituximabbased treatment, defined as no response or response lasting &lt; 6 months after completion of treatment. Time interval to assess refractoriness will be calculated between the end date (last day) of the last rituximabcontaining regimen and the day of diagnosis confirmation of the subsequent relapse. Patients must have at least one bidimensionally measurable lesion (which has not been previously irradiated) according to the Recommendations for Initial Evaluation, Staging, and Response Assessment of Hodgkin and NonHodgkin Lymphoma: The Lugano Classification. Patients affected by WM (Waldenström macroglobulinemia), who do not have at least one bidimensionally measurable lesion in the baseline radiologic assessment, must have measurable disease, defined as presence of immunoglobulin M (IgM) paraprotein with a minimum IgM level ≥ 2 x upper limit of normal (ULN) and positive immunofixation test. Histologically confirmed diagnosis of FL grade 3b. Chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL). Transformed disease (assessed by investigator): histological confirmation of transformation, or clinical and laboratory signs: rapid disease progression, high standardized uptake value (SUV) (&gt; 12) by positron emission tomography (PET) at baseline if PET scans are performed (optional). Previous or concurrent cancer that is distinct in primary site or histology from indolent Bcell NHL within 5 years before start of study treatment except for curatively treated cervical cancer in situ, nonmelanoma skin cancer and superficial bladder tumors [Ta (noninvasive tumor), Tis (carcinoma in situ) and T1 (tumor invades lamina propria)] Bulky disease Lymph nodes or tumor mass (except spleen) &gt;= 7cm LD (longest diameter) Known lymphomatous involvement of the central nervous system. Uncontrolled arterial hypertension despite optimal medical management (per investigator's assessment). Type I or II diabetes mellitus with HbA1c &gt; 8.5% at Screening. Known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. Positive cytomegalovirus (CMV) PCR test at baseline.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>indolent Non-Hodgkin lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>rituximab-refractory</keyword>
</DOC>