<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01486316</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to characterize the feasibility and impact of a diagnostic tool that may help clinicians identify when patients are at higher risk of visiting the hospital for a heart failure event. The study will use a non-experimental device that is inserted just under the skin of the chest, which continuously monitors the heart rhythm in combination with an experimental web-based heart failure risk status. Patients with atrial fibrillation and heart failure will be evaluated to collect data about the potential of this risk status to help improve patient outcome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Diagnostic Device Risk Management of Atrial Fibrillation and Heart Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient is 18 years of age or older Patient (or patient's legally authorized representative) is willing and able to provide written informed consent Patient is willing and able to comply with the protocol, including followup visits Documented paroxysmal or persistent atrial fibrillation or strong suspicion of atrial fibrillation (i.e, palpitations) Patient is indicated for the Reveal XT insertable cardiac monitor or other commerciallyavailable and substantially equivalent Medtronic insertable cardiac monitor Recent HF event within prior 120 days (HF event defined as meeting any one of the following two criteria: 1. Admission with primary diagnosis of HF 2. Intravenous HF therapy (e.g. IV diuretics/vasodilators) or ultrafiltration at any one of the following settings: admission with secondary/tertiary diagnosis of HF, emergency department, ambulance, observation unit, urgent care, HF/cardiology clinic, patient's home Willing and able to transmit data via CareLink Patient is pregnant Patient has been participating in another study that may interfere with the IDENTIFYHF protocol required procedures Endstage (Stage D or New York Heart Association class IV) heart failure Asymptomatic (Stage B or New York Heart Association class I) heart failure Severe aortic stenosis or insufficiency Existing insertable cardiac monitor implanted for more than 1 year Existing implantable pulse generator, implantable cardioverter defibrillator, cardiac resynchronization therapy device Severe renal impairment (estimated glomerular filtration rate &lt;25mL/min) Myocardial infarction within prior 30 days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>