<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02416063</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this prospective randomized double-blind study was to compare the analgesic efficacy and the side effects of dexmedetomidine (1 µg.kg-1) co-administered with bupivacaine for caudal analgesia or intravenously in children undergoing infra-umbilical surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Caudal Versus Intravenous Dexmedetomidine for Caudal Analgesia in Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Dexmedetomidine is used increasingly in pediatric anesthesia practice to prolong the duration of action of caudal block with a local anesthetic agent.But which route of administration of dexmedetomidine is the most beneficial remains unknown. The investigators performed prospective randomized double-blind study to compare the effects of caudal dexmedetomidine with intravenous dexmedetomidine on postoperative analgesia after caudal bupivacaine in children undergoing infra-umbilical surgery. 75 children (ASAⅠorⅡ,aged 1-6 yr) undergoing infra-umbilical surgery were included in this study. Anesthesia was induced with sevoflurane via a facemask, followed by placement of a laryngeal mask airway. Anesthesia was maintained with sevoflurane 2-3% in oxygen-air.Then,caudal block was applied. Patients were randomly assigned in three groups. Group B-Dcau (n = 25): Caudal bupivacaine 0.25% 1ml/kg plus dexmedetomidine 1µg/kg and 10 ml normal saline i.v.;Group B-Div (n = 25): bupivacaine 0.25% 1ml/kg and dexmedetomidine 1µg/kg(10 ml)i.v.;Group B(n = 25): bupivacaine 0.25% and 10 ml normal saline intravenous</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sevoflurane</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) I Scheduled for lower abdominal and perineal surgery Under general anesthesia Hypersensitivity to any local anesthetics Patient has history of allergy, intolerance, or reaction to dexmedetomidine Infections at puncture sites Bleeding diathesis Preexisting neurological disease Children with uncorrected cardiac lesions Children with heart block</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>