<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02416492</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of the clinical study is to evaluate the clinical efficacy of intracranial administration of SB623 cells on patients with chronic motor deficit from Traumatic Brain Injury. A secondary purpose of the study is 1) to evaluate the effect of intracranial administration of SB623 cells on disability parameters and 2) to evaluate the safety and tolerability of intracranial administration of SB623 cells. Patients with stable, chronic motor deficits secondary to focal traumatic brain injury must be 12 months post TBI.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Modified Stem Cells in Traumatic Brain Injury (TBI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>SB623 cells are adult bone-marrow-derived cells that are transiently transfected with a plasmid construct encoding the intracellular domain of human Notch-1. These cells produce trophic factors that protect neurons in models of ischemic insult. In a rat contusion model of TBI, implantation of SB623 around the area of the injury resulted in significant improvement of motor function. Further, safety evaluation of animal models implanted with SB623 cells have shown no adverse effects and no SB623-related clinical, laboratory, or histological abnormalities were found. A Phase 1/2A dose escalation study (NCT01287936) of SB623 stereotactically implanted into the brains of patients with chronic motor deficits due to ischemic stroke has been fully enrolled, with all patients followed through 18 months post-infarct. This study has shown statistically-significant improvements in motor function in each of three scales: the European Stroke Scale (ESS), the National Institute of Health Stroke Scale (NIHSS) and the Fugl-Meyer scale. To date, the study has also shown no serious adverse events attributed to SB623, and only minor adverse events mostly grade 1 or 2 (with one grade 3) that were unrelated, unlikely related, or possibly related to SB623. No dose-limiting toxicities have been observed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Documented history of TBI, with correlated MRI or CT At least 12 months postTBI Focal cerebral injury able to be identified on MRI (+/ concomitant diffuse axonal injury) Neurological motor deficit substantially due to focal cerebral injury observed on MRI GOSE score of 36 (i.e. moderate or severe disability) Require both Motricity Index 1081 (UE Scale) and 1078 (LE Scale) Able and willing to undergo computed tomography (CT) and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) Subjects must be willing to participate in study related exercises to the extent possible Able to undergo all planned neurological assessments History or presence of any other major neurological disease Any seizures in the prior 3 months The presence of contracture at any joints that would interfere with interpretation of any of the neurological assessments (e.g. contracture preventing the detection of any increase in the range of motion or ability to perform a task) Other neurologic, neuromuscular or orthopedic disease that limits motor function Clincially significant finding on MRI of brain not related to TBI Known presence of any malignancy except squamous or basal cell carcinoma of the skin History of CNS malignancy Positive findings on tests for occult malignancy, unless a nonmalignant etiology is confirmed Uncontrolled systemic illness, including, but not limited to: hypertension (systolic &gt;150 mm Hg or diastolic &gt;95 mm Hg); diabetes; renal, hepatic, or cardiac failure Uncontrolled major psychiatric illness, including depression symptoms (CESDR Scale of ≥16) Unexplained abnormal preoperative test values (blood tests, electrocardiogram [ECG], chest Xray); xray evidence of infection; uncontrolled atrial fibrillation or uncontrolled congestive heart failure Presence of craniectomy (without bone flap replacement) or other contraindication to stereotactic surgery Participation in any other investigational trial within 4 weeks of initial screening or within 7 weeks of study entry Botulinum toxin injection, phenol injection, intrathecal baclofen, or any other interventional treatments for spasticity (except bracing and splinting) within the previous 4 months. Ongoing use of other nontraditional drugs Substance use disorder (per DSMV criteria, including drug or alcohol) Contraindications to head CT or MRI Pregnant or lactating Female patients of childbearing potential unwilling to use an adequate birth control method during the 12 months of the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>