<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00030498</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Phase I trial to study the effectiveness of erlotinib in treating patients who have metastatic or unresectable solid tumors and liver or kidney dysfunction. Biological therapies such as erlotinib may interfere with the growth of tumor cells and slow the growth of the tumor</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Erlotinib in Treating Patients With Solid Tumors and Liver or Kidney Dysfunction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the maximum tolerated dose of erlotinib in patients with solid tumors and hepatic or renal dysfunction. II. Determine the pharmacokinetics of this drug in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation, multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to hepatic or renal dysfunction (albumin less than 2.5 g/dL, direct bilirubin less than 1.0 mg/dL, any AST, and creatinine normal vs direct bilirubin 1.0-7.0 mg/dL, any AST, and creatinine normal vs creatinine 2.5-5.0 mg/dL, albumin 2.5 g/dL or greater, AST less than 3 times upper limit of normal, and direct bilirubin less than 1.0 mg/dL). Patients receive oral erlotinib once daily. Treatment continues in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Cohorts of 3-6 patients receive escalating doses of erlotinib until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose preceding that at which at least 2 of 3 or 2 of 6 patients experience dose-limiting toxicity. Once the MTD is determined, at least 6 evaluable patients are treated at that dose.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colonic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Laryngeal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Astrocytoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Glandular and Epithelial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Laryngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mesothelioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oropharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Verrucous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Basal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Papilloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gliosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ependymoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nasopharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oligodendroglioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Salivary Gland Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paranasal Sinus Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Granuloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Adenoid Cystic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anus Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Unknown Primary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms, Male</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Mucoepidermoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esthesioneuroblastoma, Olfactory</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Papilloma, Inverted</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma, Subependymal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuroectodermal Tumors, Primitive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed solid tumor, including gliomas and the following epithelial malignancies: Nonsmall cell lung Mesothelioma Breast Head and neck Esophageal Pancreatic Bladder Prostate Ovarian Anal Colorectal carcinoma Cervical carcinoma Hepatocellular carcinoma Metastatic or unresectable disease Standard curative or palliative therapy does not exist or is no longer effective Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) positive Hepatic or renal dysfunction defined as one of the following: Direct bilirubin 1.07.0 mg/dL with any AST Albumin less than 2.5 g/dL Creatinine 2.55.0 mg/dL Brain metastases allowed provided patient is asymptomatic, previously treated, has stable disease for at least 2 months, and is not currently receiving steroid therapy Hormone receptor status: Not specified Male or female Performance status ECOG 02 Granulocyte count at least 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm^3 See Disease Characteristics No evidence of biliary obstruction See Disease Characteristics No evidence of renal obstruction No symptomatic congestive heart failure No unstable angina pectoris No cardiac arrhythmia No gastrointestinal tract disease that would preclude ability to take oral medications No requirement for IV alimentation No active peptic ulcer disease No prior corneal abnormalities (e.g., dry eye syndrome or Sjogren's syndrome) No prior congenital abnormality (e.g., Fuch's dystrophy) No prior abnormal slitlamp exam using a vital dye (e.g., fluorescein or BengalRose) No prior abnormal corneal sensitivity test (e.g., Schirmer test or similar tear production test) No other concurrent uncontrolled illness No ongoing or active infection No psychiatric illness or social situation that would preclude study compliance Not pregnant or nursing Fertile patients must use effective contraception No concurrent filgrastim (GCSF) or sargramostim (GMCSF) At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy (6 weeks for melphalan or mitomycin) No prior nitrosoureas See Disease Characteristics No concurrent steroids At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy At least 4 weeks since prior major surgery No prior surgical procedures affecting absorption No prior EGFRtargeting therapies, including gefitinib or Imclone C225 At least 3 months since prior suramin More than 7 days since prior grapefruit juice More than 7 days since other prior CYP3A4 inhibitors No concurrent grapefruit juice No concurrent CYP3A4 inducers, substrates, or other inhibitors No concurrent medications known to affect hepatic or renal function, including antiseizure medication or nonsteroidal antiinflammatory agents No concurrent combination antiretroviral therapy for HIVpositive patients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>