<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02555111</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Open randomized therapeutic study to assess the efficacy of Xarelto 15mg/day in the recurrence of thromboembolic event compared to an untreated group in patients with chronic portal vein thrombosis without high risk thrombophilia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Xarelto Versus no Treatment for the Prevention of Recurrent Thrombosis in Patients With Chronic Portal Vein Thrombosis.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Chronic portal vein thrombosis (PVT) is a rare disease, affecting young patients, characterized by permanent obstruction of the portal vein trunk causing portal hypertension. In 60-70% of cases it is related to high risk, moderate or mild prothrombotic risk factors. Accordingly, there are 2 types of complications from PVT :(i) gastrointestinal haemorrhage related to portal hypertension; and (ii) recurrent thrombosis. Recurrent thrombosis its most dreaded complication as it may lead to intestinal infarction with a related mortality of 20-60% and a high risk of intestinal insufficiency. Gastrointestinal haemorrhage related to portal hypertension occurs in 20% patients/year. It is less frequent in patients treated with medical or endoscopic prophylaxis for variceal bleeding. Retrospective data shows that anticoagulation does not worsen the prognosis, and may conversely improve it. Thus, in patients at risk for gastrointestinal bleeding due to portal hypertension and a mild or moderate risk of recurrent thrombosis, the benefit-risk ratio of anticoagulation therapy is unclear. The aim of this open randomised trial is to assess the efficacy of Xarelto 15mg/day, a new oral factor Xa inhibitor, in the recurrence of thromboembolic event and the risk of major bleeding compared to an untreated group in patients with chronic portal vein thrombosis without high risk thrombophilia. This is a national, multicentric, interventional study. 15 french centers already agreed to participate. 296 patients will be included on a 2 years period with 2 to 4 years treatment period. All data will be collected after informed consent will be obtained.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
	<criteria>80 years old &gt;Adults &gt; 18 years old Patients Either affected by cavernous portal, with a constituted diagnostic on radiological criteria, treated or not with anticoagulant Or acute portal thrombosis history dating back more than 6 months, documented by angiography or angioMRI ; followed or not by a repermeabilize. Patient who was used prophylaxis for gastrointestinal bleeding in portal hypertension, according to current consensus recommendations for patients with cirrhosis Barrier contraception or intrauterine device (with or without progestin), for women of childbearing age, or progestin alone. Do not use combined hormonal contraception. Presence of a high risk factor of recurrence of thrombosis veinous after review of the medical file by a validation committee composed of an hepatologist and a hematologist physician hemostasis specialist. Disease with relevant coagulopathy and bleeding risk clinically relevant (platelet &lt; 50 000, or TP &lt;30 % without AVK or Factor V &lt; 30% ou fibrinogen &lt; 0.8) Cirrhosis clinically relevant or with histological test or Budd Chiari syndrome. Personnel or first degree familial past history of spontaneous (unprovoked) deep vein thrombosis require an anticoagulant treatment Pregnancy and breast feeding women Past history of mesenteric infarction Absolute necessity of anticoagulation whatever the cause Galactose intolerance, Lapp lactase deficiency, malabsorption of glucose and galactose HIV positive Patient with impossible follow up Severe renal failure (creatinin clearance &lt; 30 ml/min) Concomitant treatment with ketoconazole, l'itraconazole, le voriconazole or posaconazole, or HIV protease inhibitor, potent CYP3A4 and Pgp inhibitors Simultaneous treatment with rifampicin or other CYP3A4 inductor Hypersensitivity to Xarelto or one of the excipients Progressive bleeding, clinically relevant including lesion or disease with significant risk of major bleeding. Concomitant treatment with other anticoagulant (unfractionated heparin (UFH), low molecular weight heparin (enoxaparin, dalteparin, etc.), heparin derivatives (fondaparinux, etc.), oral anticoagulants (warfarin, dabigatran etexilate, apixaban, etc.), unless relay with Xarelto® or "viceversa", or when administered at doses f UFH necessary to maintain the permeability of a central venous or arterial catheter. Concomitant treatment of acute coronary syndrome clopidogrel / Plavix® Liver transplantation Transjugular intrahepatic portosystemic shunt</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>thrombosis</keyword>
</DOC>