<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02555813</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This observational program collects data on tolerability, safety and efficacy regarding the use of Abraxane in metastatic pancreatic cancer patients in the daily clinical routine. Additionally data on dosage that is actually used in these patients will be collected. Patients who have pancreatic cancer and additional diseases can be documented in this study, too. Collected data might generate learnings on the optimal use of Abraxane in the daily routine setting.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Pancreatic Cancer With Abraxane</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This observational program is aimed at gaining tolerability, safety and efficacy data with the routine use of Abraxane in its labeled indication in metastatic pancreatic cancer. Additionally data on real life dosing in daily clinical routine will be analyzed. A detailed record of the medical history including co-morbidities and pre-treatment regimens will allow analysis of the impact thereof on tolerability, dosage and efficacy. Hands-on experience with nab-paclitaxel is very limited in Austria and an non-interventional study could enhance knowledge on optimal drug handling and Adverse Event management.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Metastatic pancreatic carcinoma 2. Age &gt; 18 years 3. Signed Informed Consent 4. Normal hepatic, renal and Bone Marrow functions 1. Pregnant and lactating females 2. Previous treatment for metastatic pancreatic disease 3. Known hypersensitivity to nabpaclitaxel 4. Neutrophils &lt; 1,5 x 10^9/L</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>nab-Paclitaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>Gemcitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-interventional</keyword>
</DOC>