<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00641420</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Fractionated laser resurfacing is commonly used as a treatment for acne scarring in fair skinned individuals. This study aims to test the efficacy and safety in darker skin types. Patients are randomized to either the 10mJ 40mJ dosages and receive a total of five treatments at 17% one month apart. Improvement is judged by a dermatologist as 0-25%, 25-50%, 50-75% or 75-100%. Side effects such as pigmentary abnormalities and pain are also evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of 1550nm Fractional Laser Treatment for Acne Scars in Fitzpatrick Type IV-VI Skin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Cicatrix</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female voluntary patients between the ages of 18 and 59 with Fitzpatrick skin type IVVI as verified by one of the investigators Patients with clinical diagnosis of ice pick, rolling, or boxcar type ane scarring Patients able to follow instructions If patient has a history of cold sores (herpes labialis) they must be willing to take prophylactic valtrex Written informed consent from the patients (Appendix II) Children (less than 18 years old) Pregnant or lactating women Personal history of keloids or hypertrophic scarring Active acne requiring topical or oral therapy Accutane or other oral retinoid in past year Patients with a known allergy to lidocaine Allergy to valacyclovir in a patient that needs prophylaxis Patients with an unstable or non controlled underlying medical problem Patients who are not able to follow instructions Patients who have participated in a study within the 3 months prior to study entry Patients who refuse to give written informed consent Patients with a history of a pigmentary abnormality</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>59 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acne scarring</keyword>
	<keyword>Post inflammatory hyperpigmentation</keyword>
</DOC>