<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02227550</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study objective is to demonstrate that anticoagulation with the direct factor Xa inhibitor apixaban is not less safe than Vitamin-K-antagonists (VKA) therapy in patients undergoing catheter ablation of non-valvular AF in the prevention of peri-procedural complications. The AXAFA trial will compare peri-ablational treatment with apixaban to peri-ablational treatment wit VKA in a randomized trial of patients undergoing catheter ablation of atrial fibrillation (AF).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Apixaban During Atrial Fibrillation Catheter Ablation: Comparison to Vitamin K Antagonist Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>AXAFA is an open-label trial designed to evaluate the safety and efficacy of two types of anticoagulant therapy, VKA therapy and therapy with the direct factor Xa inhibitor apixaban, in patients undergoing scheduled catheter ablation for AF. All patients will undergo the ablation procedure after pre-treatment with an anticoagulant (either apixaban in the "Xa group" or a vitamin K antagonist in the "VKA group"). Patients can undergo catheter ablation within the trial after at least 30 days of continuous effective anticoagulation. Ablation can be performed earlier when or timely after exclusion of atrial thrombi have been excluded by a clinically indicated by transthoracic echocardioggram (TEE). After TEE continuous effective anticoagulation must be ensured until the end of the trial. In the MRI-substudy will be explored wether novel oral anticoagulants (NOAC) have the potential to reduce clinically silent brain lesions after catheter ablation of AF.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin K</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Apixaban</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Factor Xa Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phenprocoumon</mesh_term>
	<criteria>I1. Nonvalvular AF (ECGdocumented) with a clinical indication for catheter ablation I2. Clinical indication to undergo catheter ablation on continuous anticoagulant therapy I3. Presence of at least one of the CHADS2 stroke risk factors Stroke or TIA age ≥ 75 years, hypertension, defined as chronic treatment for hypertension, estimated need for continuous antihypertensive therapy or resting blood pressure &gt; 145/90 mm Hg, diabetes mellitus, symptomatic heart failure (NYHA ≥ II). I4. Age ≥ 18 years I5. Provision of signed informed consent General exclusion criteria E1. Any disease that limits life expectancy to less than 1 year E2. Participation in another clinical trial, either within the past two months or still ongoing E3. Previous participation in AXAFA E4. Pregnant women or women of childbearing potential not on adequate birth control: only women with a highly effective method of contraception (oral contraception or intrauterine device) or sterile women can be randomised. E5. Breastfeeding women E6. Drug abuse or clinically manifest alcohol abuse E7. Any stroke within 14 days before randomisation Exclusion criteria related to a cardiac condition E8. Valvular AF (as defined by the focussed update of the ESC guidelines on AF, i.e. severe mitral valve stenosis, mechanical heart valve). Furthermore, patients who underwent mitral valve repair are not eligible for AXAFA. E9. Any previous ablation or surgical therapy for AF E10. Cardiac ablation therapy for any indication (catheterbased or surgical) within 3 months prior to randomisation E11. Clinical need for "triple therapy" (combination therapy of clopidogrel, acetylsalicylic acid, and oral anticoagulation) E12. Other contraindications for use of VKA or apixaban Exclusion criteria based on laboratory abnormalities E13. Severe chronic kidney disease with an estimated glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt; 15 ml/min</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Atrilal fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>anticoagulation</keyword>
	<keyword>prevention of peri-procedural complication</keyword>
	<keyword>catheter ablation</keyword>
</DOC>