<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02462057</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Vitality HealthyFood benefit is a three-tiered incentive program designed to encourage healthier food choices amongst members of Discovery Health's Vitality program. Once enrolled in the benefit, participating members can receive 10%, 15%, or 25% cash-back on the healthy foods they purchase at selected grocers. And, while overall enrollment in the program is high, there is particular interest in increasing enrollment in the benefit amongst Vitality members with diabetes. One presumed barrier to enrollment in the benefit amongst members with diabetes is a misperception of the particular relevance of the benefit and healthier food choices for their personal health. Improved messaging regarding the HealthyFood benefit and its particular salience for individuals with diabetes may be an effective means of increasing activation of the benefit in this population. The proposed study will be a collaboration between Discovery Health/Vitality and researchers at the Perelman School of Medicine at the University of Pennsylvania. In the proposed RCT, Vitality members with diabetes will be randomised to different types of messages regarding the HealthyFood benefit. The investigators will then compare the effectiveness of these different messaging strategies at increasing activation of the HealthyFood benefit amongst Vitality members with diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Testing Different Messaging Approaches to Increase Activation of a HealthyFood Benefit in Adults With Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Adults over age 18 2. Vitality health members who have not yet enrolled in the Vitality HealthyFood benefit 3. Diagnosis of type 2 diabetes (based on registration for chronic benefits for type 2 diabetes) 4. Have registered on to Discovery Health/Vitality website in the past (marker of Internet access and availability of email address) Anyone who does not meet above criteria</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>