<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02462785</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Helping individuals with diabetes to control their blood sugars through self-management is an important goal, and counting carbohydrates (CHO) remains a key part of diabetes education and management. There is very little research examining CHO counting education with adolescents who have type 1 diabetes (T1DM). The purpose of this pilot study is to evaluate a newly developed internet-based teaching module of CHO counting for adolescents, ages 12-17 years, with T1DM and who do not regularly CHO count and require instruction. A secondary aim is to assess feasibility for a future, larger-scale clinical trail. An effective web-based CHO counting tutorial could be used to strengthen current diabetes education programs and may serve as a basis for developing other teaching modules. Advantages of web-based teaching include convenience, increased accessibility, and the ability to review and reinforce teaching concepts through repetition. It may also encourage adolescents to take the initiative for their own diabetes care, beginning with a self-directed, active learning experience.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Evaluation of Internet-based Carbohydrate Counting Education for Adolescents With Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adolescents aged 1217 years with a diagnosis of T1DM for more than 1 year Followed at the SickKids Diabetes Clinic Have access to a computer with Internet connection Able to communicate in English Patients with type 2 diabetes, medicationinduced diabetes or other forms of non T1DM Patients with Celiac disease, due to differences in prescribed dietary regimen Patients who are unable to communicate in English No computer or internet access Patient with cognitive delay impeding their ability to learn CHO counting Patients who have attended a CHO counting class within the past 6 months Patients who do not eat the foods presented on the planned meal &amp; snack trays</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Adolescents</keyword>
	<keyword>Carbohydrate Counting</keyword>
	<keyword>Glycemic Control</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-Management</keyword>
	<keyword>T1DM</keyword>
</DOC>