<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02462434</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates maternal psychological distress and the impact of early palliative care team consultation on maternal anxiety and depression symptoms, coping, and quality of life/family functioning in the care of neonates born with single ventricle physiology. Half of the participants will receive early palliative care team consultation, while the other half will receive usual care (no or late palliative care intervention). The investigators hypothesize maternal stress, anxiety, and depression will be lower in the palliative care intervention group compared with the control group, and maternal coping mechanisms and perceived quality of life and family functioning will improve at the pre-discharge assessment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Early Intervention on Maternal Stress in Mothers of Fetuses Diagnosed With Single Ventricle Physiology</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Mothers of children with congenital heart disease are at increased risk of psychological morbidity including stress, anxiety, and depression. In particular, mothers of patients with single ventricle physiology who require neonatal surgery, face a great deal of stress related to the risk of serious complications including neonatal death. Previous studies have suggested that providing emotional psychosocial support may modify the development of significant psychosocial problems in parents of children with congenital heart disease. The pediatric palliative care team specializes in multiple elements of psychological and spiritual care for families of such children. The purpose of this pilot study is to evaluate maternal psychological distress and to examine the potential impact of early palliative care team consultation on maternal anxiety and depression symptoms, coping, and quality of life/family functioning in the care of neonates born with single ventricle physiology. Mothers will complete four questionnaires measuring anxiety, depression, and quality of life/family functioning at a prenatal follow up visit and again prior to neonatal surgical hospital stay discharge (or at 30 days). Infants will be randomly assigned (by date of birth) to receive early palliative care team consultation or usual care (no or late palliative care intervention). The investigators hypothesize maternal stress, anxiety, and depression will be lower in the palliative care intervention group compared with the control group, and maternal coping mechanisms and perceived quality of life and family functioning will improve at the pre-discharge assessment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stress, Psychological</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Congenital Abnormalities</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Defects, Congenital</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypoplastic Left Heart Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Mothers pregnant with fetuses with single ventricle physiology who are planned to undergo staged single ventricle palliative surgery with the first surgery occurring in the neonatal period. Mothers with neonates born at a gestational age of less than 32 weeks requiring admission and management in the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit. Mothers with neonates diagnosed with major noncardiac congenital anomalies requiring additional surgical management beyond cardiac surgery in the neonatal period. NonEnglishspeaking mothers who are unable to adequately comprehend and respond to survey questions administered as part of this study.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pediatric palliative care</keyword>
</DOC>