<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00221845</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In children with chronic kidney disease, progression to end-stage renal failure is associated with high patient morbidity and poor quality of life. In adults, inhibition of the renin angiotensin system (RAS) slows down the rate of renal failure progression. This concept is as yet unproven in children, in whom chronic renal failure (CRF) is more commonly due to hypo/dysplastic malformations than to acquired glomerulopathies as typical for adult chronic kidney disease. The current project aims at assessing the genetic and molecular mechanisms and cardiovascular consequences of progressive CRF and to develop a strategy of pharmacological renoprotection in children.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Strict Blood Pressure Control and ACE-Inhibition on Progression of Chronic Renal Failure in Pediatric Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Chronic kidney diseases affecting the nephron mass are characterized by a progressive decline of glomerular filtration rate (GFR) occurring irrespectively of the cause of the renal damage once a critical number of nephrons has been lost. Current clinical research efforts focus on preventive strategies to slow down or arrest disease progression. Systemic hypertension and glomerular hyperfiltration with resulting proteinuria and activation of vasoactive, profibrotic and proinflammatory systems have been identified as major causes of further nephron damage. Angiotensin converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitors are not only potent antihypertensive agents but also reduce proteinuria, glomerulosclerosis and tubulointerstitial fibrosis via reduction of the local angiotensin tone in the kidney, and have been demonstrated to slow down renal failure progression in adult patients. Childhood-onset ESRD is a rare but particularly devastating disease with poor life expectancy and quality of life. Chronic renal failure in children is caused by a different spectrum of nephropathies than in adults, with a preponderance of congenital or inherited abnormalities. Since hypertension, proteinuria and tubulointerstitial fibrosis are also common in pediatric chronic renal failure, there is a rationale for pharmacological renoprotection by ACE inhibition in children. The prospective, randomized European clinical trial launched by our consortium will provide the critical mass to assess several aspects of renoprotective therapy in children. Specifically, the trial is designed to address the following scientific objectives: Objective 1 is to evaluate whether ACE inhibition is equally effective in slowing down the progression rate of chronic renal failure in children with different congenital and acquired renal disorders. 400 pediatric patients will be stratified according to their underlying diseases, and the rate of loss in glomerular filtration rate will be assessed from 6 months before to 5 years after start of treatment with the ACE inhibitor ramipril. Objective 2 of the trial is to evaluate whether renal failure progression in patients treated with a fixed dose of ramipril can be further slowed down by additional antihypertensive treatment, achieving a blood pressure below the 50th percentile. To this end, patients will be randomized upon initiation of ramipril to either intensified (aiming below 50th percentile of 24-hour mean arterial pressure) or conventional antihypertensive treatment. Several gene polymorphisms have been described that may affect the rate of renal failure progression and/or the individual susceptibility to ACE inhibition. These polymorphisms include genes encoding for key proteins of the renin-angiotensin system and extracellular matrix turnover. In addition, we will screen for novel polymorphisms in genes determining structural proteins of the glomerular filter, and search for gene mutations causing renal hypo-/dysplasia. Objective 3 is to evaluate whether any of these mutations predict spontaneous disease progression and the therapeutic response to ACE inhibition and intensified blood pressure control. Glomerular endothelin (ET1) synthesis is upregulated in chronic renal failure, and urinary ET1 excretion is correlated with disease progression. ET1 antagonists partially preserve renal function and decrease proteinuria independent of the angiotensin tone. Objective 4 of the trial is to assess ET1 turnover before and after start of ACE inhibition, and to evaluate a possible predictive role of ET1 and/or ET1 degrading peptidase excretion for the persistence of proteinuria and disease progression during ACE inhibition and intensified antihypertensive therapy. Long-term survival of children with chronic renal failure is compromised by precocious atherosclerosis and excessive cardiovascular morbidity. Objective 5 is to assess and correlate prospectively the metabolic causes and morphological consequences of uremic cardiovascular disease in children, and to define their relationship with disease progression during ACE inhibition and intensified blood pressure control. Homocysteine metabolism, apolipoprotein variability, gene polymorphisms putatively involved in atherosclerosis, inflammation states, myocardial function and carotid intima-media thickness will be assessed and compared to a reference group of age-matched healthy children.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Disease Progression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 318 years Moderate state of renal failure (creatinine clearance 15 75 ml / min / 1.73 m²) Mean arterial blood pressure (ABPM) &gt; 50.percentile and/or antihypertensive treatment Written informed consent Age &lt;3 years or &gt;18 years at start of study Unstable clinical condition (vomiting, anorexia, etc) or superimposed important disease Unilateral or bilateral renal artery stenosis Urological surgery possibly affecting renal function expected during study period Insufficient compliance with prescribed antihypertensive medication during the runin period Secondary renal diseases such as lupus, amyloidosis and primary hyperoxaluria, and patients treated with immunosuppressive agents (including corticosteroids) Severe primary cardiac disease, hepatic insufficiency and malabsorption syndrome Erythropoietin or growth hormone therapy with a duration of less than 3 months prior to runin period Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ramipril</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic renal failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Disease progression</keyword>
	<keyword>Left ventricular hypertrophy</keyword>
	<keyword>Intima media thickness</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
	<keyword>Gene polymorphisms</keyword>
</DOC>