<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02423200</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess the effects of VX-745 on markers of disease in the central nervous system of patients with MCI due to AD or with mild AD. The study will also evaluate the safety and tolerability of VX-745 in these patients during 6 weeks of dosing, as well as the plasma and cerebrospinal fluid concentrations of VX-745 during dosing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Pharmacology of p38 MAP Kinase Inhibitor, VX-745, in Mild Cognitive Impairment Due to Alzheimer's Disease (AD) or Mild AD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 60 85 (inclusive) Willing and able to provide informed consent Clinical presentation consistent with MCI due to AD or of mild AD Gradual progressive decline in memory function over &gt;6 months Amnestic presentation on neuropsychological testing with rapid forgetting (% reduction 1.5 standard deviations below the mean) Clinical Dementia Rating (CDR) Sum of Box (SOB) score ≥0.5 MiniMental State Examination (MMSE) range: 20 to 30 Brain hypometabolism by 18F2fluoro2deoxyglucose (FDG)PET Participants may be taking medications for AD, provided that the dose of these medications has been stable for &gt;3 months. Evidence of neurodegenerative disease other than AD Inability for any reason to undergo MRI scans (e.g. pacemaker, vascular stent or stent graft). Patients who require sedation for screening procedures such as MRI may receive a shortacting sedative. Psychiatric disorder that would compromise ability to comply with study requirements History of cancer within the last 5 years, except basal cell carcinoma, nonsquamous skin carcinoma, prostate cancer or carcinoma in situ with no significant progression over the past 2 years Significant cardiovascular, pulmonary, renal, liver, infectious disease, immune disorder or metabolic/endocrine disorders or other disease that would preclude treatment with p38 MAP kinase inhibitor and/or assessment of drug safety and efficacy Recent (&lt;90 days) changes to AD medications prescribed for cognitive reasons or with the potential to impact cognition Psychotropic drugs taken within 1 month. Anticoagulant drugs taken within 1 week. Participation in a study of an investigational drug less than 6 months or 5 halflives of the investigational drug, whichever is longer, before enrollment in the study Male subjects with female partner of childbearing potential who are unwilling or unable to adhere to contraception requirements Female subjects who have not reached menopause or have not had a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy/salpingoophorectomy Positive urine or serum pregnancy test or plans desires to become pregnant during the course of the trial Donation of &gt;500 mL of blood or blood products within 2 months History of alcohol and/or illicit drug abuse within 6 months. Infection with hepatitis A, B or C or HIV. Any factor deemed by the investigator to be likely to interfere with study conduction</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>