<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02423850</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Diabetic foot ulcers and venous leg ulcers constitute an increasing health problem in Denmark concurrent with an ageing population and an increase in diabetes prevalence. Diabetic foot ulcers belong to the most serious and costly complications. Several studies have found that the size and depth of the ulcer is one of the major etiologic factors for delayed healing. Wound measurement is important in the monitoring of the wound healing process. For the last decade different 3D techniques for measuring ulcers have been proposed in order to measure ulcer volume, but none of the technologies have been widely used. A 3D photo-optical camera has been developed, which is able to measure ulcer area and volume. The investigators hypothesize that volumetric measurements of diabetic foot ulcers and venous leg ulcers are feasible in the assessment of ulcer healing. A prospective cohort study is conducted in which newly admitted patients with a diabetic foot ulcer or venous leg ulcer are included at the first visit at the polyclinic. The patients are followed for one year or until complete ulcer healing, amputation or death. Ulcer area and volume are measured by the 3D camera with frequent intervals. Patient anthropometrics and ulcer data are collected during the study and correlated to the ulcer healing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Volumetric Measurements of Diabetic Foot Ulcers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Method Newly admitted patients with a diabetic foot ulcer or venous leg ulcer are included at the first visit in the polyclinic. The data mentioned below are gathered at the first visit and the following examinations are performed including 3D photos. The ulcer area and ulcer volume are estimated from the photos by the 3D camera. The ulcer examination is repeated after 2, 4, 8, 12, 24, 36 and 52 weeks or until healing of the ulcer. Ulcer healing is estimated using changes in ulcer size per time unit. Patients are treated by standard ulcer treatment methods and are unaffected by the project per se. During the trial the different methods of treatment are noted including changes from initial treatment. The variables will be quantified after one year depending on time to heal, establishment of a chronic ulcer (non-healing after one year) or an amputation has been performed. At baseline the following patient data will be collected: - Demographic data: gender, age - Smoking habits - Time period between onset of ulcer to first visit in polyclinic - Body Mass Index - Comorbidity using Charlson Comorbidity Index score - Type of diabetes, duration of diabetes - Diabetic complications including retinopathy, albuminuria, coronary heart diseases and neuropathy The following examinations will be performed at baseline: - Blood pressure measurement - Peripheral blood pressure - Examination for neuropathy using monofilament - Blood samples from patients with a diabetic foot ulcer The clinical examination of the ulcer are performed at baseline and after 2, 4, 8, 12, 24, 36 and 52 weeks or until healing of ulcer: - Size of wound (surface area, volume) measured by the 3D camera - Location of the ulcer - Classification of ulcer: granulation, necrosis, epithelialisation - Secretory potential - Foot deformity - Bone affection - if osteitis is suspected an x-ray is taken - Signs of infection The different types of ulcer treatment is registered for every ulcer: - Type of bandage - Antibiotics (local, systemic) - Revision (method, frequency), - Surgery Effect variables - Ulcer volume and surface area - Percentage change in volume and surface area after 2, 4, 8, 12, 24, 36 and 52 weeks - Ulcer texture (e.g. granulation, black/yellow necrosis) Endpoints - Healing of ulcer - Amputations - Chronicity of ulcer (non-healing after 1 year) - Death of any cause Significance This project seeks to clarify whether 3D photos of ulcers will provide accurate structural measures to illuminate the background for delayed ulcer healing, and thereby to create platform for a more evidence based treatment algorithm.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Foot</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Foot Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Complications</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Newly admitted patients with diabetic foot ulcers or venous leg ulcers 18 years or older Superficial ulcer (less than 5x5 mm with no substantial loss of subcutaneous tissue) Noncompliance (dementia, mental disorders)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetic foot ulcers</keyword>
	<keyword>Leg ulcers</keyword>
	<keyword>Ulcer healing</keyword>
	<keyword>Ulcer measurement</keyword>
	<keyword>Ulcer area</keyword>
	<keyword>Ulcer volume</keyword>
	<keyword>3D measurement</keyword>
</DOC>