<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00726076</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to test a computer program for people with epilepsy. The program was developed to help people with epilepsy improve their self-management skills for taking medications, reducing stress, and sleeping well.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Managing Epilepsy Well- WebEase Project</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>WebEase is an internet self-management program for people with epilepsy. Our goal is to offer a program that supports the management of epilepsy by people with epilepsy. The program is based on proven techniques of motivational interviewing and stages of change. Before offering WebEase to the general public, we tested the program among volunteers with epilepsy. We recruited individuals with epilepsy who were willing to use the program. The program was developed by a team of researchers and physicians who treat patients with epilepsy. The program offers information on three major topics: 1) medication taking, 2) stress and 3) sleep management as it relates to epilepsy. It includes quizzes, fact sheets, and links to other authoritative websites on epilepsy. Before beginning the study, each participant completed a brief survey about medications, stress, and sleep. Then participants worked through the WebEase program. WebEase consists of three modules: medication, stress, and sleep. Each module lasts 2 weeks, and includes an interactive session geared specifically to each person's needs. During the study, each participant kept a diary of medications, stress, sleep, and seizures, which allowed them to see changes over time. After completing the WebEase program, participants completed two more brief surveys about six weeks apart. About half of the participants were asked to complete two surveys about 6 weeks apart before beginning the WebEase program. These individuals completed one survey after the end of the program.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Be 18 years of age or older Understand and speak English Have been diagnosed with epilepsy Have been on an antiepileptic medication (AED) for at least 3 months Have access to the internet Be willing to participate Have not participated in WebEase in the past Under age 18 Unable to understand and speak English Have NOT been diagnosed with epilepsy Have NOT been on an AED for at least 3 months Not willing to participate Have participated in WebEase in the past</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Epilepsy</keyword>
	<keyword>Medication</keyword>
	<keyword>Stress</keyword>
	<keyword>Sleep</keyword>
	<keyword>Lifestyle Management</keyword>
</DOC>