<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00726856</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This retrospective study evaluates the effectiveness and safety of ezetimibe plus statin or ezetimibe plus fenofibrate in dyslipidemic patients that were treated with these dual inhibition lipid lowering regimens as part of their normal standard of care. This study assesses the percentage of patients who achieve LDL-C target goals and also evaluates the patient compliance to treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Retrospective Survey Evaluating the Effectiveness and Safety of Dual Inhibition Lipid-lowering in the Treatment of Dyslipidemia (Study P05171)(COMPLETED)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Retrospective medical chart review</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dyslipidemias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fenofibrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ezetimibe</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient was &gt; 20 years and &lt; 75 years of age on the index date* Patient diagnosed with dyslipidemia who did not respond adequately based on NCEP ATP III target to previous lipid lowering treatment, and have received dual inhibition therapy, such as ezetimibe plus statins, ezetimibe plus fenofibrate or ezetimibe alone, for at least 3 months Patient has at least one Total Cholesterol and LDLC measurements at baseline and 3 months after initiating the dual inhibition therapy. Patient has the following records documented in the chart during the data collection period: Medical history and co morbidities (if available) Total Cholesterol and LDLC. test results before and after initiating the dual inhibition therapy Prescription information of lipidlowering dual inhibition regimens NOTE: * Index date: the date of initiating dual inhibition therapy Patients who do not meet all the inclusion criteria will be excluded from this survey. Patients who were enrolled in other clinical trial observing specific study procedures which deviates from normal practice will not be included in this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>