<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00726661</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicenter, prospective observational cohort study (OCS) designed to follow patients with locally recurrent or metastatic breast cancer in the United States. Two cohorts will be included: - Patients with human epidermal growth factor receptor 2-negative (HER2-negative) disease receiving their first cytotoxic chemotherapy and/or targeted therapy (approximately 825 patients) - Patients with hormone receptor-positive (HR-positive) disease receiving their first hormonal therapy for advanced disease (approximately 425 patients) Patients who have received any chemotherapy for advanced disease more than 8 weeks prior to enrollment to this OCS will not be eligible. A total of approximately 1,250 patients will be enrolled. Approximately 150 study sites will be activated in order to achieve complete enrollment by December 2010.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Observational Study of Treatment Patterns and Safety Outcomes for Metastatic or Locally Recurrent Breast Cancer (VIRGO)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed Informed Consent Form Locally recurrent or metastatic breast cancer Receipt of first systemic cytotoxic chemotherapy and/or targeted therapy among those with HER2negative disease or first hormone therapy among those with HRpositive disease for the treatment of locally recurrent or metastatic disease, within 8 weeks prior to enrollment Exclusion Criteria Any medical condition, including mental illness or substance abuse, deemed by the investigator to be likely to interfere with a patient's ability to provide informed consent or comply with the treatment Any prior chemotherapy started more than 8 weeks prior to enrollment for the treatment of locally recurrent or for metastatic breast cancer Concurrent participation only in a blinded clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Locally Recurrent Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Avastin</keyword>
</DOC>