<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02693613</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to evaluate the effect of Kremezin® on the pharmacokinetics of single dose of ASP1517 in healthy non-elderly adult male subjects when administered concomitantly or in a time separated manner.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetic Study of ASP1517 With Kremezin®</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Body weight (at screening): ≥50.0 kg and &lt;80.0 kg Bodymass index (BMI) (at screening): ≥17.6 and &lt;26.4 kg/m2 Subject must agree to use contraception consisting of two established forms (1 of which must be a barrier method) starting at the time of informed consent and continuing throughout the treatment period and for 84days after ASP1517 administration in the last period: Subject must agree not to donate sperm starting at the time of informed consent and continuing throughout 84 days after the last administration of ASP1517 in the last period. Received or is scheduled to receive any investigational drugs in other clinical trials or postmarketing studies within 120 days before screening or during the period from screening to the hospital admission day of the Period 1 (Day −1). Received or is scheduled to receive medications (including overthecounter [OTC] drugs) within 7 days before the hospital admission day of the Period 1 (Day −1). Received or is scheduled to receive supplements within 7 days before the hospital admission day of the Period 1 (Day −1). Deviates from any of the normal range of blood pressure, pulse rate, body temperature and standard 12lead electrocardiogram (ECG) specified at screening or the hospital admission day of the Period 1 (Day −1). Meets any of the following criteria for laboratory tests at screening or the hospital admission day of the Period 1 (Day −1). Normal ranges of each test specified at the study site or the test/assay organization will be used as the normal ranges in this study. Concurrent or previous drug allergies. Development of (an) upper gastrointestinal symptoms within seven days before the hospital admission day of the Period 1 (Day −1). Concurrent or previous hepatic disease, heart disease, respiratory disease, gastrointestinal disease, gastrointestinal obstruction,oesophageal varices, renal disease, endocrine disease, cerebrovascular disorder, malignant tumor, retinal neovascular lesions and macular edema. Concurrent chronic constipation or diarrhoea. A history of digestive tract excision. Previous use of hypoxia inducible factorprolyl hydroxylase inhibitors (HIFPHI) such as ASP1517 (FG4592), YM311 (FG2216) or erythropoietin products. Excessive alcohol or smoking habit.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>44 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug-drug interaction</keyword>
	<keyword>Kremezin</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>ASP1517</keyword>
</DOC>