<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02693041</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Investigators hypothesize that 1. intake of milk products containing probiotics are associated with a reduced risk of spontaneous preterm delivery. 2. intake of milk products containing probiotics are associated with a reduced risk of preeclampsia. 3. probiotics decrease the overall inflammatory state in the pregnant woman.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pregnancy Complications - A Probiotic Interventional Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The main of the Project is to determine if dietary supplementation intake of probiotics are associated with a decreased risk of spontaneous preterm delivery and preeclampsia in a randomized Clinical trial. Investigators also want to further investigate the relationship between intake of probiotics and the degree of inflammation in different compartments during pregnancy to see how the probiotic components affect the inflammatory state in the women.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pregnancy Complications</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Maternal age &gt; or = 18 y Singleton pregnancy Nulli or multiparous without maternal intercurrent diseases or pregnant women with a history of spontaneous preterm delivery or pregnant women with a history of preeclampsia. Exclusion Criteria Multiple pregnancy Gestational age &gt; 17+6 weeks at first visit Chronic intermittent diseases (e.g. diabetes mellitus, systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, Chron disease, ulcerative colitis) Uterus malformations Immunomodulatory medication Hormonal treatment (e.g. crinone, progesterone) Subject disagrees to stop intake of other products containing probiotics during study time. Subject is unable to provide written informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Probiotics</keyword>
	<keyword>inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>immunological response</keyword>
	<keyword>preterm birth</keyword>
	<keyword>preeclampsia</keyword>
</DOC>