<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02098122</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Functional recovery following SCI in adults is limited. Improvements in the quality of life of affected persons are associated with the recovery of functions that allow independent living, for example use of the arms and hands. Rehabilitative training has been shown to aid upper limb recovery. However, there are likely vast differences in the amount of time individuals spend actively training (during rehabilitation sessions in the clinic) and what they do in their non-training time (during daily life). The activity, or lack of, during the non-training period could interfere (positively or negatively), with the specific training in the rehabilitation session. However, there is little information available about this. Inertial measurement units are increasingly being used in human movement and rehabilitation research. The use of such technology is a promising approach to rapidly and discreetly collect objective movement information. The investigators plan to introduce a novel, long-term, activity sensor into clinical SCI rehabilitation. The investigators use this sensor to precisely measure movement of the upper limb over extended periods of time. Upper limb activity recordings from these sensors allow us to detail the amount and duration of activity during specific periods of upper limb rehabilitation and recovery. The investigators aim is to measure upper limb activity. The investigators aim to track changes in the activity of the upper limb during recovery and rehabilitation in patients with cervical SCI as well as collect reference values of upper limb activity in chronic sufferers. The recordings from this activity sensor will provide a more detailed understanding of how everyday upper limb activity contributes to functional recovery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Upper Limb Activity in Human SCI Rehabilitation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Tetraplegic and paraplegic subjects. Males and females aged 18 or older. Acute (defined here as &lt;90 days after admission of SCI) for the longitudinal followup study, as well as chronic (defined here as &gt;90 days after admission of SCI) for the crosssectional study, all levels of injury, complete and incomplete, traumatic and nontraumatic injuries. Good enough cognitive ability to be able to follow simple verbal instructions. Signed informed consent before study onset. A neurological disease other than SCI, which is expected to affect the upper limb function, i.e. plexus paresis. An orthopaedic or rheumatologic disease, e.g. osteoarthritis, which is expected to affect the upper limb function. Premorbid ongoing major depression or psychosis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>