<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02098187</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this early feasibility study was to investigate the pharmacokinetics of MP-3180 administered in rising doses and to evaluate the use of the Optical Renal Function Monitor (ORFM), an investigational noninvasive fluorescence detection device.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetics of MP-3180 and Use of Noninvasive Fluorescence Detection Device in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This was an open-label, rising single-dose study to investigate the pharmacokinetics of the investigational agent, MP-3180, and to evaluate the use of the Optical Renal Function Monitor (ORFM), an investigational noninvasive fluorescence detection device. Single-dose pharmacokinetics at four dose levels were evaluated following the administration of a single, intravenous dose of MP-3180. Iohexol was also administered followed by saline. Prior to administration of MP-3180 and iohexol, ORFM sensor probes were affixed to four locations on the body of each participant. The noninvasive fluorescent signal from MP-3180 was measured using the ORFM investigational device continuously for approximately four hours post MP-3180 administration. For the determination of the pharmacokinetic disposition of MP-3180 and iohexol, blood samples were collected from each participant provided the individual completed all blood collections in the study. The pharmacokinetics of MP-3180 and iohexol were assessed by statistical comparison of pharmacokinetic parameters derived from plasma concentration-time curves and urine recovery data.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age: 22 years of age or older 2. Sex: Males and not of childbearing potential females 3. Capable of informed consent 4. Weight restrictions: 1. at least 50 kg (110 lbs) for men 2. at least 48 kg (106 lbs) for women 3. all participants will have a Body Mass Index (BMI) less than or equal to 33 but greater than or equal to 19 5. All participants should be judged by the Principal Investigator or Medical SubInvestigator physician as normal and healthy during a prestudy medical evaluation performed within 28 days of the initial dose of study medication 1. Institutionalized participants will not be used 2. History of any significant cardiovascular disease, renal, pulmonary, hematologic, endocrine, immunologic, dermatologic, neurologic (including any history of seizure disorder), psychological, musculoskeletal disease or malignancies unless deemed not clinically significant by the Principal Investigator or Medical SubInvestigator. 3. Donation or loss of blood or plasma: 50 mL to 499 mL within 30 days prior to the initial dose of the study medication; or more than 499 mL within 56 days prior to the initial dose of study medication. 4. Intolerance to venipuncture. 5. Participants who have received an investigational drug within 30 days prior to the initial dose of study medication. 6. History of drug and/or alcohol abuse within the past year, unless currently enrolled in an abstinence program. 7. History of allergy or hypersensitivity to MP3180 or iohexol, or other related products, or any of the inactive ingredients. 8. History of skin sensitivity to adhesives (e.g. BandAids, surgical tape). 9. Any food allergy, intolerance, restriction or special diet that, in the opinion of the Principal Investigator or Medical SubInvestigator, could contraindicate the participant's participation in this study. 10. History of allergy or hypersensitivity to iodine containing contrast media or drugs. 11. Acute illness at the time of either the prestudy medical evaluation or dosing. 12. Social Habits: 1. Ingestion of any alcoholic, caffeine or xanthinecontaining food or beverage within the 48 hours prior to the initial dose of study medication. 2. Ingestion of any vitamins or herbal supplement within 7 days prior to the initial dose of study medication. 3. Any significant change in dietary or exercise habits within the 48 hours prior to the initial dose of study medication. 13. Medications: a. Use of any prescription or overthecounter (OTC) medications within the 7 days prior to the initial dose of study medication. 14. Not within normal limits or clinically significant for lab testing; serum chemistries, hematology, urinalysis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>22 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Glomerular Filtration Rate</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute Kidney Injury</keyword>
</DOC>