<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02098408</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cognitive deficits are known to be a core feature of schizophrenia and seem to become manifest in the prodromal or Ultra-High Risk (UHR) state of psychosis. The cognitive deficits are known to pose a critical barrier to functional recovery. Hence it is of vital importance to find intervention strategies that can alleviate these cognitive deficits and consequently improve daily functioning, and quality of life, as well as the prognosis for UHR-patients. The investigators will examine whether: - Cognitive remediation therapy will be superior to standard treatment in improving cognitive functioning in UHR- patients (null hypothesis: No difference between the two groups). - Cognitive remediation therapy will be superior to standard treatment in improving psychosocial functioning and clinical symptoms in UHR-patients (null hypothesis: No difference between the two groups).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Neurocognitive and Social Cognitive Remediation in Patients at Ultra-High Risk of Psychosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1840 yrs. Fulfill criteria for being at UltraHigh Risk of psychosis (defined by one or more of the following): Vulnerability (Trait and State Risk Factor) Group: Individuals with a combination of a trait risk factor (schizotypal personality disorder or a family history of psychotic disorder in a first degree relative) and a significant deterioration in functioning, or sustained low functioning during the past year. Attenuated Psychotic Symptoms (APS) Group: Individuals with subthreshold (intensity or frequency) positive psychotic symptoms. The symptoms must have been present during the past year. Brief Limited Intermittent Psychotic Symptoms Group (BLIPS): Individuals with a recent history of frank psychotic symptoms that resolved spontaneously (without antipsychotic medication) within one week. The symptoms must have been present during the past year. Provided informed consent. Past history of a treated or untreated psychotic episode of one week's duration or longer Psychiatric symptoms that are explained by a physical illness with psychotropic effect or acute intoxication (e.g., cannabis use). Diagnosis of a serious developmental disorder, e.g,. Asperger's syndrome Currently receiving treatment with metylphenidate. Rejects providing informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ultra-high risk psychosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Schizophrenia prodrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive remediation</keyword>
</DOC>