<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01851265</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a 2 part study for patients with solid tumours. The purpose of Part A is to measure the amount of olaparib or its breakdown products in the bloodstream for up to 72 hours after eating 3 different breakfasts (high calorie, regular and none). In Part B Patients can take olaparib capsules daily and study assessments will be recorded for 6 months (minimum). Treatment can continue for as long as the patient is benefitting. Throughout the study patients will be monitored for any side effects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>D081AC00001 Food Interaction With Olaparib Capsule in Patients With Solid Tumours</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Olaparib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients aged ≥18 years, male and female Able to eat a highfat breakfast within a 30minute period, as provided by the study site Histologically or, where appropriate, cytologically confirmed malignant solid tumour refractory or resistant to standard therapy and for which no suitable effective standard therapy exists ECOG performance status ≤2 Normal organ and bone marrow function measured within 28 days prior to administration of IP as defined in protocol Participation in another clinical study with an IP during the last 14 days (or a longer period depending on the defined characteristics of the agents used) Patients receiving any systemic chemotherapy or radiotherapy (except for palliative reasons) within 2 weeks prior to study treatment (or a longer period depending on the defined characteristics of the agents used). Toxicities (≥CTCAE Grade 2) caused by previous cancer therapy, excluding alopecia Patients unable to fast for up to 14 hours or who have type I or type II diabetes Patients who have gastric, gastrooesophageal or oesophageal cancer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>130 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>oncology, cancer, tumour, neoplasm, anticancer drug, food effect, area under the curve, pharmacokinetics, olaparib, solid tumour, metabolites, drug availability</keyword>
</DOC>