<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01640470</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Many individuals with mobility limitations, especially those who are older and have more severe impairments, use a combination of assistive devices and personal assistance to meet their needs. Assistive technology (AT), which includes devices such as wheelchairs, walkers, bathroom grab bars, and dressing aids, helps facilitate day-to-day activities and social participation (basic and instrumental activities of daily living) among these individuals and may decrease their dependence on human assistance. Although some research has reported beneficial outcomes of AT use, few studies have used controlled experimental designs. Furthermore, the results are often difficult to interpret because the AT interventions are only vaguely described. Another concern is that many individuals receive help from others, but scant attention has been paid to the impact of AT on caregivers. This neglect produces an incomplete portrayal of the effect of AT interventions. The proposed study addresses these deficiencies by evaluating the effects of a formalized dyadic AT intervention on individuals with mobility limitations and on their caregivers. The Assistive Technology Provision, Updating and Training (ATPUT)intervention involves a detailed in-home assessment of participants' current AT; the negotiation and implementation of a personal AT plan with the participants and their caregivers; and the provision of AT devices, non-structural home modifications, and device training. Objectives: 1. To determine the efficacy of the Assistive Technology Provision, Updating and Training intervention for assistance users and for their caregivers. 2. To explore how the intervention is experienced by these individuals and to help explain the study findings. General Hypotheses: The investigators anticipate this intervention will increase the daily activities and social participation of individuals with mobility limitations; decrease the psychological and physical demands on caregivers; and reduce the amount of caregiving required. Methodologies: This research will use a combination of quantitative and qualitative methods. The quantitative portion will be an experimental, single-blinded study in which the investigators randomly assign participants to either the ATPUT or a customary care group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Multi-Site Trial of the Impact of Assistive Technology With Assistance Users and Their Caregivers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>daily activity and/or mobility disability referred to homecare have an unpaid informal caregiver who is above the age of consent and willing to participate in the study can communicate in English or French. cognitive impairments that are likely to prevent them from reliably completing the study questionnaires.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>assistive technology</keyword>
	<keyword>environmental modification</keyword>
	<keyword>caregiver</keyword>
	<keyword>client-centred</keyword>
</DOC>