<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01954264</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to characterise P. falciparum transmission intensity in subjects aged ≥6 months and &lt;10 years by measurement of P. falciparum parasite prevalence, and to estimate the use of malaria control interventions at some centres selected for the EPI-MAL-002 and EPI-MAL-003 studies in sub-Saharan Western Africa.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Epidemiology Study of Malaria Transmission Intensity in Sub-Saharan Africa</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Two subsequent studies (EPI-MAL-002 and EPI-MAL-003) are planned to monitor vaccine safety prior to and after implementation of the RTS,S/AS01 candidate malaria vaccine. EPI-MAL-002 will take place before RTS,S is authorised and EPI-MAL-003 will start when RTS,S is registered and authorised in the country. A cross-sectional survey at peak transmission will provide by-site point estimates of Parasite prevalence (PP) and malaria control measure coverage in the areas participating in EPI-MAL-002/-003. EPI-MAL-006 will be conducted in advance of EPI-MAL-002/-003 in order to assess PP and malaria control measures to inform enrollment in these studies. The age group for enrollment (≥6 months - &lt;10 years) will permit analysis of PP according to the World Health Organization (WHO) definition (2-9 years) and by the Joint Technical Expert Group (JTEG) suggested age (&lt;5 years).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects' parent(s)/Legally Acceptable Representative(s) [LAR(s)] who, in the opinion of the investigator, can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol. A male or female equal or more than 6 months of age and less than 10 years of age at the time of survey. Signed informed consent or thumbprinted and witnessed informed consent obtained from the parent(s)/LAR(s) of the child. Child in care. Current active participation in any trial involving administration of an investigational malaria vaccine or malaria drug.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>9 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Saharan Western Africa</keyword>
	<keyword>Epidemiology</keyword>
	<keyword>Post-Approval Programme study</keyword>
	<keyword>Malaria</keyword>
	<keyword>Burden of Disease Study</keyword>
</DOC>