<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01954238</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability and Pharmacokinetics/Pharmacodynamics of multiple doses of GCC-4401C in healthy male subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Access Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics(PK) and Pharmacodynamics(PD) of Orally Administered GCC-4401C in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective is to investigate the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics of multiple doses of GCC-4401C in healthy male subjects. Forty-six subjects are planned for enrollment. The study consists of five cohorts (10 mg, 20 mg, 40 mg, 60 mg, and 80 mg) with eight subjects per cohort. In the 20 mg cohort, six additional subjects will receive rivaroxaban (Xarelto®) 20 mg as an active comparator in open-label fashion. Within each of the five cohorts, six subjects will be randomized to GCC-4401C and two subjects will be randomized to placebo. The secondary objectives of this study are - To characterize the single dose safety, tolerability, and PK after oral administration of GCC-4401C in healthy male subjects. - To characterize the multiple dose pharmacodynamics after oral administration of GCC-4401C in healthy male subjects. - To determine an appropriate dose range and dosing regimen of oral GCC-4401C for subsequent clinical trials. - To compare the PK and PD of GCC-4401C with an active rivaroxaban (Xarelto®)group at 20 mg in healthy male subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Factor Xa Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subject voluntarily has agreed to participate in this study and signed an Institutional Review Board (IRB)approved informed consent before any of the Screening procedures will be performed. 2. Males between 18 to 45 years of age, inclusive, at Screening. 3. Nonsmokers (or other nicotine use) as determined by history (no nicotine use over the past month prior to screening) and by urine cotinine concentration (&lt; 400 ng/mL) at Screening. 4. Body mass index (BMI) between 18.5 and 28.0 kg/m2 at Screening. 5. Healthy, determined by prestudy medical evaluation and Investigator/designee discretion (medical history, physical examination, vital signs, ECG, and clinical laboratory evaluations). 1. Clinically significant history or evidence of cardiovascular, respiratory, hepatic, renal, gastrointestinal, endocrine, neurological, immunological, or psychiatric disorder(s) as determined by the Investigator/designee. 2. Any disorder that would interfere with the absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of drugs. 3. Have any of the following, which may put them at increased risk with anticoagulant use: family history or personal history of bleeding disorders or diseases/syndromes that can either alter or increase the propensity for bleeding; any other contraindication to anticoagulant treatment, or increased bleeding risk, as judged by the Investigator. 4. Are considering or scheduled to undergo any surgical procedure during the study. 5. Any concurrent disease or condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator/designee, would make the subject unsuitable for participation in the clinical study. 6. Fecal occult blood positive test at screening and admission. 7. Subject has history of alcohol and/or illicit drug abuse within one year of the Screening visit. 8. Positive Screening test for Hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), Hepatitis C antibody, or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antibody. 9. Positive alcohol breathalyzer test at Screening or Day 1. 10. Positive urine drug test (cocaine, amphetamines, barbiturates, opiates, benzodiazepines, cannabinoids, etc.) at Screening or Day 1. 11. Subject unwilling to avoid consumption of coffee and caffeine containing beverages within 48 hours prior to Day 1 until discharge from the clinical site. 12. Subject unwilling to avoid use of alcohol or alcoholcontaining foods, medications or beverages, within 48 hours prior to Day 1 until discharge from the clinical site. 13. Donation of blood (&gt; 500 mL) or blood products within 2 months (56 days) prior to Day 1. 14. Use of overthecounter (OTC) medications, prescription medications, or herbal remedies from 14 days or 5 time their halflives whatever is more, prior to Day 1 and vitamin from 7 days prior to Day 1, until EndofStudy. By exception, acetaminophen 1000 mg per day is permitted. 15. Use of any drugs that induce or inhibit cytochrome P450 or Pglycoprotein within 30 days prior to dosing. 16. Any intake of grapefruit, grapefruit juice, Seville oranges, Seville orange marmalade, or other products containing grapefruit or Seville oranges within 7 days of dosing. 17. Use of an investigational drug within 30 days prior to Day 1. 18. Unwilling to abstain from vigorous exercise from 48 hours prior to Day 1 until EndofStudy. 19. Subject has a history of hypersensitivity to the investigational medicinal products (IMPs) or any of the excipients or to medicinal products with similar chemical structures. 20. Planning to father a child or donate sperm during the study and within 3 months following dosing. 21. Subject does not have veins suitable for cannulation or multiple venipunctures. 22. Subject is unable to understand the protocol requirements, instructions and study related restrictions, the nature, scope and possible consequences of the clinical study. 23. Subject is unlikely to comply with the protocol requirements, instructions and study related restrictions; e.g., uncooperative attitude, inability to return for Followup visits and improbability of completing the clinical study. 24. Subject has previously been enrolled in this clinical study. 25. Subjects involved in the planning or conduct of this clinical study. 26. Vulnerable subject (e.g. kept in detention)</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anti-coagulant</keyword>
	<keyword>Coagulation factor Xa inhibitor</keyword>
</DOC>