<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01502150</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this research study is to collect information on the side effects of proton therapy and the details of proton treatment plans so that researchers can develop a method to predict the risk of side effects and to improve the planning and delivery of proton treatment for patients in the future.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Data Collection of Normal Tissue Toxicity for Proton Therapy for Pediatrics</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>If you agree to take part in this study, researchers will gather information about your treatment and treatment outcomes and store it electronically in a database. By carefully evaluating the data about your treatment, researchers may improve proton treatment for patients in the future. There will be no change to your recommended standard of care and follow-up studies. The treatment information and follow-up information will be stored in a database. The information will then be available at a later date for researchers to study. The database will be stored on a secure information network, and only those people who are involved with this research and who have prior approval from the study doctor will have access to it. Researchers will request information from the follow-up visits that you have as part of your standard of care yearly or more often and test results for at least 10-15 years. The tests may be performed at other clinics, but MD Anderson researchers will request that the results be sent to them at MD Anderson. This is an investigational study. Proton radiotherapy is FDA approved. Researchers hope to enroll all children who will be treated with proton radiotherapy at MD Anderson on this study so that as much information as possible will be gathered. Up to 1000 patients will be enrolled at MD Anderson.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 1. All patients under the age of 18 who are treated with PBT will be eligible to participate in this trial. 2. Signed informed consent must be obtained from the patient or patient's representative prior to study enrollment. 1. Pregnant females are not eligible. 2. Patient or patient's parent or legal guardian representative is unable or unwilling to give informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pediatric Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Proton Radiation Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Proton beam radiotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>PBT</keyword>
	<keyword>Data Collection</keyword>
	<keyword>Database</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute and late normal tissue toxicities</keyword>
	<keyword>Dosimetric data</keyword>
	<keyword>Toxicity data</keyword>
</DOC>