<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02488499</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study investigates the effectiveness of a clinic-adapted version of the Coping Power program compared to individualized child and family treatment for children with disruptive behaviour and their parents.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Addressing Behaviour and Treatment Effectiveness Project (A.B.A.T.E. Project)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This project compares the short- and long-term effectiveness of a clinic-adapted manualized group treatment (i.e., Coping Power; CP) to individualized child and family treatment for children aged 9 - 12 with disruptive behaviour. Children and their parents who meet criteria and agree to participate in the project are randomly assigned to either the CP condition or the Individualized treatment condition. In the CP condition, children and caregivers are asked to participate in two separate but complimentary 15-session groups. Child groups target development of children's emotional and cognitive problem solving skills and caregiver groups facilitate cognitive and behavioural parenting skills. In the Individualized treatment condition children and caregivers are asked to participate in 15 one-hour individual and family treatment sessions tailored by the clinician to address the children and parent's presenting concerns. Measurement of behaviour and emotional functioning is done pre- post- and at 6-months following treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Problem Behavior</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit and Disruptive Behavior Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Parents provide free and informed consent and children assent to participate in the research, complete measures, and participate in either Coping Power or individualized treatment. Parents report symptoms consistent with clinical diagnoses of Oppositional Defiant Disorder or Conduct Disorder on the Diagnostic Interview Schedule for Children DSM IV or parents and/or teacher report at or above a Tscore of 60 (93rd percentile; borderline clinically severe range) on the Externalizing Behavior composite scale on the Behavior Assessment for Children 2nd edition. Parents or teachers report clinically severe impairment in social, family, peer or overall functioning demonstrated by scores in the clinical range on the parent or teacher completed Impairment Rating Scale. The child's cognitive functioning is at or above a standard score of 80 (Borderline Range) on the verbal and/or nonverbal scales on the Kaufman Brief Intelligence Task 2. Evidence of Autism Spectrum Disorder or Asperger's Disorder as reported by parent, teacher or physician referral (if available).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>9 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Disruptive Behaviour Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychosocial</keyword>
	<keyword>Group Treatment</keyword>
</DOC>