<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00483431</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Earlier studies have shown that high vitamin K-intake leads to improved bone and vascular health by increased carboxylation of Gla-proteins in these tissues. From all K-vitamins, menaquinone-7 (MK-7) has been identified as the most effective cofactor for the carboxylation reaction of Gla-proteins such as osteocalcin and matrix-gla protein. The question remains which dosage of MK-7 leads to optimal carboxylation levels of these proteins. The primary objective of this double-blind randomized intervention study is to establish the optimal dose of MK-7 for carboxylation of the vitamin K-dependent proteins osteocalcin in bone and matrix-gla protein in the vessel wall. The optimal dose will be the concentration at which osteocalcin and matrix-gla protein are &gt; 90% in the active (=carboxylated) form.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose-Finding Study for Vitamin K2 in Human Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin K</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin K 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin MK 7</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy male and female adults between 18 and 45 years of age. Subjects of normal body weight and height according to BMI &lt; 30 Subject has given written consent to take part in the study Subjects with (a history of) metabolic or gastrointestinal disease Subject with (a history of) soy allergy Subjects using vitamin supplements containing vitamin K Subjects presenting chronic inflammatory diseases Subjects receiving systemic treatment or topical treatment likely to interfere with evaluation of the study parameters Subjects receiving corticoϊd treatment Subjects using oral anticoagulants</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>vitamin K2</keyword>
	<keyword>dosis-response</keyword>
	<keyword>osteocalcin</keyword>
	<keyword>matrix-gla protein</keyword>
</DOC>