<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01415362</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this pilot study, the researchers investigated the feasibility of a closed-loop electroencephalography (EEG) / transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) system for treatment of epilepsy. They looked to see the feasibility of triggering tDCS stimulation within 10 seconds of a detected EEG partial-onset seizure, and also a proof-of-principle determination of whether tDCS applied during this vulnerable period may be feasible to prevent the oncoming seizure. This study required 5 visits over the course of approximately 8 weeks. Each visit was separated by at least 2 weeks. Two of the visits had 24-hour EEG monitoring sessions. During these two sessions, the EEG and tDCS were hooked into a closed loop system, such that when seizure activity wasdetected, the tDCS was triggered to deliver stimulation. Subjects received active stimulation or sham stimulation sessions during the first 24-hour visit, and the opposite during the second. The subjects were randomized and counterbalanced. We have also added a healthy subjects cohort to assess the feasibility of the closed loop system. In order to test the proof-of-concept of this system, the experiment will focus on detecting and acting upon alpha- and beta-band changes traced in the EEG activity that is being recorded, and provide tDCS stimulation based upon those changes. We will enroll 6 subjects who will have 2 visits each. During these two visits subjects will be randomized to active or sham stimulation sessions and receive the opposite during their second visit.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Closed-loop System Using Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation (tDCS) for Epilepsy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Seizures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria (Epileptics) Disabling motor simple partial seizures, complex partial seizures, and/or secondarily generalized seizures. Disabling refers to seizures that are severe enough to significantly impair functional abilities in areas such as employment, psychological or social wellbeing, education or mobility. Failed treatment with a minimum of two antiepileptic medications. Experienced an average of three or more disabling simple weekly partial seizures, complex partial seizures and/or secondarily generalized seizures. Between the ages of 18 and 70 years. No more than two epileptogenic regions in the brain. Must be able to provide informed consent themselves. Exclusion Criteria Has a progressive neurological or systemic disease. Has a history of nonepileptic seizures. Has an implanted metallic device, aneurysm clips, cochlear implants, or spinal cord stimulator. Has suffered a severe traumatic brain injury with skull fracture. Contraindications to tDCS metal in the head implanted brain medical devices Pregnancy Any implanted electrical medical device, including pacers and implanted cardiac defibrillators Inclusion criteria (Healthy Subjects) Healthy subjects age 18 and older Exclusion criteria: Existence of major neurologic or psychiatric condition (i.e. epilepsy, severe depression) History of head injury resulting in more than a momentary loss of consciousness Previous neurosurgery A history of significant alcohol or drug abuse in the prior 6 months Presence of unstable medical conditions, such as; uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, cardiac pathology, cancer, kidney insufficiency, acute thrombosis Contraindication to tDCS metal in the head implanted electronic medical devices Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>transcranial direct current stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>electroencephalography</keyword>
</DOC>