<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01415947</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The V-Chordal System is a new technology for mitral repair. The Valtech V-Chordal system, consists in the ability to adjust (elongate or shorten) the neochordae "off-pump" to achieve an optimal coaptation. The adjustment mechanism allows overcoming the main problem of chordal replacement by enabling accurate sizing of the chords.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>V-Chordal Adjustable System for Chordal Replacement in Mitral Valve Insufficiency Due to Leaflet Prolapse</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Prolapse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitral Valve Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitral Valve Prolapse</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt; 18 years Degenerative mitral insufficiency with mitral leaflet prolapsed , who are candidates for mitral valve repair according to ESC or ACC/AHA guidelines. Patient able and willing to return to the implant center for followup visits Able and willing to give informed consent and follow protocol procedures. Inadequate echocardiographic window for transthoracic imaging Severe organic lesions with retraction of chordate tendineae, severly fibrotic and immobile leaflets, severely deformed subvalvular apparatus. Evolving endocarditis or active endocarditis in the last 3 months. Heavily calcified annulus or leaflets. Congenital malformation with limited valvular tissue Patient requires mitral valve replacement. Previously implanted annuloplasty ring/band. Patient requires aortic or pulmonic valve replacement or repair. Patient is pregnant (urine HCG test result positive) or lactating. Patient has a major cardiac or noncardiac disease, which in the investigator's experience produces an unacceptable surgical risk. Life expectancy of less than twelve months. Patient is participating in concomitant research studies of investigational products.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Heart disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Device</keyword>
	<keyword>Mitral valve</keyword>
	<keyword>leaflet prolapse</keyword>
	<keyword>Heart valve disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Neochordae</keyword>
</DOC>