<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00409292</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to investigate if RAD001 is an effective treatment for pancreatic cancer that has spread and not responded to treatment. Experiments have shown that RAD001 can prevent cells from multiplying. RAD002 has also been tested in laboratory experiments imitating cancer conditions and the results have been promising.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>RAD001 in Previously Treated Patients With Metastatic Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>- Participants taking part in this research study will be given a study medication-dosing calendar for each treatment cycle. Each cycle lasts four weeks during which you will be taking the study drug, RAD001, orally every day. - Participants will come into the clinic every other week during the time of enrollment. At each clinic visit blood work will be taken to monitor the participants health and a physical exam will be performed. CT scans will be repeated every 2 months to assess the tumor. - Participants will remain on the study as long as they continue to benefit from the study medication.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pathologic confirmation of pancreatic adenocarcinoma 18 years of age or older At least one measurable site of disease according to RECIST criteria that has not been previously irradiated. If patient has had previous radiation to the marker lesion(s), there must be evidence of progression since the radiation. Treated with gemcitabinebased chemotherapy with documented tumor progression on gemcitabine or intolerance to gemcitabine. Prior treatment with no more than 1 prior chemotherapy regimen for metastatic disease. Minimum of two weeks since any major surgery, completion of radiation, or completion of all prior systemic anticancer therapy. ECOG performance status 01. Life expectancy of greater than 12 weeks. Adequate bone marrow and liver function. Must be able to swallow tablets. Prior treatment with an investigational drug within the preceding 4 weeks. Prior treatment with an inhibitor of mTOR Chronic treatment with systemic steroids or another immunosuppressive agent More than one prior chemotherapy treatment for metastatic disease Uncontrolled brain or leptomeningeal metastases, including patient who continue to require glucocorticoids for brain or leptomeningeal metastases. Other malignancies within the past 3 years except for adequately treated carcinoma of the cervix or basal or squamous cell carcinomas of the skin Patients with chronic renal insufficiency Other concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled medical disease which could compromise participation in the study. Known history of HIV seropositivity Impairment of gastrointestinal function or gastrointestinal disease that my significantly alter the absorption of RAD001. Active, bleeding diathesis or an oral vitamin K antagonist medication Women who are pregnant or breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>RAD001</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic pancreatic cancer</keyword>
</DOC>