<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02240303</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this project will be to document the central and peripheral mechanisms, which may predict clinical pain characteristics and associated physical performance in older adults. Although chronic pain is common among older adults, there is limited understanding on the processing of pain and the mechanisms by which it affects physical function in these individuals. The first aim of this study will be to examine predictors of clinical pain in older adults. These will include a comprehensive somatosensory assessment battery including mechanical and thermal detection and pain thresholds in older adults with and without chronic pain. The investigators will also assess basal cognitive and physical function to determine their associations with chronic pain. Finally, brain structure and function will be assessed in these older adults with and without pain.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pain, Brain and Mobility Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this research study is to learn more about how pain in older individuals changes the brain and impacts a person's mobility and function. Pain is influenced by biology (like hormones), psychology (thoughts and feelings), and habits (like sleep or exercise) that may make older adults more likely to have higher or lower levels of pain.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Age 65 years and older Willingness to participate in all study procedures Cognitively intact as defined by 3MS score &gt; 80 Failure to provide informed consent; Contraindications to MRI, such as claustrophobia, heart pacemaker / defibrillator, heart valve prosthesis, aneurysm clip, metallic stent, neurostimulation system, cochlear implants or inner ear prosthesis, insulin pump or other infusion pump, metal slivers in the orbital area/eye socket Active treatment for cancer or history of cancer in the past year Severe cardiac disease, including New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class III or IV congestive heart failure, clinically significant aortic stenosis, history of cardiac arrest or stroke, use of a cardiac defibrillator, or uncontrolled angina; Previous stroke with upper and/or lower extremities involvement within the last 6 months History of lifethreatening cardiac arrhythmias, stroke, severe Parkinson's disease or severe neurological disorders likely to interfere with physical function Renal disease requiring dialysis Lung disease requiring steroids Inability to reliably rate pain intensity Current use of tobacco products Uncontrolled hypertension (BP of greater than 150/99 mm Hg) Serious systemic disease that restrict normal daily activities Neurological problems with significant changes in somatosensory and pain perception at the intended stimulation sites, Uncontrolled psychiatric condition (e.g., experiencing symptoms of schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, etc.) or hospitalization within the preceding year for psychiatric illness Daily use of narcotic medication Lower extremity amputation Uncontrolled diabetes (selfreported medication use and/or HA1C value) A known diagnosis of dementia Inability to communicate because of severe hearing loss or speech disorder; Severe visual impairment, which would preclude completion of the assessments and/or intervention.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>mobility</keyword>
	<keyword>brain</keyword>
	<keyword>cognition</keyword>
</DOC>