<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00566735</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to see if galantamine HBr (Razadyne) is safe and can help treat problems with thinking and memory caused by electroconvulsive therapy (ECT).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Use of Galantamine HBr (Reminyl) in Electroconvulsive Therapy: Impact on Mood and Cognitive Functioning</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Galantamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Criteria to enter the study include males and females between the ages of 1890 (females must be post menopausal) and a DSMIV diagnosis of Major Depressive Disorder, Major Depressive Disorder with psychotic features, Bipolar Disorder, depressed type, or Schizoaffective Disorder, depressed type (19). DSMIV diagnoses of dementia and its subtypes Substance use disorder (active use within the last 6 months) Organic mental disorders; seizure disorder Unstable physical disorder or physical disorder judged to significantly affect the central nervous system function A heart rate of &lt;60 A systolic blood pressure &lt; 90 Heart block Preexisting sicksinus Chronic treatment with beta blockers Any cardiac arrythmia Hypotension Coronary artery disease Liver and renal function impairment Urge incontinence, colitis Crohn's disease, GI motility disorders, asthma and COPD Treatment with anticholinergic and cholinomimetic medications; and Female patients who are pregnant. Additionally, women subjects must be postmenopausal, surgically sterile, or using prescription oral contraceptives (e.g. estrogenprogestin combinations) , contraceptive implants (e.g. NorplantTM, DepoProveraTM ), or transdermally delivered contraceptives (Ortho EvraTM) before entry and throughout the study; and have a negative serum bHCG pregnancy test at screening. Note: Abstinence and the use of double barrier contraceptive methods are not acceptable in this study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>