<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="123690">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01492309</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>812494</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>K23MH092399</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01492309</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Beat the Blues in Pregnancy Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>TMS</acronym>
  <official_title>Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation in Pregnant Women With Depressive Disorder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>No</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_ppsd>No</is_ppsd>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine if repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation
      (TMS) will alleviate symptoms of major depressive disorder (MDD) in pregnant women.

      TMS uses electromagnetic impulses to encourage neurons in the brain to communicate more
      effectively with one another. Effective neuron communication is thought to lead to the
      lessening of depressive symptoms. In this study subjects require daily TMS treatment for
      approximately four weeks.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      We hypothesize that there will be a decline in the Hamilton Rating Scale for Depression
      (HDRS-17) scores from the beginning to end of treatment. We expect that this decrease will
      be significantly greater in subjects receiving active transcranial magnetic stimulation
      (TMS) compared to those receiving placebo TMS. Treatment response will be defined as greater
      than 50% reduction in HDRS-17 score.

      We also hypothesize that levels of Brain Derived Neurotrophic Factor (BDNF), a protein
      thought to regulate mood and cognitive functioning, will increase in subjects who respond to
      TMS treatment. We expect BDNF levels to increase by greater than or equal to 20% in those
      who respond to TMS. As previously stated, TMS response will be defined as a significant
      decrease (50% or greater) in the HDRS-17 from baseline to end of treatment.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Participant, Outcomes Assessor</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hamilton Rating Scale for Depression (HDRS-17)</measure>
    <time_frame>Test Day 1, 10 &amp; 20</time_frame>
    <description>We will be measuring changes in Hamilton Rating Scale for Depression (HDRS-17) scores from the beginning to end of treatment. The HDRS-17 will be administered on test day 1, 10, &amp; 20.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brain Derived Neurotrophic Factor Increase with Active Transcranial Magnetic Simulation (TMS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Test Day 1 &amp; 20</time_frame>
    <description>We will also be measuring levels of Brain Derived Neurotrophic Factor (BDNF), a protein thought to regulate mood and cognitive functioning. We will be obtaining BDNF values on test day 1 &amp; 20. In addition, the relationship between BDNF and various hormones (estradiol, progesterone, allopregnanolone, oxytocin, and cortisol releasing hormone) will be examined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">57</enrollment>
  <condition>Major Depressive Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>38 pregnant women with MDD will be randomized to receive active 1 Hz right-sided dorsolateral prefrontal cortex (DLPFC) TMS.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sham Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>38 pregnant women with MDD will be randomized to receive sham transcranial magnetic stimulation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Active Transcranial Magnetic Simulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will be given active TMS 5 days per week for 4 weeks for a total of 20 sessions. Each session will last approximately 10 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Neuronetics 2100 CRS TMS System</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sham Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will be given sham TMS 5 days per week for 4 weeks for a total of 20 sessions. The sham coil contains a shielding mechanism which diverts the magnetic field away from the patient. The sham treatment will last approximately 10 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sham Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>The eSham System</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Subjects are capable of giving written informed consent and complying with all study
             procedures;

          -  Female age 18-39 years old at date of enrollment;

          -  Pregnant, weeks 14-34;

          -  Current Depressive Symptoms;

          -  No change in antidepressant medication at least two weeks prior to study entry if
             using an antidepressant.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Any alcohol or drug abuse/dependence over the 6 months prior to study entry;

          -  History of a seizure disorder in subject or first degree relative;

          -  Anti-psychotic, lithium, or anti-convulsant medications within 2 weeks of study
             enrollment;

          -  History of known brain lesions, or severe head trauma;

          -  Subjects with any metallic object implanted in the skull;

          -  Subjects with significant cardiac disease;

          -  Neurological or psychiatric disorders;

          -  Serious medical illnesses that may compromise patient safety or study conduct;

          -  Currently taking a drug with known potential for fetal toxicity;

          -  Previous pregnancy with an adverse fetal outcome;

          -  Current obstetrical complications

          -  Actively suicidal;

          -  History of depression unresponsive to treatment with electroconvulsive therapy (ECT).
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>39 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Deborah R Kim, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Penn Center for Women's Behavioral Wellness</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Penn Center for Women's Behavioral Wellness</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.med.upenn.edu/womenswellness/</url>
    <description>Program Website</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kim DR, Epperson N, Paré E, Gonzalez JM, Parry S, Thase ME, Cristancho P, Sammel MD, O'Reardon JP. An open label pilot study of transcranial magnetic stimulation for pregnant women with major depressive disorder. J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2011 Feb;20(2):255-61. doi: 10.1089/jwh.2010.2353.</citation>
    <PMID>21314450</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kim DR, Gonzalez J, O'Reardon JP. Pregnancy and depression: exploring a new potential treatment option. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2009 Dec;11(6):443-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19909665</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kim D, O'Reardon JP. Editorial: the treatment of depression during pregnancy. Isr J Psychiatry Relat Sci. 2011;48(1):3-5.</citation>
    <PMID>21572235</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kim DR, O'Reardon JP, Epperson CN. Guidelines for the management of depression during pregnancy. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2010 Aug;12(4):279-81. doi: 10.1007/s11920-010-0114-x.</citation>
    <PMID>20424977</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tjoa C, Pare E, Kim DR. Unipolar depression during pregnancy: nonpharmacologic treatment options. Womens Health (Lond). 2010 Jul;6(4):565-76. doi: 10.2217/whe.10.27. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20597620</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 9, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 3, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Major Depressive Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
  <keyword>Brain Derived Neurotrophic Factor</keyword>
  <keyword>Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
