<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00895947</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to see if lozenges containing a low dose of interferon-alpha can prevent and/or reduce the severity of colds and flu. Starting about 1 month before the expected start of the winter colds and flu season in Perth, Australia, healthy volunteers will allow a lozenge containing interferon, or a lozenge containing no medicine (a placebo), to dissolve in their mouth once a day for 16 weeks. Blood tests at the start and end of treatment will determine whether interferon was able to prevent infections with cold/flu viruses. Once a week, volunteers will complete a survey about their cold/flu symptoms, medications taken, days of work missed, etc. to see if interferon was able to make their winter colds and flu less severe.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Interferon Alpha Lozenges in the Prevention of Winter Colds and Flu</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or nonpregnant female Females of childbearing potential must practice a medically accepted form of birth control Currently exhibiting an acute upper respiratory tract infection history of chronic respiratory disease requiring regular therapy(i.e. COPD, asthma, bronchitis, etc.) any condition likely to increase the risk of severe or complicated influenza (i.e. cardiac disease, chronic renal disease, endocrine diseases, including diabetes and/or immunosuppressive therapy) any condition requiring regular treatment with antihistamines, analgesics or antipyretics known infection with HIV, hepatitis B virus or hepatitis C virus any other serious, uncontrolled disease any active infections requiring use of antibiotic or antiviral drugs nonambulatory status suspected drug or alcohol abuse</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prophylaxis</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Symptoms</keyword>
	<keyword>Winter Colds and Flu</keyword>
</DOC>