<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="35743">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02641249</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB#14-000804</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02641249</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Non-invasive Intervention for Apnea of Prematurity</brief_title>
  <official_title>Neuromodulation of Limb Proprioceptive Afferents Using a Vibratory Device to Decrease Apnea, Intermittent Hypoxia and Bradycardia of Prematurity.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, Los Angeles</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Los Angeles</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Purpose of Study: Apnea of Prematurity (AOP) is common, affecting the majority of infants
      born &lt;34 weeks gestational age (GA). Apnea is accompanied by intermittent hypoxia (IH),
      which contributes to multiple pathologies, including retinopathy of prematurity (ROP),
      sympathetic ganglia injury, impaired pancreatic islet cell and bone development, and
      neurodevelopmental disabilities. Standard of care for AOP/IH includes prone positioning,
      positive pressure ventilation, and caffeine therapy, none of which is optimal. The objective
      is to support breathing in premature infants by using a simple, non-invasive vibratory
      device placed over limb proprioceptor fibers, an intervention using the principle that limb
      movements facilitate breathing.

      Methods Used: Premature infants (23-34 wks GA) with clinical evidence of AOP/IH were
      enrolled 1 week after birth. Caffeine therapy was not a reason for exclusion. Small
      vibration devices were placed on one hand and one foot and activated in a 6 hour ON/OFF
      sequence for a total of 24 hours. Heart rate, respiratory rate, oxygen saturation (SpO2),
      and breathing pauses were continuously collected.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aim: To study the effect of limb proprioceptive stimulation using a vibratory device on
      apneic events, intermittent hypoxic episodes and bradycardias in a premature infant with
      apnea of prematurity.

      The objective is to provide support and to assist impaired ventilation and oxygenation in
      apnea of prematurity (AOP). Recurrent apnea and accompanying resultant intermittent hypoxic
      (IH) episodes are significant concerns commonly encountered in premature infants, and
      optimal management is a challenge to neonatologists. AOP is defined as &quot;a pause of breathing
      for more than 15-20 seconds or accompanied by oxygen desaturation (SpO2&lt;80% for&gt;4s) and
      bradycardia (heart rate&lt;2/3 of baseline for&gt;4s), in infants born less than 37 weeks of
      gestation [Moriette G et al., 2010]. When these pauses are longer (&gt; 15s), they are
      frequently prolonged by obstructed inspiratory efforts, most likely secondary to loss of
      upper airway tonic activity [Martin RJ et al., 2012]. In extremely low birth weight (ELBW)
      infants, the incidence of IH progressively increases over the first 4 weeks of postnatal
      life, followed by a plateau and subsequent decline between 6-8 weeks.

      The incidence of AOP correlates inversely with gestational age and birth weight. Nearly all
      infants born &lt;29 weeks gestation or &lt;1,000 g [Robertson CM et al., 2009], 54% at 30 to 31
      weeks, 15% at 32 to 33 weeks, and 7% at 34 to 35 weeks gestation exhibit AOP [Martin RJ et
      al]. Both animal and human evidence show that immature or impaired respiratory control and
      the resultant IH exposure contribute to a variety of pathophysiologic issues via
      pro-inflammatory and/or pro-oxidant cascade as well as cellular mechanisms, e.g., apoptosis,
      leading to acute and chronic morbidities (e.g. retinopathy of prematurity, altered growth
      and cardiovascular regulation, disrupting zinc homeostasis which hampers insulin production
      and there by predisposing to diabetes in later life, cerebellar injuries and
      neurodevelopmental disabilities) [Martin RJ et al., 2004, Pae EK et al., 2011, 2014, ].

      Current standard of care for AOP includes prone positioning, continuous positive airway
      pressure (CPAP) or nasal intermittent positive pressure ventilation (NIPPV) to prevent
      pharyngeal collapse and alveolar atelectasis, and methylxanthine therapy (caffeine,
      theophylline), which is the mainstay of treatment of central apnea [Reher et al., 2008;
      Pantalitschka T et al., 2009; Moretti C et al., 2012; Henderson-Smart DJ et al., 2010].
      Apart from prone positioning, none of these interventions are optimal for early development.
      CPAP masks will distort the bony facial structure in early development, and methylxanthine
      interventions pose serious questions of neural development interactions.

      Hypothesis: Applying slight vibration to the limbs will reduce the number of breathing
      pauses, intermittent hypoxic episodes and bradycardias in apnea of prematurity.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total number of episodes of apnea/breathing pauses during intervention and without intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>12 hours of intervention/12 hours of no intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The total number of apneas/breathing pauses will be compared during periods of vibration (intervention) to periods of no vibrations (no intervention).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the total number of intermittent hypoxic episodes to &lt;90% lasting &gt;5 seconds/episode during the intervention and without intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>12 hours of intervention/12 hours of no intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The total number of intermittent hypoxic episodes to &lt;90% (pulse oximetry) lasting &gt;5 seconds/episode will be compared during periods of vibration (intervention) to periods of no vibrations (no intervention).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the total number of bradycardia episodes (&lt;100 beats per minute (bpm), at least 5 seconds long) during intervention and without the intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>12 hours of intervention/12 hours of no intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The total number of bradycardia episodes to &lt;100 bpm lasting &gt;5 seconds/episode will be compared during periods of vibration (intervention) to periods of no vibrations (no intervention).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">19</enrollment>
  <condition>Apnea of Prematurity</condition>
  <condition>Hypoxia</condition>
  <condition>Bradycardia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the same subject cardiorespiratory parameters - heart rate, respiratory rate and oxygen saturation were compared during the procedure (vibration) and without procedure (no vibration). The same subject had both control and treatment periods.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vibration</intervention_name>
    <description>A device providing vibrations is placed on the subject and vibration is turned on and off in a 6 hour on/off sequence. Heart rate, respiratory pauses and oxygen saturation are compared during vibration (intervention) and without vibration (no intervention) in the same subject.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>(no generic name)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Gestational age &gt; 23 weeks, &lt; 34 weeks

          2. At least 1 week old at recruitment

          3. Diagnosis of apnea of prematurity (AOP)

          4. Caffeine treatment will not be an exclusion

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Infants with major congenital anomalies/malformations which will influence central
             nervous system and long-term outcomes in these infants, such as cardiac anomalies
             (except for Patent Ductus Arteriosus or Ventricular Septal Defect) or major
             neurological malformations, like meningoencephalocele, holoprosencephaly etc.

          2. Neonates who have apnea from airway issues like laryngomalacia or tracheomalacia

          3. Neonates with history of hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy or Grade IV intraventricular
             hemorrhage
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kalpashri Kesavan, MBBS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, Los Angeles</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ronald Reagan Medical Center - UCLA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90095</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Santa Monica UCLA Mecial Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santa Monica</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90404</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 17, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 18, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, Los Angeles</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kalpashri Kesavan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Instructor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anoxia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bradycardia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
