<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02643056</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Phase II, multicenter, open labelled, uncontrolled study to evaluate the efficacy and safety profile of panitumumab in patients affected by Head and Neck cancer after at least one cisplatin or carboplatin-based chemotherapy. A translational research study is also planned to evaluate EGFR status by FISH, KRAS, B-RAF, HRAS, NRAS and PIK3CA mutation by DNA sequencing, PTEN protein expression by immunohistochemistry, and HPV genotyping by reverse hybridization. Panitumumab is administered iv on days 1 and 15 of a 28 days cycle, until progressive disease, unacceptable toxicity, pregnancy, or patient's refusal</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Investigate the Efficacy of Panitumumab in Platinum-resistant Advanced Head and Neck Squamous Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ECOG performance status 02, not pregnant. Histologically or cytologically confirmed Squamous Cell Cancer of the Head and Neck either metastatic or recurrent, judged incurable by surgery or radiation. Baseline tumor tissue, sufficient material available for EGFR determination (therapeutic target of panitumumab) and biomarker studies. Patients without available tissue at baseline or with tissue collected longer than 1 year before, may undergo tumor biopsy. Progression after or not responding to treatment with at least one cisplatin or carboplatin containing regimen. Measurable disease (RECIST 1.1). Adequate hematological values, renal and hepatic function. Patients may not be receiving any other investigational agents Platinumnaïve patients. Patients previously progressed after a regimen containing EGFRinhibiting agents (as cetuximab, panitumumab, gefitinib, erlotinib), even if there was an initial response. Clinically significant cardiovascular disease (including myocardial infarction, unstable angina, symptomatic congestive heart failure, serious uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmia) 1 year before enrollment/randomization. History of interstitial lung disease e.g. pneumonitis or pulmonary fibrosis or evidence of interstitial lung disease on baseline chest CT scan. Known or suspected brain metastases. Psychiatric disorder precluding understanding of information on trial related topics, giving informed consent Known hypersensitivity to panitumumab active ingredient or excipients. Any concomitant drugs contraindicated for use with the trial drug according to the Swissmedic approved product information HIV positive patients</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>