<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01235832</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators propose to evaluate the effects of avocado consumption (by incorporating 1 unit of fruit per day into a healthy diet) on multiple cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk factors. The investigators will compare chronic consumption of a moderate fat blood cholesterol-lowering diet incorporating one avocado per day versus a blood cholesterol-lowering Lower-Fat diet on established CVD risk factors including lipids and lipoproteins, and blood pressure (BP). The investigators also will evaluate the effects of an avocado diet on several emerging CVD risk factors. To elucidate the specific benefits of avocado and its accompanying bioactives on the aforementioned risk factors, the investigators will compare the avocado diet with a diet that has the same macronutrient profile (but without the avocado).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Avocado on Cardiovascular Disease (CVD) Risk Factors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A randomized, 3-period cross-over, controlled feeding study was designed to compare the effects of a moderate fat blood cholesterol-lowering diet that provides one avocado per day (total fat = 34% total energy, MUFA=18%, SFA &lt;7%) to an Average American diet (AAD), Lower-Fat diet (total fat = 24% total energy, SFA &lt;7%), and Moderate Fat diet (with equivalent fatty acid profile to the avocado diet) without avocado. The study population consists of 40 overweight (BMI25-35 kg/m2) men and women with moderately elevated LDL-C, between the25-90th percentiles from NHANES. The investigators hypothesize that a moderate fat heart-healthy diet, including 1 avocado per day will reduce CVD risk factors including lipids, lipoproteins, apolipoproteins, lipoprotein particle size, markers of oxidative stress and inflammation, blood pressure and reverse cholesterol transport compared to an AAD, Lower-Fat diet, and moderate fat diet without avocado.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperlipidemias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antioxidants</mesh_term>
	<criteria>healthy nonsmoking overweight (BMI 2535 kg/m2) men and women LDLC between the2590th percentile from NHANES: 105194mg/dL for males; 98190mg/dL for females) BP &gt;140/90 mmHg; A history of myocardial infarction, stroke, diabetes mellitus, liver disease, kidney disease, and thyroid disease (unless controlled on medication); Lactation, pregnancy, or desire to become pregnant during the study; Cholesterollowering medication use; Intake of putative cholesterollowering supplements (psyllium, fish oil capsules, soy lecithin, niacin, fiber, flax, and phytoestrogens, stanol/sterol supplemented foods); Vegetarianism; Nut allergies (Other food allergies were reviewed on a casebycase basis); Refusal to discontinue nutritional supplements, herbs or vitamins</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>cholesterol</keyword>
	<keyword>triglycerides</keyword>
	<keyword>low-density lipoprotein</keyword>
	<keyword>high-density lipoprotein</keyword>
	<keyword>reverse cholesterol transport</keyword>
</DOC>