<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01223859</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Interstitial radiofrequency (RF) surgery of the soft palate (SP) is an established option in the treatment of habitual snoring. The decision making process in the management of habitual snoring would benefit from diagnostic guidelines for oropharyngeal findings. The aim was to investigate the correlation of systematic clinical pretreatment oropharyngeal examination scores with the efficacy of interstitial RF surgery of SP in a multi-center study</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pretreatment Assessment of Oropharynx Ans Soft Palate Radiofrequency Surgery - a Multi-center Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>TABLE 1. The inclusion and exclusion criterion used for the multicenter study. Criteria Inclusion Exclusion _____________ Age (years) 18-65 &lt; 18, &gt; 65 Habitual snoring yes no Excessive daytime sleepiness no yes BMI (kg/m2) &lt; 28 &gt; 28 AHI (events/hour) &lt; 15 &gt; 15 Overjet (mm) &lt; 5 &gt; 5 Clinical suspicion of obstruction no yes at base of tongue Size of palatine tonsils (grade) 0-II III-IV Nose breathing problems no yes Pharyngeal tonsil hypertrophy no yes A bed partner to assess snoring yes no _____________ Abbreviations: BMI = body mass index, AHI = apnea-hypopnea index.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Snoring</mesh_term>
	<criteria>TABLE 1. The inclusion and exclusion criterion used for the multicenter study. Criteria Inclusion Exclusion _____________ Age (years) 1865 &lt; 18, &gt; 65 Habitual snoring yes no Excessive daytime sleepiness no yes BMI (kg/m2) &lt; 28 &gt; 28 AHI (events/hour) &lt; 15 &gt; 15 Overjet (mm) &lt; 5 &gt; 5 Clinical suspicion of obstruction no yes at base of tongue Size of palatine tonsils (grade) 0II IIIIV Nose breathing problems no yes Pharyngeal tonsil hypertrophy no yes A bed partner to assess snoring yes no _____________ Abbreviations: BMI = body mass index, AHI = apneahypopnea index.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Radiofrequency, ablation, RFA, RFTA, RFITT, soft palate.</keyword>
</DOC>