<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01223534</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Hypothesis: a combined strategy of tuberculin skin test (TST) followed by QuantiFERON-TB Gold In-Tube (QFT-IT) to confirm positivity (tuberculosis infection,in contact-tracing study will allow avoiding unnecessary preventive treatment without increasing rates of tuberculosis cases among contacts screened. Aim of the study: to compare a combined strategy of the TST and the QFT-IT with TST alone for the diagnosis of tuberculosis infection and for therapeutic decision in contact tracing study. Design and setting: Prospective, multicentre, comparative study in 12 hospitals in Spain. Study population: 870 subjects, household contacts of patients with culture positive pulmonary and/or laryngeal tuberculosis will be randomized to one of two strategies: Arm A (standard practice), in which treatment decisions will be based on the TST result, and Arm B (experimental), in which treatment decisions will be based on the QFT result. Interventions: participants in arm A will undergo TST; participants in arm B will undergo TST, and, in case of a positive result, QFT-IT as well. Participants with positive TST (arm A) and positive QFT-IT (arm B) will be diagnosed with tuberculosis infection and will be treated with isoniazid for 6 months. All participants will be followed for two years. End-points of evaluation: development of tuberculosis and proportion of subjects for whom treatment is prescribed in each arm.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>QuantiFERON®-TB Gold In-Tube for the Diagnosis of Tuberculosis Infection in Contact Tracing Study.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Latent Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isoniazid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥18 years. Close contact of a pulmonary and/or laryngeal tuberculosis case. Written informed consent. HIV infection. Immunosuppression other than HIV, such as decompensated liver disease, chronic renal failure, corticosteroids treatment, malignancy under chemotherapy therapy. Prior tuberculosis or positive TST. Strain resistant to Isoniazid (index case).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tuberculosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Latent tuberculosis infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Tuberculin skin test</keyword>
	<keyword>Interferon-gamma release assays</keyword>
	<keyword>Contact-tracing study</keyword>
</DOC>