<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00493883</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to provide supervised access to treatment with TheraSphere速 to eligible patients with primary and metastatic cancer and evaluate response to treatment, survival and toxicity. The study has the following objectives: - Provide supervised access to treatment with TheraSphere to eligible patients with primary and metastatic cancer to the liver. - Evaluate patient experience and toxicities associated with TheraSphere treatment - Evaluate predisposing factors that may influence results and toxicity</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of TheraSphere速 Yttrium-90 Glass Microspheres for Primary and Metastatic Liver Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will use angiographic administration of radioactive TheraSphere速 Yttirum-90 microspheres into the hepatic artery, to treat 50 patients with primary or secondary cancer involving the liver. The study population are those who have failed standard therapies, have a majority of their cancer in the liver, have a good performance status and reasonable hepatic function. Outcomes being studied are response to treatment, survival and toxicity. 1. Range of patients who can be offered TheraSphere速 2. Tumor response rates, in terms of size, volume, contrast enhancement and PET avidity 3. Survival time 4. Determine response in relation to histology and other parameters 5. Ability to tolerate repeat treatments 6. Toxicity, which may include radiation induced liver damage, pain, consequences of shunting, toxic deaths.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age &gt;= 18. 2. Cancer visible in liver on CT,MR,US or PET scan. 3. Primary cancer in the liver (hepatocellular carcinoma), or metastatic cancer involving the liver from a primary such as but not limited to lung, breast, colon, upper GI, neuroendocrine, melanoma. 4. Life expectancy greater than 2 months 5. Performance status of ECOG 2 or better (Ambulatory and capable of all selfcare, but unable to carry out any work activities. Up and about more than 50% of waking hours.) 6. Patients have tried and/or are aware of all FDA approved therapies for their condition. 1. Vascular shunt that cannot be corrected. 2. Bulky cancer outside of liver. Active cancer within the liver should be a greater volume than the active cancer outside the liver / in the remainder of body. 3. Pregnancy 4. Hematologic primary such as lymphoma, leukemia, myeloma. 5. Body weight 300 lbs. and above 6. Evidence of portal hypertension, splenomegaly or ascites.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Therasphere</keyword>
	<keyword>Yttrium</keyword>
	<keyword>liver</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>radiation</keyword>
</DOC>