<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02597075</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess whether a structured physical activity program (PA) during palliative chemotherapy improves progression-free survival (PFS) and/or patient-reported outcomes (ESAS-r) in patients with metastatic colorectal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physical Activity in Patients With Metastatic Colorectal Cancer Who Receive Palliative First-line Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>While safety and feasibility as well as some improvements in fitness, fatigue and certain aspects of quality of life have been shown for physical activity in cancer patients during treatment, none of the pre-requisites above (i-iv) is fulfilled in the setting of patients with advanced colon cancer. However, evidence, primarily from the adjuvant setting, that physical activity impacts on treatment tolerability and tumor progression is a strong enough rationale to now embark on this prospective trial. By assessing in a large randomized controlled trial whether a 12-week structured physical activity program during chemotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed colorectal cancer undergoing standard first-line chemotherapy improves progression-free survival as compared to standard first-line chemotherapy alone, all pre-requisites for a practice-changing intervention are met. The physical exercise ACTIVE-program describes a 12-week exercise program consisting of a combination of a bi-weekly aerobic exercise (cycle ergometer) supervised by a physical therapist and a self-paced increase in physical activity during daily life using a pedometer with a daily step goal as a motivational tool. In addition to the supervised exercise program twice a week, patients of the intervention group are recommended to be physically active at home. All patients will undergo standard systemic therapy for metastatic colorectal cancer. Patients in the care-as-usual group are not actively encouraged to change their physical activity level e.g. to start a fitness program during chemotherapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent according to ICH/GCP regulations before randomization. Patient with histologically or cytologically confirmed colorectal carcinoma (CRC) required to start palliative firstline systemic therapy for inoperable or metastatic disease. Patients who were diagnosed with histologically or cytologically confirmed nonmetastatic CRC earlier and now relapsed with metastatic disease are also eligible, if any prior neoadjuvant or adjuvant chemotherapy has been completed more than 4 months before inclusion into this trial. Patient has measurable disease on CT scan or MRI to be performed within 4 weeks before randomization (measurability criteria according to RECIST 1.1, nonnodal lesions ≥10 mm, lymph nodes ≥15mm) OR evaluable disease i.e. patient with nonmeasurable metastases but elevated serum tumormarker (CEA at least &gt;2xULN). Command of written and spoken language allowing for informed consent and for filling in trial questionnaires. Baseline patientreported outcomes (PROs) have been completed. WHO performance status 02. Age 1875 (80) years (if WHO is 01 upper age limit is 80 years). Any potential patient who meets any of the following criteria has to be excluded from entering the trial Cycle ergometer stress test (completed within 28 days before trial start) shows significant signs of ischemic heart disease or highgrade arrhythmias, which preclude an exercise program. Preexisting severe medical conditions precluding participation in a physical activity program as determined by the local investigator. Such conditions include: chronic heart failure (greater than NYHA II), recent myocardial infarction (less than 3 months ago), unstable angina pectoris, clinically significant arrhythmias, uncontrolled hypertension with repeated systolic blood pressure above 160mmHg, and COPD (requiring oxygen supply or GOLD stadium greater than 2). Inability to ride a cycle ergometer e.g. for musculoskeletal reasons. Inability to perform 50 Watt on a cycle ergometer (during Cycle ergometer stress test), for any reason. Patients who are a priori planned for curative surgery including metastasectomy. It is allowed to include patients for whom metastasectomy might be an option if chemotherapy induces a significant response. Any serious underlying medical condition (at the judgment of the investigator) which could impair the ability of the patient to participate in the trial (e.g. active autoimmune disease, uncontrolled diabetes). Concurrent treatment in a trial with experimental drugs or other anticancer therapy, which are hypothesized to alter tumor progression. Participation in an observational trial or a translational trial is allowed. Previous malignancy within 5 years with the exception of adequately treated cervical carcinoma in situ, localized nonmelanoma skin cancer, superficial bladder cancer (nonmuscle invasive disease), localized prostate cancer (T13). Psychiatric disorder precluding understanding of trial information, giving informed consent, filling out PRO forms, or interfering with compliance. Any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially hampering proper compliance with the trial protocol.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Colorectal Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic Colorectal Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical Activity</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
</DOC>