<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02597283</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to test the hypothesis that the Biguard stent system will lead to fewer target lesion failure compared to regular stent system in patients with coronary bifurcation lesions at one year.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Coronary Bifurcation Lesions Treated With Biguard Stent System</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The current study is designed as a multicenter, randomized and prospective study aiming to compare the effect of Biguard bifurcation stent system and regular stent system in patients with bifurcation lesions. Based on the previous studies, the rate of 1-year target lesion failure was around 12% after PCI with regular stent system. And the investigators previous data showed that this event at 12-month after Biguard bifurcation stent system was 4%. Considering the lost to follow-up, it is anticipated that up to 400 patients will be enrolled in the trial. All patients will have repeat angiography at 13 months, with clinical follow-up to 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject must be age≥18 years; Subject (or legal guardian) understands the trial requirements and the treatment procedures and provides written informed consent before any trialspecific tests or procedures are performed; Subject is eligible for percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI); Subject has symptomatic coronary artery disease or documented silent ischemia; Subject is willing to comply with all protocolrequired followup evaluations; Target lesion must be a de novo true bifurcation lesions located in a native coronary artery with a visually estimated reference vessel diameter (RVD) ≥2.50 mm and ≤4.00 mm; Target lesion must have visually estimated stenosis ≥50%; The lesion length of main branch vessel must measure &lt;40 mm, and the lesion length of side branch vessel must measure &lt;20 mm (by visual estimate); Subject with no more than one lesion existing in the same vessel can be chosen, when several bifurcation lesions existing simultaneously; Subject with knowledge of trial purpose, informed consents and volition of undergoing coronary angiography and clinical followup voluntarily. Subject has clinical symptoms and/or electrocardiogram (ECG) changes consistent with acute MI within two weeks; Subject is on dialysis or has serum creatinine level &gt;3.0 mg/dL; Subject has known allergy to the study stent system or protocolrequired concomitant medications; Subject has any other serious medical illness that may reduce life expectancy to less than 12 months; Patient with cardiac heart failure (above New York Heart Association (classification) III), or left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF)&lt; 30%; Subject with hemorrhagic tendency or history of active peptic ulcers, cerebral hemorrhage, or subarachnoid hemorrhage, cerebral stroke within half a year, as well as patients who have contraindication to antiplatelet agents or anticoagulant treatment; Subject is participating in another investigational drug or device clinical trial that has not reached its primary endpoint or intends to participate in another investigational drug or device clinical trial within 12 months after the index procedure; Subject Inability to follow the protocol and comply with followup requirements or any other reason that the investigator feels would place the patient at increased risk Subject has more than 1 lesion that requires treatment during the index procedure; Target lesion meets any of the following criteria: 1. Thrombus, or possible thrombus, present in the target vessel; 2. Excessive tortuosity proximal to or within the lesion; 3. Excessive angulation proximal to or within the lesion; 4. Chronic total occlusion lesion in target vessel not recanalized; 5. severe calcification with unsuccessfully predilated; 6. restenosis disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bifurcation lesions</keyword>
	<keyword>Percutaneous coronary intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized controlled trial</keyword>
</DOC>