<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="204722">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00423930</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>06-130</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>MSKCC-06130</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>PFIZER-MSKCC-06130</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00423930</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cisplatin, Bevacizumab, and Intensity-Modulated Radiation Therapy in Treating Patients With Stage III or Stage IV Head and Neck Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Study of Radiotherapy (IMRT) + Cisplatin + Bevacizumab for Patients With Stage III/IV Head and Neck Cancers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Genentech, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as cisplatin, work in different ways to stop the
      growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing.
      Monoclonal antibodies, such as bevacizumab, can block tumor growth in different ways. Some
      block the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Others find tumor cells and help kill
      them or carry tumor-killing substances to them. Bevacizumab may also stop the growth of head
      and neck cancer by blocking blood flow to the tumor. Specialized radiation therapy that
      delivers a high dose of radiation directly to the tumor may kill more tumor cells and cause
      less damage to normal tissue. Giving cisplatin and bevacizumab together with
      intensity-modulated radiation therapy may kill more tumor cells.

      PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying the side effects and how well giving cisplatin and
      bevacizumab together with intensity-modulated radiation therapy works in treating patients
      with stage III or stage IV head and neck cancer.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OBJECTIVES:

      Primary

        -  Determine the 2-year progression-free survival of patients with stage III or IV
           squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck treated with chemoradiotherapy comprising
           cisplatin, bevacizumab, and intensity-modulated radiotherapy.

        -  Determine the safety and tolerability of this regimen in these patients.

      Secondary

        -  Determine the median overall survival of patients treated with this regimen.

      OUTLINE:

        -  Chemoradiotherapy: Patients receive cisplatin IV over 1 hour on days 1, 2, 22, 23, 43,
           and 44 and bevacizumab IV over 30-90 minutes on days 1, 22, and 43. Patients also
           undergo intensity-modulated radiotherapy on days 1-5, 8-12, 15-19, 22-26, 29-33, 36-40,
           and 43-47. Treatment continues in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable
           toxicity.

      Between 3-4 months after completion of chemoradiotherapy, patients undergo evaluation.
      Patients with clinical evidence of residual, progressive, or persistent disease may be
      eligible to undergo neck surgery at the discretion of their physician.

      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 3 months for 2 years, every
      6 months for 3 years, and then annually thereafter.

      PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 42 patients will be accrued for this study.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival at 2 years</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">44</enrollment>
  <condition>Head and Neck Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IMRT + cisplatin + bevacizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is a single-institution phase II study. The primary endpoint is to determine 2-year progression-free survival for patients with locally or regionally advanced HNSCC treated with concurrent intensity modulated radiation therapy (IMRT) + cisplatin + bevacizumab.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>bevacizumab</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>IMRT + cisplatin + bevacizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cisplatin</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>IMRT + cisplatin + bevacizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>conventional surgery</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>IMRT + cisplatin + bevacizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>intensity-modulated radiation therapy</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>IMRT + cisplatin + bevacizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Stage III/IV HNSCC without distant metastasis, previously untreated. Patients with
             stage II squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx will also be eligible.

          -  Adequate renal function, with serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL. Patients with serum
             creatinine &gt; 1.5 mg/dL may be eligible if calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 55 ml/min
             by Cockcroft and Gault equation (or 24-hour urine collection).

          -  Age ≥ 18 years

          -  Karnofsky performance status ≥70%

          -  Adequate bone marrow function: absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/μl, platelets ≥
             100,000/μl, hemoglobin ≥ 9 gm/dl

          -  Adequate hepatic function: Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 X UNL (patients with Gilbert's
             syndrome as the cause of hyperbilirubinemia may be eligible if total bilirubin ≤ 2.5
             X UNL), aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 2.5 X UNL, alanine aminotransferase (ALT)
             ≤ 2.5 X UNL, alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2.5 X UNL.

          -  Men and women of childbearing potential must be willing to consent to using effective
             contraception while on treatment and for at least 3 months thereafter.

          -  Patients must have ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written
             informed consent document.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Prior chemotherapy or radiation therapy for HNSCC

          -  Prior treatment with bevacizumab or other agents specifically targeting VEGF

          -  Other active malignancy, other than indolent malignancies which the investigator
             determines are unlikely to interfere with treatment or efficacy analysis. For
             example, patients with non-melanoma skin cancer, in situ carcinoma of the cervix, or
             prostate cancer within the no current biochemical (PSA) or radiologic evidence of
             disease may enroll.

          -  Patients with nasopharyngeal carcinoma

          -  Patients who will receive amifostine as part of the radiation treatment plan

          -  Patients with skin breakdown/ulceration (CTCAE version 3.0, grade 2 or higher).

          -  Patients with hearing loss requiring hearing aid or intervention (i.e. interfering in
             a clinical significant way with activities of daily living).

          -  Patients with multifocal peripheral sensory alterations or paresthesias (including
             tingling) interfering with function, per patient report (example: activities of daily
             living).

          -  History of arterial thromboembolic events, including transient ischemic attack (TIA),
             cerebrovascular accident (CVA), unstable angina, or myocardial infarction (MI) within
             the last 3 years.

          -  Urine protein: creatinine (UPC) ratio ≥ 1.0 at screening. A random urine sample is
             collected. Total protein (mg/dL) and spot creatinine (mg/dL) are ordered for this
             sample. The UPC ratio is calculated from the results of these tests.

          -  International normalized ratio (INR) &gt; 1.5 or activated partial thromboplastin time
             (aPTT) &gt; 1.5 X upper limits of normal (UNL),

          -  Current use of warfarin, current use of heparin or low-molecular weight heparin,
             chronic daily treatment with aspirin (&gt; 325 mg/day) or nonsteroidal antiinflammatory
             medications known to inhibit platelet function. Treatment with dipyramidole
             (Persantine), ticlopidine (Ticlid), clopidogrel (Plavix) and or cilostazol (Pletal)
             is not allowed.

          -  Patients with gross hemoptysis or hematemesis (defined as bright red blood of 1
             teaspoon of more) within 1 month prior to Day 1 protocol treatment will be excluded
             from this trial. Patients with incidental blood mixed with phlegm are not excluded.

          -  Esophageal varices, non-healing ulcer, wound, or bone fracture are exclusion
             criteria. However, patients with skin breakdown overlying malignant neck
             lymphadenopathy may be eligible, at the discretion of the investigator.

          -  Anatomic lesion that increases the risk of serious hemorrhage, such as encasement or
             invasion of major blood vessels by primary tumor and/or by involved lymph nodes

          -  Blood pressure of &gt; 150/100 mmHg

          -  New York Heart Association (NYHA) Grade II or greater congestive heart failure.

          -  Clinically significant peripheral vascular disease

          -  History of bleeding diathesis or hemorrhagic disorder, or coagulopathy.

          -  Major surgical procedure or significant traumatic injury within 28 days prior to
             treatment with bevacizumab

          -  Core biopsy within 15 days prior to treatment with bevacizumab.

          -  Minor surgical procedures such as fine needle aspirations or placement of
             percutaneous gastrostomy tube (PEG) less than 7 days prior to treatment with
             bevacizumab

          -  History of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation, or intra-abdominal
             abscess within 6 months prior enrollment.

          -  Inability to comply with study and/or follow-up procedures

          -  Women who are pregnant or lactating
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David G. Pfister, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>August 2, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 16, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>stage II squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
  <keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
  <keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
  <keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
  <keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
  <keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
  <keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
  <keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
  <keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
  <keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the paranasal sinus and nasal cavity</keyword>
  <keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the paranasal sinus and nasal cavity</keyword>
  <keyword>tongue cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
