<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02702466</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this work is to demonstrate superiority to three months of a standardized short course of SPA Therapy of 6 days associated with personalized health education program compared to conventional therapy in the management of MSDs on the functional capabilities of the employees in their daily lives (personal or professional)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Active Prevention of Upper Limb Musculoskeletal Disorders in Thermal Environment (MUSKA).</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Musculoskeletal disorders are the leading occupational disease in industrialized countries. The symptoms are varied, their multiple risk factors, work organization may be involved. Musculoskeletal disorders affect the muscles, tendons and nerves of the mainly upper limbs (neck, shoulder, elbow, wrist and hand). Pain or functional impairment are common to all these disorders.The proposed study is part of an active preventive approach in addressing current employees with latent or symptomatic upper extremity MSD linked to a hyper solicitation. This study provide them 6 days SPA therapy (before or after work) combined with a health education program to help improve their lives over time.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>TMS latent or symptomatic of the upper limbs according to the European Consensus SALTSA / Q score with INRS Nordic &gt; 2 With or without a history of work stoppage and occupation at the time of inclusion Age: &gt; 18 years &lt; 65 years Patient affiliated to a social security scheme ( beneficiary entitled ) Patient has given its consent in writing to participate in the study Contraindication to the spa therapy Spa achieved in the last 12 months Trouble behavior or understanding making it impossible to assess</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Upper limb musculoskeletal disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Spa treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized controlled trials</keyword>
	<keyword>Education</keyword>
	<keyword>Self- management</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-care</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Non pharmacological treatment</keyword>
</DOC>