<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02702570</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators are planning to recruit approximately 30 study participants aged 50 years and older that will undergo a 4 week attention and emotion regulation intervention. The intervention systematically targets thoughts, emotions and behavior in order to promote quality of life and advance successful brain aging. The investigators will assess the feasibility of recruiting and retaining participants for an attention and emotion regulation intervention. In addition, the investigators will determine the efficacy of the intervention to enhance and promote quality of life, sustained attention, emotions, motivation and cognitive health.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Committed Actions for Successful Aging</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The CASA model is developed here in the investigators program (Geda et al) based on neuroscience and Acceptance and Commitment Therapy (ACT). The rationale for the study is that the cortico-cortical network linking the prefrontal cortex with the mesial temporal lobe is susceptible to the wear and tear of day to day life such as stress and emotional distress. The investigators hypothesize that the CASA intervention will promote emotional and cognitive health by targeting this network.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Participants will be recruited from the community via advertisement in retirement communities, church, and other social gatherings. Eligible participants are cognitively normal males and females aged 50 years and older. Inclusion criteria: Subject will sign approved consent form Male or female adults (age &gt; 50 years of age) Subject will complete all of the testing and procedures Exclusion criteria: Refusal to sign the approved consent form Refusal to complete all testing and procedures of the study Males and females &lt; age of 50 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>