<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02349555</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This open label study seeks to study the effects of a nutritional supplement on inflammatory markers, metabolic parameters, and safety in subjects compared to baseline after taking supplement for 2 and 4 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nutritional Supplement Impact on Metabolic Parameters</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary endpoint will be to determine if nutritional supplement decreases the metabolic parameter of triglycerides. Numerous studies have demonstrated the efficacy of fish oil on reducing triglycerides in subjects taking fish oil at similar doses provided in our product (see references). Additional metabolic parameters will be measured as secondary endpoints, including abdominal obesity, HDL cholesterol, blood pressure, fasting glucose, haemoglobin A1c, skin glycation (AGEs), pulse wave velocity, skin carotenoids, serum 25(OH)D concentrations, weight, and LDL density, particle size and number. The novel nutritional supplement contains many nutrients that have been shown to improve metabolic parameters.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subject male or female between the ages of 3070 at the time of informed consent. 2. Fasting Blood Glucose between 90 and 125mg/dL in the serum and 2 additional parameters at screening: Abdominal obesity defined by &gt;102 cm (&gt;40in) waist circumference in men and &gt;88cm (&gt;35in) waist circumference in women, or Triglycerides ≥ 150mg/dL, or HDL cholesterol &lt;40 mg/dL in men and &lt;50 mg/dL in women 3. Hemoglobin A1C less than 6.5% at screening 4. BMI &gt;27kg/m2 5. Blood Pressure &lt;150/90 mm Hg 6. Subject is willing and able to comply with study restrictions, procedures, and assessments. 7. Subject is able to swallow product without difficulty. 8. Subject is willing to fast for 8h prior to blood draw at screening, baseline, 2 month, and 4 month visits. 9. Subject is willing to maintain usual diet and physical activity for the duration of the study. 10. Eats 1 or fewer servings of fatty fish per week (e.g. salmon, tuna, mackerel, herring, anchovies, etc.) 11. Subject is willing to take the study multivitamin/mineral supplement for 30 days prior to starting investigational product and during the 4 month intake of investigational product. 12. Use of effective method of contraception by females of childbearing potential 30days before the screening visit and agree to continue to practice that acceptable method of contraception for the duration of her participation in the study. Acceptable methods of contraception include oral, injectable, or implantable contraceptives; intrauterine devices, diaphragm plus spermicide; abstinence (must agree to use doublebarrier method if they become sexually active), transdermal patch, or any double barrier method including a vasectomized sexual partner. Women who have had a hysterectomy (partial or total) or tubal ligation at least 6 months prior to Visit 1 or who have been postmenopausal for at least 1 year prior to Visit 1 are not considered to be of childbearing potential. 1. Subject has a known allergy or intolerance to any of the ingredients contained in the nutritional supplement. 2. Subject currently uses nicotine or has not quit using for at least 1 year. 3. Subject is taking an unapproved medication or has not been on a stable dose, for at least 8 weeks, of approved medication. 4. Subject who has undergone any type of surgery on their intestines that would interfere with product absorption, in the opinion of the investigator. 5. Subject is not willing to stop taking dietary/nutritional supplements for duration of study. 6. Subject is taking any dietary/nutritional supplements, not provided by the sponsor, within 30 days prior to investigational product administration. 7. Abnormalities in screening laboratory samples that the investigator would consider unstable/unsafe.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>