<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01015547</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to compare in very early polyarticular juvenile idiopathic arthritis (JIA) the efficacy, safety, and cost-benefit-ratio of three treatment strategies: biologic combination, combination of conventional disease-modifying drugs (DMARDs), and methotrexate alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aggressive Combination Drug Therapy in Very Early Polyarticular Juvenile Idiopathic Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>DMARD-naive polyarticular JIA patients with an early disease (onset less than 6 months) are randomized into one of three treatment strategies: (1) biological combination, i.e., anti-TNF therapy with infliximab plus methotrexate; (2) Combination of DMARDs with methotrexate, sulfasalazine, plus hydroxychloroquine; and (3) Methotrexate alone. The efficacy is evaluated by American College of Rheumatology Pediatric (ACR Pedi) criteria based on 6 core set variables (CSVs): 1. no of active joints; 2. no. of joints with pain or tenderness and limitation of motion; 3. ESR (mm/hr); 4. the Childhood Health Assessment Questionnaire (CHAQ); 5. Physician's Visual Analogue Scale (VAS); 6. Patient/Parent VAS. To fulfill ACR Pedi 75 criteria, 3/6 CSVs have to improve 75% and not more than 1/6 CSV worsen more than 30%. All direct and indirect costs are documented. The first phase of the study is open-label clinical trial lasting for 54 weeks. In the second phase of the study the patients are followed up to 5 years, and the long-term outcome of early aggressive therapy is analyzed. Serum, urine, and saliva samples are collected at 3 and 5 years for translational research.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infliximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antirheumatic Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Naltrexone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>juvenile idiopathic arthritis arthritis lasting for at least 6 weeks but not more than 6 months polyarticular disease with at least 5 active joints with at least 3 joints with pain or tenderness and limitation of motion no previous treatment with DMARDs systemic JIA any abnormality in the hematopoietic or lymphatic system any major concurrent medical condition inadequate psychosocial situation pregnancy a nonabstinent female with reproductive capacity without regular contraceptive use</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>juvenile idiopathic arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>polyarthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>combination therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>biologic agents</keyword>
	<keyword>TNF antagonists</keyword>
	<keyword>infliximab</keyword>
</DOC>