<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01015716</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate whether a 1 year worksite based life-style intervention can reduce body weight and increase physical capacity and subsequently reduce musculoskeletal disorders and increase workability in overweight health care workers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physical Exercise, Dietary Counseling and Cognitive Behavioral Training as a Combined Intervention to Reduce Weight and Increase Workability in Health Care Workers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Health care workers have a high rate of musculoskeletal disorders and sick leave and a poor workability and physical fitness. Most studies have focused on increasing physical fitness in order to increase workability and to reduce musculoskeletal disorders and sick leave. Studies however also show that many health care workers are obese and obesity has been linked to poor workability. Limited research is available on the effect of reducing body-weight in this group in order to increase workability and to decrease musculoskeletal disorders and sick leave. This study introduces a combined worksite based lifestyle intervention consisting of physical exercise, dietary counseling and cognitive behavioral training aimed at reducing weight in health care workers. On specific worksites, health care workers are cluster randomized to either intervention or control group. Effects on physical capacity, body composition, musculoskeletal disorders, workability and sick leave are evaluated before and after a 1 year intervention period</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Overweight Health care workers, working more than 15 hours pr week Pregnancy, angina pectoris and lifethreatening diseases according to safty regulations for physical evaluation methods</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Weight loss</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive Behavioral Training</keyword>
</DOC>