<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01995916</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study has been funded by National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) to compare two behavioral interventions for Menstrual Mood Disorders, including premenstrual dysphoric disorder (PMDD). Both of these interventions will be run in a group format, meaning that you will be part of a group of other women who have a menstrual mood disorder. Both of these interventions will be run by experienced mental health professionals and both interventions have been shown to be effective in reducing mood symptoms, increasing a sense of well-being, and helping individuals cope with stress. While it is expected that both interventions to be associated with some benefit, this study is designed to see which is better for women with a menstrual mood disorder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Wellness Intervention for Menstrual Mood Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mood Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Meets prospective criteria for a menstrual mood disorder, including PMDD Depression symptom severity and functional impairment based on prospective symptom ratings for 23 cycles using the Daily Record of Severity of Problems (DRSP) Clear remission of all symptoms during days 610 18 55 years of age Regular menstrual cycles Early life sexual or physical abuse (50% of sample) or no history of sexual or physical abuse (50% of sample) Absence of current PTSD symptoms using the 17item PTSD checklist (PCL) 8th grade literacy level Ability to give informed consent Current Axis I disorder or suicide ideation (histories of depression, anxiety, substance abuse, and eating disorders are allowed if in remission for &gt;2 years) Premenstrual exacerbation of chronic disorders In a current abusive relationship or residing with a former abuser A lifetime history of suicide attempt, or suicidal thoughts or gestures within 5 years of study enrollment Histories of bipolar or psychotic disorders Age &lt; 18 or &gt; 55 years Pregnancy or breastfeeding Use of psychotropic, hormonal or other agents that alter mood or biological mediators Current functional pain disorder A history of meditation practice (2+ times/week for 15+ min; some yoga allowed) Diabetes BMI &lt; 18.5 Vigorous exercise Stage 2 Hypertension Any symptom item rated &gt;2 (moderate or higher) or a total score &gt; 24 on the PTSD checklist</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>