<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01995708</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see if the investigator can help the immune system to work against myeloma. This study will see if a vaccine made with altered dendritic cells will make T cells work against tumor cells. The stem cells collected for the transplant will also be used to grow dendritic cells in the lab. The dendritic cells will carry the antigens. These cells then will be injected under the skin. The investigators will do lab studies before and after the vaccination to find out if the vaccine is working.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CT7, MAGE-A3, and WT1 mRNA-electroporated Autologous Langerhans-type Dendritic Cells as Consolidation for Multiple Myeloma Patients Undergoing Autologous Stem Cell Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Symptomatic multiple myeloma, ISS stages IIII, within 12 months of starting therapy. Completion of induction therapy with Very Good Partial Response (VGPR), or better, by International Myeloma Working Group (IMWG) criteria. Deemed eligible for ASCT by standard institutional criteria. Age ≥18 years. Documentation of CT7, MAGEA3, or WT1 expression in the bone marrow and/or bone marrow aspirate. Prior autologous or allogeneic SCT. Previous immunization against CT7, MAGEA3, other cancertestis antigens, or WT1. Known immunodeficiency, HIV positivity, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C. History of autoimmune disease (e.g., rheumatoid arthritis, SLE), other than vitiligo, diabetes, or treated thyroiditis, which are allowed. History of severe allergic reactions to vaccines or unknown allergens. Participation in any other clinical trial involving another investigational agent within 4 weeks prior to first immunization. Lenalidomiderelated toxicities before ASCT necessitating its discontinuation as part of treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>CT7</keyword>
	<keyword>MAGE-A3</keyword>
	<keyword>WT1 mRNA-electroporated Autologous Langerhans</keyword>
	<keyword>vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Autologous Stem Cell Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>13-009</keyword>
</DOC>