<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01995071</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and antiviral effect of multiple doses of ABT-493 and ABT-530 in adults with genotype 1 HCV.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety and Antiviral Effect of Multiple Doses of ABT-493 and ABT-530 in Adults With Genotype 1 Hepatitis C Virus (HCV)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antiviral Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronic HCV infection prior to study enrollment. Screening laboratory result indicating HCV genotype 1infection. Subject has plasma HCV RNA level greater than 10,000 IU/mL at Screening. Per local standard, subject is considered to be noncirrhotic or to have compensated cirrhosis. History of severe, lifethreatening or other significant sensitivity to any drug. Positive test result for Hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) or antiHuman Immunodeficiency Virus antibody (HIV Ab). Prior therapy for the treatment of HCV. Any current or past clinical evidence of Child Pugh B or C classification of clinical history of liver decompensation including ascites (noted on physical exam), variceal bleeding or hepatic encephalopathy. Any cause of liver disease other than chronic HCV infection.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Hepatitis C</keyword>
	<keyword>Cirrhosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Child Pugh A</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C virus</keyword>
	<keyword>Compensated Cirrhosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C Genotype 1</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis C</keyword>
	<keyword>Interferon-Free</keyword>
	<keyword>Cirrhotic</keyword>
</DOC>