<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00596063</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is the comparative evaluation of the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of two recombinant regular human insulin injections administered subcutaneously in healthy volunteers under the conditions of euglycemic clamp.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparative Glucose Clamp Study of Wockhardt's Insulin Human Regular for Injection and Novolin R, in Healthy Subjects.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A comparative evaluation of the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of two recombinant regular human insulin injections administered subcutaneously in healthy volunteers. It is a crossover study. The subjects shall be administered single doses of each insulin during two separate visits under the conditions of euglycemic clamp.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Healthy male or female subject. 2. Age ≥ 18 and ≤ 45 years. 3. Body Mass Index (BMI) between 18.0 and 27.0 kg/m2, inclusive. 4. Nonsmoker, defined as no nicotine consumption for at least one year. 5. Signed and dated informed consent obtained before any trialrelated activities. (Trialrelated activities are any procedure that would not have been performed during normal management of the subject.). 1. Previous participation in this trial or other clinical trials within the last 3 months. 2. Pregnant, breastfeeding or the intention of becoming pregnant or not using adequate contraceptive measures (intrauterine device (IUD) that has been in place for at least 3 months, or sterilization, or the oral contraceptive pill, which should have been taken without difficulty for at least 3 months, an approved hormonal implant). 3. Clinically significant abnormal hematology or biochemistry screening tests, as judged by the Investigator. In particular, subjects with elevated liver enzymes (AST or ALT &gt; 2 times the upper limit of normal) or impaired renal function (elevated serum creatinine values above the upper limit of normal) will not be allowed to enter the trial. 4. Any serious systemic infectious disease during the four weeks prior to the first dose of test drug, as judged by the Investigator. 5. History of any illness that, in the opinion of the Investigator, might confound the results of the trial or pose risk in administering the trial drug to the subject. In particular, subjects with significant cardiovascular disease, anemia (haemoglobin below the lower limit of normal) or hemoglobinopathy will not be allowed to enter the trial. 6. History of alcohol or drug abuse. 7. Any positive reaction of drugs of abuse. 8. Hepatitis B or C or HIV positive. 9. Use of prescription drugs within 3 weeks preceding the first dosing of insulin, except for oral contraceptives/hormonal implants. 10. Use of any insulin product for therapeutic purposes in the past. 11. Use of nonprescription drugs, except routine vitamins, within 3 weeks prior to the first dose of the test drug. Occasional use of paracetamol is permitted. 12. Mental incapacity, unwillingness or language barriers precluding adequate understanding or cooperation. 13. Blood donation of more than 500 ml within the last 12 weeks. 14. History of multiple and/or severe allergies to drugs or foods or a history of severe anaphylactic reaction. 15. Known or suspected allergy to trial product or related products.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacodynamics</keyword>
	<keyword>recombinant human insulin</keyword>
	<keyword>healthy volunteers</keyword>
</DOC>