<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00596271</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective is to investigate the immunogenicity of the Japanese Encephalitis vaccine IC51 (JE-PIV) single and concomitant with HAVRIX® 1440</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Concomitant Vaccination With the Japanese Encephalitis Vaccine IC51 and HARVIX® 1440</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, controlled, multi-center, single-blind phase 3 study. The study population consists of male and female healthy subjects, aged at least 18 years. 192 subjects will be enrolled at 2 sites in Europe.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Encephalitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Encephalitis, Japanese</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 18 years of age In female subjects either childbearing potential terminated by surgery or one year postmenopausal, or a negative serum pregnancy test during screening and the willingness not to become pregnant during the study period and 30 days after the last vaccination by practicing reliable methods of contraception Written informed consent obtained prior to study entry History of clinical manifestation of any flavivirus infection History of vaccination against Japanese encephalitis (JE), Yellow fever and Dengue fever (an antiJEV neutralizing antibody titer &gt;= 1:10 at baseline is acceptable for inclusion, these subjects will be part of the safety population, but will not be analyzed for immunogenicity in the perprotocol analysis) History of any previous Hepatitis A vaccination and infection Use of any other investigational or nonregistered drug or vaccine in addition to the study vaccine during the study period or within 30 days preceding the first dose of study vaccine Planned administration of another vaccine during the study period Immunodeficiency including postorgantransplantation or immunosuppressive therapy A family history of congenital or hereditary immunodeficiency History of autoimmune disease Administration of chronic (defined as more than 14 days) immunosuppressants or other immunemodifying drugs within six months of vaccination. Any acute infections within 4 weeks prior to enrollment Infection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), Hepatitis B (HBsAg) or Hepatitis C</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>