<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01617707</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sedative endoscopic examination using sedative premedication has been undertaken to induce conscious sedation for comfortable and painless endoscopy. Midazolam has been most widely used as a sedative premedication because it has lots of advantages, such as a short half-life, a faster onset of sedation and an excellent sedative hypnotic effect. However, midazolam has been used regardless of whether or not alcohol although using midazolam in chronic alcoholics is related to paradoxical reaction, characterized by increased talkativeness, emotional release, excitement, and excessive movement. In recent years, propofol has been used safety and effectively in sedative GI endoscopy because of its potent hypnotic effect and its ultrashort pharmacokinetic profile. Therefore, The present study was conducted to compare the safety and efficacy of BPS (propofol in combination with midazolam) with conventional sedation (midazolam) in chronic alcoholic patients undergoing diagnostic GI endoscopic procedures.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safe and Effective Sedation in Chronic Alcoholic Patients Underwent Diagnostic Endoscopic Procedures: Study Comparing Midazolam and Propofol With Midazolam</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Propofol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Midazolam</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age ≥ 20 ECOG ≥ 2 patient who consents to enroll the trial age &lt; 20 pregnant or lactating women American Society of Anesthesiology (ASA) physical status class V chronic pulmonary disease history of allergic to propofol history of complication of sedation endoscope liver failure or hepatic encephalopathy who didn't consented to enroll the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>sedation</keyword>
	<keyword>endoscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>midazolam</keyword>
	<keyword>propofol</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic alcoholics</keyword>
</DOC>