<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00941876</DOC>
	<brief_summary>HIV positive women and couples have broad reproductive health needs that are not always met within HIV services. The integration of family planning (FP) services into Tanzania's HIV Care and Treatment Clinics (CTC) will address the fertility desires of CTC clients and ultimately result in the reduction of unintended pregnancies and HIV incidence. One strategy for integrating FP and CTC services is to use a "facilitated referral" model. Facilitated referrals are enhanced referrals for additional services that have been used in other settings and which are the preferred intervention strategy the Government of Tanzania would like to pilot test. This study will evaluate the feasibility, effectiveness, and costs of implementing a "facilitated referrals" intervention by examining FP use among female clients attending HIV/AIDS Care and Treatment Centers. This study will measure whether there is a reduction in unmet need for contraception among female CTC clients after the facilitated referral integration intervention has been implemented.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Integration of Family Planning and HIV Services in Tanzania</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Female clients of Care &amp; Treatment Clinics with CD4 counts &gt;100, and are WHO Stage I III. (CTC Clients) 2. Care and Treatment providers who provide services to clients (CTC Providers) 3. Care and Treatment supervisors who are the immediate incharge supervisor for the CTC clinic. (CTC supervisor) 4. Family Planning providers who provide services to clients. (FP providers) 5. Family Planning supervisors who are the immediate incharge supervisor for the FP clinic. (FP supervisor)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>AE</keyword>
	<keyword>adverse event</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS</keyword>
	<keyword>acquired immunodeficiency syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>ALT (SGPT)</keyword>
	<keyword>alanine aminotransferase</keyword>
	<keyword>ART</keyword>
	<keyword>antiretroviral therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>AST (SGOT)</keyword>
	<keyword>aspartate aminotransferase</keyword>
	<keyword>DCF</keyword>
	<keyword>data collection forms</keyword>
	<keyword>DMC</keyword>
	<keyword>Data Monitoring Committee</keyword>
	<keyword>FDA</keyword>
	<keyword>(U.S.) Food and Drug Administration</keyword>
	<keyword>GCP</keyword>
	<keyword>Good Clinical Practice guidelines</keyword>
	<keyword>HB sAg</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatitis B surface antigen</keyword>
	<keyword>ICH</keyword>
	<keyword>International Conference of Harmonisation</keyword>
	<keyword>IND</keyword>
	<keyword>Investigational New Drug Application</keyword>
	<keyword>IRB</keyword>
	<keyword>Institutional Review Board</keyword>
	<keyword>IU</keyword>
	<keyword>International units</keyword>
	<keyword>mg</keyword>
	<keyword>milligram(s)</keyword>
	<keyword>mm3</keyword>
	<keyword>cubic millimeter(s)</keyword>
	<keyword>PCR</keyword>
	<keyword>polymerase chain reaction</keyword>
	<keyword>SAE</keyword>
	<keyword>serious adverse event</keyword>
	<keyword>µg</keyword>
	<keyword>microgram</keyword>
	<keyword>ULN</keyword>
	<keyword>upper limit of the normal range</keyword>
	<keyword>WB</keyword>
	<keyword>Western Blot</keyword>
	<keyword>To inform the Ministry of Health strategy for integrating FP and HIV/AIDS Care and Treatment Services in Tanzania</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV seronegativity</keyword>
</DOC>