<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00941525</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether 24-hour fluctuation of intraocular pressure (IOP) is associated with central corneal thickness (CCT) in subjects with ocular hypertension or open angle glaucoma and in age-matched controls. Also to evaluate whether mean IOP reduction as a response to latanoprost (0.005% Xalatan) is associated with CCT, after a 4-weeks period of treatment. Also, to evaluate whether 24-hour fluctuation of IOP is associated with corneal hysteresis (CH) measured by Ocular Response Analyzer (ORA).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Central Corneal Thickness and 24-hour Fluctuation of Intraocular Pressure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma, Open-Angle</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ocular Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Latanoprost</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and females &gt;50 years old with: Primary OpenAngle Glaucoma newly diagnosed or with antiglaucoma medical treatment &lt; =12 weeks Pseudoexfoliative Glaucoma newly diagnosed or with antiglaucoma medical treatment &lt;= 12 weeks Ocular Hypertensives newly diagnosed or with antiglaucoma medical treatment &lt;= 12 weeks Agematched controls IOP&gt;=22mmHg at the eligibility visit for glaucoma patients and ocular hypertensives For Eye Use of any ophthalmic medication (drops) during the study (except for natural tears) Inflammation of any aetiology Previous eye surgery or laser Corneal abnormalities (oedema, dystrophies etc) For Subjects Systemic diseases which affect the cornea (such as autoimmune diseases) Inability to participate due to advanced age or serious illness Mean IOP&gt;36mmHg in either eye at the eligibility visit. Subjects who cannot safety discontinue use of all IOPlowering medication(s) for washout Subjects with severe central visual field loss in either eye. Severe central visual field loss is defined as sensitivity &lt;=10dB in at least 2 of the 4 visual field test points closest to the point of fixation Other types of glaucoma (such as angleclosure glaucoma and secondary glaucomas)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Central corneal thickness</keyword>
	<keyword>24hour fluctuation of intraocular pressure</keyword>
	<keyword>Open angle glaucoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Ocular hypertension</keyword>
</DOC>