<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="25827">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02770534</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GuysThomasNHS</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02770534</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating Thromboelastography (TEG) and ETP in Sickle Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assessing the Utility of Thromboelastography (TEG) and Endogenous Thrombin Potential (ETP) in Adults With Sickle Cell Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Our primary aim in this study is to investigate the reported enhanced clotting state in
      adult patients with sickle cell disease using 2 laboratory tests; thromboelastography (TEG)
      and Endogenous Thrombin Potential (ETP), comparing the results to healthy race matched
      controls to see if there is a significant difference. Race matching of the control subjects
      is being carried out because of the well reported racial differences in coagulation
      parameters that exist in healthy individuals.

      We are aiming to study the clotting state in sickle patients on transfusion programs and
      hydroxycarbamide, both treatments offered to sickle patients to ameliorate the condition. We
      will assess the reported prothrombotic state using TEG and ETP.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      SCD is the most common inherited red cell disorder worldwide, the genetic mutation in SCD
      results in the production of abnormal haemoglobin (HbS). This leads to anaemia and
      unpredictable painful episodes referred to as a sickle cell crisis. Sickle cell crises
      result in significant chronic health problems including stroke, kidney failure, breathing
      problems, leg ulcers and chronic and ultimately leads to a decrease in life expectancy.

      The method by which sickling results in the above issues is recognised as very complex and
      it is thought these patients may have enhanced blood clotting which may play a role in the
      complications they get. Sickle cell patients are reported to have higher risk of blood clots
      such as deep vein thrombosis.

      Our primary aim in this study is to investigate the reported enhanced clotting state in
      sickle cell adult sickle cell patients using 2 laboratory tests called thromboelastography
      (TEG) and Endogenous Thrombin Potential (ETP) , we will compare the results to healthy race
      matched controls to show if there is a significant difference. We also aim to study the
      clotting state in sickle patients on a variety of treatments such as transfusion and
      hydroxycarbamide, both treatments offered to sickle patients. Many trials have shown the
      benefits of both transfusions and hydroxycarbamide in SCD, they reduce the risk of stroke
      and frequency with which patients get crises.

      To the best of our knowledge this will be the first study evaluating the clinical utility of
      TEG and ETP in adult patients with SCD

      The trial will be conducted in compliance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki
      and the principles of Good Clinical Practice. It has been submitted for approval to the
      London NHS Research Ethics Committee.

      Trial Design &amp; Flowchart This is a cross sectional case controlled clinical study in
      patients with sickle cell disease. Controls will be race and age matched participants
      without sickle cell disease. Written informed consent will be obtained from all
      participants. They will have samples taken as part of the usual clinic or inpatient
      procedure with 10 extra millilitres of blood venesected at by the phlebotomist or nurse
      scheduled to venesect them as part of their usual medical care. Healthy controls will be
      asked to provide a 10ml blood sample which will be taken by a qualified member of staff. We
      are aiming to collect samples from 100 patients in total and 20 healthy controls for
      comparison
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>results of TEG and ETP analysis:results confirming enhanced coagulation state in sickle cell patients</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
    <description>completions of analysis of all subjects and controls.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>5</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Sickle Cell Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sickle patients in steady state</arm_group_label>
    <description>Well sickle cell patients attending the outpatient clinic</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sickle cell patients admitted in crisis</arm_group_label>
    <description>Inpatients with acute vaso-occlusive crisis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sickle patients on transfusion program</arm_group_label>
    <description>Sickle patients managed on a regualar transfusion program</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sickle patients on Hydroxycarbamide</arm_group_label>
    <description>Sickle cell patients managed on hydroxycarbamide and on a stable dose for at least 3 months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Health controls</arm_group_label>
    <description>Well age and race matched individuals without a known diagnosis of sickle cell anaemia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>blood test</intervention_name>
    <description>10mls extra mls of blood taken during usual phlebotomy procedures</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sickle patients in steady state</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sickle cell patients admitted in crisis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sickle patients on transfusion program</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sickle patients on Hydroxycarbamide</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Health controls</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult sickle cell patients ( age 16+)attending registered and attending the service at
        Guys adn St Thomas Hospital.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        Patients over 16 years of age with sickle disease HbSS or HbSb0 SCD genotype must have
        been previously confirmed by high performance liquid chromatography with results on GSTT
        trust electronic patient record (EPR) All participants must be able to give written
        consent

        Exclusion Criteria:

        Any patient who is:

        Currently pregnant Has a known diagnosis with an inherited bleeding disorders e.g. von
        willebrand disease On anticoagulant therapy Has severe liver disease with liver
        transaminases greater than 5x upper limit of normal
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Beverley Hunt, FRCPath</last_name>
    <phone>020 7188 2736</phone>
    <email>Beverley.hunt@gstt.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rachel Kesse-Adu, FRCPath</last_name>
    <phone>02071882741</phone>
    <email>rachel.kesse-adu@gstt.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 10, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 10, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
