<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01163942</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to examine the effect of G-CSF on disease free survival and overall survival in aplastic anaemia patients who also receive ATG and Cyclosporin A.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Randomized Study In Severe Aplastic Anemia Patients Receiving Atg, Cyclosporin A, With Or Without G-CSF (SAA-G-CSF)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Open label, randomized, controlled study of G-CSF, ATG and Cyclosporin A versus ATG and Cyclosporin A. Subjects will be evaluated for hematologic response through day 240. Subjects who do not demonstrate a partial or complete remission by day 120 will be randomized to receive either a second course of ATG or continue their current regimen. Subjects who do demonstrate a partial or complete remission will continue their current regimen through day 240 or maintenance of a complete remission for 30 days. The last day of study treatment will be day 240.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Aplastic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenograstim</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Severe or very severe aplastic anemia Less than 6 months from diagnosis of severe aplastic anemia by bone marrow biopsy Ethical Before randomization is done the subject or legally acceptable representative must give written informed consent for participation in the study Eligibility for an HLAmatched sibling donor transplant Prior therapy with ATG Cyclosporin A &lt;4 weeks before enrollment Treatment with GCSF &lt;2 weeks before enrollment Other growth factors &lt;4 weeks before enrollment Diagnosis of Fanconi anemia, dyskeratosis congenita or congenital bone marrow failure syndrome Evidence of myelodysplastic disease Diagnosis or previous history of carcinoma (except local cervical, basal cell, squamous cells, or melanoma) Subjects who have infection, hepatic, renal cardiac, metabolic or other concurrent diseases of such severity that death is imminent Subject is pregnant (e.g. positive HCG test) or is breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>