<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01163188</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The major aim is the follow-up of the highest risk group (&lt; 32 weeks gestation/ &lt; 1500 birthweight) and their controls of the Bavarian Longitudinal Study (BLS) at the age of 24-27 years. The focus will be the identification of risk, protective and resiliency factors for cognitive and behavioural development and quality of life. MRIs of the central nervous system will be conducted to examine aberrant activation patterns during the "attention network task" in stratified subgroups. Data driven MRI methods will be evaluated in relation to clinical, behavioural and developmental parameters.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Social Adjustment and Quality of Life After Very Preterm Birth</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The major aim is the follow-up of the highest risk group (&lt; 32 weeks gestation/ &lt; 1500 birthweight) and their controls of the Bavarian Longitudinal Study (BLS) at the age of 24-27 years. All probands have been assessed previously, neonatally and at additional six time points, the last time at the age of 12-13 years. The focus will be the identification of risk, protective and resiliency factors for cognitive and behavioural development and quality of life. On the basis of previously assessed data statistical modelling of child development until age 8.5 years will be conducted across the total range of gestation from 26-42 weeks to identify social factors amenable to intervention which could be associated with a positive development especially in moderate prematurity. In addition, cross-validation of the findings is planned by means of comparisons with three international studies (Millenium Cohort, GB; POPS, NL; EPICure, GB). MRIs of the central nervous system will be conducted to examine aberrant activation patterns during the "attention network task" in stratified subgroups. Data driven MRI methods will be evaluated in relation to clinical, behavioural and developmental parameters. In line with the objectives of funding there will be a further follow-up of the BLS to answer important questions regarding health and development of very small preterms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Birth Weight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
	<criteria>very low birth weight VLBW (&lt; 1500g birthweight)and/ or very preterm birth VPT (&lt; 32 weeks of gestation) Members of the Bavarian Longitudinal Study missing compliance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>24 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>28 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>very low birthweight/ very preterm children</keyword>
	<keyword>Bavarian Longitudinal Study (BLS)</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of life and social adjustment in adulthood</keyword>
</DOC>