<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01948960</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A study to determine whether everolimus pharmacokinetics in elderly and obese patients is different compared to control patients. Furthermore the investigators will investigate the relation between metabolic response assessed with [18F] Fluorodeoxyglucose-Positron Emission Tomography (FDG-PET) and everolimus exposure and clinical benefit. The investigators will explore whether dose escalation in patients who are hypothetically underexposed will result in an increase in metabolic response.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Influence of Exceptional Patient Characteristics on Everolimus Exposure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult women (≥ 18 years of age) with metastatic or locally advanced breast cancer not amenable to curative treatment by surgery or radiotherapy. Histological or cytological confirmation of estrogenreceptor positive (ER+) breast cancer Postmenopausal women Radiological or clinical evidence of recurrence or progression on last systemic therapy prior to enrollment. Progression following a nonsteroidal aromatase inhibitor Falling into one of the following categories elderly patients (age ≥ 70 years and BMI &lt; 30 kg/m2); or obese patients (BMI ≥ 30 kg/m2 and age &lt; 70 years); or control patients (BMI &lt; 30 kg/m2 and age &lt; 70 years); Serum aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤ 5 x ULN Adequate renal function: calculated creatinine clearance, as estimated by GFR using the MDRD formula, is ≥ 30ml/min/1.73m2 Performance status ECOG 0 2 (Karnofsky index: 60 100) Patient is willing and able to sign the Informed Consent Form prior to screening evaluations Patients aged ≥ 70 years AND BMI ≥ 30 kg/m2 HER2overexpressing patients by local laboratory testing (IHC 3+ staining or in situ hybridization positive). Previous treatment with exemestane or mTOR inhibitors. Except for the treatment with exemestane in the adjuvant setting. Known hypersensitivity to mTOR inhibitors, e.g. sirolimus (rapamycin). Patients with a known history of HIV seropositivity. Any severe and / or uncontrolled medical conditions such as: Unstable angina pectoris, serious uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmia Patients with severe hepatic impairment (ChildPugh A/B/C) Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus Impairment of gastrointestinal function or gastrointestinal disease that may significantly alter the absorption of study drugs (e.g., ulcerative disease, uncontrolled nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, malabsorption syndrome) Patients who test positive for hepatitis B or C Patients being treated with drugs recognized as being strong inhibitors or inducers of the isoenzyme CYP3A within the last 5 days prior to enrollment History of noncompliance to medical regimens Patients unwilling to or unable to comply with the protocol</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>everolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>elderly patients</keyword>
	<keyword>obese patients</keyword>
</DOC>