<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT02570763</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>The current study aim examine safety feasibility utilize tDCS enhance affect-laden episodic memory consolidation among adult co-occurring alcohol use anxiety disorder recently undergone detoxification step toward translational clinical application approach .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combining Non-Invasive Brain Stimulation With Cognitive Behavioral Intervention Substance Use Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>DSM IV diagnosis panic disorder ( without agoraphobia ) , generalize anxiety disorder , social anxiety disorder within past 30 day DSM IV diagnosis alcohol dependence within last 30 day inpatient treatment Lodging Plus primarily alcohol ( vs. drug ) dependence alcohol use 30 day precede study willingness provide inform consent minimum sixth grade English reading level ( deem necessary complete study material ) ; determine able read understand consent form . Living within reasonable drive distance ( 1 hour less ) Twin Cities allow inperson followup interview lifetime history psychosis mania history . cognitive ( e.g. , dementia ) physical impairment ( e.g. , blindness ) interfere study participation report judge PI/study physician . Current suicide risk deem PI study physician serious ongoing medical condition treatment neurological sequela ( e.g. , stroke , tumor , loss consciousness 30 minute , HIV , seizures ) history ECT document loss consciousness ( LOC ) longer 30 minute LOC neurological sequela pregnancy Although seizure know risk tDCS intervention ( Fregni et al. , 2006 ; Nitsche et al. , 2008 ) , anyone history risk seizure exclude study anyone metal object implant head neck anyone take stimulant medication reason wish avoid two sorces neurostimulation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>neurostimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>comorbidity</keyword>
	<keyword>tDCS</keyword>
	<keyword>CBT</keyword>
	<keyword>anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>alcohol</keyword>
</DOC>