<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01204177</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study investigates the safety and efficacy of the combination therapy with BAY86-9766 and sorafenib in patients with liver cancer. Safety will be determined by laboratory and other evaluations. Efficacy of the combination BAY86-9766 and sorafenib will be determined by disease control rate, overall survival, time to progression, response rate and duration of response.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessing BAY86-9766 Plus Sorafenib for the Treatment of Liver Cancer.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Niacinamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or Female age &gt;/= 18 years of age Life expectancy &gt;/= 12 weeks Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of HCC, unresectable advanced or metastatic Liver function status of ChildPugh class A. ChildPugh status based on clinical findings and laboratory results during the screening period Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status (ECOG PS) of 0 or 1 Patients must have at least one naïve (not previously treated by locoregional therapy) unidimensional measurable lesion by CT or MRI according to RECIST 1.1 Adequate bone marrow, liver and renal function Previous or concurrent cancer other than HCC, except for cervical carcinoma in situ, basal cell carcinoma, superficial bladder tumors. History of cardiac disease: Congestive heart failure (CHF), unstable angina, arrhythmias, Uncontrolled hypertension Clinically significant GI bleeding (CTCAE grade 3 or higher) within 30 days Renal failure requiring hemo or peritoneal dialysis Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection Known history or symptomatic metastatic brain or meningeal tumors History of organ allograft. History of interstitial lung disease (ILD). Excluded previous therapies and medications: Prior use of systemic anticancer treatment for HCC including cytotoxic chemotherapy, targeted agents, or any experimental therapy Radiotherapy within 4 weeks prior to start of study treatment Any other investigational agents within 4 weeks from the first dose of study treatment Major surgery within 4 weeks of start of study Concomitant use of strong inhibitors and strong inducers of CYP3A4</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC)</keyword>
	<keyword>MEK inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Sorafenib</keyword>
	<keyword>Disease control rate (DCR)</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
</DOC>