<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01204047</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The specific aims of this study are: 1) to assess the test-retest reliability of a modification of an existing wheelchair propulsion assessment and 2) validate the modification against traditional measures of physical strength, power, and endurance in a group of persons with spinal cord injury (SCI).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Wheelchair Mobility Assessment of Individuals With Spinal Cord Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The ability to independently self-propel and transfer oneself is a crucial component of daily life for individuals with a spinal cord injury. This ability is related in part to an individual's strength, power, and endurance, but it is unknown which of these measures is most important to achieve a high level of wheelchair function. Identification of which physical performance parameters are best related to wheeled mobility performance is essential in developing interventions to improve said performance. Currently, clinic-friendly assessments of a person's wheeled mobility ability do not exist. We have developed a modified, clinic-friendly version of validated wheelchair mobility assessment that can be completed in most clinics. Before it can be implemented by clinicians its reliability must be established. Crossvalidating it against standard measures of physical performance will allow for the identification of the most appropriate exercise interventions to improve independent wheeled mobility.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinal Cord Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Spinal Cord Injury American Spinal Injury Association Impairment Scale (AIS) AD Selfreported ability to selfpropel themselves in a manual wheelchair Age 18 or older surgery within 6 months pressure ulcer within 3 months upper limb pain that limits completion of exercise recurrent acute infection or illness requiring hospitalization or IV antibiotics pregnancy previous myocardial infarction or cardiac surgery</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>