<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02468869</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of the proposed study is to assess the potential of information structuring for improving discharge communication. Specifically, the investigators aim to examine the advantages of an information-structuring skills training for physicians (compared to an emotion skills training) on discharge communication and associated patient outcomes, such as patients' information recall and adherence to physician recommendations. The investigators hypothesize that patients receiving structured discharge information from their trained physicians will be able to recall more information and show higher adherence to recommendations relative to controls (i.e., patients receiving discharge information from doctors trained in emotion-handling skills).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Discharge Communication</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>patients with chest pain patients with abdominal pain We will use the following exclusion criteria concerning patients with chest pain: Patients younger than 18 years of age will not be recruited because of limited ability to provide informed consent. Patients with limited ability to communicate in German (the default language at the hospital) will not be recruited to exclude additional confounds related to language proficiency. Patients with dementia will not be recruited to avoid additional confounds arising from pathological memory deficits. Patients with increased troponin level, an indicator of myocardial infarction, will not be recruited to minimize stress on these more vulnerable patients. Patients with none of five cardiovascular risk factors (cvRF; smoking history, diabetes, hypertension, dyslipidemia, age above 50 years, or family history of coronary heart disease) will not be recruited because chest pain symptoms in such patients are typically indicative of diagnoses unrelated to coronary heart disease, requiring a very different followup and health management recommendations (e.g., in the case of an anxiety disorder). We will use the following exclusion criteria concerning patients with abdominal pain: Patients younger than 18 years of age will not be recruited because of limited ability to provide informed consent. Patients with limited ability to communicate in German (the default language at the hospital) will not be recruited to exclude additional confounds related to language proficiency. Patients with dementia will not be recruited to avoid additional confounds arising from pathological memory deficits.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>recall</keyword>
	<keyword>discharge communication</keyword>
</DOC>