<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02468388</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the clinical effect of chewing gum containing maltitol, on re-mineralization of early caries following daily chewing for 6 months by school children, compared to a xylitol gum, gum base and a no gum group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Re-mineralization Effects of Sugar Free Chewing Gum Sweetened With Different Sugar-substitutes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Calcinosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Consent Informed Consent Form signed by parent or legal guardian permitting participation of their children. Be cooperative and able to be examined in the whole study duration. Aged from 8 to 13 years. General Health: Good general health (in the opinion of the investigator) without clinically significant and relevant abnormalities of medical history such as diabetic, etc. Oral Health: Display 6 permanent front teeth and two maxillary buccal surfaces with visual evidence of active initial enamel carious lesions (demineralized but not cavitated); No any form of intraoral prostheses or appliances, clinical signs of severe gingivitis or periodontitis, temporomandibular joint disorders, and malocclusions or chronic onychophagia Oral Hygiene: have good oral health habits, brushing teeth at least once per day No medical or pharmacotherapy history that might affect the outcomes of the study, e.g. use of mouthwash, gels, or chewing gum containing antimicrobial agents during the previous 3 months Disease: Presence of chronic debilitating disease, or any condition or other chronic disease which the investigators think not suitable for the study. Allergy/Intolerance: Be allergic to both maltitol and xylitol, oral care products, personal care consumer products, or their ingredients. Current Product Use: usual chewinggum (of any kind) consumer or sugarsfree candies consumer Clinical Study/Experiment: Participation in another clinical study or receipt of an investigational drug within 30 days of the screening visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>13 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>maltitol</keyword>
	<keyword>xylitol</keyword>
	<keyword>quantitative light-induced fluorescence</keyword>
	<keyword>saliva pH</keyword>
	<keyword>re-mineralization</keyword>
	<keyword>dental caries</keyword>
</DOC>