<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00984048</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicenter translational study to understand therapeutic resistance in patients undergoing first-line chemotherapy (FOLFOX/Avastin, or FOLFIRI/Avastin) for metastatic colorectal cancer. Tissue samples from liver metastasis will be collected and banked before the start of chemotherapy and at the time of progression. Additionally, blood samples will be drawn monthly and stored in the tissue biobank.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Identify Mechanisms of Resistance to Standard Therapy in Patients With Metastatic Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The major obstacle to the cure of cancer by pharmacological agents is resistance to these agents. Clinical responses of metastatic cancers to the most advanced chemotherapeutic agents usually range from 15 to 40%, indicating that intrinsic resistance, and acquired resistance occurs almost inevitably in those tumors that do respond. In patients with metastatic colorectal cancer, clinical resistance to a particular treatment is a clear endpoint (tumor growth), and is usually observed within 6-12 months of any given therapy. Thus, drug resistance and selecting appropriate therapeutic alternatives for drug-resistant cancer remain major dilemmas for oncologists. The current first-line treatment for metastatic colorectal cancer in Quebec and much of North America is a combination called FOLFOX (the fluoro-pyrimidine 5-FU given as a 46-hour infusion, folinic acid and oxaliplatin) in combination with bevacizumab (Avastin®). An alternative regimen of cytotoxic drugs, also used with Avastin®, is FOLFIRI, which simply replaces oxaliplatin with the topoisomerase inhibitor irinotecan. In the metastatic setting, studies have not demonstrated significant differences between the two regimens, such that decision-making lacks definitive tools. The objective of this study is to identify, in clinical samples, the molecular signature of clinically resistant colorectal cancer (CRC) patients for the most current and commonly used therapeutic agents. The goals of this study are two-fold. First, to build a biobank of blood and tissue specimens, prior to starting chemotherapy and at a determined time-point (progression of disease), from patients undergoing the same standard and well established first-line treatments (FOLFOX/bevacizumab or FOLFIRI/bevacizumab) for metastatic colorectal cancer. Second, to use state-of-the-art approaches by various collaborating laboratories to correlate clinical outcomes with molecular events that can be used to predict and circumscribe chemoresistance.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients with a histologically confirmed diagnosis of colorectal cancer, with at least one liver metastasis site available for biopsy. 2. For patients with liver only disease, patients deemed not to be initially resectable 3. Scheduled to receive firstline chemotherapy (FOLFOX/bevacizumab or FOLFIRI/bevacizumab) for metastatic disease. 4. Measurable metastatic disease (at least one unidimensionally measurable lesion) present after planned biopsy of metastatic site(s). 5. ECOG 0, 1 or 2. 6. Life expectancy of 12 or more weeks. 7. Age &gt; 18 years. 8. Able to adhere to the study visit schedule and other protocol requirements. 9. Normal coagulation profile (PT, PTT, INR). 1. Patients with initially resectable liver only metastases 2. Have received prior therapy for metastatic cancer. Prior adjuvant therapy is allowed. 3. Inadequate or unusable tissue as the only tissue available for biopsy. 4. Contraindication to any of the components of the the firstline chemotherapy regimen. 5. Known brain metastases or meningeal disease. 6. Female patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding. 7. Concurrent treatment with other anticancer therapy (palliative radiation is allowed but patients must have a metastatic site available for rebiopsy that has not been irradiated). 8. Abnormal coagulation profile, any anticoagulant therapy. 9. Known infection with HIV.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Colorectal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>FOLFOX</keyword>
	<keyword>FOLFIRI</keyword>
	<keyword>Avastin</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastases</keyword>
	<keyword>Liver</keyword>
	<keyword>Colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
	<keyword>Resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>Biobanking</keyword>
	<keyword>Colorectal cancer with unresectable metastases to the liver</keyword>
</DOC>