<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00984763</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Malaria is a parasite, infection with which kills over 2 million people each year. It is a major problem for those who live in endemic areas and for travellers. There is a great need for a safe effective malaria vaccine. The purpose of this study is to examine a new vaccine designed to provide immunity during the blood stage of the malaria parasite's lifecycle. The vaccine consists of AMA1-C1 which is a mixture of two recombinant synthetic AMA1 proteins from two Plasmodium falciparum strains, Alhydrogel® which is an aluminium-based adjuvant and CPG 7909 - an oligodeoxynucleotide, which enhances immune response. This study will enable the investigators to assess: 1. The ability of of a growth inhibition assay to predict the effectiveness of a malaria vaccine. 2. The safety of the vaccine in healthy volunteers 3. The response of the human immune system to the vaccine</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess Safety, Immunogenicity and Parasite Growth Inhibition of an Asexual Blood Stage Vaccine for P. Falciparum Malaria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malaria, Falciparum</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aluminum Hydroxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is willing and able to give informed consent for participation in the study Healthy, non pregnant adult aged 18 50 years Resident in or near Oxford for the duration of the challenge study Seropositive for CMV and EBV Female subjects of child bearing potential must be willing to ensure that they practice effective contraception during the study Males must be willing to use barrier contraception from day of first vaccination onwards until 3 months after the second vaccination Able (in the Investigator's opinion) and willing to comply with all study requirements Willing to allow his or her General Practitioner and consultant, if appropriate, to be notified of participation in the study Agreement to permanently refrain from blood donation. Any deviation from the normal range in biochemistry or haematology blood tests or in urine analysis as defined in Appendix B Female patient/subject who is pregnant, lactating or planning pregnancy during the course of the study Healthy volunteers who have participated in another research study involving an investigational product in the past 12 weeks Subjects who have previously received an investigational malaria vaccine History of malaria chemoprophylaxis with chloroquine within 5 months prior to the planned challenge, with Lariam within 6 weeks prior to the challenge, and Riamet® within 2 weeks prior to the challenge Travel to a malaria endemic area within the previous 6 months Planned travel to malarious areas during the study period Any history of malaria Contraindication to both antimalarial drugs (Riamet® and chloroquine) concomitant use of other drugs known to cause QTinterval prolongation, ( e.g. macrolides, quinolones, amiodarone etc) An estimated ten year risk of fatal cardiovascular disease of ≥5%, as estimated by the Systematic Coronary Risk Evaluation (SCORE) system (Conroy 2003) Family history of sudden cardiac death History of cardiac arrhythmia or prolonged QT syndrome Any history of severe allergic reaction or anaphylaxis History of a known allergy to nickel Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient state, including HIV infection; asplenia; recurrent severe infections and chronic (more than 14 days) immunosuppressant medication within the past 6 months History or evidence of preexisting autoimmune or antibody mediated disease or laboratory evidence of possible autoimmune disease (defined as antidsDNA ≥ 25 IU/mL) Seropositive for hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) or antibodies to hepatitis C virus Any ongoing chronic illness requiring hospital specialist supervision Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within the three months preceding the planned administration of the vaccine candidate History of or current intravenous drug abuse Suspected or known current alcohol abuse as defined by an alcohol intake of greater than 42 units every week Any other significant disease or disorder which, in the opinion of the Investigator, may either put the subject at risk because of participation in the study, or may influence the result of the study, or the subject's ability to participate in the study. Investigator assessment of lack of willingness to participate and comply with all requirements of the protocol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Malaria</keyword>
	<keyword>Vaccine</keyword>
</DOC>