<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00197925</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study aim to show if vaccination with autologous dendritic cells pulsed with onco-peptides in combination with adjuvant cytokine can induce a measurable immune response in patients with metastatic breast cancer, and to evaluate the clinical effect (objective response rate) of the vaccination regime.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dendritic Cell Based Therapy of Metastatic Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>HLA A2 positive patients are treated with PADRE and oncopeptide pulsed DC; p53, survivin and telomerase peptides. Each patient is given 6 immunizations with at least 5x106 peptide/lysate pulsed autologous DC. Vaccination 1-4 is given weekly and 4-6 at 2-week intervals. Those patients who exhibit stable disease, partial response or complete response after 6 injections will be given 4 more vaccinations at 2-week interval. The vaccine is applied by either intranodal or intradermal injection near the inguinal region. For adjuvant used IL-2 2 MIU sc. day 2-6. Scans and re-staging tests are performed at scheduled intervals throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically proven progressive metastatic or locally advanced breast cancer No standard treatment indicated Age: &gt; 18 WHOPerformance Status 01 At least tone measurable tumor lesions according to the RECIST criteria. Expression of the HLAA2 tissue type Life expectancy more than 3 months Acceptable CBC and blood chemistry results Written informed consent Patients with a history of any other neoplastic disease less than 5 years ago (excepting treated carcinomas in situ of the cervix and basal/squamous cell carcinomas of the skin). Patients with metastatic disease in the central nervous system (CNS). Patients with other significant illness including severe allergy, asthma, angina pectoris or congestive heart failure. Patients with acute or chronic infection including HIV, hepatitis and tuberculosis. Patients who are pregnant. Patients who have received antineoplastic therapy including chemotherapy or immunotherapy less than 4 weeks before beginning the trial. Patients who receive corticosteroids or other immunosuppressive agents. Patients with active autoimmune diseases such as lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis or thyroiditis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>dendritic cells</keyword>
	<keyword>vaccine</keyword>
</DOC>