<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02963129</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Compare the frequency of epistaxis and quality of life related to nasal bleeding in patients with HHT colonized with sataphylococo before and after being treated with mupirocin ointment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Nasal Staphylococcus Aureus Colonization in Patients With HHT</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Hereditary hemorrhagic telangiectasia is a vascular dysplasia characterized by the development of mucocutaneous telangiectasia and arteriovenous malformations in organs such as brain, lung, liver and tube digestivo. Is considered a rare disease, although It means that there is a substantial underdiagnosis. The overall prevalence is 1/5000. Approximately 60% of the general population hosts strains of Staphylococcus aureus (S. aureus) intermittently and are called intermittent carriers, 20% represent persistent carriers harboring the same strain of S. aureus and 20% of the population are never carriers. On this concept, one might think that HHT patients in whom there is an active and pathological vascular remodeling that causes bleeding, and inflammation is a known activator of abnormal angiogenesis; reducing an inflammatory factor as microbial through the eradication of nasal S. aureus could be useful to reduce bleeding in this population, directly impacting on quality of life.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Telangiectasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epistaxis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Telangiectasia, Hereditary Hemorrhagic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mupirocin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients over 18 years with possible or confirmed HHT as diagnostic criteria Curaçao. Patients with nasal S. aureus colonization culture positive Refusal to participate in the study or the informed consent process. Hypersensitivity or contraindication for topical mupirocin.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hereditary Hemorrhagic Telangiectasia</keyword>
	<keyword>Epistaxis</keyword>
</DOC>