<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02963311</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety, tolerability, and efficacy of ALN-PCSSC in participants with homozygous familial hypercholesterolemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of ALN-PCSSC in Participants With Homozygous Familial Hypercholesterolemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypercholesterolemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperlipoproteinemia Type II</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and females, ≥12 years of age with a diagnosis of homozygous familial hypercholesterolemia by genetic confirmation or a clinical diagnosis based on a history of an untreated lowdensity lipoprotein cholesterol (LDLC) concentration &gt;500 milligrams/deciliter (mg/dL) [13 millimoles/liter (mmol/L)] together with either xanthoma before 10 years of age or evidence of heterozygous familial hypercholesterolemia in both parents. Stable on a lowfat diet. Stable on preexisting, lipidlowering therapies (such as statins, cholesterolabsorption inhibitors, bileacid sequestrants, or combinations thereof) for at least 4 weeks with no planned medication or dose change for the duration of study participation. Fasting central lab LDLC concentration &gt;130 mg/dL (3.4 mmol/L) and triglyceride concentration &lt;400 mg/dL (4.5 mmol/L). Body weight of 40 kilograms (kg) or greater at screening. Should be willing and able to give written informed consent before initiation of any studyrelated procedures (if the participant is less than 18 years of age, written consent will be obtained from their guardian or legally authorized representative, with verbal assent from the child). Should be willing to comply with all required study procedures. LDL or plasma apheresis within 8 weeks prior to the screening visit, and no plan to receive it during the study because of the attendant difficulty in maintaining stable concentrations of LDLC while receiving apheresis. Use of mipomersen or lomitapide therapy within 5 months of screening. Previous treatment with monoclonal antibodies directed towards PCSK9 within 8 weeks of screening. New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III or IV heart failure or last known left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;30% or any cardiac arrhythmia within past 3 months that is not controlled by medication. Myocardial infarction, unstable angina, percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI), coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) or stroke within 3 months of enrollment. Planned cardiac surgery or revascularization. Uncontrolled severe hypertension, defined as systolic blood pressure &gt;180 millimeters of mercury (mmHg) or diastolic blood pressure &gt;110 mmHg prior to enrollment despite antihypertensive therapy. Poorly controlled diabetes mellitus, that is, glycated hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) &gt;10.0% prior to enrollment. Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt;30 ml/minute/1.73 meters^2. Active liver disease defined as any known current infectious, neoplastic, or metabolic pathology of the liver or unexplained alanine aminotransferase (ALT), aspartate aminotransferase (AST), elevation &gt;3 times the upper limit of normal (ULN), at screening confirmed by a repeat measurement at least 1 week apart. Creatine kinase (CK) &gt;5 times ULN without a known cause. Other serious comorbid disease in which the life expectancy of the participant is shorter than the duration of the trial (for example, acute systemic infection, or other serious illnesses). Any history of malignant disease, with the exception of treated basalcell carcinoma occurring &gt;5 years before screening. Females who are pregnant or nursing, or who are of childbearing potential (includes adolescent females who have reached menarche and are sexually active) and unwilling to use at least two methods of contraception (for example, oral contraceptives, barrier methods, approved contraceptive implant, long term injectable contraception, and intrauterine device) for the entire duration of the study. Exemptions from this criterion are as follows: 1. Women &gt;2 years postmenopausal (defined as 1 year or longer since their last menstrual period) and more than 55 years of age 2. Postmenopausal women (as defined above) and less than 55 years old with a negative pregnancy test within 24 hours of enrollment 3. Women who have been surgically sterilized at least 3 months prior to enrollment 4. Adolescent females who have not reached menarche Males who are unwilling to use an acceptable method of birth control (for example, condom with spermicide) during the entire study period. Known history of alcohol and/or drug abuse within 5 years. Any condition that according to the investigator could interfere with the conduct of the study, such as but not limited to the following: 1. Inappropriate for this study, including participants who are unable to communicate or to cooperate with the investigator. 2. Unable to understand the protocol requirements, instructions, and studyrelated restrictions and the nature, scope, and possible consequences of the study (including participants whose cooperation is doubtful due to drug abuse or alcohol dependency). 3. Unlikely to comply with the protocol requirements, instructions, and studyrelated restrictions (for example, uncooperative attitude, inability to return for followup visits, and improbability of completing the study). 4. Have any medical or surgical condition that in the opinion of the investigator would put the participant at increased risk from participating in the study. 5. Involved with, or a relative of, someone directly involved in the conduct of the study. Any clinically significant disease or condition affecting a major organ system, including but not limited to gastrointestinal, renal, hepatic, endocrinologic, pulmonary, neurological, metabolic, or cardiovascular disease. Any surgical or medical condition that in the judgment of the Investigator, might interfere with the pharmacokinetics, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of the study drug (if applicable). Treatment with other investigational medicinal products or devices within 30 days or 5 halflives, whichever is longer, prior to the administration of the study drug/device or planned use of investigational medicinal products or devices. Previous participation in this study or any preceding study with ALNPCSSC. Hypersensitivity to any of the ingredients of the study drug being used.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>