<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02963584</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to assess the feasibility and validity of patient-level randomization (vs. cluster randomization) in pilot trials of decision aid efficacy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Decision Aid in Chronic Total Occlusion (CTO) Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a parallel, 2-arm, randomized trial to compare an intervention group receiving CTO Choice (decision aid) to a control group receiving usual primary care. 100 patients and 60 cardiologists will be randomize by computer. The investigators will measure the effect of CTO Choice on five outcomes: (a) patient knowledge regarding CTO of PCI or medication (risk and benefit); (b) quality of the decision making process for both the patient and clinician; (c) patient and clinician acceptability and satisfaction with the decision aid; (d) rate of percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) or medication; and (e) trial processes (e.g., ability to recruit participants, collect patient outcomes). To capture these outcomes, the investigators will use patient and clinician surveys following each visit and video recordings of the clinical encounters. These video recordings will also allow us to determine the extent to which clinicians exposed to the decision aid were able to recreate elements of the decision aid which control patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Occlusion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient: 1. At least one lesion occluding the coronary artery detected by angiography or MSCTA. 2. left ventricular ejection fraction ≥ 40% on transthoracic echocardiography measurement. 3. No major barriers to provide written consent. 1. Severe coexisting conditions, such as severe renal insufficiency (GFR &lt; 30 ml/min•1.73m2), severe hepatic dysfunction [elevated glutamicpyruvic transaminase or glutamicoxal acetic transaminase level by more than threefold of the normal limitation], acute or chronic heart failure (NYHA IIIIV), acute infectious diseases, immune disorders, malignancy, etc. 2. Patients with cognitive impairment, severe hearing loss, or visual impairment who could not complete the survey. Cardiologist: 1. Doctors who work in the department of Cardiology for more than 1 years. 2. No major barriers to provide written consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>chronic total occlusion</keyword>
	<keyword>decision aid</keyword>
</DOC>