<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01750086</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to assess the relative antiresorptive properties of 2 osteoporosis medications when combined with teriparatide.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acute Effect of Teriparatide With Bisphosphonate or Denosumab on Bone Resorption</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis, Postmenopausal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bone Resorption</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Denosumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alendronate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diphosphonates</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Teriparatide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Must satisfy A and B and C below: A. Women aged 45+ B. Postmenopausal C. Osteoporotic with high risk of fracture History of significant hepatic, renal, cardiovascular, malignant disease, or conditions with impaired immune system Current alcohol or substance abuse Major psychiatric disorders Abnormal calcium level, elevated PTH, vitamin D deficiency, or anemia Known congenital or acquired bone disease other than osteoporosis Current use or past use in the past 12 months of oral bisphosphonates Current use or use in the past 3 months of estrogens, selective estrogen receptor modulators, or calcitonin Use of oral or parenteral glucocorticoids for more than 14 days in the past 6 months Any current or previous use of strontium or intravenous bisphosphonates Sensitivity to cellderived drug products or teriparatide Extensive dental work involving dental extraction or dental implant within the past 2 months or in the upcoming 2 months Inability to sit upright for 30 minutes Esophageal abnormalities</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>osteoporosis</keyword>
	<keyword>postmenopausal</keyword>
	<keyword>denosumab</keyword>
	<keyword>teriparatide</keyword>
	<keyword>alendronate</keyword>
	<keyword>Forteo®</keyword>
	<keyword>Prolia®</keyword>
</DOC>