<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02716077</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Adult patients with histologically proven melanoma who will be treated with pembrolizumab will undergo FDG PET/CT scan as an early evaluation of response to therapy. Changes in FDG uptake will be correlated with lab and pathology results.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Early FDG PET in Melanoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients, at least 18 years of age History of histologically confirmed melanoma as assessed per medical record review. Eligible for the trial UPCC #01615, "A Phase Ib Tissue Collection Study of Pembrolizumab (MK3475) in Subjects with Resectable Advanced Melanoma." Participants must be informed of the investigational nature of this study and provide written informed consent in accordance with institutional and federal guidelines prior to studyspecific procedures. Females who are pregnant or breastfeeding at the time of screening will not be eligible for this study. Female participants of childbearing potential will have a urine or serum pregnancy test at the time of the screening visit. Inability to tolerate imaging procedures in the opinion of the investigator or treating physician. Serious or unstable medical or psychological conditions that, in the opinion of the investigator would compromise the subject's safety or successful participation in the study. Ineligible for the trial UPCC #01615, "A Phase Ib Tissue Collection Study of Pembrolizumab (MK3475) in Subjects with Resectable Advanced Melanoma." Only individuals (aged 18 or over) who can understand and give informed consent will be eligible to participate in this study. Individuals who are considered to be mentally disabled will not be recruited for this study. All subjects must be able to give informed consent. We will not be using specific methods to assess decisional capacity. Economically disadvantaged persons will not be vulnerable to undue influence, as this study offers no compensation. All individuals will be told that their choice regarding study participation will in no way change their access to clinical care. This should negate any undue influence or coercion. Children, fetuses, neonates, or prisoners are not included in this research study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>