<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02716285</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Peppermint oil has shown to be effective in the treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) symptoms in several meta-analyses. However, the level of evidence is moderate and peppermint oil remains relatively under-used in IBS. Therefore, the investigators will conduct a multicenter randomized, placebo controlled trial to investigate the effects of an eight-week peppermint oil treatment in IBS patients according to current European Medicines Agency (EMA) / US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) guidelines. To improve efficacy and to reduce side effects, the investigators aim to study the use of a new peppermint oil formulation, a colon-targeted-delivery capsule that will release the oil in the (ileo-) colonic region specifically.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Peppermint Oil for the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome: Optimizing Therapeutic Strategies Using Targeted Delivery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abdominal Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colonic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colonic Diseases, Functional</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peppermint oil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age between 18 and 75 years; 2. Diagnosed with Irritable Bowel Syndrome according to the Rome III criteria: (Recurrent abdominal pain or discomfort, at least 3 days/month for the last 3 months; Symptom onset at least 6 months prior to diagnosis; Associated with two or more of the following: 1. Improvement with defecation; 2. Onset associated with a change in frequency of stool; 3. Onset associated with a change in form (appearance/consistency) of stool.) 3. Based on the medical history and previous examination, no other causes for the abdominal complaints can be defined. Especially no history of: 1. Inflammatory Bowel Disease; 2. Celiac Disease; 3. Thyroid dysfunction (if not wellregulated). If alarm symptoms (including unexplained rectal blood loss or weight loss) are present, a colonoscopy has been performed and was negative for other causes. 4. Women in fertile age (&lt;55 years old) must use contraception or be postmenopausal for at least two years. 5. Average worst abdominal pain score (on 11point NRS) of &gt; 3, during the twoweek runin period. 1. Insufficient fluency of the Dutch language; 2. Any previous use (also incidental use) of peppermint oil capsules in the last 3 months prior to inclusion (the use of peppermint tea, menthol candy etc. is allowed); 3. The inability to stop regular use of medication affecting the gastrointestinal system (such as Non Steroidal Anti Inflammatory Drugs (NSAID), laxatives, prokinetics, opioids, smasmolytics and antidiarrhoeal drugs). This use should be halted at least 1 week before enrollment into the runin period; 1. The use of 1 antidepressant drug is allowed, providing dosing has been stable for &gt; 6 weeks before enrollment; 2. The use of 1 proton pump inhibitor (PPI) is allowed, providing dosing has been stable &gt; 6 weeks before enrollment; 4. Previous major abdominal surgery or radiotherapy interfering with gastrointestinal function: 1. Uncomplicated appendectomy, cholecystectomy and hysterectomy allowed unless within the past 6 months; 2. Other surgery upon judgment of the principle investigator; 5. History of liver disease, cholangitis, achlorhydria, gallstones or other diseases of the gallbladder/biliary system; 6. Pregnancy, lactation; 7. Using drugs of abuse; 8. Known allergic reaction to peppermint.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Abdominal pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Targeted Delivery</keyword>
	<keyword>Peppermint oil</keyword>
</DOC>