<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00017706</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized clinical trial will determine the efficacy of physicians providing weight control advice to their overweight and obese patients in primary care practice.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Primary Care Physicians in Delivering Weight Control Counseling</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Enrolled physicians are randomly assigned to receive brief training in either: 1) behavioral weight control intervention or 2) obesity education. Enrolled patients are asked to see their physician for 2 weight control consultations during the year to discuss their weight and physical activity. Regardless of the training the physician receives, the weight control advice is tailored to the individual patient. Patients include men and women between the ages of 21 - 70 years, with a Body-Mass Index of 27 or greater, and they have met medical and other study eligibility criteria in order to safely participate. As a participant in the trial, all patients are asked to attend an initial baseline assessment, and two follow-up assessments; 3 and 12 months after their first weight control consultation visit with their physician in order to evaluate any changes in their weight, waist circumference, physical activity, eating patterns, and mood. The findings of this important study will shed light upon the role physician advice may have in helping overweight and obese patients lose weight and become more physically active.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>BodyMass Index greater than or equal to 27 Able to walk without assistance No untreated hypothyroidism or Cushing Disease No unstable medical or psychiatric condition No signs or symptoms of cardiovascular disease No history of gallstones No terminal illness No other acute or chronic medical condition in which weight loss is contraindicated Medically cleared for physical activity Pregnant, nursing or planning to become pregnant in the next year Had an inpatient hospital stay in the last 3 months Lost more than 10 lbs in the last 4 months Taking an OTC or prescribed medication for weight loss In treatment for an eating disorder In treatment for depression (if patient is on an antidepressant and has not had a recent episode of depression in the past 3 months then he/she is eligible)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>physician education</keyword>
	<keyword>behavioral weight control</keyword>
	<keyword>physician intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>obesity counseling</keyword>
</DOC>