<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00017030</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of ecteinascidin 743 in treating patients who have unresectable advanced or metastatic soft tissue sarcoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ecteinascidin 743 in Treating Patients With Unresectable Advanced or Metastatic Soft Tissue Sarcoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the rate of clinical benefit, in terms of the incidence of objective partial and complete response, stable disease, or minor response of more than 3 months duration, in patients with previously treated, unresectable advanced or metastatic soft tissue sarcoma treated with ecteinascidin 743. II. Determine the progression-free survival, overall survival, and response duration in patients treated with this drug. III. Determine the toxicity profile of this drug in these patients. IV. Determine the pharmacokinetic-pharmacodynamic relationship of this drug in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to number of prior cytotoxic therapies for advanced disease (1-2 vs more than 2). Patients receive ecteinascidin 743 IV over 3 hours on day 1. Treatment repeats every 3 weeks for at least 2 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients are followed every 3 months. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 36-76 patients (18-38 per stratum) will be accrued for this study within 13 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trabectedin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed advanced or metastatic soft tissue sarcoma Unresectable disease Previously treated with at least 1 prior nonadjuvant chemotherapy regimen for advanced or metastatic disease Adjuvant chemotherapy considered firstline treatment for advanced disease if the first relapse is less than 6 months after completion of therapy At least 1 bidimensionally measurable nonirradiated lesion At least 20 mm in at least 1 diameter by CT scan At least 20 by 20 mm for clinically measurable lesion No gastrointestinal stromal sarcoma No HIVrelated Kaposi's sarcoma No malignant mesothelioma No chondrosarcomas No symptomatic brain or leptomeningeal involvement PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: WHO 02 OR Karnofsky 60100% Life expectancy: At least 3 months Hematopoietic: Neutrophil count at least 1,500/mm3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm3 Hepatic: Bilirubin no greater than upper limit of normal (ULN) Alkaline phosphatase no greater than ULN (unless suspected bone metastases present) AST/ALT less than 2.5 times ULN Albumin at least 2.5 g/dL No chronic active liver disease Renal: Creatinine no greater than 1.8 mg/dL OR Creatinine clearance at least 40 mL/min Cardiovascular: No congestive heart failure No angina pectoris, even if medically controlled No myocardial infarction within the past year No uncontrolled arterial hypertension or arrhythmias Other: No other neoplastic disease within the past 5 years except nonmelanoma skin cancer or carcinoma in situ No other serious illness or medical condition No active infection No history of significant neurological or psychiatric disorders No symptomatic peripheral neuropathy grade 2 or greater Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception during and for 1 month after study PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Recovered from prior immunotherapy No concurrent prophylactic colonystimulating factors (e.g., filgrastim (G CSF) or sargramostim (GMCSF)) during first course of study No concurrent anticancer immunotherapy Chemotherapy: See Disease Characteristics At least 4 weeks since prior chemotherapy (6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin) and recovered No other concurrent chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: No concurrent anticancer hormonal therapy Radiotherapy: See Disease Characteristics Recovered from radiotherapy No concurrent radiotherapy except palliative local radiotherapy Surgery: See Disease Characteristics Other: At least 30 days since prior investigational drugs No other concurrent investigational or experimental anticancer drugs No concurrent participation in other clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage III adult soft tissue sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult soft tissue sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult soft tissue sarcoma</keyword>
</DOC>