<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00226187</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A randomized, double-blind trial of docosahexaenoic and arachidonic acid supplementation in breast-fed preterm infants Background: Docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) and arachidonic acid (AA) are essential for preterm infants. Human milk and preterm formulas contain DHA and AA, but at lower concentrations than required to approximate utero accretion rate. Objective: To evaluate the effect of a high dose DHA and AA supplement to breast-fed preterm infants in the early neonatal period. Primary endpoints are neurodevelopment at 6 and 20 months of age. Design: A randomized double-blind placebo-controlled study is carried out in four Norwegian neonatal centers. Subjects and methods: Infants with birth weight &lt; 1.5 kg are randomized to either an intervention or a control group. All infants receive fortified human milk, and a daily dose of 0.5 ml study oil per 100 ml milk. Infants in the intervention group receive oil with DHA and AA (Formulaid, Martek, USA), while the control oil contains vegetable oil without DHA or AA. Blood samples are collected at birth (cord), and at start and stop of the intervention. Plasma is analyzed for fatty acid pattern using high performance liquid chromatography.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomized Clinical Trial on Supplementation of DHA and AA to Preterm Infants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Birth Weight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Birth weight &lt; 1500 g Born at one of 4 participating neonatal centers in Norway Cerebral haemorrhage (stage 3 or 4) Major congenital malformations that are supposed to affect growth and development Illness that require prolonged parenteral nutrition (&gt;4 weeks)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>1 Month</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2005</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fatty acids</keyword>
	<keyword>Human milk</keyword>
	<keyword>Infant development</keyword>
	<keyword>Very low birthweight infants</keyword>
</DOC>