<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01848366</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Demonstrate a response to stimulation of the posterior tibial nerve using the Biowave device and a microneedle patch electrode in patients with overactive bladder symptoms. The investigators hypothesize that after at least 6 weekly treatments there will be modest improvements in overactive bladder symptoms trending toward more improvement.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Utilization of the BIOWAVE Device to Treat Overactive Bladder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Women 18 years old and over with a score of equal to or greater than 4 on the OAB-q short form for urgency and average daily urinary frequency equal to or greater than 10 times based on a 3-day voiding diary plus other inclusion criteria will be reviewed for possible enrollment in this study. Outcomes measured include Global Response Assessment (GRA) for overall bladder symptoms, a change in the 3-day voiding diary parameters and adverse events.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Overactive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women &gt;18 years of age A score of &gt; 4 on the OABq short form for urgency (question 1) Average daily urinary frequency &gt; 10 times based on a 3day voiding diary Selfreported bladder symptoms present &gt; 3 months Selfreported failed conservative care (i.e., dietary restriction, fluid restriction, bladder training, behavioral modification, pelvic muscle training, biofeedback, etc.) Off all antimuscarinics for at least 2 weeks prior to enrollment Capable of giving informed consent Ambulatory and able to use a toilet independently, without difficulty Capable and willing to follow all studyrelated procedures Pregnant as confirmed by urine pregnancy test, or plans to become pregnant during the study period Neurogenic bladder Botox® use in bladder or pelvic floor muscles in the past year Pacemakers or implantable defibrillators Primary complaint of stress urinary incontinence Current urinary tract infection (UTI) Current vaginal infection Current use of InterStim® Current use of Bion® Previously been treated with Percutaneous Tibial Nerve Stimulation (PTNS) Use of investigational drug/device therapy within the past 4 weeks. Participating or have participated within the past 4 weeks in any clinical investigation involving or impacting gynecologic, urinary or renal function. Deemed unsuitable for enrollment in study by the investigators based on subjects' history or physical examination (including skin disorders at the treatment site or peripheral neuropathy). Subjects with nerve damage that would impact either percutaneous tibial nerve or pelvic floor function.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Frequency</keyword>
	<keyword>urgency</keyword>
	<keyword>incontinence</keyword>
</DOC>