<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01848418</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to create and validate an ICF core Set for Systemic sclerosis</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Conception of an ICF Core Set for Systemic Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In 2002 was published WHO's International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health (ICF). ICF defines disability as "the negative aspects of the interaction between an individual (with a health condition) and that individual's contextual factors (personal and environmental factors)". Interactions are specified in five domains, classified from body, individual and societal perspectives by means of two lists: a list of body functions and structure, and a list of domains of activity and participation. Since an individual's functioning and disability occurs in a context, the ICF also includes a list of environmental factors. ICF core sets, which are short lists of ICF categories relevant for specific conditions, serve as practical tools for clinical practice and allow standardisation of data for health information and research. Core sets have already been developed and validated for several musculoskeletal diseases, such as low back pain, osteoarthritis, or osteoporosis, but not yet for systemic sclerosis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Scleroderma, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Scleroderma, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female aged 18 and older Diagnosis of ScS made according to ACR and/or Leroy et Medsger criteria Patient giving his informed consent to participate in the study Severe chronic disease associated with ScS : stroke, multiple sclerosis, Parkinson's disease,… Cognitive or behavioral disorders making assessment impossible Inability to speak and write French</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ICF</keyword>
	<keyword>Core sets</keyword>
	<keyword>Systemic sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Function</keyword>
	<keyword>Evaluation</keyword>
</DOC>