<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01848769</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The rationale is to investigate the systemic availability of BDP/B17MP and formoterol after single oral inhalation of CHF 1535 50/6 pMDI vs the free combination of approved BDP and Formoterol pMDIs, in asthmatic children (5 to 11 years old).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Pharmacology Study of CHF1535 pMDI 50/6 µg Versus The Free Combination In Asthmatic Children 5-11 Years Old</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Beclomethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Formoterol Fumarate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male/Female children aged 511 years Written informed consent obtained by parents/legal representative (according to local regulation) and by the minor (age and local regulation permitting). children with stable asthma on regular treatment with ICS or using shortacting inhaled beta2agonists as reliever to control asthma symptoms Forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV1) &gt; 70% of predicted values (% pred) after withholding beta2agonist treatment for a minimum of 4 h prior to each dose period. 6. A cooperative attitude and ability to be trained about the proper use of pMDI with a spacer device and compliant to study procedures. Past or present diagnoses of cardiovascular, renal or liver disease Known hypersensitivity to the active treatments Exacerbation of asthma symptoms within the previous 4 weeks Inability to perform the required breathing technique and blood sampling Hospitalization due to exacerbation of asthma within 1 month prior to inclusion Lower respiratory tract infection within 1 month prior to inclusion Disease (other than asthma) which might influence the outcome of the study Obesity, i.e. &gt; 97% weight percentile by local standards</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>ICS+LABA</keyword>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
	<keyword>Inhalation</keyword>
	<keyword>pMDI</keyword>
</DOC>