<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01858883</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Test the hypothesis that INCB039110 can be administered safely in combination with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel in subjects with advanced or metastatic cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of INCB039110 in Combination With Gemcitabine and Nab-Paclitaxel in Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Part 1: This is a dose optimization phase designed to find a tolerated regimen that includes identifying the MTD of INCB039110 (within a defined pharmacologic range) in combination with doses of gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel that have established safety and tolerability in subjects with advanced or metastatic solid tumors. Study Part 2 and Part 2A: This phase will explore the safety and tolerability of the MTD or PAD of INCB039110 when administered in combination with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel in subjects with untreated advanced or metastatic pancreatic cancer.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenograstim</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed solid tumor (Part 1) or pancreatic adenocarcinoma (Part 2) Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status ≤ 1 Received no more than 1 prior chemotherapy regimen for advanced or metastatic disease (not including neoadjuvant and/or adjuvant therapy) (Part 1) Received no prior chemotherapy for advanced or metastatic disease (Part 2 and Part 2a) Adequate renal, hepatic, and bone marrow function without frequent blood product or hematopoietic growth factor support (eg use of erythropoietin or transfusions &gt; 2 units packed red blood cells every 3 months) Ability to swallow and retain oral medication Any known contraindications to the use of a required comedication (gemcitabine or nabpaclitaxel). Evidence of uncontrolled brain metastases or history of uncontrolled seizures. Ongoing radiation therapy and/or radiation therapy administered within 28 days of enrollment or ongoing radiotherapyrelated toxicities. Presence of ≥ Grade 2 neuropathy. Inability to swallow food or any condition of the upper GI tract that precludes administration of oral medications. Recent (≤ 3 months) history of partial or complete bowel obstruction. Unwillingness to be transfused with blood components. Known history of Hepatitis B or C infection or HIV infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>