<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01030445</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess whether a non-invasive cardiac output monitor can follow heart function in children during treatments in the hospital. To establish a normal reference for children who are well and awake.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cardiac Function as Measured by Non-invasive Electrical Velocimetry Cardiac Monitor in Hospitalized Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of the study is to evaluate the ability of a new FDA-approved non-invasive Electrical Velocimetry (EV) cardiac monitor called AESCULON (Cardiotronic Inc, La Jolla CA) to detect and trend hemodynamic changes in hospitalized ambulatory pediatric patients during recovery from acute illness. We postulate that if the cardiac monitor can trend hemodynamic changes in hypertensive patients whose mean arterial pressure (MAP) decreases to normal levels, or hypotensive patients whose MAP increases to normal levels over several days, it may improve our understanding of different disease processes and allow us to improve care. We also seek to establish normative data for different measures provided by the AESCULON monitor - specifically cardiac output (CO) and systemic vascular resistance (SVR), which are the prime determinants of MAP.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Medical patients without complex medical history with expected hospital stay for less than 10 days Uncomplicated Medical Patients as define as (1) Previously healthy children or (2) Children with diagnosis of a single chronic medical disorder that is not associated with cardiac dysfunction Congenital heart disease with and without repair (includes PFO, ASD and PDA, cardiac valve disease or pulmonary hypertension Chronic lung disease (except asthma) Abnormal Hemoglobin (SSD)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>non-invasive cardiac output monitor</keyword>
	<keyword>electrical velocimetry</keyword>
	<keyword>Aesculon</keyword>
	<keyword>Icon</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatrics</keyword>
	<keyword>normal reference</keyword>
</DOC>