<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01612312</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Whereas thrombus aspiration in patients with ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) is recommended by current guidelines, there are insufficient data to unequivocally support thrombectomy in patients with non-STEMI (NSTEMI). The Thrombus Aspiration in ThrOmbus containing culpRiT lesions in Non-ST-Elevation Myocardial Infarction (TATORT-NSTEMI) trial is a 400 patient, prospective, controlled, multicenter, randomized, open-label trial. The hypothesis is that under the background of early revascularization, adjunctive thrombectomy in comparison to conventional percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) alone leads to less microvascular obstruction (MO) assessed by cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (CMR) in patients with NSTEMI. Patients will be randomized in a 1:1 fashion to one of the two treatment arms. The primary endpoint is the extent of MO assessed by CMR. Secondary endpoints include infarct size and myocardial salvage assessed by CMR, enzymatic infarct size as well as angiographic parameters, such as Thrombolysis in Myocardial Infarction-flow post-PCI and myocardial blush grade. Furthermore, clinical endpoints including death, myocardial reinfarction, target vessel revascularization and new congestive heart failure will be recorded at 6 and 12 months. Safety will be assessed by bleeding and stroke. In summary, the TATORT-NSTEMI trial has been designed to test the hypothesis that thrombectomy will improve myocardial perfusion in patients with NSTEMI and relevant thrombus burden in the culprit vessel reperfused by early PCI.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Thrombus Aspiration in ThrOmbus Containing culpRiT Lesions in Non-ST-Elevation Myocardial Infarction (TATORT-NSTEMI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ischemic symptoms such as angina pectoris &gt;20 minutes occurrence of last symptoms &lt;72 h before randomization cardiac troponin T or I levels above the 99th percentile culprit lesion containing thrombus (TIMIthrombus grade 25 within the lesion) and intended early PCI cardiogenic shock STEMI no identifiable culprit lesion or a TIMIthrombus grade &lt;2 coronary morphology ineligible for thrombectomy (e.g. very tortuous vessels, severe calcification) indication for acute bypass surgery age &lt;18 and &gt;90 years contraindications for treatment with heparin, aspirin or thienopyridines pregnancy current participation in another clinical study comorbidity with limited life expectancy &lt;6 months contraindications to CMR at study entry</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-ST-elevation myocardial infarction</keyword>
	<keyword>thrombectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>magnetic resonance imaging</keyword>
	<keyword>microvascular obstruction</keyword>
</DOC>