<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02829983</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the periodontal clinical response and the possible adverse effects of the clarithromycin combined to periodontal mechanical therapy in the treatment of patients with generalized aggressive periodontitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clarithromycin as Adjuvant to Periodontal Debridement</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To assess the periodontal clinical response and the possible adverse effects of the clarithromycin combined to periodontal mechanical therapy in the treatment of patients with generalized aggressive periodontitis.Forty patients were select and randomly assigned into two groups: Group clarithromycin with 20 subjects that received one-stage full-mouth ultrasonic debridement (FMUD) associated with clarithromycin (500 mg - 12/12 hours) for 3 days; group placebo with 20 subjects that received FMUD associated with placebo. Probing depth (PD), gain in clinical attachment level (CAL) and bleeding on probing (BOP) were evaluated at baseline, 3 and 6 months post- operatively.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aggression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aggressive Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clarithromycin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>diagnosis of Generalized Aggressive Periodontitis presence of ≥20 teeth presence of ≥ 6 sites presenting probing depth (PD) ≥5mm with bleeding on probing (BOP) and ≥2 sites with PD ≥7mm (including incisors and first molars, in addition to two other noncontiguous teeth between them) good general health &lt;35 years of age agree to participate in the study and sign a written consent pregnant or lactating suffering from any other systemic disease (e.g. cardiovascular, diabetes, blood dyscrasias, immunodeficiency, etc) which could alter the course of periodontal disease received antimicrobials in the previous 6 months taking longterm antiinflammatory drugs received a course of periodontal treatment within the last 12 months smoked</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>clarithromycin</keyword>
	<keyword>periodontal debridement</keyword>
	<keyword>aggressive periodontitis</keyword>
</DOC>