<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02829190</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The phase-contrast MRI offers the advantage to combine precisely vascular flow measurements data with morphological images. Even if the anatomy of the external carotid artery is well known, data obtained through Phase contrast MRI could permit to progress in several fields of cranio-maxillofacial surgery as for example arteriovenous malformations,radionecrosis, head and neck micro-reconstructive surgery. The aim of this study is to establish and develop Phase-contrast MRI sequences for vascular flow characterization branches of the external carotid artery in healthy patients and in pathological cases.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Feasibility Study of Phase-contrast MRI for Flow in the External Carotid Branches Arteries</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>group 1 : healthy volunteer group 2 : XRay treatment antecedent (at least 50 grays and older than one year) group 3 : antecedent of embolization of branches of external carotid artery group 4 : antecedent of muscular free flap surgery (older than one month) free and informed consent group 1 : facial pathology, antecedent of facial injury, antecedent of XRay treatment in head and neck localisation, antecedent of head and neck cancer group 2 : antecedent of surgery for head and neck cancer or for vascular disease group 3 : antecedent of surgery for head and neck cancer or for vascular disease ; antecedent of XRay treatment. group 4 : antecedent of surgery for head and neck cancer or for vascular disease ; antecedent of XRay treatment or embolization patient with guardianship or trusteeship MRI consindications pregnancy and lactation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>External carotid artery</keyword>
	<keyword>Facial artery</keyword>
	<keyword>Lingual artery</keyword>
	<keyword>Superior thyroid artery</keyword>
	<keyword>Internal maxillary artery</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase-contrast MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>Rate of flow</keyword>
	<keyword>Superficial temporal artery</keyword>
</DOC>