<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02829645</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Eating disorders (ED) are serious mental illnesses with an excess mortality and many affects in the quality of life of patients and thier relatives. Management of ED is very difficult : the prognosis remains relatively poor both in terms of remission rate and quality of life. In this context, the contribution of new strategies for pathophysiological exploration and the development of therapeutic options are crucial. In this project the investigators aim to constitute un cohort of patients from a day unit specialized in the management of ED. A prospective follow-up will be offered to patients to assess their clinical and psycho-social evolution. The overall objective is to identify which factors are prognostic of clinical improvement of the ED. We also want to better characterize patients that will migrate from diagnosis to another.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Clinical, Neuropsychological and Psychosocial Situation of Patient With Eating Disorders.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators propose to assess, with a cohort of patients with ED the prognostic value of cognitive abnormalities associated with ED (cognitive flexibility and central coherence) They will recruit 370 patients suffering from a current ED (anorexia, bulimia, binge eating disorder, Eating disorder not otherwise specified). Each patient will be reassessed every year for 3 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Feeding and Eating Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: respond to DSM 4 criteria for ED Age 15 to 65 years Signing an informed consent. Affiliated to a social security scheme or being the beneficiary of such a scheme. Exclusion criteria: Manifest inability of the subject to understand / perform clinical and neuropsychological evaluations and tasks Major protected by law (guardianship) Privation of liberty by judicial or administrative decision Pregnant or lactating women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>eating disoders</keyword>
	<keyword>neuropsychology</keyword>
	<keyword>pronostic</keyword>
</DOC>