<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02829996</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Phase II, randomized, double-masked study to evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of topical ocular delivery of fixed-dosed combinations of trabodenoson and latanoprost in subjects with Ocular Hypertension or Primary Open-Angle Glaucoma. All subjects who meet the study's enrollment criteria following Screening will undergo washout of all prohibited medications (if washout is needed), including their routine glaucoma medications. During the Placebo Run-In Period, placebo is applied twice daily to both eyes in all subjects. During the Treatment Period, study drug is applied to both eyes for a total of 8 weeks. Each subject will be assigned 4 weeks of AM and 4 weeks of PM dosing in a masked manner. AM vs PM dosing is masked utilizing Placebo in addition to the active drug product. During the Treatment Period, study drug (Active and Placebo) eye drop applications will occur twice daily, in the morning and in the evening. The Treatment Period will be followed by an Observation Period of approximately 7 days wherein no study eye drops are instilled. The purpose of the study is to assess the overall benefit/risk profile of binocular topical application of different doses of trabodenoson (3.0% and 6.0%) when combined with latanoprost (0.005% or 0.0025%) one drop daily (QD) for 8 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Fixed-Dose Combinations of Trabodenoson and Latanoprost in Adults With Ocular Hypertension or Primary Open-Angle Glaucoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma, Open-Angle</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ocular Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Latanoprost</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of ocular hypertension (OHT) or primary openangle glaucoma (POAG) Mean Intraocular pressure (IOP) of ≥25 and ≤34 Significant visual field loss or any new field loss within the past year Cuptodisc ratio &gt;0.8 Central corneal thickness &lt;490 µm or &gt;610 µm A recent (acute) or chronic medical condition that might obfuscate the Subject's study data</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>glaucoma</keyword>
	<keyword>primary open-angle glaucoma</keyword>
	<keyword>ocular hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>adenosine agonist</keyword>
	<keyword>eye drop</keyword>
	<keyword>trabodenoson</keyword>
	<keyword>trabecular meshwork</keyword>
</DOC>