<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02829164</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primitive kidney disease IgA, represented by Berger's disease and rheumatoid purpura nephropathy, are the first cause of kidney failure from chronic glomerulonephritis: changes in 20 years to end-stage renal failure is described in 10 to 30 % of cases in Berger's disease and in 15 to 20% of cases in nephropathy HSP. These two pathological entities share biological and histological characteristics, as well as common pathophysiological mechanisms, particularly the production of abnormally glycosylated IgA1 promoting their proliferation in the mesangium. Tonsils part of Iga abnormal production sites that would be associated with an infectious stimulus, tonsillectomy has been studied as a possible treatment in primitive IgA nephropathy. The benefit of tonsillectomy is controversial: many Japanese studies demonstrate its effectiveness in terms of reduction of proteinuria, improved renal function in the long term regression of histological lesions and reduced risk of relapse following clinical remission whereas European studies do not suggest its effectiveness in treating IgA nephropathy. In this context, the aim of our study is to describe the scope of practice of tonsillectomy in the treatment of primary renal disease in IgA child in the inter East region and describe the short renal become Strasbourg end of the cohort that received this treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tonsillectomy and Primitive IgA Nephropathy in Children: Strasbourg Cohort and Assessment Practices in Inter North East Region</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glomerulonephritis, IGA</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Children with a clinical diagnosis and / or histological evidence of primary IgA nephropathy Follow the University Hospital of Strasbourg since 2009 Having received a tonsillectomy in their care Children whose holders of parental authority does not oppose the use of clinical data from their child for research purposes Exclusion criteria: Children whose holders of parental authority are opposed to the use of clinical data from their child for research purposes</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tonsillectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>primary IgA nephropathy</keyword>
	<keyword>primary nephropathy</keyword>
	<keyword>IgA</keyword>
	<keyword>Berger's disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Purpura rheumatoid</keyword>
	<keyword>kidney failure</keyword>
</DOC>