<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02589275</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 3, open-label, extension trial designed to evaluate the long term safety and efficacy over 3 months of TNX-102 SL tablets taken daily at bedtime for the treatment of Fibromyalgia (FM). Patients recruits into this trial are those who have successfully completed the double-blind studies; TNX-CY-F301 and TNX-CY-F302. Anticipated start for TNX-CY-F302 is for March 2016. Patients will not be made aware of the therapy they received during the double-blind study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A 3-Month Open-Label Safety and Efficacy Study of TNX-102 SL Tablets in Fibromyalgia Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study consist of 4 study visits, including Screening/Baseline Visit 1 (Day 0, which is anticipated to be the same date as Visit 6 in F301 or F302) and visits after 1, 2 and 3 months of treatment (Visits 2-4). Primary: The primary objective of the study is to evaluate the safety of TNX-102 SL tablets taken daily at bedtime over an additional 3 months in patients with FM who have completed the double-blinded lead-in study Secondary: The secondary objective is to evaluate the efficacy of TNX-102 SL tablets taken daily at bedtime to control symptoms of FM</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibromyalgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myofascial Pain Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclobenzaprine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient met all prior inclusion and exclusion requirements for study F301 or F302 originally, and has had no intervening medical conditions, increased suicidal ideation, or requirements for concomitant medications that preclude exposure to TNX102 SL or enrollment in the extension study. The patient completed expected dosing in F301 or F302 defined as taking study medication up to Week 12, with at least 70% compliance with medication usage (based on overall drug accountability reconciliation at the end of the F301 or F302 leadin study) and no major protocol deviations. The patient has provided written informed consent to participate in this extension protocol.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>TNX-102 SL</keyword>
	<keyword>bedtime</keyword>
	<keyword>sublingual</keyword>
	<keyword>3-month</keyword>
	<keyword>long term safety</keyword>
	<keyword>long term efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Fibromyalgia</keyword>
</DOC>