<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00160667</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study will assess efficacy, safety and tolerability of brivaracetam in post-herpetic neuralgia (PHN). Duration of 7 weeks divided into 3 periods with no up-titration, nor down-titration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Assessing Efficacy of Brivaracetam in Subjects With Persistent Pain After Shingles (Post-herpetic Neuralgia)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia, Postherpetic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male/female subject aged 18 years or older. Pain present for at least 6 months after healing of the acute herpes zoster skin rash. Pain intensity score assessed on an 11point numerical pain rating scale with a score of at least 4 at the screening visit and with an average weekly score of at least 4 on an 11point numerical pain rating scale during baseline period. Subject getting any kind of psychological support to help cope with pain such as biofeedback or behavioral cognitive therapy. Subject who had undergone or who is scheduled for neurolytic or neurosurgical therapy for postherpetic neuralgia (PHN) or who receives transelectrical neural stimulation (TENS. Tricyclic antidepressants (TCAs) or nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug (NSAIDs) or permitted opioid analgesics ("strong" opioids are forbidden) that started less than 30 days and/or are not stabilized prior to screening and/or are not expected to be kept stable during the study. Intake of more than two pain treatments at trial entry (screening visit) including Tricyclic antidepressants (TCAs), nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) or permitted opioid analgesics. Subject being treated with Carbamazepine for any indication. Known coexistent source of painful peripheral neuropathy or other systemic disease associated with a secondary painful neuropathy. Subject being treated in the four weeks prior to screening visit with "strong" opioid analgesics.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Post-herpetic Neuralgia (PHN)</keyword>
	<keyword>Brivaracetam</keyword>
</DOC>