<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00160251</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to determine the safe and effective dose range of boceprevir (SCH 503034) in combination with PEG-Intron in adult subjects who have chronic hepatitis C without cirrhosis, and who have failed an adequate course of combination therapy with peginterferon-alfa plus ribavirin. A secondary objective is to explore whether ribavirin provides an additional benefit when combined with PEG-Intron plus boceprevir.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Boceprevir (SCH 503034) Plus Peg-Intron, With and Without Added Ribavirin, in Patients With Chronic Hepatitis C, Genotype 1, Who Did Not Respond to Previous Treatment With Peginterferon Alfa Plus Ribavirin (Study P03659AM2)(COMPLETED)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key inclusion criteria: Documented infection with chronic hepatitis C (CHC), genotype 1. Documented failure to respond to an adequate course of treatment (minimum 12 weeks) with peginterferonalfa plus ribavirin (failure defined as &lt;2 log drop in HCVRNA after 12 weeks of therapy or those who never become Hepatitis C Virus Ribonucleic Acid (HCV)RNA negative) No evidence of cirrhosis on liver biopsy. Results of physical examination and laboratory tests within specified ranges. Abstinence from use of abused substances. Key exclusion criteria: Women who are pregnant or nursing a child. Patients with cirrhosis, coinfection with Hepatitis B or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), and AfricanAmerican patients (by protocol amendment 2, AfricanAmerican patients can enroll). Previous treatment with any Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) polymerase or protease inhibitor. Patients who relapsed following response to previous treatment. Evidence of advanced liver disease, or liver disease from a cause other than CHC. Preexisting psychiatric condition.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>PEG-Intron</keyword>
	<keyword>Ribavirin</keyword>
	<keyword>Protease Inhibitor</keyword>
</DOC>