<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00160797</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to gather information about total knee replacement surgery using minimally invasive surgical procedures.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Total Knee Arthroplasty Outcome Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to gather information about total knee replacement surgery using minimally invasive surgical procedures. The MIS™ Minimally Invasive Solutions™ Total Knee Arthroplasty System has been cleared for use by the Food and Drug Administration. You are invited to participate in this data collection study, comparing the MIS system to standard knee replacement systems. The decision about which system and operation will be best for you has already been made by you and your orthopaedic surgeon. The information will be used to compare minimally invasive surgery and the standard surgery procedures. The results of this study will provide information that will add to the knowledge base of knee replacement surgery.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Presence of a severely disabled joint secondary to painful osteoarthritis, rheumatoid arthritis, or posttraumatic arthritis that warrants primary knee arthroplasty. Gender Males and females will be included. The maletofemale ratio will depend upon the patient population at each institution conducting the study. Age Minimum of 18 yearsold. Stable Health The patient should be able to undergo surgery and participate in a followup program based upon physical examination and medical history. Patient or patient's legal representative has read and signed the Letter to the Patient form. Patient is skeletally immature. Previous ipsilateral knee arthroplasty. Previous Patellectomy. Patient is pregnant or breastfeeding. Presence of clinically significant disease of the cardiovascular, renal, hepatic, hematologic, respiratory, endocrine, neurological, gastrointestinal, genitourinary, immune systems or other medical condition which is not well controlled. Patients who have received an investigational drug or device within the last 30 days. Patient is unwilling or unable to cooperate in a followup program.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>