<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00160966</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to characterize and evaluate risk factors of polyomavirus nephropathy (PVN) including the impact of three immunosuppressive regimens.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Immunosuppressive Regimens on Polyomavirus-related Transplant Nephropathy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Polyomavirus nephropathy (PVN) is an emerging cause of renal transplant loss. Until now the risk factors of PVN are poorly understood. Tacrolimus (Tacr) and mycophenolate mofetil (MMF) are thought to be associated with a higher risk of developing PVN. However, the way in which Tacr or MMF might enhance the susceptibility for PVN remains largely unknown. In this prospective study we will analyze whether differences in immune-reactivity patterns (Th1, Th2, B cell and monocyte responses, sCD30, immunoregulatory antibodies) of renal transplant patients induced by different immunosuppressive regimens (cyclosporine A [CsA]/MMF, Tacr/MMF, Tacr/MMF with conversion to Tacr/Everolimus [ERL]) or by cytokine promoter gene polymorphisms may account for the different risks of developing PVN. Comparison(s): renal transplant recipients stratified according to their relative immunological risk (group 1: low risk (primary recipients without pre-immunization [PRA &lt; 5%]); group 2: moderate risk (group 2a: primary recipients with low pre-immunization [PRA 6-20%]; group 2b: re-transplanted patients); group 3: very high risk (re-transplanted patients with a history of vascular rejection or recipients of a first graft with high pre-immunization [PRA &gt; 20%]) randomized to be treated with one of three immunosuppressive regimens (CsA/MMF, Tacr/MMF, Tacr/MMF with subsequent conversion to Tacr/ERL).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polyomavirus Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunosuppressive Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Cadaver kidney and living donor kidney transplant recipients Primary, secondary, and tertiary transplant recipients Preimmunized and not preimmunized transplant recipients Age &gt; 18 years Contraindications against administration of one of the four study drugs History of severe gastrointestinal morbidity Age &lt; 18 years Pregnant or breast feeding women Rejection of effective contraceptive methods with young women Combined kidney and islet cell transplantation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>kidney transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>polyoma virus associated transplant nephropathy</keyword>
	<keyword>tacrolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>mycophenolate mofetil</keyword>
	<keyword>everolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>cyclosporin A</keyword>
	<keyword>BK virus PCR</keyword>
	<keyword>viruria screening</keyword>
	<keyword>BK polyomavirus</keyword>
	<keyword>immunosuppression</keyword>
</DOC>