<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00160407</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if orlistat (Xenical) therapy in overweight patients with NASH leads to enhanced weight loss over time, with subsequent improvement in the underlying necroinflammatory and fibrotic changes that are typical of NASH.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Orlistat (Xenical) in the Treatment of Overweight Patients With Nonalcoholic Steatohepatitis (NASH)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Previous studies have suggested that steady weight loss over time will result in improvement in aminotransferases, and more importantly, underlying histopathology in patients with NASH. A total of 50 biopsy-proven NASH patients will be enrolled in a prospective, randomized fashion. Twenty-five patients have been enrolled at the primary study site at Saint Louis University. Recruitment of the next 25 patients is taking place at a study subsite at Brooke Army Medical Center in San Antonio, Texas. This will be an open-label study comparing an established weight loss program (1400-calorie diet with 30% fat) plus daily vitamin E (800 IU) and a daily multivitamin to the same weight loss program, daily vitamin E (800 IU) and multivitamin, plus orlistat (120 mg), three times daily for 36 weeks. Data to be collected from prospective patients includes demographic information, such as age, sex, past medical history, medications, height and weight. Biochemical data to be collected from prospective patients includes liver enzymes, measures of insulin resistance to include, insulin levels, lipid panel, hemoglobin A1C, free fatty acids, complete blood count, coagulation studies, and vitamin E levels. Blood will also be collected and stored for markers of inflammation and fibrosis, such as C reactive protein and TNF-alpha. A liver biopsy will be obtained at the completion of the study for both histopathologic analysis and RNA analysis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Orlistat</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Liver biopsy obtained no more than 24 months before randomization with a pathology report confirming that the histological diagnosis is consistent with NASH Compensated liver disease with the following laboratory parameters at the entry visit: Hemoglobin values of greater than or equal to 12 gm/dl for females or 13 gm/dl for males WBC count &gt; 3,000/mm3 Neutrophil count &gt; 1,500/mm3 Platelets &gt; 70,000/mm3 Albumin &gt;3.0 g/dl Serum creatinine &lt;1.4mg/dl Ability to give informed consent Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) greater than or equal to 40 U/L BMI &gt; or equal to 27 kg/m2 Patients who receive orlistat must agree to participate in Xenicare, a free dietary counseling program provided by Roche (sponsor) Any cause for chronic liver disease other than NASH Evidence of decompensated liver disease such as a history of or presence of ascites, bleeding varices, or spontaneous encephalopathy History of alcohol consumption of greater than 20 grams per day in the past 2 years Prior surgical procedures to include gastroplasty, jejunoileal or jejunocolic bypass TPN within the past 6 months History of prior organ transplantation Concurrent enrollment in other experimental treatment protocols Use of ursodeoxycholic acid, rosiglitazone, pioglitazone, or metformin within the 6month period before enrollment Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>nonalcoholic steatohepatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>enzyme inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>lipase</keyword>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>insulin resistance</keyword>
</DOC>