<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02130024</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess the development of Geographic Atrophy with either ranibizumab or aflibercept in patients with wet Age related Macular Degeneration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Comparison of Ranibizumab and Aflibercept for the Development of Geographic Atrophy in (Wet) AMD Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase IV, randomised, controlled, masked study recruiting patients with one treatment-naïve eye presenting with subfoveal choroidal neovascularisation (CNV) secondary to wet AMD. At screening, following the informed consent process, patients will be assessed for study eligibility by assessment of visual acuity using logarithm of the minimum angle of resolution (logMAR), stereoscopic biomicroscopic slit-lamp fundus examination (78 D or similar lens); fluorescein angiogram (FA); colour fundus photography; fundus autofluorescence and optical coherence tomography (OCT). Eligible patients will be enrolled and then randomised to one of two arms: Arm 1: 0.5 mg ranibizumab using an inject and extend regimen Arm 2: 2.0 mg aflibercept using an inject and extend regimen.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Geographic Atrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for study eye: Diagnosis of active subfoveal CNV secondary to wet AMD without restriction of lesion size, with visual impairment being exclusively due to an active wet AMD lesion. Active lesions will be characterised by any of the following: abnormal retinal thickness, with evidence of intraretinal, subretinal or subpigment epithelial fluid accumulation, confirmed by OCT; presence of intraretinal or subretinal haemorrhage; leakage shown on a FA unless solely due to dry, fibrotic staining; visual acuity deterioration considered likely to represent CNV. BCVA score at both Screening and Baseline must be 23 letters or more as measured by the 3 metre Early Treatment Diabetic Retinopathy Study (ETDRS)like charts, inclusively (or approximate Snellen equivalent to 3/60+3). Exclusion Criteria 1. Inability to comply with study or followup procedures. 2. Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women. 3. Women of childbearing potential, defined as all women physiologically capable of becoming pregnant, unless they are using effective methods of contraception during dosing of study treatment. Exclusion criteria for systemic medical history and conditions: 4. Any type of systemic disease or its treatment, including any medical condition (controlled or uncontrolled) that could be expected to progress, recur, or change to such an extent that it may bias the assessment of the clinical status of the patient to a significant degree or put the patient at special risk. 5. Stroke or myocardial infarction less than 3 months prior to Screening. 6. Uncontrolled blood pressure defined as systolic value of &gt;160 mm Hg or diastolic value of &gt;100 mm Hg at Screening or Baseline. 7. Known hypersensitivity to ranibizumab or aflibercept or any component of the ranibizumab or aflibercept formulation, or fluorescein. Exclusion criteria for ocular medical history and conditions: For both eyes: 8. Any active periocular or ocular infection or inflammation (e.g., blepharitis, conjunctivitis, keratitis, scleritis, uveitis, endophthalmitis) at the time of Screening or Baseline. 9. 1 or more patches of geographic atrophy &gt; 250µm in longest linear dimension. 10. Uncontrolled glaucoma (intraocular pressure [IOP] ≥30 mm Hg on medication or according to investigator's judgment) at the time of Screening or Baseline. 11. Neovascularisation of the iris or neovascular glaucoma at the time of Screening or Baseline. 12. Inability of obtaining multimodal images of sufficient quality to be analysed. For study eye: 13. Visually significant cataract (likely to require surgery within the next 12 months), aphakia, severe vitreous haemorrhage, rhegmatogenous retinal detachment, proliferative diabetic retinopathy or CNV of any cause other than wet AMD (e.g., ocular histoplasmosis, pathologic myopia macular hole) at the time of Screening and Baseline. 14. Structural damage within 0.5 disc diameter of the centre of the macula (e.g., vitreomacular traction, epiretinal membrane, scar, laser burn, foveal atrophy) at the time of screening that in the investigator's opinion could preclude visual function improvement with treatment. Exclusion criteria for prior or current systemic medication: 15. Use of other investigational drugs within 30 days or 5 halflives from baseline, whichever is longer. 16. Current or planned use of systemic medications known to be toxic to the lens, retina or optic nerve as outlined in the Lucentis and Eylea Product Information. Exclusion criteria for prior or current ocular treatment: For study eye: 17. Treatment with any antiangiogenic drugs (including any antiVEGF agents) prior to Baseline in eye. 18. Any intraocular procedure (including YttriumAluminiumGarnet capsulotomy) within 2 months prior to Baseline or anticipated within the next 6 months following Baseline. Exclusion criteria of prohibited treatments (study eye): 19. Intra or periocular corticosteroids (including sub tenon but excluding topical formulations) 20. Intraocular corticosteroid implants</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Age-related macular degeneration, ranibizumab, aflibercept, geographic atrophy, inject and extend</keyword>
</DOC>