<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02500316</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Protocol CP-4-004-EXT is designed as an open-label extension study assessing long-term MOD-4023 administration. It is open to subjects completing Phase 2 study in children with growth hormone deficiency (CP-4-004).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long Term Follow up Study of Long-acting hGH (MOD-4023) in Growth Hormone Deficient Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who completed the first year of treatment in the main study are allowed to enter the (Long Term) Open Label Extension (OLE) study. 1. Children with past or present intracranial tumor growth as confirmed by an MRI scan (with contrast). 2. History of radiation therapy or chemotherapy. 3. Malnourished children defined as: 1. Serum albumin below the lower limit of normal (LLN) according to the reference ranges of central laboratory; 2. Serum iron below the lower limit of normal (LLN) according to the reference ranges of central laboratory; 3. BMI &lt; 2 Standard Deviation for age and sex; 4. Children with psychosocial dwarfism. 5. Children born small for gestational age (SGA birth weight and/or birth length &lt; 2 SD for gestational age). 6. Presence of antihGH antibodies at screening. 7. Any clinically significant abnormality likely to affect growth or the ability to evaluate growth, such as, but not limited to, chronic diseases like renal insufficiency, spinal cord irradiation, etc. 8. Patients with diabetes mellitus. 9. Patients with impaired fasting sugar (based on WHO; fasting blood sugar &gt;110 mg/dl or 6.1 mmol/l) after repeated blood analysis. 10. Chromosomal abnormalities and medical "syndromes" (Turner's syndrome, Laron syndrome, Noonan syndrome, PraderWilli Syndrome, RussellSilver Syndrome, short stature homeoboxcontaining gene (SHOX) mutations/deletions and skeletal dysplasias), with the exception of septooptic dysplasia. 11. Closed epiphyses. 12. Concomitant administration of other treatments that may have an effect on growth such as anabolic steroids and methylphenidate for attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), with the exception of hormone replacement therapies (thyroxine, hydrocortisone, desmopressin (DDAVP)) 13. Children requiring glucocorticoid therapy (e.g. asthma) who are taking a dose of greater than 400 µg/d of inhaled budesonide or equivalents for longer than 1 month during a calendar year. 14. Major medical conditions and/or presence of contraindication to rhGH treatment. 15. Known or suspected HIVpositive patient, or patient with advanced diseases such as AIDS or tuberculosis. 16. Drug, substance, or alcohol abuse. 17. Known hypersensitivity to the components of study medication. 18. Other causes of short stature such as coeliac disease, hypothyroidism and rickets. 19. The patient and/or the parent/legal guardian are likely to be noncompliant in respect to study conduct. 20. Participation in any other trial of an investigational agent within 30 days prior to Screening.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Growth hormone deficiency (GHD)</keyword>
	<keyword>r-hGH</keyword>
	<keyword>Long-acting</keyword>
</DOC>