<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="119137">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01551979</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2011P-000373</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01551979</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Therapeutic Efficacy of Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation in Schizophrenia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Therapeutic Efficacy of Cerebellar Repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation in Patients With Schizophrenia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sidney R. Baer, Jr. Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to look at the effectiveness of repetitive transcranial magnetic
      stimulation (rTMS) as a therapeutic intervention for patients with schizophrenia. The
      primary outcome is improvement in negative symptoms related to schizophrenia. The
      investigators are focusing on negative symptoms given their greater resistance to
      pharmacological and other established therapies. If the investigators trial were to show
      beneficial effects, its clinical significance would be great.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study builds on the results of a previous phase 1, single-site study in which we
      demonstrated the safety of image-guided theta burst stimulation (TBS) form of rTMS over the
      cerebellar vermis (Demirtas-Tatlidede et al., 2010) in eigh patients with schizophrenia.

      The primary goal of the present study is to assess efficacy of iTBS to the cerebellar vermis
      on positive and negative symptoms of schizophrenia. A second, added goal is to investigate
      the mechanisms of the expected clinical improvement.

      Schizophrenia is a leading cause of mental disability and current treatments still remain
      only partially successful for many patients. Our underlying hypothesis is that modulation of
      the cerebellar vermis may enhance activity of the neural systems that sub-serve cognition
      and emotion, reestablish the disturbed cerebellar regulation in schizophrenic patients, and
      produce clinical improvement.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2012</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline on the Positive and Negative Symptoms Scale (PANSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week before treatment, last day of treatment (after 5 days of treatment), 1 and 3 weeks post treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluates the presence/absence and severity of positive, negative, and general psychopathology of schizophrenia.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline on the Clinical Global Impression (CGI)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week before treatment, last day of treatment (after 5 days of treatment), 1 and 3 weeks post treatment</time_frame>
    <description>A three item scale used to assess treatment response in psychiatric patients. They are: Severity of Illness; Global Improvement, and Efficacy Index.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Profile of Mood States (POMS)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week before treatment, last day of treatment (after 5 days of treatment), 1 and 3 weeks post treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of transient, fluctuating mood states.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Calgary Depression Scale for Schizophrenia</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week before treatment, last day of treatment (after 5 days of treatment), 1 and 3 weeks post treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Specifically developed for assessment of depression in patients with schizophrenia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Visual Analogue Scales (VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week before treatment, last day of treatment (after 5 days of treatment), 1 and 3 weeks post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Subjective measurements that will measure characteristics over a continuum to assess for change within the individual subjects.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Schizophrenia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active rTMS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>High frequency rTMS stimulation of the vermis(lobule VII) of the cerebellum.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sham rTMS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sham rTMS to the vermis (lobule VII) of the cerebellum.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>intermittent Theta Burst (iTBS) pattern (20 trains of 10 bursts given with 8s intervals) will be applied at 80% of active motor threshold. Each participant will receive 600 pulses per session.
Sham participants will undergo the same procedures as those in the active rTMS group.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active rTMS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sham rTMS</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</other_name>
    <other_name>Noninvasive Brain Stimulation</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Age between 18-65 years

          -  Diagnosis of schizophrenia according to DSM-IV criteria (Diagnostic and Statistical
             Manual) by a board-certified psychiatrist

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Preexisting or progressive neurological disorders

          -  Prior neurological procedures

          -  Previous head injury

          -  Change in antipsychotic medication during the last 4 weeks

          -  Been an inpatient in a psychiatry clinic within the last month

          -  Any other axis 1 diagnosis

          -  Patients may not be actively enrolled in a separate intervention study

          -  Patients unable to undergo a brain MRI

          -  Any unstable medical condition

          -  History of seizures, diagnosis of epilepsy, history of abnormal (epileptiform_ EEG,
             or family history of treatment resistant epilepsy

          -  Possible pregnancy. All female participants of child bearing age are required to have
             a pregnancy test.

          -  Any metal in the brain, skull, or elsewhere unless approved by the responsible MD

          -  Any medical devices (ie. cardiac pacemaker, deep brain stimulator, medication
             infusion pump, cochlear implant, vagal nerve stimulator) unless otherwise approved by
             the responsible MD

          -  Substance abuse (alcohol, amphetamines, cocaine, MDMA
             [methylenedioxymethamphetamine], ecstasy, PCP [phencyclidine], Angle dust) or
             dependence within the past six months

          -  No medication is an absolute exclusion from TMS. Medications will be reviewed by the
             responsible MD and a decision about inclusion will be made based on the following:
             the patient's past medical history, drug dose, history of recent medication changes
             or duration of treatment, and combination with other CNS (central nervous system)
             active drugs (the published TMS guidelines review of medications to be considered
             with TMS)
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark Halko, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02134</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://tmslab.org</url>
    <description>Related Information</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Batini C, Buisseret-Delmas C, Corvisier J, Hardy O, Jassik-Gerschenfeld D. Brain stem nuclei giving fibers to lobules VI and VII of the cerebellar vermis. Brain Res. 1978 Sep 22;153(2):241-61.</citation>
    <PMID>80249</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Demirtas-Tatlidede A, Freitas C, Cromer JR, Safar L, Ongur D, Stone WS, Seidman LJ, Schmahmann JD, Pascual-Leone A. Safety and proof of principle study of cerebellar vermal theta burst stimulation in refractory schizophrenia. Schizophr Res. 2010 Dec;124(1-3):91-100. doi: 10.1016/j.schres.2010.08.015.</citation>
    <PMID>20817483</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Demirtas-Tatlidede A, Freitas C, Pascual-Leone A, Schmahmann JD. Modulatory effects of theta burst stimulation on cerebellar nonsomatic functions. Cerebellum. 2011 Sep;10(3):495-503. doi: 10.1007/s12311-010-0230-5.</citation>
    <PMID>21132574</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fregni F, Boggio PS, Valle AC, Rocha RR, Duarte J, Ferreira MJ, Wagner T, Fecteau S, Rigonatti SP, Riberto M, Freedman SD, Pascual-Leone A. A sham-controlled trial of a 5-day course of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation of the unaffected hemisphere in stroke patients. Stroke. 2006 Aug;37(8):2115-22. Epub 2006 Jun 29.</citation>
    <PMID>16809569</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fregni F, Thome-Souza S, Bermpohl F, Marcolin MA, Herzog A, Pascual-Leone A, Valente KD. Antiepileptic effects of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in patients with cortical malformations: an EEG and clinical study. Stereotact Funct Neurosurg. 2005;83(2-3):57-62. Epub 2005 Jun 30.</citation>
    <PMID>15990468</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fregni F, Freedman S, Pascual-Leone A. Recent advances in the treatment of chronic pain with non-invasive brain stimulation techniques. Lancet Neurol. 2007 Feb;6(2):188-91. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17239806</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>George MS, Wassermann EM, Williams WA, Callahan A, Ketter TA, Basser P, Hallett M, Post RM. Daily repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) improves mood in depression. Neuroreport. 1995 Oct 2;6(14):1853-6.</citation>
    <PMID>8547583</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>George MS, Nahas Z, Kozel FA, Goldman J, Molloy M, Oliver N. Improvement of depression following transcranial magnetic stimulation. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 1999 Dec;1(2):114-24. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11122913</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gershon AA, Dannon PN, Grunhaus L. Transcranial magnetic stimulation in the treatment of depression. Am J Psychiatry. 2003 May;160(5):835-45. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>12727683</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hajak G, Marienhagen J, Langguth B, Werner S, Binder H, Eichhammer P. High-frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in schizophrenia: a combined treatment and neuroimaging study. Psychol Med. 2004 Oct;34(7):1157-63.</citation>
    <PMID>15697042</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hashimoto M, Ohtsuka K. Transcranial magnetic stimulation over the posterior cerebellum during visually guided saccades in man. Brain. 1995 Oct;118 ( Pt 5):1185-93.</citation>
    <PMID>7496779</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Heath RG. Modulation of emotion with a brain pacemamer. Treatment for intractable psychiatric illness. J Nerv Ment Dis. 1977 Nov;165(5):300-17.</citation>
    <PMID>303280</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Heath RG, Dempesy CW, Fontana CJ, Myers WA. Cerebellar stimulation: effects on septal region, hippocampus, and amygdala of cats and rats. Biol Psychiatry. 1978 Oct;13(5):501-29.</citation>
    <PMID>728506</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Huber TJ, Schneider U, Rollnik J. Gender differences in the effect of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in schizophrenia. Psychiatry Res. 2003 Aug 30;120(1):103-5.</citation>
    <PMID>14500119</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jardri R, Lucas B, Delevoye-Turrell Y, Delmaire C, Delion P, Thomas P, Goeb JL. An 11-year-old boy with drug-resistant schizophrenia treated with temporo-parietal rTMS. Mol Psychiatry. 2007 Apr;12(4):320.</citation>
    <PMID>17389898</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jin Y, Potkin SG, Kemp AS, Huerta ST, Alva G, Thai TM, Carreon D, Bunney WE Jr. Therapeutic effects of individualized alpha frequency transcranial magnetic stimulation (alphaTMS) on the negative symptoms of schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. 2006 Jul;32(3):556-61. Epub 2005 Oct 27.</citation>
    <PMID>16254067</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Martin PI, Naeser MA, Theoret H, Tormos JM, Nicholas M, Kurland J, Fregni F, Seekins H, Doron K, Pascual-Leone A. Transcranial magnetic stimulation as a complementary treatment for aphasia. Semin Speech Lang. 2004 May;25(2):181-91. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15118944</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ohtsuka K, Enoki T. Transcranial magnetic stimulation over the posterior cerebellum during smooth pursuit eye movements in man. Brain. 1998 Mar;121 ( Pt 3):429-35.</citation>
    <PMID>9549519</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Papez JW. A proposed mechanism of emotion. 1937. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci. 1995 Winter;7(1):103-12.</citation>
    <PMID>7711480</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pascual-Leone A, Rubio B, Pallardó F, Catalá MD. Rapid-rate transcranial magnetic stimulation of left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in drug-resistant depression. Lancet. 1996 Jul 27;348(9022):233-7.</citation>
    <PMID>8684201</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rollnik JD, Huber TJ, Mogk H, Siggelkow S, Kropp S, Dengler R, Emrich HM, Schneider U. High frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) of the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in schizophrenic patients. Neuroreport. 2000 Dec 18;11(18):4013-5.</citation>
    <PMID>11192620</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rossi S, Hallett M, Rossini PM, Pascual-Leone A; Safety of TMS Consensus Group.. Safety, ethical considerations, and application guidelines for the use of transcranial magnetic stimulation in clinical practice and research. Clin Neurophysiol. 2009 Dec;120(12):2008-39. doi: 10.1016/j.clinph.2009.08.016. Epub 2009 Oct 14. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19833552</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schmahmann JD. The role of the cerebellum in cognition and emotion: personal reflections since 1982 on the dysmetria of thought hypothesis, and its historical evolution from theory to therapy. Neuropsychol Rev. 2010 Sep;20(3):236-60. doi: 10.1007/s11065-010-9142-x. Epub 2010 Sep 7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20821056</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schutter DJ, van Honk J, d'Alfonso AA, Peper JS, Panksepp J. High frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic over the medial cerebellum induces a shift in the prefrontal electroencephalography gamma spectrum: a pilot study in humans. Neurosci Lett. 2003 Jan 16;336(2):73-6.</citation>
    <PMID>12499043</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 12, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 1, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
  <keyword>repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
