<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02681302</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to determine the safety and clinical effect of combined checkpoint inhibition administered after autologous hematopoietic stem cell transplantation in each of six clinical cohorts of high risk and recurrent disease. In addition to assessing the incidence and severity of adverse events and rates of complete response and progression free survival, investigators intend to monitor immune reconstitution, phenotype and TCR repertoire throughout treatment and at the time of disease progression. Investigators will also analyze the gut microbiome prior to conditioning, throughout treatment, post-transplant and at time of relapse.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Combined Check Point Inhibition After Autologous Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation in Patients at High Risk for Post-transplant Recurrence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase Ib-IIA study of post-transplant combined check point inhibitors for patients with a high risk of relapse (&gt;50%) after an autologous hematopoietic stem cell transplant. Patients will accrue to study by disease groups and followed separately by group for incidence and severity of toxicity, ability to receive intended schedule of combined check point inhibitors and for complete response and progression free survival (PFS) rates. Complete response and progression free survival rates will be compared to published standards for each disease group. Expected PFS at 18 months for all post-transplant groups without check point inhibitors is less than 50%. Each group with PFS at 18 months in 4 or more patients (57%) will be considered for eligibility in a successor phase IIB expansion trial.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Be willing and able to sign informed consent Be 18 years or older and 80 years or younger on the day of signing consent Have a confirmed diagnosis of: De novo diffuse large B cell lymphoma that failed to achieve a PET negative complete response to primary rituximab and anthracycline based multiagent chemotherapy and at least maintain stable disease after salvage chemotherapy. Stable disease (SD) for lymphoma is defined as no progression and failure to achieve at least a 50% decrease in sum of the product of the diameters (SPD) of up to six of the largest dominant nodes or nodal masses. These nodes or masses should be selected according to all of the following: they should be clearly measurable in at least 2 perpendicular dimensions; if possible they should be from disparate regions of the body; and they should include mediastinal and retroperitoneal areas of disease whenever these sites are involved. Recurrent high risk diffuse large B cell lymphoma defined as relapsing within one year of initiation of rituximab and anthracycline based multiagent chemotherapy or a sAAIPI (secondline ageadjusted International Prognostic Index) intermediate or high at relapse and at least stable disease after salvage chemotherapy. De novo high risk T cell lymphoma with at least stable disease after primary therapy. High risk T cell lymphoma is defined as Stage III or IV disease at presentation; failure to achieve CR after frontline chemotherapy. Recurrent T cell lymphoma with at least stable disease after salvage therapy. De novo high risk multiple myeloma with at least stable disease after primary therapy. High risk myeloma is defined as those carrying 1q amplifications, 1p deletions, 13q deletions by conventional cytogenetics, p53 deletions, highrisk GEP 70 scores, t(4;14), t(14;16) and t(14;20), hypodiploidy. For patients with both cytogenetic aberrations and a GEP 70 score, the GEP 70 score will supercede the cytogenetics for the purpose of risk stratification. Recurrent myeloma within 3 years after a single autologous transplant and at least stable disease after salvage therapy. Stable disease for multiple myeloma is defined as failure to achieve at least 50% reduction of serum Mprotein and reduction in 24hurinary Mprotein of at least 90%. Be deemed eligible for an autologous stem cell transplantation as per institutional guidelines of the Blood and Marrow Transplantation Program at John Theurer Cancer Center at Hackensack University Medical Center Have a performance status of 2 or lower on ECOG performance scale Female subjects of childbearing potential should have a negative urine or serum pregnancy test within 24 hours prior to receiving the first dose of ipilimumab and nivolumab. If the urine test is positive or cannot be confirmed as negative, a serum pregnancy test will be required. Female subjects of childbearing potential should agree to ongoing pregnancy testing, to be performed prior to each dosing of ipilimumab and nivolumab Females of childbearing potential must be willing to use 2 methods of birth control or be surgically sterile, or abstain from heterosexual activity for the course of the study through 120 days after the last dose of study medication. Subjects of childbearing potential are those who have not been surgically sterilized or have not been free from menses for &gt; 2 years. Male subjects must agree to use a latex condom during sexual contact with females of childbearing potential even if they have had a successful vasectomy starting with the first dose of study therapy through 120 days after the last dose of study therapy. 9. Allowable transplant preparative regimens are the following: For nonHodgkin lymphoma groups (A, B,C,D) BEAM: carmustine 300 mg/m2 day 6, etoposide 200 mg/m2 and cytarabine 200 mg/m2 days 5 to 2, melphalan 140 mg/m2 day 1 For Myeloma groups (E and F) Melphalan 200 mg/m2 day 1 Has known active central nervous system (CNS) metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis. Subjects with previously treated brain metastases may participate provided they are stable (without evidence of progression by imaging for at least four weeks prior to the first dose of trial treatment and any neurologic symptoms have returned to baseline), have no evidence of new or enlarging brain metastases, and are not using steroids for at least 7 days prior to trial treatment. This exception does not include carcinomatous meningitis which is excluded regardless of clinical stability. Is unable or unwilling to sign informed consent. Has a diagnosis of immunodeficiency or is receiving systemic steroid therapy (more than or equivalent to 20 mg/day of prednisone) or any other form of immunosuppressive therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of trial treatment. The use of physiologic doses of corticosteroids may be used at the investigator's discretion Has received an allogeneic stem cell transplant. Has a known history of active TB (Bacillus Tuberculosis) Has a history of hypersensitivity to nivolumab, ipilimumab or any of its excipients Has had a prior anticancer monoclonal antibody (mAb) within 4 weeks prior to Day 1 of checkpoint inhibitor treatment administration or who has not recovered (i.e., t administration mAb) within 4 weeks prior to t dose of trial treatment. Rituximab within that time frame is allowed. Has active autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment in the past 2 years (i.e. with use of disease modifying agents, corticosteroids or immunosuppressive drugs). Replacement therapy (eg. thyroxine, insulin, or physiologic corticosteroid replacement therapy for adrenal or pituitary insufficiency, etc.) is not considered a form of systemic treatment. Has known history of, or any evidence of active, noninfectious pneumonitis. Has an active infection requiring intravenous systemic therapy. Has a history or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or laboratory abnormality that might confound the results of the trial, interfere with the subject's participation for the full duration of the trial, or is not in the best interest of the subject to participate, in the opinion of the treating investigator. Has known psychiatric or substance abuse disorders that would interfere with cooperation with the requirements of the trial. Is pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father children within the projected duration of the trial, starting with the prescreening or screening visit through 120 days after the last dose of trial treatment. Has received prior therapy with an antiPD1, antiPDL1, or antiPDL2 agent. Has a known history of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) (HIV 1/2 antibodies). Has known active Hepatitis B (e.g., HBsAg reactive) or Hepatitis C (e.g., HCV RNA [qualitative] is detected). Has received a live vaccine within 30 days of planned start of study therapy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>