<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02681016</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of sirolimus-eluting coronary stent "Calypso" (Angioline, Russia) in comparison with everolimus-eluting coronary stent "Xience" (Abbott Vascular, USA)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sirolimus-eluting Stent CALYPSO vs Everolimus-eluting Stent XIENCE</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Stenosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients considered for coronary angioplasty with stenting due to Ischemic heart disease (Stable angina, Unstable angina, nonST Myocardial Infarction). Target vessel lesion in coronary artery with diameter measurements &gt;2.5 mm &amp; &lt; 4.5 mm. Signed, documented informed consent prior to admission to the study Age &lt;18 years or &gt;75 years Renal insufficiency (GFR/MDRD &lt;30 ml/min) Subject has a platelet count &lt; 100,000 cells/mm3 or &gt; 700,000 cells/mm3. Known nonadherence to DAPT LVEF &lt;30% Known oncology Severe cardiac valvular pathology, requiring operative treatment within 1 year Anemia (HB&lt;100 g/l) Continuing bleeding Acute coronary syndrome (STelevation Myocardial infarction) Anamnesis of previous coronary angioplasty/stenting or CABG NYHA class (dyspnoea) IV or hospitalization during last year due to Chronic cardiac failure as a primary diagnosis. Pregnancy Coronary pathology requiring CABG or staged scheduled coronary angioplasty/stenting except cases of unscheduled staged coronary angioplasty/stenting within 4 weeks after primary procedure.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Calypso</keyword>
	<keyword>Xience</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary stenosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug-eluting stent</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary angioplasty with stenting</keyword>
	<keyword>Ischemic Heart Disease</keyword>
</DOC>