<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01579110</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether Levamisole plus prednisone can further improve the efficacy，extend the remission duration and reduce the dosage of prednisone for newly diagnosed warm antibody autoimmune hemolytic anemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Levamisole Combined With Standard Prednisolone in Warm Antibody Autoimmune Hemolytic Anemia.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The first line treatment in warm antibody autoimmune hemolytic anemia (WAIHA) is the glucocorticoid, but most of the patients, hemolytic events will frequently recurred after end of treatment or during the gradual reduction in dosage of prednisolone. As a result, many patients will finally accepted long-term glucocorticoids or other immunosuppressive drugs. How to reduce the relapse rate of AIHA is still difficult. Levamisole（LMS）is a immunoregulator.Recent studies have shown LMS has been widely used to treat autoimmune diseases ,such as rheumatoid arthritis, systemic lupus erythematosus and idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura. The purpose of this study is to determine whether LMS combined with prednisolone can further improve the efficacy，extend the remission duration and reduce the dosage of prednisone for newly diagnosed warm antibody autoimmune hemolytic anemia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autoimmune Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hematologic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemolysis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immune System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pathologic Processes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Hemolytic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Hemolytic, Autoimmune</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autoantibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levamisole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical and biochemical signs of hemolytic anaemia Positive Coombs test with antiIgG or and with antiCD3d Newly diagnosed Warm Autoimmune Hemolytic Anemia Adequate contraceptive measures for women of childbearing potential informed consent signed Active infection which requires antibiotic treatment Pregnant or lactating women Epilepsy and mental illness Kidney and liver function abnormal</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>autoimmune hemolytic anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>hemolytic anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Levamisole</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment of autoimmune hemolytic anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>warm antibody dependant autoimmune hemolytic anemia</keyword>
</DOC>