<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01125501</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Protandim will decrease markers of oxidative stress/inflammation in subjects with metabolic syndrome and proteomics will identify protein profiles that correlate with markers or/changes in oxidative stress.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Protandim and the Metabolic Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Evaluate the effects of Protandim on protein profile changes and markers of inflammation and oxidation in subjects (40-60 years of age) with the Metabolic Syndrome.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age = 4060 years of age Meets at least 3 of the 5 criteria for the metabolic syndrome (as defined by NCEP/ATP III criteria) NCEP/ATP III criteria Central obesity as measured by waist circumference: Men — Greater than 40 inches Women — Greater than 35 inches Fasting blood triglycerides greater than or equal to 150 mg/dL Blood HDL cholesterol: Men — Less than 40 mg/dL Women — Less than 50 mg/dL Blood pressure greater than or equal to 130/85 mmHg or on antihypertensive Rx Fasting glucose greater than or equal to 100 but &lt; 125 mg/dL Women taking hormone replacement therapy for post menopause Signs or symptoms of acute coronary syndrome History of congestive heart failure (prior myocardial infarction, coronary artery disease including stent placement, coronary artery bypass graft, EBCT calcium score of at least 100, or a positive stress test) Serum creatinine &gt; 1.5 mg/dL, AST or ALT &gt; 2 times ULN, HgA1c &gt;6.5%, severely depressed or elevated blood cell lines, triglycerides &gt; 500, TSH outside of normal range, elevated calcium, blood pressure &gt; 160/100, urine protein &gt; 30 ,g/dl. Concurrent medical conditions/illnesses in which expected life expectancy is 2 years or less and/or are likely to require frequent hospitalizations and treatment adjustments (e.g., cirrhosis, active malignancy, , or highly active rheumatologic condition, lupus, rheumatoid arthritis or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and diabetes). Participation in any other investigational substance or medical device study within 30 days before this trial and/or participation in such entity during this trial. Known pregnancy. Supplementation with nutraceuticals or if so one month washout before initiating the study before initiating this trial. Taking statins or fibrates to lower cholesterol Inability or unwillingness to provide written informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>