<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02782715</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The specific aims of this study are: 1. To determine the safety and feasibility of treating patients with a combination of MRI guided stereotactic body radiation therapy and microwave ablation. 2. To assess short and long-term toxicity rates of patients treated with a combined modality approach. 3. To assess local control, survival, and pathologic response to treatment</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PII SBRT + Microwave Ablation in Renal Cell Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Renal cell carcinoma is traditionally managed via a surgical approach. Increasingly, local therapy with radiofrequency and microwave ablation is being utilized as an alternative for patients who may not tolerate a nephrectomy or who refuse one. Although local control rates for small lesions are excellent, they drop off precipitously for lesions over 4 cm. Furthermore, lesions in critical areas such as the renal hilum may be difficult to treat with this method. Stereotactic body radiation therapy (SBRT) has had a long record of treating patients with inoperable tumors in locations such as the lung and central nervous system, and there is increasing evidence that it may be useful for patients with renal cell carcinoma. The recent emergence of MRI-guided radiation therapy allows for direct visualization of tumors during treatment, and may potentially allow clinicians to treat tumors more precisely. This phase I study will treat renal cell carcinoma patients using a combination of MRI-guided stereotactic body radiation therapy and microwave ablation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with imaging findings consistent with renal cell carcinoma Deemed medically inoperable per urology evaluation Tumor size &gt;4cm in largest dimension ECOG performance status of &lt;2 Signed informed consent document(s) Patients with metastatic disease will not be excluded Patients who fail MRI screening Pregnant or nursing women History of prior radiation therapy to the upper abdomen History of invasive cancer in the last 3 years (except for appropriately treated lowrist prostate cancer, treated nonmelanoma/melanoma skin cancer, appropriately treated ductal carcinoma in situ or early stage invasive carcinoma of breast and appropriately treated insitu/early stage cervical/endometrial cancer) Treatment with a nonapproved or investigational drug within 28 days of study treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>