<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02782312</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to assess the efficacy and safety of Salmeterol-Fluticasone （ICS and LABA）combined inhaled therapy for non-cystic fibrosis（non-CF）bronchiectasis patients with chronic airflow obstruction. Moreover, subgroup analysis is performed to explore which populations of bronchiectasis patients this treatment is suitable for.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Salmeterol-Fluticasone Combined Inhaled Therapy for Non-cystic Fibrosis Bronchiectasis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Inhaled ICS and LABA have proved obvious benefit for asthma or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) patients. However, there is presently no clear evidence on the effect of ICS and LABA combined inhaled therapy for non-CF bronchiectasis patients. This study is designed as a prospective, randomized,control trial. Patients are divided into two groups, one group inhaled with ICS and LABA (Seretide), another group received routine therapy (oxygen uptake, phlegm dissipation, hemostasis postural drainage and naturopathy).The course of treatment is 12 months. All patients underwent reviews at baseline entry to the study and at months 6 and 12 of treatment. The quality of life (QOL) scores：St George's dyspnea score (SGRQ score）, modified british medical reserach council（mMRC score) and COPD assessment test (CAT score); lung function test: forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV1）,FEV1% predicted, the ratio of forced expiratory volume in one second and forced vital capacity (FEV1/FVC%); short-acting β2-adrenergic agonist（SABA）use and the incidence of adverse event were monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Bronchiectasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone Propionate, Salmeterol Xinafoate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Salmeterol Xinafoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>stable bronchiectasis; have the ability to complete the pulmonary function tests; FEV1/FVC&lt;70%; ≥2 exacerbations within the past year a cigarette smoking history more than 10 packyears;cystic fibrosis or traction bronchiectasis due to various pulmonary fibrosis; an active pulmonary mycobacterial infection; fungal infection; active sarcoidosis; active allergic bronchopulmonary aspergillosis (ABPA); asthma as defined by the Global Initiative for Asthma (GINA); patients with severe cardiopulmonary dysfunction; with impaired hepatic or kidney function; with hypogammaglobulinemia or other autoimmune diseases; pregnant or breastfeeding women; or patients with a known intolerance for ICS or LABAs.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bronchiectasis</keyword>
	<keyword>ICS+LABA</keyword>
</DOC>