<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02782923</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a single-center, prospective controlled simulation study designed comparing and evaluating the driving performance of subjects who have had cervical spine surgery and the use of a validated driving simulator. To date, there haven't been evidence-based recommendations to determine a patient's "fitness to drive" in the peri-operative or postoperative state. The objective of this study is to delineate the effect cervical spine procedures have on driving performance in the peri-operative time period. The study will take place at New York University Langone Medical Center - Hospital for Joint Diseases which will include the surgeries. The follow up visits will be at the NYU Center for Musculoskeletal Care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Driving After Cervical Spine Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Study Subjects Age between 18 and 80 years Indicated for elective cervical spine surgery (including ACDF [single or multilevel], posterior cervical laminectomy and fusion, posterior cervical laminoplasty, posterior cervical foraminotomy, cervical disc replacement) after failing at least 6 weeks of nonoperative treatment modalities Valid driving license Regular use of a vehicle Signed consent form Inclusion Criteria Control Subjects: Age between 18 and 80 years No preexisting or recent injuries to neck, torso, back No neurologic or systemic debilitating conditions Valid driving license Regular use of a vehicle Signed consent form Significant visual impairment Significant debilitating neurological condition with loss of function of one or more extremities Recent extremity surgery Recent eye surgery Previous history of motion sickness, vertigo in simulated settings Recent history of chemical or narcotic dependency involved in active litigation related to their spine problem a the time of screening. Involved in workers compensation related to their spine problem at the time of screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cervical Spine Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Simulation</keyword>
</DOC>