<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02782260</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Subjects with pterygium and associated dry eye symptoms (DES) are randomized into an active cohort (receiving ocular administration of Dipyridamole) or placebo cohort (ocular administration of vehicle). Monthly follow up is conducted for 12 months. Testing conducted at follow up will assess dry eye / pterygium symptoms and endpoints and review the efficacy of the intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessment of the Efficacy of Ocular Dipyridamole in the Treatment of Dry Eye Symptomology in Subjects With Pterygium</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Keratoconjunctivitis Sicca</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dry Eye Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pterygium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dipyridamole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Able to provide informed consent. Ineligible or refused surgical excision, or had recurrence of pterygium following surgical excision Able to follow the study instructions, including application of the study product Agreement not to change the type of lubricating eye drops used (if any) during their participation in the study. Assessed as having at least pterygium stage 01 (pinguecula) based on Johnston, Williams &amp; Sheppard's classification for pterygium Concomitant dry eye symptoms, as determined by one or more of the following Subject interview (modified Ocular Surface Disease Index test), Tearing, Itch / foreign body sensation, Positive Fluorescein test, Positive TBUT test, Positive Tear meniscus test Inability to provide informed consent Dry eye due to other factors Known lacrimal obstruction Contact lens wearers Noncorrected refraction Allergy or sensitivity to dipyridamole or excipients Use of dipyridamole in the last 6 months Other eye conditions (i.e. active ocular infection, herpes keratitis in last 6 months, corneal disorder abnormality excluding pterygium, history of ocular acne rosacea, blepharitis) which would impact results Diagnosis of ALS (Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis) Existing conditions which are contraindicated or precaution in use of dipyridamole or excipients Use of eye drops (other than ocular lubricants) Pregnant or breastfeeding Inability to apply the medical product or follow the study procedures Anything that the PI thinks would impact the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>