<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="67700">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02224508</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PCORI-1306-02198</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02224508</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of a Health Plan Initiative to Mitigate Chronic Opioid Therapy Risks</brief_title>
  <acronym>CARE</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of a Health Plan Initiative to Mitigate Chronic Opioid Therapy Risks</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Group Health Cooperative</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Group Health Cooperative</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Sixty million American adults suffer from moderate to severe chronic pain. Of
      these, 5 to 8 million currently use opioids long-term. With increased opioid prescribing for
      chronic pain, an epidemic of prescription opioid addiction and overdose has arisen. This
      necessitates action to stem opioid-related morbidity and mortality. Group Health (GH), a
      large nonprofit health plan, developed and implemented opioid risk reduction strategies for
      doctors and patients in some, but not all, of its clinics. The risk reduction initiative
      achieved large opioid dose reductions, near universal documentation of care plans, and
      marked increases in patient monitoring. Rigorous evaluation of patient outcomes resulting
      from the opioid risk reduction initiative, incorporating patient perspectives, is needed to
      guide health care improvement efforts to reduce opioid risks regionally and nationally.

      Research goal: The investigators will evaluate a major health plan initiative to reduce
      risks of long-term opioid use for chronic pain. Starting in 2008, some GH clinics reduced
      prescribing of high opioid doses. In 2010 the same clinics increased care planning and
      monitoring of chronic opioid therapy (COT) patients. Our research goal is to evaluate
      effects of this initiative on health and safety outcomes of COT patients. We will test
      whether the initiative influenced pain outcomes; patient-reported opioid benefits and
      problems; and opioid-related adverse events.

      Design and Outcomes: The investigators will assess effects of GH's opioid risk reduction
      initiative among COT patients using opioids long-term. The investigators will compare COT
      patients from clinics that implemented the initiative with COT patients from care settings
      that did not implement the initiative. The investigators will use survey data to assess
      patient-reported outcomes including pain severity, depressive symptoms, and patient
      perceptions of opioid benefits and problems, including validated measures of prescription
      opioid use disorder. They will interview and compare 800 COT patients using opioids
      long-term from clinics that implemented the risk reduction initiative and 800 COT patients
      from care settings that did not.

      Impact: This research will provide an urgently needed, rigorous evaluation of a major risk
      reduction initiative among COT patients. Evaluation results will guide efforts of health
      plans, clinicians and patients nationwide to ensure safe, effective and compassionate
      chronic pain care.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Detailed description not provided
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prescription Opioid Use Disorder (defined by DSM5 criteria).</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year prior to interview</time_frame>
    <description>Prescription Opioid Use Disorder is defined by multiple indicators of opioid abuse and addiction from 9 criteria in the DSM5 manual of the American Psychiatric Association. In this research, it will be assessed using the Psychiatric Research Interview for Substance and Mental Disorders (PRISM5, Columbia University)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain severity (intensity, interference with activities, enjoyment): PEG scale</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week prior to interview</time_frame>
    <description>PEG (Pain - Enjoyment - Interference with General Activities) pain scale consisting of 3 0-10 ratings of pain intensity, interference with activities due to pain, and reduced enjoyment of life due to pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Depression</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks prior to interview</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ-8) depression scale</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1589</enrollment>
  <condition>Drug Use Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Drug Abuse</condition>
  <condition>Drug Addiction</condition>
  <condition>Drug Dependence</condition>
  <condition>Drug Habituation</condition>
  <condition>Pain</condition>
  <condition>Depressive Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Opioid Risk Reduction Initiative</arm_group_label>
    <description>Opioid risk reduction initiative for chronic opioid therapy patients implemented in Group Health integrated group practice clinics.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care</arm_group_label>
    <description>Usual care for management of chronic opioid therapy patients implemented in Group Health network care settings.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population will be Chronic Opioid Therapy (COT) patients from Group Health
        clinics. We will interview and compare 800 COT patients using opioids long-term from
        clinics that implemented the risk reduction initiative and 800 COT patients from care
        settings that did not.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Enrolled for at least one year prior to sampling for survey

          -  Received 70+ days supply of opioids in 2 of 4 quarters, including the most recent 90
             days

          -  Received 45+ days supply of opioids in the other 2 quarters

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Received cancer diagnoses, other than non-melanoma skin cancer, at least twice in the
             prior year

          -  Received any skilled nursing facility care in the prior year

          -  Received any hospice care or

          -  Received any opioids from an oncologist
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael R VonKorff, ScD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Group Health Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 3, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 15, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Analgesics, Opioid</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>A complete, cleaned, de-identified copy of the final dataset used in conducting the final analyses will be made available to other qualified researchers within nine months of the end of the final year of funding upon approval by the Group Health Human Subject's Review Committee.
Given the complexity of the final dataset, our expectation would be that other researchers using the data would require technical assistance from our research team to understand the data and to employ appropriate methods of data analysis. Or, other researchers may prefer to have us analyze the study data to produce analyses according to their specifications. Since use of the dataset by other investigators, or analyses carried out by us for other researchers, would occur after the grant award period has ended, we will expect necessary funding of technical support, data transfers and/or data analyses to be obtained by the research team requesting access to the final dataset.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
