<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02709265</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate systemic and urine pharmacokinetics in spontaneously breathing healthy volunteers following a single dose of amikacin/fosfomycin, using the PARI Investigational eFlow Nebulizer System or the PARI LC Sprint Nebulizer. Three doses (30/12 mg, 60/24 mg, 90/36 mg amikacin/fosfomycin) will be evaluated. Following this evaluation, a single dose and nebulizer will be chosen to further evaluate systemic, bronchoalveolar, and urine pharmacokinetics in spontaneously breathing healthy volunteers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-Label Phase 1 Study of Aerosolized Amikacin and Fosfomycin in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 1 open-label study of three doses of amikacin/fosfomycin. Approximately 30 healthy volunteers will be dosed in five cohorts of six subjects each. The first (sentinel) subject in each of the first three cohorts will be dosed alone. If no significant safety or tolerability events occur, the remaining five subjects in each of the first three cohorts will be dosed. The first cohort (n=6) will be administered the 30/12 mg dose of amikacin/fosfomycin. The second cohort (n=6) will be administered the 60/24 mg dose of amikacin/fosfomycin. The third cohort (n=6) will be administered the 90/36 mg dose of amikacin/fosfomycin. All doses in cohorts 1, 2, and 3 will be delivered with the PARI Investigational eFlow Nebulizer System. The fourth cohort (n=6) will be administered the 90/36 mg dose of amikacin/fosfomycin using the PARI LC Sprint Nebulizer. The fifth cohort (n=6) will test the lowest dose level at which all subjects achieved &gt; 0.3 µg/mL amikacin peak serum concentration. The nebulizer used to deliver doses in cohort 5 will be determined after amikacin concentrations from cohorts 1 through 4 are reviewed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Amikacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fosfomycin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males or females aged ≥18 years and ≤ 80 years of age (Cohorts 1, 2, 3, and 4). Males or females aged ≥ 18 years and ≤ 65 years of age (Cohort 5). Females of childbearing potential must be using contraception. Acceptable methods of contraception include male or female condom with spermicide gel or foam, hormonal contraceptive combined with a condom, Intrauterine Device (IUD), tubal ligation, diaphragm with spermicide, or total abstinence with a backup if the subject becomes active. Able to communicate with site personnel and to understand and voluntarily sign the Informed Consent Form. History of previous allergy or sensitivity to amikacin or fosfomycin. Use of oral fosfomycin in the 28 days prior to admission to Phase 1 facility. History of reactive airways disease (such as asthma or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease [COPD]), cystic fibrosis, or bronchiectasis. Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) positive. Active Hepatitis B or C. Cigarette/eCigarette smoking or use of other nicotine or tobacco containing products within seven days prior to study drug administration. Positive for drugs of abuse or alcohol use at screening or admission to Phase 1 facility. A Breathalyzer test will be used to screen for the presence of alcohol. A urine standard panel will be used to test for the following substances (with serum testing for confirmation, as needed): Opiates Oxycodone Methadone Cocaine Tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) Benzodiazepines Amphetamines / Methamphetamines Barbiturates Methylenedioxymethamphetamine (MDMA) Phenylcyclohexyl piperidine (PCP) Tricyclic Antidepressants Participation in a clinical study with administration of an investigational drug product within the previous 30 days, or five halflives of the previously administered investigational product. Donation of blood or significant blood loss within the 8 weeks prior to admission to Phase 1 facility. Donation of plasma within the week prior to admission to Phase 1 facility. Any other condition which in the view of the Investigator is likely to interfere with the study or put the subject at risk. Pregnant or nursing.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>