<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00997256</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To demonstrate the influence of a herbal preparation containing hypericum, passionflower, and valerian on sleep structure, improvement of attention, and well-being in comparison to placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Investigate Effects of a Herbal Drug Compared to Placebo on Sleep</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To demonstrate the influence of the herbal combination preparation Neurapas® balance on the objective sleep structure in comparison with placebo. A further aim was to investigate whether treatment with Neurapas® balance versus placebo brings about an improvement in attention and well-being and whether these changes are related to the improvement in the sleep structure. 1. Does the administration of 3 x 2 Neurapas® balance tablets over a period of three days vs. placebo lead to an improvement in continuity of sleep? 2. Does the administration of 3 x 2 Neurapas® balance tablets over a period of three days vs. placebo lead to an improvement in sleep architecture, especially an increase in deep sleep? 3. Does the administration of 3 x 2 Neurapas® balance tablets over a period of three days vs. placebo lead to an improvement in morning attentional performance? 4. Does the administration of 3 x 2 Neurapas® balance tablets over a period of three days vs. placebo lead to an improvement in morning well-being?</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Healthy male volunteers aged between 18 and 55 years Normal sleeping times (at least 6 hours a night), going to sleep between 22.00 and 1.00 hours, getting up between 6.00 and 9.00 hours Written informed consent The volunteer is willing and able to cooperate fully The volunteer agrees not to drink any alcohol for the duration of the study Participation in another study in the last 30 days or participation in this study at an earlier date Lack of verbal or intellectual ability to communicate adequately and to understand the information to volunteers Legal incompetence Smoker Shift worker Transatlantic flight in the last 4 weeks Taking psychotropic drugs within the last 4 weeks Taking medicines that influence the EEG within the last 4 weeks Diseases that influence the sleep EEG History of known medication / drug / alcohol misuse according to ICD10 coding F10 F19 Known intolerance/hypersensitivity/allergy to St. John's wort, valerian or passionflower Taking inadmissible concomitant medication (anxiolytic, neuroleptic or hypnotic drugs, cyclosporin, sedative, sleeppromoting or moodenhancing medicines, antidepressants other than the trial medication, coumarintype anticoagulants, oral contraceptives, tranquillisers, homeopathic remedies, digoxin, theophylline, indinavir, nortriptyline, amitriptyline) Known lightsensitivity</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>sleep-EEG</keyword>
	<keyword>sleep architecture</keyword>
	<keyword>sleep duration</keyword>
	<keyword>sleep continuity</keyword>
	<keyword>REM-sleep</keyword>
	<keyword>vigilance</keyword>
	<keyword>well-being</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy volunteers</keyword>
</DOC>