<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00997776</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this trial was to examine the effectiveness of a short-term leg strengthening exercise program compared to attention control on improving leg strength, walking speed and endurance, physical performance, and physical function one year after hip fracture.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Leg Strengthening Exercise After Hip Fracture</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Poor functional outcomes are reported for the majority of older adults who sustain a hip fracture. The ability of hip fracture patients to make sustained functional improvements above and beyond natural recovery is unknown. It has been shown that gym-based programs can help old adults regain function after hip fracture. It is unclear if these results could be translated into the home setting that lacks the gym-based equipment, or if improvement would be sustainable. This program compares high intensity strength training performed in the home twice weekly for 10 weeks to an attention placebo control in which participants receive sensory electrical stimulation to leg muscles.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Successful fixation (partial or total hip replacement or open reduction internal fixation) of a hip fracture within the last 6 months Were 65 years of age or older, were living at home prior to the fracture, had a physician referral and were discharged from physical therapy. Medical history of unstable angina or uncompensated congestive heart failure, ongoing chemotherapy or renal dialysis, history of stroke with residual hemiplegia, Parkinson disease, absent sensation in the lower extremities due to sensory neuropathy, life expectancy of less than 6 months, and Folstein mental status scores &lt; 20.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hip Fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Functional Performance</keyword>
</DOC>