<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00614679</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective is to investigate the ability of systemic intravenous antibiotic plus antibiotic/anti-biofilm (i.e. N-acetylcysteine) lock catheter technique in eradicating uncomplicated catheter associated bacteremia and salvaging the infected vascular catheter. Secondary objectives include duration to clearance of bacteremia, future recurrence of bacteremia, need for catheter removal and death.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Novel Catheter Lock Solution for Treatment of Tunneled Hemodialysis Catheter-Associated Bacteremia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bacteremia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Catheter-Related Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tigecycline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients who have an indwelling hemodialysis catheter for 10 or more days and evidence of a catheter associated bloodstream infection as evidenced by 1)quantitative blood cultures obtained through the lumen of the catheter yield concentrations of bacterial colonies that are 5 or more fold higher than peripheral blood cultures, or 2)blood cultures obtained through the lumen of the catheter becomes positive 2 or more hours earlier than peripheral blood cultures. Patients will be excluded if 1) they are unable or unwilling to provide informed consent, 2) have evidence of a complicated bacteremia such as endocarditis, septic thrombophlebitis, septic emboli, osetoemylitis, deep seated abscesses etc 3)evidence of an exit site infection around the catheter such as a pus pocket, drainage or erythema. 4) patient is allergic to NAC or the proposed antibiotic (if patient is allergic to minocycline, tigecycline will not be used). 5) patient is pregnant or will become pregnant.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>biofilm</keyword>
	<keyword>catheter lock solution</keyword>
	<keyword>catheter salvage</keyword>
</DOC>