<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00614315</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this clinical study is to evaluate the performance of the Optimized FLAIR™ Delivery System.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>FLAIR™ Delivery System Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Constriction, Pathologic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The subject is either a male or nonpregnant female ≥ 18 years old. The subject has been properly informed about the study per IRB requirements, and has signed and dated the IRBapproved ICF. The subject is willing to comply with the protocol requirements and can be contacted by telephone. The subject has a synthetic AV access graft located in an arm that has been implanted for &gt; 30 days and has undergone at least one successful dialysis session prior to the index procedure. Angiographic evidence indicates that the subject has a stenosis of &gt;50% located at the graftvein anastomosis of the subject's synthetic AV access graft. The target lesion is estimated to be ≤ 7 cm in length by angiography prior to performance of any interventional procedures. The entire target lesion is located within 7 cm of the graftvein anastomosis, as verified by angiography, such that approximately 1 cm of the FLAIR™ Endovascular Stent Graft will extend into nondiseased vein and approximately 1 cm but no more than 2 cm of the FLAIR™ Endovascular Stent Graft will extend into nondiseased AV graft. Graft diameter at the deployment site is between 5 mm and 8 mm, as verified by angiography. Full expansion of an appropriately sized angioplasty balloon, in the operator's judgment, can be achieved during primary angioplasty. The subject has a life expectancy of &lt; 6 months. The presence of a previously placed stent and/or stent graft located in the treatment area. The treatment area is defined as the entire target lesion and 1 cm of landing zone into both nondiseased AV graft and nondiseased vein. The subject has an infected AV access graft or other infection. The location of the target lesion would require that the FLAIR™ Endovascular Stent Graft be deployed fully across the elbow joint. The location of the target lesion would require that the FLAIR™ Endovascular Stent Graft cross an angle (between the outflow vein and synthetic AV access graft) that is &gt; 90 degrees. The subject has an uncorrected blood coagulation disorder. The subject has a known allergy or sensitivity to contrast media which cannot be adequately premedicated. Subject is currently enrolled or scheduled to be enrolled in other investigations that conflict with followup testing or confounds data in this trial. The subject has a known hypersensitivity to nickeltitanium.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>