<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00614705</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a proof-of-concept study to determine if PH-797804 reduces neuropathic pain associated with post-herpetic neuralgia. Suitable patients will be randomized to receive either PH-797804 or placebo for 4 weeks, during which time they will also record their pain symptoms using various pain scales.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PH-797804 Versus Placebo For The Treatment Of Neuropathic Pain Associated With Post-Herpetic Neuralgia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuralgia, Postherpetic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female, at least 18 years of age Patients must have pain present for more than 3 months after healing of the Herpes zoster skin rash. There is no upper limit on the duration of PHN. Patients at screening visit (V1) must have a score ≥40 mm on the Pain Visual Analog Score (VAS). Patients having other severe pain, which may impair the selfassessment of the pain due to postherpetic neuralgia History within the previous year of: myocardial infarction, cardiac arrhythmia (e.g. atrial fibrillation, paroxysmal atrial fibrillation, atrial flutter, supraventricular tachycardia, ventricular tachycardia), left ventricular failure, New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class IIIIV congestive heart failure requiring treatment, unstable angina, coronary angioplasty, coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) or cerebrovascular accident (including transient ischemic attacks). Tuberculosis without treatment and/or positive tuberculin reaction to PPD (Purified Protein Derivative) without known (documented) vaccination with the bacilli CalmetteGuerin vaccine (BCG). A positive approved immunoassay/ELISA blood test for TB (e.g. TB TSPOT™, QuantiFERONGold Any clinically significant skin lesions as described in Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events for Dermatology (CTCAE) Version 3.0 ECG abnormalities at screening or randomization Evidence of organ dysfunction or hematopoietic disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>