<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02158676</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will recruit patients submitted to bariatric surgery. Individuals will be supplemented with 6g/day of prebiotic or synbiotic or placebo (maltodextrin) for 15 days. Immunological, metabolic and anthropometric parameters will be assessed before and after the supplementation. Our hypothesis is that prebiotic or synbiotic supplementation modulate plasma concentrations of immunological and metabolic parameters and anthropometric measures of subjects undergoing gastric bypass Roux-Y.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Prebiotic and Synbiotic Supplementation in Individuals Undergoing Roux-en-y Gastric Bypass.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will recruit patients submitted to roux-en-y gastric bypass. Individuals that meet the inclusion criteria will be randomized by means of a computer program on three study groups: 1) Prebiotic group: Oral supplementation with 6g/day of prebiotic for 15 days. 2) Synbiotic group: Oral supplementation with 6g/day of synbiotic for 15 days. 3) Placebo group (control): Oral supplementation with 6g/day of placebo (maltodextrin) for 15 days. Will be assessed the effects of supplementation on the plasma cytokines, plasma lipopolysaccharide (bacterial endotoxin), plasma cellular fatty acid profile, metabolic parameters (lipid profile, glycemic status and insulin resistance) and nutritional status. Blood samples will be collected before the surgery and the supplementation will begin 30 days after surgery.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Age greater than 18 years and less than 65 years Body mass index (BMI)&gt; 40kg/m2 or&gt; 35kg/m2 with at least one comorbidity Failure in the nonpharmacological and pharmacological treatment. Significant intellectual limitations without adequate family support. Uncontrolled psychiatric disorder. Alcohol dependence and / or illicit drugs dependence. Current use of antiinflammatory drugs and / or antibiotics and / or immunosuppressants Display intolerance prebiotics and / or probiotics and / or symbiotic Having made use of prebiotic and / or probiotic and / or symbiotic prior to the study period.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Roux-en-y gastric bypass</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammatory markers</keyword>
	<keyword>Nutritional status</keyword>
	<keyword>Fatty acids</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucose</keyword>
	<keyword>Prebiotic</keyword>
	<keyword>Synbiotic</keyword>
</DOC>