<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02158923</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether individualized ventilatory management combining the use of low tidal volumes, alveolar recruitment maneuvers, individually titrated positive end-expiratory pressure and postoperative individualized ventilatory support will decrease postoperative complications, unplanned ICU readmissions, ICU and hospital length of stay and mortality compared to a standardized Lung Protective Ventilation (LPV) for all patients at risk.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Individualized Perioperative Open Lung Ventilatory Strategy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Postoperative Complications</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory System Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age not less than 18 Risk of postoperative pulmonary complication moderatehigh defined by a score ≥ 26 on the risk scale ARISCAT (based on the analysis of seven factors, where a score between 26 and 44 points defines a moderate risk, and a score&gt; 44 points define a high risk, included in the Information Booklet Investigator). Planned abdominal surgery&gt; 2 hours. Signed informed consent for participation in the study. Age less than 18 years. Pregnant or breastfeeding. Patients with BMI &gt;35. Syndrome of moderate or severe respiratory distress: PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 200 mmHg. Heart failure: NYHA IV. Hemodynamic failure: CI &lt;2.5 L/min/m2 and / or requirements before surgery ionotropic support. Diagnosis or suspicion of intracranial hypertension (intracranial pressure&gt; 15 mmHg). Mechanical ventilation in the last 15 days. Presence of pneumothorax. Presence of giant bullae on chest radiography or computed tomography (CT). Patient with preoperatively CPAP. Participation in another experimental protocol at the time of intervention selection.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ventilation</keyword>
	<keyword>lung</keyword>
	<keyword>lung complications</keyword>
	<keyword>postoperative complications</keyword>
	<keyword>perioperative lung protective ventilation</keyword>
</DOC>