<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01688128</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to examine the efficacy of the Ubiquitous Spaced Retrieval-based Memory Advancement and Rehabilitation Training (U-SMART) in the elderly individuals with mild cognitive impairment (MCI) by an open-label, controlled, crossover Trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Ubiquitous SR-based Memory Advancement and Rehabilitation Training (U-SMART)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Spaced Retrieval-based Memory Advancement and Rehabilitation Training (SMART) which consisted of 24 one-hour face-to-face sessions (Lee, Park et al. 2009) was developed based on the spaced retrieval training (SRT), which was effective in improving memory retention span of very mild to mild Alzheimer's disease patients. The Ubiquitous SMART (U-SMART) by transforming the current SMART to a self-administered program using an application working on IPAD was developed, and showed its feasibility and efficacy in the elderly individuals with mild cognitive impairment in the preliminary study. (ClinicalTrials.gov ID: NCT01628653) To validate the efficacy of the U-SMART, an open-label, controlled, crossover design of clinical trial were planned in this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged 5590 Educational level above 1 year and confirmed literacy Diagnosed to mild cognitive impairment by International Working Group on Mild Cognitive Impairment Clinical Dementia Rating (CDR) of 0 or 0.5 Diagnosed to dementia by DSMIV Evidence of delirium, confusion Any neurological conditions causing cognitive decline such as Parkinson's disease, brain hemorrhage, brain tumor, normal pressure hydrocephalus Evidence of severe cerebrovascular pathology History of lossofconsciousness over 1 hour due to head trauma or repetitive head trauma of mild severity History of substance abuse or dependence such as alcohol Presence of depressive symptoms that could influence cognitive function Presence of medical comorbidities that could result in cognitive decline Use of medication that could influence cognitive function seriously</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mild cognitive impairment</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Spaced retrieval Training</keyword>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Memory enhancement</keyword>
	<keyword>U-healthcare</keyword>
</DOC>