<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01688323</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To look at what types of measures can be used to predict how an older person will tolerate chemoradiation treatment for head and neck cancer. This study uses surveys and a blood draw to look at the different measures.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Finding Predictors of Side Effects to Chemoradiation Treatment in Elderly Patients With Head and Neck Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Purpose: To identify baseline predictors of change in function over the course of treatment with chemoradiotherapy in patients with head and neck cancer. Participants: Patients 65 or older who have an appointment at the North Carolina Cancer Hospital (NCCH) or other participating sites, have planned chemoradiotherapy for head and neck cancer Procedures (methods): Consenting subjects will complete a Geriatric Assessment, Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy - Head and Neck and give a blood sample for CBC and p16INK4a at the start of their chemoradiotherapy, at week four, at the end and 90 days post therapy. They will also complete a health behavior questionnaire at baseline.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients will be eligible for this protocol provided they have an appointment at the North Carolina Cancer Hospital (NCCH), have planned chemoradiotherapy for head and neck cancer (any histology) and consent to complete the Geriatric Assessment. No exclusions will be made based on gender, ethnicity, performance status or race. Patient must be able to read and speak English. Signed, IRB approved written informed consent. Age of at least 65 years. Enrollment in other studies, both therapeutic and observational, will not result in exclusion. Exclusion Criteria Inability to read and speak English. Inability to comply with study for any other reason than language</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Geriatrics</keyword>
	<keyword>Oncology</keyword>
	<keyword>Biological Markers</keyword>
	<keyword>Survey Instruments</keyword>
	<keyword>p16</keyword>
	<keyword>Geriatric Oncology</keyword>
	<keyword>Biological Markers of Aging</keyword>
	<keyword>Symptom Assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Older Persons</keyword>
	<keyword>Head and Neck Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>