<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02063399</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if the screening of nasopharyngeal carcinoma using plasma Epstein-Barr virus DNA analysis would result in the down-staging of the NPC cases in asymptomatic individuals.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma Screening Using Plasma Epstein-Barr Virus DNA Analysis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) infection is an important etiological factor for nasopharyngeal carcinoma (NPC). In a pilot study, we have shown that the analysis of Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) DNA in blood can detect early and asymptomatic NPC. However, it is unlcear if NPC screening can improve the prognosis of the screened NPC subjects. 20,000 male subjects aged from 40 to 60 will be recruited because the incidence of NPC is higher in this target group. Twenty millilitres of venous blood will be collected from each subject at enrolment for plasma EBV DNA analysis. Subjects who have initial positive results for plasma EBV DNA will have another testing within 4 weeks. Subjects who have persistently positive results for the two plasma EBV DNA analyses will be investigated using nasal endoscopic examination. A third blood samples will be collected on the day of endoscopy. For those subjects who have persistently positive plasma EBV DNA results on the three occasions but negative endoscopy results will be further investigated by MRI. After the initial screening, all participants will be phone interviewed yearly to update their cancer status.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nasopharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age 40 to 60 years ethnic Chinese male history of nasopharyngeal carcinoma currently having a malignant disease active autoimmune disease HIV infection on systemic steroid treatment on immunosuppressant treatment</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>62 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>NPC</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer screening</keyword>
	<keyword>Plasma EBV DNA</keyword>
</DOC>