<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="7836">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03004924</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SHP640-303</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2016-003361-25</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03004924</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Bacterial Conjunctivitis With SHP640 Compared to PVP-Iodine and Placebo</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 3, Multi-center, Randomized, Double-Masked Study to Evaluate the Clinical Efficacy and Safety of SHP640 (PVP-Iodine 0.6% and Dexamethasone 0.1%) Ophthalmic Suspension Compared to Placebo in the Treatment of Bacterial Conjunctivitis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shire</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shire</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine if an investigational treatment is effective
      compared with placebo and PVP-Iodine in the treatment of adults and children with bacterial
      conjunctivitis.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of SHP640 and Placebo on clinical resolution as measured by bulbar conjunctival injection</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 5</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of SHP640 and Placebo on clinical resolution as measured by watery conjunctival discharge</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 5</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bacterial Eradication Status of SHP640 and Placebo as measured by absence of all bacterial species</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 5</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">721</enrollment>
  <condition>Adenoviral Conjunctivitis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SHP640</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants instructed to instill 1 drop of SHP640 (0.1 percent (%) Dexamethasone and 0.6% povidone-iodine [PVP-I]) ophthalmic suspension in each eye 4 times daily (QID) (with a minimum of 2 hours between doses) for 7 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PVP-I 0.6%</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants instructed to instill 1 drop of PVP-I (0.6% PVP-I) ophthalmic solution in each eye 4 times QID (with a minimum of 2 hours between doses) for 7 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants instructed to instill 1 drop of placebo ophthalmic solution in each eye 4 times QID (with a minimum of 2 hours between doses) for 7 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SHP640</intervention_name>
    <description>Instill 1 drop of SHP640 (0.1% Dexamethasone and 0.6% povidoneiodine [PVPI]) ophthalmic suspension in each eye QID (with a minimum of 2 hours between doses) for 7 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SHP640</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PVP-I 0.6%</intervention_name>
    <description>Instill 1 drop of PVP-I (0.6% PVP-I) ophthalmic solution in each eye 4 times QID (with a minimum of 2 hours between doses) for 7 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PVP-I 0.6%</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Instill 1 drop of placebo ophthalmic solution in each eye 4 times QID (with a minimum of 2 hours between doses) for 7 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. An understanding, ability, and willingness to fully comply with study procedures and
             restrictions (by the parent(s), guardian, or legally authorized representative, if
             applicable).

          2. Ability to voluntarily provide written, signed, and dated (personally or via a
             parent(s), guardian, or legally-authorized representative(s) informed consent (and
             assent, if applicable) to participate in the study.

          3. Subjects of any age at Visit 1 (Note: subjects &lt; 3 months of age at Visit 1 must have
             been full-term, ie &gt;=37 weeks gestational age at birth).

          4. Have a positive AdenoPlus® test at Visit 1 in at least 1 eye.

          5. Have a clinical diagnosis of suspected adenoviral conjunctivitis in at least 1 eye
             (the same eye as the AdenoPlus positive eye) confirmed by the presence of the
             following minimal clinical signs and symptoms in that same eye:

               -  Report presence of signs and/or symptoms of adenoviral conjunctivitis for ≤ 3
                  days prior to Visit 1

               -  Bulbar conjunctival injection: a grade of &gt;=1 on 0-4 scale of Bulbar
                  Conjunctival Injection Scale

               -  Watery conjunctival discharge: a grade of &gt;=1 (mild) on a 0-3 Watery
                  Conjunctival Discharge Scale

          6. Be willing to discontinue contact lens wear for the duration of the study.

          7. Have a Best Corrected Visual Acuity (BCVA) of 0.60 logMAR or better in each eye as
             measured using an Early Treatment Diabetic Retinopathy Study (ETDRS) chart. BCVA will
             be assessed by an age appropriate method in accordance with the AAP Policy Statement
             for Visual System Assessment in Infants, Children, and Young Adults by Pediatricians
             (Donahue and Baker, 2016; American Academy of Pediatrics, 2016). The policy statement
             recommends formal vision screening can begin at 3 years of age. VA measurements for
             children under the age of 3 will be done at the discretion of the investigator. If
             not done, child should be able to fixate on and follow a moving object, except
             subjects &lt;2 months of age who have not yet developed this ability. Subjects &lt;2 months
             will be enrolled at the discretion of Investigator.

          8. Male, or non-pregnant, non-lactating female who agrees to comply with any applicable
             contraceptive requirements of the protocol or females of non-childbearing potential.

        Exclusion Criteria:

        Subjects are excluded from the study if any of the following exclusion criteria are met.

          1. Current or recurrent disease that could affect the action, absorption, or disposition
             of the investigational product, or clinical or laboratory assessments, per
             investigator's discretion.

          2. Current or relevant history of physical or psychiatric illness, any medical disorder
             that may make the subject unlikely to fully complete the study, or any condition that
             presents undue risk from the investigational product or procedures.

          3. Have known or suspected intolerance or hypersensitivity to the investigational
             product, closely related compounds, or any of the stated ingredients.

          4. Prior enrollment in a FST-100 or SHP640 clinical study.

          5. Subjects who are employees, or immediate family members of employees (who are
             directly related to study conduct), at the investigational site.

          6. Have a history of ocular surgical intervention within ≤ 6 months prior to Visit 1 or
             planned for the period of the study.

          7. Have a preplanned overnight hospitalization during the period of the study.

          8. Have presence of any intraocular, corneal, or conjunctival ocular inflammation (eg,
             uveitis, iritis, ulcerative keratitis, chronic blepharoconjunctivitis), other than
             adenoviral conjunctivitis.

          9. Have presence of corneal subepithelial infiltrates at Visit 1

         10. Have active or history of ocular herpes.

         11. Have at enrollment or within ≤30 days of Visit 1, a clinical presentation more
             consistent with the diagnosis of ocular allergy, toxic conjunctivitis, or
             non-adenoviral ocular infection (eg, bacterial, fungal, acanthamoebal, other or
             parasitic).

         12. Neonates or infants (ie. subjects less than 12 months of age) who have suspected or
             confirmed (based on the result of any test conducted prior to screening)
             conjunctivitis of gonococcal, chlamydial, herpetic or chemical origin.

         13. Neonates or infants (ie. subjects less than 12 months of age) whose birth mothers had
             any sexually transmitted disease within 1 month of delivery or any history of genital
             herpes.

         14. Presence of nasolacrimal duct obstruction at Visit 1 (Day 1).

         15. Presence of any significant ophthalmic condition (eg, Retinopathy of Prematurity,
             congenital cataract, congenital glaucoma) or other congenital disorder with
             ophthalmic involvement that could affect study variables.

         16. Be a known intraocular pressure (IOP) steroid responder, have a known history of
             glaucoma, be a glaucoma suspect, or have a known history of an elevated IOP &gt; 21
             mmHg.

         17. Have any known clinically significant optic nerve defects.

         18. Have a history of recurrent corneal erosion syndrome, either idiopathic or secondary
             to previous corneal trauma or dry eye syndrome; presence of corneal epithelial defect
             or any significant corneal opacity at Visit 1.

         19. Presence of significant, active condition in the posterior segment which requires
             invasive treatment (eg, intravitreal treatment with VEGF inhibitors or
             corticosteroids) and may progress during the study participation period.

         20. Have used any topical ocular or systemic anti-virals or antibiotics within &lt;= 7 days
             of enrollment.

         21. Have used any topical ocular NSAIDs within &lt;=1 day of enrollment.

         22. Have used any topical ophthalmic steroids in the last &lt;=14 days.

         23. Have used any systemic corticosteroid agents within &lt;=14 days of Day 1. Stable
             (initiated ≥30 days prior to enrollment) use of inhaled and nasal corticosteroids is
             allowed, given no anticipated change in dose for the duration of the study. Topical
             dermal steroids are allowed except in the peri-ocular area.

         24. Have used non-corticosteroid immunosuppressive agents within &lt;=14 days of Day 1.

         25. Have used any topical ophthalmic products, including tear substitutes, and
             over-the-counter preparations such as lid scrubs, within 2 hours of Visit 1 and be
             unable to discontinue all topical ophthalmic products for the duration of the study.
             Use of hot or cold compresses is also not permitted during the study.

         26. Have any significant ocular disease (eg, Sjogren's syndrome) or any uncontrolled
             systemic disease or debilitating disease (eg, cardiovascular disease, hypertension,
             sexually transmitted diseases/infections, diabetes or cystic fibrosis), that may
             affect the study parameters, per Investigator's discretion.

         27. Any known history of immunodeficiency disorder or known active conditions
             predisposing to immunodeficiency, such as human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis B
             or C, evidence of active hepatitis A (antihepatitis A virus immunoglobulin M), or
             organ or bone marrow transplantation.

         28. Within 30 days prior to the first dose of investigational product:

               -  Have used an investigational product or device, or

               -  Have been enrolled in a clinical study (including vaccine studies) that, in the
                  investigator's opinion, may impact this Shire-sponsored study.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shire Physician</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Shire</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Shire Contact</last_name>
    <email>ClinicalTransparency@Shire.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>December 22, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 19, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Conjunctivitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Conjunctivitis, Bacterial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Conjunctivitis, Inclusion</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Iodine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Povidone-Iodine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
