<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="58778">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02340819</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TED-C14-004</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02340819</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Safety, Efficacy and Pharmacokinetics of Teduglutide in Japanese Subjects With PN-dependent Short Bowel Syndrome (SBS)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A 3-Stage, Open-label, Multicenter Study Including Long-term Extension to Evaluate the Safety, Efficacy and Pharmacokinetics of Teduglutide in Japanese Subjects With PN-dependent Short Bowel Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shire</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shire</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of an investigational
      treatment (teduglutide) in Japanese patients with PN-dependent SBS. This study will also
      look at how teduglutide moves through the body (pharmacokinetics).
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute and percent change from baseline in weekly PN/I.V</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Absolute and percent change from baseline in weekly PN/I.V</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax (tmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre and Post Dose through 12 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Single-dose pharmacokinetics</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">11</enrollment>
  <condition>Short Bowel Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>0.05 mg/kg/day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Teduglutide</intervention_name>
    <description>0.05 mg/kg/day</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Men and women, 16 years of age or older at the time of signing the ICF

          2. Subjects with SBS as a result of major intestinal resection (eg, due to injury,
             volvulus, vascular disease, cancer, Crohn's disease) that resulted in at least 12
             continuous months of PN/I.V. dependency prior to signature of ICF

          3. For subjects with a history of Crohn's disease, the subject should be in clinical
             remission for at least 12 weeks prior to dosing as demonstrated by clinical
             assessment, which may include procedure-based evidence of remission.

          4. PN/I.V. requirement of at least 3 times per week during the week before screening and
             during the 2 weeks prior to baseline to meet caloric, fluid or electrolyte needs

          5. Stable PN/I.V. requirement for at least 4 consecutive weeks immediately prior to the
             start of teduglutide treatment,

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Participation in a clinical study using an experimental drug within 30 days or an
             experimental antibody treatment within 3 months prior to signing the ICF, or
             concurrent participation in any clinical study using an experimental drug that would
             affect the safety of teduglutide

          2. Previous use of native GLP-2 or human growth hormone within 6 months prior to
             screening

          3. Previous use of intravenous glutamine, octreotide, GLP-1 analog, or dipeptidyl
             peptidase-IV inhibitors within 30 days prior to screening

          4. Previous use of teduglutide

          5. Serial transverse enteroplasty or any other bowel lengthening procedure performed
             within the past 3 months

          6. Subjects with active Crohn's disease or subjects who require biological therapy (eg,
             anti-tumor necrosis factor or natalizumab) that had been introduced or changed during
             the 6 months prior to screening

          7. Subjects with inflammatory bowel disease who require chronic systemic
             immunosuppressant therapy that was introduced or changed during the last 3 months

          8. Unstable absorption due to cystic fibrosis, untreated Hirschsprung's disease or known
             DNA abnormalities (ie, Familial Adenomatous Polyposis, Fanconi syndrome)

          9. Radiographic or manometric evidence of pseudo-obstruction or severe known dysmotility
             syndrome

         10. Evidence of clinically significant obstruction on upper GI series with small bowel
             follow-through done within 6 months prior to screening

         11. Major GI surgical intervention within 3 months prior to screening (insertion of
             feeding tube or endoscopic procedure is allowed)

         12. Unstable cardiac disease, congenital heart disease or cyanotic disease, with the
             exception of subjects who had undergone ventricular or atrial septal defect repair

         13. Currently diagnosed with cancer or a history of any cancer except basal cell
             carcinoma within 5 years

         14. Active clinically significant pancreatic or biliary disease

         15. More than 4 SBS-related or PN-related hospital admissions (eg, catheter sepsis, bowel
             obstruction, severe water-electrolyte disturbances) within 12 months prior to
             screening visit

         16. Hospital admission, other than scheduled, within 30 days prior to screening

         17. Signs of severe hepatic impairment at time of stabilization.

         18. Signs of disturbed renal function at time of stabilization

         19. Clinical signs of abnormal pancreatic condition, with abnormal laboratory results at
             time of stabilization

         20. Pregnant or lactating women

         21. Female subjects who are not surgically sterile or postmenopausal (defined as 55 years
             or older and/or at least 2 years had elapsed since her last menses) or who are not
             using medically acceptable methods of birth control during and for 30 days after the
             treatment period

         22. Not capable of understanding or not willing to adhere to the study visit schedule and
             other protocol requirements

         23. Evidence of untreated intestinal obstruction or clinically significant active
             stenosis

         24. Any condition or circumstance that in the investigator's opinion put the subject at
             any undue risk, prevented completion of the study, or interfered with analysis of the
             study results
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shire Study Physician</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Shire</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tohoku University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sendai</city>
        <state>Aoba-ku</state>
        <zip>980-8574</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yokohama Municipal Citizen's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Yokohama</city>
        <state>Hodogaya-ku</state>
        <zip>240-8555</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital of Hyogo College of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hyogo</city>
        <state>Nishinomiya</state>
        <zip>663-8501</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Osaka University Hospital, Department of Gastroenterological Surgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>Osaka</city>
        <state>Suita</state>
        <zip>565-0871</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Osaka University Hospital, Department of Pediatric Surgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>Osaka</city>
        <state>Suita</state>
        <zip>565-0871</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 2, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>November 13, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Short Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
