<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00897611</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Studying levels of tumor DNA in the samples of blood from patients with cancer may help doctors find out whether the cancer has grown and how much. PURPOSE: This laboratory study is comparing levels of tumor DNA with MRI and CT scan findings to measure cancer growth in patients with grade III or grade IV malignant glioma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tumor DNA and MRI/CT Scan Findings in Patients With Grade III or Grade IV Malignant Glioma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Correlate changes in the level of serum tumor-specific DNA over time with changes in brain tumor size as measured by serial MRI or CT scans in patients with grade III-IV malignant gliomas. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Blood samples are collected from patients at baseline and every 2 months thereafter. Tumor and nontumor plasma is extracted. Plasma samples are analyzed by polymerase chain reaction (PCR) to assess the p16_ink4a, p73, and O ^6-MGMT gene promoter methylation profile. Quantitative realtime PCR is performed on samples with tumor-specific DNA to determine the plasma concentrations of each methylated tumor-specific gene and the total plasma tumor-specific DNA concentration. Patients also undergo MRI or CT scans every 2 months. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 60 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed malignant brain tumor One of the following grade III or IV supratentorial gliomas: Anaplastic astrocytoma Anaplastic oligodendroglioma Glioblastoma multiforme Newly diagnosed or recurrent disease Planning to undergo anticancer therapy on a New Approaches to Brain Tumor Therapy (NABTT) Consortium clinical trial PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Karnofsky performance status 60100% PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic oligodendroglioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult giant cell glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult brain tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>adult glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult gliosarcoma</keyword>
</DOC>