<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="214741">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00290147</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NMRC 2004.0002</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>WRAIR 1191</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>HSRRB A-13304</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>62787A 810S A0235</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00290147</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety Study of a Dengue Virus DNA Vaccine</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I Clinical Trial of a Dengue-1 DNA Vaccine</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>U.S. Army Medical Research and Materiel Command</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Army Medical Materiel Development Activity</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>U.S. Army Medical Research and Materiel Command</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to exame the safety of a DNA vaccine against dengue-1.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Dengue is a desease that affects 100 million people throughout the world mainly in tropical
      countries in the South Pacific, Asia, the Caribbean, and Africa. The disease often presents
      with high fever, severe headache, and joint/muscle pain that usually goes away on its own,
      but it can also present as a sometimes deadly hemorrhagic (bleeding) disease. Humans catch
      this disease by being bitten by mosquitoes that have been infected with dengue virus.
      Scientists at the Naval Medical Research Center have been working on vaccines to prevent
      dengue disease. This vaccine, referred to as D1ME, is an experimental DNA vaccine that
      contains genes from the dengue-1 virus. The purpose of this study is to test the safety of a
      new experimental vaccine against dengue and to see if the vaccine can stimulate the immune
      system.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2006</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and reactogenicity as evaluated by clinical visits and safety labs.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measurement of anti-dengue antibody and T cell responses.</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment>24</enrollment>
  <condition>Dengue</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>D1ME (dengue-1 premembrane/envelope DNA vaccine)</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Available to participate for the duration of the study (approximately 12 months)

          -  Completion and review of knowledge assement quiz

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Pregnant (by history or as ascertained by pregnancy test) or lactating female

          -  Female who intends to become pregnant during the study

          -  Plan to have elective surgery during the study period

          -  HIV infection

          -  Known immunodeficiency or currently receiving immunosuppressive therapy (inhaled and
             topical steroids are allowed)

          -  History of splenectomy

          -  Administration of a vaccine not foreseen by the study protocol during the period
             starting 30 days before each dose of vaccine and ending 30 days after vaccination

          -  Evidence of active (acute or chronic) hepatitis B or C infection

          -  Autoimmune diseaseor subjects who describe a first-degree relative with clearly
             documented autoimmune disease

          -  Acute or chronic, clinically significant cardiac, pulmonary, hepatic, or renal
             abnormality, as determined by physical examination or basic laboratory screening

          -  Clinical or laboratory evidence of significant anemia

          -  History of flavivirus infection or previous receipt of flavivirus vaccine

          -  Positive serology for flaviviruses (all four dengue virus serotypes, Japanese
             encephalitis, Yellow fever virus, and West Nile virus), HIV-1, Hepatitis B surface
             antigen, or anti-hepatitis C virus antibodies prior to enrollment

          -  Use of any investigational or non-registered drug or vaccine other than the study
             vaccine within 60 days preceding the first dose of study vaccine, or planned use
             during the study period.

          -  Previous history of allergic or anaphylactic reaction to any vaccine

          -  Planned travel to areas with endemic dengue during the study period

          -  Any other significant finding which, in the opinion of the investigator, would
             increase the risk of having an adverse outcome from participating in this protocol
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Charmagne Beckett, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Naval Medical Research Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Walter Reed Army Institute of Research, Bldg 503</name>
      <address>
        <city>Silver Spring</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20910</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2009</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>October 24, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 9, 2006</firstreceived_date>
  <keyword>Dengue</keyword>
  <keyword>DNA vaccine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Dengue</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
