<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01823809</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to assess the diagnostic accuracy of a combined use of non-invasive coronary angiography with multi-slice computed tomography (MSCT) and stress cardiac magnetic resonance (CMR) imaging in patients with obstructive lesions on MSCT and with low to intermediate pre-test likelihood of coronary artery disease (CAD) as compared to invasive coronary angiography (CAG) and Fractional Flow Reserve (FFR) measurements.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Non-invasive and Invasive Assessment of Coronary Artery Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenosine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients with stable angina pectoris with low to intermediate pretest likelihood of CAD; 2. no previous history of CAD; 3. obstructive stenosis (≥50% luminal narrowing) on MSCT coronary angiography; 4.informed consent. 1. patients with a previous history of CAD; 2. patients with contraindications for MSCT: a.cardiac rhythms other than sinus rhythm, b.pregnancy, c.allergy for contrast medium, d.renal failure (estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt; 50ml/min), e.resting heart rate &gt;75 bpm plus contraindications for betablockade, f. weight &gt;100 kilograms; 3. contraindications for cardiac magnetic resonance (CMR) imaging: a.MRincompatible implants, b. Claustrophobia, c. contraindications for adenosine: i. known or suspected hypersensitivity to adenosine, ii. known or suspected bronchoconstrictive or bronchospastic disease, iii. 2nd or 3rd degree atrioventricular (AV) block, iv. Sinus bradycardia (heart rate &lt; 45 bpm), v. Systemic arterial hypotension (&lt;90 mmHg). d. contraindications for gadolinium: i. renal failure (estimated eGFR &lt;30 ml/min); 4. no informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Computed Tomography</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiac Magnetic Resonance</keyword>
	<keyword>Fractional Flow Reserve</keyword>
</DOC>