<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01823094</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Investigators hope to learn more about how to use computed tomography (CT) scans to measure blood flow in lung tumors and how it may change in response to treatment. This measurement technique is called computed tomography perfusion (CTP). CT scanners use X-rays to produce 3-dimensional images of the body. Currently, doctors determine the response to treatment by measuring the size of the tumor. Investigators are trying to find out if measuring the blood flow in the tumor is equal to or better than measuring the size of the tumor.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CTP Imaging of Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an experimental study of CT perfusion (CTP) imaging in subjects with non-small cell lung cancer. The objectives of this study are to demonstrate the feasibility of CT blood flow measurements in lung cancer, to develop a foundation for the use of CT blood flow measurements in lung cancer to assess the response to treatment, and to develop an optimized CTP imaging protocol for evaluating blood flow in solid body tumors. In this study, tumor blood flow will be evaluated at baseline and follow-up routine CT examinations of patients with non-small cell lung cancer, and the response of tumor blood flow will be recorded as a secondary endpoint. This research study will entail two study visits - one required and one optional - which will coincide with regularly scheduled standard of care CT scans.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<criteria>adult patients with non small cell lung cancer who receive, or are considered for, systemic therapy renal failure pregnancy known contrast allergy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>computed tomography</keyword>
	<keyword>blood flow</keyword>
</DOC>