<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01913652</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Soft tissue sarcomas (STS) are a rare group of malignant heterogenous tumors (&gt; 50 histological subtypes, including liposarcoma, the commonest subtype of STS) with distinct genetic, pathological and clinical profiles, and varying patterns of tumor spread. The optimal cytotoxic treatment for this group of patients remains uncertain. Single agents which are most effective include doxorubicin and ifosfamide, but objective response rates and progression-free survival times remain modest. There is clearly a need to improve treatment options for liposarcoma. Eribulin, a antimicrotubule agent that targets the protein tubulin in cells, interfering with cancer cell division and growth , has demonstrated activity in STS. Therefore, it is reasonable to explore whether other anti-microtubule agent like cabazitaxel have a role in STS. Cabazitaxel has been shown to be a relatively safe, effective and tolerated. This drug has been approved by FDA for prostate cancer. The main objective of this trial is to determine whether cabazitaxel or prolonged infusional ifosfamide demonstrate sufficient antitumor activity for liposarcoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ph II Cabazitaxel DD Liposarcoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Liposarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ifosfamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isophosphamide mustard</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Local diagnosis of dedifferentiated liposarcoma Age 1870 yrs WHO performance status 01 Radiological or histological diagnosis of inoperable locally advanced or metastatic disease, with evidence of disease progression within the past 6 months Clinically and/or radiographically documented measurable disease within 21 days prior to randomization.At least one site of disease must be unidimensionally measurable according to RECIST 1.1. One previous chemotherapy regimen for locally advanced or metastatic dedifferentiated liposarcoma (this could include preoperative chemotherapy for primary disease if subsequent complete resection was not achieved). Adequate organ functions Birth control measures Written informed consent More than 1 prior molecularly targeted therapy (e.g. CDK4 inhibitor). Any prior such therapy must be completed at least 4 weeks before randomization. Symptomatic CNS metastases Previous encephalopathy of any cause or other significant neurological condition Concurrent or planned treatment with strong inhibitors or inducers of cytochrome P450 3A4/5 Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>dedifferentiated liposarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>cabazitaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>ifosfamide</keyword>
</DOC>