<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01913626</DOC>
	<brief_summary>assessing the Efficiency of cognitive group therapy for patients with subjective memory complains, using the neuropsychological computerized assessment of WebNeuro by Brain resource (BRC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assessing the Efficiency of Cognitive Group Therapy for Patient With Subjective Memory Complains Using the WebNeuro System From Brain Resource(BRC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>the study includes patients with subjective memory complains - who are concerned about having memory problems, that passed successfully the conventional basic cognitive assessment and who are not demented. the patients were referred to our occupational therapy clinic for cognitive group therapy. the aim of the study is to assess the efficiency of such therapy, using the neuropsychological computerized assessment of WebNeuro by Brain resource (BRC). the computerized assessment last 40 minutes and provide information about different cognitive aspects compared to a norm according to age, sex and education. each patient will pass the neuropsychological computerized assessment twice: at the beginning of the study and after participating in the cognitive group therapy. the cognitive group therapy is composed of eight meetings including information about memory processes, learning and practicing tools and strategies to improve cognition and memory. each individual will be his one control, we will compare the patient achievements in the different cognitive aspects before and after the cognitive intervention. our hypothesis is that the cognitive group therapy will improve the participants achievements in the neuropsychological computerized assessment.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>age 50 years old and more 8 years of education know reading and writing in hebrew know how to use the computer neurologic or psychiatric conditions: apraxia, aphasia, depression, brain tumor</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>subjective memory complains</keyword>
</DOC>