<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="144217">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01223235</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10-099</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01223235</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Polyvalent Vaccine-KLH Conjugate + Opt-821 Given in Combination With Bevacizumab</brief_title>
  <official_title>A PILOT STUDY OF A POLYVALENT VACCINE-KLH CONJUGATE + OPT-821 GIVEN IN COMBINATION WITH BEVACIZUMAB IN PATIENTS WITH RECURRENT EPITHELIAL OVARIAN, FALLOPIAN TUBE, OR PRIMARY PERITONEAL CANCER WHO ARE IN SECOND OR GREATER COMPLETE OR PARTIAL CLINICAL REMISSION</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Genentech, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The immune system of the body has the ability to fight and eliminate infections and cancers.
      Immune treatments, such as in this study, seek to teach the immune system to find and
      destroy cancer cells. The purpose of this study is to test whether it is safe to treat the
      cancer with a vaccine and another drug called bevacizumab (also known as Avastin).
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To establish the safety of immunization with polyvalent antigen - KLH + OPT-821 vaccine conjugate</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>in combination with bevacizumab in patients with recurrent epithelial ovarian, fallopian tube or primary peritoneal cancer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the immunogenicity of the vaccine</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>when given in the presence of bevacizumab</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To explore the relationship between a multiplex biomarker panel of angiogenesis markers and progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Fallopian Tubes Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Peritoneal Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>bevacizumab &amp; polyvalent vaccine-KLH conjugate + OPT-821</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is a single institution, open label, pilot study of bevacizumab and the polyvalent vaccine-KLH conjugate + OPT-821 in patients with recurrent epithelial ovarian, fallopian tube, or primary peritoneal cancer.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>bevacizumab and the polyvalent vaccine-KLH conjugate + OPT-821</intervention_name>
    <description>A maximum of 6 doses of the polyvalent-KLH vaccine and OPT-821 will be administered to each patient as per the schedule. Bevacizumab will be administered once every two weeks until week 11 and then once every three weeks according to the schedule. When the 6 vaccinations of the polyvalent-KLH vaccine +OPT821 are completed, patients may still continue to receive bevacizumab on the once every three week schedule.</description>
    <arm_group_label>bevacizumab &amp; polyvalent vaccine-KLH conjugate + OPT-821</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Histologically documented epithelial carcinoma arising in the ovary, fallopian tube
             or peritoneum.

          -  Patients who have received cytoreductive surgery and chemotherapy with at least one
             platinum based chemotherapy regimen. Patients who received neoadjuvant chemotherapy
             are eligible.

          -  Patients with relapsed ovarian, fallopian tube or primary peritoneal cancer who have
             now completed chemotherapy and/or surgery for recurrent disease. Eligible patients
             are those who would be appropriate to enter a period of observation if standard
             management were considered.

          -  Patients who have asymptomatic residual measurable disease on CT scan or be in
             complete clinical remission. Patients may have an elevated CA-125. (Complete clinical
             remission is defined as serum CA-125 ≤ 35 IU/ml, negative physical examination and
             without objective evidence of disease by computed tomography (CT) of the abdomen and
             pelvis.)

          -  Adequate hematologic, coagulation, renal and hepatic function.

          -  ANC &gt; = to 1,000 cells/mm3; platelets &gt; or = 100,000 cells/mm3

          -  PT such that international normalized ratio (INR) is &lt; 1.5 (or an in-range INR,
             usually between 2 and 3, if a patient is on a stable dose of therapeutic warfarin)
             Serum creatinine &lt; or = to 1.5 mg/dl

          -  Bilirubin, SGOT, Alk Phos &lt; 2.5x upper limit normal

          -  Urine protein : creatinine (UPC) ratio must be &lt; 1 . If UPC ratio &gt; 1, collection of
             24-hour urine measurement of urine protein is recommended as part of the patient's
             medical management off-study.

          -  Karnofsky performance status &gt; 70%

          -  Expected survival of at least 4 months

          -  Age ≥ 18 years. This protocol does not include children because the number of
             children with cancer is limited, and because a nationwide pediatric cancer research
             network already accesses the majority. Furthermore, the incidence of ovarian,
             fallopian tube, or peritoneal cancer in children is extremely infrequent.

          -  Patients who are ≥ 4 weeks from completion of prior cytotoxic chemotherapy. Prior
             bevacizumab and/or immunotherapy treatment are permitted

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Inability to comply with study and/or follow-up procedures

          -  Current or recent (within 4 weeks of the first infusion of this study) participation
             in another experimental drug study.

          -  Active malignancy, other than superficial basal cell and superficial squamous (skin)
             cell, or carcinoma in situ of the cervix within last five years

          -  Patients must have undergone standard cytoreductive surgery as part of primary
             treatment to be eligible for this study and therefore are not of childbearing
             potential.Nursing mothers are excluded.

          -  Inadequately controlled hypertension (defined as systolic blood pressure &gt;150 mmHg
             and/or diastolic blood pressure &gt; 90 mmHg)

          -  Prior history of hypertensive crisis or hypertensive encephalopathy

          -  New York Heart Association (NYHA) Grade II or greater congestive heart failure (see
             Appendix C)

          -  History of myocardial infarction or unstable angina within 6 months prior to Day 1

          -  History of stroke or transient ischemic attack within 6 months prior to Day 1

          -  Known CNS disease, except for treated brain metastasis

          -  Treated brain metastases are defined as having no evidence of progression or
             hemorrhage after treatment and no ongoing requirement for dexamethasone, as
             ascertained by clinical examination and brain imaging (MRI or CT) during the
             screening period. Anticonvulsants (stable dose) are allowed. Treatment for brain
             metastases may include whole brain radiotherapy (WBRT), radiosurgery (RS; Gamma
             Knife, LINAC, or equivalent) or a combination as deemed appropriate by the treating
             physician. Patients with CNS metastases treated by neurosurgical resection or brain
             biopsy performed within 3 months prior to Day 1 will be excluded

          -  Significant vascular disease (e.g., aortic aneurysm, requiring surgical repair or
             recent peripheral arterial thrombosis) within 6 months prior to Day 1

          -  History of hemoptysis (≥ 1/2 teaspoon of bright red blood per episode) within 1 month
             prior to Day 1

          -  Evidence of bleeding diathesis or significant coagulopathy (in the absence of
             therapeutic anticoagulation) or tumor involving major vessels.

          -  Major surgical procedure such as laparotomy, open biopsy, or significant traumatic
             injury within 28 days prior to Day 1 or anticipation of need for major surgical
             procedure during the course of the study

          -  Core biopsy or other minor surgical procedure, excluding placement of a vascular
             access device, within 7 days prior to Day 1

          -  History of abdominal fistula or gastrointestinal perforation within 6 months prior to
             Day

          -  Patients with clinical symptoms or signs of GI obstruction who require parenteral
             hydration, parenteral nutrition, or tube feeding

          -  Patients with evidence of abdominal free air not explained by paracentesis or recent
             surgical procedure

          -  Serious, non-healing wound, active ulcer, or untreated bone fracture

          -  Known hypersensitivity to any component of bevacizumab

          -  Allergy to seafood

          -  Active autoimmune disease (i.e. rheumatoid arthritis, ulcerative colitis etc); or
             immune deficiency (HIV, hypogammaglobulinemia); or known active infections with
             Hepatitis B or Hepatitis C; or those receiving immunosuppressive drugs (such as
             chronic systemic corticosteroids or cyclosporin, etc); or those receiving chronic
             antiinflammatory drugs (intermittent use of anti-inflammatory drugs is permitted).
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Paul Sabbatini, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mskcc.org/mskcc/html/44.cfm</url>
    <description>Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>August 15, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>October 14, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>FALLOPIAN TUBE</keyword>
  <keyword>OVARY</keyword>
  <keyword>PERITONEUM</keyword>
  <keyword>BEVACIZUMAB (AVASTIN)</keyword>
  <keyword>GLOBO H-KLH CONJUGATE</keyword>
  <keyword>MUC-1 KLH</keyword>
  <keyword>OPT-821</keyword>
  <keyword>TF (C) - KLH</keyword>
  <keyword>TN(C)-KLH</keyword>
  <keyword>10-099</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peritoneal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
