<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02866669</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The central objective of this proposal is to rigorously compare two strategies designed to improve BP control in primary care practices serving rural Southeastern African Americans with low socioeconomic status (SES) living in the "Black Belt". The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) Disparities Report identifies individuals with rural residence, minority ethnicity, and low SES as being at high risk for poor health outcomes. The "Black Belt" region stretches from eastern Texas in an arc to Maryland and includes residents with all 3 of these characteristics - the proverbial triple threat. This traditionally agricultural region is characterized by steep poverty, low educational attainment, scarce resources, and mostly African American residents. The Black Belt is in the heart of the Stroke Belt, a geographic area long recognized to have the highest cardiovascular disease (CVD) mortality in the US. The AHRQ Disparities Report also cites that the Southeast has lower quality of care than the rest of the US, thus effective strategies to optimize CVD prevention in general and hypertension (HTN) control specifically are urgently needed here. In year 1 (AIM 1) we're engaging community members (community members who have experience being community peer advisors or have high blood pressure) to develop the study interventions and protocols. In years 2-5, the investigators will test these interventions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Collaboration to Improve Blood Pressure in the US Black Belt-addressing the Triple Threat</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>African American adults aged 1985 years Uncontrolled HTN, defined as BP &gt;140/90 mm Hg at the time of study enrollment Black Belt resident English speaking Willing to work with a peer coach Willing to sign informed consent Plans to move out of the area within the next two years Advanced illness with limited life expectancy Pregnant or plans to get pregnant in the next year Advanced chronic kidney disease (estimated glomerular filtration rate &lt;45 ml/min/1.73 m2) Unwillingness to work with a peer coach or to sign informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>