<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02521493</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase III trial studies response-based chemotherapy in treating newly diagnosed acute myeloid leukemia or myelodysplastic syndrome in younger patients with Down syndrome. Drugs used in chemotherapy work in different ways to stop the growth of cancer cells, either by killing the cells, by stopping them from dividing, or by stopping them from spreading. Response-based chemotherapy separates patients into different risk groups and treats them according to how they respond to the first course of treatment (Induction I). Response-based treatment may be effective in treating acute myeloid leukemia or myelodysplastic syndrome in younger patients with Down syndrome while reducing the side effects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Response-Based Chemotherapy in Treating Newly Diagnosed Acute Myeloid Leukemia or Myelodysplastic Syndrome in Younger Patients With Down Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the 2-year event-free-survival (EFS) for children with standard risk Down syndrome (DS) acute myeloid leukemia (AML) (minimal residual disease [MRD]-negative after one cycle of induction therapy) after elimination of high dose (HD) Ara-C (cytarabine) from the treatment regimen. II. To determine the 2-year EFS for children with high risk DS AML (MRD-positive after one cycle of induction therapy) after intensification of treatment equivalent to that used for high risk AML in children without DS. EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES: I. To determine the extent to which elimination of HD Ara-C from the treatment of standard risk DS AML decreases adverse events and resource utilization. II. To determine if elimination of HD Ara-C from treatment of standard risk DS AML results in a significant decrease in the number of days per patient spent on protocol therapy compared to predecessor study AAML0431. III. To determine if elimination of HD Ara-C from treatment of standard risk DS AML results in a significant decrease in the average number of days of hospitalization per patient compared to predecessor studies AAML0431 and A2971. IV. To determine if elimination of HD Ara-C from treatment of standard risk DS AML results in a significant decrease in the number (per patient) and rate (per duration of treatment) of sterile site infections compared to the predecessor study AAML0431. V. To determine if elimination of HD Ara-C from treatment of standard risk DS AML results in a significant decrease of resource utilization by AML treatment compared to the predecessor study AAML0431. VI. To compare the feasibility and analytical characteristics of flow cytometry, polymerase chain reaction (PCR) and targeted error-corrected sequencing of GATA binding protein 1 (globin transcription factor 1) (GATA1) mutations as methods to detect MRD in DS AML. VII. To establish a DS AML cell bank of viably frozen bone marrow samples collected at the end of induction and corresponding non-tumor deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) samples collected at end of Induction 1. OUTLINE: INDUCTION I: Patients receive cytarabine intrathecally (IT) on day 1 and intravenously (IV) continuously over 96 hours, daunorubicin hydrochloride IV over 1-15 minutes, and thioguanine orally (PO) twice daily (BID) on days 1-4. Induction I continues for a minimum of 28 days. Patients are assigned to 1 of 2 treatment arms based on their MRD status after completion of Induction I. ARM A (STANDARD RISK): INDUCTION II: Patients receive cytarabine IV continuously over 96 hours, daunorubicin hydrochloride IV over 1-15 minutes, and thioguanine PO BID on days 1-4. Induction II continues for a minimum of 28 days. INDUCTION III: Patients receive cytarabine, daunorubicin hydrochloride, and thioguanine as in Induction II. Induction III continues for a minimum of 28 days. INTENSIFICATION I: Patients receive cytarabine IV continuously over 168 hours on days 1-7 and etoposide IV over 60-120 minutes on days 1-3. Intensification I continues for a minimum of 28 days. INTENSIFICATION II: Patients receive cytarabine and etoposide as in Intensification I. Intensification II continues for a minimum of 28 days. ARM B (HIGH RISK): INDUCTION II: Patients receive high dose cytarabine IV over 1-3 hours BID on days 1-4 and mitoxantrone hydrochloride IV over 15-30 minutes on days 3-6. Induction II continues for a minimum of 28 days. INTENSIFICATION I: Patients receive high dose cytarabine IV over 1-3 hours BID and etoposide IV over 60-120 minutes on days 1-5. Intensification I continues for a minimum of 28 days. INTENSIFICATION II: Patients receive high dose cytarabine IV over 3 hours BID on days 1, 2, 8, and 9. Patients also receive asparaginase or asparaginase Erwinia chrysanthemi (E. carotovora) intramuscularly (IM) or IV over 30 minutes on days 2 and 9. Intensification II continues for a minimum of 28 days. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 1 month, monthly for 12 months, every 3 months for 12 months, every 6 months for 3 years, annually for 5 years, and then at relapse.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Down Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myeloproliferative Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Podophyllotoxin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Daunorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitoxantrone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cytarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Asparaginase</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>6-Mercaptopurine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thioguanine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>2-Aminopurine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have constitutional trisomy 21 (Down syndrome) or trisomy 21 mosaicism (by karyotype or fluorescence in situ hybridization [FISH]) Patients with previously untreated de novo AML who meet the criteria for AML with &gt;= 20% bone marrow blasts as set out in the World Health Organization (WHO) Myeloid Neoplasm classification Patients with cytopenias and/or bone marrow blasts who do not meet the criteria for the diagnosis of AML (WHO Myeloid Neoplasm classification) because of &lt; 20% marrow blasts are eligible if they meet the criteria for a diagnosis of myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS) Patients with a history of transient myeloproliferative disorder (which may or may not have required chemotherapy intervention), who: Are &gt; 8 weeks since resolution of transient myeloproliferative disease (TMD) with &gt;= 5% blasts, OR Patients sho have an increasing blast count (&gt;= 5%) in serial bone marrow aspirates performed at least 4 weeks apart Children who have previously received chemotherapy, radiation therapy or any antileukemic therapy are not eligible for this protocol, with the exception of cytarabine for the treatment of TMD There are no minimal organ function requirements for enrollment on this study Note: Previous cardiac repair with sufficient cardiac function is not an exclusion criteria Each patient's parents or legal guardians must sign a written informed consent All institutional, Food and Drug Administration (FDA), and National Cancer Institute (NCI) requirements for human subjects research must be met Patients with promyelocytic leukemia (FrenchAmericanBritish [FAB] M3) Prior therapy Patients =&lt; 30 days from the last dose of cytarabine used for treatment of TMD</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>91 Days</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>3 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>