<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00134563</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective was to determine the effect of teriflunomide on the frequency of relapses in patients with relapsing multiple sclerosis (MS). Secondary objectives were: - to evaluate the effect of teriflunomide on the accumulation of disability as measured by Expanded Disability Status Scale [EDSS], the burden of disease as measured by Magnetic Resonance Imaging [MRI] and patient-reported fatigue; - to evaluate the safety and tolerability of teriflunomide.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Teriflunomide in Reducing the Frequency of Relapses and Accumulation of Disability in Patients With Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study period per participant was approximatively 128 weeks broken down as follows: - Screening period up to 4 weeks, - 108-week double-blind treatment period (approximatively 2 years)*, - 16-week post-treatment elimination follow-up period. '*' Participants successfully completing the week 108 visit were offered the opportunity to enter the optional long-term extension study LTS6050 - NCT00803049.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Multiple sclerosis [MS] subject who was ambulatory (EDSS of ≤ 5.5) Exhibiting a relapsing clinical course, with or without progression (relapsing remitting, secondary progressive or progressive relapsing); Meeting McDonald's criteria for MS diagnosis; Experienced at least 1 relapse over the 1 year preceding the trial or at least 2 relapses over the 2 years preceding the trial; No relapse onset in the preceding 60 days prior to randomization; Clinically stable during the 30 days prior to randomization, without adrenocorticotrophic hormone [ACTH] or systemic steroid treatment. Clinically relevant cardiovascular, hepatic, neurological, endocrine or other major systemic disease; Significantly impaired bone marrow function; Pregnant or nursing woman; Alcohol or drug abuse; Use of cladribine, mitoxantrone, or other immunosuppressant agents such as azathioprine, cyclophosphamide, cyclosporin, methotrexate or mycophenolate before enrollment; Any known condition or circumstance that would prevent in the investigator's opinion compliance or completion of the study;</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Multiple Sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Relapsing Remitting</keyword>
	<keyword>Secondary Progressive</keyword>
	<keyword>Progressive Relapsing</keyword>
</DOC>