<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02935452</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Generating Engagement in Network Involvement (GENIE) Tool is designed to support people to find and join social activities in their own neighbourhoods. Evidence has shown that people with more social support have increased ability to manage long term conditions and ill health. Patients with Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease (COPD) have difficulty breathing every day; this is both tiring and makes its difficult to socialise as they did prior to having their condition. COPD can be managed with medicines, and exercise, but will never be cured, so it is considered a 'long term condition.' This study plans to use a social mapping tool (GENIE) with COPD patients that are already part of the community service. The aim of the study is to increase opportunities to socialise and get day to day support outside of the health service. Patients will be offered either the tool, or usual care. If the study is successful then use of health care may reduce in the COPD patients already using the COPD service.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Implementing and Evaluating the Genie Tool in COPD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The main aim here is to increase long term health care management options in Solent NHS ( National Health Service) Trust by building social capacity to support self-management. The GENIE tool will be introduced into the COPD service to improve options for social groups and exercise when leaving a pulmonary rehabilitation group, or when clinically unable to participate in exercise. The implementation of the GENIE tool aims; - to build social networking awareness and the importance of utilising existing social resources in the professional and voluntary members of the COPD service - to use social network mapping techniques and preference elicitation to engage COPD patients in reflecting on their support preferences and needs, help them access further resources and knowledge - Evaluate the success of the social mapping techniques (GENIE) in the COPD patient population - Evaluate the cost benefit to the health service of the GENIE in the COPD patient population</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Emphysema</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults over 18 with a predominant diagnosis of COPD Ability to understand spoken English Attending PR assessment/ enrolled in Pulmonary Rehabilitation (PR) or maintenance therapy Ability and capacity to make their own decision and consent freely No clear COPD diagnosis Inability to consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Self-management</keyword>
	<keyword>Supportive self-management</keyword>
	<keyword>Normalisation process theory</keyword>
	<keyword>Social networks</keyword>
</DOC>