<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01492842</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The proposed study is a substudy of ATN 106 and a cross sectional study intended to be conducted at each of the AMTUs newly participating in ATN III. The intent is to enroll all youth with behaviorally-acquired HIV who have enrolled in ATN 106. The study involves a review of the subjects' medical chart and a collection of an oral rinse sample.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Correlates of Oral Human Papillomavirus Infection in Adolescents and Young Adults With Behaviorally Acquired HIV</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>ATN 114 is a cross-sectional substudy of ATN 106. In addition to sharing data collected in ATN 106, an oral rinse sample along with the subject's self reported history and medical chart abstraction of HPV vaccination status and medical chart abstraction of a history of oral condylomata, oral dysplasia and oral tumor viruses will be collected in ATN 114. Recruitment is expected to last approximately one year, similar to the same timeframe for ATN 106. Enrollment may be terminated earlier at the discretion of the ATN Executive Committee and/or the ATN 114 protocol team should ATN 106 also terminate enrollment early. Individuals who have agreed to participate in ATN 106 may be simultaneously approached at any clinic visit, or, for community-based sites, contacted directly for participation in ATN 114. Site staff may also contact individuals via phone, e-mail, or any other agreed-upon methods of communication. Site staff should try as much as possible to incorporate the study visit into a regularly scheduled clinic visit.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Papillomavirus Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Behaviorally acquired HIVinfection as indicated by medical chart abstraction or selfreported history of sexual risk and/or needle using behaviors; and Completion of the ATN 106 study visit (the same day or up to a maximum of 14 calendar days). Exclusion Criteria Presence of serious psychiatric symptoms (e.g., active hallucinations, thought disorder) that would impair the individual's ability to complete the study measures; Visibly distraught (e.g., suicidal, homicidal, exhibiting violent behavior); or Intoxicated or under the influence of alcohol or other substances at the time of consent/assent for ATN 114.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>