<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00327392</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Very often patients receive medications before a diagnostic, therapeutic, or surgical procedure to help them relax, keep them calm, and to relieve them from pain. This is called procedural sedation. With respect to minimal-to-moderate procedural sedation for minor surgical procedures, a patient is first given a pain-relief medication (analgesic) and then a medication to help him/her relax and keep calm (sedative). AQUAVAN is a chemically modified form of propofol, a commonly-used sedative drug. AQUAVAN acts like a slow release version of propofol, and is being studied to see if it can safely keep patients calm and relaxed during their medical procedure and then allow for rapid and clear-headed recovery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Safety Study of AQUAVAN® (Fospropofol Disodium) Injection for Sedation During Minor Surgical Procedures.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 3 open-label, single-arm study designed to evaluate the safety of AQUAVAN following pretreatment with an analgesic, fentanyl, in patients who are undergoing minor surgical procedures that require minimal-to-moderate sedation. All patients will be placed on supplemental oxygen via nasal cannula and an electrocardiogram monitor, pulse oximeter, and blood pressure monitor will be attached prior to administration of fentanyl. Assessments will be made to evaluate the safety of AQUAVAN in patients undergoing minor surgical procedures.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fospropofol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Propofol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Number of sites/patients: Approximately 18 sites and 125 patients. 1. Patient must be able to understand, either orally or in writing, and be able to consent and complete the required assessments and procedures. 2. Patient provides signed/dated Informed Consent and Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) of 1996 authorization after receiving a full explanation of the extent and nature of the study. 3. Patient must be at least 18 years of age and undergoing one of the specified minor surgical procedures at the time of screening. 4. If female, patient must be surgically sterile, postmenopausal, or not pregnant or lactating and must have been using an acceptable method of birth control for at least 1 month prior to dosing, with a negative urine pregnancy test result at screening and predose. 5. Patient meets American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) Physical Classification System status of P1 to P4. 1. Patient has a history of allergic reaction or hypersensitivity to any anesthetic agent or opioid. 2. Patient does not meet nils per os (NPO) status per ASA guidelines or institution's guideline. 3. Patient has a Mallampati Classification Score of 4; or a Mallampati Classification Score of 3 and a thyromental distance &lt;4 cm, or for any other reason has a difficult airway, in the opinion of the Principal Investigator. 4. Patient has an abnormal, clinically significant 3lead ECG finding at predosing period. 5. Patient has participated in an investigational drug study within 1 month prior to study start. 6. Patient is unwilling to adhere to pre and postprocedural instructions. 7. Patient for whom the use of fentanyl citrate injection (fentanyl) is contraindicated.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Arthroscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>AV Shunt</keyword>
	<keyword>Bunion</keyword>
	<keyword>Dilatation and Curettage</keyword>
	<keyword>Esophagogastroduodenoscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>Hysteroscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>Lithotripsy</keyword>
	<keyword>Rotator Cuff/ Shoulder</keyword>
	<keyword>Transesophageal Echocardiography</keyword>
	<keyword>Ureteroscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>AQUAVAN</keyword>
	<keyword>Sedation</keyword>
</DOC>