<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02112383</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Procrastination is defined as a voluntarily delay of an intended course of action despite expecting to be worse-off for the delay, and is considered a persistent behavior pattern that can result in major psychological suffering. About one-fifth of the adult population and half of the student population are presumed having substantial difficulties due to recurrent procrastination in their everyday life. However, chronic and severe procrastinators seldom receive adequate care due to preconceptions and the lack of understanding regarding procrastination and the treatment interventions that are assumed beneficial. Cognitive behavior therapy is often deemed treatment of choice, although the evidence supporting its use is scarce, and only one randomized controlled trial has been performed. The primary aim of the current study is therefore to test the efficacy of cognitive behavior therapy delivered as either a group intervention or via the Internet. Participants will consist of students recruited through the Student Health Centre at Karolinska Institutet. A randomized controlled trial with a sample size of 100 participants divided into two conditions will be employed; a ten week Internet-based cognitive behavior therapy intervention, and an eight week group intervention based on cognitive behavior therapy. The current study is believed to result in two important findings. First, different interventions inherent in cognitive behavior therapy are assumed to be helpful for people suffering from problems caused by procrastination. Second, both a group intervention and an Internet-based cognitive behavior therapy intervention are presumed suitable for administering treatment for procrastination, which is considered highly important as the availability of adequate care is limited, particularly among students. The current study will increase the knowledge regarding the efficacy of different treatments of procrastination, as well as enhance the overall comprehension of the difficulties related to dilatory behavior.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Group Versus Internet-based Cognitive Behavior Therapy for Procrastination</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Fluent in Swedish Computer with Internet access and a working email Registered as students at one of the affiliated universities of the Student Health Centre at Karolinska Institutet Primary difficulties related to chronic and severe procrastination Severe depression (30 points or more on MADRSS) Acute conditions in need of treatment; suicidal ideation, neuropsychiatric conditions (ADHD, ADD), misuse of alcohol or drugs, bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, and psychosis Ongoing psychotherapy Ongoing psychotropic medication (unless dose is stable three months prior the entering treatment)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Procrastination</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive behavior therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Internet interventions</keyword>
	<keyword>Group intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Students</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized controlled trial</keyword>
</DOC>