<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00337467</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose is to explore whether atazanavir/ritonavir (ATV/RTV) single enhanced protease inhibitor therapy can maintain virologic suppression without a marked increase in virologic failure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase IIIb Study to Evaluate the Effectiveness and Safety of Atazanavir/Ritonavir as Single Enhanced Protease Inhibitor Therapy in Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV)-Infected Subjects Evidencing Virologic Suppression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atazanavir Sulfate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Protease Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Protease Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>On continued antiretroviral (ARV) treatment, with no discontinuation periods, for the previous 6 months (24 weeks). Absence of evidence or suspected virologic failure on antiretroviral therapy Absence of known primary mutations in the protease gene Only 1 highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART) prior to current one HIV RNA &lt; 50 copies/mL in the last 6 months (single blip below 200 c/mL allowed) On ATV/RTV +2 nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitors (NRTIs) (or 1 NRTI + tenofovir [TDF]) for at least 8 weeks before study entry, without treatmentlimiting adverse effects Presence of a newly diagnosed HIVrelated opportunistic infection or any medical condition requiring acute therapy at the time of enrollment. Active disease condition (e.g. moderate to severe hepatic impairment/active renal disease/history of clinically significant heart conduction disease) Patients with chronic hepatitis B receiving lamivudine (3TC), Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate (TDF) or emtricitabine (FTC). CD4 &lt; 100 cells/mm3 Grade IV laboratory values: Hemoglobin &lt; 6.5 g/dL or white blood cells (WBC) &lt;800/mmm3 or absolute neutrophil count &lt; 500/mm3, or platelets &lt; 20,000/mm3 or diffuse petechiae.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV-Infected Patients Evidencing Virologic Suppression</keyword>
</DOC>