<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00842036</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research compares the benefits of the original treatment, Community Reinforcement and Family Training (CRAFT), with the Treatment Entry Training (TEnT) component of CRAFT to determine if TEnt alone can produce the primary outcome of CRAFT -- treatment entry of the drug user. We also look at the impact on the well-being of the concerned significant other and the drug use of their loved one.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CRAFT Behavior Therapy: Treatment Entry Component</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The consequences of drug abuse are not limited to drug users; they also extend to their families and concerned significant others (CSOs). Research shows that CSOs of drug users have increased prevalence of illness, domestic violence, and problems in mood and functioning. Because CSOs are troubled by the negative effects of drug use on the drug user and themselves, they may be a social community that is particularly invested in learning ways to positively influence the drug user. We compare the benefits of the original treatment, Community Reinforcement and Family Training (CRAFT), with the Treatment Entry Training (TEnT) component of CRAFT to see if the TEnt is sufficient to produce the primary and most consistent outcome of CRAFT -- treatment entry of the drug user.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Behavior, Addictive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Opioid-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Concerned Significant Other (CSO) and Person of Concern (PC) over 18 years of age is a family member (such as a close relative, spouse, intimate partner), roommate or significant other who is concerned about a PC reports that the PC has a pattern of drug or alcohol use that meets the criterion for abuse or dependence on stimulants, opiates, or alcohol according to DSMIVTR reports that the PC is not currently in treatment and has not received treatment during the past 6 weeks (other than detoxification) reports having been in the relationship with the identified PC for at least 3 months reports contact with the identified PC on at least 12 of the past 30 days with no planned change in the amount of contact in the next 10 months provides evidence that the PC has refused to seek treatment when CSO asked does not demonstrate complete understanding of their participation by reading the consent form and passing a consent quiz that tests comprehension of the basic elements of informed consent and requirements of the protocol, or does not agree to participate by signing an informed consent declines to: provide valid locator information, allow videotaped sessions, and/or participate in followups CSO has a drug abuse problem themselves as determined through clinical assessment and DSMIVTR criteria is not able to comprehend the content in the selfreport materials (written at about 6th grade reading level) reports that the PC behaves in a manner consistent with an unremitting psychosis or another psychiatric disorder (e.g., significant developmental delay) that would contraindicate the planned CRAFT intervention intends to receive more than 6 hours of individual counseling focusing on the PC's addiction for the 6 months after they are enrolled in the study PC has a recent history of severe domestic violence (e.g., the PC has committed criminal assault during the past 2 years, or has a history of severe violence involving a weapon or resulting in hospitalization has an immediate family member, friend, roommate, coworker, or other person who has already enrolled in the study and his/her participation is not likely to be independent of the initially enrolled CSO's participation fails to complete 2 sessions with a family trainer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Family Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Relationship Dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Family Dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Family Relations</keyword>
	<keyword>Stimulant Dependence</keyword>
	<keyword>Opiate Dependence</keyword>
	<keyword>Alcohol Dependence</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavior Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Substance Abuse</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Addiction</keyword>
</DOC>