<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02535299</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objectives: To investigate the treatment effect between insulin,metformin and Liraglutide; in Type 2 Diabetes in our hospital, in order to investigate the possible mechanism about telomere-telomerase system and Par-4.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Par-4 and Telomere-telomerase System in Type 2 Diabetes Patients Who Received GLP-1 or Metformin Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>160 Type 2 diabetes in our hospital will divide into 4 groups: group A (40 healthy volunteers), group B (40 patients who give basal and insulin treatment, group C（40 patients who give basal and Liraglutide treatment),group D（40 patients who give basal and metformin treatment). The age, height, weight, blood glucose, glycosylated hemoglobin A1c（HbA1c）,homeostasis model assessment(HOMA-IR), lipid, blood pressure, course of disease, telomere length,telomerase activity will record respectively. And High-sensitive C-reactive protein (HsCRP), Par-4, GST,SOD,GSH-PX,ATF-6,CHOP,XBP-1 and Tumor necrosis factor-α（TNF-α） will detect as Baseline. After each group's treatment, Change from baseline of all indexes will record, Multifactor logistic regression will be analyzed the correlations between each positive indexes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon-Like Peptide 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Newly dignosised type 2 diabetes according to WHO criteria.glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) was more than 10%; Seronegative for antibodies against insulin, islet cells and glutamic acid decarboxylase (GAD); Type 1 diabetes mellitus,presence of autoimmune diabetes indicated by antibodies to insulin, islet cells, and GAD； Gestational diabetes; patients with heart, liver, or renal function impairment;presence of severe infections or cerebrovascular disease;</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>telomere-telomerase</keyword>
	<keyword>Par-4</keyword>
	<keyword>GLP-1</keyword>
	<keyword>metformin</keyword>
</DOC>