<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01138111</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to investigate whether Florbetaben (BAY94-9172)positron emission tomography (PET) is able to distinguish between subjects with mild cognitive impairment (MCI) progressing to Alzheimer's disease (AD) from those with MCI not progressing to AD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Florbetaben (BAY94-9172) PET (Positron Emission Tomography) Imaging in MCI (Mild Cognitive Impairment) Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mild Cognitive Impairment</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amyloidosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Presence of MCI defined as abnormal cognition on objective testing in the absence of dementia or significant functional loss. Absence of systemic or other neurological disease that may contribute to cognitive impairment or prevent followup over two years. Able to give written informed consent. Age &gt;/= 60 years of age &gt;/= 7 years of education Mini mental state examination (MMSE) score &lt; 24 at baseline Clinical dementia rating (CDR) score &gt; 0.5 at baseline Patients who receive regular medication of drugs which may adversely impact cognition (e.g. tricyclic antidepressants, antipsychotics and/or large doses of hypnotics or anxiolytics) Existing or history of cancer History of severe head trauma, brain surgery or intracranial hematoma with permanent brain lesion Lifetime history of major affective disorder, schizophrenia, or schizoaffective disorder Contraindications to MRI (Magnetic resonance imaging) Relevant history, physical or imaging findings of neurological disease other than MCI and mild depression History of severe anaphylactic reaction or high risk of allergic reaction to drugs Patient has received another investigational drug in the preceding 14 days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Florbetaben</keyword>
	<keyword>Amyloid beta-protein</keyword>
	<keyword>MCI</keyword>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's disease</keyword>
</DOC>