<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01138540</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is planned to compare, in patients sedated, intubated and mechanically ventilated, the efficacy and safety of the Lateral Trendelenburg position in comparison to the Semirecumbent Position to prevent incidence of ventilator-associated pneumonia (VAP).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Gravity-VAP (Ventilator-Associated Pneumonia) Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is planned to compare, in patients sedated, intubated or tracheostomized and mechanically ventilated, the efficacy and safety of two body positions in reducing incidence of ventilator-associated pneumonia. The semi-recumbent position prevents gastro-oropharyngeal aspiration of bacteria laden gastric contents and the "gastro-pulmonary" route of colonization. The lateral-Trendelenburg position aims to promote outward drainage of bacteria-laden oropharyngeal secretion, while avoiding bacterial translocation from the oropharynx into the lungs.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pneumonia, Ventilator-Associated</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age ≥ 18 years 2. Patients expected to be orotracheally intubated for at least 48 hours or longer 3. Enrollment time window within 12 hours following intubation 1. Current and past participation in an other intervention trial conflicting with the present study 2. Previous endotracheal intubation longer than 12 hours during the previous 30 days 3. Patients with documented bronchiectasis 4. Cystic fibrosis 5. Witnessed pulmonary aspiration either prior or at intubation 6. Patients with increased intracranial pressure, brain edema; or medical conditions that can worsen with increase in intracranial pressure 7. Patients with significant heart failure and activity impairment (Class IIIIV of the New York Heart Association (NYHA) 8. Spinal cord injury 9. BMI &gt; 35, or weight above 300 pound 10. Grade IV Intraabdominal pressure: IAP &gt; 25 mmHg or abdominal compartment syndrome , defined as a sustained IAP &gt; 20 mmHg that is associated with new organ dysfunction / failure 11. Pregnancy 12. Orthopedic problems that will not allow the patient to be kept in one of the study positions</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>VAP</keyword>
</DOC>