<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02713425</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research study aims to test the feasibility and effectiveness of using an entertaining video game as an addition to traditional therapy for the treatment of anxiety disorders in youth, particularly those youth who may have limited access to mental health treatment in the traditional clinical setting.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pediatric Anxiety Intervention With an Entertaining Video Game: Feasibility Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this research is to learn whether or not youth with social anxiety find a therapeutic video game engaging and useful. Children between the ages of 7 &amp; 17 who have been diagnosed with a social anxiety disorder will be invited to participate in this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 7 to 17 2. Primary diagnosis of: 1. social phobia, 2. separation anxiety disorder 3. A parent or other primary care giver available to participate with the child in all assessment and treatment activities 4. Estimated average intelligence 5. English speaking 6. Received les than 3 treatment sessions for social anxiety disorder 1. History of and/or current diagnosis of: 1. psychosis, 2. autism, 3. bipolar disorder, 4. mental retardation, 5. oppositional defiant disorder, 6. PTSD, 7. selective mutism, or 8. major depressive disorder 2. Current suicidality or recent suicidal behavior 3. Parent to be involved in study who is unable to adequately participate due to intellectual or psychiatric difficulties 4. Starting or changing the dosage of a psychiatric medication in the last two months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>Social Phobia</keyword>
	<keyword>Separation Anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>Generalized Anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>GAD</keyword>
	<keyword>Phobia</keyword>
	<keyword>video game</keyword>
	<keyword>teen</keyword>
	<keyword>youth</keyword>
	<keyword>child</keyword>
	<keyword>adolescent</keyword>
</DOC>