<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01969058</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II study is being done in HIV-infected subjects on antiretroviral therapy to evaluate the effects of isotretinoin (a drug that is approved for use in the treatment of severe acne) on the immune system. Your immune system helps your body fight infections. When your immune system is not working well, you may be at greater risk for diseases that are common in aging, like heart disease, weaker bones, and kidney disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Isotretinoin on Immune Activation Among HIV-1 Infected Subjects With Incomplete CD4+ T Cell Recovery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Isotretinoin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HIV1 infection, documented by any licensed rapid HIV test or HIV enzyme or chemiluminescence immunoassay (E/CIA) test kit at any time prior to study entry and confirmed by a licensed Western blot or a second antibody test by a method other than the initial rapid HIV and/or E/CIA, or by HIV1 antigen, plasma HIV1 RNA viral load. NOTE: The term "licensed" refers to a US FDAapproved kit, which is required for all IND studies. CDC (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention) guidelines mandate that confirmation of the initial test result must use a test that is different from the one used for the initial assessment. A reactive initial rapid test should be confirmed by either another type of rapid assay or an E/CIA that is based on a different antigen preparation and/or different test principle (eg, indirect versus competitive), or a Western blot or a plasma HIV1 RNA viral load. Receiving ART therapy for at least 12 months prior to study entry. No plans to change the ART regimen in the 6 months after study entry. HIV1 RNA below the lower limit of detection using an FDAapproved assay obtained within 30 days prior to study entry by any laboratory that has a CLIA certification or its equivalent (eg, &lt;50 copies/mL on Roche Amplicor HIV1 Monitor assay, &lt;75 copies/mL on the Versant HIV1 RNA assay by branched DNA, &lt;40 copies/mL on the Abbott m2000sp/m2000rt realtime PCR test, &lt; 20 copies/mL on the COBAS AmpliPrep/TAQMAN HIV1 assay). All measurements of HIV1 RNA within the 12 months prior to study entry must be below the limit of detection with the following exception: NOTE A: 1 viral blip (&lt;200 copies/mL) is permitted if it is preceded and followed by viral loads below the limits of detection. NOTE B: The virologic assay must have a lower limit of detection of ≤ 75 copies/mL. CD4+ cell count &lt;350 cells/mm3 obtained at screening within 30 days prior to entry at any laboratory that has a CLIA (Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments) certification or its equivalent. The following laboratory values obtained within 30 days prior to entry by any laboratory that has a CLIA certification or its equivalent: 1. Hemoglobin A1c (HgbA1c) levels ≤ 6.5% 2. Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL 3. Platelet count ≥ 50,000/mm3 4. Creatinine ≤1.5 mg/dl 5. CrCl ≥ 60 mL/min, calculated by the CockcroftGault method 6. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (SGOT) ≤1.5x upper limit of normal (ULN) 7. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (SGPT) ≤1.5x ULN 8. Serum lipase ≤1.5x ULN 9. Fasting triglyceride level ≤200 mg/dL 10. Fasting glucose &lt;126mg/dL Karnofsky performance score &gt;/=70 within 30 days prior to entry. Men and postmenopausal females aged ≥ 18 years and ≤ 80 years at entry. Note: Postmenopausal is defined as having either: 1. Appropriate medical documentation (see note) of prior complete bilateral oophorectomy (i.e., surgical removal of the ovaries, resulting in "surgical menopause" and occurring at the age at which the procedure was performed), OR 2. Permanent cessation (12 consecutive months or more of amenorrhea) of previously occurring menses as a result of ovarian failure with documentation of hormonal deficiency by a certified healthcare provider (i.e., "spontaneous menopause"). Hormonal deficiency should be properly documented (see note) in the case of suspected spontaneous menopause as follows: 1. If age &gt;54 years and with the absence of normal menses: Serum FSH (Follicle Stimulating Hormone) level elevated to within the postmenopausal range based on the laboratory reference range where the hormonal assay is performed. 2. If age ≤ 54 years and with the absence of normal menses: Negative serum or urine HCG with concurrently elevated serum FSH (follicle stimulating hormone) level in the postmenopausal range, depressed estradiol (E2) level in the postmenopausal range, and absent serum progesterone level, based on the laboratory reference ranges where the hormonal assays are performed. NOTE: "Appropriate documentation", and "properly documented" means written documentation or oral communication from a clinician or clinician's staff documented in source documents of an operative report, discharge summary, or No active hepatitis B or C infection. NOTE: For subjects who have documentation of prior infection, but no active hepatitis infection, evidence of clearance must be greater than 1 year. Ability and willingness of subject to provide informed consent. Willingness to adhere to the iPLEDGE program requirements. Indication of willingness to participate in the substudy A5330s. NOTE: In the event that 12 or fewer subjects have enrolled into A5330s by the time enrollment in the main study has reached 50% of the accrual target, A5330s enrollment will be required. Preexisting diagnosis of diabetes. Currently receiving treatment with fibrate, nicotinic acid, tetracycline, fish oil &gt;1g/d, or methotrexate. Known active healing fracture or any severe bone disorders. NOTE: does not include healed fractures or history of old fractures. Receipt of any of the following medications within 30 days prior to entry: systemic steroids (including intraarticular steroids; inhaled or nasal steroid therapy is permitted), interleukins, systemic interferons (including intraarticular steroid injection; local injection of interferon alpha for treatment of human papilloma virus is permitted), or systemic chemotherapy. Known allergy/sensitivity or any hypersensitivity to vitamin A, retinoids, or any of their derivatives. Active drug or alcohol use or dependence that, in the opinion of the site investigator, would interfere with adherence to study requirements. Acute or serious illness requiring systemic treatment and/or hospitalization within 60 days prior to entry. Weight &lt; 40 kg or &gt; 150 kg. History of major depression or suicide attempt requiring hospitalization, or psychotic episode requiring medication or hospitalization. History of inflammatory bowel disease such as Crohn's disease, or Ulcerative colitis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>