<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00286455</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of alogliptin, once daily (QD), in adults with type 2 diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Alogliptin in Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There are approximately 19 million people in the United States who have been diagnosed with diabetes mellitus, of which 90% to 95% are type 2. The prevalence of type 2 diabetes varies among racial and ethnic populations and has been shown to correlate with age, obesity, family history, history of gestational diabetes, and physical inactivity. Over the next decade, a marked increase in the number of adults with diabetes mellitus is expected. Takeda is developing SYR-322 (alogliptin) for the improvement of glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Alogliptin is an inhibitor of the dipeptidyl peptidase IV enzyme. Dipeptidyl peptidase IV is thought to be primarily responsible for the degradation of 2 peptide hormones released in response to nutrient ingestion. It is expected that inhibition of dipeptidyl peptidase IV will improve glycemic (glucose) control in patients with type 2 diabetes. The aim of the current study is to evaluate the efficacy of alogliptin in subjects with type 2 diabetes mellitus who are inadequately controlled and who have failed treatment with diet and exercise. Individuals who participate in this study will be required to commit to a screening visit and up to 14 additional visits at the study center. Study participation is anticipated to be about 34 weeks (or 8.5 months).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alogliptin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Type 2 diabetes mellitus, experiencing inadequate glycemic control, and are receiving no current antidiabetic therapy. Subjects will qualify if both of the following conditions apply: Subject has failed treatment with diet and exercise for at least one month prior to Screening Subject has received less than 7 days of any antidiabetic therapy within the 3 months prior to Screening Diagnosis of type 2 diabetes must be based on current American Diabetes Association criteria. Body mass index greater than or equal to 23 kg/m2 and less than or equal to 45 kg/m2 Fasting Cpeptide concentration greater than or equal to 0.8 ng per mL (greater than or equal to 0.26 nmol per L). (If this screening criterion is not met, the subject still qualifies if Cpeptide greater than or equal to1.5 ng per mL (greater than or equal to 0.50 nmol per L) after a challenge test. Glycosylated hemoglobin concentration between 7.0% and 10.0%, inclusive If regular use of other, nonexcluded medications, must be on a stable dose for at least the 4 weeks prior to Screening. However, as needed use of prescription or overthecounter medications is allowed at the discretion of the investigator. Systolic blood pressure less than or equal to 180 mm Hg and diastolic pressure less than or equal to 110 mm Hg Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 12 g per dL (greater than or equal to 120 gm per L) for males and greater than or equal to 10 g per dL (greater than or equal to 100 gm per L) for females Alanine aminotransferase less than or equal to 3 times the upper limit of normal Serum creatinine less than or equal to 2.0 mg per dL (less than or equal to 17 micromol per L) Thyroidstimulating hormone level less than or equal to the upper limit of the normal range and the subject is clinically euthyroid Neither pregnant (confirmed by laboratory testing in females of childbearing potential) nor lactating. Female subjects of childbearing potential must be practicing adequate contraception. Adequate contraception must be practiced for the duration of participation in the study. Able and willing to monitor their own blood glucose concentrations with a home glucose monitor. No major illness or debility that in the investigator's opinion prohibits the subject from completing the study. Able and willing to provide written informed consent. Exclusion Criteria Urine albumin to creatinine ratio of greater than1000 μg per mg (greater than 113 mg per mol) at Screening. If elevated, the subject may be rescreened within 1 week. History of cancer, other than squamous cell or basal cell carcinoma of the skin, that has not been in full remission for at least 5 years prior to Screening. (A history of treated cervical intraepithelial neoplasia 1 or cervical intraepithelial neoplasia 2 is allowed). History of laser treatment for proliferative diabetic retinopathy within the 6 months prior to Screening. History of treated diabetic gastric paresis. New York Heart Association Class III or IV heart failure regardless of therapy. Currently treated subjects who are stable at Class I or II are candidates for the study. History of coronary angioplasty, coronary stent placement, coronary bypass surgery, or myocardial infarction within the 6 months prior to Screening. History of any hemoglobinopathy that may affect determination of glycosylated hemoglobin. History of infection with hepatitis B, hepatitis C, or human immunodeficiency virus. History of a psychiatric disorder that will affect the subject's ability to participate in the study. History of angioedema in association with use of angiotensinconverting enzyme inhibitors or angiotensinII receptor inhibitors. History of alcohol or substance abuse within the 2 years prior to Screening. Receipt of any investigational drug within the 30 days prior to Screening or a history of receipt of an investigational antidiabetic drug within the 3 months prior to Screening. Prior treatment in an investigational study of alogliptin. Excluded Medications Treatment with antidiabetic agents (other than study drug following enrollment in the study) is not allowed within the 3 months prior to Screening and through the completion of the endoftreatment/early termination procedures. (Exception: if a subject has received other antidiabetic therapy for less than 7 days within the 3 months prior to Screening.) Treatment with weightloss drugs, any investigational antidiabetics, or oral or systemically injected glucocorticoids is not allowed from 3 months prior to randomization through the completion of the endoftreatment/early termination procedures. Inhaled corticosteroids are allowed. Subjects are not to take any medications, including overthecounter products, without first consulting with the Study Doctor.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Glucose Metabolism Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Dysmetabolic Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Type II Diabetes; Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Lipoatrophic</keyword>
	<keyword>Dyslipidemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>