<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00286819</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open -label randomized phase II study of dose-dense Fluorouracil/Epirubicin/Cyclophosphamide (FEC) administered with Epirubicin of 75mg/m2 (FEC75) and Epirubicin 90mg/m2 (FEC90) in untreated patients with early breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose Density FU 75 and FU 90 as Adjuvant Therapy for Early Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Arm A: the FEC75 regimen will be given at the following doses: Fluorouracil 500mg/m2 by i.v. bolus or infusion. Epirubicin 75mg/m2 by 30 minutes i.v infusion and Cyclophosphamide 500mg/m2 by i.v bolus or infusion. All three drugs will be administered intravenously on Day 1 of each 14-day cycles. Arm B: the FEC90 regimen will be given at the following doses: Fluorouracil 500mg/m2 by i.v. bolus or infusion.Epirubicin 90mg/m2 by 30 minutes i.v infusion and Cyclophosphamide 500mg/m2 by i.v bolus or infusion. All three drugs will be administered intravenously on Day 1 of each 14-day cycles. Pegfilgrastim fixed dose of 6mg as a single subcutaneous injection will be given in both arms on Day 2 of each cycle. Six cycles of adjuvant chemotherapy will be administered in both arms (A + B)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epirubicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients with histological diagnosis of invasive breast cancer Patients with early stage I, II,III breast cancer amendable for complete surgical resection. Patients with any nodal status Patients with ER and PR negative tumors. In case of axillary involvement:any hormonal receptors status. perfomance Status 01 on the ECOG Scale patients indicated for adjuvant chemotherapy No previous chemotherapy or radiotherapy Patients have to be randomized within 8 weeks after surgery. Its recommended that patients will start chemotherapy within 1 month after surgical treatment. active infection pregnancy/breast feeding serious concomitant systemic disorders incompatible with the study Second primary malignancy (expect in situ carcinoma of the cervix or adequately treated basal cell carcinoma of the skin) Use of any other investigational agent within 4 weeks before enrollment into the study Cocurrent administration of radiation therapy, chemotherapy, hormonal therapy or immunotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>early breast cancer,</keyword>
	<keyword>Fluorouracil</keyword>
</DOC>