<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00810225</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Determine if: - genetic differences of CNDP1 gene - the previously defined GWI/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (GWI/CFS) cerebrospinal fluid proteome contents - psychometric - other variables can differentiate between veterans of the 1990-1991 Persian Gulf War who have autonomic, neurological and other symptoms and those without these complaints.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Gulf War Illness (GWI) by Comparing GWI and Healthy Veterans</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Persian Gulf Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Evidence of military enlistment between August 1, 1990 and July 31, 1991, and deployment for 30 consecutive days to: Persian Gulf waters and adjacent land areas Other global locations U.S. only Status prior to 1990 and 1991: Active duty National Guard Reserves Current active duty military personnel Any one who was not active duty military personnel between August 1, 1990 and July 31, 1991 HIV/AIDS; pregnancy or lactation; potential hepatitis; drug addiction; chronic inflammatory, infectious, or autoimmune medical illnesses not associated with GWI; incarceration; dementia, other cognitive limitation; or reliance on a caregiver in order to respond to the questionnaires and other study tests. Amputations of one or both hands and forearms will be permitted but hand grip tests will not be tested</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>CNDP1</keyword>
	<keyword>carnosine dipeptidase 1</keyword>
	<keyword>Persian Gulf War</keyword>
	<keyword>Gulf War Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>GWI</keyword>
	<keyword>Gulf War Illness</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Fatigue</keyword>
	<keyword>Fibromyalgia</keyword>
	<keyword>Veterans</keyword>
	<keyword>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Migraine headaches</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuropathy</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiple Chemical Sensitivity</keyword>
</DOC>