<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02838030</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Worldwide, the incidence of preeclampsia ranges from 2 to 10% of pregnancies. The World Health Organization (WHO) estimates that the incidence of preeclampsia is seven times higher in developing countries than in developed (2.8% and 0.4%). In Mexico it is estimated that preeclampsia - eclampsia is a major cause of maternal and perinatal morbidity and mortality. Because it is an idiopathic heterogeneous syndrome associated with endothelial damage, so far there is no effective treatment to decrease the morbidity and mortality of this entity, so it is necessary to strengthen prevention; the use of aspirin alone is inconclusive, in addition to the information the investigators have reduced the effect of these strategies on arterial stiffness; Moreover, it has been observed that L-arginine lowers blood pressure in this population. It is for this that is of interest to know the efficacy and safety of the combination of L-arginine low dose, which is known as an important eNOS in NO production substrate, and aspirin for its qualities of antiinflammatory and anticoagulant in the prevention of preeclampsia and also determine their effect on arterial stiffness as a noninvasive method, as is the applanation tonometry.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Aspirin and L-arginine in High Risk Preeclamptic</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>It will conduct a clinical trial, double-blind, randomized and placebo control group female patients with 12 weeks of gestation have one or more risk factors for developing preeclampsia. 2 groups will be formed with 82 patients each, chance will determine the intervention (acetylsalicylic + L-arginine acetylsalicylic acid or acid + placebo). At the beginning and end of the intervention clinical and laboratory determinations, the end will be determined in both groups the incidence of preeclampsia, severity and number needed to treat is made. The data obtained were analyzed using SPSS statistical software version 22. It was considered statistically significant at p &lt;0.05.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspirin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pregnant before 12 weeks of gestation High risk of preeclampsia Signature of informed consent in writing Noncompliance &gt; 20% of drug intake Lack of tolerability Larginine or acetylsalicylic acid Compliance with at least one noninclusion criteria during the course of the study Serious adverse event Withdrawal of consent</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>44 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Preeclampsia</keyword>
	<keyword>L-arginine</keyword>
</DOC>