<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01853033</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety, tolerability and pharmacokinetics of ABT-122 in subjects with Rheumatoid Arthritis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability and Pharmacokinetics of Multiple Subcutaneous Injections of ABT-122 in Subjects With Rheumatoid Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase 1, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multiple ascending dose study. Twenty-four subjects with Rheumatoid Arthritis will be selected to participate. Subjects will be randomized to receive either ABT-122 or placebo. ABT-122 or placebo will be administered as subcutaneous (under the skin) injections in three dosing groups.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA) &gt; 3 months. On methotrexate (MTX) therapy =&gt; 3 months and on a stable dose for at least 4 weeks. Except for MTX, must have discontinued all diseasemodifying antirheumatic drugs (DMARDs) for at least 3 months or 5 halflives, whichever is longer. Body Mass Index (BMI) is 19 to 38, inclusive. Other than RA, subjects should be in good general health. Evidence of antiABT122 antibody on a serum sample taken at Screening. History of significant allergic reaction; or history of anaphylactic reaction to any agent; or history of major reaction to any IgG containing product. History of persistent chronic or active infection(s) requiring hospitalization or treatment with intravenous or oral antimicrobials/antibiotics within the past 30 days. History or evidence of active tuberculosis (TB) or the subject has evidence of risk factor for latent TB. Subject has any medical condition or illness other than RA that is not well controlled with treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tolerability</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunogenicity</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Rheumatoid Arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
</DOC>