<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01853878</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to test a potential new kind of anti-cancer treatment, called PRAME immunotherapy in resected patients with lung cancer. As of 18 July 2014, the recruitment was stopped prematurely and the study was unblinded. Only patients on active treatment will have the option to continue in the study. Patients randomised to the Placebo group were withdrawn. There will no longer be an active follow-up of patients after discontinuation or completion of the treatment. The study will end 30 days after the last dose will be administered. As a result, primary and secondary objectives will not be assessed as planned. All clinical and safety data collected in the study will be analysed descriptively. For each biological sample already collected in the scope of this study and not tested yet, testing will not be performed by default, except if a scientific rationale remains relevant despite the premature termination of the study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Demonstrate the Benefit of a New Kind of Anti-cancer Treatment [PReferentially Expressed Antigen of MElanoma (PRAME) Immunotherapy] for Patients With Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC), After Removal of Their Tumor</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>During the treatment period, safety monitoring will continue as initially foreseen. Reporting of post-study adverse events (AEs) and serious AEs (SAEs) will continue as per protocol. In the best interest of the patient, no more biological samples for protocol research purposes (i.e. serum sampling for humoral immunity, whole blood sampling for pharmacogenetics) will be taken.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient has radically resected NSCLC The NSCLC is of pathological stage IAT1b, IB, II or IIIA NSCLC The surgical technique for resection of the patient's tumor is anatomical, involving at least a segmentectomy The patient's tumor shows expression of PRAME. The patient is ≥ 18 years of age at the time of first consent. Written informed consent has been obtained from the patient prior to performance of any studyspecific procedure. The patient is free of disease (no residual tumor, no locoregional recurrence, no distant metastasis), as confirmed by a post thoracic surgery contrastenhanced computed tomography (CT scan) of the chest, upper abdomen and by a contrastenhanced CT scan or Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) of the brain. Other examinations should be performed as clinically indicated. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0, 1 or 2 at the time of randomization Adequate bonemarrow reserve, adequate renal, hepatic and adrenal function as assessed by standard laboratory criteria If the patient is female, she must be of nonchildbearing potential, i.e. have a current tubal ligation, hysterectomy, ovariectomy or be postmenopausalor if she is of childbearing potential, she must practice adequate contraceptionfor 30 days prior to administration of study product, have a negative pregnancy test and continue such precautions during all study treatment period and for 2 months after last treatment administration. Patients who the investigator believes can and will comply with the requirements of this protocol (e.g. return for active followup visits). The patient is diagnosed with a concomitant malignancy and/or has a history of malignancy within the past five years or has had a malignancy that has been in complete remission for less than 5 years. Patients with effectively treated non melanoma skin cancers or effectively treated carcinoma in situ of the cervix both of which in remission for less than 5 years will be eligible. The patient has received any anticancer specific treatment, including radiotherapy, immunotherapy, hormonal therapy, chemotherapy or neoadjuvant chemotherapy, except for: Administration of adjuvant platinumbased doublet chemotherapy for the treatment of the current NSCLC allowed between surgery and randomization. Treatment of previous malignancies as allowed by the protocol. The patient has been diagnosed with a Potential ImmuneMediated Disease (pIMD). Patients with vitiligo are not excluded from the study. The patient has a history of confirmed adrenal dysfunction. The patient requires concomitant treatment with any immunosuppressive agent, or with systemic corticosteroids prescribed for chronic treatment (more than 7 consecutive days). The patient needs chronic long term oxygen therapy (LTOT). The patient has medically uncontrolled congestive heart failure or hypertension, unstable heart disease or uncontrolled arrhythmia at the time of randomization. The patient has an uncontrolled bleeding disorder. The patient has undergone splenectomy. The patient is known to be Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV)positive. The patient has psychiatric or addictive disorders that may compromise his/her ability to give informed consent, or to comply with the trial procedures. The patient has other concurrent severe medical problems, unrelated to the malignancy, that would significantly limit full compliance with the study or expose the patient to unacceptable risk. The patient has a history of allergic disease or reactions likely to be exacerbated by any component of the study investigational product. The patient has received any investigational or nonregistered product within the 30 days preceding randomization, or planned use during the study period. For female patients: the patient is pregnant or lactating or is planning to become pregnant.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Antigen-Specific</keyword>
</DOC>