<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02973321</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: The primary objective of this study is to assess the dose-response relationship of SAR425899 versus placebo in terms of glycemic control as measured by the change in glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1c). Secondary Objectives: - To assess the effect of SAR425899 on body weight. - To assess the safety and immunogenicity profile of SAR425899, including assessment of the heart rate (HR) change by electrocardiogram (ECG) and Holter monitor. - To assess the proportion of patients achieving predefined HbA1c targets of &lt;7% and &lt;6.5% as well as the proportion of patients achieving ≥5% and ≥10% body weight loss. - To assess the effect of once daily dosing of SAR425899 on additional parameters of glycemic control and lipid metabolism. - To assess the effect of once daily dosing of SAR425899 on additional pharmacodynamic (PD) biomarkers. - To assess the pharmacokinetic (PK) profile and parameters of SAR425899, inter-individual and inter-occasion variability in PK parameters using a population PK approach.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess the Safety and Efficacy of SAR425899 in Patients With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The total study duration will be approximately 30 weeks, consisting of 3 weeks screening period at the site, a 26 weeks treatment period, and 3 days post treatment follow up period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria : Patients with type2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) for at least 3 months before the screening visit. On diet/exercise and/or treatment with metformin (stable dose of ≥1500 mg/day or maximal tolerated dose) for at least 3 months prior to screening. Signed informed consent. Exclusion criteria: At screening, patient's age &lt; legal age of adulthood and &gt;80 years. Glycated hemoglobin at screening visit &lt;7.0% or &gt;10.0%. Body mass index (BMI) &lt;25 kg/m^2 or &gt;45.0 kg/m^2. Pregnant or lactating women. Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) not protected by highlyeffective method(s) of birth control and/or who are unwilling or unable to be tested for pregnancy. Diagnosis of type 1 diabetes mellitus. Fasting plasma glucose of &gt;15 mmol/L (270 mg/dL) measured by the central laboratory at screening (Visit 1), and confirmed (&gt;15 mmol/L [270 mg/dL]) by a repeat test before randomization. Treatment with glucoselowering agents(s) other than metformin, currently or within the 3 months prior to screening. Previous insulin use, except for episode(s) of shortterm treatment (≤15 consecutive days) for intercurrent illness or pregnancy, or use of insulin within the last 6 months. Contraindication(s) to metformin use. Contraindication(s) to liraglutide use. Significant change in body weight in the 3 months before screening. Poorly controlled hypertension (a resting systolic blood pressure (SBP) &gt;160 mm Hg and/or diastolic blood pressure (DBP) &gt;95 mm Hg at screening). History of long QT syndrome and/or QTc more than 450 ms at screening visit. History of pancreatitis or pancreatectomy. History of weight loss surgery. Personal or immediate family history of medullary thyroid cancer (MTC) or genetic conditions that predispose to MTC. Any prior exposure to drugs belonging to the class of glucagonlike peptide1 (GLP1) receptor agonists/GLP1 analogs. Contraindications or known hypersensitivity reaction to glucagon. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>