<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01827306</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Biofreeze速 is a topical analgesic, frequently used in the office or given to a patient for home use as a way to mitigate pain during the course of treatment. Rehabilitative exercises are considered an important component of care for shoulder pain patients, although pain can be a limiting factor in the advancement of rehabilitation. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the addition of Biofreeze速 to an in-office group of shoulder pain patients to determine its impact on pain reduction. Methods: Patients 18-64 years old with mechanical shoulder pain who are candidates for standard shoulder therapy will be randomized into two groups (N=20). The Control group (N=10) will receive standard shoulder therapy alone while the Intervention group (N=10) will receive standard shoulder therapy plus Biofreeze速 just prior to initiating the in-office exercise program. Values of pain (NPRS) and disability (ASES) will be recorded at baseline, 2 weeks, and 4 weeks. Hypotheses will be addressed by repeated measures ANOVAs within and between group, time, and interaction main effects. Clinical Relevance: Progression of therapeutic exercises can be limited by pain and the associated disability. The ability to decrease shoulder pain and disability with a topical analgesic will allow health care professionals to advance patients through a therapeutic exercise program without the restriction of pain. In turn, patients will correct the underlying condition of their shoulder pain at a faster rate.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Biofreeze速 on Shoulder Pain and In-office Exercise Performance</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Shoulder Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Menthol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1864 years old mechanical shoulder pain candidates for conservative care pregnancy radicular symptoms not a candidate for conservative care history of recent shoulder surgery</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>