<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01243840</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose of the study 1. The predictive value of central aortic pressure and aortic pulse wave velocity (PWV) in a Japanese population is not known. The purpose of this study is to quantify the predictive value of these indices in the determination of cardiovascular risk. 2. Recently, a non-invasive method to separate the aortic pressure waveform into the separate ejection pressure wave and reflected pressure wave has become available. With this decomposition method, it is possible to estimate aortic PWV (named AVI). The second objective of this study is to determine if AVI can be a substitute for carotid-femoral PWV (cf-PWV), the current gold standard for aortic PWV measurement. 3. To study vascular aging of the Japanese population by evaluating central blood pressure and aortic PWV by age, and compare these values to similar studies done in Caucasian and Chinese patient populations. 4. To study the relationship between the magnitude of the aortic reflected pressure wave and the degree of left ventricular (LV) hypertrophy and LV diastolic function.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Japan Central Aortic Pressure Prospective Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Subjects who visit hospital for their health checks Healthy volunteers who agree to participate in this study History of coronary artery disease, cerebrovascular disease, congestive heart failure, aortic dissection Subjects taking vasoactive drugs (antihypertensive and/or nitrates) Atrial fibrillation or atrial flutter Renal dysfunction (serum creatinine ≥3 mg/dl) Type I diabetes mellitus Hepatic dysfunction (AST and/or ALT ≥100 IU/l) A history of malignant tumor within 5 years of enrollment or suspected Pregnancy, possible pregnancy Chronic inflammation disease Not suited to the clinical trial as judged by a collaborating physician Inability to give informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Central aortic pressure</keyword>
	<keyword>Aortic pulse wave velocity</keyword>
	<keyword>Aortic PWV using a single pressure recording</keyword>
	<keyword>Vascular aging</keyword>
	<keyword>Left ventricular hypertrophy</keyword>
	<keyword>Left ventricular diastolic function</keyword>
</DOC>