<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01024816</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether Restorative yoga versus stretching exercises will reduce risk factors for metabolic syndrome in adults with metabolic syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Practicing Restorative Yoga or Stretching for the Metabolic Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Metabolic abnormalities, including visceral adiposity, insulin resistance, hyperglycemia, hypertension and dyslipidemia, occur together and are associated with excessive caloric intake and inadequate physical activity. Persons with the metabolic syndrome are at high risk of developing type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease. Lifestyle and behavioral interventions reduce these risks, but many individuals with increased metabolic risk find it difficult to achieve and maintain weight loss and increased physical activity. We are conducting a rigorous randomized controlled trial at two clinical sites to determine if Restorative yoga compared to stretching exercises improves the metabolic syndrome among overweight and underactive individuals who meet criteria for the metabolic syndrome.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Anyone between the ages of 21 and 65 who may meet the criteria for the metabolic syndrome can signup for the screening process. A more thorough screening process will be conducted to determine whether or not you are eligible to enroll in the study Underactive Overweight Pregnancy or breast feeding Chronic illnesses: cancer, kidney disease, cirrhosis of the liver, rheumatologic diseases, or chronic infections Not ambulatory or neurological condition causing impaired mobility Weight over 400 pounds History of or plans for bariatric surgery Inability to speak and read English</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metabolic Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Restorative Yoga</keyword>
	<keyword>Stretching</keyword>
	<keyword>Visceral adiposity</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized controlled trial</keyword>
</DOC>