<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01024530</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of ex vivo expanded autologous immune killer cells in treating hepatocellular carcinoma patients in： 1. Reduction of tumor size 2. Reducing the relapse rate: Reducing the frequency of TACE treatment by IKC injections.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II/III Trial of Hepatocellular Carcinoma Patients Treated by ex Vivo Expanded Autologous Immune Killer Cells as the Adjunct Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Sign and give written informed consent. 2. Age≧20 years, but＜80 years. 3. Hepatocellular carcinoma by CT, MRI, AFP, angiography or cytology/biopsy examinations. 4. Barcelona staging system stage B and C. 5. Never receive TACE treatment and comply with the standard of TACE treatment. 6. ChildPugh stage A and B. 7. ECOG performance status 0 to 2. 1. Participant of other clinical trial within the past 4 weeks of screening period. 2. Receiver of chemotherapy, radiotherapy, immunotherapy, hormone therapy, local tumor therapy, or target therapy within the past 4 weeks of screening period. 3. Carriers of HIV or HTLV within the past 4 weeks of screening period. 4. With Active acute or chronic infection（by investigator's judgement）. 5. Other diseases, except hepatocellular carcinoma, which are lifethreatening to the patients（by investigator's judgement)for example: 5.1 Active cardiac disease requiring therapy for coronary artery disease, congestive heart failure, arrhythmia or myocardial infarction. 5.2 With previous history of encephalopathy within the past six months. 5.3 Involved Involving systemically or known central nerve system diseases（brain or meningeal metastasis）. 6. Women of pregnant or breastfeeding or childbearing potential but without adequate contraception.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>hepatocellular carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>HCC</keyword>
	<keyword>NK</keyword>
	<keyword>immune killer cells</keyword>
</DOC>