<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01024699</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine differences in the XLIF and TLIF procedures with respect to perioperative variables in adult patients with low-grade symptomatic spondylolisthesis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>XLIF® vs. MAS®TLIF for the Treatment of Symptomatic Lumbar Degenerative Spondylolisthesis With or Without Central Stenosis.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is a prospective multi-center randomized evaluation of clinical and radiographic outcomes of two commonly used lumbar interbody fusion procedures (XLIF and TLIF) in adult patients with low-grade symptomatic spondylolisthesis. The study seeks to identify differences between the procedures with respect to perioperative variables.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Spondylolisthesis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female patients who are at least 18 years of age; Patients who present with symptomatic Grade I or II degenerative spondylolisthesis at 1 or 2 contiguous lumbar levels between L1 and L5 and are surgical candidates for interbody lumbar fusion surgery; symptoms should include radiculopathy and/or neurogenic claudication with or without back pain; Patients who have been unresponsive to at least 6 months of conservative treatments or exhibit progressive neurological symptoms in the face of conservative treatment; Patients who understand the conditions of enrollment and are willing to sign an informed consent to participate in the study. Patients with lumbar pathologies requiring treatment at more than 2 levels; Patients who have had previous lumbar fusion surgery; Patients with lytic spondylolisthesis or a defect of the pars interarticularis; Patients with radiographic confirmation of Grade IV facet joint disease or degeneration; Patients with noncontained or extruded herniated nucleus pulposus</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>