<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01816451</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study was to verify physiological responses to constant-load (continuous) vs. variable-intensity (interval) during 14 weeks of aerobic exercise on active men. The hypothesis was that would be differences in physiological variables on distinct modes of execution performed on the treadmill over a period of 14 weeks of training.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physiologic Adaptations to Interval and Continuous Running at Low Volume and Vigorous Intensity Over 14-Weeks.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Initially there were thirty five subjects, but due factors outside the present study, three individuals were excluded from the program. Two individuals during maximal exercise test (VO2) showed clinical impairment test being interrupted by the doctor and the third individual presented a plantar fasciitis in the early familiarization. Thirty two healthy and active males volunteered to participate in the study. All subjects exercised habitually, with at least 1 year experience aerobic training. The Human Ethics Committee of Rio de Janeiro Federal University approved this study (no 58659/02471312.8.0000.5257).The subjects performed a total of nine visits to the laboratory of the Brazilian Navy at City of Rio de Janeiro for physical tests on different days, except between visits I-II and VII-III. The interval between visits was one week between visits II-III-IV and VIII-IX, six weeks between the first day of training and visits V, four weeks between V-VI-VIII. All subjects from interval and continuous groups performed a total of 46 sessions of supervised running program.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>self reporting no contraindication to highintensity exercise. physically active on cardiorespiratory activities in a regular basis for at least six months. presence of negative responses on all items of the Questionnaire of Physical Activity Readiness (PARQ Test). make use of medication that may interfere with the results, especially inhibitors appetites and dietary supplements. presence of joint problems that prevents the achievement of training. presence of disorders such as diabetes, dyslipidemia and anemia have performed intense exercise with lowers members before the training sessions.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>32 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>aerobic capacity</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiorespiratory training</keyword>
	<keyword>blood lactate concentration</keyword>
	<keyword>heart rate</keyword>
</DOC>