<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02633800</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a 'randomized study' which means you may receive a substance that looks like the active medication but is not (called placebo). The study will test an investigational study drug called patritumab/placebo. Patritumab may work when combined with other medications that are approved for the treatment of head and neck cancer. They are called cetuximab, cisplatin or carboplatin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Trial Using Patritumab or Placebo in Combination With Cetuximab and a Platinum Agent for Patients With Squamous Cell Cancer of the Head and Neck</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms by Site</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult subjects ≥18 years old Histologically confirmed recurrent disease or metastatic SCCHN tumor and/or from its lymph nodal metastases originating from the oral cavity, oropharynx, hypopharynx, and larynx Must have or be willing to provide tumor tissue for testing Measurable disease per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumor (RECIST) Version 1.1 Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 or 1 Adequate hematological function Adequate renal function Adequate hepatic function Agreement to use effective contraception while on the study and for 6months after the end of the study Provided written informed consent(s) Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt;50% Prior EGFR targeted regimen Prior antiHER3 therapy Prior chemotherapy for recurrent/metastatic disease Anticancer therapy between biopsy and submission of sample History of other malignancies, except adequately treated nonmelanoma skin cancer, curatively treated insitu disease, or other solid tumors curatively treated with no evidence of disease for ≥ 2 years Known history of brain metastases or active brain metastases Uncontrolled hypertension Clinically significant electrocardiograph (ECG) findings Myocardial infarction within 1 year before enrollment, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina, or arrhythmia requiring medication Platinumcontaining drug therapy with radiotherapy less than 6 months before study drug treatment Therapeutic or palliative radiation therapy or major surgery within 4 weeks before study drug treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>squamous cell cancer of the head and neck</keyword>
</DOC>