<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02633878</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Threatened miscarriage is manifested by vaginal bleeding, with or without abdominal pain, while the cervix is closed and the fetus is viable and inside the uterine cavity.Threatened miscarriage is a common complication of pregnancy occurring in 20% of all clinically recognized pregnancies and about half of these will eventually result in pregnancy loss.Micronized progesterone which is used in a range of indications including infertility due to luteal insufﬁciency and threatened and habitual abortion, has a similar molecular structure and pharmacological effects to endogenous progesterone.Chinese Herbal Medicines is a part of Traditional Chinese Medicines and has been widely used for the treatment of miscarriage in China and other Asian countries for centuries.CHM have become very popular alternative to Western medicines and are commonly used as an alternative treatment for threatened miscarriage.Amongst all the causes for threatened miscarriage, "Kidney Deficiency" is the most important cause leading to threatened miscarriage and "Shou Tai Pill" is the most frequently used formula (72.0%) to treat threatened miscarriage.This basic formula is made up of four individual Chinese medicines, including Chinese Dodder Seed (Semen Cuscuta), Chinese Taxillus Twig (Flerlia Taxillus), Himalayan Teasel Root (Radix Dipsaci), and Donkey-hide Glue (Colla Corii Asini).Furthermore, supplementary of Common/Wingde Yan Rhizoma in the formula can enhance the therapeutic effects by further strengthening kidney of pregnant women.The goal of this double-bind, randomized and double dummy controlled trial is to determine which of the two oral medications, CHM or Micronized progesterone, and will mostly likely result in live birth in women with threatened miscarriage.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chinese Herbal Medicine and Micronized Progesterone for Threatened Miscarriage RCT</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Abortion, Spontaneous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abortion, Threatened</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Progesterone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age of women between 1837 years. 2. Pregnant (as confirmed by positive urinary pregnancy tests). 3. Vaginal bleeding with or without abdominal pain, while the cervix is closed by visual exam and the fetus is viable inside the uterine cavity during early pregnancy(510 weeks gestation). 4. No previous treatment for miscarriage. 5. Ability and willingness to give informed consent. 6. Willingness to be randomized and to take daily study medications for up to several months. 1. Pregnancies of Unknown Location (PUL). This will include pregnancies with an hCG level &gt; 2500mIU/mL without visualization of an intrauterine or extrauterine pregnancies. 2. Ectopic pregnancy. 3. Multiple pregnancy. 4. &gt; 2 prior pregnancy losses including biochemical pregnancy and intrauterine pregnancy loss or a pregnancy loss ≥ 6 weeks from LMP. 5. Nonviable pregnancy. 6. Serial serum hCG levels which show a decline or a plateau (2 day increase ≤ 10%). 7. Intrauterine abnormalities and Fibroids distorting uterine cavity (as assessed by ultrasound). 8. Known abnormal parental karyotype . 9. Bleeding attributed to a vulvar, vaginal, or cervical source unrelated to the pregnancy. 10. Presence of a congenital or acquired bleeding diathesis. 11. Presence of contributing major medical disorders. 12. Use of agents that may contribute to bleeding such as aspirin, NSAIDs, etc. 13. Current use of Chinese Herbal Medicines within 2 months. 14. Current use of progestins oral, intramuscular, vaginal, etc within 2 months. 15. Known current or recent alcohol abuse or illicit drug use. 16. Current diagnosis of sexually transmitted infection.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>37 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>