<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00547157</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to estimate, with pre-specified precision, the difference in local-regional control (LRC) rate at 2 years in subjects receiving chemoradiotherapy (CRT) or panitumumab plus radiotherapy (PRT) as first line treatment for locally advanced squamous cell carcinoma for the head and neck (SCCHN). A formal hypothesis will not be tested in this trial; however, the treatment arm difference in LRC rates at 2 years will be estimated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Radiotherapy Plus Panitumumab Compared to Chemoradiotherapy With Unresected, Locally Advanced Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Head and Neck</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary Objective: To estimate, with pre-specified precision, the difference in local-regional control (LRC) rate at 2 years in subjects receiving chemoradiotherapy (CRT) or panitumumab plus radiotherapy (PRT) as first line treatment for locally advanced squamous cell carcinoma for the head and neck (SCCHN). Secondary Objectives: To estimate the difference between 2 treatment regimens (CRT vs PRT) on other measures of clinical benefit, including LRC, overall response rate (ORR), progression-free survival (PFS), overall survival (OS); and safety. Tertiary Objectives: To estimate the difference in health-related quality of life (HRQoL) and performance status in subjects receiving PRT or CRT. Exploratory Objectives: To investigate potential biomarker development based on assessment of blood and tumor and the proposed mechanism of actions of study drugs. In addition, to investigate the effect of genetic variation in cancer genes and drug target genes on SCCHN and subject response to study drugs (separate informed consent required). Hypothesis: A formal hypothesis will not be tested in this trial; however, the treatment arm difference in LRC rates at 2 years will be estimated. Study Design: This is a phase 2, open-label, randomized, multicenter study. Eligible subjects will be randomized in a 2:3 ratio to either of the following regimens: Arm 1 CRT: - Accelerated fractionation RT: 70 to 72 Gy - delivered over 6 to 6.5 weeks - Cisplatin: 100 mg/m2 (given on days 1 and 22 of RT) or Arm 2 PRT: - Accelerated fractionation RT: 70 to 72 Gy - delivered over 6 to 6.5 weeks - Panitumumab: 9.0 mg/kg Q3W (given on days 1, 22, and 43 of RT)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed SCC of the oral cavity, oropharynx, hypopharynx or larynx Stage III or Stage IVab (M0) disease according to the American Joint Committee on Cancer staging manual 6th edition (locally advanced) ECOG performance status of 0 or 1 Bidimensionally measurable disease &gt;/= 10 mm in at least 1 dimension NO Primary tumor of the nasopharynx, sinuses, salivary gland, or skin NO Subjects requiring prophylactic tracheostomy NO Prior (or concomitant) malignancy (except nonmelanomatous skin cancer or in situ cervical cancer), other than the study disease (SCCHN), unless treated with curative intent with no evidence of disease for &gt;/= 3 years NO Prior treatment for locally advanced SSCHN NO Prior surgery for SCCHN (except nodal sampling or biopsy for study disease) NO Major surgery &lt;/= 28 days before randomization or minor surgery &lt;/= 14 days before randomization with the exception of feeding tube placement, dental extractions, central venous catheter placement, biopsies and nodal sampling</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>head and neck</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>radiotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>chemoradiotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>panitumumab</keyword>
	<keyword>locally advanced head &amp; neck cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>EGFr</keyword>
	<keyword>epidermal growth factor receptor</keyword>
	<keyword>SCCHN</keyword>
	<keyword>locally advanced SCCHN</keyword>
	<keyword>HNC</keyword>
	<keyword>epidermal growth factor</keyword>
</DOC>