<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00547664</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall aim of this study is to find out whether Hylenex recombinant (for short, Hylenex) in subcutaneous (SC) injection improves the speed and effectiveness of SC opioids in hospice patients. Specifically, this study proposes to compare the level of self-reported pain in hospice patients started on SC infusions of morphine and hydromorphone (Dilaudid) over the initial 8 hours of opioid infusion with and without the preceded co-injection of Hylenex. Hospice patients include both home-bound patients as well as those under intensive care in hospice houses.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Hylenex in the Treatment of Pain Among Hospice Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>As of January 2009, 58 patients were recruited to the study as study subjects. Target goals for the study is to recruit 88 subjects with full and accurate information with about 44 patients in the Hylenex group and another group of subjects in the control group.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Nonpregnant, nonlactating adults 18+ years enrolled in inpatient facilities at LifePath or Good Shepherd Hospice 2. Ability to provide informed consent; Patient has decisionmaking capacity (SPMSQ score 6+) 3. Ability to provide numerical report on pain level on pain scale 4. Englishspeaking 5. Pain not satisfactorily controlled with current meds oral, topical, or rectal; Pain level greater than 3 at admission on a 010 scale 6. Able to selfadminister bolus dose or ask someone to hit bolus button 7. Estimated life expectancy of 3 days or more 8. Patients appropriate for continuous SC infusion with either morphine or hydromorphone. 1. History of allergy or hypersensitivity to Hylenex or any components of product 2. Patients on infusion therapy for pain management up to 14 days prior to entering inpatient facilities. 3. Patients who are actively dying identified by any of the following physical signs and symptoms: 1. noncommunicative or unresponsiveness; b) confusion/disorientation about time, place, and people; c) significant chest congestion with gurgling sounds; d) restless and repetitive motions; e) little or no food or fluid intake; f) minimal urine output and g) different breathing pattern, i.e., shallow rapid breaths with period of no breathing.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hylenex, time tagged pain pain reduction, hospice population</keyword>
</DOC>