<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00769249</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Gathering information about the positive changes in quality of life of older patients with cancer and their care givers may help doctors learn more about the disease and plan better treatment. PURPOSE: This research study is looking at positive changes in the quality of life of older cancer patients and their caregivers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Positive Changes in Quality of Life of Older Cancer Patients and Their Caregivers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - To use prior data from an existing registry (Quality of Life Survey Registry for Persons With Cancer and Family Caregivers protocol CASE-8Z05) and to expand upon these data by adding measures that capture the particularly salient concepts of the patient/caregiver dyadic relationship and posttraumatic growth. - To identify rates and psychosocial correlates of posttraumatic growth among older adult cancer patient/spouse or partner dyads. OUTLINE: Patients and their caregivers complete three questionnaires that will take approximately 20 minutes either by mail or telephone. The questionnaires comprise of demographic and psychosocial correlates of posttraumatic growth including age, ethnicity, socioeconomic status, education, anxiety, relationship quality, coping style, social support, and cultural beliefs about caring for elders.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Patient must meet the following criteria: Confirmed cancer of any type Currently receiving medical care at the Ireland Cancer Center at University Hospitals of Cleveland Must have enrolled and participated in CASE8Z05 Identified available family caregiver of a patient diagnosed with stage III or IV cancer PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Patients must meet the following criteria: ECOG performance status 03 Cognitively competent to be interviewed Able to speak and comprehend English Caregivers must be able to speak and comprehend English PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>psychosocial effects of cancer and its treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>unspecified adult solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
</DOC>