<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00769587</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Thalidomide may stop the growth of systemic mastocytosis by blocking blood flow to the disease. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well thalidomide works in treating patients with relapsed or progressive systemic mastocytosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Thalidomide in Treating Patients With Relapsed or Progressive Systemic Mastocytosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the objective response rate at 6 months in patients with systemic mastocytosis treated with thalidomide. Secondary - Determine the tolerability of this drug in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients receive oral thalidomide once daily for 6 months in the absence of disease progression.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mastocytosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precancerous Conditions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mastocytosis, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thalidomide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of systemic mastocytosis Aggressive or borderline (smoldering) disease (in first line or more) Relapsed or progressive disease Measurable or evaluable disease Presence of cKit D816V mutation in the skin, spine, or infiltrated organs No nonsymptomatic mastocytosis PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Life expectancy &gt; 3 months Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception for 1 month prior to, during, and until first menstrual cycle after completion of study treatment Bilirubin &lt; 2 times normal (unrelated to disease) Liver enzymes &lt; 2 times normal (unrelated to disease) Creatinine ≤ 300 mmol/L No central or peripheral neuropathy leading to psychiatric concerns No HIV positivity No active infection or other serious underlying illness that would preclude treatment No history of thromboembolism or deep vein thrombosis No geographical, social, or psychological reasons preventing medical monitoring PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: More than 4 weeks since prior antitumor therapy (e.g., chemotherapy, radiotherapy) No other concurrent treatment specific for this disease No concurrent participation in another experimental drug trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>aggressive systemic mastocytosis</keyword>
	<keyword>smoldering systemic mastocytosis</keyword>
</DOC>