<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02204761</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot clinical trial studies proton beam radiation therapy in treating patients with thoracic cancer that has come back and have received prior radiation therapy. Proton beam radiation therapy uses high energy protons to kill tumor cells and may cause less damage to normal tissue.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Proton Beam Radiation Therapy in Treating Patients With Recurrent Thoracic Cancer Who Have Received Prior Radiation Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the grade 3 toxicity associated with thoracic re-irradiation with proton therapy, with prospectively applied normal organ radiation dose limits. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the efficacy of thoracic re-irradiation with proton therapy. OUTLINE: Patients undergo proton beam radiation therapy per standard of care. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 3 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Second Primary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thoracic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women of childbearing age must have a negative pregnancy test Patients must have received prior radiation treatment to the chest; records of prior radiation treatment must be available Patients must have received prior chest radiation at least 3 months prior to enrollment in this trial; radiation treatment to other body sites not overlapping with current radiation fields are allowed within the 3 months period (example, brain radiation is allowed) Patients must have a prior diagnosis of cancer inside the thoracic cavity; both primary thoracic malignancies (such as lung cancer) as well as metastatic lesions (such as metastatic breast cancer or colorectal cancer to the lungs) are allowed; patient must have pathologic confirmation of the recurrent thoracic tumor, or have an enlarging thoracic mass (as seen on two computed tomography [CT] scans at least 6 weeks apart, with either a &gt; 25% or &gt; 5 mm increase in longest dimension) Patients must have a life expectancy of &gt; 6 months Patients must have measurable disease to be treated with proton radiation (minimum tumor dimension at least 10 mm on CT imaging) Patients should have either nonmetastatic cancer of the thorax, or metastatic cancer to the thorax and candidate for definitive radiation dose to the thoracic tumor (not palliative intent), tumor radiation dose to at least BED2Gy 60 Gy Patients must be able to receive proton radiation treatment All stages of cancer are eligible There are no limits on prior therapy; patients are allowed to have prior chemotherapy and surgery; patients are allowed to have concurrent chemotherapy with radiation treatment; patients are allowed to have chemotherapy or surgery after radiation treatment Patients are allowed to be on another study concurrent with this protocol Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document Patients who have never received radiation to the chest Patients who received radiation to the chest within the past 3 months (in a region that overlaps with current radiation fields) Patients with life expectancy &lt; 6 months Pregnant women Patients unable to provide informed consent Prisoners</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>