<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02204722</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is to evaluate efficacy and safety of Imatinib in two groups of patients; all patients should be diagnosed less than 3 months as chronic myeloid leukemia in a chronic phase. The group A, the reference group, will have 10% or less than 10% of the BCR-ABL level after three month dosing and be maintained their dose of 400mg/day. On the other hand, the group B, will have more than 10% and the dose will be increased from 400mg/day to 600mg/day. The superiority of the group B will be proved by evaluating the MMR rate of these two groups after 12 months of administeration of Imatinib.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate Efficacy and Safety of Glinib in Newly Diagnosed CML Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelogenous, Chronic, BCR-ABL Positive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Imatinib Mesylate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>at the age of 18 or more newly diagnosed within three months as a Chronic Myeloid Leukemia with positive Philadelphia chromosome and appearance of BCRABL transcript with 0 2 of ECOG Performance Status with normal renal function with normal hepatic function able to understand and decide to involve the study history of radiation therapy for more than 25% of bone marrow due to other malignant diseases history of other clinically relevant malignant tumors with bleeding disorders which are not related to leukemia evidence of clinically relevant cardiac dysfunction with severe disease which cannot be regulated by other organs a previous administration of Imatinib more than a week prior to the first dose. participation in other drug study(eg. intervention trial) within 30 days prior to the screening visit HIVinfected females with pregnancy, childbearing or lactating potential other reasons determined by investigators</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>