<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02204904</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study ALD 103 is a multi-site, global, data collection study that is designed to evaluate safety and efficacy of allogenic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (allo-HSCT) in patients with CALD aged 17 or younger.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Observational Study to Evaluate Allogeneic HSCT Outcomes for Cerebral Adrenoleukodystrophy (CALD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study ALD-103 is a multi-site, global, prospective and retrospective data collection study that is designed to evaluate outcomes of allo-HSCT in male subjects ≤17 years of age with CALD. Retrospective subjects will be ≤17 years of age at the time of treatment; prospective subjects will be ≤17 years of age at the time of consent. This is an observational study that does not involve the use of an investigational drug or medicinal product. It allows for collection of specific data points related to the allo-HSCT procedures and outcomes. Suitability for allo-HSCT and the choice of the treatment protocol utilized for these subjects will be determined by the subjects' treating physicians as per their institutional policies/protocols and other local treatment guidelines. Procedures to be performed will be those according to institutional protocols and the accepted management of CALD, including supportive care, choice of graft source, allo-HSCT protocol, prophylaxis, and management of graft-versus-host disease (GVHD). Subjects will be monitored from Screening before allo-HSC infusion, through their Month 48 Visit after allo-HSC infusion. Follow-up will include monitoring of outcome measures at Months 1, 2, 3, 6, 9, 12, 18, 24, 36, and 48 after allo-HSC infusion (prospective analysis). In addition to the subjects in the prospective analysis, subjects who received an allo-HSCT on or after January 1, 2013 who will be available for at least the Month 24 visit (24 ± 1 months after allo-HSC infusion) may also be enrolled and followed through their Month 48 Visit after their most recent allo-HSC infusion (partial prospective analysis and retrospective analysis, as applicable).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adrenoleukodystrophy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Provide informed consent from a competent custodial parent or guardian with legal capacity to execute a local Institutional Review Board (IRB)/Independent Ethics Committee (IEC) approved consent. In addition, informed assent will be sought from capable subjects, in accordance with the directive of the institution's IRB/IEC and all other local requirements. 2. Be male and aged 17 years and younger (i.e., &lt;18 years of age) at the time of parental/guardian consent and, where appropriate, subject assent. 3. Have a confirmed diagnosis of CALD as defined by abnormal VLCFA profile and cerebral lesion on brain MRI. 4. Be scheduled for alloHSCT evaluation/procedure (prospective) at a study site or have received their most recent alloHSC infusion on or after January 1, 2013. 1. Previous treatment with a gene therapy product. 2. Received their most recent alloHSC infusion prior to January 1, 2013.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>X-linked Adrenoleukodystrophy</keyword>
	<keyword>Hematopoietic Stem Cells</keyword>
</DOC>