<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01249599</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this prospective single-center study is to evaluate endothelial function, arterial compliance, sympathetic nervous activity at rest and after mental and physical stress, carotid atherosclerosis, oxidative stress parameters, quality of life and platelet adhesion in patients with apical ballooning syndrome and age-matched controls.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Stress-induced Vascular Dysfunction: Evaluation of Endothelial Function in a Cohort of Patients With Takotsubo Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of this prospective single-center study is to evaluate endothelial function, arterial compliance, sympathetic nervous activity at rest and after mental and physical stress, carotid atherosclerosis, oxidative stress parameters, quality of life and platelet adhesion in patients with Takotsubo Syndrome (apical ballooning syndrome/broken heart syndrome) and age-matched controls.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Takotsubo Cardiomyopathy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: We plan to include male or female subjects, age 1880 with a diagnosis of Takotsubo Syndrome (according to standard clinical criteria[Strony, J., et al., Analysis of shear stress and hemodynamic factors in a model of coronary artery stenosis and thrombosis. Am J Physiol, 1993. 265(5 Pt 2): p. H178796.]) in the last 10 years. Moreover, patients matched to the Takotsubo patients for age and cardiovascular risk factors will be included in the control group. All patients will signed an written informed consent Exclusion criteria: Long acting nitrates, or PDE5Hemmer Alcohol or drug abuse, Malignancy (unless healed or remission &gt; 5 years) Disease with systemic inflammation (e.g. rheumatoid arthritis, M. Crohn) Pulmonary Hypertension Participation in another study within the last month</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Takotsubo Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>apical balooning syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>stress-cardiomyopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>endothelial function</keyword>
	<keyword>sympathetic nervous activity</keyword>
	<keyword>platelet adhesion</keyword>
	<keyword>arterial compliance</keyword>
</DOC>