<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03060733</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective is to obtain stool samples from post-therapy subjects already undergoing evaluation for an H. pylori infection by upper esophagogastroduodenoscopy (EGD) and gastric biopsy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Helicobacter Pylori Sample Collection Protocol Post Therapy Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Stools will be collected and tested, at a later date, in a clinical performance study with an investigational H. pylori antigen assay. This study will be coordinated by the Sponsor.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abdominal Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Helicobacter Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anorexia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult ≥ 22 years, either gender Subject previously diagnosed with H. pylori infection by EGD and gastric biopsy Subject received and completed FDA approved treatment option Minimum of 4 weeks to one year has lapsed after completion of FDA approved treatment option Subject is already undergoing EGD and gastric biopsy as part of routine care to measure H. pylori posttherapy response Biopsy is obtained from antrum and/or corpus is tested by CRM At least two of the three CRM tests are performed Subject whose EGD with biopsy procedure occurred ≤ 7 days prior to stool collection Willing and able to sign the IRB approved Informed Consent form for this project, or able to provide Informed Consent in accordance with 21 CFR 50 Subpart B Any subject that does not meet the inclusion criteria Subject with current severe H. pylori infection Subject ingested compounds that may interfere with detecting of H. pylori, e.g. 4 weeks for antibiotics and 2 weeks for Bismuth preparations or proton pump inhibitors prior to collection Pregnant or lactating Inability or unwilling to perform required study procedures Subject is unable or unwilling to provide informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>22 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>