<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02966600</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this randomized controlled trial was to assess the impact of progressive resistance exercise (PRE) in PD patients with akinesia and rigidity (AR-subtype). The investigators hypothesized the intervention would have a beneficial effect on the study outcomes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Strength Training and Different Subtypes of Parkinson´s Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Twenty-eight patients with PD AR-type of both sexes, were recruited for this trial. Each participant were assigned randomly to either intervention (N=13) or control (N=15) group. The intervention group participated in sixteen PRE training sessions for eight weeks: two sessions per week on non-consecutive days, sixty-seventy min each one. The control group followed their usual weekly physical activity routine. All patients underwent antrophometrical and neuromuscular function assessment (CoP measurements -primary outcomes- and the Ten-Meters Walk Test -TMWT- -secondary outcomes-). In addition, they were asked to provide ratings for the Spanish validated versions of the the Freezing of Gait Questionnaire (FOG-Q, 6-item version) -secondary outcomes-, the 39-item Parkinson ́s disease Questionnaire (PDQ39) -secondary outcomes- and the MDS-UPDRS -secondary outcomes-. Additionally, ratings of perceived exertion (RPE) (Borg &gt;6-20 scale) - secondary outcomes-, were recorded at the end of each PRE training session. Tests were carried out at three times: pre-test (before the training program), post-test (eight weeks after pre-tests, at the end of the training period), and four weeks after the post-test (re-test).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosed with PD ARtype and Hoehn and Yahr Scale 12, (H&amp;Y) Do not express any type of dementia Able to stand for two min without assistance; Able to walk ten metres without assistance. Exclusion criteria: To suffer a neurological disease other than PD. Do not meet some of the inclusion criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>