<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02966886</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to determine the difference in disease specific quality of life outcome measures between patients diagnosed with osteoarthritis of the shoulder joint whom require a total shoulder replacement between the following study arms: 1)TSA using an augmented component compared with TSA using a standard component with eccentric reaming in patients 65 years of age or younger or 2) TSA using an augmented component or reverse shoulder arthroplasty in patients older than 65 years of age as measured by the Western Ontario Osteoarthritis of the Shoulder Index (WOOS) score at post-operative time intervals (ie. 3, 6, 12 and 24 months). The secondary objective is to determine the difference in disease specific quality of life between treatment allocations in both age groups as measured by the Constant score, the American Shoulder and Elbow Surgeons Standardized Shoulder Assessment form (ASES) and the EuroQol Group EQ-5D-5L score at post-operative time intervals (ie. 3, 6, 12 and 24 months). A secondary objective will be to determine the survivorship of the components as measured by the degree of radiographic lucencies and component alignment determined by a CT scan at 1 and 5 years post-surgery between study allocations in both age groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Approach to Glenoid Management in Shoulder Osteoarthritis (OA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients who have failed standard nonsurgical management of their shoulder arthritis who would benefit from a shoulder arthroplasty. Failed medical management will be defined as persistent pain and disability despite adequate standard nonoperative management for 6 months. Medical management will be defined as: 1. The use of drugs including analgesics and nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs 2. Physiotherapy consisting of stretching, strengthening and local modalities (ultrasound, cryotherapy, etc) 3. Activity modification 2. Patients 65 years of age or younger will present with a type B2 glenoid deficiency, as defined by the Walch classification system, with greater than 15 degrees of retroversion. 3. Imaging, and intraoperative findings confirming advanced humeral head cartilage loss, with or without glenoid cartilage loss. 1. Walch B2 glenoid with less than 15 degrees of retroversion and who are 65 years of age or younger. 2. Active joint or systemic infection 3. Rotator cuff arthropathy 4. Significant muscle paralysis 5. Charcot's arthropathy 6. Major medical illness (life expectancy less then 1 year or unacceptably high operative risk) 7. Unable to speak or read English/French 8. Pregnancy 9. Psychiatric illness that precludes informed consent 10. Unwilling to be followed for 1 year</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Surgical Management</keyword>
</DOC>