<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02053350</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to test the efficacy of alanyl-glutamine supplementation in the treatment of C. difficile infection. We hypothesize that alanyl-glutamine when given with standard antibiotic treatment for C. difficile infection will decrease diarrhea, mortality and recurrent disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Study of Alanyl-glutamine Supplementation for the Treatment of C. Difficile Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glycine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult of either gender, 18 years or older, with C. difficile infection (CDI) Diarrhea associated with C. difficile positive stool assay Within 48 hours of receiving either metronidazole for mildmoderate disease or vancomycin for severe uncomplicated disease Admitted in the hospital at the time of enrollment Ability to provide informed consent Have an understanding of study procedures Ability to comply with study procedures for the entire length of the study Hypotension or shock Megacolon or moderate to severe ileus Acute abdomen Severe leukocytosis (WBC &gt; 20,000 cells /µL) Admission to intensive care unit on enrollment Inability to tolerate oral medication Other known etiology of diarrhea (e.g. other enteric pathogen, other intestinal disease) Inflammatory bowel disease (e.g. Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis) Enrollment in another investigational drug trial Currently receiving other alternative treatment for CDI (e.g. antibiotics other than metronidazole or vancomycin; probiotics; immunoglobulin therapy; fecal transplant) Pregnancy Unavailable for followup visits Life expectancy of &lt; 6 months Chronic liver disease or in subjects without known liver disease, ALT &gt; 3x normal Chronic kidney disease or in subjects without known kidney disease, estimated Creatinine clearance of &lt; 30 ml/min, even after rehydration</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Clostridium difficile</keyword>
	<keyword>glutamine</keyword>
	<keyword>diarrhea</keyword>
	<keyword>alanyl-glutamine</keyword>
</DOC>