<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02053792</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will examine the long-term safety and efficacy of rIX-FP for the control and prevention of bleeding episodes in children and adults with severe hemophilia B. The study will include subjects who have not previously been treated with Factor IX products, subjects who previously completed a CSL-sponsored rIX-FP lead-in study and subjects requiring major non-emergency surgery who have not previously completed a CSL-sponsored rIX-FP lead-in study. A surgical prophylaxis substudy will examine the efficacy of rIX-FP in subjects with hemophilia B who are undergoing non-emergency major or minor surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Safety and Efficacy Extension Study of a Recombinant Fusion Protein Linking Coagulation Factor IX With Albumin (rIX-FP) in Patients With Hemophilia B</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia B</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Main study inclusion criteria: For previously treated subjects, either: Completed a CSLsponsored rIXFP (CSL654) study, including study CSL654_3001 [NCT01496274] or study CSL654_3002 [NCT01662531]. Or: Scheduled to have a major nonemergency surgery within approximately 8 weeks from the anticipated date of receiving the first rIXFP injection. Not previously completed a CSLsponsored rIXFP leadin study. Male, 12 to 70 years of age. Documented severe hemophilia B (FIX activity of ≤ 2%), or confirmed at screening by the central laboratory. Subjects who have received FIX products (plasmaderived and / or recombinant FIX) for &gt; 150 exposure days (EDs), confirmed by their treating physician. No confirmed history of FIX inhibitor formation at screening by the central laboratory For previously untreated subjects: Male, up to 18 years of age. Documented severe hemophilia B (FIX activity of ≤ 2%), or confirmed at screening by the central laboratory. Never previously been treated with FIX clotting factor products (except previous exposure to blood components). No confirmed history of FIX inhibitor formation Surgery substudy inclusion criterion: Must require nonemergency surgery Exclusion criteria: Main study exclusion criteria: Currently receiving a therapy not permitted during the study. Any issue that, in the opinion of the investigator, would render the subject unsuitable for participation in the study. For subjects who have previously completed a CSLsponsored rIXFP study: Unwilling to participate in the study for a total of 100 exposure days. For subjects requiring major nonemergency surgery who have not previously completed a CSLsponsored rIXFP leadin study: Known hypersensitivity (ie, allergic reaction or anaphylaxis) to any FIX product or hamster protein. Known congenital or acquired coagulation disorder other than congenital FIX deficiency. Currently receiving IV immunomodulating agents such as immunoglobulin or chronic systemic corticosteroid treatment. Low platelet count, kidney or liver disease. Human immunodeficiency virus positive with a CD4 count &lt; 200/mm3. For previously untreated subjects: Known congenital or acquired coagulation disorder other than congenital FIX deficiency (except for vitamin K deficiency of the newborn). Known kidney or liver dysfunction or any condition which, in the investigator's opinion, place the patient at unjustifiable risk. The surgical substudy does not have any additional exclusion criteria, although subject(s) in France will not be eligible for the surgery substudy.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>