<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02452190</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to determine the effect of reslizumab (110 mg) administered subcutaneously every 4 weeks on clinical asthma exacerbations in adults and adolescents with asthma and elevated blood eosinophils who are inadequately controlled on standard-of-care asthma therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Reslizumab in Patients With Uncontrolled Asthma and Elevated Blood Eosinophils</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent is obtained. The patient is male or female, 12 years of age and older, with a diagnosis of asthma. The patient has FEV1 reversibility according to standard American Thoracic Society (ATS) or European Respiratory Society (ERS) protocol. The patient has required an inhaled corticosteroid. The patient has required an additional asthma controller medication besides inhaled corticosteroids. the patient has a history of asthma exacerbation. The patient must be willing and able to comply with study restrictions, perform requisite procedures and remain at the clinic for the required duration during the study period, and be willing to return to the clinic for the followup evaluation as specified in this protocol. Additional criteria may apply, please contact the investigator for more information The patient has any clinically significant, uncontrolled medical condition (treated or untreated) that would interfere with the study schedule or procedures, interpretation of efficacy results, or compromise the patient's safety. The patient has another confounding underlying lung disorder The patient has a known hypereosinophilic syndrome. The patient has a diagnosis of malignancy within 5 years of the screening visit, except for treated and cured nonmelanoma skin cancers. The patient is a pregnant or lactating woman, or intends to become pregnant during the study. Any woman becoming pregnant during the study will be withdrawn from the study. The patient is a current smoker or has a smoking history. The patient participated in a clinical trial within 30 days or 5 halflives of the investigational drug before screening, whichever is longer. The patient was previously exposed to reslizumab. The patient has a history of an immunodeficiency disorder including HIV. The patient has current or suspected drug and alcohol abuse. The patient has an active helminthic parasitic infection or was treated for one within 6 months of screening. The patient has a history of allergic reaction or hypersensitivity to any component of the study drug. Additional criteria may apply, please contact the investigator for more information</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>