<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01267422</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is meant to assess the safety and efficacy of rAAV2-ND4 treatment of Leber hereditary optic neuropathy with 11778 LHON mutation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of rAAV2-ND4 Treatment of Leber Hereditary Optic Neuropathy (LHON)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Leber's Hereditary Optic Neuropathy (LHON) is a maternally inherited ocular disorder associated with a mutation in mtDNA . The common manifestation is visual loss which caused by the respiratory chain enzymes complex dysfunction resulting in increased oxidative stress enzymes production. Material and Method Seven patients with 11778 LHON mutation were randomly treated with a Single IVT Injection of recombinant Adeno-Associated Virus-NADH dehydrogenase, subunit 4 (complex I)（rAAV2-ND4)（0.05ml).The dose was 5 × 10^9 vg/0.05 mL for patients younger than 12 years old, and 1 × 10^10 vg/0.05 mL for patients older than 12 years old. The visual acuity, visual evoked potential （VEP）,optical coherence tomography（ OCT）, computerized visual field, electroretinograms(ERG), retinal nerve fiber layer(RNFL)and Liver and kidney function in plasma were compared before and after treatment at 1,3,and 6, months interval.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Optic Nerve Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Optic Atrophy, Hereditary, Leber</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. comply with Leber hereditary optic neuropathy diagnostic criteria. 2. in patients with informed consent, voluntary participation. 3. signed informed consent. 4. 8 ≤ Age ≤ 60 years old, good health, the patient can tolerate local anesthesia surgery. 5. to comply with doctor's instructions, can in the time of referral. 1. Cardiopulmonary and renal function in severe weakness, cancer, a variety of bleeding disorders, acute sensing disease, high fever, high fever disease, women during pregnancy, heart disease, such as postoperative recovery period. 2. Are participating in other clinical studies of patients. 3. Patients with mental disorders.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Leber's Hereditary Optic Neuropathy,11778 LHON mutation,</keyword>
	<keyword>rAAV2-ND4,triamcinolone acetonide</keyword>
</DOC>