<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02090725</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purpose for this study is to provide access to 3,4 DAP, a drug which has demonstrated to be effective in treating weakness associated with Lambert-Eaton Myasthenic Syndrome. LEMS is a rare autoimmune cause of a defect in neuromuscular transmission. The disorder is clinically characterized by fluctuating muscle weakness, hyporeflexia and autonomic dysfunction.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Controlled Trial of 3,4-Diaminopyridine (3-4DAP) in Lambert-Eaton Myasthenic Syndrome (LEMS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>More than half of LEMS cases are associated with malignancy, usually small cell lung cancer. These paraneoplastic cases progress more quickly than primary autoimmune LEMS. An overlap syndrome with other autoimmune diseases is often detected in LEMS patients. 3,4 DAP is effective in LEMS because it increases calcium influx into the nerve terminal by blocking potassium efflux and thereby prolonging the presynaptic action potential. 3,4 DAP is less likely to provoke epileptic seizures than its precursor, 4-aminopyridine, because it is less able to cross the blood-brain barrier. 3,4 DAP is effective in increasing strength and improving autonomic symptoms in LEMS patients of both the primary autoimmune and paraneoplastic etiologies.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Muscle Weakness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paresis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lambert-Eaton Myasthenic Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>3,4-diaminopyridine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>4-Aminopyridine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female majority between 45 and 60 years of age diagnosed with LambertEaton Myasthenic Syndrome. subjects must be taking full dose of pyridostigmine does subject have a history of liver problems? does subject have a history of prolonged QTc syndrome (which is a condition where there is prolongation between the start of the Q wave and the end of the T wave in the heart's electrical cycle).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>fluctuating muscle weakness</keyword>
	<keyword>hyporeflexia</keyword>
	<keyword>autonomic Dysfunction</keyword>
</DOC>