<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02090543</DOC>
	<brief_summary>According to recent guidelines, long-term anticoagulation is recommended for patients with atrial fibrillation (AF) and a risk profile with CHA2DS2-VASc score of 1 or more. Vitamin K antagonists(VAK) and novel oral anticoagulants such as rivaroxaban are current treatment options for AF patients with additional risk factors for stroke. Currently there are only limited information to what extend AF patients prefer one or the other treatment option based on patient relevant characteristics of novel oral anticoagulants vs. VKAs. It is also unknown which of the characteristics influences patient preference most and how this relates to a neutral comparator. Furthermore, an additional unknown factor is also how patient evaluate their current treatment and if this leads to differences among treatment with VKAs and rivaroxaban.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>BAY 59-7939 (Xarelto, SPAF), Non Interventional Studies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivaroxaban</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phenprocoumon</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A.General Criteria (Group 1and Group2): diagnosed nonvalvular AF older than 18 years general capability and willingness to perform a structured patient interview in German no participation in any other clinical or observational study over the last 3 month Additional criteria for Group1 (VKAexperienced): active VKAtherapy for at least 3 month without significant interruptions in case of perioperative interruption VKA treatment should not have been hold for more than two weeks. Additional criteria for Group2 (rivaroxabanexperienced patients): active rivaroxabantherapy for at least 3 month without significant interruptions in case of perioperative interruption VKA treatment should not have been hold for more than two weeks. participation in any other clinical or observational study over the last 3 month</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>