<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00948155</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will demonstrate the behavioral responses to varenicline, helping to better understand its mechanisms. Hypotheses for the study are to observe decreases in smoking topography and nicotine cigarette choice on varenicline, relative to placebo; and decreases on day 21 relative to day 7 during varenicline treatment. We also propose to examine if extended duration of treatment has clinical significance in decreasing smoking behaviors, thus increasing the efficacy of varenicline.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Measuring Smoking Behaviors While Using Varenicline</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is designed to examine the behavioral responses a cigarette smoker may have to using varenicline. Behavioral responses may help to better understand its mechanisms which in turn could improve treatment outcomes. The primary hypothesis for the study is to observe decreases in smoking topography, an objective measure of smoking behavior or puffing, on varenicline, relative to placebo; and decreases on day 21 relative to day 7 during varenicline treatment. We will also examine puffing and nicotine cigarette choices during lab visits at baseline, and Days 7 and 21. We also propose to examine if extended duration of treatment has clinical significance in decreasing smoking behaviors, thus potentially increasing the efficacy of varenicline.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tobacco Use Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Varenicline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>self report minimum 10 daily cigarettes self report smoking every day past 5 years between the ages 2165 self report intention to try to quit smoking in the next 6 months self reported use of any nicotinecontaining products other than nonmenthol cigarettes self reported history or current treatment of substance abuse (other than nicotine dependence) self reported alcohol use greater than 25 standard drinks per week; currently pregnant, planned pregnancy or lactating (females: negative urine pregnancy screen) self reported history or current diagnosis of any Axis 1 disorders except past depression self reported serious or unstable disease within past year self reported history of epilepsy or seizure disorder; self reported history or current diagnosis of COPD (chronic obstructive pulmonary disease), cardiovascular disease, heart attack, or uncontrolled hypertension self reported kidney function impairment any current or recent (30 day) use of: smoking cessation medications, antipsychotics, antidepressants, antianxiety, panic medications, stimulants or opiatecontaining medications less than 5 years of daily smoking any medical condition or concomitant medication that could compromise participant safety or treatment provide a baseline carbon monoxide (CO) reading &lt; 10 ppm self reported use of non filtered cigarettes inability to provide informed consent or complete any of the study tasks as determined by the Principal Investigator and/or Study Physician</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>smoking</keyword>
	<keyword>nicotine</keyword>
	<keyword>varenicline</keyword>
</DOC>