<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03053518</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an initial validation study of the Personal Nutrition Project (PNP) algorithm in a North American population with recently diagnosed Type 2 Diabetes (T2D). This is a 2-stage, single-group feeding study in 20 individuals, including 10 participants managed with lifestyle alone, and 10 managed with lifestyle plus metformin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Validation of Machine Learning Based Personalized Nutrition Algorithm to Reduce Postprandial Glycemic Excursions Among North American Individuals With Newly Diagnosed Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The PNP algorithm, which uses a machine learning algorithm to predict postprandial glycemic, may be efficacious for generating tailored dietary advice to moderate the participant's glycemic response to food.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt;21 years to &lt;70 years Diagnosed with T2DM within 2 years with an HbA1c&lt;7% Diabetes management by metformin or lifestyle intervention Fasting Cpeptide ≥ 0.5 mg/mL (0.17 nmol/L) (to exclude those for whom hyperglycemic exposure is driven by βcell failure rather than dietary behaviors, as well as those requiring escalation of the medication regime) Ownership a smart phone and are willing to use it to monitor multiple factors influencing glycemic response to glycemia (e.g., sleep, physical activity, diet, stress, medication, and hunger) are unable or unwilling to provide informed consent; are unable to participate meaningfully in an intervention that involves selfmonitoring using software available in English (e.g., due to uncorrected sight impairment, illiterate, nonEnglishspeaking, dementia); are pregnant, are currently trying to become pregnant, or who become pregnant during the study are institutionalized (e.g., in a nursing home or personal care facility, or those who are incarcerated and have limited control over selfmanagement) have had or are planning to have bariatric surgery during the study have a history of heart disease, kidney disease, or retinopathy (to ruleout those with longstanding, undiagnosed T2D) those with an active infection requiring antibiotics in the last 3 months or who develop an active infection requiring antibiotics during the study; those who use acetaminophen and are unwilling or unable to discontinue its use during the study (acetaminophen affects CGM accuracy)39 immunosuppressive drugs within three months prior to participation and Chronically active inflammatory or neoplastic disease in the three years prior to enrollment. Patients with known food allergy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperglycemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Personal Nutrition Project</keyword>
</DOC>