<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03053921</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Aim of the study was to evaluate the clinical efficacy of placental membrane with coronally advanced flap in covering single and multiple Miller's class I and II gingival recession defects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Placental Membrane for Root Coverage</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>STUDY DESIGN A total number of 60 teeth in 15 subjects were selected. Patients with bilateral Miller's class I and II gingival recession defects in the maxillary or mandibular anterior and premolar region were selected and divided into two groups using a split mouth design. GroupI (Control) -30 recession defects treated with coronally advanced flap alone, using Zucchelli's technique. Group II (Test) - 30 recession defects treated with coronally advanced flap, using Zucchelli's technique along with placental membrane. CLINICAL PARAMETERS: 1. Probing Pocket Depth(PPD) 2. Clinical Attachment Level(CAL) 3. Height of Gingival Recession(HGR) 4. Width of Gingival Recession(WGR) 5. Width of Keratinized Gingiva(WKG) The clinical parameters were assessed &amp; recorded on 0 day, 90th day and 180th day</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Gingival Recession</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients within the age group 23 to 55 years 2. Bilateral, upper or lower, Miller's class I and Class II gingival recession defects confined to the anterior and premolar region. 3. Presence of identifiable cementoenamel junction 4. Presence of keratinized tissue apical to the exposed root 1. Systemic complications 2. Occlusal interferences 3. Any contraindication for periodontal surgery and taking medication which are known to interfere with periodontal tissue health or healing 4. Previous periodontal surgery on the involved site 5. Smokers 6. Pregnant and lactating mothers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>23 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>gingival recession</keyword>
	<keyword>Zuchellis technique,</keyword>
	<keyword>placental membrane</keyword>
</DOC>