<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="26502">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02761733</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CE-12-11-4309</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02761733</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effectiveness of a Decision-Support Tool for Adult Consumers With Mental Health Needs and Their Care Managers</brief_title>
  <official_title>Researching the Effectiveness of a Decision-Support Tool for Adult Consumers With Mental Health Needs and Their Care Managers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Felton Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of New Mexico</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Felton Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary goal of the proposed study is to investigate the implementation and
      effectiveness of the mPOWR (Moving Patient-centered Outcomes through Wellness and Recovery)
      in diverse urban and rural community mental health settings. The study compares patient
      participation and outcomes using the mPOWR system to a usual care control condition. Four
      community mental health agencies participate in the research: two in San Francisco (urban)
      and two in N.M. (rural). One site in each setting serves as the mPOWR implementation site
      and the other serves as the control site. Service sites were randomly assigned to
      intervention or usual care conditions. A quasi experimental design was used; only eligible
      participants were enrolled in the study (e.g., exclusion criteria of moderate to severe
      cognitive impairment, patient services structured for provision of mPOWR implementation,
      etc.). The study design will employ repeated quantitative measures to assess change in
      outcomes within and across conditions over time. Qualitative methods in the form of focus
      group interviews will also be used to round out the information obtained about patient and
      provider expectations and experiences. Primary outcomes of interest include: Short Form
      Health Survey-12 (SF-12; physical and mental health aspects of health and well-being);
      Outcome Rating Scale (ORS; general well-being, personal well-being, close relationships, and
      work/school/friend relationships); Shared Decision Making Questionnaire (congruence of
      patient's and provider's participation in therapeutic decision making and patient's
      understanding of treatment and treatment options); Working Alliance Inventory (perception of
      therapeutic alliance); and Satisfaction Questionnaire (communication patterns between
      physicians and their patients).
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Research on the impact of decision-support tools for providers and patients has not included
      frontline care managers within community mental health settings. In particular, the care
      management field lacks effective models for integrating results-based and patient-centered
      care into routine practice with diverse adults with complex mental health and social service
      needs. For over five years, Family Service Agency of San Francisco (FSA) developed and
      piloted a mental health decision-support tool entitled the Assessment Diagnostic Evaluation
      and Planning Tool (ADEPT) for use by patients and front-line providers. The ADEPT was
      developed by a team of researchers, frontline providers, and FSA patients to collect data
      and track patient progress over time. Yet, its strong focus on diagnostic screening and
      excessive length limited its relevance to patients in guiding service decisions. Over the
      past two years, a team of FSA patients and care managers revised the tool, eliminating its
      diagnostic component and retaining two measures of quality of life and community living
      skills that were reviewed and/or adapted by patients to reflect meaningful outcomes in the
      delivery of services. Decision aids and a communications toolkit were also developed to
      support the use of shared-decision making (SDM) processes in the provision of services.
      Together, these instruments and tools make up the Moving Patient Outcomes toward Wellness
      and Recovery (mPOWR) system. mPOWR ensures that the patient-provider relationship remains
      focused on patient identified outcomes and use of SDM throughout care. The primary goal of
      the study is to investigate the implementation and effectiveness of the mPOWR in diverse
      urban and rural community mental health settings.

      FSA has partnered with senior faculty from the University of New Mexico to serve as
      independent researchers for this study. The study involves four community mental health
      agencies: two in San Francisco (urban) and two in N.M. (rural). One (randomly chosen) site
      in each setting serves as the mPOWR implementation site and the other serves as the control
      site. The study population initially enrolled included 240 (60/site X 4 sites) diverse
      adults with chronic mental health conditions. The specific aims for this study are: (1) To
      improve patient and provider participation in shared-decision making and engagement in
      mental health treatment, to improve [patient] personal Quality of Life, and to improve
      [patient] access to community/social services; (2) To increase patient understanding of
      their treatment and of treatment options; to increase their personal treatment progress; (3)
      To increase patient functionality and sense of perceived support for their therapeutic
      outcomes.

      Primary outcomes of interest include: Short Form Health Survey-12 (SF-12; physical and
      mental health aspects of health and well-being); Outcome Rating Scale (ORS; general
      well-being, personal well-being, close relationships, and work/school/friend relationships);
      Shared Decision Making Questionnaire (congruence of patient's and provider's participation
      in therapeutic decision making and patient's understanding of treatment and treatment
      options); Working Alliance Inventory (perception of therapeutic alliance); and Satisfaction
      Questionnaire (communication patterns between physicians and their patients). Qualitative
      methods in the form of focus group interviews will also be used to round out the information
      obtained about patient and provider expectations and experiences. Data will be collected in
      a time series design.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Short Form Health Survey-12 (SF-12)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in scores on the SF-12 from Baseline to 24 month follow-up Description: The Health Survey Short Form-12 (SF-12) includes 12 items that assess for physical and mental aspects of health and well-being.</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Outcome Rating Scale (ORS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in scores on the Outcome Rating Scale from Baseline to 24 month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Outcome Rating Scale includes a visual analog scale that records four questions about general well-being, personal well-being, close relationships, and work/school/friend relationships. Analyses will examine treatment progress via change in ORS scores from pre- to post-intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Shared Decision Making Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in scores on the Shared Decision Making Questionnaire from Baseline to 24 month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Shared Decision Making Questionnaire includes 9 questions that assess for congruence of patient's and provider's participation in therapeutic decision making and patient's understanding of treatment and treatment options. Analyses will examine change in Shared Decision Making Questionnaire scores from pre- to post-intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Working Alliance Inventory</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in scores on the Working Alliance Inventory from Baseline to 24 month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Working Alliance Inventory includes 12 items administered to both the patient and provider that measure the perception of therapeutic alliance in a clinical dyad during the process of developing a relationship required for effective psychotherapy. Analyses will examine change in patient- and provider-reported Working Alliance Inventory scores from pre- to post-intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Satisfaction Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in scores on the Satisfaction Questionnaire from Baseline to 24 month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Satisfaction Questionnaire includes 19 questions that evaluate communication patterns between physicians and their patients. Analyses will examine change in Satisfaction Questionnaire scores from pre- to post-intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">240</enrollment>
  <condition>Mental Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>mPOWR System</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Moving Patient Outcomes toward Wellness and Recovery (mPOWR) consists of an assessment questionnaire and decision support tools which map onto 6 life domains which are measured by the questionnaire.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment as usual</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Moving Patient Outcomes toward Wellness and Recovery (mPOWR)</intervention_name>
    <description>An mPOWR intervention and toolkit that consists of strategies, prompts, and decision aids designed to foster patient involvement in treatment. The mPOWR intervention includes a questionnaire that assesses quality of life and consumer functioning for use in the development of consumer-centered goals and outcomes within the mPOWR intervention.</description>
    <arm_group_label>mPOWR System</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Men and women over the age of 18 who are receiving mental health services.

        Exclusion Criteria:

        Temporary Exclusion:

          -  Disruptive, aggressive, or severely disorganized behaviors;

          -  Visibly intoxicated or under the influence of illicit drugs.

        General Exclusion:

          -  Moderate to severe cognitive impairment;

          -  Developmental disability that precludes comprehension;

          -  Language issues: Intervention is only offered in English and Chinese;

          -  Patient services structured for provision of mPOWR implementation (e.g., not in and
             out of inpatient or crisis stabilization services).
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joyce Chu, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Felton Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <reference>
    <citation>Larson CO, Schlundt D, Patel K, Beard K, Hargreaves M. Validity of the SF-12 for use in a low-income African American community-based research initiative (REACH 2010). Prev Chronic Dis. 2008 Apr;5(2):A44. Epub 2008 Mar 15.</citation>
    <PMID>18341779</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ware J Jr, Kosinski M, Keller SD. A 12-Item Short-Form Health Survey: construction of scales and preliminary tests of reliability and validity. Med Care. 1996 Mar;34(3):220-33.</citation>
    <PMID>8628042</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Johnson JA, Coons SJ. Comparison of the EQ-5D and SF-12 in an adult US sample. Qual Life Res. 1998 Feb;7(2):155-66.</citation>
    <PMID>9523497</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Miller, S., et al., The Outcome Rating Scale: A Preliminary Study of the Reliability, Validity, and Feasibility of a Brief Visual Analog Measure. J Brief Therapy, 2003. 2(2): p. 91-100.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kriston L, Scholl I, Hölzel L, Simon D, Loh A, Härter M. The 9-item Shared Decision Making Questionnaire (SDM-Q-9). Development and psychometric properties in a primary care sample. Patient Educ Couns. 2010 Jul;80(1):94-9. doi: 10.1016/j.pec.2009.09.034. Epub 2009 Oct 30.</citation>
    <PMID>19879711</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hanson, W., K. Curry, and D. Bandalos, Reliability Generalization of Working Alliance Inventory Scale Scores. Educational and Psychological Measurement, 2002. 62(4): p. 659-673.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Horvath, A. and L. Greenberg, Development and validation of the Working Alliance Inventory. J Counseling Psychology, 1989. 36: p. 223-233.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Campbell C, Lockyer J, Laidlaw T, Macleod H. Assessment of a matched-pair instrument to examine doctor-patient communication skills in practising doctors. Med Educ. 2007 Feb;41(2):123-9.</citation>
    <PMID>17269944</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 3, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 20, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Shared Decision Making</keyword>
  <keyword>Case Management</keyword>
  <keyword>Decision Aid</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
