<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02403856</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Calcific tendinitis of the rotator cuff is a common cause of chronic pain of the shoulder. Needling and lavage of the calcification is one of the therapeutic options after failure of conservative management with physiotherapy and anti-inflammatory drugs. Needling is usually followed by a corticosteroid injection in the subacromial bursae in order to prevent acute pain reaction due to the intervention. However, the relevance of this injection has never been proven. Moreover, corticosteroid could prevent the inflammatory reaction induced by the needling and thus the body's natural calcium resorption processes. Finally, corticosteroids could have deleterious effect on the tendon structures and favour local infection. Our hypothesis is that corticosteroid have no significant effect on acute pain after needling and therefore should not been performed systematically after needling.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Tolerance of Ultrasound-guided Needling and Lavage of Calcific Tendinitis of the Rotator Cuff Performed With or Without Subacromial Corticosteroid Injection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Tendinopathy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Shoulder pain for at least 3 month Positive Hawkins, Yocum and/or Neer test for impingement Calcific deposit &gt;= 5 mm on shoulder xray in one the tendon of the rotator cuff Allergy to lidocaïne or methylprednisolone acetate Acute pain suggestive of resorption of the calcification with illdefined calcification on XRay Other shoulder diseases : ostearthritis of the glenohumeral or acromioclavicular joint Sonographic findings of rotator cuff tear Subacromial steroid injection in the previous month Uncontrolled diabetes Pregnant women Contraindication for the use of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs or paracetamol/acetaminophene</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>calcifying tendinitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Needle lavage</keyword>
	<keyword>Shoulder</keyword>
	<keyword>Corticosteroid injection</keyword>
	<keyword>Ultrasound-guided</keyword>
</DOC>