<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02403622</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overarching objective of this study is to address the knowledge gap regarding the short-term and long-term safety of fecal microbiota transplants (FMT). The design will be a prospective, open-label, multi-center longitudinal cohort study to assess the short- and long-term safety of FMT as well as the clinical resolution of diarrhea among 150 patients with 3 or more episodes of clostridium difficile infection (CDI defined as 3 unformed stools over 24 hours for 2 consecutive days and either a positive stool test for CDI or pseudomembranes on colonoscopy/sigmoidoscopy). Subjects will be adult outpatients referred to one of the study centers after at least three recurrent episodes of CDI and previous treatment with at least one 10-day course of oral vancomycin or fidaxomicin. After FMT by colonoscopy/sigmoidoscopy or enema, patients will be followed prospectively and monitored for clinical resolution and adverse events at: 3 days (telephone), 3 weeks (clinical assessment), 8 weeks (telephone), 6 months (telephone), and 12 months (telephone) after FMT. Subjects who recur will be offered a second FMT by colonoscopy with a different donor. Microbiome analysis will be conducted from stool samples at baseline and each of the 5 follow-up intervals.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety of FMT: OpenBiome Outcomes and Longitudinal Follow-up (STOOL) for Recurrent Clostridium Difficile Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Adult (at least 18 years of age) Outpatient Third or further documented CDI episode and Unable to maintain CDI cure after standard therapy with oral vancomycin or fidaxomicin Previous treatment with at least one course of tapered/pulse vancomycin or Inability to taper or stop vancomycin or fidaxomicin without developing diarrhea requiring antibiotic therapy. Improvement of CDI symptoms on vancomycin or fidaxomicin Unable to comply with study followup procedures or travel to clinical site for followup visits at discretion of MD Unable to provide informed consent at discretion of MD Participating in another clinical trial Pregnant or nursing currently or planned pregnancy in next 1 year Evidence of toxic megacolon or gastrointestinal perforation Peripheral white blood cell count &gt;30 x 109/L and/or temperature &gt;38 degrees Celsius Admission to an intensive care unit within prior 7 days for any reason Previously undergone FMT Severely immunocompromised patients o Documented history (self or physician identified) HIV infection with any cluster of differentiation 4 (CD4) count AIDSdefining diagnoses Inherited/primary immune disorder Immunosuppressant medications Neutropenia with absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt;0.5 x 109/L Active gastroenteritis due to infectious cause other than CDI Short gut syndrome Colostomy Ascites Endstage liver disease Untreated, insitu colorectal cancer Irritable bowel syndrome Inflammatory bowel disease including Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis Microscopic colitis including collagenous colitis and lymphocytic colitis Severe food allergy (anaphylaxis) that cannot be confirmed as having been excluded from a donor's diet within the five days prior to donation Anorectal disorder/severe rectal sphincter tone abnormality or inability to retain enema material Unable or unwilling to tolerate colonoscopy/sigmoidoscopy, colonoscopy prep, or enema for any reason at discretion of MD Severe underlying disease that the patient is not expected to survive for the subsequent 12 months at the discretion of the MD. Any conditions for which, in opinion of MD, the treatment may pose a health risk</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>