<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02403037</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the feasibility of a three-parallel-arm, placebo-controlled randomized trial using a standard auricular acupressure protocol for managing nausea and vomiting in a homogenous group of female breast cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy. The null hypotheses of this study are: (1) There will be no significant difference in the occurrence, frequency and severity of acute/delayed nausea and vomiting among groups during the intervention period; (2) There will be no significant difference in the occurrence, frequency and severity of anticipatory nausea and vomiting among groups before the second cycle of chemotherapy; (3) There will be no significant difference in quality of life status among groups at the end of the first cycle of chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Auricular Acupressure for Chemotherapy-Induced Nausea and Vomiting in Female Breast Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Chemotherapy-induced nausea and vomiting (CINV) is one of the most common and distressing side-effects among cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy. Despite steady progresses in antiemetic prophylaxis and treatment during the past decades, approximately half of cancer patients receiving moderately to highly emetogenic chemotherapy still experience significant nausea and vomiting. Considering the facts that CINV is difficult to be completely controlled by antiemetics along, healthcare professionals has explored the role of non-pharmacological interventions as adjunctive therapy for controlling CINV. Among which, auricular therapy (AT) is a promising approach but the evidence has still not been concluded. The aim of this study is to test the feasibility of a randomized controlled trial using auricular acupressure for managing nausea and vomiting in female breast cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy. The objectives of this study will be: (1) to pilot the methodological procedures of the randomized controlled trial using a standard auricular acupressure protocol for controlling CINV; (2) to determine the recruitment rate and the attrition rate during the whole study periods; (3) to examine the effects of auricular acupressure on the occurrence, frequency and severity of CINV as well as the QoL status in female breast cancer patients receiving chemotherapy; (4) to identify potential adverse events associated with auricular acupressure; (5) to explore patients' experiences and burdens on completing the trial and the reasons for study attrition; and (6) to refine the study protocol for a future multicenter, large-scale randomized controlled trial. A three-parallel-arm, placebo-controlled randomized pilot and feasibility study will be adopted. One hundred and fourteen breast cancer patients scheduled to receive the first cycle of chemotherapy will be recruited from three provincial hospitals in Fuzhou, China, and will be randomly assigned to one of the three groups: the true AT group, the sham AT group or the standard care group. Participants in the true AT group will receive standard anti-emetic medications plus a 5-day auricular acupressure at the specific ear acupoints, and participants in the sham AT group will receive standard anti-emetic medications plus a 5-day auricular acupressure at the same acupoints as in the true AT group but no pressure will be applied, while participants in the standard care group will only be provided with the standard anti-emetic medications. The feasibility outcomes will be the recruitment rate and consent rate during the recruitment stage, and the attrition rate during the study periods. The future main study outcomes will also be measured including the occurrence, frequency and severity of nausea and vomiting, quality of life (QoL) status and potential adverse events associated with AT. After completing the pilot clinical trial, a nested qualitative interview will be conducted to explore participants' experiences and burdens on completing the trial and the reasons for study attrition.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Nausea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antiemetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emetics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult female patients aged above 18 years old; A diagnosis of breast cancer stage IIII; Chemotherapy naive; Auricular therapynaive; Be able to communicate in Chinese mandarin; Had at least completed a primary school education; Agree to participate in the study and be willing to give written informed consent; Scheduled to receive the first cycle of anthracyclinebased chemotherapy with moderately high emetogenic potentials; Be provided with standard antiemetic medications during chemotherapy. Extremely weak, disabled or immunocompromised patients; Not cooperate with the study intervention and any other procedures; Have concurrent radiotherapy or other kinds of antineoplastic therapy; Currently participate in studies on antiemetic drugs or other kinds of nonpharmacological interventions to control CINV, or other studies which may have some interactions with the study; Have other health problems which may affect the symptoms of nausea and vomiting during chemotherapy including a series of gastrointestinal diseases, liver disease, migraine, tinnitus and Ménière's disease, etc.; Have a history of chronic alcohol use which could contribute to minimal level of nausea or vomiting; Ear skin problems which are not appropriate for auricular acupressure including infections, scars, rashes, frostbite, moles, ear abrasions or abscess, etc.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Auricular Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Acupressure</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Nausea</keyword>
	<keyword>Vomiting</keyword>
</DOC>