<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00528853</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A major source of graft failure and dysfunction in lung transplantation is known to be bronchiolitis obliterans (BO)and its clinical correlate called bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome(BOS). In fact, BOS is the leading cause of death in lung recipients beyond one year post transplant. Currently, our ability to assess lung injury after transplant is less than ideal. The purpose of this study is to use new computerized tomography(CT) technology, specifically , 64 bit acquisition, to detect and predict the onset of lung injuries, with the hope of finding better therapies that currently exist.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Correlation of Lung Biopsy, BAL, and High Resolution CT Scan in Lung Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Total enrollment : 10 Lung transplant patients will undergo CT Scans before scheduled bronchoscopies which are routinely performed at 1, 3, 6, 9, and 12 months post transplant. Imaging will be done with the newest generation scanner, with intent to analyze all pertinent areas of the lung for pathology, but especially the bronchial anastomoses, the lung parenchyma with focus on gas exchanging lobules of the lung, and any suspected abnormalities from physical exam, laboratory tests, or prior chest xray. CT imaging will precede bronchoscopy and biopsy so that CT interpretation will be unencumbered by changes due to the bronchoscopic procedure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Bronchiolitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bronchiolitis Obliterans</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Lung transplant patients who are at least 18 years of age. All patients must be able to give written informed consent. Lung transplant patients who are unable to undergo a CT Scan. Lung transplant patients who are unable to give informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bronchiolitis Obliterans Syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>