<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00079976</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the safety and efficacy of tigecycline in the treatment of selected serious infections caused by VRE. The primary efficacy endpoint will be the clinical response for all subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Evaluating Tigecycline in Selected Serious Infections Caused by Vancomycin-Resistant Enterococcus (VRE) or Methicillin-Resistant Staphylococcus Aureus (MRSA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bacterial Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Staphylococcal Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gram-Positive Bacterial Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vancomycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methicillin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tigecycline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Minocycline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subjects aged 18 years or older Isolation of one of the following multiantibiotic resistant bacteria: vancomycinresistant Enterococcus faecium, vancomycinresistant Enterococcus faecalis, or methicillinresistant Staphylococcus aureus, alone or as part of a polymicrobial infection Have a confirmed diagnosis of a serious infection (eg, bacteremia [unless due to an excluded infection], complicated intraabdominal infection, complicated skin and skin structure infection, or pneumonia) requiring administration of intravenous (IV) antibiotic therapy Subjects with any concomitant condition or taking any concomitant medication that, in the opinion of the investigator, could preclude an evaluation of a response or make it unlikely that the contemplated course of therapy or followup assessment will be completed or that will substantially increase the risk associated with the subject's participation in this study Anticipated length of antibiotic therapy less than 7 days For subjects with VRE, known or suspected hypersensitivity to tigecycline or linezolid, or other compounds related to these classes of antibacterial agents (eg, oxazolidinones, tetracyclines, minocycline, doxycycline). For subjects with MRSA, known or suspected hypersensitivity to tigecycline or vancomycin, or other compounds related to these classes of antibacterial agents (eg, tetracyclines, minocycline, doxycycline)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Staphylococcus aureus</keyword>
	<keyword>Bacterial Infections</keyword>
</DOC>