<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00979602</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to characterize the safety, immunogenicity, and relative efficacy of the H1N1 (swine) flu vaccines GSK2340273A and GSK2340274A in adults 18 years of age or older.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Immunogenicity, and Relative Efficacy of H1N1 Vaccines in Adults Aged 18 Years and Older</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Collaborators: United States Department of Health and Human Services, Office of Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who the investigator believes can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol. Written informed consent obtained from the subject. Male and female adults, &gt;= 18 years of age at the time of the first vaccination. Satisfactory baseline medical assessment by history and physical examination. Safety laboratory test results within the parameters specified in the protocol. Comprehension of the study requirements, ability to comprehend and comply with procedures for collection of safety data, expressed availability for the required study period, and ability and willingness to attend scheduled visits as demonstrated by signature on the informed consent document. Access to a consistent means of telephone contact, which may be either in the home or at the workplace, land line, or mobile, but NOT a pay phone or other multipleuser device. Female subjects of nonchildbearing potential may be enrolled in the study. Female subjects of childbearing potential may be enrolled in the study, if the subject: has practiced adequate contraception for 30 days prior to vaccination; and has a negative pregnancy test on the day of first vaccination; and has agreed to continue adequate contraception during the entire treatment period and for 2 months after completion of the vaccination series. Medical history of physicianconfirmed infection with an A/California/7/2009 (H1N1)vlike virus. Previous vaccination at any time with an A/California/7/2009 (H1N1)vlike virus vaccine. With the exception of seasonal influenza vaccination, administration of any vaccine(s) within 30 days before study vaccination on Day 0. Seasonal influenza vaccine may be administered up to 14 days prior to study vaccination on Day 0. Planned administration of any vaccine other than the study vaccines between Day 0 and the phlebotomy 21 days after vaccination. Planned administration of any monovalent pandemic (H1N1)vlike vaccine other than the study vaccines during the whole study (Day 0 Day 385). Previous vaccination with an H1N1vlike virus vaccine or a medical history of physicianconfirmed infection with an H1N1vlike virus. Presence of evidence of substance abuse or of neurological or psychiatric diagnoses which, although stable, are deemed by the investigator to render the potential subject unable/unlikely to provide accurate safety reports. Presence of a temperature &gt;= 38.0ºC (&gt;= 100.4 ºF), oral temperature assessment preferred, or acute symptoms greater than "mild" severity on the scheduled date of first vaccination. Diagnosed with cancer, or treatment for cancer, within 3 years. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition, based on medical history and physical examination. Receipt of systemic glucocorticoids within 1month prior to study enrollment, or any other cytotoxic or immunosuppressive drug within 6 months of study enrollment. Topical, intraarticularly injected, or inhaled glucocorticoids, topical calcineurin inhibitors, or imiquimod are allowed. Receipt of any immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within 3 months of study enrollment or planned administration of any of these products during the study period. Any significant disorder of coagulation or treatment with warfarin derivatives or heparin. Persons receiving individual doses of low molecular weight heparin are eligible if no such doses are given in the 24 hours before a study vaccination. Persons receiving prophylactic antiplatelet medications, e.g., lowdose acetylsalicylic acid, and without a clinicallyapparent bleeding tendency, are eligible. History of an acute evolving neurological disorder or history of GuillainBarré syndrome within 6 weeks of receipt of seasonal influenza vaccine. With the exception of seasonal influenza vaccination, administration of any vaccines within 30 days before study vaccination on Day 0. Seasonal influenza vaccine may be administered up to 14 days prior to study vaccination on Day 0. Planned administration of any vaccine other than the study vaccine between Day 0 and the phlebotomy 21 days after the second study vaccine dose. Use of any investigational or nonregistered product within 30 days preceding the first dose of study vaccine, or planned use during the study period. Any known or suspected allergy to any constituent of influenza vaccines; a history of anaphylactictype reaction to any constituent of influenza vaccines; or a history of severe adverse reaction to a previous influenza vaccine. Known pregnancy or a positive urine betahuman chorionic gonadotropin test result prior to vaccination. Lactating or nursing women.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>GSK Bio's influenza vaccine GSK2340274A</keyword>
	<keyword>Influenza Vaccines</keyword>
	<keyword>GSK Bio's influenza vaccine GSK2340273A</keyword>
	<keyword>influenza infection</keyword>
</DOC>