<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00864097</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the analgesic efficacy and safety of tanezumab added on to diclofenac SR in patients with osteoarthritis of the knee or hip currently experiencing partial benefit from, and are tolerating, diclofenac 150 mg/day therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Analgesic Efficacy And Safety of Tanezumab Added On To Diclofenac SR In Patients With Osteoarthritis Of The Knee Or Hip</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study was terminated on 16 Nov 2010 following a US FDA clinical hold for tanezumab osteoarthritis clinical studies which halted dosing and enrollment of patients on 23 June 2010 for potential safety issues.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diclofenac</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Analgesics</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Osteoarthritis of the knee or hip according to ACR criteria with KellgrenLawrence Xray grade equal to, or greater than, 2. Patients must be experiencing some benefit from their current stable dose regimen of oral diclofenac 150 mg/day and be tolerating their diclofenac regimen. Pain and function levels as required by the protocol at Screening and Baseline. Willing to discontinue all nonstudy pain medications throughout the study except as permitted per protocol. Willing and able to comply with lifestyle guidelines, scheduled visits, treatment plan, laboratory tests and other study procedures. Pregnant women. BMI greater than 39. History of other disease that may involve index knee or hip including inflammatory joint diseases, chrystalline disease (gout or pseudogout), endocrinopathies, metabolic joint diseases, lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis (RA), joint infections, neuropathic disorders, avascular necrosis, Paget's disease or tumors. Fibromyalgia, regional pain caused by lumbar or cervical compression with radiculopathy or other moderate to severe pain that may confound assessments or selfevaluation of the pain associated with OA. Signs and symptoms of clinically significant cardiac disease within 6 months prior to screening. Diagnosis or TIA within 6 months prior to screening or diagnosis of stroke with residual deficits that would preclude completion of required study activities. History, diagnosis , signs or symptoms of clinically significant neurological and/or psychiatric disease/disorder. At Screening: uncontrolled hypertension, hemoglobin A1c greater than or equal to 10%, ALT or AST greater than or equal to 3X upper limit of normal, creatinine exceeding 150 micromol/L in men or 133 micromol/L in women. Patients on warfarin or other coumadin anticoagulant therapy and/or lithium therapy within 30 days prior to Screening. Known hypersensitivity to NSAIDs (eg, diclofenac), cyclooxygenase inhibitors or paracetamol (acetaminophen).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Arthritis monoclonal antibody nerve growth factor (NGF) anti-NGF tanezumab PF-04383119 RN-624 OA</keyword>
</DOC>