<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00864240</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To determine the dose-response relationship for Clobex TM (clobetasol propionate) Lotion, 0.05%. This information will be used to estimate the ED50, D1, D2 parameters for use in a full bioequivalence study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Dose-response "Pilot" Study of Topically Delivered Clobetasol Propionate Lotion in Healthy Adult Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Type: Interventional Study Design: Randomized, open label, one period, dose response, vasoconstrictor assay study. Official Title: Dose Response of Clobex 0.05% Lotion Further study details as provided by Actavis Elizabeth LLC: Primary Outcome Measures: · Vasoconstrictor Response</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Clobetasol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Nontobaccousing female subjects, 18 to 50 years of age, inclusive. A demonstrated blanching response to Clobex TM (clobetasol propionate) Lotion, 0.05 %. A body mass index (BMI) 30 kg/m2 or less as calculated according to Novum Standard Operating Procedures. Good health as determined by lack of clinically significant abnormalities in medical history and clinical assessment, as judged by the Investigator. Signed and dated informed consent form which meets all criteria of current FDA regulations. History of allergy to any systemic or topical corticosteroid (including clobetasol) or to any cream, lotion, ointment, gel, cotton, soap, cosmetic, rubber, or tape, which in the opinion of the Investigator would compromise the safety of the subject or the study. Presence of any skin condition or coloration that would interfere with placement of test sites or the response or assessment of skin blanching. Significant history or current evidence of chronic infectious disease, system disorder (especially hypertension or circulatory disease), or organ dysfunction. Presence of a medical condition requiring regular treatment with prescription drugs. Drug or alcohol addiction requiring treatment (inpatient or outpatient) in the 12 months prior to dosing. Use of any topical dermatological drug therapy (including topical corticosteroids) on the flexor surface of the ventral forearms in the 30 days prior to dosing. Use of any tobacco products in the 30 days prior to dosing. Receipt of any drug as part of a research study within 30 days prior to initial study dosing. Pregnant or lactating.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vasoconstriction</keyword>
	<keyword>Clobetasol</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy adult females</keyword>
</DOC>