<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02550106</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluate the proportion of patients with an urticaria control test [UCT] score of greater than or equal to 12 at Week 12.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Omalizumab in Chronic Spontaneous Urticaria Patients Non Responding to Initial Standard antihistaminE Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Urticaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Omalizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Histamine Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Histamine H1 Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patients aged between 18 and 75 years. Diagnosis of CSU for ≥ 6 months and an inadequate response to nsH1 antihistamines at the time of the request, as defined by the following: The presence of itch and hives for &gt; 6 consecutive weeks at any time prior to enrollment, despite current use of H1 antihistamine therapy during this time period. Weekly UAS7 score (range 0 to 42) 16 and UCT score (range 0 to 16) &lt; 8 prior to enrollment (Day 1) Current use of an H1 antihistamine for CSU on the day of the initial visit and Day Informed consent Treatment with an investigational agent within 30 days before enrollment. Routine (daily or every other day during 5 or more consecutive days) doses of the following medications within 30 days prior to Day 7: systemic or cutaneous (topical) corticosteroids (prescription or over the counter), hydroxychloroquine, methotrexate, cyclosporine, or cyclophosphamide. Intravenous (i.v.) immunoglobulin G or plasmapheresis within 30 days prior to Day 7 Regular (daily/every other day) doxepin (oral) use within 14 days prior to Day 7. Any H2 antihistamine use within 7 days prior to Day 7. Any leukotriene receptor antagonist (LTRA) (montelukast or zafirlukast) within 7 days prior to Day 7. Concomitant use of cyclosporine or any other immunosuppressive agent. Hypersensitivity to omalizumab or any component of the formulation. History of anaphylactic shock.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>CHRONIC SPONTANEOUS URTICARIA, OMALIZUMAB, URTICARIA CONTROL TEST</keyword>
</DOC>