<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02550015</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to examine if high intensity interval training after stroke is more effective than standard care to increase maximal oxygen uptake, reduce known risk factors for recurrent stroke and improve function.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>High Intensity Interval Training After Stroke</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Stroke is a leading cause of adult disability. Well designed studies have shown that the majority of the stroke population have low aerobic capacity and many are inactive. This is negative for their health and well-being. Physical inactivity may increase their risk of having recurrent stroke. The optimal training mode and intensity to improve aerobic capacity after stroke are not clear. High intensity interval training (ie. 90-95% of peak heart rate) has been proven to be more beneficial than moderate and low intensity exercise in order to improve maximal oxygen uptake in patients with cardiac disease. The response from this training on aerobic capacity and physical function in the stroke population are not known.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Approved informed consent Independent walking &gt; 2 minutes First episode of stroke (ischemic or hemorrhagic) Minimum 3 months poststroke Living in the community and able to travel to assessment and training site Approval to participate from the study's responsible medical doctor Modified Rankin Scale 03 Impaired cognitive function to give valid informed consent to participate Instability of cardiac conditions (ie. serious rhythm disorder, valve malfunction) Other conditions where test of maximal oxygen uptake is contraindicated Poorly controlled hypertension (&gt;180/100), measured at rest &gt; 5 years post stroke Subarachnoid hemorrhage Participating in other ongoing intervention study Other serious illness influencing testing of cardiorespiratory fitness and function at 1 year followup</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Exercise training</keyword>
	<keyword>Oxygen consumption</keyword>
</DOC>