<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00947427</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Canakinumab is a fully human anti-interleukin-1β (anti-IL-1β) monoclonal antibody (IgG-1 class). Canakinumab is designed to bind to human IL-1β and to functionally neutralize the bioactivity of this pro-inflammatory cytokine. The study is a two-arm, multicenter, randomized, double-masked, placebo-controlled clinical trial. 66 subjects will be randomly assigned to receive either monthly subcutaneous injections of 2.0 mg/kg Canakinumab, or placebo for 12 months. All groups will receive standard intensive diabetes treatment with insulin and dietary management. Participants randomly assigned to Canakinumab treatment or placebo will receive a total of 12 injections over one year. All subjects will be followed for 1 year of treatment plus 1- 3 years of additional follow-up until study end. Enrollment is expected to occur over two years.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Canakinumab Study in Individuals With Newly Diagnosed Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Between the ages of 645 years Be within 3months (100 days) of diagnosis of type 1 diabetes Must have at least one diabetesrelated autoantibody present Must have stimulated Cpeptide levels &gt;0.2 pmol/ml measured during a mixed meal tolerance test (MMTT) conducted at least 21 days from diagnosis and within 37 days of randomization If participant is female with reproductive potential, she must be willing to avoid pregnancy and have a negative pregnancy test during the 12 months of treatment and for an additional 3 months after completing treatment Be at least one month from time of last live immunization received Willing to forgo live vaccinations for 24 months Must be willing to comply with intensive diabetes management Must weigh at least 20 kg (44 lbs) at study entry Are immunodeficient or have clinically significant chronic lymphopenia (low white blood cell count) Have an active infection Have a positive PPD test result Be currently pregnant or lactating, or anticipate getting pregnant Ongoing use of medications known to influence glucose tolerance Require use of other immunosuppressive agents Have serologic evidence of current or past HIV, Hepatitis B, or Hepatitis C infection Have any complicating medical issues or abnormal clinical laboratory blood counts or results that interfere with study conduct; history of malignancies Be currently participating in another type 1 diabetes treatment study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>type 1 diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>newly diagnosed T1D</keyword>
	<keyword>T1D</keyword>
	<keyword>canakinumab</keyword>
	<keyword>anti IL-1</keyword>
</DOC>