<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00947635</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose is to investigate possible mechanisms of increased blood lipid levels following transplantation, and also to see if a comprehensive dietary intervention is effective in reducing blood lipid levels in post-transplant patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cholesterol and Fatty Acid Synthesis in Islet and Liver Transplant Patients and Effect of Dietary Intervention</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Post-transplantation patients frequently have an increase in blood lipid levels presumed to be due to immunosuppressive agents, however it is currently unknown the mechanisms by which this occurs. Dietary interventions have frequently been unsuccessful in these patients, which may be due to single-nutrient interventions and lack of support and guidance. This research will use stable isotope methods to estimate cholesterol and fatty acid synthesis to determine if these pathways are affected by immunosuppression in patients before and after islet and liver transplant. In addition, it will be determined if a multi-nutrient dietary intervention will be implemented post-transplant can reduce blood lipid levels in to prevent further polypharmacy these patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperlipidemias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>on islet or liver transplant list posttransplant &gt;3 months physically able to participate in study and intervention &lt; 18 years of age family history of premature cardiovascular disease or familial hyperlipidemia (control subjects) cholestatic diseases (liver transplant patients) type 2 diabetes</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 1 diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Transplants</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunosuppression</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperlipidemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Nutrition Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>