<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01966133</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Investigators hypothesise that the use of transarterial chemoembolisation (TACE) after liver resection in patients with hepatocellular carcinoma can eradicate residual cancer cells in the liver and thus improve survival of patients with high risk factors for residual tumor. The aim of this study is to compare the survival of patients with high risk factors for residual tumor undergoing liver resection plus post-operative TACE versus liver resection alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TACE as an Adjuvant Therapy After Hepatectomy for HCC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Liver resection is the mainstay of curative treatment for hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). However, recurrence is common after surgery and most occurs in the liver, especially for the patients with high risk factors for residual tumor, such as tumors with a diameter more than 5 cm, multiple nodules, and microvascular invasion. Transarterial chemoembolisation (TACE) is an effective palliative treatment for HCC. It involves the infusion of chemotherapeutic agent admixed with iodised oil followed by embolisation of the hepatic arterial flow using small particles. This procedures allows application of smaller dose of chemotherapy concentrated to the liver and thus is well tolerated with minimal side effects. The main complications of TACE are liver function damage, mild feverish symptoms, vomit , etc. But most of them are reversible. We conduct a randomised controlled trial evaluating the efficacy of using TACE after hepatectomy in HCC patients with high risk factors for residual tumor (tumors with a diameter more than 5 cm, multiple nodules, or microvascular invasion).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethiodized Oil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HCC patients received curative hepatectomy with negative resection margin Tumors with a diameter more than 5 cm, multiple nodules, or microvascular invasion were defined as high risk factors for residual tumor and used for patient stratification. Age from 18 to 70 ChildPugh class A ASA class I to III ECOG performance status Grade 0 or 1 Patients receiving concomitant local ablation or previous TACE Main portal vein tumour thrombus extraction during hepatectomy Tumour arising from caudate lobe Presence of extrahepatic disease Impaired liver function with either clinically detected ascites, hepatic encephalopathy, serum albumin &lt; 25g/L or bilirubin &gt; 50micromol/L Renal impairment with creatinine &gt; 200micromol/L Severe concurrent medical illness persisting &gt; 6 weeks after hepatectomy History of other cancer Hepatic artery anomaly making TACE not possible Allergy to doxorubicin or lipiodol Pregnant woman Informed consent not available</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>HCC</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomised controlled trial</keyword>
	<keyword>TACE</keyword>
	<keyword>Resection</keyword>
</DOC>