<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01361100</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicentric feasibility study aimed to evaluate the Oncoral® test. The study includes 2 steps. The first one aims to validate the algorithm defined at the time when the test was developed in patients with different tumour stages. Patients will be enrolled before any treatment. They will immediately undergo the test. No follow-up will be realized. In total, 100 patients will be included in this first step. The estimated period of inclusion is 6 months. If the algorithm is validated, the second step of the study will start. The purpose is to determine the characteristics of the test. Enrollment will concern smokers and alcohol drinkers at high risk of developing an epidermoid carcinoma of the upper aerodigestive tract. Patient follow-up will vary with both the result of the test and the biopsy, up to a maximum of one year. In total, 385 patients will be enrolled in this step during an estimated period of 18 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Oncoral® Test in Epidermoid Carcinomas of the Upper Aerodigestive Tract</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>First step: Man or woman aged more than 40 years With frequent alcohol intoxication and/or smoking With histologically confirmed epidermoid carcinoma of the upper aerodigestive tract No treatment delivered for this disease Signed, written informed consent Mandatory affiliation with a health insurance system Second step: Man or woman aged more than 40 years With frequent alcohol intoxication and/or smoking With no sign of an epidermoid carcinoma of the upper aerodigestive tract Signed, written informed consent Mandatory affiliation with a health insurance system First step: Previous history of cancer except carcinoma in situ of the uterine cervix or skin basal cell carcinoma treated with curative intent Gingivorrhagia when the test is realised Hypersensitivity to aspirin or to benzoate Asthmatic, diabetic patients or patents with chronic bronchitis requiring oxygen therapy Patients taking antibiotics at enrolment or during the previous week Second step: Previous history of cancer except carcinoma in situ of the uterine cervix or skin basal cell carcinoma treated with curative intent Patient already treated for a cancer Gingivorrhagia when the test is realised Hypersensitivity to aspirin or to benzoate Asthmatic, diabetic patients or patients with chronic bronchitis requiring oxygen therapy Patients on antibiotics at enrolment or during the previous week</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Otolaryngology</keyword>
</DOC>