<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01361035</DOC>
	<brief_summary>What's the purpose of this study? This 4-year study is designed: (1) to teach primary care physicians how to recognize low health literacy patients and effectively counsel them on cancer screening using risk communication and shared decision making and (2) to assess the impact of training on changes in physician communication behavior and changes in low health literacy patients' cancer screening behaviors. This study proposal is based on the hypothesis that physician training in cancer screening guidelines, health literacy, and communication skills will improve provider-patient interactions during encounters dealing with preventive health maintenance especially cancer screening. How will the proposed study be implemented? Thirty-two physicians in the New Orleans metropolitan area will be recruited and randomly assigned to one of two groups. The unit of randomization will be the health care organization or clinic. The intervention group will receive training in health literacy, cancer screening, risk communication and shared decision-making. The control group will not receive communication training until the end of the study. Physicians in both groups will undergo three clinic visits with standardized patients (actors trained to portray real patients; mystery shoppers) but they will not be aware that they are conducting visits with actors. The visits will occur at study enrollment and at 6 and 12 months. At the end of each clinic visit, the standardized patients will rate the physicians' communication skills. Each physician assigned to the intervention group will receive verbal feedback on communication skills from the standardized patients and complete a web-based tutorial. Physicians in the control group will not have access to the web-based tutorial until the end of the study. For each physician, 10-15 patients with limited health literacy will be recruited to the study. Each patient will rate his/her perceived involvement with care and global satisfaction with care at study enrollment and annually for three years. Age and gender-appropriate referral rates for breast, cervical and colorectal cancer screening and patients' receipt of such screening will be assessed annually for three years. All study physicians, regardless of group assignment, will receive performance feedback (report cards) on their cancer screening rates among low health literacy patients in their clinic.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Using Effective Provider-Patient Communication to Improve Cancer Screening Among Low Literacy Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Physician Physicians who practice at these clinic sites at least one half day per week are eligible to participate in this study. Patient Eligible patients include men and women age 40 to 75, individuals enrolled in the clinic practice for at least one year, and individuals identified as having low or inadequate health literacy via the Rapid Estimate of Adult Literacy in Medicine. Physician Any provider planning to leave before the end of 12 months will be excluded. Patient Patients will be excluded if they plan to change primary care provider or site of health plan, have resided in the United States for less than five years, or do not speak English</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>health literacy</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer screening</keyword>
	<keyword>doctor-patient communication</keyword>
	<keyword>standardized patient</keyword>
	<keyword>continuing medical education</keyword>
</DOC>