<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01058213</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a 16 week exercise training program for people with severe to very severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). The purpose of this study is to find out if performing strength training prior to initiating exercise training on a stationary bicycle is associated with greater gains in functional status than bicycle training alone or concurrent bicycle and strength training together.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nurse Managed Sequential Strength Training and Bicycle Training in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Volunteers are randomly assigned to one of three groups: 1). 8 weeks of resistance (strength) training followed by 8 weeks of bicycle exercise training, 2). 8 weeks of chair exercise followed by 8 weeks of resistance (strength) training and bicycle exercise training, or 3). 8 weeks of chair exercise followed by 8 weeks of bicycle exercise training. The length of the training is 16 weeks for all 3 groups. Volunteers train 3 days per week in our lab located in the Chicagoland area and are supervised by an exercise specialist.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>FEV1/FVC &lt; 70 and FEV1 &lt; 55%, &gt; 45 years of age, experience dyspnea with exertion, stable clinical condition (Stable clinical condition is defined as free of respiratory tract infections for at least two months prior to enrollment, no recent change in the color, consistency, or quantity of sputum, afebrile and no recent change in medical therapy.) evidence of restrictive lung disease or asthma, acute respiratory infection, taking oral corticosteroids on a regular basis, &gt;3 exacerbations in the previous year, currently participating in pulmonary rehabilitation, the presence of a potentially debilitating disease or the presence of a condition that would make it potentially unsafe to exercise. We will adhere to the American College of Sports Medicine guidelines and exclude those who do not meet their guidelines for exercise testing and training. Pregnant women or women who plan to become pregnant during the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>46 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulmonary rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Resistance Training</keyword>
	<keyword>Aerobic Training</keyword>
	<keyword>Dyspnea</keyword>
</DOC>