<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02726542</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Fatty liver disease is an increasing problem in overweight and obese adolescents. The purpose of this study is to test the effect of growth hormone on liver fat in obese adolescents with increased liver fat.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Augmenting Growth Hormone to Ameliorate Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease in Adolescents</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is a significant health problem in obese adolescents. Obese children and adolescents have significant reductions in growth hormone secretion, and we hypothesize that augmenting growth hormone in this population will decrease liver fat. Growth hormone inhibits hepatic de novo lipogenesis, which is an important source of hepatic lipid. Patients with pituitary GH deficiency have a higher prevalence of NAFLD and non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH) than the general population, and replacement of GH in these individuals reduces signs of liver damage. The purpose of this study is to test the hypothesis that growth hormone treatment will decrease liver fat quantity in adolescents who begin the trial with more than 5% liver fat measured by magnetic resonance spectroscopy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hormones</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 1. Males and Females ages 1825yo 2. BMI ≥95th percentile and/or ≥30kg/m^2 3. Hepatic fat ≥5% by hydrogen magnetic resonance spectroscopy (1HMRS) 4. IGF1 standard deviation score (SDS) ≤ 0.5 Exclusion criteria: 1. Alcohol consumption of &gt;14 drinks per week (Females) or &gt;21 drinks per week (Males) 2. Use of insulin or oral antidiabetic medications, or hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) &gt;7% or fasting glucose ≥126mg/dL 3. Use of corticosteroid, gonadal steroids, or methotrexate ≤ 3 months prior to baseline visit 4. Known diagnosis of alpha1 antitrypsin deficiency, Wilson's disease, hemochromatosis, or autoimmune hepatitis 5. hemoglobin &lt; 11.0 g/dL or weight &lt; 50kg 6. aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt;2.5x upper limit of normal (ULN), total bilirubin &gt; ULN, positive hepatitis B surface antigen (sAg), or positive hepatitis C antibody 7. Routine magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) exclusion criteria (including weight &gt;450 pounds) 8. Use of weightloss medications or previous weight loss surgery 9. Pregnant or breastfeeding, or, for sexuallyactive females, unwillingness to use an appropriate form of contraception during the study 10. Known cirrhosis or clinical evidence of cirrhosis or portal hypertension on imaging or exam 11. Use of growth hormone (GH) or growth hormone releasing hormone within the past 1 year 12. Change in lipid lowering or antihypertensive medications within 3 months of screening 13. Change in vitamin E or ursodiol &lt;6 months before screen; subjects on stable doses of Vitamin E and/or Ursodiol for ≥6 months will be eligible. 14. History of malignancy or active malignancy 15. History of hypopituitarism, head irradiation or any other condition or chronic illness known to affect the GH axis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>adolescence</keyword>
	<keyword>fatty liver</keyword>
	<keyword>growth hormone</keyword>
</DOC>