<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="142990">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01239381</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10-139</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>Other</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01239381</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Individualized Stereotactic Body Radiotherapy of Liver Metastases</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Study of Individualized Stereotactic Body Radiotherapy of Liver Metastases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Brigham and Women's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Stereotactic body radiation therapy (SBRT) is a technique that is used to deliver radiation,
      to sites in the body. All participants in this study will be treated with SBRT using proton
      beam radiation. Proton beam radiation uses tiny particles to deliver radiation to tumors.
      The purpose of this research study is to determine if SBRT with protons will prevent tumor
      growth and reduce the treatment side effects for liver metastases.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      -  Participants receiving SBRT with protons, will receive radiation treatment as an
           outpatient at the Francis H. Burr Proton Therapy Center at Massachusetts General
           Hospital.

        -  Not everyone who participates in this study will be receiving the same dose of
           radiation. The dose received will be determined by the size and location of the
           tumor(s).

        -  Participants will receive 2-3 SBRT treatments per week for two weeks.

        -  During radiation therapy visits the following tests/procedures will be performed: vital
           signs, physical examination, routine blood tests, research blood tests, and radiation
           planning.

        -  Follow-up assessments will be performed once at 9 weeks after study treatment, then at
           6 months, 12 months, 18 months and 24 months after treatment.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Local Control Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To demonstrate a 1 year local control rate of greater than 70%</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Toxicity rate</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the frequency and severity of treatment related toxicities of this treatment program</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dosimetric differences</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the dosimetric differences (prescription dose selected and non-target liver dose) between patients treated with photons and protons.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>2-year Local Control Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the 2-year local control rate of this treatment program</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Liver Metastases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SBRT-Proton</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>SBRT by proton radiation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Stereotactic body radiotherapy-proton</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose will be determined by the size and location of the tumor(s); 2-3 treatments per week for two weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>SBRT-Proton</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Biopsy-proven cancer diagnosis of a solid tumor with 1-4 liver metastases. There is
             no upper size limit. Liver metastases may be diagnosed by imaging alone, no liver
             biopsy is required. Extrahepatic disease is allowed if it have been stable for 3
             months prior to study entry, the dominant disease burden is intrahepatic and the
             patient is referred for definitive radiation therapy to the disease in the liver

          -  Measurable disease, defined as at least one lesion that can be accurately measured in
             at least one dimension as 10mm or greater with spiral CT scan

          -  Patients may have had prior chemotherapy, targeted biological therapy, surgery,
             transarterial chemoembolization (TACE), radiofrequency ablation, or cryosurgery for
             their disease as long as the prior therapy occured greater than 3 weeks elapsed
             before the first radiation treatment. Patients may not have had prior liver directed
             radiation, including radioembolization.

          -  18 years of age or older

          -  Expected survival must be greater than three months

          -  ECOG performance status of 0, 1 or 2

          -  Patients must have at least 800mL of uninvolved liver

          -  Normal organ and marrow function as outlined in the protocol

          -  If patient has underlying cirrhosis, only Child-Pugh classification Group A patients
             should be included in this study. Clinical assessment of ascites and encephalopathy
             is required. Child-Pugh classification must be determined for all study participants
             at the time of eligibility analysis.

          -  Women of child-bearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception
             prior to study entry and for the duration of study participation

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Women who are pregnant or lactating

          -  Patients with gross ascites or encephalopathy

          -  Local conditions or systemic illnesses which would reduce the local tolerance to
             radiation treatment, such as serious local injuries, active collagen vascular
             disease, etc.

          -  Prior liver directed radiation treatment, including selective internal radiation

          -  No serious medical illness, which may limit survival to less than 3 months

          -  No serious psychiatric illness which would limit compliance with treatment

          -  Participants who have had chemotherapy or radiotherapy within 3 weeks prior to
             starting study treatment or those who have not recovered from adverse events due to
             agents administered more than 3 weeks earlier

          -  Participants may not be receiving any other investigational agents, or any other
             anti-cancer therapy during treatment

          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac
             arrhythmia.

          -  Only solid tumors are permitted. Thus, individuals with a liver mass from a diagnosis
             of lymphoma or leukemia are excluded
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Theodore S. Hong, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber Cancer Institue</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>December 15, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>June 14, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Theodore Sunki Hong</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Attending Radiation Oncologist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>proton radiation</keyword>
  <keyword>stereotactic body radiotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>SBRT</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
