<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00026858</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Most bone marrow transplantations for malignant and non-malignant disease include whole body irradiation. Techniques for administering that treatment, including patient positioning, lung and soft tissue compensation, dose rate, total dose and fractionation differ between institutions. These differences are optimized at each institution to limit toxicity and maximize therapeutic outcome. Technically complex procedures such as total body radiation are subject to equipment failures. Such failures mid-treatment could be catastrophic to the patient, since therapy must be timely and compatible therapy may not be available elsewhere in the community. The purpose of this protocol is to provide backup between George Washington University Medical Center and the Radiation Oncology Branch of the NCI to allow for orderly, safe, and compatible therapies in the event of equipment failure; or replacement of a linear accelerator or any other malfunctioning equipment necessary to deliver TBI; or any emergent situation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Total Body Irradiation for Bone Marrow Transplants: Collaborative Efforts</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Most bone marrow transplantations for malignant and non-malignant disease include whole body irradiation. Techniques for administering that treatment, including patient positioning, lung and soft tissue compensation, dose rate, total dose and fractionation differ between institutions. These differences are optimized at each institution to limit toxicity and maximize therapeutic outcome. Technically complex procedures such as total body radiation are subject to equipment failures. Such failures mid-treatment could be catastrophic to the patient, since therapy must be timely and compatible therapy may not be available elsewhere in the community. The purpose of this protocol is to provide backup between George Washington University Medical Center and the Radiation Oncology Branch of the NCI to allow for orderly, safe, and compatible therapies in the event of equipment failure; or replacement of a linear accelerator or any other malfunctioning equipment necessary to deliver TBI; or any emergent situation.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Patients must sign informed consent. Supporting institution physicians must agree that therapy is appropriate and safe.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2002</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bone Marrow Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Total Body Irradiation</keyword>
</DOC>