<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02710487</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sleep benefit (SB) is a prominent spontaneous, apparently unpredictable, transitory improvement in motor function reported by around 50% of patients affected by Parkinson's Disease (PD) after sleep and before taking their first dose of dopaminergic medications. The aim of this study is to test the hypothesis that objective and/or subjective improvement of motor function might be due to a carry-over effect of Rapid Eye Movements (REM) sleep at awakening from this sleep phase.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sleep, Awake &amp; Move - Part II</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The "Awake &amp; Move" study is the second part of the Sleep, Awake &amp; Move project. This study will be conducted in a subgroup of unselected, consecutive patients having completed the part I of the Sleep, Awake &amp; Move project (i.e. the "Sleep &amp; Move" study). The investigators plan to explore the carry-over effect of REM sleep on motor function in a subgroup of PD subjects p. In this interventional study the investigators expect to induce SB by awakening the subjects from nocturnal REM sleep in a sleep laboratory setting, but not from Non-Rapid Eye Movements (NREM) sleep (control intervention).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnostic criteria of idiopathic Parkinson's disease (UKPDBB) Mild to moderate disease (Hoehn &amp; Yahr score ≥ 1 and &lt; 3) Mentally and physically capable to give informed consent Stable antiparkinsonian and psychotropic therapy for the last 30 days Atypical parkinsonian syndrome Cognitive impairment (MMSE ≥ 26) Deep brain stimulation History of cerebrovascular disease, epilepsy, or other disabling neurological diseases Psychiatric disorders, excepting mild depression Alcohol abuse Other clinically significant severe concomitant disease states Inability to follow the procedures of the study (e.g. due to language problems, psychological disorders, etc.) Participation in another study with investigational drug within the 60 days preceding and during the present project. subjects with (a) sleepdisordered breathing [Respiratory Disorder Index (RDI)≥ 5] and (b) with no clearcut distinction of REM and NREM sleep, based on a videopolysomongraphical recording.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Parkinson's disease, Sleep Benefit</keyword>
</DOC>