<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="30103">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02714816</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ATH-2015-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02714816</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Natural History Study of Patients With Leber Congenital Amaurosis Associated With Mutations in RPE65</brief_title>
  <official_title>Natural History Study of Patients With Leber Congenital Amaurosis Associated With Mutations in RPE65</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>MeiraGTx UK II Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>MeiraGTx UK II Ltd</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The inherited retinal dystrophies are a clinically and genetically heterogeneous group of
      conditions, which often present in childhood. These disorders can be usefully divided
      according to whether they (i) are stationary or progressive; and (ii) exhibit predominantly
      rod or cone involvement, or central receptor disease. The underlying molecular genetic basis
      of the majority of monogenic inherited retinal disease has now been characterised.

      Leber Congenital Amaurosis (LCA) is a diagnosis for a group of severe, autosomal recessively
      inherited rod - cone dystrophies that typically result in complete visual loss in the third
      or fourth decade of life. One form, LCA2, is caused by a mutation in the gene encoding
      RPE56, an RPE-specific 65-kDa isomerase. Non-functional RPE65 results in photoreceptor cells
      that are unable to respond to light resulting in these patients being visually impaired.

      Proof of principle studies for RPE65 gene replacement therapy has been demonstrated with the
      use of recombinant adeno-associated virus serotype 2 (rAAV2/2) vectors in animal models.
      Furthermore clinical trials of gene replacement therapy in RPE65 associated LCA (RPE65-LCA)
      have shown significant promise. All three clinical trials showed improvement in visual
      function over the first year, however longer term follow up demonstrated progressive visual
      loss and that initial improvements were not maintained.

      Greater efficacy was noted in animal models and we feel the relatively lower efficacy of
      treatment in participants was most likely due to insufficient production of RPE65 protein
      from AAV2/2 hRPE65 in the human eye. As the maximal tolerated vector dose had been reached
      for AAV2/2 hRPE65, an optimised therapeutic vector (AAV2/5-OPTIRPE65) has been developed to
      drive higher transgene expression levels. (Professor Robin Ali and Prof James Bainbridge -
      unpublished data).

      In preparation for human clinical trials, a detailed prospective phenotypic study will be
      undertaken to investigate the natural history of RPE65-LCA. Such a study will help identify
      suitable patients for therapeutic intervention. Furthermore through greater phenotyping an
      optimal window for intervention and specific parameters to help quantify effect and identify
      clinical end points may have been ascertained .
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Researchers have been very successful in the continued studies with previously ascertained
      subjects. Further patients already on the MEH genetic database will also be recruited. Given
      the rarity of LCA-RPE65 the investigators will also potentially recruit patients referred to
      Moorfields Hospital by consultants around the World. Subjects will be assessed annually for
      a total of up to 5 years follow-up.

      Recruitment target is approximately 15 to 25 genetically confirmed patients.

      Assessments that will be undertaken depending on age, co-operation and ability to undertake
      the test include (see schedule of assessments):

      8.1 Complete clinical ocular examination, including visual acuity testing (for near and
      distance), contrast sensitivity, anterior segment slit lamp examination and posterior
      segment slit lamp examination.

      8.2 Colour fundus photography.

      8.3 SDOCT imaging. In order to ensure a good volume scan minimal oversampling will be
      performed but undertake sufficient B scans per volume (n=128). The investigators will then
      do high-resolution line scans with oversampling, 1 horizontal and 1 vertical, through the
      centre of the fovea.

      8.4 Adaptive optics imaging.

      8.5 Electrophysiological assessment incorporating the protocols recommended by the
      International Society for Clinical Electrophysiology of Vision (ISCEV). Full-field
      electroretinogram (FFERG) - a measure of global retinal function - will not be undertaken if
      previously documented to be undetectable - the majority of patients will have undetectable
      FFERG. Pattern ERG (PERG) and multifocal ERG (mfERG) will be undertaken on an annual basis
      to determine change in central retinal function over time (often residual central function
      till late in disease) - but will not be repeated once found to be undetectable.

      8.6 Visual Field Testing. The Octopus 900 perimeter will be used. Static full-field testing
      will be undertaken employing the GATE strategy, and size V test targets. Further analysis
      will be undertaken to model the entire hill-of-vision which will enhance the information
      obtained with full-field static perimetry.

      8.7 Mesopic and Scotopic Microperimetry.

      8.8 Colour vision testing.

      8.9 Vision guided mobility. This will be assessed by measuring the ability of each subject
      to navigate a simple route in a range of controlled illuminances.

      8.10 Quality of Life Questionnaire.

      8.11 Blood tests. Molecular confirmation of a mutation within the RPE65 gene by an
      accredited laboratory may be undertaken.

      Specific Aims of the study

      Perform detailed phenotyping, including autofluorescence imaging, microperimetry, AO and OCT
      imaging, spectral sensitivity and visual field testing, both in previously ascertained
      patients and newly identified subjects.

      Obtain OCT and AO images using the latest high-resolution technology in order to gain
      insights into the in vivo retinal structure and compare these with the functional data
      obtained

      Thereby establish well-characterised cohorts of individuals with RPE65-LCA.

      To use the information gained to provide more accurate advice to patients and assist in
      identifying potential participants, time points to intervene, and efficacy endpoints that
      may be used in planned interventions.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Analysis of retinal structure and function</measure>
    <time_frame>6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Retinal structure will be analysed using state of the art Adaptive optics and SD-OCT and Fundal autofluorescence. This will be correlated with assessment of visual acuity, psychophysical visual assessment, visual mobility, retinal sensitivity and visual fields</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life Questionnaires</measure>
    <time_frame>6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of Visual impairment using appropriate, validated questionnaires</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Retinal Sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>6 years</time_frame>
    <description>To be assessed in Microperimetry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Retinal Structural analysis with Adaptive Optics</measure>
    <time_frame>6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Retinal Structure analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fundal Autofluorescence</measure>
    <time_frame>6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Presence or Absence</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of Visual Fields</measure>
    <time_frame>6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of Visual Fields with analysis of hill of vision</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Leber Congenital Amaurosis</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with RPE65-LCA condition
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients with RPE65 associated retinal dystrophy

          -  Minimum subject age of 3 years

          -  Able to give consent/parent or guardian able to give consent

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients unable or unwilling to undertake consent or clinical testing
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michel Michealides, Prof</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UCL/Moorfileds</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anna Morka, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>02037252350</phone>
    <email>anna.morka@athena-vision.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Julie Bakobaki</last_name>
    <phone>02037252349</phone>
    <email>julie.bakobaki@athena-vision.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kellogg Eye Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>MI 48105</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Adrienne Chen</last_name>
      <phone>734-232-9167</phone>
      <email>chenad@med.umich.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Anna Morka</last_name>
      <phone>02037252350</phone>
      <email>anna.morka@athena-vision.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>John Heckenlively</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Moorfields Eye Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Neruban Kumaran, Dr</last_name>
      <email>neruban.kumaran@moorfields.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Sophie Connor</last_name>
      <phone>02075662821</phone>
      <email>sophie.connor@moorfields.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michel Michealides, Prof</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>June 8, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 8, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Leber Congenital Amaurosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Blindness</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
