<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01606774</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators plan to identify 80 pregnant women at low risk for obstetrical complications and replace 4-5 routine third trimester visits with a structured program of home weight, blood pressure and urine protein monitoring along with regular structured phone interviews and a 28 week ultrasound. The investigators hypothesis is that this protocol is both safe and acceptable.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Modernized Approach to Prenatal Care in Low Risk Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fetal Growth Retardation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &lt; 35 Doesn't live alone Current phone number Previous pregnancy No prior second trimester miscarriage/fetal loss after 13 weeks Previous delivery If yes, all had uncomplicated antepartum course All Deliveries &gt; 37 weeks All birth weight &gt; 2700 grams Maternal BMI between 18.5 and 30 No chronic medical problems No current substance abuse Spontaneous conception No family history of preeclampsia Agrees to first trimester aneuploidy screening Clinically significant abnormalities on routine physical exam or routine laboratory results Multiple pregnancy Fetal abnormalities detected on either the 1114 week or the 18 week ultrasound including a nuchal translucency &gt; 3 mm but not including second trimester markers for aneuploidy or a low lying placenta A risk of fetal aneuploidy on first trimester screening &gt; 1:300 PAPPA &lt; 5 %ile or HCG &lt; 1 %ile (abnormalities of these serum analytes routinely obtained as part of aneuploidy screening are associated with an increased risk of adverse outcome) Elevated blood pressure (&gt; 140/90), Cervical length &lt; 3 cm at the 18 week ultrasound (which is associated with an increased risk for preterm delivery).</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>