<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02549846</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Investigators will study whether immediate statin treatment after the onset of stroke is beneficial on the neurological protection</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>AdminiStration of Statin On Acute Ischemic stRoke patienT Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>It is much more important in Japan than Western to improve the prognosis after stroke because the prevalence and mortality rate of stroke in Japan is about 3-4 times as those of acute myocardial infarction. Investigators will study whether immediate statin treatment after the onset of stroke is beneficial on the neurological protection since most of previous studies with statins just showed the preventive effects from onset of primary or recurrent cerebral infarction.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atorvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rosuvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>the Informed consent will be acquired by the document. Age: 20 years of age or older. Gender: unquestioned hospitalization, outpatient: hospital Patients by MRI at the time of hospital transport, it has been confirmed diagnosed with cerebral infarction ingestible in within 24 hours after admission In the study treatment period, patients that can be defined treatment in this clinical study implementation plan patients with a history of hypersensitivity to the treatment agent of the present study Patients acute hepatitis, chronic hepatitis acute exacerbation, liver cirrhosis, it is believed that the liver cancer, liver function jaundice or the like is reduced, or a biliary obstruction Patients suspected of being pregnant or pregnant Patients in the administration of the cyclosporine or telaprevir patients with moderate or severe renal impairment (SCr ≧ 2.5mg / dL or eGFR &lt;30mg / dL) Patients who received a diagnosis of acute coronary syndrome within 6 months valvular disease, atrial fibrillation, patients with atrial thrombus Patients familial hypercholesterolemia patient admission NIHSS score is greater than or equal to 3 is more than 20 or before the onset mRS score patients with other doctors deemed inappropriate</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>