<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03057808</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to enroll approximately 450 subjects to see if a behavioral weight management program is successful in helping military female personnel who are pregnant or post-partum to manage their weight during and after their pregnancy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gestational Weight Gain and Postpartum Weight Loss in Active Duty Women (Moms Fit 2 Fight)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Investigators will randomize 450 consented participants to 1 of 3 interventions: a) a gestational weight gain intervention (GWG-only); b) a postpartum weight loss intervention (PPWL-only), or c) a combined gestational weight gain and postpartum weight loss intervention (GWG+PPWL) to determine the efficacy of the interventions on GWG as well as PPWL. Procedures: Interested individuals will be directed to call the study telephone number to learn more and determine whether eligibility criteria is met. Individuals who meet the telephone screening eligibility criteria will be invited to schedule a Screening Visit, during which written informed consent will be obtained. At this visit, eligibility will be assessed and measures will be administrated. The potential participant will also be asked to complete a one-week dietary and exercise self-monitoring run-in and receive medical clearance from their obstetrician to participate. Should she continue to be interested, she will return for a Baseline Visit and will be randomized. Randomized participants will have 5 in person scheduled visits after their Screening Visit and Baseline Visit to the Wilford Hall Ambulatory Surgical Center (WHASC) or San Antonio Military Medical Center (SAMMC) Obstetrics (OB) clinic. These visits will be scheduled at gestational week 32, 36, as well as at 6- weeks, 6-months, and 12- month postpartum. At these visits, physical measurements will be collected and participants will complete various questionnaires.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Gain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants will be active duty military personnel, stationed in the San Antonio area Participants must be less than 12 weeks gestation upon recruitment (based on the date of their last menstrual period and then confirmed by their physician at their first prenatal visit, which typically occurs at 68 weeks gestation at WHASC and SAMMC) Participants also must be within the normal, overweight, or obese BMI ranges Must have at least 1.5 years left on their current duty assignment Are generally in good health Currently not smoking at the time of conception Expecting multiple babies (e.g. twins) Diabetic Not interested in participating in a a program for 21 months</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>Postpartum</keyword>
</DOC>