<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02481414</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase II study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of a human papilloma virus (HPV) therapeutic vaccine called PepCan (HPV 16 E6 peptides combined with Candida skin testing reagent called Candin®) in adult females over a 12 month time period. As the results from the Phase I trial demonstrated some efficacy against non-16 HPV types, Candin alone will also be tested. Therefore, there will be two treatment arms: (1) PepCan and (2) Candin. Subjects found to be eligible for vaccination will be randomized in a double-blinded fashion at a 1:1 ratio. Each participant will be receiving injections four times with three weeks between injections. Clinical and virological responses will be assessed at 6 and 12 months. Safety will be assessed from the time of enrollment to 12 Month Visit. Immunological assessments will be made at 4 time points (prevaccination, after 2 injections, 6 month after 4 injections and 12 months after 4 vaccinations).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Trial of PepCan to Two Therapy Arms for Treating Cervical High-Grade Squamous Intraepithelial Lesions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma in Situ</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cervical Intraepithelial Neoplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Squamous Intraepithelial Lesions of the Cervix</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Dysplasia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged 1850 years Had recent (≤ 60 days) Pap smear result consistent with high grade squamous intraepithelial lesion (HSIL) or "cannot rule out HSIL" or HSIL on colposcopyguided biopsy Untreated for HSIL or "Cannot rule out HSIL" Able to provide informed consent Willingness and able to comply with the requirements of the protocol with a good command of the English language History of disease or treatment causing immunosuppression (e.g., cancer, human immunodeficiency virus, organ transplant, autoimmune disease) Being pregnant or attempting to be pregnant within the period of study participation Breast feeding or planning to breast feed within the period of study participation Allergy to Candida antigen History of severe asthma requiring emergency room visit or hospitalization Current use of betablocker medication (may not respond to epinephrine in case of anaphylaxis) History of invasive squamous cell carcinoma of the cervix History of having received PepCan If in the opinion of the Principal Investigator or other Investigators, it is not in the best interest of the patient to enter this study</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>HSIL, CIN II/III</keyword>
</DOC>