<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01431443</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the acute and chronic effect of consumption of flavanol-rich chocolate on endothelium function in pregnant women at high risk for preeclampsia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Consumption of Chocolate in Pregnant Women.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Although numerous strategies have been studied, no effective prevention or treatment of preeclampsia is yet available for pregnant women. This is surprising considering the growing body of literature that supports the hypothesis of a beneficial effect of dark chocolate consumption through the activity of flavanols on the endothelial function and blood pressure regulation, to find any clinical data among pregnant women with preeclampsia. The primary objective of the trial is to investigate the acute and chronic effect of consumption of flavanol-rich chocolate on endothelial function in pregnant women at high risk of preeclampsia. This 12-week efficacy study will permit us to verify the sustainability of the effect of daily intake of flavanol-rich chocolate intake.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pre-Eclampsia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pregnant women between the ages of 18 and 40 years. Presence of uterine diastolic notches measured by uterine artery Doppler between 10 and 14 weeks. Hypertension requiring medication. Currently or previously use of medications interfering with glucose or lipids metabolism. Use of supplements or natural health products that interfere with blood pressure. Consumption of 1 or more alcohol drink per day. Allergy or intolerance to nuts or chocolate.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Randomized double blind trial</keyword>
	<keyword>Cocoa flavonoids</keyword>
	<keyword>Endothelial function</keyword>
	<keyword>Blood pressure</keyword>
	<keyword>Pregnant women</keyword>
	<keyword>Preeclampsia</keyword>
	<keyword>Uterine artery flow</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulsatility index</keyword>
</DOC>