<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01857908</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Adrenal androgens are serum biomarkers of interest that may help guide abiraterone acetate treatment, particularly at the time of progression. Biomarkers may also help identify pathways to resistance of abiraterone acetate treatment. The most practical way of approaching this question is to explore surrogate biomarkers of prostate cancer including quantification of pharmacodynamic endocrine biomarkers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Correlative Study of Biomarkers of Resistance in Patients With Castrate Resistant Prostate Cancer Treated With Abiraterone</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Goals of this study include: - Explore which circulating endocrine markers or endocrine related markers have the best potential to predict clinical response to abiraterone acetate in CRPC patients - Explore the utility of microRNA, circulating DNA and exosome analyses in complementing the previous objective</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abiraterone Acetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed written informed consent. Before any study procedures are performed, subjects (or their legally acceptable representatives) will have the details of the study described to them, and they will be given a written informed consent document to read. If subjects consent to participate in the study, they will indicate that consent by signing and dating the informed consent document in the presence of study personnel Be suitable for receiving treatment with abiraterone acetate and prednisone Patients must have histologically or cytologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the prostate without neuroendocrine differentiation or small cell histology Patients may not receive any other investigational agent or dose escalation of abiraterone acetate during study participation Patient consents to comply to treatment with abiraterone acetate as directed by their physician Taking a dose of abiraterone acetate other than 1g daily or lack of compliance to daily dosing of abiraterone acetate and prednisone Patients receiving spironolactone or any other steroidogenic compounds in excess of the associated prednisone 5mg bid are excluded due to the potential for androgen receptor agonism</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Adenocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Abiraterone</keyword>
	<keyword>Abiraterone Acetate</keyword>
	<keyword>Zytiga</keyword>
	<keyword>Correlative study</keyword>
	<keyword>Castrate Resistant Prostate Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Abiraterone Correlative study</keyword>
</DOC>