<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02229669</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study compared the clinical outcomes of coronally advanced flap using two different surgical strategies in the treatment of multiple gingival recessions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Coronally Advanced Flap With Two Different Techniques for the Treatment of Multiple Gingival Recessions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of this split-mouth, randomized controlled trial was to compare the clinical outcomes of coronally advanced flap (CAF) using two different surgical strategies in the treatment of multiple gingival recessions. Recessions were randomly treated according to a split-mouth design by means of: CAF with oblique interdental incisions (OBL technique) or CAF with horizontal interdental incisions (HOR technique). Marginal gingival recession (REC), clinical attachment level (CAL), pocket probing depth (PPD), height of keratinized tissue (HKT) and thickness of keratinized tissue (TKT) were measured at baseline, 3 and 6 months after treatment. Patient-centered outcomes concerning morbidity and improvement in the esthetic appearance were recorded using a Visual Analogue Scale (VAS).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Gingival Recession</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gingival Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Periodontal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Systemically healthy subjects Patients should have bilateral Class I and II MGRs (Miller 1985) in maxillary tooth (at least three recessiontype defects affecting adjacent teeth in each side of the maxilla). At least 20 teeth and no sites with attachment loss and probing pocket depth (PPD) &gt; 3 mm. Fullmouth plaque and bleeding on probing of &lt; 20%. Involved tooth should present tooth vitality, absence of caries, restorations or extensive noncarious cervical lesion. History of smoking. Antimicrobial and antiinflammatory therapies in the previous 2 months. Previous mucogingival surgery at the region to be treated Systemic conditions that could affect tissue healing (e.g. diabetes). Use of orthodontic appliances.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>