<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02924753</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a study for patients who have been previously treated for B-ALL. The purpose of this study is to determine the safety and feasibility of CART-19 cells to the patients with relapsed and refractory CD19+ B-ALL.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Safety and Efficacy of CART-19 Cells in B-cell Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia (B-ALL).</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Subjects will be staged and the suitability of their T cells for CART-19 manufacturing will be determined at entry phase,. Subjects will be collected large numbers of peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) for CART-19 manufacturing. The T cells will be purified from the PBMC, transduced with CART-19 lentiviral vector, expanded in vitro and then administered to subjects. Subjects will have blood tests to assess safety and efficacy, and persistence of the CART-19 cells at regular intervals through four weeks after their last infusion of the study. Following the 6 months of intensive follow-up, subjects will be evaluated quarterly for two years with a physical examination, blood tests, bone marrow aspirate, minimal residual disease (MRD) and persistence of CART-19. Following this evaluation, subjects will be evaluated health problems every year for an additional thirteen years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Burkitt Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fludarabine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. 4 years to 70 years, expected survival &gt; 3 months 2. CD19 positive Bcell acute lymphoblastic leukemia 3. Karnofsky Performance Status (KPS) &gt;70 4. Relapsed after allogeneic or autologous stem cell transplantation (SCT); 5. Cardiac function: 12 levels; Liver: TBIL≤3 Upper Limit of Normal (ULN)，aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤2.5 ULN，ALT ≤2.5 ULN; kidney: Cr≤1.25 ULN; bone marrow: White Blood Cell (WBC) ≥ 3.0×109/L, Hb ≥90 g/L, Platelet (PLT) ≥ 80×109/L） 6. No serious allergic constitution 7. No other serous diseases that conflicts with the clinical program 8. No other cancer history 9. No serious mental disorder 10. Informed consent is signed by a subject or his lineal relation. 1. Pregnant or lactating women; (female participants of reproductive potential must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test) 2. Uncontrolled active infection, HIV infection, syphilis serology reaction positive 3. Active hepatitis B or hepatitis C infection 4. Recent or current use of glucocorticoid or other immunosuppressor 5. With severe cardiac, liver, renal insufficiency, diabetes and other diseases 6. Transaminase &gt;2.5 ULN, Bilirubin &gt;3 ULN，Creatinine&gt;1.25 ULN 7. Participate in other clinical research in the past three months; previously treatment with any gene therapy products 8. Researchers think of that does not fit to participate in the study, or other cases that affect the clinical trial results</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>