<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02924350</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This single center study will investigate the efficacy of an experimental stannous fluoride containing dentifrice in relieving DH compared with a standard fluoride dentifrice after short term use.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Efficacy of an Occluding Dentifrice in Providing Relief From Dentinal Hypersensitivity (DH)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dentin Sensitivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tin Fluorides</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorophosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorides</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Consent: Demonstrates understanding of the study procedures, restrictions and willingness to participate as evidenced by voluntary written informed consent and has received a signed and dated copy of the informed consent form Aged 1865 years inclusive Understands and is willing, able and likely to comply with all study procedures and restrictions Good general and mental health with, in the opinion of the investigator or medically qualified designee: a) No clinically significant and relevant abnormalities of medical history or oral examination. b) Absence of any condition that would impact on the participants safety or wellbeing or affect the individual's ability to understand and follow study procedures and requirements At Visit 1 (Screening): a) Selfreported history of DH lasting more than six months but not more than 10 years. b) Minimum of 20 natural teeth. c) Minimum of 2 accessible nonadjacent teeth (incisors, canines, premolars), preferably in different quadrants, that meet all of the following criteria: Signs of facial/cervical gingival recession and/or signs of erosion or abrasion (EAR). Tooth with modified gingival index (MGI) score =0 adjacent to the test area (exposed dentine) only [Lobene, 1986] and a clinical Tooth with signs of sensitivity measured by qualifying evaporative air assessment (Y/N response) mobility of ≤1, Tooth with signs of sensitivity measured by qualifying evaporative air assessment (Y/N response) At Visit 2, Baseline (Pretreatment):Minimum of two, nonadjacent accessible teeth (incisors, canines, premolars), that meet all of the following criteria:Tooth with signs of sensitivity, measured by qualifying tactile stimulus (Yeaple ≤ 20g) and evaporative air assessment (Schiff sensitivity score ≥ 2) Teeth which meet the EAR, MGI and mobility inclusion criteria and none of the dentition exclusion criteria at Screening should be assessed by tactile stimulus at Visit 2. Those teeth which meet the required tactile threshold (Yeaple ≤ 20g) should then be assessed by evaporative air stimulus. When two teeth that meet the study criteria are identified, no further testing is necessary A woman who is known to be pregnant or who is intending to become pregnant over the duration of the study A woman who is breastfeeding Known or suspected intolerance or hypersensitivity to the study materials (or closely related compounds) or any of their stated ingredients Participation in another clinical study (including cosmetic studies) or receipt of an investigational drug within 30 days of the screening visit Previous participation in this study Participation in study 205084 Recent history (within the last year) of alcohol or other substance abuse An employee of the sponsor or the study site or members of their immediate family The site for this protocol is the Clinical trials Unit in the Bristol Dental School and Hospital. Employees of the Bristol Dental School and Hospital not associated with the Clinical Trials unit are eligible to participate Presence of chronic debilitating disease which, in the opinion of the investigator, could affect study outcomes Any condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, causes xerostomia Dental prophylaxis within 4 weeks of Screening Tongue or lip piercing or presence of dental implants on the selected Test Teeth Gross periodontal disease, treatment of periodontal disease (including surgery) within 12 months of Screening, scaling or root planning within 3 months of Screening Vital teeth bleaching within 8 weeks of Screening Desensitizing treatment within 8 weeks of Screening (professional sensitivity treatments and nondentifrice sensitivity treatments) Tooth with evidence of current or recent caries, or reported treatment of decay within 12 months of Screening Tooth with exposed dentine but with deep, defective or facial restorations, teeth used as abutments for fixed or removable partial dentures, teeth with full crowns or veneers, orthodontic bands or cracked enamel. Sensitive teeth with contributing aetiologies other than erosion, abrasion or recession of exposed dentine Sensitive tooth not expected to respond to treatment with an overthecounter dentifrice in the opinion of the investigator Use of an oral care product indicated for the relief of dentine hypersensitivity within 8 weeks of screening (participants will be required to bring their current oral care products to the site in order to verify the absence of known antisensitivity ingredients) Daily doses of medication/treatments which, in the opinion of the investigator, could interfere with the perception of pain. Examples of such medications include analgesics, anticonvulsants, antihistamines that cause marked or moderate sedation, sedatives, tranquilisers, antidepressants, moodaltering and antiinflammatory drugs Currently taking antibiotics or has taken antibiotics within 2 weeks of Baseline Daily dose of a medication which, in the opinion of the investigator, is causing xerostomia Any participants who, in the judgment of the investigator, should not participate in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>