<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00684034</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The influence of hemodialysis on oxidative stress, endothelial activation, inflammation and on the redox state of lymphocytes should be clarified as well as the putative relationships between all these parameters.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Redox State in the Course of Chronic Renal Insufficiency and Hemodialysis: Implications in Morbimortality</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Up to now, no anti-oxydative treatment has been able to reduce the mortality of the patients with Kidney Failure. Thus it is necessary to have a better knowledge of oxydative stress mechanisms in patients with KF in order to find more efficacious treatments. The influence of hemodialysis upon oxidative stress is not well known.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 and 80 years old man or woman dialysing at least 3 times a week for at least 6 months and having no residual renal function Rate of haemoglobin &gt; 11 g / dl Clinically stable patient that is having had no considerable event (cardiovascular problem, infection, surgical operation) with the exception of angioplasty of fistula or prosthesis vascular, in the previous 3 months the entrance to the study Patient capable of understanding and of following the essay, in particular knowing how to read the note of information. Pregnant woman Treatment by corticoids or immunosuppresseurs hemopathy sly chronic cancer or infection in evolution Cardiovascular event (infarct, unstable angor, coronary bypasses, confusions of the rhythm, AVC, amputation) or infectious (bloodpoisoning, pneumopathie, meningitis) or surgical operation in the previous 3 months the inclusion in the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Redox state in the course of chronic renal insufficiency and hemodialysis.</keyword>
</DOC>