<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00684216</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial studies the effects on quality of life and on time to second progression of the sequence endocrine therapy-capecitabine versus the sequence capecitabine-endocrine treatment. It is anticipated that the time on study (which is the time between randomization and the discontinuation of the second treatment in the sequence) will be similar for both arms of the study. The quality of life during this period, however, could be better in the patient group receiving the most effective first agent in the sequence. If this proves to be true, the conventional wisdom that endocrine therapy should be continued until no further endocrine options remain, must be abandoned.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Second-line Endocrine Treatment Followed by Capecitabine Versus Capecitabine Followed by Endocrine Treatment in Patients With Metastatic ER Positive Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized phase II/II study. Patients are randomized for the sequence capecitabine-hormonal therapy versus hormonal therapy- capecitabine. At progression the patient should receive the other protocol treatment (e.g. if the patient was randomized to capecitabine, at progression the treatment should be switched to hormonal treatment).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Exemestane</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anastrozole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Letrozole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tamoxifen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Written informed consent. 2. Proven infiltrating breast cancer with distant metastases or inoperable locally advanced disease. 3. Positive estrogen receptor (≥ 10% positive nuclei at immunohistochemistry). Progesterone and HER2 neu receptor have to be known. 4. Progressive disease during first line hormonal therapy (either tamoxifen or aromatase inhibitor) for metastatic or inoperable locally advanced disease. Simultaneous use of LHRH analogs is allowed. OR Recurrence of disease (M1) during adjuvant hormonal therapy (either tamoxifen or aromatase inhibitor). 5. No prior chemotherapy for metastatic disease 6. Willing and able to participate in Quality of Life investigation 1. Other malignancy except carcinoma in situ, unless the other malignancy was treated 5 or more years ago with curative intent without the use of chemotherapy or radiation therapy. 2. Pregnancy or breast feeding women. 3. Contraindications to the use of capecitabine 4. Known CNS metastases</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>metastatic</keyword>
	<keyword>ER positive</keyword>
	<keyword>PD during/after first line hormonal treatment</keyword>
</DOC>