<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00496067</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of Doppler guided Uterine Artery Occlusion (D-UAO) as treatment for the reduction of fibroid-associated symptoms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Uterine Artery Occlusion for Fibroid Related Bleeding</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>DUAO is intended for bilateral occlusion of the uterine arteries</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leiomyoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myofibroma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Menorrhagia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>25 to 50 years of age Subject has a negative urine or blood pregnancy test prior to the procedure. At the time of enrollment to the study, the subject has no intent of further childbearing and intends to use appropriate contraception throughout the first 12 months of the study period (unless sterilized) Normal pap smear within 36 months of study procedure (most recent) Cervix suitable for tenaculum placement as determined by pelvic exam (adequate length of cervix, absence of cervical fibroid/lower fibroid to prevent clamp placement) At least one intramural or subserosal or submucosal uterine fibroid with a minimum diameter of greater than or equal to 3 cm, and all fibroids with a diameter less than or equal to 8cm with a prevailing pathology (e.g., as opposed to adenomyosis) of fibroids determined through ultrasound Symptomatic subject presenting with at least one of the following fibroid symptoms: pelvic pressure, menorrhagia, metrorrhagia, pelvic pain, increasing abdominal girth or dyspareunia due to fibroids. Subject has evidence of bilateral ureteric flow Subject agrees to participate in the study, including completion of all studyrelated procedures and evaluations, and documents this agreement by signing the Ethics Committeeapproved informed consent. Pregnancy as confirmed by positive urine or blood pregnancy test Menopausal as defined by elevated folliclestimulating hormone (FSH) and decreased oestradiol hormone levels as determined by the hospital local laboratory reference range criteria Presence of any pedunculated submucosal or pedunculated subserosal fibroid(s) as determined by MRI, ultrasound or hysteroscopy Presence of an intrauterine device (IUD) Any hydronephrosis as determined on renal ultrasound prior to the procedure Clinical history of any thromboembolic disease or known thrombophilia Blood Urine Nitrogen (BUN) greater than 7.2mmol/L* and/or serum creatinine greater than 106μmol/L* unresolved with change in diet or hydration History or current evidence of gynecologic malignancy (confirmed by hysteroscopy or endometrial biopsy), atypical endometrial hyperplasia, or chronic pelvic inflammatory disease Pelvic mass outside the uterus other than uterine fibroids Any current acute or chronic systemic infection or localized pelvic infection, including a urinary tract infection Use of GonadotropinReleasing Hormone (GnRH) agonist, danozol or mifepristone within 6months prior to the start of the study procedure Using anticoagulation therapy (except over the counter treatments (e.g. aspirin)), or have an underlying bleeding disorder Unsuitable for MRI examination (e.g. severe claustrophobia, nonMRIcompatible implanted metalloid devices) Prior endometrial ablation, uterine artery embolization, or uterine artery ligation Poor procedural candidate due to medical conditions as determined by the investigator (e.g. anesthesia class, renal insufficiency, heart disease);</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fibroids</keyword>
	<keyword>Menorrhagia</keyword>
	<keyword>Menorrhagia associated with uterine fibroids</keyword>
</DOC>