<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00496015</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this trial is to assess if the rate of febrile reactions following the co-administration of a booster dose of pneumococcal conjugate vaccines with standard infant vaccines is lowered when paracetamol is given prophylactically and to assess the impact of pneumococcal conjugate vaccine on pneumococcal and H. influenzae nasopharyngeal carriage compared to control group receiving meningococcal conjugate vaccine (GSK134612). This protocol posting deals with objectives &amp; outcome measures of the booster phase. The objectives &amp; outcome measures of the primary phase are presented in a separate protocol posting (NCT number = NCT00370318).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prophylactic Antipyretic Treatment in Children Receiving Booster Dose of Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine GSK1024850A</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Protocol Posting has been updated in order to comply with the FDA Amendment Act, Sep 2007.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Streptococcal Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heptavalent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antipyretics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acetaminophen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who the investigator believes that their parents/guardians can and will comply with the requirements of the protocol should be enrolled in the study. A male or female between, and including, 1215 months of age at the time of the vaccination. Written informed consent obtained from the parent or guardian of the subject. Free of obvious health problems as established by medical history and clinical examination before entering into the study. Subjects in the unprimed group • A male or female who previously participated in study 107017 and received 3 doses of pneumococcal conjugate vaccine GSK1024850A. For all subjects: Concurrently participating in another clinical study, at any time during the study period, in which the subject has been or will be exposed to an investigational or a noninvestigational product Indication, other than specified in the protocol, for prophylactic antipyretic treatment. Use of any investigational or nonregistered product (drug or vaccine) other than the study vaccines within one month preceding the dose of study vaccines, or planned use during the entire study period. Chronic administration (defined as more than 14 days) of immunosuppressants or other immunemodifying drugs within 6 months prior to the dose of study vaccines. Planned administration/administration of a vaccine not foreseen by the study protocol, during the period starting one month before the dose of study vaccines and up to one month after the dose of study vaccines. History of, or intercurrent, diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis, polio, hepatitis B, Haemophilus influenzae type b disease. History of allergic disease or reactions likely to be exacerbated by any component of the vaccines. History of seizures (this criterion does not apply to subjects who have had a single, uncomplicated febrile convulsion in the past) or progressive neurological disease. Acute disease at the time of enrolment. Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient condition based on medical history and physical examination. A family history of congenital or hereditary immunodeficiency. Major congenital defects or serious chronic illness. Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products within three months preceding administration of the dose of study vaccines or planned administration during the study period. Subjects of which both parents have a history of atopia. Subject has received systemic antibiotic therapy for acute illness within 24 hours prior to the vaccination. Subject is likely to receive antipyretic treatment as a result of a concomitant illness or has been treated with paracetamol within the past 24 hours. DTPaHBVIPV/Hib vaccine: Known hypersensitivity after previous administration of diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis, polio, hepatitis B and Hib vaccines or to any component of the vaccines. Encephalopathy. As with other vaccines, administration of DTPaHBVIPV/Hib should be postponed in subjects suffering from acute mild, moderate or severe illness. For subjects in the APAP, APNAP and NAP groups: • Administration of any pneumococcal, diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis, polio, hepatitis B and/or Haemophilus influenzae type b vaccines other than allowed and used in study 107017. For subjects in the APAP group: • Subject with any contraindication to treatment with paracetamol. For subjects in the unprimed group: Previous vaccination with meningococcal polysaccharide vaccine of serogroup A, C, W135 and/or Y. Previous vaccination with meningococcal polysaccharide conjugate vaccine of serogroups A, C, W135 and/or Y. Planned administration of a hepatitis B vaccine not foreseen by the study protocol during the period starting one month after the dose of study vaccines and up to study end. Previous vaccination with tetanus toxoid containing vaccines including T, DTP, DT, DTPIPV, DTPHBVIPV and HibTT vaccines six months prior to study entry. History of meningococcal disease due to serogroup A, C, W, or Y. Administration of any pneumococcal vaccine since birth. Full vaccination history since birth not available.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Streptococcus Pneumoniae Vaccines</keyword>
	<keyword>Meningococcal disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Carriage</keyword>
	<keyword>Prophylactic antipyretic</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Pneumococcal vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Fever</keyword>
	<keyword>Pneumococcal disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunogenicity</keyword>
	<keyword>Meningococcal vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Booster vaccination</keyword>
</DOC>