<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01903902</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of paclitaxel-eluting balloon (SeQuent® Please) for treatment of lesions in native small coronary arteries.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Paclitaxel-eluting Balloon for Treatment of Lesions in Native Small Coronary Arteries</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Drug-eluting balloon (DEB) have emerged as a potential alternative to overcome the limitations of drug-eluting stents such as restenosis or stent thrombosis. DEB angioplasty is proven to be effective clinically for the treatment of in-stent restenosis. However, DEB for de novo lesions, especially in small vessels is less studied. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of paclitaxel-eluting balloon (SeQuent® Please) for treatment of lesions in native small coronary arteries.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 19 years Patients who are appropriate for percutaneous coronary intervention using drugeluting balloon in native small coronary artery (vessel diameter ≥ 2.25 mm and ≤ 2.75 mm, lesion length &lt; 25 mm) Informed consent Chronic total obstruction lesion Severe calcified lesion Left main coronary lesion Lesion having intravascular thrombus Shock status from any cause including cardiogenic shock Left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 30% Need for coronary artery bypass surgery Allergic reaction for paclitaxel Severe allergic for contrast agent (Visipaque) or statin Pregnancy, breastfeeding or Expectation for pregnancy in women of childbearing age</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Coronary artery disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Balloon angioplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug-eluting balloon</keyword>
</DOC>