<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01903434</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to measure and compare the amounts of the study drug evacetrapib found in the blood after taking two different formulations. The study has 3 periods. Participants will take each formulation by mouth at least once. A minimum of 14 days will pass between study drug doses. The safety and tolerability of the study drug will also be examined. Information about any side effects that may occur will also be collected. This study will last approximately 6 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Evacetrapib (LY2484595) in Healthy Participants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Evacetrapib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male participants agree to use a reliable method of birth control and not donate sperm during the study and for 90 days after study completion Female participants who are not of childbearing potential due to surgical sterilization confirmed by medical history, or menopause Have a body mass index of 18 to 32 kilograms per square meter (kg/m^2) Are reliable and willing to make themselves available for the duration of the study and are willing to follow study procedures Are currently enrolled in, or have completed or discontinued within the last 30 days from, a clinical trial involving an investigational product Have known allergies to evacetrapib, related compounds or any components of the formulation, or history of significant allergic disease as determined by the investigator Have a history or presence of cardiovascular, respiratory, hepatic, renal, gastrointestinal, endocrine, hematological, or neurological disorders Regularly use known drugs of abuse and/or show positive findings on urinary drug screening Are women who are pregnant or lactating Have used or intend to use overthecounter or prescription medications (including vitamins/mineral supplements, herbal medicine) 14 days prior to enrollment and during the study Have donated blood of more than 500 milliliter (mL) within the last month Have an average weekly alcohol intake that exceeds 21 units per week (males) and 14 units per week (females), or are unwilling to stop alcohol consumption from 48 hours prior to each dose and while resident at the Clinical Research Unit (CRU) Currently smoke or use tobacco or nicotine products</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>