<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01599845</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Investigation of the differences between the levels of extracellular and intracellular nano-particles in workers exposed to environmental particles during their employment to enhance understanding the process of penetration of the particles to respiratory epithelial cells.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Differential Pattern of Deposition of Nano Particles in the Airways of Exposed Workers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study investigates the following questions: Does occupational exposure to nanoparticles influence permeation of such particles to respiratory airways? Is there a correlation between the levels of nanoparticles in sample biological fluids of the patients and their pulmonary functions. Is there a correlation between the levels of nanoparticles in sample biological fluids of the patients and respiratory tract infections. The study protocol includes the following steps: Initial interview of the patient Measurement of nanoparticles in samples of exhaled breath condensate using NanoSight LM 20 Measurement of nanoparticles in induced sputum. And finally examination of the relationship between the measured parameters and the indices of pulmonary infection, and pulmonary function as measured by the pulmonary department of the TASMC.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults over 20 years of age who visit Ichilov Hospital for medical complaints/inquiries regarding respiratory tract. Study population is composed of people who are exposed to environmental particles form industrial sources. Informed consent is requested from each subject. Unemployed individuals. Individuals who are not working in industrial jobs, such as office workers and secretaries.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lung</keyword>
	<keyword>Alveoli</keyword>
	<keyword>Nanoparticles</keyword>
	<keyword>Particulate matter</keyword>
	<keyword>Exhaled breath condensate</keyword>
	<keyword>Induced sputum</keyword>
	<keyword>Forced expiratory volume</keyword>
	<keyword>Force vital capacity</keyword>
</DOC>