<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01315236</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy, safety and tolerability of 84 days of daily dosing of 590 mg of LAI versus placebo in patients with recalcitrant NTM lung disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Arikayce for Nontuberculous Mycobacteria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Mycobacterium Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycobacterium Infections, Nontuberculous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amikacin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key 1. Diagnosis of pulmonary nontuberculous mycobacterial lung disease in accordance with the 2007 ATS/IDSA criteria with evidence of nodular bronchiectasis and/or cavitary disease by chest computed tomography (CT). 2. History of chronic infection with either Mycobacterium avium complex or Mycobacterium abscessus or mixed infection with both species (defined as at least 2 documented positive cultures in the prior 2 years, of which at least one was obtained in the 6 months prior to screening). 3. Positive sputum culture obtained at screening visit with either Mycobacterium avium complex or Mycobacterium abscessus or mixed infection with one dominant species. 4. Receiving ATS/IDSA guidelinesbased treatment regimen defined as: adherent to a multidrug regimen for at least 6 months prior to screening with persistently positive mycobacterial cultures. 5. Ability to produce at least 3 mL of sputum or be willing to undergo an induction that produces at least 3 mL of sputum for clinical evaluation. 6. Female of childbearing potential agrees to practice an acceptable method of birth control (e.g., abstinence, hormonal or barrier methods, partner sterilization, or IUD). Key 1. Forced Expiratory Volume in 1 second (FEV1) &lt;30% of predicted at Screening. 2. Presence of any clinically significant cardiac disease as determined by Investigator. The QTc criteria for Exclusion is QTc&gt; 450 msec for males or QTc&gt; 470 msec for females. 3. Subjects with hemoptysis of ≥60 mL in a 24 hour period within 4 weeks prior to screening. 4. Active pulmonary malignancy (primary or metastatic) or any malignancy requiring chemotherapy or radiation therapy within one year prior to screening or anticipated during the study period. 5. Active allergic bronchopulmonary mycosis or any other condition requiring systemic steroids at a dose ≥ equivalent of 10 mg/day of prednisone within 3 months prior to screening or anticipated during the study period. 6. Pulmonary tuberculosis requiring treatment or treated within 2 years prior to screening. 7. History of lung transplantation. 8. Hypersensitivity to aminoglycosides. 9. Any change in chronic NTM multidrug regimen within 28 days prior to Study Day 1. 10. Evidence of biliary cirrhosis with portal hypertension. 11. History of daily, continuous oxygen supplementation. 12. Smoking tobacco or any substance within 6 months prior to screening or anticipated inability to refrain from smoking throughout the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>