<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01315678</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A major factor in the respiratory health of Cystic Fibrosis (CF) subjects is the prevalence of chronic Pseudomonas aeruginosa infections. The Pseudomonas aeruginosa infection rate in CF patients increases with age and by age 18 years approximately 85% of CF patients in the US are infected. Liposomal amikacin for inhalation (Arikayce™) was developed as a possible treatment for chronic infection due to Pseudomonas aeruginosa in CF patients. The purpose of this European Registration study is to determine whether Arikayce™ is effective in treating chronic lung infections caused by Pseudomonas aeruginosa in Cystic Fibrosis subjects. The effectiveness, safety and tolerability of Arikayce™ will be compared to TOBI, an inhalation antibiotic already available for use. The study will enroll approximately 300 subjects in clinics in Europe and Canada. Subjects will be required to visit the clinic 9 times (including the Screening visit) over a period of approximately 6 months. No overnight stays at the clinic will be required.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate Arikayce™ in CF Patients With Chronic Pseudomonas Aeruginosa Infections</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cystic Fibrosis (CF) is a genetic disease resulting from mutations in the cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator (CFTR) gene. Patients with CF manifest pathological changes in a variety of organs that express CFTR. The lungs are frequently affected often resulting in chronic infections by bacteria such as Pseudomonas aeruginosa and airway inflammation. Treatment of chronic lung infections is one of the principal goals of CF therapy. Arikayce™ (liposomal amikacin for inhalation) is a sustained-release formulation of amikacin encapsulated inside nanoscale liposomal carriers designed for administration via inhalation. It is hypothesized that the sustained-release pulmonary targeting and biofilm penetration properties of this formulation will have several advantages over current therapies in treating CF patients with chronic lung infection caused by Pseudomonas aeruginosa. This Phase 3 European Registration study has been designed to evaluate the efficacy, safety and tolerability of Arikayce™ in treating CF patients with chronic bronchopulmonary infection compared to a currently available antibiotic, TOBI® (tobramycin) Inhalation Solution. Eligible subjects will be randomized 1:1 to receive 590 mg of Arikayce™ once daily via a PARI Investigational eFlow® Nebulizer or 300 mg TOBI® BID via a PARI LC® PLUS nebulizer. Subjects will receive 3 cycles of treatment with each cycle being comprised of 28 days on treatment followed by 28 days off-treatment. Total study duration is up to 186 days (~6 months) including an up to 18 day Screening period. Subjects will be evaluated for safety, tolerability and efficacy bi-weekly during the first 4 weeks of treatment, and thereafter every 4 weeks for the duration of the study. Pharmacokinetics (PK) of Arikayce™ in blood, sputum and 24-hour urine will be determined in a subgroup of study subjects who consent to PK evaluation. At the completion of the TR02-108 protocol, subjects who have consented and meet study safety criteria may enroll in the long-term, open-label, multi-cycle extension study of 590 mg of Arikayce™ (under a separate protocol TR02-110).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pseudomonas Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tobramycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amikacin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Written informed consent or assent Confirmed diagnosis of CF History of chronic infection with Pseudomonas aeruginosa Sputum culture positive for Pseudomonas aeruginosa at Screening FEV1 ≥ 25% of predicted value at Screening Key FEV1 &lt;25% of predicted at Screening History of major complications of lung disease within 8 weeks prior to Screening Hemoptysis of ≥60 mL in a 24hour period within 4 weeks prior to Screening History of positive culture for Burkholderia cepacia within 2 years prior to Screening History of pulmonary tuberculosis or nontuberculous mycobacterial lung disease treated within 2 years prior to Screening or requiring treatment at the time of screening History of Allergic BronchoPulmonary Aspergillosis or any other condition requiring systemic steroids at a dose ≥ equivalent of 10 mg/day of prednisone within 3 months prior to Screening Presence of any clinically significant cardiac disease History of lung transplantation Daily, continuous oxygen supplementation or nighttime supplemental oxygen requirement of greater than 2 L/min Administration of any investigational products within 8 weeks prior to study Day 1 Smoking tobacco or any substance within 6 months prior to screening or anticipated inability to refrain from smoking throughout the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cystic Fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Respiratory Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulmonary Cystic Fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>CFTR</keyword>
	<keyword>Amikacin</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-bacterial Agents</keyword>
</DOC>