<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02674672</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To establish the clinical safety and efficacy of the VenaTech® Retrievable Vena Cava Filter</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Safety and Efficacy Study for Implantation and Retrieval Procedures Using the VENATECH® Retrieval Filter System</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Embolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Embolism</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pulmonary thromboembolism with contraindication to anticoagulation. Failure of anticoagulant therapy in thromboembolic diseases. Prevention of pulmonary embolism in patients with a recent history ( &lt;3 months) of DVT/ PE who need to undergo urgent surgery at high risk of DVT/PE with temporary contraindication to the use of therapeutic doses of anticoagulants. Emergency treatment following massive pulmonary embolism where anticipated benefits of conventional therapy are reduced and Chronic, recurrent pulmonary embolism where anticoagulant therapy has failed or is contraindicated The filter should not be implanted in patients with : A vena cava which has a diameter &lt; 14 mm or &gt; 28 mm (due to the risk of device migration) Risk of septic embolism Known allergy to the materials contained in the kit, allergy to contrast media. Severely disabled patients whose lifeexpectancy, up to 6 months, appears limited according to the investigator's opinion. In addition, exclusion criteria are also extended to : Patients who cannot be regularly followed up by the participating center Subject who already has an implanted vena cava filter Subject who has a duplicated IVC Subject who has a contrast allergy to both iodinated contrast and noniodinated contrast material Subject unable to understand information about participation in the study due to a language barrier, intellectual deficiency, psychiatric problems… Subject who has a renal failure (creatinemia clearance &lt; 30ml/min)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>VenaTech® Retrievable Vena Cava Filter</keyword>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
	<keyword>efficacy</keyword>
</DOC>