<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02674750</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 2, open-label, multicenter trial designed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of CUDC-907 in subjects 18 years and older with Relapsed/Refractory (RR) MYC-altered Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma (DLBCL).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of CUDC-907 in Patients With RR DLBCL, Including Patients With MYC Alterations</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients with RR DLBCL will be eligible for treatment with CUDC-907, as long as they have tumor tissue available that can be tested for MYC-altered disease based on one of the following: - Fresh tumor tissue obtained from biopsy accessible lesions , or - Archived tumor tissue (most recent available) Subjects will be required to submit archival tumor samples (most recent available) or fresh tumor samples for central FISH and IHC testing. Subjects whose tumors have been previously characterized as MYC-altered are strongly encouraged to enter the study. For subjects who enter the study with unconfirmed MYC-altered disease, fresh tumor samples are preferred.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age ≥ 18 years. 2. At least 2 but no more than 4 prior lines of therapy for the treatment of de novo DLBCL and ineligible for (or failed) autologous or allogeneic stem cell transplant (SCT) (salvage therapy, conditioning therapy and maintenance with transplant will be considered one prior treatment). NOTE: For follicular lymphoma transformed to DLBCL (tFL/DLBCL), single agent noncytotoxic therapy will not be considered as a line of therapy. 3. Histopathologically confirmed diagnosis of one of the following: RR DLBCL per the 2008 World Health Organization (WHO) classification of hematopoietic and lymphoid tumors (Swerdlow et al, 2008). High grade Bcell lymphoma (HGBL), with MYC and BCL2 and/or BCL6 rearrangements or DLBCL, NOS per the 2016 revision of the WHO classification of lymphoid neoplasms (Swerdlow et al, 2016). Diagnosis of tFL/DLBCL is allowed. However, other Bcell lymphomas including other transformed indolent lymphomas/DLBCL per the 2008 WHO classification, and Burkitt lymphoma are not eligible. 1. Known primary mediastinal, ocular, epidural, testicular or breast DLBCL. 2. Active CNS involvement of their malignancy. 3. Known allergy or hypersensitivity to phosphatidylinositol 3 kinase (PI3K) inhibitors or any component of the formulations used in this study. 4. Cytotoxic anticancer therapy (e.g., alkylating agents, antimetabolites, purine analogues) or any other systemic anticancer therapy within 2 weeks of study entry. 5. Radiotherapy delivered to nontarget lesions within one week prior to starting study treatment or delivered to target lesions that will be followed on the study (note: prior sites of radiation will be recorded). 6. Treatment with experimental therapy within 5 terminal halflives (t1/2) or 4 weeks prior to enrollment, whichever is longer. 7. Current or planned glucocorticoid therapy, with the following exceptions: Doses ≤ 10 mg/kg/day prednisolone or equivalent is allowed, provided that the steroid dose has been stable or tapering for at least 14 days prior to the first dose of CUDC907. Inhaled, intranasal, intraarticular, and topical steroids are permitted.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>DLBCL</keyword>
	<keyword>MYC</keyword>
</DOC>