<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00542815</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a PIII multi-center, open-label, flexible dose, long-term safety study, that in conjunction with the E07(NCT00416520), E08(NCT00542386) and E09(NCT00451295) studies will allow exposure to MCI-196 for up to 52 weeks</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of MCI-196 in Chronic Kidney Disease Stage V Subjects on Dialysis With Hyperphosphatemia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Following completion of one of the Phase III studies (E07, E08 or E09) eligible patients will receive either MCI-196 for up to 52 weeks. The study is in two periods. The initial period allows flexible dosing for a period of 8 weeks. This will allow subjects to achieve individually optimised doses. After 8 weeks, subjects will continue flexible dosing with MCI-196 but with titration intervals every 4 weeks instead of every 2 weeks. Subjects previously exposed to MCI-196 will end the study at Week 40.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperphosphatemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sevelamer</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinically stable haemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis treatment. Stable phosphate control Stabilised phosphorus diet. female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test. Male subjects must agree to use appropriate contraception. Completed one of the MCI196 PIII studies Current clinically significant medical comorbidities, which may substantially compromise subject safety, or expose them to undue risk, or interfere significantly with study procedures and which, in the opinion of the Investigator, makes the subject unsuitable for inclusion in the study. Body Mass Index (BMI) &lt;= 16.0 kg/m2 or =&gt;40.0 kg/m2. Current or a history of significant gastrointestinal motility problems Positive test for HIV 1 and 2 antibodies. History of substance or alcohol abuse within the last year. Seizure disorders. History of drug or other allergy. Temporary catheter with active signs of inflammation or infection. The subject has participated in a clinical study with any experimental medication (with the exception of MCI196 PIII studies) in the last 30days or experimental biological product within the 90 days prior to signing of informed consent form.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Kidney Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Dialysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperphosphatemia</keyword>
</DOC>