<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02247388</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To study the efficacy of AB-CASI against standard of care in a randomized controlled trial in the Emergency Department.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Automated Bilingual Computerized Alcohol Screening and Intervention in Latinos (AB-CASI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The research team will rigorously test the efficacy of AB-CASI, against a standard condition (SC) in a first-of-a-kind ED randomized controlled trial. Studying an urban adult (≥ 18 y/o) Latino ED population, the objectives are to demonstrate the superiority of AB-CASI compared to SC in: 1) reduction of alcohol consumption (Aims 1), 2) reduction of negative health behaviors and consequences (Aim 2), and 3) increasing 30-day treatment engagement (Aim 3). The investigators will also explore variation of the AB-CASI intervention on alcohol consumption, alcohol-related negative health behaviors and consequences, and 30-day treatment engagement by Latino subpopulations (Puerto-Rican, Mexican-American, Cuban-American, South/Central American) as well as other potential modifiers (age, birthplace, gender, preferred language, reason for ED visit, and smoking status). English and Spanish speaking Latino adults presenting to the Bridgeport Hospital ED will be screened using the study inclusion and exclusion criteria.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>English and Spanish speaking adult ≥ 18 y/o Latino patients who present to the Bridgeport Hospital's ED Drink over the NIAAA lowrisk limits. Primary language other than English or Spanish Current enrollment in an alcohol or substance abuse treatment program Current ED visit for acute psychosis Condition that precludes interview or ABCASI use i.e., life threatening injury/illness In police custody Inability to provide two contact numbers for followup</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alcohol Dependence</keyword>
	<keyword>Alcoholism</keyword>
	<keyword>AB-CASI</keyword>
	<keyword>Emergency Department</keyword>
</DOC>