<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02141074</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted globally. The aim of the trial is to investigate the safety and efficacy of nonacog beta pegol (N9-GP) in previously untreated patients with Haemophilia B.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Nonacog Beta Pegol (N9-GP) in Previously Untreated Patients With Haemophilia B</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Blood Coagulation Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemostatic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent obtained before any trialrelated activities. Trialrelated activities are any procedures that are carried out as part of the trial, including activities to determine suitability for the trial Male, age below 6 years at the time of signing informed consent Patients with the diagnosis of haemophilia B (FIX (coagulation factor IX) activity level below or equal to 2%) based on medical records or central laboratory results Previously untreated or exposed to FIX containing products less than or equal to 3 exposure days (5 previous exposures to blood components is acceptable) Any history of FIX inhibitors (defined by medical records) Known or suspected hypersensitivity to trial product or related products Previous participation in this trial. Participation is defined as first dose administered of trial product Receipt of any investigational medicinal product within 30 days before screening Congenital or acquired coagulation disorder other than haemophilia B Any chronic disorder or severe disease which, in the opinion of the Investigator, might jeopardise the patient's safety or compliance with the protocol Patient's parent(s)/LAR(s) (legally acceptable representative) mental incapacity, unwillingness to cooperate, or a language barrier precluding adequate understanding and cooperation</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>