<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02141126</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim of this research is to evaluate changes in lower limb strength and physical function following six weeks of resistance training and routine physiotherapy versus a control group of routine physiotherapy only in an older inpatient population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lower Limb Resistance Training in Older Inpatients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, single blinded, randomised controlled trial recruiting consecutive appropriate patients in this post-acute rehabilitation unit. There are two groups (i) exercise intervention and (ii) control. It will not be possible to blind the treating physiotherapist or the patient to the exercise intervention; hence the single (assessor) blinded design. The study will be based in St James's Hospital, Dublin. Assessments and the delivery of the exercise intervention will be conducted in the Physiotherapy department. Patients will be recruited in the inpatient setting. Appropriate patients will be approached, and the intervention explained to them. The patient will be given an information leaflet and 24-hours to consider involvement in the study</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Muscle Weakness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paresis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients, male and female elderly inpatients 65 years. Patients must be medically stable. Patients who are able to follow onestage commands. Patients must be able to give informed consent. Unstable medical condition. Patients who are unable to follow onestage commands. Acute pain or fracture Patients who are unable to stand or require more than assistance of two staff to mobilise/transfer. Patients who have been admitted with a recent diagnosis of stroke, due to their varying patterns of recovery.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Older adults</keyword>
	<keyword>Strength training</keyword>
	<keyword>Muscle mass</keyword>
	<keyword>Function</keyword>
	<keyword>Inpatients</keyword>
</DOC>