<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02141048</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether the Parent Centre's Positive Parenting Skills Training (PPST), a parenting programme being delivered in South Africa, is effective in improving parenting, and child behaviour related outcomes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Parent Centre's Positive Parenting Skills Training.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The evaluation of the PPST will assess both the fidelity of the intervention's implementation, as well as the outcomes of the programme in a randomised controlled trial. Programme facilitators and intervention group participants will provide data for the former. For the outcome evaluation, two types of participants will be recruited who will provide self-report data: primary caregivers (n = 80) and where possible another adult living in the home with this primary caregiver and their selected child (n = 60). This "other adult" data will serve to verify the primary caregivers' self-report data. Both participants will provide demographic information, and report on parenting behaviour and child behaviour. Their data will be analysed separately in intention to treat analyses and secondary analyses which consider moderators of programme effectiveness.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Problem Behavior</mesh_term>
	<criteria>This study will include two types of participants: (1) primary caregivers and (2) another adult. Both have separate eligibility criteria. 1. Primary caregivers (the person most responsible for the wellbeing of a child) Has a child between the ages of 512 years Looks after this child for a minimum of four nights a week Indicated interest in the programme and expressed willingness to enrol in the study 2. Another adult in the household (if available) Lives with the index child (selected by the formerly mentioned caregiver) for at least four nights a week (1) Primary Caregiver Has already participated in the Parent Centre's Positive Parenting Skills Training or the Parenting and Leadership Training</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Parenting programme</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomised controlled trial</keyword>
	<keyword>South Africa</keyword>
	<keyword>Positive parenting</keyword>
	<keyword>Child behaviour problems</keyword>
	<keyword>Implementation fidelity</keyword>
	<keyword>Low- and middle-income country</keyword>
</DOC>