<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02248805</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary goal of this Phase 1 study is to characterize the safety and tolerability of MGD007 and establish the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of MGD007 administered on either weekly or every three week schedules of administration among patients with metastatic colorectal carcinoma. Pharmacokinetics, pharmacodynamics, and the anti-tumor activity of MGD007 will also be assessed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 1 Study of MGD007 in Relapsed/Refractory Metastatic Colorectal Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a two-arm open-label, multi-center, Phase 1 dose-escalation study to define a MTD, describe preliminarily safety, and to assess PK, immunogenicity, and potential anti-tumor activity of MGD007 administered on either weekly or every three week schedules in patients with relapsed or refractory metastatic colorectal cancer. In the initial phase of the study, two dose schedules will be assessed in dose escalation, once weekly and once every three weeks administration of single agent MGD007. Following the establishment of an MTD, additional patients will enroll in two separate dose expansion cohorts at that treatment dose and schedule. In all segments of the study, patients who benefit from MGD007 treatment and continue to meet eligibility may continue treatment in Cycles 2 and beyond.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For the dose escalation cohorts, histologicallyproven metastatic colorectal adenocarcinoma that is refractory to 2 prior standard treatment regimens or standard treatment was declined. For the dose expansion cohorts, histologicallyproven metastatic colorectal adenocarcinoma that is refractory to 1 prior standard treatment regimen or standard therapy was declined. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1 Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks Measurable disease Intolerance to at least 2 prior standard therapy regimens Acceptable laboratory parameters Adult (≥18 years old) Known brain metastasis Any prior history of or suspected current autoimmune disorders (with the exception of vitiligo, resolved childhood atopic dermatitis, prior Grave's disease) Prior history of allogeneic bone marrow, stemcell, or solid organ transplantation Prior treatment with checkpoint inhibitors and other immunotherapy treatments, including antiLAG3, antiPD1, antiPDL1 or antiCTLA4 antibodies, if less than 5 half lives before study drug administration Prior history of Grade 3 or greater drugrelated diarrhea/colitis during treatment with checkpoint inhibitors or other immunotherapy treatments. Treatment with any local or systemic antineoplastic therapy or any other investigational agent in the 4 weeks prior to study drug administration Require, at the time of study entry, treatment with steroids &gt; 10 mg/day of oral prednisone (or equivalent), except topical use, steroid inhaler, nasal spray or ophthalmic solution History of clinically significant cardiovascular disease, gastrointestinal disorder, or significant pulmonary compromise. Second primary malignancy that has not been in remission for greater than 3 years, with the exception of nonmelanoma skin cancer, cervical carcinoma in situ,or squamous intraepithelial lesion on PAP smear, localized prostate cancer (Gleason score &lt;6), or resected melanoma in situ.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>colorectal carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV colorectal cancer</keyword>
</DOC>