<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02605759</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To demonstrate the feasibility, safety and efficacy of the CryoBalloon Ablation System for the treatment of esophageal squamous cell dysplasia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Coldplay Cryoablation of Dysplastic Squamous Tissue in Patients With Esophageal Squamous Cell Dysplasia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Multi-center, prospective, single arm, non-randomized study. The study will proceed in two phases: a pilot phase, followed by the feasibility, safety and efficacy phase. In the pilot phase, up to five (5) patients at one (1) site will be treated with the CryoBalloon Ablation System to confirm its safety and feasibility in the treatment of squamous dysplasia. The second phase will be conducted at two (2) centers and will enroll up to 50 subjects to evaluate the feasibility, safety and efficacy of the CryoBalloon Ablation System for the treatment of squamous dysplasia.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>At least one unstained lesion (USL) in the esophagus upon high resolution endoscopy with Lugol's staining Flat (type 0IIb) appearance of the USL Total area of USLs is a maximum longitudinal size of 6cm and covering a maximum of onehalf of the circumference of the esophagus Proven (by histopathological analysis) mediumgrade or highgrade intraepithelial neoplasia (MGIN or HGIN) in at least one USL Older than 18 years of age at time of consent Operable per institution's standards Provides written informed consent on the Ethics Committeeapproved informed consent form Willing and able to comply with study requirements for followup Esophageal stenosis or stricture preventing advancement of a therapeutic endoscope within 4cm of the treatment zone Other USLs containing MGIN, HGIN, or ESSC outside the designated treatment area Any previous ablative therapy in the esophagus (photodynamic therapy, multipolar electrical coagulation, argon plasma coagulation, laser treatment) or any radiation therapy to the esophagus Any previous esophageal surgery (except antireflux surgery) Any cancer (squamous cell or nonsquamous cell) within the previous five (5) years Active inflammation in the treatment zone due to esophageal reflux, as confirmed by endoscopic examination Known history of unresolved drug or alcohol dependency that would limit ability to comprehend or follow instructions related to informed consent, posttreatment instructions or followup guidelines Pregnant or planning to become pregnant during the study followup period Life expectancy ≤2 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>