<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01594632</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A study to assess the contraceptive effectiveness of Sino-implant (II).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety,Effectiveness and Acceptability of Sino-implant II in DR</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Randomized trial to assess the contraceptive effectiveness of Sino-implant (II) and to compare levonorgestrel concentrations, safety and acceptability of Sino-implant (II) and Jadelle.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Contraceptive Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levonorgestrel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>• In good general health Aged between 18 and 44 years, inclusive Not pregnant Not lactating Not wishing to become pregnant in the next five years Request longacting reversible contraception If previously used injectable contraceptives for pregnancy prevention, be more than 9 months since last injection of DepoProvera and more than 3 months after the last injection of a combined injectable contraceptive If previously used LNGcontaining oral pills or implants, be more than 1 week after last hormone intake or implant removal Be able to understand the information provided and to make personal decisions on participation Consent to participation and sign a consent form Agree and be able to return to the clinic for followup visits over five years</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>44 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>AE adverse event</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS acquired immunodeficiency syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>ALT (SGPT) alanine aminotransferase</keyword>
	<keyword>ART antiretroviral therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>AST (SGOT) aspartate aminotransferase</keyword>
	<keyword>DCF data collection forms</keyword>
	<keyword>DMC Data Monitoring Committee</keyword>
	<keyword>FDA (U.S.) Food and Drug Administration</keyword>
	<keyword>GCP Good Clinical Practice guidelines</keyword>
	<keyword>HB sAg Hepatitis B surface antigen</keyword>
	<keyword>ICH International Conference of Harmonization</keyword>
	<keyword>IND Investigational New Drug Application</keyword>
	<keyword>IRB Institutional Review Board</keyword>
	<keyword>IU International units</keyword>
	<keyword>mg milligram(s)</keyword>
	<keyword>mm3 cubic millimeter(s)</keyword>
	<keyword>PCR polymerase chain reaction</keyword>
	<keyword>SAE serious adverse event</keyword>
	<keyword>µg microgram</keyword>
	<keyword>ULN upper limit of the normal range</keyword>
	<keyword>WB Western Blot</keyword>
</DOC>