<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="50302">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02451358</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>QIV06</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>U1111-1143-8370</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>CTRI/2015/05/005770</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02451358</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of a Single Dose or Two Doses of a Quadrivalent Influenza Vaccine in Subjects Aged 6 Months or Older in India</brief_title>
  <official_title>Immunogenicity and Safety of a Single Dose or Two Doses Given 28 Days Apart of a Quadrivalent Influenza Vaccine Administered Via the Intramuscular Route in Subjects Aged 6 Months or Older in India</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sanofi Pasteur, a Sanofi Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sanofi</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the study is to generate immunogenicity and safety data in the whole population
      to support registration of the Quadrivalent Influenza Vaccine (QIV) in India:

      Primary objective:

        -  To describe in each age group the immune response induced by a single injection
           (subjects aged &gt;9 years) or 2 injections (subjects aged 6 months to 8 years) of QIV.

      Secondary objective:

        -  To describe in each age group the safety profile of QIV.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      All participants will be vaccinated with the quadrivalent influenza vaccine (QIV)
      (split-virion, inactivated) Northern Hemisphere (NH) 2014-2015 formulation by the
      intramuscular (IM) route.

      Immunogenicity of the vaccine will be assessed at baseline (Day 0) and 28 days after the
      last injection. Safety data will be collected up to 28 days after each vaccination. Serious
      adverse events (SAEs), including adverse events of special interest (AESIs) will be
      collected throughout the trial.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric mean titers of antibodies to vaccine antigens pre- and post-vaccination with Fluzone Quadrivalent vaccine</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28 post-vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Immunogenicity will be evaluated prior to vaccination and at 28 days after vaccination using the hemagglutination inhibition (HAI) technique. For each vaccine strain, serum HA antibody titers will be expressed as Geometric Mean (GM) of HAI titers obtained in duplicates for pre- (Day 0) and post-vaccination (28 days after the final vaccination).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Seroprotection and seroconversion to vaccine antigens following vaccination with Quadrivalent Inactivated Influenza Vaccine</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28 post-vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Seroprotection is defined as: A titer ≥ 40 (l/dil) at pre-vaccination and at Day 28 after the final vaccination. Seroconversion is defined as: Either a pre-vaccination titer &lt; 10 (1/dil) and a post-vaccination titer ≥ 40 (1/dil), on Day 28 or a pre-vaccination titer ≥ 10 (1/dil) and a ≥ 4-fold increase in post-vaccination titer at Day 28 after the final vaccination.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants reporting solicited injection-site and systemic events and unsolicited adverse events following vaccination with Quadrivalent Inactivated Influenza Vaccine.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 up to 1 month (age 9 years and older) 2 months (Age 6 months to 8 years old participants) post-vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Participants 6 Months to 23 Months of Age Solicited injection-site reactions: Tenderness, Redness, and Swelling; Solicited systemic reactions: Fever (Temperature), Vomiting, Abnormal crying, Drowsiness, Loss of appetite, and Irritability.
Participants age 2 Years and older Solicited injection-site reactions: Pain, Redness, and Swelling; Solicited systemic reactions: Fever (Temperature), Headache, Malaise, Myalgia, and Shivering.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Influenza</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: (Infants, toddlers and children)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants aged 6 to 35 months will receive 2 injections 28 days apart of QIV</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: (Children)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants aged 3 to 8 years will receive 1 injection of QIV</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3: (Adolescents)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants aged 9 to 17 years will receive 1 injection of QIV</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4: (Adults)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants aged 18 years or older will receive 1 injection of QIV</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Quadrivalent Inactivated Influenza Vaccine, No Preservative</intervention_name>
    <description>0.25 mL, Intramuscular (2 injections 28 days apart for participants aged 6 to 35 months )</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: (Infants, toddlers and children)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>QIV, No Preservative</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Quadrivalent Inactivated Influenza Vaccine, No Preservative</intervention_name>
    <description>0.5 mL, Intramuscular</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: (Children)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>QIV, No Preservative</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Quadrivalent Inactivated Influenza Vaccine, No Preservative</intervention_name>
    <description>0.5 mL, Intramuscular (2 injections 28 days apart for participants aged 3 to 8 years)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3: (Adolescents)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>QIV, No Preservative</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Quadrivalent Inactivated Influenza Vaccine, No Preservative</intervention_name>
    <description>0.5 mL, Intramuscular</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4: (Adults)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>QIV, No Preservative</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Aged 6 months or older on the day of inclusion

          -  For subjects aged 6 to 35 months only: born at full term of pregnancy (≥37 weeks) or
             birth weight ≥2.5 kg or both

          -  Informed consent form has been signed and dated by the subjects / subjects' parent(s)
             or another legally acceptable representative and by an independent witness, if
             required by local regulations. For subjects aged 7 to 17 years of age, assent form
             has been signed and dated by the subject.

          -  Subject / subjects' parent/legally acceptable representative are able to attend all
             scheduled visits and to comply with all trial procedures.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Subject is pregnant, or lactating, or of childbearing potential (to be considered of
             non-childbearing potential, a female must be pre-menarche or post-menopausal for at
             least 1 year, surgically sterile, or using an effective method of contraception or
             abstinence from at least 4 weeks prior to vaccination and until at least 4 weeks
             after vaccination)

          -  Participation at the time of study enrollment (or in the 4 weeks preceding the first
             trial vaccination) or planned participation during the present trial period in
             another clinical trial investigating a vaccine, drug, medical device, or medical
             procedure

          -  Receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks preceding the first trial vaccination or
             planned receipt of any vaccine in the 4 weeks following any trial vaccination (except
             oral poliomyelitis vaccine (OPV) received during national immunization days)

          -  For subjects aged 9 years or older only: previous vaccination against influenza (in
             the previous 6 months) with either the trial vaccine or another vaccine

          -  For subjects aged 6 months to 8 years only: previous priming with any influenza
             vaccine (i.e., subjects who received two doses last influenza season or one or more
             doses at any time before last season)

          -  Receipt of immune globulins, blood or blood-derived products in the past 3 months

          -  Known or suspected congenital or acquired immunodeficiency; or receipt of
             immunosuppressive therapy, such as anti-cancer chemotherapy or radiation therapy,
             within the preceding 6 months; or long-term systemic corticosteroid therapy
             (prednisone or equivalent for more than 2 consecutive weeks within the past 3 months)

          -  Self-reported history of seropositivity for Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV),
             Hepatitis B, or Hepatitis C, after questioning

          -  Known systemic hypersensitivity to any of the vaccine components, or history of a
             life-threatening reaction to the vaccine(s) used in the trial or to a vaccine
             containing any of the same substances

          -  Self-reported thrombocytopenia or as reported by the parent/legally acceptable
             representative, contraindicating intramuscular (IM) vaccination

          -  Bleeding disorder, or receipt of anticoagulants in the 3 weeks preceding inclusion,
             contraindicating IM vaccination

          -  Deprived of freedom by an administrative or court order, or in an emergency setting,
             or hospitalized involuntarily

          -  For subjects aged 9 years or older only: current alcohol abuse or drug addiction

          -  Chronic illness that, in the opinion of the investigator, is at a stage where it
             might interfere with trial conduct or completion

          -  Moderate or severe acute illness/infection (according to investigator judgment) on
             the day of vaccination or febrile illness (axillary temperature ≥ 38.0°C). A
             prospective subject should not be included in the study until the condition has
             resolved or the febrile event has subsided

          -  Identified as an Investigator or employee of the Investigator or study center with
             direct involvement in the proposed study, or identified as an immediate family member
             (i.e., parent, spouse, natural or adopted child) of the Investigator or employee with
             direct involvement in the proposed study.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Sanofi Pasteur SA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <email>RegistryContactUs@sanofipasteur.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Vadodara</city>
        <state>Gujarat</state>
        <zip>390001</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Mandya</city>
        <state>Karnataka</state>
        <zip>571401</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Pune</city>
        <state>Maharashtra</state>
        <zip>411043</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Mumbai</city>
        <state>Parel</state>
        <zip>400012</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Pimpri</city>
        <state>Pune</state>
        <zip>411018</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Ludhiana</city>
        <state>Punjab</state>
        <zip>141008</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Kolkata</city>
        <state>West Bengal</state>
        <zip>700017</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Bangalore</city>
        <zip>560054</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.sanofipasteur.com</url>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.sanofi.com</url>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>August 9, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 14, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Influenza</keyword>
  <keyword>Quadrivalent Inactivated Influenza Vaccine (QIV)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
