<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00671515</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to begin to test whether or not pioglitazone, an FDA approved medication used to treat high blood sugar, may be safe and effective in treating Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) in patients with comorbid Metabolic Syndrome (METSYN).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pioglitazone for the Treatment of Major Depressive Disorder Comorbid With Metabolic Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pioglitazone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Be male or female between the ages of 18 and 70 DSMIV diagnosis of major depressive disorder Currently depressed as confirmed by the MINIPlus at the screening visit Quick Inventory of Depressive SymptomatologySelfReport(QIDSSR) score &gt; 11 at study baseline Meets criteria for the metabolic syndrome as defined by the NCEP ATP III criteria Pregnancy or breast feeding Unstable or inadequately treated medical illness as judged by the investigator Severe personality disorder Serious suicidal risk as judged by the investigator or having a score &gt; 2 on item 18 of the Inventory of Depressive SymptomatologyClinician Rated (IDSCR) scale Known history of intolerance or hypersensitivity to pioglitazone Treatment with pioglitazone in the 3 months prior to randomization Currently taking an antidiabetic/glucoselowering agent. Antidiabetic agents that are prohibited include insulin, rosiglitazone, metformin, sitagliptin, sulfonylureas (e.g. glyburide, glipizide, glimepiride), nonsulfonylurea secretagogues (e.g. repaglinide, nateglinide), incretins (e.g. exenatide), and αglucosidase inhibitors (e.g. acarbose, miglitol). Diagnosed with dementia Diagnosed with heart failure Transaminase elevation &gt;2.5 times the upper limit of normal Presence of renal impairment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Depressive Disorder, Major</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic Syndrome X</keyword>
	<keyword>pioglitazone</keyword>
</DOC>