<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02016430</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Our group has recently identified the association between gut-flora-mediated carnitine and phosphatidylcholine metabolism, specifically trimethylamine-N-oxide (TMAO), and cardiovascular risk. This study investigates the ability for dietary intervention to modulate TMAO levels.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gut Flora Metabolite Reduction After Dietary Intervention (GRADY)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a pilot human study to characterize the relationship between gut flora-associated TMAO generation and dietary intervention. The investigators hypothesize that tailored dietary interventions may help to reduce the ability for gut flora to generate TMAO in individuals with elevated TMAO levels. Specific aims include: 1. To investigate the proportion of subjects with persistently elevated circulating TMAO levels. 2. To compare the amount of TMAO generated from gut flora using stable-isotope-labelled choline, carnitine, and betaine in subjects with elevated versus normal circulating TMAO levels. 3. To evaluate the effect of dietary interventions on the amount of TMAO generated from gut flora using stable-isotope-labelled choline, carnitine, and betaine in subjects with elevated circulating TMAO levels.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Men and women age 18 years or above. Elevated TMAO metabolizers (&gt;5 µM) based on screening test. Willing to remain on aspirin or able to be off aspirin or aspirin products for 1 week prior to starting study and staying on the same aspirin regimen during the duration of the 12week study. Willing to sign consent form or to follow study protocol, which includes 12week dietary modification. Significant chronic illness or endorgan dysfunction, including known history of uncompensated heart failure, renal failure, pulmonary disease, hematologic diseases. Active infection or received antibiotics within 2 months of study enrollment Use of overthecounter probiotic within past month, or ingestion of yogurt within past 7 days Having undergone bariatric procedures or surgeries such as gastric banding or bypass. Pregnancy. Any condition which, in the judgment of the Investigator, would place a patient at undue risk by being enrolled in the trial, or cause inability to comply with the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>TMAO</keyword>
	<keyword>Gut Flora</keyword>
	<keyword>Dietary Intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Choline</keyword>
	<keyword>Carnitine</keyword>
</DOC>