<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00270621</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the Strongest Families (formerly Family Help Program)is to evaluate the effectiveness of the Strongest Families distance intervention compared to usual or standard care that is typically provided to children with mild to moderate Enuresis diagnoses. This is a single-centre trial based at the IWK Health Centre. The primary outcome is change in diagnosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Family Help Program: Nighttime Enuresis Treatment Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of the Family Help Program is to deliver, primary care mental health services to children and their families in the comfort and privacy of their own home. Approximately 46 children (5-12 years of age)suffering from pediatric enuresis (at least 2 times a week) will be randomized. The intervention is delivered from a distance, using the urine alarm system accompanied by educational materials (manuals, video-tapes, audio-tapes) and telephone consultation with a trained paraprofessional "coach" who is supervised by a licensed health care professional. The telephone coach delivers consistent care based on written protocols, with on-going evaluation by a professional team. Fifty percent of the eligible participants will receive Family Help Program telephone-based treatment and 50% will be referred back to their family physician to receive standard care as determined by that physician. Those receiving standard care will be evaluated for outcome results and then compared to the Family Help treated participants. It is anticipated that Family Help treatment will be proven to be as or more effective than standard care.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Enuresis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nocturnal Enuresis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Is your child 3 to 12 years of age child wets the bed more than twice per week child dry during the day child received any treatment for bedwetting in the past 6 months child at any time been dry for 6 months or longer child currently on Imipramine or Desmopressin</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>