<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02567201</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Aim : To assess the ability of healthy subjects and patients with a severe motor disability to voluntary control their attention Material and Methods: Population: healthy subjects, patients with brain injury Electroencephalographic study to research attentional modulation during different kind of stimulation (visual, auditory, tactile) Sudy 1: passive recording. Study 2: active recording (instruction of attentional control given to the subject). Study 3: active recording with a feedback obtained after a processing of the brain activity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Electrophysiological Evaluation of Voluntary Attention</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria for patients : Adults, man or woman, left or righthanded, from 18 years old to 80 yearsold ; Diagnosis : Lockedin syndrome : &lt; Brainstem injury, without any evolution for at least 1 month, etiology : vascular, traumatic &lt; Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Or Minimal conscious state or Unresponsive Wakefulness Syndrome consecutive to a severe acquired brain injury for at least one month Or with a severe brain injury, since birth or acquired, for at least one month Subjects affiliated to social security; Signature of consent form by the patient or by a relative (family member or "the trusted person") if obtaining a consent is impossible Inclusion criteria of Healthy subjects Adults, man or woman, left or righthanded, from 18 years old to 80 yearsold ; Without known auditory impairment Subjects able to understand the experimental instructions Subjects affiliated to social security; Signature of consent form Exclusion criteria of patients and healthy subjects Medical history : psychiatric disorders (except if due to brain injury), neurologic disorders (except if due to brain injury) For healthy subjects : history of brain injury Pregnant women or breastfeeding women Person under legal protection Medicolegal conflicts Absence of consent by the subject or the patient or his/her representant</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Voluntary attention</keyword>
	<keyword>Electroencephalogram</keyword>
	<keyword>Brain-computer interface</keyword>
	<keyword>Disorders of consciousness</keyword>
</DOC>