<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01691209</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study shall explore whether treatment of atopic dermatitis is equally effective with Phoenix medical device as compared to standard therapy (Hydrocortisone cream).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy/Safety Study to Explore a New Topical Formulation in Atopic Dermatitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis, Atopic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eczema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrocortisone 17-butyrate 21-propionate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cortisol succinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrocortisone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrocortisone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female Caucasians aged between 18 and 60 years Patients with mild atopic dermatitis (AD) presenting a scoring AD (SCORAD) rating below 50 Skin type I IV according to Fitzpatrick Acute AD symptoms on each assessment areas (local SCORAD ≥ 3 and &lt;= 12) at Baseline Acute symptom of pruritus at Baseline Any other skin disease at the test area that would interfere with the clinical assessment in the opinion of the investigator Moles, tattoos, strong pigmentation, or scars at the test area that would interfere with the clinical assessment Regular intake of antiphlogistic drugs (for example nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs [NSAIDs]) Any condition or treatment which might influence the trial (e.g. any treatment with topical antibiotics, antifungals, or corticoids) within 14 days prior to screening as well as during the trial (exception: topical treatment of AD lesions other than the test areas (for example, face) with low potency steroids restricted to small areas) UVtherapy or the use of solarium within 30 days before screening as well as during the trial Any alternative treatment of AD (e.g. acupuncture, kinesiology, and homoeopathy) within 30 days before screening as well as during the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Phoenix</keyword>
	<keyword>Hydrocortison</keyword>
	<keyword>mild atopic dermatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
</DOC>