<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02205216</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Freezing of gait in Parkinson's disease (PD) is a major cause of disability and falls and responds often incompletely to conventional therapy. The pathogenesis remains largely unknown and therapeutic alternatives are needed. Rehabilitative interventions that consist of learning cognitive strategies with sensory cueing to prevent and to overcome FOG represent the most efficacious intervention, but difficulties in learning and execution of these cognitive strategies are the main cause of failure. Transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) enhances motor task learning and execution in patients with PD and might enhance the efficacy of rehabilitative interventions. This study intends to address the following question whether tDCS can enhance the efficacy of rehabilitative interventions in the treatment of freezing of gait in Parkinson's disease?</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Can tDCS Enhance Efficacy of Rehabilitative Intervention for Freezing of Gait in Parkinson's Disease?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>men and women aged 30 to 80 years with DOPAresponsive PD Hoehn and Yahr (HY) grade of 2 to 4 while "off" must be on a regimen including levodopa total dose of levodopa and dopamine agonists (using dopamine equivalents) has to be equal to or more than 300 milligrams per day Gait difficulties with Freezing of Gait as defined by MDSUPDRS I score ≥ 2 in FOG Optimal conventional PD medication for &gt; 1 month prior to screening scheduled for rehabilitative intervention for the treatment of freezing of gait significant concurrent medical or psychiatric disease history of seizures and epilepsy Dementia or other neurodegenerative disease (besides PD) pallidotomy, implanted electrodes and generator for deep brain stimulation pregnancy surgically or traumatically implanted foreign bodies such as an implanted medical pump, implanted hearing aids, metal plate in the skull, or metal implant in the skull or eyes (other than dental appliances or fillings) that may pose a physical hazard during tDCS. Study would cause undue risk or stress for reasons such as tendency to fall, excessive fatigue, general frailty, or excessive apprehensiveness. significant postural instability with daily falls, inability to walk the parcours or inability to walk 10 meters. presence of significant cognitive dysfunction as determined by Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MOCA) &lt;20 or mentally impaired patients having no capacity to provide their own consent (the physician establishing the diagnosis and applying UPDRS will evaluate patient's mental capacity using conventional clinical interview). presence of other comorbid conditions that can contribute to gait dysfunction (orthopedic, rheumatologic, cardiac, other) presence of clinically significant hallucinations participation in any rehabilitation therapy for FOG within the last six months prior to screening</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>tDCS</keyword>
	<keyword>FOG</keyword>
	<keyword>Freezing of Gait</keyword>
	<keyword>Parkinson</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehabilitation</keyword>
</DOC>