<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00935597</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess preliminary efficacy and to determine the safety and feasibility of ex vivo generated dendritic cell (HDC) infusion with and without donor lymphocyte infusion (DLI) after allogeneic stem cell transplant (SCT). We also wish to establish the feasibility of apheresis shipment as well as vaccine shipment and stability in the population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Host Dendritic Cells in Allograft Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 1870 Ability to sign informed consent ECOG performance status ≤3 Life expectancy &gt; 6 months Adequate cardiac function: MUGA or Echocardiogram demonstrating &gt;50% Ejection Fraction Adequate pulmonary function with DLCO &gt; 50% Adequate hepatic function Bilirubin ≤ 1.5mg/dl Alkaline phosphatase ≤5 times the upper limit of normal Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or serum glutamicoxaloacetic transferase (SGOT) ≤ 3 times the upper limit of normal Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase (SGPT) ≤ 3 times the upper limit of normal Adequate renal function Estimated creatinine clearance &gt; 40ml/min Diagnosis of one of the following NonHodgkin's lymphoma excluding Follicular lymphoma and Marginal Zone Lymphoma Hodgkin's lymphoma Multiple myeloma Chronic lymphocytic leukemia Eligible for allogeneic stem cell transplant with identified HLAidentical sibling (6/6 HLA match) or volunteer unrelated donor (8/8 allele HLAmatched (A, B, Cw, DRB1) Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test prior to enrollment Women of childbearing potential must use effective means of birth control throughout the study. Men should not father a child while enrolled in the study. Effective means of birth control include condom, vasectomy or abstinence. Malignancies other than melanoma within five years of study entry, except carcinoma insitu of the cervix or basal/squamous cell skin cancers Concurrent illnesses that would preclude survival &gt; 6 months other than the disease under study Pregnancy or nursing HIV infection Treatment with prior donor lymphocyte infusion Prior allogeneic stem cell transplant History of autoimmune diseases including systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis and thyroiditis Active infections including fungal infections and viral hepatitis GVHD greater than grade I GVHD of the skin Patient Exclusion Criteria for Part B (post Stem Cell Transplant) Malignancies other than melanoma within five years of study entry, except carcinoma insitu of the cervix or basal/squamous cell skin cancers Concurrent illnesses that would preclude survival &gt; 6 months other than the disease under study. Pregnancy or nursing HIV infection Treatment with prior donor lymphocyte infusion Prior allogeneic stem cell transplant More than 4 prior relapses History of autoimmune diseases including systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis and thyroiditis Active infections including fungal infections and viral hepatitis GVHD greater than grade I GVHD of the skin No cytotoxics will be given within 4 weeks of administration of the investigational cell therapy Patients cannot receive any investigational agents within 30 days prior to administration of the investigational cell therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Relapsed Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Hodgkin's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Lymphocytic Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Relapsed Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma (excluding follicular lymphoma and marginal zone lymphoma)</keyword>
</DOC>