<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02102113</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall purpose of this study is to determine whether a family history of psychosis is associated with an altered cannabinoid system. This will be tested by studying individuals with and without a family history of psychosis and comparing their responses to delta 9-tetrahydrocannabinol (THC), a probe of the cannabinoid system. We hypothesize, that compared to controls with no family history of psychoses, individuals with a family history of psychoses will have an altered response to THC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Probing the Cannabinoid System in Individuals With a Family History of Psychosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dronabinol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria FHP: Exposure to cannabis at least once in their lifetime Medically and psychiatrically healthy based on screening Having one relative with a confirmed psychotic disorder Exclusion Criteria FHP: Current or lifetime major DSMIV Axis I disorder Current or lifetime treatment (at least 6 months) with psychotropic medications for major psychiatric or neurological illness Major or unstable medical illness that might impact safety of the subject in the study Cannabis naive IQ less than 85 Less than a high school diploma or its educational equivalent Pregnancy or lactation Major current or recent (&lt;6 weeks) psychosocial stressors. Inclusion Criteria FHN : Exposure to cannabis at least once in their lifetime Medically and psychiatrically healthy based on screening Exclusion Criteria FHN: Having a family member with psychosis Current or lifetime major DSMIV Axis I disorder Current or lifetime treatment (at least 6 months) with psychotropic medications for major psychiatric or neurological illness Major or unstable medical illness that might impact safety of the subject in the study Cannabis naive IQ less than 85 Less than a high school diploma or its educational equivalent Pregnancy or lactation Major current or recent (&lt;6 weeks) psychosocial stressors.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>