<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02357368</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective cohort study focusing on HIV negative women. The investigators want to learn how the following types of contraceptive methods: Depot medroxyprogesterone acetate (DMPA), Etonogestrel impant (Eng-Implant) and Levonorgestrel intrauterine device (Lng-IUD) impacts the vaginal immune environment</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Hormonal Contraception on HIV Acquisition and Transmission Risk</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The three proposed aims will evaluate the effect of three contraceptive methods: Depot medroxyprogesterone acetate (DMPA), Etonogestrel impant (Eng-Implant) and Levonorgestrel intrauterine device (Lng-IUD) on: (1) HIV target immune cells within the female genital mucosa; (2) markers of T-cell activation and trafficking within the female genital mucosa; and (3) secreted cytokines and chemokines within the female genital mucosa.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Medroxyprogesterone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levonorgestrel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Medroxyprogesterone Acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etonogestrel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female Age 1845 years Normal menses (2235 day intervals) for at least 3 cycles Intact uterus and cervix Interested in to DMPA, EngImplant or LngIUD Willing to delay initiation of hormonal contraception for up to 1 month Willing to use condoms or abstain from sexual intercourse for at least 48 hours before each genital tract sampling (condoms will be made available) Able and willing to provide informed consent, and undergo serial blood and CVL sampling Negative HIV screening. Pregnant within the last 3 months Breastfeeding History of loop electrosurgical excision procedure, conization, or cryosurgery within the past year Use of hormonal contraception or IUD in the past 6 months or, Known history of medical condition that would interfere with the conduct of the study Symptomatic vaginal infection or genital ulcer disease at screening Taking medications that interact with selected contraceptive Contraindications to selected contraceptive per the CDC medical eligibility criteria(67) or judgment of clinician.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV-negative</keyword>
</DOC>