<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02357290</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Children between the ages of 5-17 years old who have or display symptoms of emotional dysregulation (explosiveness, mood swings, irritability, and/or violent behavior) are invited to participate in a 12-week research study to determine the effectiveness and safety of the natural treatment N-acetylcysteine (NAC) for children with emotional and behavioral problems. After undergoing a comprehensive evaluation by medical doctors with a specialty in this area, children who are found eligible to participate in this research study will be treated with NAC. Following the evaluation period, this research study requires 12 weekly visits, either in our office or over the phone, in an effort to closely monitor each child's response to the medication. Eligible participants will receive study-related evaluations and weekly study visits with our study doctors at no cost.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-Label Study of N-Acetylcysteine in Children and Adolescents 5-17 With Bipolar Spectrum Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This will be a 12-week, open-label study of NAC in the treatment of bipolar disorder in children and adolescents. Subjects will include youth ages 5-17 years with a bipolar spectrum disorder (type I, II, or NOS), mixed, manic, or hypomanic state, according to the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, Fifth Edition DSM-5 (American Psychiatric Association, 2013). The primary outcome measures will be improvement in manic symptoms as measured by the Young Mania Rating Scale (YMRS) and improvement in depressive symptoms as measured by the Child Depression Rating Scale (CDRS). Bipolar diagnoses will be made according to the DSM-5 in a clinical evaluation by a Child Psychiatrist and confirmed using the Schedule for Affective Disorders and Schizophrenia for School-Age Children - Epidemiological Version (K-SADS-E)(Orvaschel, 1994). All subjects must have a YMRS score of at least 20. Only patients who are not responding to their current treatment regimen will be tapered from their medications; youth on concomitant psychiatric medications will be permitted to continue those medications as listed in the concomitant medication section.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acetylcysteine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>N-monoacetylcystine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female subjects, 517 years of age Subjects must have a DSMIV diagnosis of a bipolar spectrum disorder (type I, II, or Not Otherwise Specified) and currently display mixed, manic, or hypomanic symptoms (without psychotic features) according to clinical assessment based on the DSMIV and confirmed with structured diagnostic interview Subjects and their legal representative must have a level of understanding sufficient to communicate intelligently with the investigator and study coordinator and to cooperate with all tests and examinations required by the protocol Subjects and their legal representatives must be considered reliable. Each subject and his/her authorized legal representative must understand the nature of the study. The subject's authorized legal representative must provide written consent and the subject must provide written assent. Subjects must have an initial score on the YMRS of at least 20. Investigator and his/her immediate family (defined as the investigator's spouse, parent, child, grandparent, or grandchild) Serious or unstable illness including hepatic, rental, gastroenterological, respiratory, cardiovascular (including ischemic heart disease), endocrinologic, neurologic, immunologic, or hematologic disease Uncorrected hypothyroidism or hyperthyroidism History of sensitivity to Nacetylcysteine, a history of intolerance to Nacetylcysteine, or a nonresponder after 2 months of treatment at adequate doses as determined by the clinician Severe allergies or multiple adverse drug reactions Current or past history of seizures Current DSMIV substance use, abuse, or dependence Judged clinically to be at serious suicidal risk Current diagnosis of schizophrenia Pregnancy CSSRS score ≥ 4 IQ &lt; 70</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>mania</keyword>
	<keyword>temper tantrum</keyword>
	<keyword>irritability</keyword>
	<keyword>mood</keyword>
	<keyword>bipolar</keyword>
</DOC>