<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02300298</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To determine the appropriateness of the dose of nintedanib 200 mg b.i.d. plus docetaxel 75 mg/m2 as starting dose by evaluating the safety in Japanese patients with body surface area (BSA) &lt;1.5 m2 and locally advanced or metastatic adenocarcinoma subtype non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) after failure of first line platinum- based chemotherapy</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nintedanib Plus Docetaxel in Japanese Patients With Adenocarcinoma Subtype Non-small Cell Lung Cancer After Failure of First Line Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nintedanib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 1. Patients aged 20 years or older at the date of informed consent 2. Patients with BSA&lt;1.5 m2 at screening 3. Patients with histologically/cytologically confirmed locally advanced or metastatic adenocarcinoma subtype NSCLC after failure of first line platinumbased chemotherapy (patients with nontarget lesion only are eligible) First line chemotherapy may include continuation or switch maintenance therapy. One prior adjuvant and/or neoadjuvant chemotherapy is accepted. 4. Patients who have life expectancy of at least 3 months 5. Patients who are Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) of 0 or 1 at screening 6. Patients obtained written informed consent in accordance with ICHGCP and Japanese GCP Exclusion criteria: 1. Patients who have received more than one prior line of chemotherapy (i.e., second or third line chemotherapy) for advanced or metastatic NSCLC (Prior monotherapies with an epidermal growth factor receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitors [EGFRTKI]) or anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK) inhibitor can be allowed) 2. Patients who have received previous therapy with other vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) or vascular endothelial growth factor receptor (VEGFR) inhibitors (other than bevacizumab) for the treatment of NSCLC at any time 3. Patients who have received following treatments within 4 weeks prior to start of study therapy 1) Other investigational drugs 2) Chemo, hormone, immunotherapy, or monoclonal antibody. 4. Patients who have received molecular target therapy including EGFR TKIs and ALK inhibitors within 2 weeks prior to start of study therapy 5. Patents who have received radiotherapy within the past 3 months (in the case of limited field [e.g. brain or bone metastasis] radiotherapy with palliative intent), within 2 weeks) prior to start of study therapy 6. Patients who not recovered clinically relevant therapy related toxicities from previous chemotherapy and/or radiotherapy (=CTCAE grade 2 AE from previous treatment) at screening further exclusion criteria may be applied</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>