<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02529020</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The latest findings on the ergogenic effects of a dentistry-design, bite-aligning mouthpiece require additional research to assess its impact on anaerobic ability and ventilatory parameters. This study was aimed at determining the ergogenic acute effects of wearing a custom-made mouthpiece on oral airflow dynamics, Wingate Test performance parameters.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Jaw Clenching on Anaerobic Ability and Ventilatory Flows</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objectives of this study are to investigate the acute effects of a customized, bite-aligning mouthpiece on the different parameters assessed during a Wingate Test, as compared to clenching the jaw without a mouthpiece, in a physically-active, male population. The study also investigate the influence of wearing a mouthpiece on non-forced and forced airflow dynamics, as compared to open mouth and a jaw clenching without mouthpiece. Mouthpieces are made using a new scanning method that simplified the fitting process and lowered its cost. A nonrandomized study was designed to compare the effect of the occlusion condition on the anaerobic power and airflow dynamics. Conditions of wearing or not wearing mouthguard (MOUTHG and NO-MOUTHG, respectively) are randomly distributed in all tests. Each subject participate in three sessions. The first session is used to obtain informed consent assess anthropometric measurements and to scan the subject's mouth structure. In the second session, subjects are familiarized with the test protocols via a learning session that included demonstration of Wingate Test and the airflow dynamics measurements. Subjects also perform the airflow tests and the first Wingate Test trial. In the third session, subjects perform the second Wingate Test trial. Conditions are randomly distributed in all tests. Wingate Test trials were separated by three days and subjects were not allowed to perform intensive training workloads.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Mouth Breathing</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy physical active males Acute or chronic injury that caused pain during testing procedures Temporomandibular joint disorders</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>mouthguard</keyword>
	<keyword>ventilation</keyword>
	<keyword>anaerobic power</keyword>
	<keyword>ergogenic effects</keyword>
</DOC>