<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01374100</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cancer patients face a number of symptoms related to treatment or disease which may impair quality of life, such as decreased functional capacity, fatigue, nausea an vomiting, distress, depression and unmet psychological needs. Due to this array of symptoms, cancer patients often seek supportive complementary and alternative medicine, which many patients use along with conventional treatments. Qigong, a type traditional chinese medicine, is a mind-body exercise that combines meditation, slow physical movements, and controlled breathing. The investigators hypothesise that Qigong therapy is better in the reduction of anxiety and depression levels and the improvement of quality of life in patients with lung and gastrointestinal (GI) cancer who are eligible for anti-cancer treatment, when compared to standard exercise training.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Qigong Therapy in Patients With Advanced Lung and Gastrointestinal Cancer Undergoing Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>As per summary above</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. A pathologically (histological or cytological) confirmed clinical diagnosis of nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC) or GI cancer 2. Stage 3 or 4 disease and eligible for anticancer treatment 3. Performance status (PS) of 0 2 as determined by the Eastern Cooperative Oncology GroupPerformance Status 4. Life expectancy estimated at &gt; 4 months 5. Age 18 years or older 6. Willing and able to provide informed consent 7. Must be approved for participation by the oncology treatment team 8. Able to communicate in French or English 1. Contraindication to exercise as determined by the oncology treatment team 2. Severe cardiac or neuromuscular/skeletal disease 3. Engaging in interventions to address anxiety or depressive symptoms 4. Brain metastases 5. Active psychiatric conditions 6. Pregnant or breastfeeding mothers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Qigong</keyword>
	<keyword>Complementary Medicine</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Traditional Chinese Medicine</keyword>
	<keyword>Meditation</keyword>
	<keyword>Standard Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Advanced cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
	<keyword>Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale</keyword>
	<keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer Nutrition-Rehabilitation Program</keyword>
	<keyword>Edmonton Symptom Assessment Scale</keyword>
	<keyword>Simmonds Functional Assessment</keyword>
</DOC>