<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01374984</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a post-marketing study to verify the clinical benefits of VIGIV [CNJ-016, Vaccinia Immune Globulin Intravenous (Human), sterile solution] in the resolution of complications resulting from smallpox vaccination in eligible patients treated with VIGIV.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>VA-005 Clinical Outcomes of VIGIV Treatment of Smallpox Vaccination Complications or Vaccinia Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label Phase 4 study designed to collect additional data to assess the safety and efficacy of VIGIV [CNJ-016, Vaccinia Immune Globulin Intravenous (Human), sterile solution] in the first 100 consented patients treated with VIGIV.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vaccinia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Smallpox</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>gamma-Globulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rho(D) Immune Globulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects treated with VIGIV deployed from the US Strategic National Stockpile for any of the following conditions: Eczema vaccinatum. Progressive vaccinia. Severe generalized vaccinia. Vaccinia infections in individuals who have skin conditions such as burns, impetigo, varicellazoster, or poison ivy, or in individuals who have eczematous skin lesions because of either the activity or extensiveness of such lesions. Aberrant infections induced by vaccinia virus that include its accidental implantation in eyes (except in cases of isolated keratitis), mouth, or other areas where vaccinia infection would constitute a special hazard. Informed consent voluntarily signed by subject, legal guardian or representative to participate in the study. For minors, the informed consent form must be signed by a legally acceptable representative and when appropriate, informed consent/assent must also be obtained from the minor.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>smallpox</keyword>
	<keyword>vaccination</keyword>
	<keyword>complications</keyword>
</DOC>