<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02906020</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objectives: - Part 1: To determine the safety and tolerability of GZ/SAR402671 administered orally, as compared to placebo in patients with early-stage Parkinson's disease (PD) carrying a GBA mutation or other pre-specified variants. - Part 2: To determine the efficacy of GZ/SAR402671 administered orally daily, as compared to placebo in patients with early-stage Parkinson's disease carrying a GBA mutation or other pre-specified variants. Secondary Objectives: Part 1: - To assess the pharmacokinetic (PK) profile of oral dosing of GZ/SAR4027671 in plasma when administered in early-stage Parkinson's disease patients carrying a GBA mutation. - To assess the exposure of GZ/SAR402671 in cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) when administered in early-stage Parkinson's disease patients carrying a GBA mutation. Part 2: - To demonstrate overall safety and tolerability of GZ/SAR4027671 administered orally in early-stage Parkinson's disease patients carrying a GBA mutation as compared to placebo. - To assess the pharmacodynamic response to daily oral dosing of GZ/SAR402671 in plasma and CSF as measured by glucosylceramide (GL-1) when administered in early-stage Parkinson's disease patients carrying a GBA mutation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Global Study to Assess the Drug Dynamics, Efficacy, and Safety of GZ/SAR402671 in Parkinson's Disease Patients Carrying a Glucocerebrosidase (GBA) Gene Mutation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The total study duration per subject in Part 2 will be approximately 168 weeks that will consist of 6.5 weeks of screening period, 52 weeks of treatment period, 104 weeks of follow-up period, and 6 weeks of post-treatment observation period. Part 1 maximal treatment duration will be up to 48 weeks in Japan, and up to 64 weeks outside Japan.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria : Male and female adults with a diagnosis of PD and who are heterozygous carriers of a GBA mutation associated with PD or patients carrying known sequence variants associated with GBAPD (such as E326K), in addition to have a diagnosis of PD (with at least 2 of the following signs: resting tremor, postural instability, akinesia/hypokinesia or muscle rigidity), must have rapid eye movement (REM) sleep behavior disorder (RBD) confirmed by historically documented polysomnography or by questionnaire. Age ≥18 years to 70 years inclusive at the time of informed consent signing (for Japanese patients only: Age ≥20 years to 70 years, inclusive, at the time of signing the informed consent. Note: Japanese patients refers only to Japanese patients enrolled and living in Japan). Has symptoms of PD ≥2 years. Hoehn and Yahr (H and Y) stage of 2 or lower at baseline; for patients on a stable dose of PI medication, this should be done in the "ON" state. Stable medication regimen of PD drugs for at least 30 days (at least 60 days for rasagiline) prior to randomization. The patient is willing to abstain from grapefruit containing products for 72 hours prior to administration of the first dose of GZ/SAR402671 and for duration of the entire treatment period (Periods 2 and 3). Signed written consent. Exclusion criteria: Parkinsonism due to drug(s) or toxin(s). Patients carrying mutations in genes other than GBA that have been associated with an increased risk for PD, specifically LRKK2 (G2019S). Patients with Gaucher disease (GD), defined by the presence of 2 mutated GBA alleles. Montreal Cognitive Assessment score &lt;20 at Screening Visit. Patients with prior surgical history of deep brain stimulation (DBS). Patients with baseline brain MRI without contrast showing a structural abnormality that is a possible cause of their PD signs or symptoms. Hepatic insufficiency with liver function tests (LFT) &gt;2 times upper limit of normal at Screening Visit. The patient has prior known positive result on any of the following tests: hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), antihepatitis C virus (antiHCV) antibodies, antihuman immunodeficiency virus 1 and 2 antibodies (antiHIV 1 and antiHIV 2 Ab). Patients with a positive hepatitis B surface antibody (HBsAb) test with a history of prior hepatitis B immunization are eligible if other criteria are met (ie, negative tests for : HBsAg, hepatitis B core antibody [HBcAb],and hepatitis C [HCVAb]. Renal insufficiency as defined by creatine &gt;1.5 times normal at Screening Visit. The patient has received strong or moderate inducers or inhibitors of CYP3A4 within 30 days or 5 halflives from screening, whichever is longer, prior to randomization. The patient has, according to World Health Organization (WHO) Grading, a cortical cataract &gt; onequarter the lens circumference (grade cortical cataract2 [COR2]) or a posterior subcapsular cataract &gt;2 mm (grade posterior subscapsular cataract [PSC2]). Patient with nuclear cataracts will not be excluded. The patient is currently receiving potentially cataractogenic medications, including chronic regimen (more frequently than every 2 weeks) of any dose or route of corticosteroids or any medication that can cause cataract, according to the prescribing information. If female, pregnancy (defined as positive betahuman chorionic gonadotrophin [BetaHCG] blood test) or lactating or breastfeeding. Any medical disorders that, in the opinion of the Investigator, could interfere with studyrelated procedures. This includes condition(s) that preclude the safety performance of routine lumbar punctures, such as prohibitive spinal diseases, bleeding diasthesis, or clinically significant coagulopathy or thrombocytopenia. Current participation in another investigational interventional study. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>