<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02906241</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research has the overall goal of increasing rates at which African American and White men with prostate cancer make an informed decision to participate in a cancer clinical trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PACCT: Partnering Around Cancer Clinical Trials</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This research utilizes two distinct research designs to evaluate two separate behavioral interventions. The first is a between-subject randomized controlled trial to evaluate a patient-focused intervention. The intervention consists of a booklet designed to encourage patients to view themselves as part of the patient-physician team and to participate actively in clinical interactions by asking questions and stating concerns. The second is a within-subject interrupted time series design to evaluate a physician-focused intervention. The intervention is an educational module and email reminders designed to encourage physicians to discuss trials with all eligible patients using patient-centered communication.In the patient-focused intervention, patients are randomized to an intervention or usual care group, and comparison of outcomes is made between groups.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Physician participants Inclusion criteria: Treat patients with prostate cancer Able to recruit patients to clinical trials Exclusion criteria: Do not treat patients with prostate cancer Not able to recruit patients to clinical trials Patient Participants Inclusion criteria: Black, African American or White; Nonhispanic confirmed diagnosis of prostate Cancer Seeing a participating physician for less than a year and expect to see this physician at least once in the coming year Able to read and write English well enough to understand and sign consent forms and respond to questionnaires Exclusion criteria: Not black, African American or White; non Hispanic No confirmed diagnosis of prostate cancer Not seeing a participating physician or seeing a participating physician for &gt; than one year Not able to read and write English well enough to understand and sign consent forms and respond to questionnaires</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>African Americans</keyword>
	<keyword>prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Minority</keyword>
	<keyword>Racial /Ethnic disparity</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer care</keyword>
	<keyword>patient-physician communication</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer clinical trial accrual</keyword>
</DOC>