<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01479530</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The rationale for conducting this study is to evaluate the efficacy, tolerability, and safety of rasagiline compared to placebo in levodopa-treated Parkinson's Disease (PD) Chinese patients with motor fluctuations. Azilect® (Rasagiline) is indicated for the treatment of idiopathic PD as monotherapy (without levodopa) or as adjunct therapy (with levodopa) in patients with end of dose fluctuations.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Azilect® (Rasagiline) in Levodopa-treated Parkinson's Patients With Motor Fluctuations in China</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rasagiline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levodopa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with idiopathic PD. Patients with motor fluctuations averaging at least 1 hour daily in the "OFF" state during the waking hours. Patients with a Modified Hoehn and Yahr stage ≤3 in the "ON" state. Patients taking optimised levodopa or dopa decarboxylase inhibitor (DDI) therapy; they must be stable for at least 14 days prior to baseline. Patients receiving at least 3 daily doses of levodopa and not more than 8 daily doses of levodopa. Patients who have demonstrated the ability to keep accurate "24hour" diaries prior to randomisation. Patients with a clinically significant or unstable medical or surgical condition that would preclude his/her safe and complete study participation. Patients with a clinically significant or unstable vascular disease. Patients who have undergone a neurosurgical intervention of PD. Patients with severe disabling dyskinesias. Patients with a clinically significant psychiatric illness, including a major depression, which compromises their ability to provide consent or participate fully in the study. Patients with a Mini Mental State Examination (MMSE) score ≤24. Patients with a diagnosis of melanoma or a history of melanoma, or a suspicious lesion. Other inclusion and exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Rasagiline</keyword>
	<keyword>Azilect</keyword>
	<keyword>Parkinson´s Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Motor fluctuations</keyword>
</DOC>