<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02683733</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Inflammatory Bowel Disease, including ulcerative colitis, is thought to result from an imbalance of pro-inflammatory and anti-inflammatory factors. As such, the majority of treatment options are directed at attempting to control the chronic inflammation and prolonging remission of clinical symptoms. Several studies have proven that curcumin has well-established anti-inflammatory properties. However, curcumin has poor bioavailability and prior studies have needed to use high concentrations in order to study the efficacy of the product. The investigators propose that a bio-enhanced preparation of curcumin will require a lower dosage to reach and affect its target tissue and will subsequently produce less adverse side effects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bio-enhanced Curcumin as an Add-On Treatment in Mild to Moderate Ulcerative Colitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aminosalicylic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Curcumin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mesalamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who have mild to moderate ulcerative colitis, with a current Partial Mayo Index greater than or equal to 2 and less than or equal to 6 Age 18 years and above Male or female Patients who have given consent and area able to follow the treatment given Patients who are able to record their responses in survey form at regular followup visits Patients who are in remission from ulcerative colitis, or who have a Partial Mayo Index Score of 0 or 1 Patients who have been taking azathioprine or mercaptopurine for &lt;12 weeks for the treatment of their ulcerative colitis Patients who are taking steroids or biologic agents for the treatment of their ulcerative colitis Patients who have severe ulcerative colitis, or who have a Partial Mayo Index Score of 7 or above Patients who are noncompliant with medication or regular follow up visits Patients who are unable to or unwilling to record their responses in survey form Patients with comorbid illnesses, including: Diabetes Mellitus, Stage III or above Congestive Heart Failure, chronic pancreatitis, severe liver or renal disease Patients who have current gallstones or any biliary dysfunction Patients with anemia (Hemoglobin &lt;10), thrombocytopenia, abnormal lymphocyte counts, or coagulation abnormalities Patients who currently have an ongoing severe infection/sepsis Patients with a history of malignancy Patients who are currently pregnant or nursing Patients who are current smokers</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>