<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02721550</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a perspective, multicenter,single arm, open label, Phase 2 study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of treatment with CMNa combined with preoperatie concurrent chemoradiotherapy in patients with locally advanced squamous cell esophageal carcinoma . Analyses of primary objective (pathologic Complete Response) will be done as defined in the protocol.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Trial of CMNa Combined With Preoperatie Concurrent Chemoradiotherapy for Locally Advanced ESCC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary end ponit of this study is pathological complete response.And the primary hypothesis is the CMNa will improve patholofical response rate and thus improve OS、DFS. Assuming bilateral a=0.05, statistical power of 80%.The total sample size is 40 cases.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Signed written informed consent prior to study entry 2. Patients with ESCC in thoracic segment which is resectable（T23，N01，M0） confirmed by imaging and pathology or cytology; 3. Patients have tumor lesions which can be objectively measured ,the length of tumor:≤8cm, the width of tumor:≤5cm;If the tumor cross the GEJ and violate the proximal stomach, the tumor must include esophagus and GEJ. The tumor is less than 2cm of the stomach 4. Not infringe bronchial wall; no esophagustracheal fistula. 5. normal bone marrow reserve: ANCcount ≥1500/mm3;platelet count ≥100,000/mm3,hemoglobin≥9g/dl 6. normal hepatic funcion:bilirubin level ≤1.5×ULN;AST/ALT≤1.5×ULN 7. normal renal function: serum creatinine≤1.5mg/dl and calculated creatinine clearance ≥60ml/min 8. normal cardiac function 9. ECOG PS of 0 or 1 10. Expected lifetime≥3 months 11. Subjects tumor tissue available for the relevant biomarker detection 1. Female subject who is during pregnancy or lactation, and the subject who have fertility don't take effective contraception during study. 2. Any mental illness or nervous system lesions or can't tell treatment response clearly (such as cerebrovascular accident sequelae) 3. Any serious uncontrolled disease and infection, such as severe heart, liver, kidney diseases or diabetes, can't complete the treatment plan 4. Patients who have other malignant lesions, except curable skin cancer (non melanoma skin cancer),carcinoma in situ of cervix or serve disease cured for 5 years 5. Primary lesions were multifocal 6. Patients with distant metastasis. A small amount of stomach tumor violate GEJ or the distal esophageal. 7. Patients who have obvious esophageal ulcers or have above moderate pains in chestback or have symptoms of esophageal perforation 8. received anticancer treatment of esophageal cancer before the group, including surgery, radiotherapy, chemotherapy (induction of chemotherapy before the group is greater than or equal to two cycles). 9. Cervical esophageal cancer confirmed by iconography 10. Not esophageal squamous carcinoma confirmed by pathology or cytology 11. History of active hepatitis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>