<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02721147</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The central goal of this study is to examine the feasibility, acceptability, and preliminary efficacy of the IE intervention on patient and partner sexual QOL and relationship outcomes, and on patient psychosocial outcomes. We expect that the IE will show adequate feasibility, acceptability, and preliminary efficacy. Secondarily, based on the rationale that barriers exist that limit participation in intensive sexual QOL interventions for breast cancer survivors, an innovative secondary aim will investigate the perspectives of study-eligible patient candidates who opt out of participating in the pilot trial. We expect that we will be able to identify the participation barriers and intervention preferences of breast cancer survivors with sexual concerns who opt out of the intensive trial in order to inform the development of different interventions for future study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Study of an Intimacy Enhancement Intervention for Couples Facing Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Female 2. Age &gt; 21 years 3. Has diagnosis of nonrecurrent stage IIII breast cancer 4. Completed active treatment (e.g., chemotherapy, radiation therapy, surgery) 6 months5 years ago (current use of endocrine therapy is acceptable) 5. Has a partner or spouse who is &gt; 21 6. Lives with a romantic partner &gt; 6 months 7. Score of &gt; 3 on Patient Care Monitor Sexual Concerns screening item 8. No hearing impairment in patient or partner 1. Not able to speak English, as stated in medical record or as observed by study team member 2. ECOG Performance score &gt; 2 OR too ill to participate as judged by physician/in medical record 3. Overt cognitive dysfunction or psychiatric disturbance such as suicidal ideation or severe mental illness, as observed or judged by the researcher, referring source, or other qualified observer. 4. Past history of any cancer other than nonmelanoma skin cancer 5. Currently participating in couple/marital therapy 6. Currently pregnant</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>