<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02721407</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this clinical trial is to study the feasibility and efficacy of anti-CD22:TCRz:4-1BB chimeric antigen receptor (CAR)-modified T (CAR-T) cells in treating recurrent patients with refractory or resistant lymphoma to anti-CD19:TCRz:CD28 CAR-T cells. Recently, cancer immunotherapy, treatments aiming to arm patients with immunity specifically against cancer cells, has emerged as a promising therapeutic strategy. Among the many emerging immunotherapeutic approaches, clinical trials utilizing CARs against B cell malignancies have demonstrated remarkable potential. CARs combine the variable region of an antibody with T-cell signaling moieties to confer T-cell activation with the targeting specificity of an antibody. Thus, CARs are not MHC-restricted so they are not vulnerable to MHC down regulation by tumors. However, defined by the recession of evaluable lesions, the persistence and efficacy of CAR-T cells are still restricted by the "target" selection. Previous clinical studies largely utilized CD19 for the in vivo targeting of CAR-T cells, which preferentially become refractory or resistant due to the heterogeneity of lymphoma. This clinical investigation is to test a hypothesis whether anti-CD22 CAR-T cells work more effective in lymphoma patients refractory or resistent to anti-CD19:TCRz:CD28 CAR-T cells.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Anti-CD22 CAR-T Therapy for CD19-refractory or Resistant Lymphoma Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary Objectives 1. To determine the safety of CD22.CAR-T cells in lymphoma patients refractory or resistent to anti-CD19:TCRz:CD28 CAR-T cells 2. To determine in vivo dynamics and persistency of CD22.CAR-T cells. Secondary Objectives 1. To determine the feasibility of CD22.CAR-T cells in lymphoma patients refractory or resistent to anti-CD19:TCRz:CD28 CAR-T cells 2. To determine in vivo dynamics and persistency of CD22.CAR-T cells. 3. To assess the intratumoral infiltration of CD22.CAR-T cells. 4. To correlate the subsets and differentiation of CD22.CAR-T cells to observed anti-tumor efficacy</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Follicular</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Mantle-Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1.18 Years to 70 Years, Male and female; 2.Expected survival &gt; 12 weeks; 3.Performance score 02; 4.Histologically confirmed as CD19positive lymphoma and who meet one of the following conditions; Patient receive at least 24 prior combination chemotherapy regimens (not including single agent monoclonal antibody therapy) and fail to achieve CR; or have disease recurrence; or not eligible for allogeneic stem cell transplantation; or disease responding or stable after most recent therapy but refused further treatment; Disease recurrence after stem cell transplantation; Diagnosis as lymphoma, but refuse conventional treatment such as chemotherapy, radiation, stem cell transplantation and monoclonal antibody therapy 5.Creatinine &lt; 2.5 mg/dl; 6.ALT/AST &lt; 3x normal; 7.Bilirubin &lt; 2.0 mg/dl; 8.Adequate venous access for apheresis, and no other contraindications for leukapheresis; 9.Take contraceptive measures before recruit to this trial; 10.Written voluntary informed consent is given. 11.Refractory ot resistant to prior antiCD19 CARTs 12.At least one evaluable CD22positive recurrent lesion, confirmed by two independent pathologist. 1. Patients with symptoms of central nervous system 2. Accompanied by other malignant tumor 3. Active hepatitis B or C, HIV infection 4. Any other diseases could affect the outcome of this trial 5. Suffering severe cardiovascular or respiratory disease 6. Poorly controlled hypertension 7. A history of mental illness and poorly controlled 8. Taking immunosuppressive agents within 1 week due to organ transplantation or other disease which need longlasting administration 9. Occurrence of unstable pulmonary embolism, deep vein thrombosis, or other major arterial/venous thromboembolic events 30 days prior to assignment 10. Reaching a steady dose if receiving anticoagulant therapy before assignment 11. Female study participants of reproductive potential must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test performed within 48 hours before infusion 12. Pregnant or lactating women 13. Subject suffering disease affects the understanding of informed consent or comply with study protocol.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>