<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02721706</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objectives: To evaluate the cost-effectiveness of implementing a malnutrition screening tool "CIPA" at the Hospital Universitario Nuestra Señora de la Candelaria (HUNSC), comparing the impact on health and the healthcare costs of hospitalised patients who are screened for malnutrition and of patients following standard clinical practice. Methodology: The study will consist of a controlled trial on patients admitted to the Internal Medicine and General and Digestive Surgery wards at the HUNSC. In both wards patients will be randomised to a control or to an intervention group. The control group will follow usual hospital clinical care, while the intervention group will be administered the screening tool "CIPA" for early detection of malnutrition cases and they will be treated according to the screening results. The following variables will be evaluated: length of stay in hospital, mortality, readmissions and in-hospital complications. Cost-effectiveness analysis will be undertaken measuring effectiveness by Quality-Adjusted Life Years (QALYs). Cost per patient will be measured by identifying health care resource utilisation, and the cost-effectiveness measure will be the Incremental Cost-Effectiveness Ratio (ICER). Investigators will calculate the incremental cost per QALY gained related to the intervention. This analysis will allow to quantify the costs (incurred and saved) related to the introduction of the malnutrition screening tool CIPA in the hospital context and to measure the health impact of screened patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cost-effectiveness Study of the New Nutrition Screening Tool CIPA at Hospital Admission</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Formal consent to participate in the study. Patients admitted to the Internal Medicine or General Surgery wards. Patients treated with nutritional support before CIPA screening is performed. Patients transferred from other wards. Patients with an expected length of stay less than 72 hours. CIPA screening unfeasible for any reason. Patients with poor shortterm prognosis. Bed destination at hospital admission nonrandomized. Patients participating in other investigation study. Pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Nutrition assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>inpatients</keyword>
	<keyword>cost-benefit analysis</keyword>
	<keyword>quality of life</keyword>
	<keyword>body composition</keyword>
	<keyword>mass screening</keyword>
</DOC>