<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00770588</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a double blind, multicentre, randomized, placebo-controlled study. The eligible patients will be randomized to receive gefitinib or placebo at 1:1 ratio. This study will recruit 296 male or female, histologically or cytologically diagnosed locally advanced or metastatic NSCLC patients with a World Health Organization (WHO) Performance Status (PS) 0-2. Patients must have completed 4 cycles of platinum based first line doublet chemotherapy without experiencing disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. The chemotherapy shall be given every 3 weeks, which includes cisplatin or carboplatin, combined with any one of the following: gemcitabine, paclitaxel, docetaxel, vinorelbine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assess the Efficacy, Safety and Tolerability of Gefitinib (Iressa® 250mg) as Maintenance Therapy in Locally Advanced or Metastatic (Stage IIIB/IV) Non Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gefitinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed locally advanced or metastatic (stage=IIIB/IV) nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC) before the front line chemotherapy. Note: sputum cytology alone is not acceptable Patients have completed 4 cycles of first line platinum contained doublet chemotherapy without progression or intolerable toxicity. Patients with PR or SD on study entry need to have one or more measurable lesions according to RECIST criteria. The study treatment should be started at least 3 weeks (21 days) but no more than 6 weeks (42 days) since last dose of chemotherapy, and within 4 weeks (28 days) since last tumour assessment. Prior exposure to monoclonal antibodies or small molecule inhibitors against EGFR receptors. (e.g. gefitinib, erlotinib, C225) Patients with previously diagnosed and treated CNS metastases or spinal cord compression may be considered if they are clinically stable and have been discontinued from steroid therapy for at least 4 weeks prior to first dose of study medication. Any evidence of clinically active interstitial lung disease (patients with chronic, stable, radiographic changes who are asymptomatic need not be excluded) Known biomarker status of one or more of the following: Tumour EGFR gene copy number, tumour EGFR gene mutation status, tumour EGFR protein expression.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC)</keyword>
	<keyword>Gefitinib</keyword>
</DOC>