<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00583986</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a study to investigate the reliability, ruggedness and safety of the top mounted actuation indicator (TMAI) when used with Levalbuterol HFA MDI.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Reliability of a Top Mount Actuation Indicator With Levalbuterol MDI in Adult and Pediatric Subjects With Asthma or COPD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label, multicenter, TMAI study with Levalbuterol HFA MDI in adult and pediatric subjects with asthma or COPD. Period I: One week, open-label, run-in period during which subjects must have asthma or COPD symptoms requiring use of, as needed, Levalbuterol HFA MDI(without TMAI) on at least half of the days [4-12 actuations on a single day]. Period II: Nine week, open-label period during which subjects will use the Levalbuterol HFA MDI with TMAI PRN. The total study duration for a subject will not exceed 10 weeks. This study was previously posted by Sepracor Inc. In October 2009, Sepracor Inc. was acquired by Dainippon Sumitomo Pharma., and in October 2010, Sepracor Inc's name was changed to Sunovion Pharmaceuticals Inc.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albuterol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject must have a documented diagnosis of asthma or COPD for a minimum of 6 months. Subject must have stable baseline asthma or COPD and have been using a betaadrenergic agonist, and/or antiasthma antiinflammatory medication, and/or overthecounter asthma medication for at least 6 months. Subject must be in good health with the exception of their reversible airways disease and not suffering from any chronic condition that might affect their respiratory function. Female subject who is pregnant or lactating. Subject who has a history of hospitalization for asthma or COPD within 45 days. Subject with currently diagnosed lifethreatening asthma or COPD, defined as a history of asthma or COPD episodes requiring intubation, associated with hypercapnia, respiratory arrest, or hypoxic seizures within 3 months prior. Subject with supplemental oxygen use Subject with a history of cancer Subject with hyperthyroidism, diabetes, hypertension, cardiac diseases, or seizure disorders that currently are not well controlled by medication. Subject with asthma with a greater than 10pack per year history of cigarette smoking or use of any tobacco products within 6 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>top mounted</keyword>
	<keyword>actuation indicator</keyword>
	<keyword>Asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</keyword>
</DOC>