<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01811706</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Investigators expect there will be improvement in walking speed and steadiness after taking Dalfampridine, thereby improving activities of daily living and enhancing social and occupational functions for patients with spinocerebellar ataxia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dalfampridine and Gait in Spinocerebellar Ataxias</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Twenty spinocerebellar ataxia patients will be randomized to receive either Dalfampridine or placebo over a total period of 10 weeks. After entering the study, patients will return every 2 weeks for evaluation. After four weeks, intervention will be stopped and patient will enter a 2-week wash out period where they do not take any drug. Then, patients will be given the opposite treatment (Dalfampridine or placebo) and this "crossover" study will be performed for another 4 weeks. Investigators expect there will be improvement in walking speed and steadiness after taking Dalfampridine, thereby improving activities of daily living and enhancing social and occupational functions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ataxia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebellar Ataxia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinocerebellar Ataxias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Spinocerebellar Degenerations</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Machado-Joseph Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>4-Aminopyridine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Individuals at age 18 years or older. Individuals who can provide the informed consent Genetic confirmed definite spinocerebellar ataxias (SCA) Able to complete two trials of the timed 25foot walk at screening Patients who has severe ataxia and unable to ambulate. Any orthopedic condition that would affect motor performance. Patients with secondary ataxia from general medical disorders Individuals who have major psychiatric disorders that prevents compliance History of epilepsy Patients with active drug or alcohol use or dependence that would interfere with adherence to study requirements Inability or unwillingness of subject or legal guardian/representative to give written informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>