<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01811875</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary objective: To assess post-marketing immunogenicity of Optivate® by monitoring plasma inhibitor levels for at least 100 Exposure Days (EDs) for each subject. Secondary objectives: To assess efficacy and tolerability by monitoring FVIII recovery and adverse events</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicentre, Non-controlled, Prospective, Post-Marketing Safety Study Following Long-Term Prophylactic OptivateTreatment in Subjects With Severe Haemophilia A</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Factor VIII</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent or, if less than 18 years of age written assent (where possible) and their parent/guardian's written informed consent. Severe haemophilia A (&lt; 1%# FVIII:C). Previously Treated Patients (PTPs) with &gt; 150 exposure days on prior Factor VIII therapy (of which at least the last 50 EDs or 2 years treatment can be confirmed by way of subject records). Immunocompetent with CD4 count &gt; 200 / µl. HIV negative or a viral load &lt; 200 particles / µl. subjects suffering from severe haemophilia A (&lt;2%) may be enrolled, but only after approval by BPL. Subjects with a Factor VIII of &lt;2% may not constitute more than 50% of the total patient population. A separate statistical evaluation will be conducted for the &lt;1% and &lt;2% populations. • History of inhibitor development to FVIII or a positive result on the Nijmegen Bethesda at screening (quantitative result of &gt; 0.6 BU) prior to the administration of Optivate®. Known or suspected hypersensitivity to the investigational medicinal product or its excipients. Clinically significant liver disease, renal disease, or coagulopathy other than haemophilia A. History of unreliability or non cooperation (including not being able to complete the study diary). Participating in, or have taken part in another trial within the last 30 days.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Haemophilia A</keyword>
</DOC>