<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03106025</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is collecting data along with other academic institutions regarding the accuracy of ocular ultrasound in diagnosing retinal detachment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of Ocular Point of Care Ultrasound in Diagnosing Retinal Detachment in the Emergency Department: A Prospective Study.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a prospective, cross-sectional study to assess the utility of point of care ultrasound in the diagnosis of ocular complaints in the emergency department with specific focus on the accuracy of diagnosis when compared to that of a blinded ophthalmologist. Ocular complaints represent between 2% and 3% of ED visits (Walker et al, 2011). This percentage may include vision-threatening diagnoses including retinal detachment, which can occur in 3-4% of patients presenting with ocular complaints (Alotaibi et al, 2011). However, the equipment and expertise required to adequately assess for conditions such as retinal detachment are limited in busy emergency departments due to the time consuming and challenging nature of the examination. Incorporating the use of an ultrasound could provide a more available, focused, and timely assessment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinal Detachment</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dissociative Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitreous Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitreous Detachment</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants may include any patient that is greater than 18 years old with any complaint of vision loss, flashers, floaters and/or any other patient whom the emergency physician feels requires an evaluation for mac on retinal detachment, mac off retinal detachment, vitreous hemorrhage, and or vitreous detachment. Patients that meet this eligibility criterion must also be receiving a consult by a Loma linda ophthalmology physician in order to obtain comparative time values and accuracy for ED physician diagnosis versus ophthalmologist diagnosis. Exclusion Criteria includes any ocular trauma, any concern for ruptured globe, or any other extraneous reason determined by the treating ED physician. Excluded patients also include: pregnant women, patients &lt; 18 years of age, and patients not receiving an ophthalmology consult.We will be excluding pregnant women in order to minimize the exposure to ultrasonography for expectant mothers. We will be excluding patients &lt;18 years of age because it is unlikely that the data from these patients will significantly contribute to our investigation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>