<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03106428</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess safety and tolerability, describe the dose-limiting toxicities, determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) or the highest protocol-defined dose (maximum administered dose) in the absence of establishing the MTD, and a recommended dose for further evaluation of MEDI7247 in patients with selected hematological malignancies who have relapsed after, or are refractory to prior standard therapy, and for whom there is no standard salvage regimen available.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Multiple Ascending Dose Study of MEDI7247 in Patients With Selected Relapsed/Refractory Hematological Malignancies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age ≥ 18 years at the time of screening. 2. Written informed consent and any locally required authorization 3. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 4. Female patients of childbearing potential who are sexually active with a nonsterilized male partner must use at least one highly effective method of contraception from 7 days postscreening, and must agree to continue using such precautions for 90 days after the last dose of investigational product. 5. Nonsterilized male patients who are sexually active with a female partner of childbearing potential must use a male condom plus spermicide from 7 days postscreening and for 90 days after receipt of the last dose of investigational product. 1. Received cytotoxic chemotherapy within 21 days (or 42 days for nitrosureas or mitomycin C) prior to the first scheduled dose of MEDI7247. 2. Received major surgery (as defined by the Investigator), radiotherapy, or immunotherapy within 28 days of the first scheduled dose of MEDI7247. 3. Received an investigational drug within 14 days or 5 halflives, whichever is shorter, of the first scheduled dose of MEDI7247 or not recovered from associated toxicities. 4. Patients who have previously received an autologous SCT, are excluded if less than 90 days have elapsed from the time of transplant or the patient has not recovered from transplantassociated toxicities prior to the first scheduled dose of MEDI7247. 5. Failure to recover from all prior treatmentrelated nonhematological toxicities to ≤ Grade 1 prior to the first scheduled dose of MEDI7247 (except for alopecia and neuropathy). 6. Patients at risk of nondisease related major bleeding (eg, recent GI hemorrhage or neurosurgery, within previous 21 days). 7. Central nervous system (CNS) disease that is untreated, symptomatic, or requires therapy to control symptoms. 8. Active human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus (HCV) infections at the time of screening.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>