<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02511977</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The control of biofilm around implants is critical to the success of the implant rehabilitation of edentulous jaw with overdentures, and it is the dentist's duty to inform and guide patients, and keep their maintenance in order to prevent pathological processes that can lead to the implanted component loss.The aim of the present retrospective longitudinal study was to evaluate through clinical periodontal parameters and radiographic images in dental implants rehabilitated with overdentures installed seven years ago. individuals who underwent the installation of dental implants for making full implant-supported upper and lower mucus dentures in the Department of Implant Dentistry, Faculty of Dentistry, University of Santo Amaro, São Paulo, Brazil, in 2007. The periodontal parameters such as probing depth, plaque index, bleeding index and mobility as well as radiographic examination, are key to determine the correct diagnosis in dental implants. The control of biofilm around the implants seems to be a decisive factor for maintaining tissue health. We believe that the maintenance appointments are fundamental, but more studies should be conducted to elucidate microbial and immunological factors in implants placed and due for some time.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation Clinical and Radiographic Images in Dental Implants Rehabilitated With Overdentures</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The control of biofilm around implants is critical to the success of the implant rehabilitation of edentulous jaw with overdentures, and it is the dentist's duty to inform and guide patients, and keep their maintenance in order to prevent pathological processes that can lead to the implanted component loss.The aim of the present retrospective longitudinal study was to evaluate through clinical periodontal parameters and radiographic images in dental implants rehabilitated with overdentures installed seven years ago. individuals who underwent the installation of dental implants for making full implant-supported upper and lower mucus dentures in the Department of Implant Dentistry, Faculty of Dentistry, University of Santo Amaro, São Paulo, Brazil, in 2007. The periodontal parameters such as probing depth, plaque index, bleeding index and mobility as well as radiographic examination, are key to determine the correct diagnosis in dental implants. The control of biofilm around the implants seems to be a decisive factor for maintaining tissue health.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Rehabilitation should be:prothesis type overdenture, with at least 2 implants placed in the mandible and 3 implants in the maxilla per person individuals who have annual maintenance for the past seven years, individuals who have not returned for the last seven years, Individuals who said they went to the dentist at least once a year, for whatever treatment, were included in the maintenance group, Individuals who denied any visit to the dentist in the last seven years were included in the no maintenance group. smokers, as those who, for any reason, should make systemic medication suspension for clinical evaluation, individuals in need of antibiotic prophylaxis for carrying out the clinical examinations, Patients with less than seven annual maintenance consultations in the last seven years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dental Prosthesis</keyword>
	<keyword>Implant-Supported</keyword>
</DOC>