<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00777309</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, double blind phase 2 study designed to compare treatment with ARQ 197 plus erlotinib to erlotinib plus placebo in patients with non-small cell lung cancer. The study will enroll patients who have had one prior chemotherapy regimen (other than erlotinib) for NSCLC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomized Phase 2 Study of Erlotinib + ARQ 197 Versus Erlotinib + Placebo in Previously Treated Patients With Locally Advanced or Metastatic Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, double blind phase 2 study designed to compare treatment with ARQ 197 plus erlotinib to erlotinib plus placebo in patients with non-small cell lung cancer. The study will enroll patients who have had one prior chemotherapy regimen (other than erlotinib) for NSCLC. The study will evaluate progression-free survival between the two arms. A total of 154 patients will be enrolled.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Provide signed and dated informed consent prior to studyspecific screening procedures 2. ≥ 18 years old 3. Histologically or cytologically confirmed inoperable locally advanced or metastatic (stage IIIB/IV) NSCLC 4. ≥ one prior chemotherapy regimen (including adjuvant chemotherapy)(not to have included erlotinib or other EGFR inhibiting agent) 5. Measurable disease as defined by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) 6. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 to 1 7. Male or female patients of childproducing potential must agree to use double barrier contraception, oral contraceptives or avoidance of pregnancy measures during the study and for 90 days after the last day of treatment 8. Females of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test 9. Good organ function 10. Confirmed availability of archival pathology samples (10 unstained paraffinembedded slides) or tissue block suitable for subsequent analysis of KRAS, EGFR, and cMet 1. Previous receipt of erlotinib or other EGFR inhibiting therapy 2. Receipt of any antitumor treatment for NSCLC within 4 weeks (2 weeks for radiotherapy) prior to the start of designated treatment 3. Documented major surgical procedure within 4 weeks prior to randomization. 4. Symptomatic central nervous system metastases either considered in the opinion of investigator to be clinically unstable or which require steroids, antiepileptics, or other symptomrelieving medications 5. Pregnant, breastfeeding, or refusing double barrier contraception, oral contraceptives or avoidance of pregnancy measures 6. Significant gastrointestinal disorder that, in opinion of Investigator, could interfere with the absorption of ARQ 197 and/or erlotinib (e.g. Crohn's disease, small or large bowel resection, malabsorbtion syndrome) 7. Unable or unwilling to swallow the complete dose of erlotinib or ARQ 197 8. Any known contraindication to treatment with ARQ 197 or erlotinib 9. Any known hypersensitivity to any of component of ARQ 197 or erlotinib 10. Other malignancy within 5 years of randomization, with the exception of adequately treated intraepithelial carcinoma of the cervix uteri, prostate carcinoma with a PSA value &lt; 0.2 ng/ml or basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin 11. Previously diagnosed grade 3 or 4 (CTCAE) bradycardia or other heart arrhythmia 12. Any other significant comormid condition that, in opinion of the Investigator, would impair study participation or cooperation 13. Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
</DOC>