<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00651495</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic diseases are the primary cause of morbidity and mortality for older Americans. Active patient participation in treatment decision-making has the potential to significantly improve outcomes in chronic disease care, but interventions to increase participation remain underused. Some studies have found that older individuals are less interested in participating in clinical decision-making, but other studies find that exposing patients to decision aids (PtDAs) increases their desire to take an active role in making decisions with their physicians. The present study targets hard-to-reach seniors by showing decision aids focused on chronic disease management in senior centers. Decision aids will be made available in two senior centers through a lending library and by conducting group screenings of the decision aids followed by moderated discussion of the content with participants. A randomized encouragement design will be used to test the effectiveness of a modest financial incentive on increasing seniors' participation in group screenings. The investigators will evaluate the effects of the intervention on seniors' decision-making role preferences, attitudes, perceived social norms and self efficacy for asking questions of their physician, health-related quality of life, physical activity, and changes in prescribed treatment regimens and self-care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Activating Seniors to Improve Chronic Disease Care</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 55 years old. Able to ambulate Able to complete selfadministered surveys Able to speak and read English Not willing to provide consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Decision aids</keyword>
	<keyword>Seniors</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic disease management</keyword>
	<keyword>Advance directives</keyword>
</DOC>