<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00865969</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess efficacy and safety of belinostat in patients with relapsed or refractory peripheral T-cell lymphoma (PTCL), who failed at least one prior systemic therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Belinostat in Relapsed or Refractory Peripheral T-Cell Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label, multicenter, single arm efficacy and safety study in patients with relapsed or refractory peripheral T-cell lymphoma, who have failed at least one prior systemic therapy. Approximately 120 patients will be enrolled. Patients will be treated with 1000 mg/m² belinostat administered as a 30-minute IV infusion on days 1-5 of every 3-week cycle until there is disease progression or unmanageable treatment-related toxicities. The primary study endpoint is objective response rate (ORR) based on the IHP revision IWG criteria. Safety will be evaluated during the study and for 30 days after the last administration of study drug. Adverse events and laboratory studies will be graded according to NCI-CTCAE v. 3.0.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Peripheral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Belinostat</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Histone Deacetylase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: A histologically confirmed diagnosis of PTCL Patients must have relapsed or refractory disease after at least one prior systemic anticancer regimen. Systemic anticancer therapy is defined as chemotherapy or immunotherapy administered systemically. Patients must have at least one site of disease measurable in two dimensions by computed tomography (CT). Age ≥ 18 years. Adequate bone marrow, liver, and renal functions. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 02. Negative pregnancy test for women of childbearing potential. Exclusion criteria: Relapse within 100 days of autologous or allogeneic bone marrow transplant. Prior HDAC inhibitor therapy. Coexisting active infection or any medical condition likely to interfere with trial procedures. Severe cardiovascular disease. Clinically significant central nervous system disorders with altered mental status or psychiatric disorders precluding understanding of the informed consent process and/or completion of the necessary studies. Active concurrent malignancy (except adequately treated nonmelanoma skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix). Symptomatic or untreated central nervous system (CNS) metastases. Pregnant or breastfeeding women. Known infection with HIV, hepatitis B or hepatitis C.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Belinostat</keyword>
	<keyword>peripheral T-cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>PXD101</keyword>
	<keyword>PTCL</keyword>
	<keyword>HDAC inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>histone deacetylase inhibitor</keyword>
</DOC>