<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02059317</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to compare on day 0 the maximum Lyapunov exponent (lmax, an indicator of local dynamic stability) of chronic low back pain patients versus that of healthy volunteers matched for age (± 5 years), sex and body mass index (BMI ± 15% of low back pain patients).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Dynamic Stability in the Low Back Pain Patient</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The secondary objectives of this study are: To compare lmax in the different experimental conditions within each group (chronic lower back pain patients, healthy volunteers). To compare changes in lmax for low back pain patients at D7 and 6 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>General inclusion criteria: The patient/subject must have given his/her informed and signed consent The patient/subject must be insured or beneficiary of a health insurance plan Inclusion criteria for low back pain patients: The patient has chronic low back pain lasting for more than 6 months and which is not postoperative in nature General exclusion criteria: The patient/subject is participating in another study The patient/subject is in an exclusion period determined by a previous study The patient/subject is under judicial protection, under tutorship or curatorship The patient/subject refuses to sign the consent It is impossible to correctly inform the patient/subject The patient/subject is pregnant, parturient, or breastfeeding Exclusion criteria for low back pain patients: The patient has a history of spinal surgery The patient has a history of preexisting postural disorder related to lumbalgia The patient has undergone a localized infiltration treatment (e.g. cortisone shots) in the last month The subject has a balance disorder, blindness, inability to carry out the experimental protocol Exclusion criteria for healthy volunteers: The subject has a history of acute low back pain &gt; 15 days or which has resulted in a work stoppage of more than 7 days in the 5 years preceding the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>