<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02059239</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial is for men and women with whose lymphoma (non-Hodgkin or Hodgkin) did not respond to treatment or has returned after responding to previous therapy, and who are in need of a stem cell transplant. The purpose of this study is to test the safety and effectiveness of giving the drug Bendamustine, followed by high dose chemotherapy, within two weeks prior to a stem cell transplant for lymphoma that has not achieved a complete response to salvage (treatment used for relapsed disease) chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lymphoma Bridge Transplant Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Subjects with Hodgkin's or Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma that did not respond to treatment or have disease that has returned after responding to previous treatment, and are in need of a stem cell transplant will be eligible for this pilot study. Thirty subjects will be enrolled, with 15 subjects assigned to the autologous transplant cohort (according to disease status and eligibility) and 15 subjects to the allogeneic transplant cohort (according to diseases status and eligibility). Subjects will undergo the following a number of screening procedures to determine eligibility. All eligible subjects will receive bendamustine at a dose of 200 mg/ m2/ day for two days on Days - 24 and Day - 23 followed by a short break of 10 - 14 days. Subjects will then receive the conditioning regimen, BEAM (carmustine, etoposide, cytarabine arabinoside, and Melphalan) and alemtuzumab for 6 days (Day -6 to Day -1) followed by an autologous or allogeneic transplant. Subjects with pathological confirmed B-cell malignancies will also receive rituximab 375 mg/m2 on Days + 1 and +8 post-transplant. Subjects with T-cell lymphoma will be enrolled in the study but will not receive rituximab. After the transplantation all subjects will receive medication to prevent graft vs host disease and supportive care to prevent infections. To speed up the recovery of stem cells, subjects will receive post-transplant filgrastim (G-CSF). After discharge from the hospital, subjects will be seen regularly in the clinic for an exam and assessments. All these tests are considered standard of care.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alemtuzumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cytarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carmustine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Melphalan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bendamustine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>must have histologically or cytologically confirmed relapsed or primary refractory lymphoma (including Hodgkin's Lymphoma) staged with PET scan to have Allogeneic arm: Progressive disease or No response to salvage therapy or Partial response to salvage therapy defined as &gt; 50% reduction in bidirectional area of masses but SUV remains ≥8 in at least some PET avid areas Autologous arm: Partial response of &gt;50% reduction in bidirectional area of masses and SUV reduction to &lt;8 in PET avid areas Subjects must have evaluable disease. Subjects must have received at least one induction therapy and one line of salvage therapy that each incorporate at least two drugs that are standard of care for lymphoma (such as alkylating agents, anthracyclines, topo II inhibitors, vinca alkaloids, corticosteroids, if the disease was PET avid) Age &gt;18 years. KPS (Karnofsky Performance Score) ≥ 60% For autologous transplants: Subjects must have an adequate number of CD34+ stem cells collected to allow for transplantation. This number is defined as ≥ 2x106 CD34+ cells / kg body weight. If not previously collected and stored, the subject must be willing to undergo stem cell mobilization and collection as per standard practice. If sufficient cells cannot be collected, subjects will be offered the option to proceed with the allogeneic arm of the study. Male and female subjects must use an effective contraceptive method during the study and for a minimum of 6 months after study treatment. Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test within 2 weeks prior to enrollment. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document. Known to be positive for HIV Subjects may not be receiving any other investigational agents (defined as non FDAapproved agents) at the time of initiating bendamustine regimen. Women who are pregnant or breast feeding. Women of childbearing age must use adequate contraception and have a negative pregnancy test. The risks to an unborn fetus or potential risks in nursing infants are unknown. History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition to any medications listed in the protocol. Subject with severely decreased Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction (LVEF) or severely impaired pulmonary function tests (PFT's) Uncontrolled illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>NHL</keyword>
	<keyword>HL</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>