<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02059577</DOC>
	<brief_summary>70 children and adults with autism spectrum disorders will be enrolled in a 1-year, single-blind treatment study. Assessments will be conducted at the beginning and end of the study, including measurements of nutritional, metabolic, and digestive status and assessments of autism severity and overall functioning. Half of the participants will be randomized into a treatment study, and half will be randomized to no changes in their current treatments. Treatments will be added in a sequential manner over 12 months, including vitamin/minerals, essential fatty acids, carnitine, digestive enzymes, and healthy, gluten-free, casein-free diets. A dedicated team of nutritionists, nurses, and physicians will support and monitor the participants throughout the study. A group of 50 neurotypical children and adults, of similar age and gender, will be included for comparison.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nutritional and Dietary Treatment Study for Children/Adults With Autism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Caseins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Magnesium Sulfate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Autism Group 1. Diagnosis of autism spectrum disorder (autism, PDDNOS, or Asperger's) by a psychiatrist, psychologist, or developmental pediatrician 2. Verification of diagnosis by an ADOS evaluation (conducted by ASU staff) 3. Age of 2.5 years to 60 years Enrollment Criteria Nonautism Group 1. No diagnosed mental disorders, including autism spectrum disorders, ADHD, depression, anxiety, etc. 2. No firstdegree relatives of individuals with autism (no siblings or parents) 3. Age of 2.5 years to 60 years Exclusion Criteria Autism Group 1. Major changes in behavioral or medical treatments in the previous two months, or intention to make such changes during the 12 months of the study. 2. Usage of nutritional supplements (vitamins, minerals essential fatty acids, carnitine) or special diets in the previous two months Exclusion Criteria Nonautism Group 1) Usage of nutritional supplements (vitamins, minerals essential fatty acids, carnitine) or special diets in the previous two months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>vitamins</keyword>
	<keyword>minerals</keyword>
	<keyword>essential fatty acids</keyword>
	<keyword>Epsom salts</keyword>
	<keyword>carnitine</keyword>
	<keyword>digestive enzymes</keyword>
	<keyword>gluten-free casein-free diet</keyword>
</DOC>