<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00260533</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the effectiveness and tolerability of atomoxetine (Strattera) in adult patients with generalized social anxiety disorder (an anxiety disorder characterized by a fear of interpersonal interactions).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Tolerability of Atomoxetine (Strattera) in Adult Patients With Generalized Social Anxiety Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Controlled studies show that approximately 50% of patients with generalized social anxiety disorder(GSAD)will respond to treatment with available pharmacotherapeutic agents such as SSRI's. This still leaves 50% that respond partially or not at all. Those who do respond, often experience adverse events (e.g., sexual dysfunction), which leads them to discontinue treatment. Thus, there is a strong rational for identifying alternatives to SSRI's that are effective with fewer side effects (or with a different side-effect profile, that features less sexual dysfunction)for the treatment of GSAD. Available data demonstrate that sustained-release venlafaxine, a dual reuptake inhibitor, is also effective for GSAD.(Stein et al., 2005). It is unclear from these studies whether serotonin reuptake is integral to efficacy for social anxiety disorder, or whether norepinephrine reuptake will convey similar efficacy. Atomoxetine (Strattera)an inhibitor of the presynaptic norepinephrine transporter, is an ideal candidate to address both these issues.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phobic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atomoxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and Women, ages 1865, in good general health Meet DSMIV criteria for Social Anxiety Disorder Pregnant or breastfeeding Narrow angle glaucoma Any uncontrolled medical condition or any medical condition which would represent a contraindication to atomoxetine (Strattera) pharmacotherapy (e.g., hepatic insufficiency, untreated hypertension, untreated cardiovascular or cerebrovascular disease) Any concomitant nonpsychotropic medications that the physician determines are a contraindication to atomoxetine (Strattera) pharmacotherapy (e.g., Albuterol, various pressor agents) Bipolar disorder, or any psychotic or organic mental disorder or dementia Current substance abuse or dependency Current active suicidal ideation Current use of herbal psychoactive treatments such as St. John's Wort Concurrent psychotropic medication is not permitted for 2 weeks prior to randomization (4 weeks in the case of fluoxetine) or at any point thereafter. Receipt of formal psychotherapy concurrently Inability, in the investigator's opinion, to comply with study procedures or assessments</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>