<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01596842</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Extra-renal sources of 1, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D can be increased to normal serum 1, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D levels in chronic kidney disease patients after administration of high dose 25-hydroxyvitamin D. The investigators observed that 1, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D concentrations were significantly increased after 3 months of omega-3 FA supplementation compared to baseline levels without 25-hydroxyvitamin D administration in dialysis patients. In this study, the investigators hypothesized that omega-3 FA and 25-hydroxyvitamin D supplementations may increase 1, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D concentrations much more compared to 25-hydroxyvitamin D supplementation only in hemodialysis patients with insufficient or deficient 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Omega-3 Fatty Acid on Vitamin D Activation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who were treated with hemodialysis for at least 6 months with 25hydroxyvitamin D &lt; 30 ng/mL Patients with a history of active infection within 3 months, Patients with fish oil or omega3 fatty acid supplementation within 3 months, Patients with a history of fish, gelatin, and/or omega3 fatty acid allergies, Patients with a history of hospital admission within 3 months, Patients with a history of bleeding within 3 months, Patients with thrombocytopenia, Patients with current use of warfarin, Patients with an albumin level &lt; 3.0 g/dL, Patients with malignancy and/or liver cirrhosis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Omega-3 fatty acid</keyword>
	<keyword>vitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>ergocalciferol</keyword>
	<keyword>hemodialysis</keyword>
</DOC>