<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01596231</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a study designed to test whether a single administration of kudzu extract (2 mg) will significantly reduce the number of drinks consumed during a single 1 ½ hours drinking session when given as pretreatment 2 ½ hours before the drinking session.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Kudzu Treatment for Alcohol Abuse</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In a laboratory experimental setting, subjects will be treated with placebo or 2 grams of kudzu extract 2.5 hours before an afternoon drinking session. The investigators hypothesis is that the kudzu pretreatment will reduce alcohol consumption in this free choice, self-administration paradigm.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alcohol Drinking</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Capable of understanding and complying with the protocol Good physical and mental health (normal physical exam, ECG, blood and urine chemistries) Body Mass Index between 1830, inclusive Age 2140 years Moderate to heavy alcohol drinkers (on the average 20+ drinks/week) or a selfreported pattern of incidences of binge drinking 2 or more times per week (4 or more alcoholic beverages in one sitting) Have a stable living situation with current postal address Concurrent diagnosis of Axis I disorder Current or past alcohol dependence; may meet criteria for alcohol abuse. Other drug dependence acceptable only if greater than 3 years. Immediate family history pattern of alcoholism or problem drinking (parents or siblings) Current drug abuse (other than alcohol or marijuana abuse). Past drug abuse is acceptable. Subjects cannot be actively seeking treatment for any drug or alcohol dependence. Subjects cannot use marijuana more than once a week. Marijuana abuse/dependence are acceptable if the use criteria is met. Maintained on an antipsychotic or antidepressant medication; taking prescription medications except certain shortterm anti fungal agents and some tropical creams for dermal conditions. Tobacco use greater than 5 cigarettes per day History of major head trauma resulting in cognitive impairment or history of seizure disorder Heavy caffeine use (greater than 500 mg on a regular, daily basis) Subject has active hepatitis and/or aspartate aminotransferase (AST), alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt; 3x the upper limit of normal For female volunteers, a positive pregnancy test</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alcohol consumption</keyword>
	<keyword>Kudzu extract</keyword>
</DOC>