<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01596920</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the present study is to further establish in a randomized controlled trial, the safety and efficacy of weekly Grafix® administration versus control in patients with chronic diabetic foot ulcers. The primary endpoint is complete wound closure of the index wound, defined as 100% re-epithelialization as determined by the Investigator. Grafix® is a product regulated for use in the US by the FDA as a Human Cellular and Tissue Based Product (HCT/P) under Title 21 CFR Part 1271.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Grafix® DFU: Open-Label Extension Option to Evaluate Safety &amp; Efficacy of Grafix® for Chronic Diabetic Foot Ulcers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The treatment indication is for chronic, diabetic foot ulcers (DFUs) between 1cm2 and 15cm2 located below the malleoli on the plantar or dorsal surface of the foot. Patients must have confirmed Type I or Type II Diabetes. Patients will receive treatment every week for 12 weeks duration in the Single-Blind Treatment phase of the trial. Patients who receive Grafix® or control will be evaluated for primary efficacy up to 84 days, and for safety and wound re-occurrence for 84 days after wound closure. Patients in the control group whose wounds are not closed at the end of treatment may be offered Grafix® in an Open-Label Treatment phase. The Open-Label Treatment phase can last up to an additional 84 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Foot</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Foot Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Between 18 years and 80 years of age inclusive, as of the date of screening 2. Confirmed diagnosis of Type I or Type II Diabetes 3. An Index Ulcer defined as chronic (presence of wound for &gt; 4 weeks) but not present for more than 52 weeks at the Screening Visit 4. Index Ulcer is located below the malleoli on the plantar or dorsal surface of the foot 5. The Index Ulcer is between 1cm2 and 15 cm2 at the Screening Visit 6. The Index Ulcer extends into the dermis or subcutaneous tissue without evidence of exposed muscle, tendon, bone, or joint capsule 7. Wound is free of necrotic debris 8. Patient has adequate circulation to the foot as documented by either: Ankle Brachial Index (ABI) &gt; 0.70 and &lt; 1.30, or In patients with noncompressible ankle vessels defined as an ABI ≥ 1.30, a Toe Brachial Index (TBI) ≥ 0.50 In patients with noncompressible ankle vessels defined as an ABI ≥ 1.30 and TBI cannot be performed (e.g., toe is absent, wounds are present, or site cannot perform a TBI), a Doppler waveform in the posterior tibial or dorsalis pedis arteries at the ankle consistent with adequate flow in the foot (biphasic or triphasic) and other diagnostic confirmation of adequate flow (e.g., duplex imaging, normal pulse volume recording [PVR] testing). 1. Index Ulcer is of nondiabetic pathophysiology 2. Gangrene is present on any part of the affected foot 3. Index Ulcer is over an active Charcot deformity 4. The longest dimension of the Index Ulcer exceeds 5 cm at the Baseline Visit 5. Patient is currently receiving dialysis 6. Patient has a glycated hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) level of &gt; 12% 7. Chronic oral steroid use &gt; 7.5 mg daily 8. Requiring intravenous (IV) antibiotics to treat the index wound infection 9. Patient has an ulcer within 15cm of the Index Ulcer identified for study consideration 10. Patient is receiving oral or parenteral corticosteroids, immunosuppressive or cytotoxic agents 11. Patient is Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) positive or has Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS) 12. Current evidence of osteomyelitis, cellulitis, or other evidence of infection including fever or pus drainage from the wound site 13. Patient has active malignancy other than nonmelanoma skin cancer 14. Patient's Index Ulcer has decreased by ≥ 30% during 1week screening period as determined by criteria provided by the Wound Core Lab 15. Patient's random blood sugar is &gt; 450 mg/dl at screening 16. Patient has untreated alcohol or substance abuse at the time of screening 17. Pregnant women 18. Patient is currently enrolled or participated in another investigational device, drug, or biological trial within 60 days of screening 19. Patient has allergy to primary or secondary dressing materials used in this trial 20. Patient has had within the last 30 days, or is currently undergoing, or is planning for wound treatments with enzymes, growth factors, living skin, dermal substitutes or other advanced biological therapies</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic DFUs</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetic Foot Ulcers</keyword>
</DOC>