<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02663973</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The principal goal of this study is to describe the epidemiology of breast cancer in the Brazilian population</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Evaluation of Breast Cancer at Brazilian Institutions - Project AMAZONA III</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The principal goal of this study is to describe the epidemiology of breast cancer in the Brazilian population. Other specific goals are: - To evaluate the demographic and socio-demographic profile, comorbidities and reproductive risks, anthropometric profile and family history. - Characterize the breast tumors immunophenotype through anatomopathological data, such as: tumor grade, estrogen receptor, progesterone receptor, HER2, Ki67. - Describe the screening tests, main symptoms and cancer stage in the moment of the diagnosis. - Describe the initial cancer treatment and locally advanced such as surgery, radiotherapy, chemotherapy and endocrine therapy. - Describe palliative treatment for recurrent or metastatic breast cancer: chemotherapy, radiotherapy, biphosphonate, and others. - Evaluate the clinical outcomes such as: local or diffuse relapse, period of time until progression to metastatic cancer, global lifespan and specific breast cancer lifespan. - Evaluate clinical complications of the metastatic disease, such as: brain metastasis, spinal cord compression, skeletal related events. - Analyze the demographical and socio-economical characteristics, clinical-pathological characteristics of the tumor, treatment, clinical outcomes, type of institution (private/public), and other factors that may impact clinical outcome.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Woman ≥ 18 years old Invasive breast cancer stage I to IV proven by histology or cytology Patients with new pathological diagnosis of invasive primary BC after the site activation date Pathological diagnosis of invasive breast cancer during recruitment (6 months before center activation or until 3000 patients included) New primary cancer on the same breast or contralateral breast. Patient's medical chart is available and adequate for data collection Patient properly signed the informed consent form</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>