<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01824563</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this investigation is to generate the needed PMCF data for the HiFocus Mid-Scala electrode. As a point of interest the investigators would like to evaluate the benefit to patients with low-frequency residual hearing implanted with the HiFocus Mid-Scala Electrode. The HiFocus Mid-Scala electrode array is designed to allow surgeons the flexibility to use a variety of contemporary surgical techniques that have been shown to enable easy insertion and to minimize cochlear trauma (see, e.g., Adunka and Buchman, 2007; Friedland and Runge-Samuelson, 2009; Roland et al., 2007). Temporal bone experiments have shown the HiFocus Mid-Scala electrode array to be straightforward to insert while causing minimal trauma to cochlear structures during and after surgery (Lenarz et al., 2010). In addition , the HiFocus Mid-Scala has already shown to be a safe electrode and promising post op clinical results in the premarketing study that is now in the final stage.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Benefits of the HiResolutionTM Bionic Ear System in Adults With Low-Frequency Hearing</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hearing Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years of age or older Definite Postlingual onset of severetoprofound hearing loss as documented by completing main stream primary education. Local language proficiency Bilateral, sensorineural hearing loss Previous inner ear surgery or active middle ear pathology. Cochlear malformation or obstruction Presence of additional disabilities that would prevent or interfere with participation in the required study procedures Medical or psychological conditions that contraindicate surgery or impact the ability to manage an implanted device or the studyrelated procedures Evidence of central auditory lesion or compromised auditory nerve Concurrent participation in other study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>