<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01099579</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether atazanavir powder combined with ritonavir is safe and well tolerated and produces appropriate drug exposure in children ≥3 months to &lt;6 years of age.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PRINCE: Study of Atazanavir (ATV)/Ritonavir (RTV)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atazanavir Sulfate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Confirmed human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)1 infection diagnosed by a positive virologic test result on 2 separate occasions by: HIV DNA polymerase chain reaction HIV RNA with values ≥1,000 copies/mL Positive HIV enzymelinked immunosorbent assay at ≥18 months of age, with confirmatory Western blot or indirect immunoflourescence antibody Infants and children of either sex, aged ≥3 months to &lt;5 years and 6 months at time of first treatment, and weight &gt;5 to &lt;25 kg with any screening baseline plasma viral load Screening plasma viral load ≥1,000 copies/mL by Roche Amplicor® HIV RNA Assay Documented genotypic and phenotypic sensitivity at screening to ATV (fold change in susceptibility &lt;2.2) and to at least 2 nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitors (NRTIs) approved in the infant's country Genotypic sensitivity at screening to atazanavir (ATV) and at least 2 NRTIs Antiretroviral (ARV) treatmentnaive or ARV treatmentexperienced. Treatmentexperienced participants are defined by previous exposure to ARVs through either prior treatment for HIV infection or through postnatal treatment with ≥1 ARV for the prevention of mother to child transmission. For the purposes of this study, participants exposed to ARVs in utero or intrapartum may be included in the study but will be considered treatment naive. ATVnaive participants must have genotypic sensitivity at screening to ATV (fold change in susceptibility &lt;2.2) and to both components of the local NRTI backbone. The NRTIs must have been approved for pediatric use at the local country level. Key Experienced participants who received ATV or ATV/ritonavir (RTV) at any time prior to study enrollment or with a history of 2 or more protease inhibitor failures ARVnaïve or experienced HIV1 infected patients with contraindication to study medications syncope Family history of QTc interval syndrome, Brugada syndrome, right ventricular dysplasia, or a corrected QTc interval at screening of &gt;440 ms One of the following cardiac rhythm abnormalities documented on screening electrocardiogram: 1st degree atrioventricular (AV) block as defined by protocol, type I 2nd degree AV block while awake, type II 2nd degree AV block at any time, complete AV block at any time, or ageadjusted heart rate &lt;2nd percentile) History of pancreatitis, peripheral neuropathy, malignancy that requires systemic therapy, or any medical condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, added undue risk to trial participation Malabsorption syndrome Presence of a newly diagnosed HIVrelated opportunistic infection or any medical condition requiring acute therapy at the time of enrollment Weight &lt;5 or ≥25 kg at date of first dose (Day 1). &gt;Grade 2 aspartate transaminase or alanine transaminase abnormalities Hypersensitivity to any component of the study medication formulations (ATV/RTV, or a locally prescribed NRTI with a pediatric indication) Infants and children of either gender &lt;3 months or ≥5 years and 6 months at the time of first treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>66 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV, Pediatric</keyword>
</DOC>