<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02812420</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this clinical research study is to learn if the combination of durvalumab and tremelimumab is safe and tolerable when given to patients with bladder cancer before surgery to remove the bladder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pre-Surgical Study Evaluating Anti-PD-L1 Antibody (Durvalumab) Plus Anti-CTLA-4 (Tremelimumab) in Patients With Muscle-Invasive, High-Risk Urothelial Carcinoma Who Are Ineligible for Cisplatin-Based Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Drug Administration: If participant is found to be eligible to take part in this study, participant will receive durvalumab and tremelimumab by vein on Day 1 of Weeks 1 and 5. Each study drug infusion will last 1 hour. Participant will receive tremelimumab first and then participant will receive durvalumab about 1 hour later. Study Visits: During Day 1 of Weeks 1 and 5: - Participant will have a physical exam. - Participant's vital signs will be measured within 30 minutes before, every 15 minutes while participant is receiving the study drugs, and 3 times over 1 hour after the end of participant's dose of durvalumab. - Blood (about 3-4 teaspoons) and urine will be collected for routine tests. The blood will also be used to test for hepatitis A, B, and C. This blood or urine collection will also include a pregnancy test if participant can become pregnant. - Blood (about 3-4 tablespoons) will be drawn for immune system testing and thyroid function testing. - Participant will have a cystoscopy to check the status of the disease. If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant may need to have a surgery to remove the tumors. If participant needs this surgery because the disease got worse very quickly, participant may be taken off study. During Week 9 to 11: - Participant will have a physical exam, including measurement of participant's vital signs. - Blood (about 3-4 teaspoons) and urine will be collected for routine tests. The blood will also be used to test for hepatitis A, B, and C. - Participant will have an EKG. - Blood (about 3-4 tablespoons) will be drawn for immune system testing. During Week 9 to 11, participant will have surgery to remove part or all of participant's bladder. Participant will sign a separate consent explaining the surgery and its risks. If during screening participant was told that participant was not eligible to have surgery at Week 9 to 11, participant will have a biopsy after participant's last dose of study drugs. After Surgery (during Weeks 15-17): - Participant will have a physical exam, including measurement of participant's vital signs. - Blood (about 3-4 teaspoons) and urine will be collected for routine tests. The blood will also be used to test for hepatitis A, B, and C. - Blood (about 3-4 tablespoons) will be drawn for immune system testing. Length of Study: Participant will be off study after the Week 17 visit. Participant will no longer be able to take the study drugs if the disease gets worse, if intolerable side effects occur, or if participant is unable to follow study directions. Participation on the study will be over after the follow-up visits. Follow-up Visits: - About 90 days after last dose of study drug, participant will be asked about any side effects and how participant is doing. - Every 3 months for a total of 1 year from the start on the study, participant will be called and asked how participant is doing. This phone call should last about 15 minutes. This is an investigational study. Tremelimumab and durvalumab are not FDA or commercially available for the treatment of bladder cancer. The use of these drugs are considered investigational. Up to 15 participants will be enrolled in this study. All will take part at MD Anderson.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Urologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tremelimumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age &gt;/= 18 years at the time of screening. In general, urothelial cancer occurs in the 6th to 8th decade of life, so it is unlikely that pediatric patients will be included. 2. Patients must have tissue resected by transurethral resection of bladder tissue (TURBT) at the MD Anderson Cancer Center. 3. Patients must have histologic proof of urothelial cancer. This includes bladder cancer, in addition to other tumors of the urothelial lining including renal pelvis, ureteral, and urethral cancer. Upper tract urothelial carcinoma will also be included. This group may include any patient requiring cystectomy, including muscle invasive disease (cT23aN0M0), whose tumor could not be completely removed at transurethral resection. 4. continued 3) Patients with the following highrisk features who are not candidates for traditional neoadjuvant chemotherapy will be included for this trial: micropapillary, sarcomatoid and plasmacytoid features; 3D mass on exam under anesthesia (EUA); lymphovascular continued from 3)invasion; hydronephrosis (unless in the opinion of the treating physician, this is not due to tumor); high grade (grade 3) tumors of the ureter, renal pelvis, or tumors in these areas with radiographic abnormality large enough to recognize as an abnormal mass by CT or MRI imaging; direct invasion of the prostatic stroma or the vaginal wall (i.e. cT4a disease). Patients who are candidates for but refusing conventional chemotherapy may be considered eligible. For patients in whom eligibility is unclear, final arbitration will be determined by the Principal Investigator. 5. Subjects must have no prior exposure to immunotherapy, such as, but not limited to other antiCTLA4, antiPD1, or antiPDL1 antibodies excluding vaccines 6. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 01. 7. Able and willing to give valid written consent for available archival tumor samples or fresh tumor biopsies/resections. 8. Adequate organ and marrow function (subjects must not have received transfusions or growth factor support within 28 days prior to first dose), as defined below: a. Hemoglobin &gt;/= 9 g/dL b. Absolute neutrophil count &gt;/= 1,000/mm^3 c. Platelet count &gt;/= 100,000/mm^3 d. Total bilirubin &lt;/= 1.5 × ULN except subjects with documented Gilbert's syndrome (&gt; 3 × ULN), who must have a baseline total bilirubin &lt;/= 3.0 mg/dL e. Renal function: creatinine &gt; 1.5 x ULN, or a creatinine clearance of &lt; 60 ml/min as calculated by CockcroftGault or by 24hour urine collection. 9. Females of childbearing potential who are sexually active with a nonsterilized male partner must use a highly effective method of contraception from the time of screening, and must agree to continue using such precautions for 180 days after the final dose of investigational product. Cessation of contraception after this point should be discussed with a responsible physician. Periodic abstinence, the rhythm method, and the withdrawal method are not acceptable methods of contraception. They must also refrain from egg cell donation for 180 days after the final dose of investigational product. 10. Nonsterilized males who are sexually active with a female partner of childbearing potential must agree to use a highly effective method of contraception from Day 1 through 90 days after receipt of the final dose of investigational product. In addition, they must refrain from sperm donation for 90 days after the final dose of investigational product 1. Concurrent enrollment in another clinical trial, unless in a followup period or it is an observational study. 2. Any concurrent chemotherapy, immunotherapy, biologic, or hormonal therapy for cancer treatment. Concurrent use of hormones for noncancerrelated conditions (e.g. insulin for diabetes and hormone replacement therapy) is acceptable. 3. Any investigational anticancer therapy received within 28 days prior to the first dose of durvalumab and tremelimumab. 4. Major surgical procedure (as defined by the PI or coPIs within 28 days prior to the first dose of durvalumab and tremelimumab or still recovering from prior surgery. 5. Unresolved toxicities from prior anticancer therapy, defined as having not resolved to NCI CTCAE v4.03 Grade 0 or 1 with the exception of alopecia and laboratory values listed per the inclusion criteria. Subjects with irreversible toxicity that is not reasonably expected to be exacerbated by durvalumab and tremelimumab may be included (e.g. hearing loss) after consultation with the Principal Investigator. 6. Known or suspected autoimmune disease. Patients with a history of inflammatory bowel disease (including Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis) and autoimmune disorders such as rheumatoid arthritis, systemic progressive sclerosis [scleroderma], Systemic Lupus Erythematosus or autoimmune vasculitis [e.g., Wegener's Granulomatosis] are excluded from this study. Patients with a history of Hashimoto's thyroiditis only requiring hormone replacement, Type I diabetes, or psoriasis not requiring systemic treatment, or conditions not expected to recur in the absence of an external trigger are allowed to participate. Any condition requiring systemic treatment with corticosteroids (&gt;10mg daily prednisone equivalents) or other immunosuppressive medications within 14 days prior to first dose of study drug. Inhaled steroids and adrenal replacement steroids doses &gt;10mg daily prednisone equivalents are permitted in the absence of active autoimmune disease. 7. History of primary immunodeficiency. 8. Patients who have organ allografts. 9. True positive test results for hepatitis A, B, or C during screening. 10. Known history of testing positive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or known acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS). 11. Receipt of live, attenuated vaccine within 28 days prior to the first dose of durvalumab and tremelimumab (NOTE: Subjects, if enrolled, should not receive live vaccine during the study and for 180 days after the last dose of both drugs). 12. Females who are pregnant, lactating, or intend to become pregnant during their participation in the study. 13. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, current pneumonitis, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, interstitial lung disease, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements or compromise the ability of the subject to give written informed consent. 14. Other invasive malignancies within 2 years except for noninvasive malignancies such as cervical carcinoma in situ, nonmelanomatous carcinoma of the skin, or ductal carcinoma in situ of the breast, etc. that has/have been surgically cured. 15. Any evidence of metastatic urothelial carcinoma. 16. Known allergy or hypersensitivity to study drug formulations.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Malignant neoplasms of urinary tract</keyword>
	<keyword>Urothelial Carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Muscle-invasive, high-risk bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Ineligible for neoadjuvant cisplatin-containing chemotherapies</keyword>
	<keyword>Bladder cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Cystectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>Bladder cancer surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Durvalumab</keyword>
	<keyword>MEDI4736</keyword>
	<keyword>Tremelimumab</keyword>
	<keyword>Phone calls</keyword>
</DOC>