<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02812342</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to investigate the use of topical tofacitinib to promote hair regrowth in patients with alopecia areata, alopecia totalis, and alopecia universalis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Topical Tofacitinib for the Treatment of Alopecia Areata and Its Variants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This will be an open label clinical trial. We plan to treat 10 adults with AA (with at least 2 patches of alopecia involving the scalp), AT or AU with tofacitinib ointment for a maximum of 6 months. During treatment, patients will be evaluated every 4 weeks and effectiveness of the medication will be measured by changes in hair growth. Laboratory evaluation will be performed before and during treatment in order to monitor for adverse effects of the medication.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alopecia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alopecia Areata</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tofacitinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of AA with at least 2 patches of alopecia involving the scalp, AT or AU Stable hair loss present for 6 months or longer No treatment for alopecia areata in the past 1 month No evidence of spontaneous hair regrowth Patients have received treatment known to affect alopecia areata within 1 month of enrolling in the study Patients whose current episode of AT or AU is more than 5 years Patients with a history of malignancy (except history of successfully treated basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin) Patients known to be HIV or hepatitis B or C positive Patients with positive tuberculin skin test or positive QuantiFERON® TB test Patients with leukopenia or anemia Patients with renal or hepatic impairment Patients taking immunosuppressive medications, including but not limited to prednisone, methotrexate, mycophenolate mofetil, azathioprine, tacrolimus, cyclosporine, or TNFα inhibitors Women who are pregnant or nursing</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alopecia</keyword>
</DOC>