<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01773278</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patients with biochemically confirmed SLOS are being treated with cholesterol supplementation and antioxidant medication. They are carefully monitored with visits to clinic, laboratory testing including cholesterol and 7-dehydrocholesterol levels, vitamin levels, blood counts and liver and kidney function. On an annual basis, the patients undergo a series of tests under anesthesia, including electroretinogram (ERG), brainstem audiometry (ABR), and ophthalmologic exam under anesthesia to follow pigmentary retinopathy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cholesterol and Antioxidant Treatment in Patients With Smith-Lemli-Opitz Syndrome (SLOS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Smith-Lemli-Opitz Syndrome (SLOS) is an autosomal recessive disorder caused by a metabolic error in the final step of cholesterol biosynthesis, leading to cholesterol deficiency and accumulation of the cholesterol precursor, 7-dehydrocholesterol.Patients with SLOS display complex medical problems including growth failure, intellectual disability, behavioral disorders, progressive retinal dystrophy, hearing loss and photosensitivity. Dr Elias was one of the original geneticists who discovered the cause of this disorder in 1994, and ever since has been treating SLOS patients with cholesterol supplementation. Since 2008, a second medication called AquADEKS, a mixture of vitamins and other compounds with antioxidant properties was added to the treatment regimen. The purpose of the AquADEKS is to allow treatment with antioxidant medications in an effort to prevent retinal degeneration, hearing and skin problems associated with SLOS. This protocol has been approved by the Colorado Multiple Institutional Review Board and supported by the Clinical Translational Research Center (CTRC) since 2001. Since the last Colorado Multiple Institutional Review Board annual review, the following updated information is available about the protocol: 1. New research has revealed that oxysterols are toxic compounds made from the cholesterol precursor, 7-dehydrocholesterol. These oxysterol compounds are severely neurotoxic and treatment with antioxidants may help lower their levels, resulting in slowing of retinal deterioration. Testing of oxysterol levels in patients with SLOS is now ongoing, in collaboration with a laboratory at Vanderbilt University (Dr Ned Porter). It is hoped that testing of oxysterol levels in blood may help provide more updated info to help guide treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hearing Loss</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cleft Palate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertelorism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypospadias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Genetic Diseases, X-Linked</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Smith-Lemli-Opitz Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinitis Pigmentosa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antioxidants</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of SmithLemliOpitz Syndrome Elevated levels of 7dehydrocholesterol and 8dehydrocholesterol Must be able to travel to Children's Hospital Colorado annually Must have insurance coverage for ERG/ABR studies absence of detectable 7dehydrocholesterol/8dehydrocholesterol allergy to Antioxidant medication</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Antioxidant treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Oxysterols</keyword>
	<keyword>Cholesterol deficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Accumulation of 7-dehydrocholesterol</keyword>
	<keyword>electroretinogram (ERG)</keyword>
	<keyword>Auditory Brainstem Response (ABR)</keyword>
</DOC>