<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01722500</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim of the International Study of Childhood Obesity, Lifestyle and the Environment (ISCOLE) is to determine the relationship between lifestyle characteristics and obesity in a large multi-national study of 10 year-old children, and to investigate the influence of behavioral settings and physical, social and policy environments on the observed relationships within each country.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>International Study of Childhood Obesity, Lifestyle and the Environment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Data will be collected in 12 countries (500 children per site) from five major regions of the world (Eurasia &amp; Africa, Europe, Latin America, North America, and the Pacific). Cross-sectional evaluations will be undertaken in each country. The physical characteristics of the children will be directly measured in order to classify their body weight and adiposity status, and physical activity and dietary patterns will be measured with the most objective techniques currently available. A concise set of environmental measures that are feasible, valid and meaningful across the international settings included in this research will also be employed. The results of this study will provide a robust examination of the correlates of obesity and weight gain in children, focusing on both sides of the energy balance equation. The results will also provide important new information that will inform the development of lifestyle interventions to address childhood obesity that can be culturally adapted for implementation around the world.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>students 10 years of age has pacemaker or other internal medical devices</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>9 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>11 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>International</keyword>
	<keyword>Childhood</keyword>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>ISCOLE</keyword>
	<keyword>Pennington Biomedical Research Center</keyword>
	<keyword>PBRC</keyword>
	<keyword>longitudinal</keyword>
	<keyword>multinational</keyword>
</DOC>