<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01722513</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this prospective, randomized, controlled study is to investigate the effect of pretreatment with intravenous Alprostadil on the incidence of CIN in a high-risk population of patients with both type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) and CKD undergoing coronary angiography, and evaluate the influence of such potential benefit on short-term outcome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Alprostadil Prevent Contrast Induced Nephropathy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The number of cardiac angiography and percutaneous coronary interventions (PCI) has increased steadily in recent years. This has resulted in the increasing incidence of contrast-induced nephropathy (CIN). Major risk factors for CIN include older age, diabetes mellitus (DM), chronic kidney disease (CKD). The aim of this prospective, randomized, controlled study is to investigate the effect of pretreatment with intravenous Alprostadil on the incidence of CIN in a high-risk population of patients with both type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) and CKD undergoing coronary angiography, and evaluate the influence of such potential benefit on short-term outcome.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alprostadil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient that underwent coronary angiography T2DM CKD stages 2 and 3, eGFR 30 to 89ml/min per 1.73m2 Alprostadil naive, or not on Alprostadil treatment for at least 14 days Withdrawal metformin or aminophylline for 48h before angiography serum Cr. More than 3 mg/dl electrolyte and acidbase imbalance pulmonary edema allergy to Alprostadil</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Contrast Induced Nephropathy</keyword>
</DOC>