<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01722019</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Endovenous ablation of the greater saphenous vein has nowadays the same outcome as open crossectomy and stripping. The two most performed techniques for endovenous ablation are the endovenous laser ablation and the radiofrequency ablation. According to the trial of Rasmussen, they are equivalent for occlusion but the lower laser wave lengths resulted in more pain and paresthesia. The newer wave length of 1470 nm showed lesser side effects in observational studies. The aim of this study is to compare radiofrequency ablation with the VNUS closure fast ® with laser ablation with a 1470 nm wave length in combination with a new fiber, the Tulip fiber ®. This fiber has the shape of a tulip at his tip which avoids point necroses of the vessel wall and on consequence results in lesser side effects from wall perforations such as pain, haematoma,…</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Multicentric Trial Between Radiofrequency Ablation With VNUS Closure Fast ® and Endovenous Ablation With 1470 nm Diode Laser and Tulip Fiber ® for Treatment of Primary Venous Insufficiency.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Venous Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Endovenous ablation of the great saphenous vein (GSV) planned Patient signed informed consent Patient must complete the 1 year followup CEAP between 2 and 6 BMI=&lt;35 Diameter of the GSV in upward position less than 20 mm diameter No problems in deep venous system No informed consent is signed Latex allergy Arterial insufficiency Deep vein thrombosis or deep vein insufficiency Klippel Trenaunay Diameter fo GSV &gt; 20 mm Cross dilation with 2 or more insufficient side branches Previous GSV operation Redooperation Carcinoma less than 1 year ago BMI &gt; 35 Liverinsufficiency with contraindication for local tumescence Intake of warfarins Pregnancy, breastfeeding, &lt; 3 months after pregnancy Bilateral GSV insufficiency that has to be treated Cross insufficiency of the accessory saphenous vein or insufficiency of the subterminal valve of the GSV</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>venous insufficiency</keyword>
</DOC>