<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="184975">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00685932</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21107</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00685932</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mobius速 Post-cesarean Pain Randomized Control Trial</brief_title>
  <official_title>Mobius Pain Study: A Randomized Controlled Trial of Standard Versus Mobius速 Retraction at Cesarean Delivery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Apple Medical Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to investigate whether the use of the Mobius速 retractor
      decreased post-operative pain after cesarean section verses conventional retractor use.
      Based on clinical experience and a pilot study, we suspect that the retractor will decrease
      overall pain as well as lateral pain.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, randomized, patient blinded trial of standard surgical retraction
      versus Mobius速 retraction at cesarean delivery. Women will be approached by their provider
      at their 36 week prenatal visit regarding potential study participation. They will be given
      a letter describing the study. If a woman is interested, she will be contacted by a study
      nurse who will obtain informed consent. Ideally, women will be approached prior to the onset
      of labor or date of scheduled cesarean delivery so as to provide adequate time to review the
      study and ask questions. Women who undergo antenatal admission will be also approached by
      their provider regarding possible study participation and given a recruitment letter. If
      they are interested, then a study nurse will obtain informed consent.

      Consenting women will be randomized after the decision to deliver by cesarean section is
      made. Randomization will be performed in blocks to control for scheduled versus unscheduled
      cesarean deliveries using a random numbers generator. Assignments will be kept in
      sequentially number opaque envelopes. Women will not be informed of their assignment until
      after discharge from the hospital. Efforts will be made in the operating room to avoid
      disclosing group assignment and the consent forms will not contain the specific name of the
      retractor under study. The operative team will be aware of group assignment.

      Participants will complete a 7 item pain scale each post-operative day until discharge. This
      pain scale has been used in a pilot study and found to be accurate. The pain scale is a
      single page and takes less than 5 minutes to complete.

      Charts will be reviewed to obtain clinical information which may have an impact on
      post-operative pain. This includes information about current and past substance abuse.
      Because of the increased amounts of post-operative pain experienced by women who use
      methadone during pregnancy, this group of women will be excluded from the study. To protect
      the information regarding substance abuse, a certificate of confidentiality has been
      obtained from the NIH.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single Blind (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary outcome measure if decreased overall post- cesarean section pain in the Mobius arm of the study.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 days post-operatiion</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondarily we will examine if the Mobius retractor decreases asymmetrical pain which is significantly more common in cesarean section patients versus vaginal delivery patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 days post-operation</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">125</enrollment>
  <condition>Cesarean Section</condition>
  <condition>Pregnancy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will be randomly assigned to have conventional retractions (ie Rich retractors and similar) used in the usual fashion during the cesarean procedure.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mobius</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will be randomized to have the providers who are performing the cesarean section use the Mobius retractor during the cesarean section procedure after the peritoneal cavity is opened.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mobius Retractor</intervention_name>
    <description>The Mobius retractor is a dual ring elastic self retaining retractor that is inserted into the abdominal cavity after the peritoneal incision has been established. It is then left in place during the hysterotomy incision, delivery of the fetus, hysterotomy repair, inspection and irrigation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mobius</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Over 18 years old

          -  Potential for having a cesarean section (scheduled or unscheduled) at Dartmouth
             Hitchcock Medical Center

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Less than 18 years old

          -  Unable to consent due to language barrier or psychiatric illness

          -  Current methadone use for chronic pain

          -  Stat cesarean section
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michele Lauria, MD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lebanon</city>
        <state>New Hampshire</state>
        <zip>03756</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.dhmc.org</url>
    <description>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center home page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rafique Z, Shibli KU, Russell IF, Lindow SW. A randomised controlled trial of the closure or non-closure of peritoneum at caesarean section: effect on post-operative pain. BJOG. 2002 Jun;109(6):694-8.</citation>
    <PMID>12118650</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chanrachakul B, Hamontri S, Herabutya Y. A randomized comparison of postcesarean pain between closure and nonclosure of peritoneum. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2002 Feb 10;101(1):31-5.</citation>
    <PMID>11803097</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Giacalone PL, Daures JP, Vignal J, Herisson C, Hedon B, Laffargue F. Pfannenstiel versus Maylard incision for cesarean delivery: A randomized controlled trial. Obstet Gynecol. 2002 May;99(5 Pt 1):745-50.</citation>
    <PMID>11978282</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kadir RA, Khan A, Wilcock F, Chapman L. Is inferior dissection of the rectus sheath necessary during Pfannenstiel incision for lower segment Caesarean section? A randomised controlled trial. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2006 Sep-Oct;128(1-2):262-6. Epub 2006 Apr 18.</citation>
    <PMID>16621227</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nafisi S. Influence of uterine exteriorization versus in situ repair on post-Cesarean maternal pain: a randomized trial. Int J Obstet Anesth. 2007 Apr;16(2):135-8. Epub 2007 Feb 5.</citation>
    <PMID>17276669</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dunn EA, O'Herlihy C. Comparison of maternal satisfaction following vaginal delivery after caesarean section and caesarean section after previous vaginal delivery. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2005 Jul 1;121(1):56-60.</citation>
    <PMID>15950369</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Granot M, Lowenstein L, Yarnitsky D, Tamir A, Zimmer EZ. Postcesarean section pain prediction by preoperative experimental pain assessment. Anesthesiology. 2003 Jun;98(6):1422-6.</citation>
    <PMID>12766652</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pan PH, Coghill R, Houle TT, Seid MH, Lindel WM, Parker RL, Washburn SA, Harris L, Eisenach JC. Multifactorial preoperative predictors for postcesarean section pain and analgesic requirement. Anesthesiology. 2006 Mar;104(3):417-25.</citation>
    <PMID>16508387</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thompson JF, Roberts CL, Currie M, Ellwood DA. Prevalence and persistence of health problems after childbirth: associations with parity and method of birth. Birth. 2002 Jun;29(2):83-94.</citation>
    <PMID>12051189</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dodd J, Pearce E, Crowther C. Women's experiences and preferences following Caesarean birth. Aust N Z J Obstet Gynaecol. 2004 Dec;44(6):521-4.</citation>
    <PMID>15598289</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McCarthy M Jr, Chang CH, Pickard AS, Giobbie-Hurder A, Price DD, Jonasson O, Gibbs J, Fitzgibbons R, Neumayer L. Visual analog scales for assessing surgical pain. J Am Coll Surg. 2005 Aug;201(2):245-52. Erratum in: J Am Coll Surg. 2005 Nov;201(5):826.</citation>
    <PMID>16038823</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2011</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>October 19, 2011</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 26, 2008</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cesarean section</keyword>
  <keyword>Postpartum pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Post-cesarean pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Surgical retractor</keyword>
  <keyword>Elastic retractor</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
