<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03094663</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A comparison of two pain control methods - the combination of Adductor Canal Block (ACB)/Periarticular Injection (PAI)/Infiltration of the interspace between the popliteal artery and the capsule of the posterior knee (IPACK) versus the Periarticular Injection (PAI) - in patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty. Primary outcome is NRS pain scores with ambulation on postoperative day one (24 hours post-block administration).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adductor Canal Block With Periarticular Injection and IPACK (ACB/PAI/IPACK) Versus Periarticular Injection (PAI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Joint Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cefazolin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epinephrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Racepinephrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epinephryl borate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with osteoarthritis scheduled for a primary either partial or total knee arthroplasty with a participating surgeon Age 18 to 80 years Planned use of regional anesthesia Ability to follow study protocol English speaking (secondary outcomes include questionnaires validated in English only) Patients of participating surgeons Hepatic or renal insufficiency Younger than 18 years old and older than 80 Patients undergoing general anesthesia Allergy or intolerance to one of the study medications BMI &gt; 40 Diabetes ASA of IV Chronic gabapentin/pregabalin use (regular use for longer than 3 months) Chronic opioid use (taking opioids for longer than 3 months, or daily oral morphine equivalent of &gt;5mg/day for one month) Patients with severe valgus deformity and flexion contracture</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>IPACK</keyword>
	<keyword>PAI</keyword>
</DOC>