<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03094390</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aims to test the accuracy of the total thoracic fluid content (TFC) measured by cardiometry can predict weaning-induced pulmonary edema and subsequently weaning failure. Area under receiver operating characteristic curve (AUROC) will be determined, sensitivity, specificity, and best cutoff value will be calculated for TFC in prediction of weaning failure.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Total Thoracic Fluid Content in Prediction of Failure of Weaning From Mechanical Ventilation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Weaning from mechanical ventilation is a serious and challenging process in critical care practice. Weaning failure is associated with poor patient outcomes. Increased mortality in patients with failed weaning was due to development of complications related to re-intubation. Detection and correction of the cause of failed spontaneous breathing trial (SBT) helps the intensives to improve the outcome of the next trials. Fluid overload and positive cumulative fluid balance is a risk factor of weaning failure. Weaning induced pulmonary edema (WIPE) has been reported in both cardiac and non-cardiac patients. Many tools for prediction of weaning induced cardiac edema have been reported. The gold standard for detection of WIPE was pulmonary artery catheter. More simple tools have been investigated for detection of WIPE in patients with or without previous cardiac dysfunction such as extravascular lung water, B-natriuretic peptide (BNP) levels, and biological signs of hemoconcentration. Although measurement of extravascular lung water is a reliable tool for prediction of WIPE, it has the disadvantage of the need of advanced monitor with invasive arterial line. Bioreactance is a new technology used for measurement of cardiac output and total thoracic fluid content (TFC). More recently, electrical velocimetry is a newer technology with good performance in cardiac output monitoring. The use of electrical velocimetry in measurement of TFC has the advantage of being non-invasive with no need for advanced skills. The aim of this work is to validate the use of TFC (measured by electrical velocimetry) and extravascular lung water (measured by lung ultrasound) in prediction of weaning success.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Patients aged 18 years or more scheduled for a twohour spontaneous weaning trial (SBT) using Tpiece or lowpressure support level. Age &lt; 18 years old. Pregnant patients. Neuromuscular disease (stroke, myasthenia gravis and GuillainBarrésyndrome). Tracheostomy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>