<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03094351</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is the first randomized controlled study to compare the robot-assisted thoraco-laparoscopic esophagectomy (RATE) to minimally invasive conventional thoraco-laparoscopic esophagectomy (CTLE). The aim of this trial is to evaluate the safety, risks of the robot-assisted esophagectomy, and to compare the short-term operative outcomes and long-term oncological outcomes between the two surgical treatments.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Robot-assisted Thoraco-laparoscopic Esophagectomy Versus Minimally Invasive Conventional Thoraco-laparoscopic Esophagectomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objective: This study aims to compare the oncological outcomes between robot-assisted thoraco-laparoscopic esophagectomy and minimally invasive conventional thoraco-laparoscopic esophagectomy. Study design: Randomized controlled parallel-group superiority trial Study population: Patients (age &gt;= 18 and &lt;= 75 years) with histologically proven surgically resectable (cT1-4a, N0-3, M0) squamous cell carcinoma of the intrathoracic esophagus with Karnofsky score above 80. Intervention: 300 patients will be randomly allocated to either A) robot-assisted thoraco-laparoscopic esophagectomy (n=150) or B) minimally invasive conventional thoraco-laparoscopic esophagectomy (n=150). Patients will receive the following interventions: Group A. Robot-assisted thoraco-laparoscopic esophagectomy, with gastric conduit formation. Group B. minimally invasive conventional thoraco-laparoscopic esophagectomy, with gastric conduit formation. Main study parameters/endpoints: Primary outcome is 5-year overall survival rate and 5-year disease free survival rate. Secondary outcomes are 3-year overall survival rate, 3-year disease free survival, (in hospital) mortality within 30 and 60 days, R0 resections, operation related events, postoperative recovery, lymph nodes status, quality of life. Follow-up: 60 months after randomization.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically proven squamous cell carcinoma of the intrathoracic esophagus. Surgical resectable (T14a, N03, M0) Age ≥ 18 and ≤ 75 years Karnofsky score above 80 Written informed consent Carcinoma of the cervical esophagus Histologically proven adenocarcinoma or undifferentiated carcinoma. Prior thoracic surgery at the right hemithorax or thorax trauma. Infectious disease with systemic therapy indicated.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>robot assisted esophagectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>minimally invasive esophagectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>esophageal cancer</keyword>
</DOC>