<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00225433</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In vitro fertilization (IVF) is a common procedure used to assist couples who have difficulty conceiving a pregnancy. IVF is a process where oocytes (eggs) are retrieved from a woman's ovaries and fertilized with sperm in the laboratory. In order to maximize the number of oocytes that can be retrieved, a women undergoes ovarian stimulation with recombinant follicle stimulating hormone (FSH). Typically 6-20 oocytes are retrieved, but in some cases there is a limited response to the stimulation, producing a limited number of oocytes. This is called poor ovarian response. This study is designed to objectively compare two treatment regimens currently advocated in clinical practice, but never compared directly. The purpose is to assess ovarian response to starting treatment at the end of the preceding cycle may increase the number of developing oocytes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Luteal Phase FSH in the IVF Poor Responder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ganirelix</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Follicle Stimulating Hormone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Infertile women planning to undergo IVF 2. Poor ovarian response in mostrecent previous IVF cycle within the past 18 months as defined by the following criteria: A) &lt;5 dominant follicles day of hCG, B) &lt;5 oocytes retrieved, or C) cancellation of a previous IVF cycle due to poor response to ovulation stimulation. 3. Aged 2042 (inclusive) at the time of randomization 4. Presence of both ovaries 5. Normal pap smear within past three years 6. At least 45 days after the last IVF cycle 7. Be willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study 8. Have given written informed consent, prior to any studyrelated procedure, not part of normal medical care, with the understanding that consent may be withdrawn by the patient at any time without prejudice to their future medical care. 1. Clinically significant systemic disease 2. Current regular cigarette smoking by patient report 3. Known to be positive for Human Immunodeficiency Virus 4. Any medical condition which, in the judgment of the investigator and sponsor, may interfere with the absorption, distribution, metabolism or excretion of the medications used 5. Abnormal, undiagnosed gynecological bleeding 6. Known allergy or hypersensitivity to human gonadotropin preparations 7. Simultaneous participation in another investigational drug or device trial 8. Subject fails, in 2 separate menstrual cycle attempts, to have FSH ≤12.0 and an ultrasound exam within normal limits (per standard for IVF) at the Baseline Visit 9. For subjects randomized to the Luteal Phase Regimen, failure to ovulate in 2 separate menstrual cycle attempts, as evidenced by ovulation predictor kit, progesterone level, and /or visualization of corpus luteum cyst on an ovary by ultrasound exam at the Luteal Visit</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>42 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>infertility</keyword>
	<keyword>in vitro fertilization</keyword>
</DOC>