<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02186249</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to provide treatment with nivolumab in combination with ipilimumab to subjects who are anti-(CTLA)-4 and anti-PD-1 treatment-naive and have unresectable or metastatic melanoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Expanded Access Program With Nivolumab in Combination With Ipilimumab in Patients With Tumors Unable to be Removed by Surgery or Metastatic Melanoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For more information regarding BMS clinical trial participation, please visit www.BMSStudyConnect.com Men and women 18 years and older Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 01 Histologicallyconfirmed unresectable stage III or stage IV melanoma, as per American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC) staging system, Including mucosal and ocular melanoma Subjects must be antiCTLA4 treatmentnaive and antiPD1 treatmentnaive. Subjects may have had other prior systemic treatment for localized or metastatic disease Subjects with brain metastases are eligible if these have been treated and there is no magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) evidence of progression for at least 2 weeks after treatment is complete and within 28 days prior to first dose of study drug administration. There must also be no requirement for high doses of systemic corticosteroids that could result in Immunosuppression (&gt;10 mg/day prednisone equivalent) for at least 2 weeks prior to study drug administration Active (symptomatic) and not treated brain metastases or leptomeningeal metastases Life expectancy &lt; 6 weeks Subjects with active, known, or suspected autoimmune disease. Subjects with Type I diabetes mellitus, hypothyroidism only requiring hormone replacement, skin disorders (such as vitiligo, psoriasis, or alopecia) not requiring systemic treatment, or conditions not expected to recur in absence of an external trigger are permitted to enroll Subjects with a condition requiring systemic treatment with either corticosteroids (&gt;10 mg daily prednisone equivalents) or other immunosuppressive medications within 14 days of treatment. Inhaled or topical steroids and adrenal replacement steroid doses &gt; 10 mg daily prednisone equivalent are permitted in the absence of active autoimmune disease Subjects who received prior therapy with an antiCTLA4, antiPD1, antiPDL1 or antiPDL2, antiCT137 (or any other antibody or drug specifically targeting Tcell costimulation or checkpoint pathways) or subject is expected to require any other form of systemic antineoplastic therapy while receiving nivolumab</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>