<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01660451</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of the study (part A) is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of BAY80-6946 in patients with indolent or aggressive Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma, who have progressed after standard therapy. 30 patients will be enrolled to both indolent and aggressive disease group. The objective of the study part B is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of BAY80-6946 in patients with relapsed/refractory follicular lymphoma. 120 patients will be enrolled in the part B of the study. Further objectives are to evaluate the pharmacokinetics and biomarkers. Quality of life will be a further objective of part B of the study. In a cohort of 20 patients (enrolled both in part A and B) an ECG substudy will be performed to assess the potential for cardiac toxicity and QT/QTc interval prolongation of BAY80-6946. After an up to 28-day screening period, eligible patients will start treatment with BAY80-6946 at a dose of 0.8 mg/kg (Part A) and at a dose of 60 mg (Part B). Treatment will be continued until disease has progressed or until another criterion is met for withdrawal from study. An end-of-treatment visit will be performed within 7 days after discontinuation of study treatment. Thirty to 35 days after last study drug administration, a safety followup visit will be performed for the collection of adverse events (AEs) and concomitant medication data. Patients will be contacted quarterly to determine overall survival status up to 3 years after last patient first treatment. In Part B, patients will enter the Active Assessment Followup Period. The end of study notification to Health Authorities will be based on the completion of the collection of survival data. The efficacy is measured by the decrease in tumor size. Tumor assessments will be done at Screening, every 8 weeks during Year 1, every 12 weeks during Year 2, and every 6 months during Year 3. Blood samples will be collected for pharmacokinetic analysis. Archival tumor tissue and blood samples will be collected for biomarker analysis (mandatory) and for central pathology review (part B), fresh biopsy tissue will also be collected if available.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-label, Uncontrolled Phase II Trial of Intravenous PI3K Inhibitor BAY80-6946 in Patients With Relapsed, Indolent or Aggressive Non-Hodgkin's Lymphomas (CHRONOS-1)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Indolent NHL: Histologically confirmed diagnosis of follicular lymphoma (FL) grades 1, 2 or 3a, marginal zone lymphoma (including nodal or splenic marginal zone Bcell lymphoma and mucosaassociated lymphoid tissue [MALT] lymphoma), lymphoplasmacytic lymphoma/Waldenström macroglobulinemia, chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL). Relapsed after ≥ 2 prior chemotherapy or immunotherapybased regimens for indolent NHL, or refractory to 2 prior chemotherapy and/ or immunotherapybased regimens. Aggressive NHL: Histologically confirmed diagnosis of grade 3b follicular lymphoma (FL), transformed indolent lymphoma, diffuse large Bcell lymphoma (DLBCL), mediastinal large Bcell lymphoma, mantle cell lymphoma (MCL), peripheral Tcell lymphoma unspecified, or anaplastic large cell lymphoma primary systemic type, or angioimmunoblastic T cell lymphoma. Relapsed after ≥ 2 prior chemotherapy regimens, including the following: Firstline treatment with standard anthracyclinecontaining regimen (e.g., cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, vincristine, and prednisone or equivalent). At least 1 additional combination chemotherapy regimen. Patients relapsed after or refractory to first prior chemotherapy and/or immunotherapybased regimen for aggressive NHL and not eligible for highdose regimen followed by transplant. Highdose chemotherapy, or chemoradiotherapy with autologous stem cell transplantation is considered 1 regimen. Patients with CD20 expressing neoplastic cells must have received prior rituximab, if available. Patients with transformed indolent lymphoma must have received at least 2 prior chemotherapy and/or immunotherapybased regimens Consent to provide fresh tumor tissue during screening Indolent Bcell NHL lymphoma (study part B): Histologically confirmed diagnosis of indolent Bcell NHL, with histological subtype limited to the following: Follicular lymphoma (FL) grade 123a Small lymphocytic lymphoma (SLL) with absolute lymphocyte count &lt; 5 x 109/L at the time of diagnosis and at study entry Lymphoplasmacytoid lymphoma/Waldenström macroglobulinemia (LPL/WM) Marginal zone lymphoma (MZL) (splenic, nodal, or extranodal) Relapsed or refractory after ≥ 2 prior lines of therapy (refractory defined as not responding to a standard regimen or progressing within 6 months of the last course of a standard regimen). Patients must have received Rituximab and alkylating agents. For all patients: Male or female patients &gt; 18 years of age ECOG performance status ≤ 2 (ECOG: Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group) Life expectancy of at least 3 months Adequate bone marrow, liver and renal function as assessed within 7 days before starting study treatment Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ≥ lower limit of normal (LLN) for the Institution Availability of archival tumor tissue Uncontrolled hypertension (blood pressure ≥ 150/90 mmHg despite optimal medical management) Patients with evidence or history of bleeding diathesis. Any hemorrhage or bleeding event ≥ CTCAE Grade 3 within 4 weeks of start of study medication (CTCAE: Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events). History or concurrent condition of interstitial lung disease Unresolved toxicity higher than CTCAE grade 1 (NCICTC version 4.0) attributed to any prior therapy/procedure excluding alopecia. (NCI: National Cancer Institute) Prior treatment with PI3K inhibitors Systemic corticosteroid therapy (ongoing) Hepatitis B or C. All subjects must be screened for hepatitis B and C up to 28 days prior to study drug start using the hepatitis virus panel laboratorial routine. Subjects positive for HBsAg or HBcAb will be eligible if they are negative for HBVDNA; subjects positive for HCV IgG will be eligible if they are negative for HCV RNA. For Part B: Histologically confirmed diagnosis of follicular lymphoma grade 3b or transformed disease and chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) History or concurrent condition of interstitial lung disease or severely impaired pulmonary function Excluded medical conditions: Previous or concurrent cancer that is distinct in primary site or histology from indolent Bcell NHL within 5 years prior to treatment start EXCEPT for curatively treated cervical cancer in situ, nonmelanoma skin cancer and superficial bladder tumors [Ta (noninvasive tumor), Tis (carcinoma in situ) and T1 (tumor invades lamina propria)]. Hepatitis B or C. All subjects must be screened for hepatitis B and C up to 28 days prior to study drug start using the hepatitis virus panel laboratorial routine. Subjects positive for HBsAg or HBcAb will be eligible if they are negative for HBVDNA; subjects positive for HCV IgG will be eligible if they are negative for HCVRNA. Type I or II diabetes mellitus with HbA1c &gt; 8.5% or fasting plasma glucose &gt; 160 mg/dL at screening. Previous or concurrent cancer that is distinct in primary site or histology from indolent Bcell NHL within 5 years prior to treatment start EXCEPT for curatively treated cervical cancer in situ, nonmelanoma skin cancer and superficial bladder tumors [Ta (noninvasive tumor), Tis (carcinoma in situ) and T1 (tumor invades lamina propria)].</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Clinical trial, phase II</keyword>
	<keyword>Phosphatidylinositol 3-Kinase</keyword>
	<keyword>Class I, Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>