<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01660958</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Project Grow Smart evaluates the impact of a 12-month intervention of micronutrient-fortified food and an early learning intervention on young children's cognitive ability. There is an infancy phase and a preschool phase. The infant phase is conducted through home visits - micronutrient sachets are distributed to be mixed with food. The preschool phase is conducted in Anganwadi Centers. Hypothesis #1 is that infants who receive both the micronutrients and the early learning intervention will have better scores on measures of child development than children who receive neither. Children who receive one of the two interventions will have intermediate scores. Hypothesis #2 is that preschoolers in Anganwadi Centers that receive the micronutrient-enriched food wll have better scores on measures of child development than children in Anganwadi Centers who do not. The preschool phase is conducted in Anganwadi Centers (AWC), which are like preschools. Preschoolers age 36-48 months are recruited. AWC are classified as high or low stimulation, based on a rating system (Early Childhood and Childcare Environmental Rating Scale, ECERS). AWC are randomized into 2 cells: 1) multiple micronutrient-fortified food or 2) placebo-fortified food. Preschoolers receive the food in the AWC; their mothers receive information on iron-rich food. For both phases, evaluations are conducted at recruitment and after 6 and 12 months and focus on changes in the children's cognitive performance and micronutrient (iron) status. The investigators hypothesize that innovative multiple micronutrient (MN) fortification strategies for infants and preschoolers combined with early learning opportunities will impact children's micronutrient status, growth and development in Nalgonda district of Andhra Pradesh, India.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Project Grow Smart: Intervention Trial of Multiple Micronutrients and Early Learning Among Infants in India</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Project Grow Smart evaluates the impact of a 12-month intervention of micronutrient-fortified food and an early learning intervention on young children's cognitive ability. There is an infancy phase and a preschool phase. In the infant phase, 6-12 month old infants are recruited and randomized into one of four cells to receive: 1) sachets of multiple micronutrients or sachets of placebo (vitamins) to be added to the infant's food and 2) an early learning intervention delivered in the home or control (no early learning intervention). Families of all infants will receive information on iron rich foods. The preschool phase is conducted in Anganwadi Centers (AWC), which are like preschools. Preschoolers age 36-48 months are recruited. AWC are classified as high or low stimulation, based on a rating system (Early Childhood and Childcare Environmental Rating Scale, ECERS). AWC are randomized into 2 cells: 1) multiple micronutrient-fortified food or 2) placebo-fortified food. Preschoolers receive the food in the AWC; their mothers receive information on iron-rich food. For both phases, evaluations are conducted at recruitment and after 6 and 12 months and focus on changes in the children's cognitive performance and micronutrient (iron) status. The investigators hypothesize that innovative multiple micronutrient (MN) fortification strategies for infants and preschoolers combined with early learning opportunities will impact children's micronutrient status, growth and development in Nalgonda district of Andhra Pradesh, India.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Micronutrients</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trace Elements</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participating children must be in one of two age groups: 612 months or 3648 months, inclusive, at time of recruitment. Participants must reside in the Nalgonda district of Andhra Pradesh, India. Participating children 36 to 48 months of age must attend an Anganwadi Center (preschool) in the Nalgonda district that is participating in Project Grow Smart. Participating caregivers must be at least 18 years of age at the time of recruitment. Children with chronic diseases, developmental disabilities, mental retardation, or severe physical handicaps will be excluded Children with signs of clinical undernourishment (wasting &lt;= 3 SD wt/lgth; anemia &lt; 7 g/dl) will be excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>48 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Micronutrient Deficiencies</keyword>
	<keyword>Early Child Development</keyword>
	<keyword>Infant Growth</keyword>
	<keyword>Iron Deficiency</keyword>
</DOC>