<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01660022</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Phase I Study to investigate the safety, tolerability &amp; pharmacokinetics of co-administered single doses of OZ439 and Piperaquine to healthy subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Tolerability &amp; Pharmacokinetics of Co-administered Single Doses of OZ439 &amp; Piperaquine to Healthy Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Placebo-controlled, double-blind, five-cohort, 2-period (per cohort) dose-escalation study. For each subject, the study included a screening evaluation (within 21 days of the 1st dose), dosing on 2 separate occasions (Period 1 and Period 2) and a follow-up visit (6 weeks following the final dose). Within each cohort, subjects were randomised into two sequences to receive OZ439 in Period 1 and OZ439 plus piperaquine in Period 2 (sequence 1, 8 subjects) or OZ439-matching placebo in Period 1 and OZ439/piperaquine matching placebos in Period 2 (sequence 2, 4 subjects). Safety and tolerability were evaluated: Physical examination, ECG assessments including a full baseline matched profile of ECG tracings, vital signs, laboratory evaluations, in particular liver function tests and adverse events.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Piperaquine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy males &amp; females, 1855 years old BMI 18 to 30kg/m2; total body weight &gt;50kg Healthy, determined by prestudy medical history, physical examination vital signs, 12 Lead ECG Females of nonchildbearing potential. Males must agree to use a double barrier method of contraception Lab tests at screening within the reference ranges Any condition that could affect drug absorption, e.g. gastrectomy, diarrhea Clinically relevant abnormalities in ECG Family history of sudden death or of congenital prolongation of QTc interval History of symptomatic cardiac arrhythmias or with clinically relevant bradycardia Electrolyte disturbances History of drug or alcohol abuse, tobacco users Participation in evaluation of any drug for 3 months before the study Administration of ANY systemic medication/herbal product within 14 days of first dose of study drug. unaccustomed strenuous exercise within 7 days of any study visit Alcohol consumption within 24 hours of any study visit Consumption of any fruit juice or food containing grapefruit within 7 days Positive test for HIV1, HBsAg or HCV Positive urine drug screen at Screening or admission Severe allergies/multiple drug allergies Volunteers who have donated blood or experienced significant blood loss within 90 days of screening Hemoglobin below lower limit of the reference range Clinically relevant abnormal lab values indicative of physical illness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Healthy</keyword>
	<keyword>Volunteers</keyword>
</DOC>