<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01660230</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and pharmacokinetic profile of single and multiple ascending intravenous doses of 3K3A-APC in healthy adult subjects aged 18-55 years.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Pharmacokinetics of Single and Multiple Ascending Doses of 3K3A-APC in Healthy Adult Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single-center, sequential-cohort, double-blind, placebo-controlled, single- and multiple-ascending dose study. Eligible adult subjects will be assigned sequentially to 1 of 10 cohorts, at successively higher single doses, followed by successively higher multiple doses. Single IV Doses: 5 subjects per cohort, aged 18-55, will be randomized in a 4:1 manner to receive active drug (6, 30, 90, 180, 360, and TBD µg/kg) or to receive matching placebo (Cohorts 1-6). Multiple IV Doses: 8 subjects per cohort, aged 18-55, will be randomized in a 3:1 manner to receive active drug (90, 180, 360, and TBD µg/kg) or to receive matching placebo every 12 hours for 5 doses (Cohorts 7-10). Single-Dose Cohorts Subjects receiving a single dose will be confined in a Phase 1 unit for 12 hours prior to dosing, during dosing, and for 24 hours after dosing (Study Day 1-2) for observation and PK sampling. Subjects will return on Study Day 4 (~72 hours after infusion) and Study Day 15 for additional safety evaluations. A 28-Day follow-up phone call will be made to subjects to collect AEs that occur within 28-days of the dose. Multiple-Dose Cohorts Subjects receiving multiple doses will be confined in a Phase 1 unit for 12 hours prior to dosing through 24 hours following the last dose (Study Day 1-4) for observation and PK sampling. Subjects will return on Study Day 6 (~72 hours after last infusion) and Study Day 15 for additional safety evaluations. A 28-Day follow-up phone call will be made to subjects to collect AEs that occur within 28-days of the last dose.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Healthy males or nonpregnant, nonlactating females 2. Both men and women of childbearing potential (i.e., not surgically sterile or postmenopausal defined as age &gt; 40 years without menses for ≥ 2 years) must agree to use a barrier method of contraception plus a spermicide throughout the study. 3. Age 18 to 55 years, inclusive 4. Body Mass Index (BMI) of 19 to 30 kg/m2, inclusive (see APPENDIX B) 5. Willing and able to complete all study visits 6. Agreement to abstain from smoking and drinking alcoholic beverages from 48 hours prior to randomization through last Study Day (15) 7. Signed informed consent form (ICF) 1. Any medical problem for which the subject is being evaluated and/or treated 2. Activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) greater than upper limit of normal (ULN) 3. Platelet count &lt; 125,000 cells/mm3 4. International Normalized Ratio (INR) &gt; 1.3 5. Any other clinically significant abnormalities in laboratory values (chemistries, hematology, coagulation studies, and urinalysis see APPENDIX C) 6. Clinically significant abnormalities on electrocardiogram (ECG) 7. Positive serum βHCG pregnancy test at screening or on Study Day 1 (for all women, regardless of childbearing potential) 8. Positive urine drug screen at screening or on Study Day 1 (see APPENDIX C) 9. Positive blood test for hepatitis B surface antigen, hepatitis C antibody, or HIV antibody 10. Known family history of bleeding or blood clotting disorders 11. History of bleeding diathesis 12. History of liver disease with ongoing coagulopathy 13. Use of any prescription or nonprescription medications or supplements within 7 days prior to Study Day 1, excluding hormonal contraceptives 14. Use of anticoagulant medication within 14 days prior to Study Day 1 15. Major surgery within 60 days prior to Study Day 1 16. Receipt of an investigational drug within 30 days prior to Study Day 1 17. Donation of blood or plasma within 30 days prior to Study Day 1 18. Any other condition, that in the opinion of the Site Investigator, may adversely affect the safety of the subject, the subject's ability to complete the study, or the outcome of the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>APC, 3K3A, 3K3A-APC, volunteer, healthy</keyword>
</DOC>