<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002546</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Radiation therapy uses high-energy x-rays to damage tumor cells. Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. It is not yet known whether radiation therapy is more effective than combination chemotherapy in treating patients with cancer of the uterus. PURPOSE: This randomized phase III trial is studying radiation therapy to see how well it works compared to combination chemotherapy in treating patients with cancer of the uterus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Radiation Therapy Compared With Combination Chemotherapy in Treating Patients With Cancer of the Uterus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Compare the survival, progression-free interval, and failure patterns in patients with optimally debulked stage I-IV carcinosarcoma of the uterus treated with whole abdominal radiotherapy vs ifosfamide and cisplatin. - Compare the incidence and type of acute and late adverse events observed with these treatment regimens in this patient population. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, multicenter study. Patients are randomized to one of two treatment arms. - Arm I: Patients receive whole abdominal radiotherapy 5 days a week for 4 weeks, followed by radiotherapy boost to the pelvis 5 days a week for 2.2 weeks. - Arm II: Patients receive cisplatin IV followed by ifosfamide IV over 1 hour on days 1-4. Treatment continues every 3 weeks for 3 courses. Patients are followed every 3 months for 2 years, every 6 months for 3 years, and then annually thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 216 patients will be accrued for this study within 6 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isophosphamide mustard</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ifosfamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed primary homologous or heterologous carcinosarcoma of the uterus (corpus and cervix) Surgical stage IIV disease, including positive adnexa, tumor invading the serosa, positive pelvic and/or paraaortic nodes, involvement of the mucosa of the bowel, bladder, or rectum, intraabdominal metastases, positive pelvic washings, or vaginal involvement within planned radiation port Prior total abdominal hysterectomy with bilateral salpingooophorectomy and maximum tumor resection of all gross intraabdominal/pelvic disease, including grossly involved pelvic and paraaortic nodes within 8 weeks before study No greater than 1 cm residual disease Cervical sarcomas also allowed No metastasis beyond the abdominal cavity at diagnosis, including the following: Parenchymal liver metastasis Lung metastasis Positive inguinal lymph nodes Positive scalene nodes Radiographic or pathologic evidence of bone or brain metastasis PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 21 and over Performance status: GOG 02 Hematopoietic: WBC at least 3,000/mm3 Granulocyte count at least 1,500/mm3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm3 Hepatic: Bilirubin no greater than 1.5 times normal SGOT no greater than 3 times normal Albumin at least 3 g/dL No acute hepatitis Renal: Creatinine no greater than 1.5 mg/dL OR Creatinine clearance at least 50 mL/min Other: No septicemia No severe infection No severe gastrointestinal bleeding No prior invasive or concurrent malignancy within the past 5 years except nonmelanoma skin cancer PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: No prior chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: Prior hormonal therapy allowed Radiotherapy: See Disease Characteristics No prior radiotherapy Surgery: See Disease Characteristics Other: No prior therapy that would preclude study therapy</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage I uterine sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II uterine sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III uterine sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV uterine sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>uterine carcinosarcoma</keyword>
</DOC>