<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002160</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To determine the safety and efficacy of SNX-111 in controlling severe, chronic pain in cancer and AIDS patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Multicenter Phase II/III, Placebo-Controlled Study of SNX-111 Administered Intrathecally to Cancer and AIDS Patients With Chronic Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients are randomized to receive SNX-111 or placebo (AS PER AMENDMENT 1/22/98: with randomization weighted 2:1 in favor of SNX-111) via external pump and an intrathecal catheter (thin tube inserted into the spinal canal). (AS PER AMENDMENT 1/22/98: the dose is increased every 24 hours, in the absence of onset of analgesia or adverse events. After 2-5 days, patients who respond to their medication continue treatment at home for 5-8 days. Patients who do not respond will be switched to the other regimen (i.e., placebo to SNX-111, or SNX-111 to placebo). After 10 days, responding patients are unblinded and asked to enroll in the long-term, open-label extension protocol. Patients remain on a fixed dose at the therapeutic level found in the previous study. The dose may be increased or decreased at the discretion of the investigator. Patients may continue therapy on a long-term basis until the drug is approved.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ziconotide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Concurrent Medication: Allowed: Rescue analgesia. Patients must have: Chronic pain related to AIDS or cancer. Unsatisfactory response to prior opioid therapy. Life expectancy &gt; 3 months (or 1 month if an infusion pump is in place). Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following symptoms or conditions are excluded: Signs of sepsis or inadequately treated infection. Patients with the following prior conditions are excluded: History of heart disease, heart failure, or asthma.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 1998</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS-Related Complex</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain</keyword>
	<keyword>Palliative Care</keyword>
	<keyword>omega-conopeptide MVIIA</keyword>
	<keyword>Calcium Channel Blockers</keyword>
</DOC>