<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002563</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Quality-of-life assessment in patients undergoing cancer treatment may help determine the intermediate- and long-term effects of treatment on patients with cancer. PURPOSE: This clinical trial studies the impact of therapy on the health status and quality of life of patients with stage I or stage II Hodgkin's disease who are receiving radiation therapy with or without chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SWOG-9208 Quality of Life and Health Status in Patients With Stage I or Stage II Hodgkin's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Evaluate prospectively the health status and quality of life of patients with Stage I/IIA Hodgkin's disease randomized on protocol SWOG-9133 (CLB-9391) to treatment with subtotal nodal irradiation with vs. without 3 courses of doxorubicin/vinblastine. II. Describe the short-term effects of these treatments on these patients and compare their impact on quality of life (i.e., patient symptom status, health status, fatigue). III. Evaluate the intermediate and long-term effects of these treatments on these patients and compare their impact on quality-of-life outcomes over 5 years. OUTLINE: Quality-of-Life Assessment. Cancer Rehabilitation Evaluation System Short Form, CARES-SF; Symptom and Personal Information Questionnaire (including Symptom Distress Scale, MOS SF-36 Fatigue Scale, MOS SF-36 Health Perception Rating, Demographics); Cover Sheet. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: Approximately 500 patients will be accrued over 7 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Patients must be eligible for and registered to SWOG9133 PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Patients must be able to complete the questionnaires in English. If they are not able to complete questionnaires in English, patients may be registered to SWOG9133 without participating in SWOG9208. The Symptom and Personal Information Questionnaire #1, the Cancer Rehabilitation Evaluation System Short Form (CARESSF) and Cover Sheet must be completed prior to registration and randomization on SWOG9133.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage I adult Hodgkin lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II adult Hodgkin lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>psychosocial effects of cancer and its treatment</keyword>
</DOC>