<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002754</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Monoclonal antibodies can locate tumor cells and either kill them or deliver tumor-killing substances to them without harming normal cells. PURPOSE: Phase I/II trial to determine the effectiveness of monoclonal antibody therapy in treating patients who have primary or metastatic melanoma or brain tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Monoclonal Antibody Therapy in Treating Patients With Primary or Metastatic Melanoma or Brain Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the toxicity and maximum tolerated dose of iodine-131-labeled monoclonal antibody fragment ME1-14 F(ab')2 administered intracystically in patients with recurrent or newly diagnosed primary or metastatic malignant melanoma or other brain tumors. II. Identify any objective therapeutic responses to this treatment. OUTLINE: All patients receive a fixed dose of monoclonal antibody fragment ME1-14 F(ab')2 via an intralesional catheter; cohorts of 3-6 patients receive escalating doses of isotope conjugated to the antibody until the maximum tolerated dose is determined. Patients with newly diagnosed disease at entry may receive additional therapy with external-beam radiotherapy beginning 4 months after radioimmunotherapy (or sooner if disease progression occurs). Patients with recurrent disease at entry are followed without further therapy for at least 4 months after radioimmunotherapy; alternative therapy may be offered upon progression. All patients are followed at 4, 8, 16, and 24 weeks after treatment, then every 12 weeks for 1 year. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: Three to six patients will be entered at each dose studied.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed primary or metastatic malignant melanoma OR Histologically confirmed supratentorial malignant brain tumor Newly diagnosed or recurrent primary or metastatic tumor Eligible primary histologies, including but not limited to: Glioblastoma multiforme Mixed anaplastic glioma Anaplastic astrocytoma Other astrocytoma Gliosarcoma Anaplastic oligodendroglioma The following excluded: Diffusely infiltrating tumors Multifocal tumors Infratentorial tumors Subependymal spread No measurable enhancing lesion extending more than 1 cm beyond margins of surgical cavity on contrastenhanced CT or MRI performed within 72 hours after resection Intralesional catheter placed at resection Patency of catheter demonstrated by radiolabeled albumin flow Reactivity of neoplastic cells with intact Me114 IgG2a or Me114 F(ab')2 demonstrated by immunohistology with polyclonal rabbit antibody or monoclonal mouse antibody PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 3 and over Performance status: Karnofsky 50%100% Hematopoietic: Absolute neutrophil count greater than 1,000/mm3 Platelet count greater than 100,000/mm3 Hepatic: Bilirubin less than 1.5 mg/dL AST less than 1.5 times normal Alkaline phosphatase less than 1.5 times normal Renal: Creatinine less than 1.2 mg/dL Other: Not pregnant PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: At least 6 weeks since antineoplastic chemotherapy unless unequivocal tumor progression Endocrine therapy: Concurrent corticosteroids allowed at lowest possible dose and stable for at least 10 days prior to entry Radiotherapy: At least 3 months since radiotherapy to site of measurable disease within the nervous system unless unequivocal tumor progression Surgery: See Disease Characteristics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent adult brain tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>adult glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>tumors metastatic to brain</keyword>
	<keyword>childhood high-grade cerebral astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic oligodendroglioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult mixed glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent childhood cerebral astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult giant cell glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult gliosarcoma</keyword>
</DOC>