<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002173</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To provide an alternative therapy to HIV-infected patients for whom there is no comparable or satisfactory alternative drug or therapy available.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Expanded Access Open Label Protocol of Remune (HIV-1 Immunogen) in HIV-1-Infected Adults With CD4 Count 550 Cells /Ml and Greater.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients must have: HIV1 seropositivity. CD4 counts &gt;= 550 cells/ml. NOTE: If a patient's CD4 count is 550 to 600 cells/ml, the patient must either rescreen within 30 days for Study 806 or wait 6 months before entering the expanded access program. Patient must have failed or been intolerant to other comparable or alternative marketed therapies or must not be a candidate for such therapies. Patient must not meet inclusion criteria for other Remune trials. Patient must have laboratory tests within specified limits. Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following symptoms and conditions are excluded: Clinically significant cardiac, hepatic, renal or gastrointestinal dysfunction. Current participation in a Remune study. Concurrent Medication: Excluded: Use of any immunemodulating drugs. Induction therapy or initiation of new treatment regimen for an AIDSdefining condition. Current participation in a Remune study. Patients with any of the following prior conditions are excluded: Previous participation in a Remune study. Prior Medication: Excluded: Previous participation in a Remune study. Excluded within 30 days of study entry: Use of any immunemodulating drugs. Induction therapy or initiation of new treatment regimen for an AIDSdefining condition within 30 days of Day 1 visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 1998</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS Vaccines</keyword>
	<keyword>CD4 Lymphocyte Count</keyword>
	<keyword>Salk HIV Immunogen</keyword>
</DOC>