<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002572</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Biological therapy uses different ways to stimulate the immune system and stop cancer cells from growing. Cytotoxic T cells combined with interleukin-2 may be an effective treatment for recurrent brain tumors. PURPOSE: Phase I trial to study the effectiveness of cytotoxic T cells and interleukin-2 in treating adults with recurrent brain tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cytotoxic T Cells and Interleukin-2 in Treating Adult Patients With Recurrent Brain Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Evaluate the toxicity of allogeneic cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTL) when repeatedly instilled directly into the brain to treat recurrent primary brain tumors. II. Evaluate the response produced by allogeneic CTL and interleukin-2. III. Correlate CTL surface phenotype and degree of patient/donor HLA mismatch to response and toxicity. OUTLINE: Surgery plus Biological Response Modifier Therapy. Tumor resection; plus intracavitary cytotoxic T lymphocytes, CTL; intracavitary Interleukin-2 (Chiron), IL-2, NSC-373364. CTL are generated in vitro by mixing irradiated patient lymphocytes (cultured with IL-2 and Monoclonal Antibody OKT 3, MOAB OKT 3, NSC-618843) with allogeneic lymphocytes and culturing the mixture with IL-2. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: 10 patients will be treated. If severe toxicity occurs in the first 5 patients, the study will close.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aldesleukin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interleukin-2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Muromonab-CD3</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Kernohan Grade III/IV primary malignant brain tumor that has failed conventional surgical resection and radiotherapy Evidence of recurrent tumor on gadoliniumenhanced MRI following completion of radiotherapy (minimum 5,000 cGy for adults) required The following histologies are eligible: Anaplastic astrocytoma Anaplastic oligodendroglioma Glioblastoma multiforme Mixed anaplastic glioma Surgical resection of progressing brain tumor feasible No evidence of tumor extending across the midline from one hemisphere to the other No multifocal tumor or leptomeningeal spread PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: Over 18 Performance status: Karnofsky 60100% Life expectancy: At least 2 months Hematopoietic: WBC greater than 2,000 Platelets greater than 100,000 Hct at least 28% Hepatic: Bilirubin less than 1.5 mg/dl Renal: Creatinine less than 1.5 mg/dl Cardiovascular: No major cardiovascular problems Pulmonary: No major pulmonary problems Other: Seronegative for HTLV/HIV, syphilis, and hepatitis B and C No concurrent systemic infection Ability to maintain proper nutrition (orally or intravenously) during the study period required No pregnant women PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: More than 4 weeks since systemic chemotherapy (6 weeks since carmustine), with the WBC increasing on 2 consecutive determinations at least 3 days apart Endocrine therapy: Not specified Radiotherapy: At least 8 weeks since radiotherapy Surgery: See Disease Characteristics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2000</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent adult brain tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>adult glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult anaplastic oligodendroglioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult mixed glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult giant cell glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult gliosarcoma</keyword>
</DOC>