<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002148</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the tolerability and safety of OPC-14117. To evaluate effects of OPC-14117 on cognitive function, quality of life, and activities of daily living.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Parallel Group, Placebo-Controlled, Tolerability, Safety, and Efficacy Study of OPC-14117 in HIV Dementia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients receive OPC-14117 or placebo bid for 12 weeks, followed by 12 weeks of open label therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>AIDS Dementia Complex</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients must have: HIV seropositivity. Cognitive impairment. Prior Medication: Allowed: Prior OPC14117 other than on the current study. Antiretroviral therapy if stable for 6 weeks prior to study entry (12 weeks for stavudine). Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following symptoms or conditions are excluded: Current opportunistic CNS infection (i.e., toxoplasmosis or cryptococcal meningitis). Severe premorbid psychiatric illness including schizophrenia and major depression that would interfere with protocol compliance. CNS neoplasms. Any other clinically significant condition or laboratory abnormality that would interfere with ability to participate on study. Current participation in other drug studies. Patients with the following prior conditions are excluded: Past history of opportunistic CNS infection (i.e., toxoplasmosis or cryptococcal meningitis). History of chronic neurological disorders such as serious head injury, documented stroke, multiple sclerosis, uncontrolled epilepsy, Tourette's syndrome, and other neurodegenerative processes such as Huntington's disease. History of adverse reaction / allergy to OPC14117. Prior participation on this study. Prior Medication: Excluded: Other investigational drugs within the past 30 days. Alcoholism within past 6 months (more than 2 drinks daily).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 1996</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cognition Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS-Related Complex</keyword>
	<keyword>Free Radical Scavengers</keyword>
	<keyword>Antioxidants</keyword>
	<keyword>OPC 14117</keyword>
</DOC>