<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002576</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Combining more than one drug may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: Randomized phase III trial to compare the effectiveness of combination chemotherapy consisting of cyclophosphamide, vincristine, and prednisolone, with either mitoxantrone or doxorubicin in treating patients with intermediate- or high-grade non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination Chemotherapy in Treating Older Patients With Intermediate- or High-Grade Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Assess the treatment-related neurologic and hematologic toxicities of patients aged 65 years and over with intermediate- or high-grade non-Hodgkin's lymphoma randomized to CHOP (cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, vincristine, prednisolone) vs. MCOP (mitoxantrone, cyclophosphamide, vincristine, prednisolone). II. Compare the survival rate in these patients. OUTLINE: Randomized study. The following acronyms are used: CHOP CTX/DOX/VCR/PRDL CTX Cyclophosphamide, NSC-26271 DHAD Mitoxantrone, NSC-301739 DOX Doxorubicin, NSC-123127 MCOP DHAD/CTX/VCR/PRDL PRDL Prednisolone, NSC-9900 VCR Vincristine, NSC-67574 Arm I: 4-Drug Combination Chemotherapy. CHOP. Arm II: 4-Drug Combination Chemotherapy. MCOP. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 200 patients will be entered over approximately 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitoxantrone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vincristine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed intermediate or highgrade non Hodgkin's lymphoma of the following types: Diffuse centroblastic Diffuse immunoblastic B and Tcell lymphoblastic Peripheral Tcell (mixed or large cell) and Ki1 No Stage IA (nonbulky) disease suitable for radiotherapy alone PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 65 and over Performance status: Not specified Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Cardiovascular: No severe ischemic heart disease No cardiomyopathy that would restrict doxorubicin use Other: No other serious medical conditions that would affect treatment outcome No prior malignancy except: Nonmelanomatous skin cancer Adequately treated in situ cervical cancer Sufficiently fit to receive treatment PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: No prior chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: Not specified Radiotherapy: No prior radiotherapy Surgery: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage I adult diffuse mixed cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I adult immunoblastic large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I adult lymphoblastic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I adult Burkitt lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II adult diffuse mixed cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II adult immunoblastic large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II adult lymphoblastic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II adult Burkitt lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult diffuse mixed cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult immunoblastic large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult lymphoblastic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult Burkitt lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult diffuse mixed cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult immunoblastic large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult lymphoblastic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult Burkitt lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>contiguous stage II adult diffuse mixed cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>contiguous stage II adult immunoblastic large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>contiguous stage II adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>contiguous stage II adult Burkitt lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>contiguous stage II adult lymphoblastic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>noncontiguous stage II adult diffuse mixed cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>noncontiguous stage II adult immunoblastic large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>noncontiguous stage II adult diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>noncontiguous stage II adult Burkitt lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>noncontiguous stage II adult lymphoblastic lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>