<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002227</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see if it is safe and effective to give efavirenz plus stavudine plus lamivudine to patients who have never taken anti-HIV drugs.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Efavirenz in HIV-Infected Patients Who Have Never Taken Anti-HIV Drugs</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients will be given combination treatment with efavirenz, stavudine, and lamivudine.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stavudine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Efavirenz</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lamivudine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients must have: Documented diagnosis of HIV infection with plasma HIVRNA greater than or equal to 10,000 copies/ml. Life expectancy of at least 12 months. Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following symptoms or conditions are excluded: Current bilateral peripheral neuropathy greater than or equal to Grade 2. Proven or suspected acute hepatitis due to any cause. Recurrent episodes of moderate to severe diarrhea, or vomiting lasting for more than 4 days within 3 months prior to dosing. Hypersensitivity to any component of the formulation of efavirenz, stavudine, or lamivudine. Any clinically significant laboratory findings obtained during the screening evaluation (see laboratory values). Any clinically significant disease (other than HIV infection) or clinically significant findings found during the screening of medical history or physical examination. Any malignancy that requires systemic therapy. Any active AIDSdefining opportunistic infection or disease. Concurrent Medication: Excluded: Astemizole, cisapride, clarithromycin, ketoconazole, itraconazole, midazolam, rifabutin, rifampin, terfenadine, thalidomide, triazolam, vincristine, zalcitabine or any medications contraindicated for concomitant use with stavudine or lamivudine as described in the current information package insert. Patients with the following prior conditions are excluded: History of acute or chronic pancreatitis. A life expectancy of less than 12 months. Difficulty swallowing capsules/tablets. Inability to communicate effectively with study personnel. Prior Medication: Excluded: Any other experimental drug within 30 days of introducing study treatment. Vaccination within 3 weeks of screening visit. Any prior antiretroviral therapy. Interferon started within 30 days of initiating study treatment. Risk Behavior: Excluded: Current alcohol or illicit drug use which interferes with patient's ability to follow study regimen.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 1998</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy, Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>Stavudine</keyword>
	<keyword>Lamivudine</keyword>
	<keyword>Reverse Transcriptase Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>efavirenz</keyword>
</DOC>