<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002008</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To determine the safety, immunogenicity, biological activity, ad pharmacokinetics of sargramostim ( recombinant granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor; GM-CSF ) human granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor ( GM-CSF ), given by subcutaneous ( SC ) injection to patients with leukopenia in association with HIV infection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Open Label Phase I Study of Subcutaneously Administered Recombinant Human GM-CSF in Patients With AIDS Virus Infection and Leukopenia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukopenia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients must have: Serum antibody to HIV with or without evidence of HIV. Antigenemia. Anticipated survival of at least 6 months. Allowed: Kaposi's sarcoma. Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following conditions or symptoms are excluded: Malignancy other than Kaposi's sarcoma. Excessive diarrhea (more than 5 liquid or nonliquid stools per day). Currently hospitalized or hospitalized within the last 4 weeks for the treatment of opportunistic infection. Primary hematologic or infectious disorders unrelated to AIDS virus infection. Dementia or altered mental status that would prohibit the giving and understanding of informed consent. Patients with the following are excluded: History of malignancy other than Kaposi's sarcoma. Currently hospitalized or hospitalized within 4 weeks for the treatment of opportunistic infection. Prior Medication: Excluded within 3 weeks of study entry: Marrow suppressive medication. Excluded within 4 weeks of study entry: Any investigational drug. Prior Treatment: Excluded within 4 weeks of study entry: Systemic cytotoxic chemotherapy. Irradiation. Risk Behavior: Excluded within 3 months of study entry: Regular, excessive users of alcohol, hallucinogens, or agents which are addicting.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 1989</verification_date>
	<keyword>Leukopenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Evaluation</keyword>
	<keyword>Granulocyte-Macrophage Colony-Stimulating Factor</keyword>
</DOC>