<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002266</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To compare AS-101 dosing schedules (once a week; 3 times a week; 5 times a week; or 5 times per week on alternate weeks) on the effect on clinical immunology and virus burden in AIDS or AIDS related complex (ARC) patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Open Parallel Study to Determine the Optimum Dosing Schedule for AS-101 in AIDS/ARC Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ammonium trichloro(dioxoethylene-O,O'-)tellurate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Concurrent Medication: Allowed: Standard therapy for infections. Acyclovir. Ganciclovir. Allowed only with permission of WyethAyerst medical monitor: Zidovudine (AZT). Immunomodulators. Specific therapy for malignancies (including Kaposi's sarcoma). Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following conditions or symptoms are excluded: Evidence of severe liver dysfunction (serum albumin &lt; 3 g/dl, SGOT or SGPT &gt; 5 x upper limit of normal, prothrombin time &gt; 15 seconds), or gastrointestinal, renal, respiratory, endocrine, hematologic, cardiovascular system abnormalities or psychiatric disorder other than abnormalities secondary to AIDS or AIDS related complex (ARC). Evidence of AIDSrelated central nervous system involvement. Disseminated Kaposi's sarcoma. Concurrent Medication: Excluded without permission of WyethAyerst medical monitor: Zidovudine (AZT). Immunomodulators. Specific therapy for malignancies (including Kaposi's sarcoma). Patients with the following are excluded: Evidence of major system abnormalities other than abnormalities secondary to AIDS or AIDS related complex. Concomitant conditions as specified in Patient Exclusion Coexisting Conditions. Unlikely or unable to comply with the requirements of the protocol. Prior Medication: Excluded within 4 weeks of study entry: Systemic antiviral agents. Immunosuppressive agents. Immune stimulators such as BCG vaccine, isoprinosine, or other immunomodulators. Patients must: Have a diagnosis of AIDS or AIDS related complex (ARC). Demonstrate intolerance or refusal to take zidovudine (AZT). Provide written informed consent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 1990</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy, Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS-Related Complex</keyword>
	<keyword>ammonium trichloro(dioxoethylene-O,O'-)tellurute</keyword>
</DOC>