<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002440</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to see if it is safe and effective to give 1592U89 plus certain protease inhibitors (PIs) to HIV-infected patients who never have been treated with anti-HIV drugs. This study also examines how the body processes these drugs when they are given together.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of 1592U89 in Combination With Protease Inhibitors in HIV-Infected Patients Who Have Never Taken Anti-HIV Drugs</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this Phase II, open-label study patients (16 per treatment group) are randomized to receive 1592U89 in combination with one of five protease inhibitors: indinavir, saquinavir, ritonavir, nelfinavir, or 141W94 for up to 48 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nelfinavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Protease Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Indinavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Saquinavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amprenavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abacavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Protease Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Concurrent Medication: Allowed: Local treatment for Kaposi's sarcoma. GMCSF, GCSF or erythropoietin. Patients must have: HIV1 infection documented by a licensed HIV1 antibody ELISA and confirmed by Western blot detection of HIV1 antibody or a positive HIV1 blood culture. CD4+ cell count &gt;= 100 cells/mm3 within 14 days of study drug administration. HIV1 RNA &gt;= 5,000 copies/ml within 14 days of study drug administration. No active or ongoing AIDSdefining opportunistic infection or disease. Signed, informed consent from parent or legal guardian for patients less than 18 years of age. Prior Medication: Allowed: Local treatment for Kaposi's sarcoma. Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following conditions or symptoms are excluded: Malabsorption syndrome, or other gastrointestinal dysfunction, that might interfere with drug absorption or render the patient unable to take oral medication. Lifethreatening infection or other serious medical condition that may compromise a patient's safety. Concurrent Medication: Excluded: Other investigational agents. NOTE: Those available through Treatment IND or expanded access programs are evaluated individually. Chemotherapeutic agents for the initial 24 weeks of study (except local treatment for Kaposi's sarcoma). Agents with documented antiHIV activity in vitro. Foscarnet. Immunomodulating agents such as systemic corticosteroids, interleukins, thalidomide, anticytokine agents or interferons. Antioxidants. Concurrent Treatment: Excluded: Radiation therapy within the first 24 weeks of study. Patients with the following prior conditions are excluded: History of clinically relevant pancreatitis or hepatitis within the last 6 months. Participation in an investigational HIV1 vaccine trial. Prior Medication: Excluded: Antiretroviral therapy, including reverse transcriptase inhibitor and protease inhibitor therapy. Cytotoxic chemotherapeutic agents within 30 days of study drug administration. HIV1 vaccine dose within the 3 months prior to study drug administration. Immunomodulating agents, such as systemic corticosteroids, interleukins or interferons within 30 days of study drug administration. Prior Treatment: Excluded: Radiation therapy within 30 days of study drug administration. Alcohol or illicit drug use that may interfere with patient compliance.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 1998</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV-1</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy, Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Protease Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>Mutation</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV-1 Reverse Transcriptase</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Protease</keyword>
	<keyword>Reverse Transcriptase Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-HIV Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>abacavir</keyword>
</DOC>