<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002557</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Combining more than one drug may kill more tumor cells. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of etoposide with or without doxorubicin and methotrexate in treating patients who have mycosis fungoides.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination Chemotherapy in Patients With Advanced or Recurrent Mycosis Fungoides</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Assess the response rate in patients with Stage III/IV or recurrent mycosis fungoides or Sezary syndrome treated with oral etoposide, with the addition of doxorubicin, then methotrexate for poor responders. II. Assess changes in the hematologic and immunologic status of the tumor in these patients. OUTLINE: Patients are treated sequentially on Regimens A, B, and C depending on response. The following acronyms are used: CF Leucovorin calcium, NSC-3590 DOX Doxorubicin, NSC-123127 MTX Methotrexate, NSC-740 VP-16 Etoposide, NSC-141540 Regimen A: Single-Agent Chemotherapy. VP-16. Regimen B: 2-Drug Combination Chemotherapy. VP-16/DOX. Regimen C: 3-Drug Combination Chemotherapy. VP-16/DOX/MTX. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: Study duration will be at least 3 years with an anticipated accrual of 3 patients/year.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycoses</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycosis Fungoides</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levoleucovorin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Stage III/IV mycosis fungoides or Sezary syndrome Stage I/II cutaneous Tcell lymphoma in relapse following interferon therapy also eligible PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: Not specified PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Prior interferon alpha for Stage I/II disease allowed Chemotherapy: Prior isotretinoin for Stage I/II disease allowed Endocrine therapy: Prior topical steroids for Stage I/II disease allowed Radiotherapy: Prior ultraviolet therapy for Stage I/II disease allowed Prior xray therapy for Stage I/II disease allowed Surgery: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2000</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage III cutaneous T-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV cutaneous T-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent cutaneous T-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>