<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002921</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Some tumors need growth factors produced by the body to keep growing. Suramin may interfere with the growth factor and stop the tumor from growing. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of suramin in treating patients with stage III or stage IV adrenocortical cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>S9427, Suramin in Treating Patients With Stage III or Stage IV Adrenocortical Cancer Incurable by Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Assess the response of patients with adrenocortical carcinoma treated with suramin. II. Evaluate the qualitative and quantitative toxic effects of this therapy. OUTLINE: Patients are described according to stage, performance status, prior radiotherapy, prior surgery, and prior mitotane therapy. Patients receive suramin IV for 5 days in the first week, then twice a week for 2 weeks, and then weekly for a total of 12 weeks. Hydrocortisone is taken PO twice daily. Following a 12 week rest, patients receive a second course; those with stable or responding disease continue treatment for a maximum of four courses. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A maximum of 40 patients will be accrued at a rate of 6-7 per year.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adrenocortical Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrocortisone 17-butyrate 21-propionate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cortisol succinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrocortisone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydrocortisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Suramin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed adrenocortical carcinoma in Stage III or IV and incurable by surgery Bidimensionally measurable disease PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: SWOG 02 Hematopoietic: WBC at least 4,000/mm3 Absolute granulocyte count at least 2,000/mm3 Platelet count at least 150,000/mm3 Prothrombin time and partial thromboplastin time no greater than upper limit of normal (ULN) Hepatic: SGOT and alkaline phosphatase no greater than 2 times ULN Renal: Creatinine clearance at least 50 mL/min Serum creatinine no greater than ULN Other: No second malignancy within 5 years except adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin,in situ carcinoma of the cervix, or other cancer for which patient has been disease free for 5 years Not pregnant or nursing Effective contraception required of fertile patients PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: No concurrent biologic therapy At least 4 weeks since prior biologic therapy (one regimen only) Chemotherapy: No concurrent chemotherapy At least 4 weeks since prior mitotane No other prior chemotherapy allowed Endocrine therapy: At least 6 weeks since prior hormonal therapy No concurrent hormonal therapy Radiotherapy: At least 4 weeks since prior radiation therapy (to less than 25% of bone marrow) No concurrent radiation therapy Surgery: Prior surgery allowed in relapsed patients with no other prior treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage III adrenocortical carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adrenocortical carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>