<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002477</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Combining more than one drug may kill more cancer cells. PURPOSE: Randomized phase III trial to compare the effectiveness of adjuvant therapy using platinum-based chemotherapy drugs with no adjuvant therapy in treating patients with early stage invasive ovarian epithelial cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adjuvant Chemotherapy Compared With Observation in Treating Patients With Resected Early Stage Ovarian Epithelial Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine whether adjuvant chemotherapy with a platinum-containing regimen (e.g., carboplatin or CAP: cyclophosphamide/doxorubicin/cisplatin) prolongs survival in patients with early stage ovarian cancer compared to those receiving no adjuvant treatment. OUTLINE: Randomized study. Patients are randomized to Arm I or II; treatment should begin within 6 weeks of surgery. Regimens listed in Arm I are recommended, but other platinum-containing regimens are allowed provided the doses at a minimum meet those listed below. Arm I: Single-agent Chemotherapy or 3-Drug Combination Chemotherapy. Carboplatin, CBDCA, NSC-241240; or CAP: Cyclophosphamide, CTX, NSC-26271; Doxorubicin, DOX, NSC-123127; Cisplatin, CDDP, NSC-119875. Arm II: Observation. No adjuvant therapy. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A maximum of 2,000 patients will be randomized.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed invasive ovarian cancer of epithelial origin All tumor resected prior to randomization Uncertain whether immediate chemotherapy is required PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: Any age Performance status: Sufficient to receive chemotherapy Hematopoietic: Not specified Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Not specified Other: No prior malignancy except nonmelanomatous skin cancer No clear contraindication to chemotherapy PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: No prior chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: Not specified Radiotherapy: No prior radiotherapy Surgery: Minimum recommended surgical procedures (when possible): Thorough surgical staging Total hysterectomy/bilateral salpingooophorectomy Omentectomy, as follows: Total supracolonic omentectomy if omentum involved Removal of distal 2 cm or infracolonic omentectomy in the absence of macroscopic disease</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage I ovarian epithelial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II ovarian epithelial cancer</keyword>
</DOC>