<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002115</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To study the safety, tolerance, pharmacokinetics, and anti-HIV effects of PMEA ( adefovir ) when administered daily by intravenous (IV) and/or subcutaneous (SC) injection in patients with advanced HIV disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase I/II Study of the Safety, Tolerance, and Pharmacokinetics of 9-(2-Phosphonylmethoxyethyl)Adenine ( PMEA; Adefovir ) in Patients With Advanced HIV Disease.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients receive a single IV or SC dose of PMEA daily for 4 weeks. A maximum tolerated dose will be defined for these regimens.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adefovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adefovir dipivoxil</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Concurrent Medication: Allowed: Other antiretroviral therapy IF on a stable dose for at least 4 weeks prior to study entry. Prophylactic therapy with aerosolized pentamidine, oral trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole (Bactrim, Septra) or dapsone, and fluconazole or ketoconazole IF on a stable prophylactic regimen for at least 4 weeks prior to study entry. Patients must have: HIV seropositivity. Elevated p24 antigen (&gt; 40 pg/ml). Mean CD4 count &lt;= 100 cells/mm3. Life expectancy of at least 3 months. Prior Medication: Allowed: Other prior antiretroviral therapy. Prophylactic therapy with aerosolized pentamidine, oral trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole (Bactrim, Septra) or dapsone, and fluconazole or ketoconazole. Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following symptoms or conditions are excluded: Inadequate venous access. Active serious infection (other than HIV infection) requiring parenteral antibiotic therapy. Clinically significant cardiac disease, including symptoms of ischemia, congestive heart failure, or arrhythmia. Psychiatric disturbance or illness that may affect compliance. Malignancy other than Kaposi's sarcoma. Concurrent Medication: Excluded: Investigational agents other than stavudine (d4T). Interferonalpha. Ganciclovir. Foscarnet. Diuretics. Amphotericin B. Aminoglycoside antibiotics. Other nephrotoxic agents. Acyclovir at doses &gt;= 2 g/day. Prior Medication: Excluded within 2 weeks prior to study entry: Investigational agents other than stavudine (d4T). Interferonalpha. Ganciclovir. Foscarnet. Diuretics. Amphotericin B. Aminoglycoside antibiotics. Other nephrotoxic agents. Excluded within 4 weeks prior to study entry: Systemic therapy for Kaposi's sarcoma. Substance abuse.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 1995</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Antiviral Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Adenine</keyword>
</DOC>