<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002928</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. PURPOSE: Phase II trial to study the effectiveness of paclitaxel in treating patients with recurrent or progressive advanced epithelial ovarian cancer following previous paclitaxel.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Paclitaxel in Treating Patients With Recurrent or Progressive Advanced Ovarian Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Evaluate the activity of paclitaxel when administered on a weekly schedule to patients with advanced ovarian cancer who have failed paclitaxel on a 3 or 24 hour infusion schedule. II. Evaluate the toxic effects of paclitaxel when administered on a weekly schedule in this patient population. III. Correlate response with quality of life outcomes, including symptom distress, performance status, and global quality of life. OUTLINE: This is a single center, open label study. Paclitaxel is administered intravenously every week as a 1 hour infusion. Patients receive prophylactic anti-allergy premedication prior to paclitaxel. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: 25-30 patients accrued per year.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed recurrent or progressive epithelial ovarian cancer defined as: A serial rise in CA 125 over a minimum of 3 samples to a level greater than 50% of the upper limit of normal OR Measurable or evaluable disease Disease progression following paclitaxel given by 3 or 24 hour infusion within the past 6 months PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 18 and over Performance status: Karnofsky at least 60% Life expectancy: Not specified Hematopoietic: AGC at least 1500/uL Platelet count at least 100,000/uL Hepatic: Bilirubin no greater than 1.5 mg/dL Renal: Creatinine no greater than 2.0 mg/dL Other: No active or uncontrolled infections No history of grade 34 peripheral neuropathy of any etiology No previously developed severe hypersensitivity reactions to paclitaxel Not pregnant or lactating Patients of childbearing potential must use effective method of contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy: Not specified Chemotherapy: Prior platinum based chemotherapy required Complete recovery from the myelosuppressive effects of prior chemotherapy for a minimum of 3 weeks At least one prior regimen of paclitaxel by 3 or 24 hour infusion within 6 months prior to study, with no intervening chemotherapy Endocrine therapy: No hormone therapy within 3 weeks of entry onto protocol Radiotherapy: No prior radiation therapy to major bone marrow ares within 4 weeks of entry onto protocol Surgery: Not specified</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent ovarian epithelial cancer</keyword>
</DOC>