<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002543</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. PURPOSE: : Phase I trial to study the effectiveness of gallium nitrate in young patients who have malignant brain tumors, neuroblastoma, rhabdomyosarcoma, non-Hodgkin's lymphoma, or refractory solid tumor.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gallium Nitrate in Treating Children With Brain Tumor, Neuroblastoma, Rhabdomyosarcoma, Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma, or Refractory Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the safety and side effects of gallium nitrate (GAN) when used as an anticancer agent in pediatric patients with refractory solid tumors, including malignant brain tumors, neuroblastoma, rhabdomyosarcoma, and non-Hodgkin's lymphoma. II. Evaluate these side effects in these patients. OUTLINE: Single-Agent Chemotherapy. Gallium Nitrate, GAN, NSC-15200. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: At least 3 patients will be accrued at each dose studied.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhabdomyosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gallium nitrate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Biopsyproven rhabdomyosarcoma, nonHodgkin's lymphoma, or other solid tumor refractory to conventional therapy or for which no effective curative therapy is known Rebiopsy required if disease recurs more than 2 years after initial diagnosis recommended if radiographic abnormalities suggest tumor recurrence within 5 months of completing radiotherapy or chemotherapy PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age: 21 and under at diagnosis Performance status: Karnofsky 50%100% Life expectancy: More than 4 weeks Hematopoietic: (unless extensive bone marrow involvement) ANC greater than 750 Platelets greater than 75,000 Hepatic: Not specified Renal: Creatinine normal for age OR Glomerular filtration rate at least 50 mL/min per 1.73 square meters Other: Adequate nutritional status No serious uncontrolled infection No pregnant or nursing women PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: At least 2 weeks since other anticancer therapy and recovered Prior radiotherapy or surgery for symptomatic lesions allowed provided site of evaluable disease remains untreated Prior bone marrow or stem cell transplantation allowed No concurrent anticancer therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent childhood rhabdomyosarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent childhood brain tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent neuroblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent childhood lymphoblastic lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>unspecified childhood solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent childhood small noncleaved cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent childhood large cell lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>