<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002130</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To examine the continued safety and tolerability of four doses of vesnarinone in HIV-infected patients who have completed a short-term study (less than 12 months on continuous treatment) of the drug.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Long-Term, Follow-On Safety Study of Four Doses of OPC-8212 (Vesnarinone) in HIV-Infected Persons</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients who have completed a limited duration study (less than 12 months of continuous treatment) of vesnarinone on protocols FDA 234A or FDA 234B and who have no current signs or symptoms of AIDS-defining illnesses may roll over to this study and continue receiving their regimen of vesnarinone for 12 months beyond their original participation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vesnarinone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Concurrent Medication: Allowed: Chemoprophylaxis for Pneumocystis carinii, candida, and mycobacteria. Acyclovir for acute treatment of herpes. Exclusion Criteria Concurrent Medication: Excluded: Antiretroviral agents, including ddI, ddC, AZT, and d4T. Immunosuppressive agents. Investigational HIV drugs/therapies including vaccines. Interferon or other immunomodulating agents. Corticosteroids (other than topical). Megestrol acetate. Agents known to cause neutropenia. Ganciclovir. Cytotoxic chemotherapy. Concurrent Treatment: Excluded: Radiation therapy. Patients with the following prior conditions are excluded: Poor compliance (less than 80 percent of drug taken) on the Phase I protocol (FDA 234A or FDA 234B). Missed more than one clinic visit on the Phase I protocol. Prior Medication: Excluded: Acyclovir as prophylaxis for herpes within 48 hours prior to study entry. Patients meet the following criteria: Successful completion of shortterm therapy with vesnarinone on FDA 234A or FDA 234B. Active illicit drug abuse.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 1996</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Antiviral Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>vesnarinone</keyword>
</DOC>