<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002186</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the safety of topically applied SP-303 gel and to compare the efficacy of SP-303 gel in combination with acyclovir, relative to acyclovir alone, for the treatment of recurrent Herpes Simplex Virus (HSV) 1 and 2 infections, affecting the genital, perianal and neighboring areas, in patients with AIDS.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Double-Blind Placebo-Controlled Study Comparing the Combination of 15% SP-303 Gel With Acyclovir Versus Acyclovir Alone for the Treatment of Recurrent Herpes Simplex Virus (HSV) Infections in Subjects With Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (AIDS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This trial is a double-blind, multicenter, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Participants are randomized to topical 15% SP-303 gel and oral acyclovir or to matching topical placebo gel and oral acyclovir. At presentation, patients are stratified by total lesion area within each treatment group. SP-303 or matching placebo is topically applied three times a day until all lesions are reepithelialized or for 14 days, whichever occurs earlier. Acyclovir is administered by mouth each day, three times a day, until all lesions are reepithelialized or for 14 days, whichever occurs earlier. Patients are evaluated for lesion healing and adverse events 3 times per week during the treatment period. The primary efficacy endpoint will be complete lesion healing and the primary analysis will be time to complete healing.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Herpes Simplex</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acyclovir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Patients must have: AIDS, according to the CDC criteria. Documented recurrent (at least 1 prior episode) perineal (genital, perianal and neighboring areas) mucocutaneous herpes simplex virus (HSV) types 1 or 2 infection in the active phase. Duration of current episode of recurrent HSV lesions of 3 days or less. Ability to read and write, must be intellectually competent, and able to understand the purposes and risks of the study. Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following symptoms and conditions are excluded: Active internal anal or rectal herpes. Inability to comply with protocol. Impaired renal function. Patients with the following prior conditions are excluded: Prior episode of recurrent genital herpes infection with documented clinical failure of acyclovir as a treatment regimen. Uncompensated hepatic, cardiac, or renal failure within 1 month of the study. History of hypersensitivity to acyclovir. Previous enrollment in this study. 1. Treatment with another medication (topical, oral, or intravenous) with known antiHSV activity within the past 5 days. Systemic immunomodulatory therapy within 30 days prior to study. Previous treatment with SP303. Required: Unchanged antiretroviral therapy for the 2 weeks prior to study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 1998</verification_date>
	<keyword>AIDS-Related Opportunistic Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Herpes Simplex</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy, Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>Acyclovir</keyword>
	<keyword>Antiviral Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Gels</keyword>
	<keyword>SP 303</keyword>
</DOC>