<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002151</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To characterize the safety and efficacy of fixed doses of MDL 28,574A administered alone and in combination with zidovudine ( AZT ) in patients with asymptomatic or mildly symptomatic HIV infection. To examine the demographic effects on population pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of MDL 28,574A alone and in combination with AZT.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomized, Double-Blind Active-Controlled, Dose-Ranging Study of the Safety and Efficacy of Chronically Administered MDL 28,574A in the Treatment of HIV-Infected Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Concurrent Medication: Allowed: Prior antiretroviral agents for up to 6 months per agent. Patients must have: HIV infection. Asymptomatic or mildly symptomatic. CD4 count 301 500 cells/mm3. Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following condition are excluded: Unable or unwilling to comply with study procedures. Concurrent Medication: Excluded: Chemoprophylactic therapy for mycobacterial infection. Any nonstudy prescription medications without approval of investigator. Patients with the following prior conditions are excluded: History of grade 3 or 4 toxicity to &lt;= 600 mg/day AZT. History of intolerance to lactose. Chronic diarrhea within 6 months prior to study entry. Unexplained intermittent or chronic fever, defined as temperature &gt;= 38.5 C for any 7 days within the 30 days prior to study entry. Prior Medication: Excluded: Antiretroviral therapy within 2 weeks prior to study entry. Prior HIV vaccines. Biological response modifiers within 30 days prior to study entry. Prior foscarnet. Any investigational drug with a washout &lt; 5 halflives prior to study entry. Any medications known to alter renal, hepatic, or hematologic / immunologic function (such as barbiturates, phenothiazines, cimetidine, immunomodulators, etc.) within 14 days prior to study entry. Recent history of alcohol and/or drug abuse.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 1996</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy, Combination</keyword>
	<keyword>AIDS-Related Complex</keyword>
	<keyword>Zidovudine</keyword>
	<keyword>MDL 28574</keyword>
</DOC>