<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00002095</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the efficacy of oral ganciclovir in preventing progression to cytomegalovirus (CMV) disease (e.g., CMV retinitis, gastrointestinal CMV disease) in CMV-infected people with HIV infection and CD4 lymphocyte counts &lt;= 100 cells/mm3. To evaluate the efficacy of this drug in reducing morbidity associated with coinfection by both CMV and HIV.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomized, Double-Blind Study of the Efficacy and Safety of Oral Ganciclovir for the Prevention of CMV Disease in People Infected With the Human Immunodeficiency Virus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cytomegalovirus Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ganciclovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ganciclovir triphosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Concurrent Medication: Allowed: Topical or ophthalmic nucleoside analogs. Patients must have: Confirmation of HIV infection. Documented CMV infection. No past or present CMV disease (e.g., retinitis, colitis, esophagitis). Adequate visualization of the retina of both eyes by ophthalmologist. CD4 count &lt;= 50 cells/mm3 (in patients WITHOUT a history of an AIDSdefining opportunistic infection or chronic gynecologic infection) OR CD4 count &lt;= 100 cells/mm3 (in patients WITH a history of an AIDSdefining opportunistic infection or chronic gynecologic infection). Exclusion Criteria Coexisting Condition: Patients with the following symptoms or conditions are excluded: Presence of gastrointestinal disease or symptoms not controlled with medications (e.g., persistent nausea, abdominal pain or persistent diarrhea within the past 4 weeks that is not controllable with medication). Inability to comply with protocol. Concurrent Medication: Excluded: The following nucleoside analogs: IV ganciclovir, IV acyclovir for more than 2 weeks total duration, oral acyclovir at doses &gt; 1000 mg/day, vidarabine, amantadine hydrochloride, cytarabine, idoxuridine. FIAU, FIAC, foscarnet, CMV hyperimmune globulin, IV immune globulin, CMV monoclonal antibody, HPMPC. Imipenemcilastatin (Primaxin). Patients with the following prior condition are excluded: History of hypersensitivity to acyclovir. Prior Medication: Excluded within the past 60 days: Ganciclovir, foscarnet, FIAC, FIAU, CMV hyperimmune globulin, CMV monoclonal antibody, or HPMPC.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 1993</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ganciclovir</keyword>
	<keyword>Cytomegalovirus Infections</keyword>
	<keyword>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</keyword>
</DOC>