<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01721538</DOC>
	<brief_summary>SCENARIO is a trial to investigate the role of non-drug weight reduction in secondary prevention of stroke. It is a single-blinded, randomized, controlled multicentre trial with two arms. The therapy arm is participating in a comprehensive weight reducing program, whereas the control group takes part in a lecture on healthy nutrition. The primary study objective is to assess the efficacy of non-drug therapeutic weight reduction in the secondary prevention of stroke. Secondary objectives are functional outcome, cognitive status, post stroke depression, and health-related quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Secondary Prevention of Stroke Through Non-drug Therapeutic Weight Reduction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of ischemic stroke Age: 20 85 years BMI ≥ 25.0 kg/m² or waist circumference in men ≥ 94cm and in women ≥ 80cm Functional impairment, which would allow to participate in weight reduction program (mRS 04, NIHSS 012) Patient must be capable of understanding informed consent Written informed consent for participation in the study Intracerebral hemorrhage as primary cause of stroke (secondary hemorrhage is not an exclusion criterion) Speech disturbance (aphasia or sever dysarthria) Dimming of consciousness Stroke due to arterial dissection or coagulation disorder Drugrelated weight changes during previous 3 months Changes in appetite influencing medication listed in appendix during previous 3 months Bariatric surgery in the past Diabetes mellitus with a history of severe ketoacidosis Pregnancy or nursing Severe comorbid disorders, e.g.: AVBlock ≥ 2nd degree Heart insufficiency (NYHA &gt; 2) Pericarditis, pericardial effusion Severe kidney insufficiency (Creatinine &gt; 3 mg/dl; Urea &gt; 150 mg/dl) Hepatic insufficiency (GOT &gt; 3 x ULN; GPT &gt; 3 x ULN) Severe psychiatric disease within the last six months (psychosis, suicide attempts) Chronic alcohol addiction or drug addiction HIV or hepatitis infection Bleeding peptic ulcer (unless there is radiological evidence of healing 6 months prior to start of obesity program) Cognitive impairment with MMSE &lt; 20 Depression with BDI &gt; 20 Patients who are unable to give consent to study participation (MMSE &lt; 20, aphasia) Recurrent stroke or myocardial infarction in the period between screening for study participation and start of weight reduction program Simultaneous participation in another clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>weight reduction</keyword>
</DOC>