<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02694276</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim is to evaluate if internet- delivered CBT, based on behavioral activation and exposure principles, improves wellbeing and QoL in symptomatic AF patients.The study will include 30 patients with symptomatic AF despite optimal medical treatment in accordance with current guidelines.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Internet-based Cognitive Behavior Therapy for Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Atrial fibrillation (AF) is the most common cardiac arrhythmia (irregular heartbeat) affecting 3% of the population. AF is associated with poor quality of life (QoL) and large costs for society. In a considerable proportion of patients, AF symptoms (e.g., palpitations, fatigue, and chest pain) are not alleviated by current medical or interventional treatments. Psychological factors can worsen AF symptoms, and anxiety and depression are common among AF patients. Symptom preoccupation and avoidance of social and physical activities are likely to play important roles in the development of anxiety, depression, disability and healthcare utilization. The aim is to evaluate if CBT, based on behavioral activation and exposure principles, improves wellbeing and QoL in symptomatic AF patients. Method: Pilot study with a pre-post-design and no control group. The internet-delivered CBT-program will last for 10 weeks and include weekly therapist support, consisting of online messages and telephone calls.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A) Paroxysmal AF ≥ once per month that causes moderate to severe symptoms and leads to significant distress or interferes with daily life (i.e. EHRA class ≥ IIb) [31]; B) Age 1875 years; C) Able to read and write in Swedish. C) Heart failure with severe systolic dysfunction (ejection fraction ≤ 35%); D) Significant valvular disease; E) Other severe medical illness; F) Severe depression or risk of suicide; G) Alcohol dependency.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>