<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="107043">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01710839</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>12246</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01710839</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Widefield Angiography Guided Targeted-retinal Photocoagulation Combined With Anti VEgf Intravitreal Injections for the Treatment of Ischemic Central Retinal Vein Occlusion, Hemi Retinal Vein Occlusion, and Branch Retinal Vein Occlusion</brief_title>
  <acronym>WAVE</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase IV Open Label Trial of the Safety, Tolerability and Efficacy of 0.5mg Ranibizumab Intravitreal Injections Combined With Wide Field Angiography Guided Panretinal Photocoagulation vs. 0.5mg Ranibizumab Intravitreal Injection Monotherapy in Subjects With Ischemic Central Retinal Vein Occlusion, Hemi Retinal Vein Occlusion, and Branch Retinal Vein Occlusion Who Incompletely Respond to at Least 2 Consecutive Intravitreal Injections in the Past 4 Months.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Charles C Wykoff, PhD, MD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Genentech, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Greater Houston Retina Research</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To see if Lucentis 0.5mg combined with Targeted Pan Retinal photocoagulation will decrease
      the total number of intravitreal injections in a year for ischemic central retinal vein
      occlusion, hemi-retinal vein occlusions and branch retinal vein occlusions compared to
      standard of care
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The WAVE trial is a phase IV, open label, 12-month trial of intravitreal ranibizumab 0.5 mg
      in patients (n=30) with ischemic CRVO, HRVO and BRVO who have been previously treated with
      ranibizumab or any other anti-VEGF intravitreal injection therapy, who are incomplete
      responders to 2 or more consecutive intravitreal anti-VEGF injections in the past 4 months.
      Randomization is 1:4, 1=control, ranibizumab only, 4=treatment arm. In total, 6 subjects
      will be randomized to control and 24 randomized to treatment arm.

      Cohort 1- 24 Subjects previously treated Patients will receive 6 doses of ranibizumab 0.5
      mg, followed by PRN intravitreal injection of ranibizumab 0.5 mg based on pre-defined
      retreatment criteria for up to 11 total injections.

      Wide field angiography guided peripheral targeted-retinal photocoagulation (TRP), will be
      divided into 2 sessions if needed, one at the 2 weeks post injection visit and another later
      at M4/V7, if repeat wide field angiogram indicates areas not sufficiently treated in the
      first TRP session

      Cohort 2- 6 Subjects, previously treated patients will receive 6 doses of ranibizumab 0.5
      mg, followed by PRN intravitreal injection of ranibizumab 0.5 mg based on pre-defined
      retreatment criteria for up to 11 total injections.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Total number of intravitreal injections in a 12 month period</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the number of intravitreal injections over 12 months.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Acuity</measure>
    <time_frame>12 month period</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate the mean change from baseline in ETDRS BCVA at 12 months.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Retinal Ischemia</measure>
    <time_frame>12 month period</time_frame>
    <description>Quantify change in area of perfused and ischemic retina.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Foveal Avascular Zone</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assess change in foveal avascular zone area and largest diameter, measured during the early phase of the angiogram</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence and severity of adverse events (ocular and non-ocular).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neovascularization of the Iris, Optic Nerve and Elsewhere</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percent of patients that develop neovascularization of the iris, optic nerve and/or elsewhere.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Central Foveal Outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean change in Central Foveal Volume on High Resolution OCT.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Aqueous VEG F Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>VEGF, other cytokines and ranibizumab levels in aqueous and serum samples at randomization and at the exit or early termination visit.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Field</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Goldman Visual Field changes at 6 and 12 months from baseline.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Central Retinal, Hemi Retinal &amp; Brach Retinal Vein Occlusions</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Targeted Pan Retinal laser combined with 0.5mg ranibizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cohort 1 (n=24), previously treated with at least 2 consecutive or more intravitreal injections of any anti-VEGF agent with persistent or recurrent macular edema will receive 6 loading doses of 0.5 mg ranibizumab followed by PRN treatment with ranibizumab 0.5 mg; after receiving the first loading dose of ranibizumab, the subject will have peripheral targeted-retinal photocoagulation (TRP) based on 200° wide field angiography with possibility of a second session of TRP at M4/M7, if non-perfusion persists based on angiogram.The 200°wide field angiography will indicate areas of peripheral ischemia which will be selectively treated, preserving areas of more perfused retina.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ranibizumab 0.5mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cohort 2 (n=6), previously treated with at least 2 consecutive or more intravitreal injections of any anti-VEGF agent with persistent or recurrent macular edema will receive 6 loading doses followed by PRN monthly treatment with ranibizumab 0.5 mg.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>0.5mg Ranibizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>intravitreal injections</description>
    <arm_group_label>Targeted Pan Retinal laser combined with 0.5mg ranibizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ranibizumab 0.5mg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lucentis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Targeted Pan Retinal Photocoagulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Targeted Pan Retinal Photocoagulation based on wide field angiography</description>
    <arm_group_label>Targeted Pan Retinal laser combined with 0.5mg ranibizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PRP</other_name>
    <other_name>Pan Retinal Photocoagulation</other_name>
    <other_name>TRP</other_name>
    <other_name>Pan Laser</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Age &gt; 18 years

          -  Visual acuity between 20/25 and 20/800, ETDRS best corrected visual acuity

          -  Ability to provide written informed consent and comply with study assessments for the
             full duration of the study

        Patients previously treated with any ITV anti-VEGF:

        • With at least 2 consecutive monthly intravitreal injections of anti-VEGF medications
        with presence of persistent or recurrent macular edema in the past 4 months

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  IOP over 30 mm Hg

          -  Any previous retinal laser photocoagulation to the study eye

          -  Previous intravitreal injection in the study eye of any corticosteroid treatment

          -  Previous vitrectomy in study eye (posterior or anterior associated with vitreous loss
             in cataract surgery)

          -  Intracapsular cataract extraction

          -  Any previous radiation treatments to head/neck that the principal or sub investigator
             feels is clinically relevant

          -  Inability to assess iris or angle neovascularization (corneal opacity precluding
             gonioscopy)

          -  Significant cardiovascular disease or cancer that would prevent follow-up visits or
             completion of the 12 month study

          -  Significant diabetic retinopathy in the fellow eye (diabetic macular edema,
             proliferative diabetic retinopathy, or high-risk non-proliferative diabetic
             retinopathy)

          -  Participation in another simultaneous medical investigator or trial

          -  Ocular disorders or concurrent disease in the study eye that may confound
             interpretation of study results, compromise visual acuity or require medical or
             surgical intervention, including history of retinal detachment, macular hole, or
             choroidal neovascularization of any cause (e.g., DME, AMD, ocular histoplasmosis, or
             pathologic myopia)

          -  Structural damage to the center of the macula in the study eye prior to CRVO, HRVO
             and BRVO likely to preclude improvement in visual acuity following the resolution of
             macular edema, including atrophy of the retinal pigment epithelium, subretinal
             fibrosis, laser scar(s)

          -  Vitreomacular traction or clinically significant epiretinal membrane in the study eye
             evident biomicroscopically or by OCT (vitreomacular attachment OK)

          -  Infectious blepharitis, keratitis, scleritis, or conjunctivitis (in either eye) or
             current treatment for serious systemic infection

          -  Spherical equivalent of the refractive error in the study eye of more than -8
             diopters myopia (For patients who have had refractive or cataract surgery in the
             study eye, preoperative spherical equivalent refractive error of more than -8
             diopters myopia is not allowed)

          -  Uncontrolled Blood pressure: defined as systolic pressure &gt; 180mmHg and/or diastolic
             pressure of &gt;110 mm Hg (sitting) during the screening period

          -  Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus

          -  Renal failure requiring dialysis or renal transplant

          -  Pregnancy (positive pregnancy test) or lactation

          -  Premenopausal women not using adequate contraception. The following are considered
             effective means of contraception: surgical sterilization or use of oral
             contraceptives, barrier contraception with either a condom or diaphragm in
             conjunction with spermicidal gel, an IUD, or contraceptive hormone implant or patch.

          -  History of other disease, metabolic dysfunction, physical examination finding, or
             other findings giving reasonable suspicion of a disease or condition that
             contraindicates the use an investigational drug, might affect interpretation of the
             results of the study, or render the subject at high risk from treatment complications

          -  History of allergy to fluorescein, not amenable to treatment

          -  Inability to obtain fundus photographs or fluorescein angiograms of sufficient
             quality to be analyzed by the principal investigator (PI) and/or the
             sub-investigator.

          -  History of allergy to humanized antibodies or any component of the ranibizumab
             formulation
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Charles C Wykoff, PhD, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Retina Consultants Houston</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Retina Consultants of Houston/The Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Retina Consultants of Houston</name>
      <address>
        <city>Katy</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77494</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Retina Consultants of Houston</name>
      <address>
        <city>The Woodlands</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77384</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Armaly MF. Ocular pressure and visual fields. A ten-year follow-up study. Arch Ophthalmol. 1969 Jan;81(1):25-40.</citation>
    <PMID>5763217</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Boyd SR, Zachary I, Chakravarthy U, Allen GJ, Wisdom GB, Cree IA, Martin JF, Hykin PG. Correlation of increased vascular endothelial growth factor with neovascularization and permeability in ischemic central vein occlusion. Arch Ophthalmol. 2002 Dec;120(12):1644-50.</citation>
    <PMID>12470137</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brown DM, Campochiaro PA, Singh RP, Li Z, Gray S, Saroj N, Rundle AC, Rubio RG, Murahashi WY; CRUISE Investigators.. Ranibizumab for macular edema following central retinal vein occlusion: six-month primary end point results of a phase III study. Ophthalmology. 2010 Jun;117(6):1124-1133.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.ophtha.2010.02.022. Epub 2010 Apr 9.</citation>
    <PMID>20381871</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Campochiaro PA, Brown DM, Awh CC, Lee SY, Gray S, Saroj N, Murahashi WY, Rubio RG. Sustained benefits from ranibizumab for macular edema following central retinal vein occlusion: twelve-month outcomes of a phase III study. Ophthalmology. 2011 Oct;118(10):2041-9. doi: 10.1016/j.ophtha.2011.02.038. Epub 2011 Jun 29.</citation>
    <PMID>21715011</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>A randomized clinical trial of early panretinal photocoagulation for ischemic central vein occlusion. The Central Vein Occlusion Study Group N report. Ophthalmology. 1995 Oct;102(10):1434-44.</citation>
    <PMID>9097789</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Natural history and clinical management of central retinal vein occlusion. The Central Vein Occlusion Study Group. Arch Ophthalmol. 1997 Apr;115(4):486-91. Erratum in: Arch Ophthalmol 1997 Oct;115(10):1275.</citation>
    <PMID>9109757</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Christen WG, Glynn RJ, Manson JE, Ajani UA, Buring JE. A prospective study of cigarette smoking and risk of age-related macular degeneration in men. JAMA. 1996 Oct 9;276(14):1147-51.</citation>
    <PMID>8827967</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Conn G, Bayne ML, Soderman DD, Kwok PW, Sullivan KA, Palisi TM, Hope DA, Thomas KA. Amino acid and cDNA sequences of a vascular endothelial cell mitogen that is homologous to platelet-derived growth factor. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1990 Apr;87(7):2628-32.</citation>
    <PMID>2320579</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Connolly DT, Heuvelman DM, Nelson R, Olander JV, Eppley BL, Delfino JJ, Siegel NR, Leimgruber RM, Feder J. Tumor vascular permeability factor stimulates endothelial cell growth and angiogenesis. J Clin Invest. 1989 Nov;84(5):1470-8.</citation>
    <PMID>2478587</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Connolly DT, Olander JV, Heuvelman D, Nelson R, Monsell R, Siegel N, Haymore BL, Leimgruber R, Feder J. Human vascular permeability factor. Isolation from U937 cells. J Biol Chem. 1989 Nov 25;264(33):20017-24.</citation>
    <PMID>2584205</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>de Vries C, Escobedo JA, Ueno H, Houck K, Ferrara N, Williams LT. The fms-like tyrosine kinase, a receptor for vascular endothelial growth factor. Science. 1992 Feb 21;255(5047):989-91.</citation>
    <PMID>1312256</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hayreh SS, Klugman MR, Podhajsky P, Kolder HE. Electroretinography in central retinal vein occlusion. Correlation of electroretinographic changes with pupillary abnormalities. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 1989;227(6):549-61.</citation>
    <PMID>2483144</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>October 28, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>October 17, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Greater Houston Retina Research</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Charles C Wykoff, PhD, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Deputy Director of Research</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CRVO</keyword>
  <keyword>BRVO</keyword>
  <keyword>HRVO</keyword>
  <keyword>Macular edema</keyword>
  <keyword>vein occlusion</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Retinal Vein Occlusion</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
