<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00561392</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluated the safety and efficacy of 10 cm^2 rivastigmine patch in patients with Alzheimer Disease (MMSE 10-26). The primary objective was the percentage of patients who stayed on the target size of 10 cm^2 for at least 8 weeks. This proportion was then compared to historical data of the percentage of patients who could reach a rivastigmine capsule target dose of 12 mg and stay on it at least 8 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Effectiveness of 10 cm^2 Rivastigmine Patch in Patients With Alzheimer's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rivastigmine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males, and females not of childbearing potential (surgically sterile or at least one year postmenopausal), of at least 50 years of age Probable Alzheimer's disease according to the NINCDSADRDA (National Institute of Neurological and Communicative Diseases and Stroke/Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disorders Association) and DSMIV (Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders) criteria MMSE (MiniMental State Examination) score of &gt; 10 and &lt; 26 Patients initiating therapy for the first time with a cholinesterase inhibitor (patients prescribed both rivastigmine and memantine are allowed) Patients who failed to benefit from previous cholinesterase inhibitor treatment Patients not treated according to the product monograph for rivastigmine capsules patients involved in a clinical trial Current diagnosis of an active skin lesion/disorder that would prevent accurate assessment of the adhesion and potential skin irritation of the patch (e.g., atopic dermatitis, wounded or scratched skin in the area of the patch application) Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria applied to the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Rivastigmine</keyword>
	<keyword>Patch</keyword>
</DOC>