<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01836068</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To find out if it is possible for HIV-1 patients to maintain antiretroviral medications during allogeneic bone marrow transplant</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Optimized Antiretroviral Therapy During Allogeneic Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation in HIV-1 Individuals</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Determine the feasibility of maintaining optimal ART in HIV-1 infected patients during allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplant (HSCT). The primary outcome is the fraction of patients who maintain any form of anti-retroviral therapy, including enfuvirtide monotherapy, through day 60 post-transplant. If patients are unable to take oral anti-retroviral medications, but are able to tolerate subcutaneous enfuvirtide monotherapy this will be considered maintenance of ART. Failure to maintain ART will be defined as ≥ 24 hours without any anti-retroviral therapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Enfuvirtide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HIV1 infection, as documented by a rapid HIV1 test or any FDAapproved HIV1 enzyme or chemiluminescence immunoassay (E/CIA) test kit and confirmed by western blot at any time prior to study entry. Alternatively, two HIV1 RNA values &gt; 200 copies/mL at least 24 hours apart performed by any laboratory that has CLIA certification, or its equivalent may be used to document infection. Patients must be ≥ 18 years of age. Plan to undergo a Myeloablative, HLA matched or partially HLAmismatched (haploidentical), relateddonor bone marrow transplantation that includes highdose posttransplantation Cy using bone marrow from a related donor: Plan to undergo a Nonmyeloablative, HLA matched or partially HLAmismatched, relateddonor bone marrow transplantation that includes highdose posttransplantation Cy using bone marrow from a related donor: Patients with a known history of enfuvirtide resistance will not be eligible for this trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV positive</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV-1</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Marrow Transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>Allogeneic BMT</keyword>
	<keyword>BMT</keyword>
</DOC>