<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01836679</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of Chidamide combined with paclitaxel and carboplatin in patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chidamide in Combination With Carboplatin and Paclitaxel in Advanced Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study is to evaluate efficacy which includes the progression free survival (PFS), PFS at 6 months, objective response rate, duration of response rate, overall survival and time to progression, and safety which include adverse events, vital signs, laboratory tests, of the treatment of chidamide plus paclitaxel and carboplatin in patients with advanced non small cell lung cancer.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with histology or cytology confirmed nonsmallcell lung cancer,stage IIIb or IV. Newly diagnosed or relapsed after surgery but have not received systemic drug therapy.Adjuvant chemotherapy after surgery should have completed for more than one year at study entry. Aged 18~75 years Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) mutation negative or EGFR status is unknown With at least one measurable lesion White blood cell count≥4×10^9/L,platelet count≥100×10^9/L and hemoglobin≥11g/L Life expectancy ＞3 months Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of ≤1 at study entry Women of childbearing age should have pregnancy test negative and would like to conduct birth control during the study Have signed informed consent Patients with clinically significant corrected QT interval prolongation, or ventricular tachycardia,or auricular fibrillation, or ≥Grade 2 sinoauricular heartblock,or ≥Grade 3 atrioventricular block,or myocardial infarction within one year, or congestive heart failure,or patients with symptomatic coronary disease which need to be treated by drug The size of fluid area detected by cardiac ultrasonography in cavum pericardium is ≥10mm during diastolic period Organ transplant patients Patients with active bleeding or new thrombotic diseases Patients with body temperature ＞38.5℃ for more than 3 days Total bilirubin ＞1.5 fold of upper limit of normal (ULN), ALT/AST＞1.5 fold of ULN or serum creatine ＞1.5 fold of ULN Patients with symptomatic brainmetastasis Pregnant or lactating women Patients with mental disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chidamide,lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>