<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00912925</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being conducted to demonstrate the safety and clinical efficacy of Aldurazyme treatment in MPS I patients</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Study of Aldurazyme in Patients With Mucopolysaccharidosis (MPS) I</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mucopolysaccharidoses</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mucopolysaccharidosis I</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient had a documented diagnosis of MPS I confirmed by measurable clinical signs and symptoms of MPS I and a fibroblast or leukocyte alphaLiduronidase enzyme activity level of less than 10% of the lower limit of the normal range of the measuring laboratory. Female patients of childbearing potential had a negative pregnancy test (urinebetahuman chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)) at baseline (all female patients of childbearing potential and sexually mature male patients were advised to use a medically accepted method of contraception throughout the study). The patient was capable of standing independently for 6 minutes and walking a minimum of 5 meters within 6 minutes. The patient was capable of performing a reproducible FVC maneuver. The patient had a baseline FVC value that was less than or equal to 80% of the patient's predicted normal FVC value based on polgar predicted values for standing height for children 5 through 7 years of age and the Hankinson predicted values for ages 8 and above. The patient had undergone a tracheostomy. The patient had previously undergone a bone marrow transplantation. The patient was pregnant or lactating. The patient has received an investigational drug within 30 days prior to study enrollment. The patient had a medical condition, serious intercurrent illness, or other extenuating circumstance that could have significantly interfered with study compliance including all prescribing evaluations and followup activities. The patient had a known hypersensitivity to rhIDU or to components of the active or placebo test solutions.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>