<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00449254</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Multi-center, multiple-dose, randomized, double-blind, three-arm, placebo-controlled study of fixed-dose repeated oral dosing for 30 days of 10 mg and 30 mg MP-101 and placebo in obese subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 2a Randomized, Double-Blind Study of Oleoyl-Estrone in Male Morbidly Obese Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Oleoyl-estrone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estrone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estropipate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is willing and able to provide signed informed consent. Subject is a male and is between 1860 years of age. Subject is obese as defined as a BMI of 40 55. Subject is reasonably healthy and have a reasonably acceptable medical history Subject has a stable weight for the past 30 days per subject report. Subject who has at least one factor of the metabolic Subject exhibits stable behavior patterns with regard to smoking and exercise Subject can read, speak and write the English language and agrees to follow study procedures. Subjects who have received any investigational medication within 3 months prior to administration of study drug Subjects with confirmed positive results of UDS or Alcohol Subjects who are unwilling to return to the clinical research center on specified days during the treatment periods. Subjects who have taken exclusionary medication Subjects with any clinically significant laboratory abnormality or illness which, in the opinion of the Investigator, would contraindicate study participation Subjects who have a history of testing positive for Hepatitis B virus, Hepatitis C virus, or HIV. Subject has been involved in a formal or informal (selfimposed) diet regimen within the last 30 days. Subject has a confirmed diagnosis or history of cancer, with the exception of nonmelanoma skin cancer. Subject is otherwise unsuitable for the study, in the opinion of the investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2007</verification_date>
</DOC>