<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00449839</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A pharmacokinetic study of insulin pump treatment using Insulin Aspart. The study consist of three different periods A, B and C where a constant the insulin infusion rate is given during the periods. In period B and C will the infusion start with a bolus. It will be investigated if a steady state of insulin will be obtained faster in period B and C then A.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Changes of the Infusion Rate in Insulin Pump Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A pharmacokinetic study of insulin pump treatment using Insulin Aspart. The study consist of three different periods A, B and C where a constant the insulin infusion rate is given during the periods. Each period will last 12 hours and blood will be drawn to measure absorbed Insulin Aspart. During period A will a constant the infusion rate of insulin be given. In period B and C will there at the start of the constant infusion rate be given a bolus. The bolus in period C is calculated on the basis of the results in period B, therefore will all participants experience period C last where as period A and B is randomized cross-over. Period C is written in the protocol as optional and it is evaluated after period A and B if period C will be performed. The hypothesis is that steady state of insulin will be obtained faster in period B and C than A.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin degludec, insulin aspart drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Aspart</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Long-Acting</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent Healthy volunteer Men and women between ≥18 and &lt;50 years Women in the childbearing age should be sufficient protected against pregnancy (use birth control pill or intrauterine device or be sterilized or hysterectomized) BMI between 1830 kg/m^2 (both included) Suspected or known allergy against the drug used in the study or similar drugs Previous history of endocrinology disease (including Diabetes Mellitus) Suspected or known alcohol or drug abuse Any disease influencing the study, evaluated by the investigator Pregnancy, breastfeeding or the wish of becoming pregnant during the study period. Furthermore women in the child bearing age not sufficient protected against pregnancy (sufficient is: use of birth control pill or intrauterine device or be sterilized or hysterectomized) Participation in other research projects during the last 3 months before this project</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Insulin pump treatment CSII</keyword>
	<keyword>Absorption</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin Aspart</keyword>
</DOC>