<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00449553</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to asses changes in glycosylated hemoglobin, fasting blood lipids and genetic polymorphism's in peroxisomal proliferator activated receptors--gamma receptor after 6 months of pioglitazone, once daily (QD), treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Observational Study to Assess Glycosylated Hemoglobin Changes After 6 Months of Treatment With Pioglitazone.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The metabolic control in type 2 diabetes mellitus can be measured by means of glycosylated hemoglobin. A low value glycosylated hemoglobin indicates a good metabolic control, and has been shown to be associated with a better prognosis regarding diabetic complications. Type 2 diabetes is a disease with a profound genetic component. Peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma is a transcription factor implicated in adipocyte differentiation, lipid and glucose metabolism. Peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor alfa is a transcription factor implicated in lipid oxidation and gluconeogenesis and is present in liver, kidney, heart, skeletal muscle and adipose tissue. Pioglitazone is a thiazolidinedione that targets nuclear peroxisomal proliferator activated receptors, members of the super family of ligand activated transcription factors. Specifically, thiazolidinediones bind to the peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma and affect transcription factors that influence expression of genes responsible for the production of proteins important in carbohydrate and lipoprotein metabolism. These include increases in glucose transporters 1 and 4 resulting in enhanced peripheral glucose utilization by fat and skeletal muscle. This is a pharmacoepidemiological study to evaluate whether the individual genotype of the patients have any influence on the efficacy of pioglitazone.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pioglitazone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Fulfills all requirements for treatment with pioglitazone. Willing to start treatment with pioglitazone. Has previously participated in this study. Is currently taking or have taken oral antidiabetic medications other than sulfonylurea or metformin within the last 30 days.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Glucose Metabolism Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Dysmetabolic Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Type II Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus, Lipoatrophic</keyword>
	<keyword>Dyslipidemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>