<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00449280</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to determine whether a significant pharmacokinetic interaction exists between rapamycin and sorafenib. This study will also look at the toxicity of the combination of rapamycin and sorafenib and the antitumor activity of the combination in subjects with advanced cancers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Drug Interaction Study of Sorafenib and Rapamycin in Advanced Malignancies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Niacinamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Solid cancer for which curative measures have failed or for which there is no known superior treatment ECOG performance status 02 Measurable or nonmeasurable disease Life expectancy of greater than 12 weeks and no anticipated need for other antineoplastic therapy in the next 4 weeks Age 18 years or older Patients must have adequate organ and marrow function as defined below: ALT and AST less than or equal to 2.5 x the ULN (&lt; 5 x ULN for patients with liver involvement). hemoglobin greater than or equal to 9 g/dL absolute neutrophil count greater than or equal to 1,500/μL platelets greater than or equal to 100,000/μL (greater than or equal to 35,000/μL without transfusion for patients with CLL/SLL or follicular lymphoma) total bilirubin less than or equal to 1.5 x ULN creatinine less than or equal to 1.5 x ULN Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test within 7 days of the start of treatment. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document Must not have any evidence of bleeding diathesis. Patients who have had chemotherapy or immunotherapy within 3 weeks or radiotherapy within 14 days prior to entering the study Patients may not be receiving any other investigational agents or any concomitant antineoplastic therapy Patients with uncontrolled brain metastases. Concurrent illness or medication exclusions HIVpositive patients receiving combination antiretroviral therapy are excluded from the study because of possible pharmacokinetic interactions with sorafenib or rapamycin.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>metastatic</keyword>
	<keyword>advanced disease</keyword>
	<keyword>phase I</keyword>
</DOC>