<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01933035</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To utilise extended platelet parameters in order to individuate Immune Thrombocytopenia (ITP) from hypo-proliferative causes of thrombocytopenia. To develop the clinical potential of the extended platelet parameters as they pertain to distinguishing different causes of thrombocytopenia from one another. To test the hypothesis that mean platelet component (MPC) and mean platelet mass (MPM) might distinguish between thrombocytopenia related to bone marrow dysfunction and immune mediated destruction of platelets.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Extended Platelet Parameters as a Means to Differentiate Immune Thrombocytopenia From Hypo-proliferative Thrombocytopenias.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patient to be registered at the Haematology-Oncology department Mount Sinai Roosevelt Hospital. Inclusion criteria are as follows: All individuals age 18yrs and above capable of rendering consent Known ITP confirmed by response to IVIG, glucocorticoids, or WinRho and exclusion of all other possible causes of thrombocytopenia Confirmed aplastic anemia [as assessed through bone marrow trephine biopsy]. Chemotherapy-induced thrombocytopenia assessed at time of predicted nadir.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thrombocytopenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Aplastic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Purpura, Thrombocytopenic, Idiopathic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All individuals age 18yrs and above capable of rendering consent Known ITP confirmed by response to intravenous immune globulin (IVIG), glucocorticoids, or winRho and exclusion of all other possible causes of thrombocytopenia Confirmed aplastic anemia [as assessed through bone marrow trephine biopsy] Chemotherapy induced thrombocytopenia assessed at time of predicted nadir. Suspected multifactorial thrombocytopenias and thrombocytopenia due to hypersplenism Chronic active hepatitis Those infected with HIV Patients receiving concomitant radiotherapy Gravid females Congenital thrombocytopenias</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ITP</keyword>
	<keyword>Thrombocytopenia</keyword>
	<keyword>mean platelet mass</keyword>
	<keyword>mean platelet component</keyword>
</DOC>