<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01403259</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of SOX regimen (S-1 plus oxaliplatin) as salvage treatment in patients with relapsed or metastatic nasopharyngeal carcinoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SOX as Salvage Treatment in Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The treatment option in patients with platinum-resistant relapsed or metastatic nasopharyngeal carcinoma is limited. Previous studies showed that both S-1 and oxaliplatin were effective in head and neck cancer. Moreover, SOX (S-1 plus oxaliplatin) was proved to be tolerable in advanced stage gastric cancer. Therefore, we aim to evaluate this regimen in salvage setting of nasopharyngeal carcinoma.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nasopharyngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age range: 1875 years old Histological confirmed incurable relapsed or metastatic nasopharyngeal carcinoma Prior exposure of at least one line of platinumcontaining regimen ECOG performance status 01 Life expectancy of more than 3 months Bone marrow function: ANC≧1.5×109/L, PLT≧100×109/L, Hb≧80g/L Liver function: total bilirubin, ALT and AST &lt;1.5×UNL Renal function: Cr&lt;1.5×UNL, CCR≧50ml/min Without &gt; 1 grade of neuropathy With curable treatment option With CNS involvement Prior platinum exposure only in neoadjuvant/adjuvant setting or concurrently used with radiotherapy Treated with &gt; 2 lines of palliative chemotherapy With prior exposure of S1 or oxaliplatin History of other malignancies except cured basal cell carcinoma of skin and carcinoma insitu of uterine cervix Significant active infection Pregnant or lactating women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Nasopharyngeal carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>S-1</keyword>
	<keyword>Oxaliplatin</keyword>
</DOC>