<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01220102</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this observational study is to assess the efficacy of Epiduo and patient adherence under daily clinical practice conditions in adults and adolescents (12 to 20 years) with moderate inflammatory acne using this drug first time in topical monotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of Epiduo and Treatment Adherence of Adolescent Patients With Inflammatory Acne</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objective of this observational study is to assess the efficacy of Epiduo and patient adherence under daily clinical practice conditions in adults and adolescents (12 to 20 years) with moderate inflammatory acne using this drug first time in topical monotherapy. This non-interventional trial will include a larger population of teenaged acne patients in order to establish the practical contribution of a new mini-questionnaire to the evaluation of adherence for the physician in the daily clinical practice in general and in young adults topically treated with Epiduo in particular. In addition safety and local tolerability profile of Epiduo are to be assessed under marketed conditions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Adapalene</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adapalene, Benzoyl Peroxide Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Benzoyl Peroxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient has been diagnosed with moderate inflammatory acne Topical monotherapy of acne with Epiduo is indicated, the decision about treating the patient with Epiduo has been made independently from this study The patient is aged between 12 and 20 years Pregnancy or breastfeeding Hypersensitivity to the medication or any of the ingredients Other contraindications mentioned in the Epiduo SPC</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>20 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>acne</keyword>
	<keyword>Epiduo</keyword>
	<keyword>adapalene/ benzoyl peroxide</keyword>
</DOC>