<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02586363</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this clinical trial, the investigator will clarify the difference in pharmacokinetics between the group single dose Cavir Tab. 0.5mg and single dose Cavir Tab. 0.5mg with high fatty meal for healthy adult volunteer. The investigators evaluate the effect of food intake on the absorption of Cavir Tab. 0.5mg.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Evaluation of Cavir Tab. 0.5mg With Food Effect on Pharmacokinetics and Safety</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Entecavir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy male, aged 19 ~ 45 at screening date Subject`s weight is in range from 120 percentage to +120 percentage of ideal body weight which is calculated by { height (cm) 100} * 0.9. The Subject is willing and able to provide written informed consent to participate in the study Subject has a history of clinically significant disease. Subject has a digestive disease (Crohn`s disease, ulcer, acute or chronic pancreatitis etc) or abdomen surgery (exclude, simple appendectomy or hernia operation). Subject has a hypersensitivity history which is clinically significance or additives. Subject is inappropriate to screening (disease history, physical examination, vital sings, electrocardiogram, laboratory test etc.) Subject has a laboratory test result as indicated by and one of the following. serum aspartate aminotransferase&gt; 1.25 * normal limit serum Total bilirubin &gt; 1.5 * normal upper limit serum CPK &gt; 1.5 * normal upper limit eGFR(estimated Glomerular Filtration Rate) calaulated by MDRD (Modification of Diet in Renal Disease) formula &lt; 60 mL/min/1.73m2 Subject is hypertension(SBP&gt;140mmHg or DBP&gt;90mmHg) or hypotension(SBP&lt;90mmHg, DBP&lt;60mmHg) Subject has a drug abusing history. Subject is currently abusing alcohol (more than 210 g/week), caffeine(more than 5cups/day) or smoking(more than half pack).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Entecavir</keyword>
	<keyword>Food effect</keyword>
	<keyword>Cavir Tab 0.5mg</keyword>
	<keyword>Baraclude Tab. 0.5mg</keyword>
</DOC>