<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02586753</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine which regimen is better for esophageal squamous carcinoma in concurrent chemoradiation(CCRT),paclitaxel or S1 plus cisplatin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Paclitaxel or S1 Plus Cisplatin in Concurrent Chemoradiotherapy for Squamous Cell Carcinoma of Esophagus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Radiotherapy:Patients will be conducted CT simulation, and three-dimensional conformal radiation therapy (3DCRT) was performed. 1.8-2.0 Gy/fraction, 5 fractions a week, with a total dose of 60-66Gy will be delivered for all patients by 6-MV-X-ray of linear accelerator. Chemotherapy: Patients will be concurrently administered with irradiation every 3 weeks with PT regimen (cisplatin of 20 mg/m2/d, d1-3; PTX(paclitaxel)of 135mg/m2/d, d1) for 4 cycles or PS regimen (cisplatin of 20 mg/m2/d, d1-3; S1(Tegafur Gimeracil Oteracil Potassium Capsule)of 50mg/m2/d, d1-14) for 4 cycles. For the first 2-cycles of chemotherapy they will be concurrently given with irradiation and the remained 2 cycles, after irradiation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Pathologically proven squamous cell carcinoma of esophagus . 2. Locally advanced esophageal cancer , with no operation indication 3. M1a disease defined ( AJCC 1998) , including celiac lymph node for lower thoracic esophageal cancer and cervical lymph node involvement for upper thoracic esophageal cancer 4. Subjects haven't been given neither radiotherapy nor chemotherapy before 5. Age of 1870 6. PS ≦2 7. Hemogram : WBC≧ 4000/mm3 or ANC ≧ 2000 /mm3 and Platelet ≧ 100,000/mm3 . Biochemistry : GOT/GPT ≦ 3.5 times , Cr ≦ 1.5 mg/dl and Bilirubin ≦ 2.0 mg/dl 8. With no difficulty in eating 9. Expected lifetime ≧3 months 1. Invasion to surrounding organ ( T4 disease ) . 2. Distant metastasis , except M1a disease . 3. Complete obstruction of the esophagus, or patients who have the potential to develop perforation 4. Women in status of pregnancy 5. Patients who have complications exist as following: Uncontrolled angina and heart failure, have a history of hospitalization in 3 months A history of myocardial infarction in the past 6 months There is a need for antibiotic treatment of acute bacterial or fungal infection Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, or other lung disease requiring hospitalization Drug addiction, alcoholism and AIDS disease or longterm virus carriers Uncontrollable seizures, or loss of insight because of mental illness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>