<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02586129</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Randomized, double-blind, active-controlled, multicenter phase 3 trial to evaluate the safety and efficacy of YH14755 in subjects with dyslipidemia and Type II Diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trial of YH14755 in Subjects With Dyslipidemia and Type II Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase 3 trial to evaluate the safety and efficacy of YH14755 in subjects with dyslipidemia and Type II Diabetes. In YH14755 treatment group, 88 subjects will be assigned and the subjects administer YH14755 for 16 weeks. In Metformin treatment group, 88 subjects will be assigned and the subjects administer Metformin for 16 weeks. In Rosuvastatin treatment group, 88 subjects will be assigned and the subjects administer Rosuvastatin for 16 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyslipidemias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rosuvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed Informed Consent Subjects with Dyslipidemia and Type II Diabetes 6.5% ≤ HbA1c level ≤ 9.0% and LDLC level ≤ 250mg/dL(6.5 nmal/L) at screening BMI ≤ 45kg/m2 Subjects who dose not administered diabetes treatment at least 4 weeks prior to screening visit. 19 years later, men and women under the age of 75 Pregnant women, nursing mothers or subject who does not agree to assigned contraception in the study Subject with type I Diabetes Subject with hypertension which does not controlled by treatment(have blood pressure &gt; 160/110mmHg) Have a known allergy to drugs Have administered Cyclosporine Have administered Obesity treatment within 12 weeks prior to screening visit Participated in any other clinical trials within 30 days prior to the first administration Subject who is judged to be ineligible by investigator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>