<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02467842</DOC>
	<brief_summary>All participants will receive a single dose of their assigned vaccine on Day 0. They will be followed up for immunogenicity and safety through Day 21 post-vaccination. The serious adverse events are collected for 6 months post-vaccination.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunogenicity and Safety of Quadrivalent Influenza Vaccine (NBP607) in Adults and Elderly Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In a randomized controlled phase III trial undertaken in 10 university hospitals of South Korea, adults and elderly subjects are randomly assigned in a 2:1:1 ratio to NBP607-QIV versus cell culture-based trivalent inactivated influenza vaccine, NBP607-Y and NBP607-V. Immunogenicity is assessed 3 weeks after vaccination by hemagglutination inhibition (HI) assay. Safety is assessed for 6 months post-vaccination: solicited adverse events for 7 days, unsolicited AEs for 21 days and SAE for 6 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults aged 19 years and older Those who are able to comply with the requirements for the study If women, a negative pregnancy test and willingness to use birth control measures for the entire study duration Disorders in immune function Any malignancy or lymphoproliferative disorder History of GuillainBarré syndrome Individuals with a known bleeding diathesis, or any condition that may be associated with a prolonged bleeding time Experience of fever (&gt;38.0 ℃) within 24 hours following vaccination Body temperature &gt;38.0 ℃ at the vaccination day Concomitant medications/therapy such as immunosuppressants or immune modifying drugs, systemic corticosteroids, immunoglobulins, blood or blood derived products within 3 months Influenza vaccination within 6 months Subjects who have participated in other interventional study within 4 weeks Any vaccination within 1 month Those who are planning to receive any vaccine within 1 month from the study vaccine Individuals with any serious chronic or progressive disease Pregnant or breastfeeding women Any other reason that in the opinion of the investigator might interfere with the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Influenza vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Quadrivalent</keyword>
	<keyword>Inactivated cell culture-derived</keyword>
</DOC>