<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02467413</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of BAC patients with Alzheimer's disease or vascular dementia.The secondary objective of this study is to evaluate the safety of BAC patients with Alzheimer's disease or vascular dementia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>BAC in Patient With Alzheimer's Disease or Vascular Dementia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is designed as a randomized, double-blind, vehicle-controlled and parallel trial to evaluate the efficacy and safety of BAC in patients with Alzheimer's disease or vascular dementia. Eligible patients will be randomly assigned to receive either one of topical application of BAC or BAC matched vehicle, topical application on external nasal skin, scalp, and neck, 30mL/day, 2 times daily. The treatment duration for each patient is 12 weeks, which consists of 6 visits located at Screening, Baseline (Week 0), Weeks -2, -4, -8, and -12. During the treatment period, patients may continue to receive routinely used medications or treatments for Alzheimer's disease or vascular dementia except those prohibited under this protocol.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dementia, Vascular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A patient is eligible for the study if all of the following apply: 1. With either gender aged at least 40 years old 2. With a diagnosis of one of the following disease i. Vascular dementia according to the NINDSAIREN International Workshop criteria or ii. Alzheimer's disease according to the NIAAA criteria iii. "Mixed" dementia (possible Alzheimer's disease with cerebrovascular disease) according to the NIAAA criteria Note: 1. NINDSAIREN: National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke and Association Internationale pour la Recherche et l'Enseignement en Neurosciences 2. NIAAA: National Institute on AgingAlzheimer's Association 3. With mildtomoderate dementia (score of the MiniMental State Examination (MMSE) defined as between 10 to 24) 4. Able to read, write, communicate, and understand cognitive testing instructions 5. Having a responsible caregiver who spends adequate time daily with the patient; the caregiver will accompany the patient to all clinic visits during the study and supervise all study dosing requirements and concomitant medications 6. Signed, by patients and the responsible caregiver, the written informed consent form 1. With largeartery stroke (thrombotic stroke) 2. With radiological evidence of other brain disorders (subdural hematoma, posttraumatic / postsurgery) 3. With dementia caused by other brain diseases except Alzheimer's disease and vascular dementia (e.g. Parkinson's disease, demyelinated disease of the central nervous system, tumor, hydrocephalus, head injury, central nervous system infection including syphilis, acquired immune deficiency syndrome, etc.) 4. With clinical evidence of pulmonary, hepatic, gastrointestinal, metabolic, endocrine or other life threatening diseases judged by investigators not suitable to enter the study 5. With clinically unstable hypertension, diabetes mellitus, and cardiac disease for the last 3 months 6. With history of stroke and hospitalized for stroke in the previous 3 months 7. With history of alcohol or drug abuse 8. With one of the following abnormal laboratory parameters: hemoglobin &lt; 10 mg/dL or platelet &lt; 100*109/L; creatinine or total bilirubin more than 1.5 times the upper limit value; alanine aminotransferase (ALT), aspartate aminotransferase (AST), alkaline phosphates (ALP), or γglutamyl transferase (γGT) more than 2 times the upper limit of normal 9. With depression, not wellcontrolled with medications. 10. With any uncontrolled illness judged by the investigator that entering the trial may be detrimental to the patient 11. With known or suspected hypersensitivity to any ingredients of study product and vehicle 12. Pregnant or lactating or premenopausal with childbearing potential but not taking reliable contraceptive method(s) during the study period 13. Enrollment in any investigational drug trial within 4 weeks before entering this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Vascular Dementia</keyword>
</DOC>