<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02467608</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Assess the Efficacy of HUEXC030 as Add-on Excipient to Eradicate Anti-Tuberculosis Drugs Induced Hepatic Injury ( ATDH ) in Subjects with Pulmonary Tuberculosis</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of HUEXC030 in Subjects With Pulmonary Tuberculosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study drug is Isoniazid formulated with HUEXC030 as excipient for eradicating ATDH, whereas the reference control is Isoniazid formulated with inactive excipient. Subjects who fulfill all the entry criteria and have written informed consent will be enrolled to the study. Eligible subjects will be randomized in a 1:1 ratio to receive study drug or reference control drug. Subjects will be genotyped according to a selected panel of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) and categorized into high risk or low risk groups for occurring ATDH via a specific haplotype consists of CYP2E1 and NAT2 SNPs. Based on an extensive study result during 2007 to 2011,the estimated frequency for patients bearing high risk genotypes in Taiwanese population is around 25%. Approximately 352 subjects will be enrolled for genotype screening in order to recruit 88 high risk subjects for each of 44 subjects in the intervention and control arms. Subjects who are stratified as high risk groups will be administered the test drug or reference control drugs oral daily for 6 months or until treatment completion, i.e. bacteriologically confirmed negative of active M. tuberculosis. Subjects who are of low risk genotype will be removed from study after 8 weeks of study treatment, then return to conventional TB medication under the care of their investigator for at least one follow-up visit at 4 weeks after the End of Study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tuberculosis, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Drug-Induced Liver Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Isoniazid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Main inclusion criteria: 1. A definite case of pulmonary TB 2. Patient who is exposed to 3 or less doses of firstline antiTB drug treatment for current disease. 3. Age ≥ 20 years 4. Have well documented baseline liver function tests that indicates patient's adequate liver function for enrollment to study. i. AST and ALT &lt; 3x ULN ii. total serum bilirubin &lt; 2.0 mg/dL Main 1. Have alcoholic liver disease or habitual alcohol consumption &gt; 30 g/day for more than one year 2. Previously diagnosed of: i. extrapulmonary TB without concomitant lung invasion ii. HIV iii. liver malignancy iv. liver cirrhosis v. any other systemic diseases that may cause liver dysfunction 3. Documented history of serious allergic reaction or resistance to isoniazid, rifampicin, ethambutol, pyrazinamide, sugar alcohols or any structurally related compounds 4. Subjects who will be using the following therapies after TB treatment starts: i. antiretroviral agents ii. oral corticosteroids 5. Subjects are pregnant or lactating 6. Subjects with childbearing potential who are not committed to take reliable contraception during the participation of the study and at least 4 weeks after the end of the study treatment 7. Subjects with any other serious disease considered by the investigator not in the condition to enter into the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HUEXC030</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulmonary Tuberculosis</keyword>
</DOC>