<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00313729</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as temozolomide, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well temozolomide works in treating patients with supratentorial low-grade glioma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Temozolomide in Treating Patients With Low-Grade Glioma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the efficacy of temozolomide, defined as response rate (complete and partial response), in patients with supratentorial mixed low-grade glioma. Secondary - Assess the safety profile of temozolomide in patients with supratentorial low-grade glioma. - Assess the time to tumor progression in patients treated with temozolomide. OUTLINE: Patients receive oral temozolomide once daily on days 1-5. Treatment repeats every 28 days for up to 12 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 3 months for 1 year, every 4 months for 1 year, every 6 months for 1 year, and then annually thereafter. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 120 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically proven supratentorial lowgrade (grade II) glioma of any of the following histologic subtypes: Oligodendroglioma Astrocytoma Oligoastrocytoma Has undergone surgical resection or biopsy within 35 days after diagnosis of lowgrade glioma Study treatment must begin between 14 days and 4 months after surgical resection or biopsy Evaluable disease by gadoliniumMRI PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Karnofsky performance status 60100% Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dL Creatinine &lt; 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) BUN &lt; 1.5 times ULN Bilirubin &lt; 1.5 times ULN SGOT &lt; 2.5 times ULN Alkaline phosphatase &lt; 2 times ULN Life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks No nonmalignant systemic disease resulting in the patient being a poor medical risk No acute infection requiring intravenous antibiotics No frequent vomiting or medical condition that would interfere with oral medication intake (e.g., partial bowel obstruction) No other concurrent malignancies except surgically cured carcinoma in situ of the cervix or basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin Prior malignancies must be in remission for ≥ 5 years No known HIV positivity No AIDSrelated illness Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics No prior radiotherapy, interstitial brachytherapy, or radiosurgery for lowgrade glioma No prior biological therapy or chemotherapy for lowgrade glioma No other concurrent chemotherapy No concurrent radiotherapy or biological therapy No concurrent prophylactic growth factors No concurrent epoetin alfa No other concurrent investigational drugs</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult oligodendroglioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult mixed glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult diffuse astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult pilocytic astrocytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult pineal gland astrocytoma</keyword>
</DOC>