<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00668837</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Open-Label Extension to the double-blind effectiveness and safety study R076477-SCH-305 to evaluate long-term safety and tolerability in patients with schizophrenia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A 52 Week Open-label Extension Trial Following the Double-blind Efficacy and Safety Study R076477-SCH-305.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective of the open-label extension trial was the long-term assessment of safety and tolerability of flexibly-dosed ER OROS paliperidone (3 to 15 mg/day) in patients with a diagnosis of schizophrenia. Other measures assessed in the extension study included: change in the total Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale (PANSS) score; change in PANSS subscale (positive and negative) scores; overall functioning, as measured by the Clinical Global Impression Scale-Severity (CGI-S); personal and social functioning, as measured by the Personal and Social Performance Scale (PSP); and quality of life parameters, as measured by the Schizophrenia Quality of Life Scale, Revision 4 (SQLS-R4). Paliperidone ER OROS® tablet formulation (3 to 15 mg/day) to be taken orally for 52 weeks</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paliperidone Palmitate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Study R076477SCH707 enrolled patients who met the DSMIV criteria of schizophrenia for at least 1 year Eligible patients were experiencing active symptoms at the time of enrollment and had a PANSS total score between 70 and 120 The openlabel extension study population comprised patients who had completed the 6week doubleblind phase of the study or who had discontinued due to lack of efficacy after at least 21 days of treatment. Not eligible to enter the openlabel phase if believed to be at significant risk for suicidal or violent behavior during the openlabel extension trial Were pregnant Or had received an injection of a depot antipsychotic since entry into the preceding doubleblind phase</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Paliperidone</keyword>
	<keyword>schizophrenia</keyword>
</DOC>