<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02971813</DOC>
	<brief_summary>While cardiac rehabilitation (CR) has been shown to be effective at improving cardiovascular disease (CVD), participation is generally poor. For this reason, the current research, a prospective, randomized controlled pilot study, will evaluate the impact of a social media intervention on motivation for exercise and adherence to CR sessions. Participants will be randomly assigned to a Facebook™ group or an enhanced education comparison group. The intervention will include access to a private Facebook™ group in which participants will receive weekly educational posts, weekly provider support and have the opportunity to communicate with other cardiac rehabilitation patients. Patients in the comparison group will be given the same educational materials, but these will be supplied in handout form, or email if the patient is absent from cardiac rehabilitation. Participants will be asked to fill out a pre-post motivational questionnaire and the total number of sessions attended at the end of 3 months will be tallied. This study is grounded in Self-Determination Theory (SDT) and utilizes the Behavioral Regulation in Exercise Questionnaire (BREQ-2), which is based on the SDT.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Social Media Intervention for Exercise Motivation and Cardiac Rehabilitation Adherence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Research is still needed to determine the effectiveness of social networking interventions used to promote health. Few randomized controlled trials have examined the use of social networking as a tool for exercise adherence or health promotion. Further, there is no research that addresses the use of social media and particularly Facebook, as a tool to affect autonomous motivation in cardiac rehabilitation. 1. The purpose of the current randomized pilot trial is to determine the effect of a social media intervention, providing education, peer support and provider support, on autonomous motivation and self-determination for exercise, and the adherence to CR in patients with CVD during a 12-week CR program. 2. A secondary aim of this pilot is to test the feasibility of doing a larger, long-term trial. The feasibility of a larger trial will be based on participant use of the Facebook group (number of "hits") and sample size. 3. It is hypothesized that patients exposed to a social media intervention will show an increase in autonomous motivation for exercise and will attend a higher percentage of CR sessions compared to a comparison group who receive educational handouts and emails. It is also hypothesized that the greater the number of times a participant uses the private Facebook group (number of "hits"), the greater the number of CR sessions attended and the greater the change in autonomous motivation. Theoretical Framework This study is grounded in Self-Determination Theory which defines motivation in terms of intrinsic and extrinsic sources. Self-determination theory focuses on social and cognitive factors and how those factors influence an individual's motivation. Self-Determination Theory specifically examines conditions that lead to self-motivation (autonomous or intrinsic in nature) and states that 3 processes are necessary for it to exist: competence, autonomy and relatedness. There are 3 aspects of a setting that support these processes and that are motivationally supportive: Autonomy support, structure and involvement. 1. Autonomy support minimizes pressure on participants and offers choice by helping individuals to engage in an activity for personal reasons. 2. Structure helps individuals to set realistic goals and offers positive and informative feedback. 3. Involvement describes the interaction with and support of significant others. The SDT is an appropriate framework for the examination of exercise motivation. When examining CR adherence, motivation for exercise is an important concept. It is possible that intrinsic motivation, when present, may be enough to help patients overcome the many obstacles associated with non-adherence to exercise and CR. The Behavioral Regulation in Exercise Questionnaire-2 (BREQ-2) is an instrument that employs the SDT in order to measure the quality of motivation for exercise, and especially autonomous motivation through the use of the Relative Autonomy Index (RAI). Methods Research Design This is a prospective, randomized controlled pilot trial to evaluate the impact of a social media intervention on motivation for exercise and adherence to cardiac rehabilitation sessions. Setting The setting for this study will be in the outpatient CR at the Main Campus of the Cleveland Clinic Health System in Northeast Ohio and in patients' homes or other locations where home computers might be accessed. Sample All patients who are current and regular Facebook users, have qualified for cardiac rehabilitation (diagnosed with CVD), and are entering cardiac rehabilitation at the Main Campus of the Cleveland Clinic, will be asked to participate in the study at the time of the cardiac rehabilitation entrance visit. Current Facebook users were chosen as it is important that participants are skilled at using the internet and familiar with social media. Regular use will be defined as logging onto Facebook at least 2 times in the last month. Inclusion criteria will include both men and women 18 years of age or older who speak English and live within 100 miles of the Main Campus of the Cleveland Clinic. Participants must be able to read English and state an understanding of the consent and the Behavioral Regulation in Exercise Questionnaire-2 (BREQ-2). There will be no exclusion based on diagnosis, however, participants must be able to exercise well enough to qualify to take part in CR. Intervention Motivation for exercise will be measured at baseline and post-intervention using the BREQ-2. The BREQ-2 is a validated instrument that measures forms of intrinsic and extrinsic regulation of exercise behavior and is based on Self-Determination Theory. A relative autonomy index (RAI) can be calculated from the BREQ-2, which gives a score of relative autonomy, placing an individual's motivation type on the self-determination continuum from a motivated (lacking intention to exercise) to intrinsically motivated (self-determined or autonomously motivated). Cardiac rehabilitation adherence will be determined by the number of CR sessions attended in a 3 month period of time. To examine association between a social media support (Facebook) and the outcome variables of CR adherence and motivation, the number of "hits" on the private Facebook site will be counted for each participant. Educational and supportive posts "liked" by participants will also be counted. Data Collection Procedures: 1. After IRB approval, volunteers will be recruited from the Cleveland Clinic Main Campus at the intake visit for CR. Volunteers will be screened for Facebook use and interest in the study, the protocol will be explained and participants will be asked to sign consent. The consent will address the fact that Facebook is a public forum and names and comments are seen by other participants and the research team. The Facebook group will be private in the sense that those not in the group will not be able to see the content. 2. Participants will be given a baseline BREQ-2 survey, given at the time of CR intake. 3. Participants will be randomized to Facebook versus enhanced education groups using a stratified, blocked randomization. 4. The Facebook intervention will include peer support, education, provider support and text message prompts when new posts are added. These interventions are designed to minimize pressure, offer choices, and allow for peer interaction, positive feedback, guidance and direction, in order to collectively provide autonomy support, structure and involvement. 1. Peer interaction on Facebook will be as frequently as the participant freely chooses to do so and will be monitored by the research team for appropriateness of content. 2. Educational posts will cover 12 topics that will encourage participants in heart-care while offering a variety of suggestions and encouraging autonomous healthcare choices. These 12 educational topics will be standardized such that postings will occur on the Facebook group, one each week and then the same ones will be re-posted again every 12 weeks. The posts may be in the form of text, video and/or pictures. 3. Provider support will be composed and posted in a standardized fashion, much like the educational posts. Topics will include motivational quotes, encouragement, reminders to exercise independently, and reminders to contact providers with questions (attached document). Providers will be nurses on the research team, exercise physiologists and nurse practitioners and physicians who may or may not choose to reveal personal identities. Input from the above providers will be used to compose messages prior to implementation of the study. All Facebook participants will see the same content. Provider support will also include links to the Cleveland Clinic Health Chats, in which patients can chat online with providers at set dates and times. 5. The comparison group will receive the same educational materials as the Facebook group but will receive it in handout form, or via email if the patient misses cardiac rehabilitation on a particular week. The comparison group will have the typical peer interactions in CR and provider support will be "usual care". 6. The data collection for this study will take place during the entrance visit for CR at which time the participants will receive the BREQ-2 survey. Data for Facebook "hits" will be obtained by the Health and Vascular Institute Resource Center at The Cleveland Clinic. Data will also be collected on the number of times educational or supportive posts are "liked" by participants. 7. Post-testing will take place at the completion of the CR program, defined as completing the full number of sessions allotted by insurance, Medicaid or Medicare. If a participant drops out of CR prior to completion, post-testing will be done as soon as the participant can return for testing, if he or she is willing to do so. Post-testing will include a BREQ-2 survey as well as a count of the number of sessions completed in a 3 month period of time. It is anticipated that this pilot will take 1 year to complete. Data Analysis: Statistical Methods This is a feasibility study and the sample size obtained will determine if the study is appropriately powered to detect the desired effect size. Patient characteristics will be summarized by group using frequencies and percentages for categorical factors, and means and standard deviations for continuous measures. In order to generate the best possible estimate of impact of primary predictors, the model will adjust for key demographic variables (age, gender, race, employment, distance to cardiac rehabilitation and socioeconomic status), and key clinical variables (cardiac rehabilitation indication, hypertension, diabetes, hyperlipidemia and waist circumference). Pearson correlation coefficient will be calculated and those ≥ 0.3 will be included as a covariate in final multivariate analysis. Groups will be compared on overall motivation with analysis of covariance models, using the RAI from the BREQ-2. Two-sample t-tests will be used to compare number of sessions completed. Multivariate analysis of variance models will be used to evaluate differences in the change between individual motivation subtypes between groups. Analyses will be performed using SAS software (version 9.4; Cary, NC). An overall significance level of 0.05 will be assumed for all tests. Sample Size Planned enrollment 30 patients in each group. In the first 9 months of 2016, cardiac rehabilitation at the main campus of the Cleveland Clinic had approximately 170 patient intakes. It is assumed that there will be a similar number of patient intakes for a 9 month period in 2017. It is estimated that 40% may meet eligibility requirements and agree to participate. Allowing for use of the first 8 participants to establish the Facebook group, the estimated sample size would then be 60 total participants for randomization to study group who can then be included in analysis. With this sample size, there will be 86% power to detect large effect sizes (d=0.8) for the study outcomes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All male and female patients who are current and regular Facebook™ users, 18 years of age or older, have qualified for cardiac rehabilitation (diagnosed with cardiovascular disease), and are entering cardiac rehabilitation at the Main Campus of the Cleveland Clinic, will qualify for the study. Participants must be able to exercise to the extent that they can take part in cardiac rehabilitation, must live within 100 miles and must be able to read and speak English.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cardiac rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>social media</keyword>
	<keyword>adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>motivation</keyword>
</DOC>