<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01604629</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate that patients with Spondylarthropathies in remission under antiTNF therapy, can maintain the remission with a maintenance dose inferior to the currently recommended dose schedule.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of a Protocol for Dose Reduction in Patients With Spondylarthropathies and Clinical Remission With Anti-TNF</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>It has been shown that the withdrawal of treatment follows with a flare of the disease in a short time after the suspension but it has not been evaluated in controlled trials if remission could be maintained with a lower dose. A multicenter, national, open-label, randomized and controlled clinical trial of 3 years duration (2 years for inclusion + 1 year follow-up) is proposed to address this issue. The study will include 190 patients with Spondylarthropathies in stable treatment with any single anti-TNF agent and compliance with criteria of clinical remission for at least 4 months. Patients will be randomized to intervention or control arm, with stratification according to the antiTNF product thet were receiving prior to inclusion. Patients will be followed with the calendar of visits recommended by the Spanish Society of Rheumatology for clinical practice. The proposed hypothesis is of non-inferiority of the experimental arm with dose reduction versus the control arm with standard treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Spondylarthropathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etanercept</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infliximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients older than 18 years Patients with Spondylarthropathies according ASAS group criteria. Patients under treatment with antiTNF therapy (infliximab, adalimumab, etanercept, golimumab) who present established clinical remission Patients to give their informed consent to participate in the study Patients with secondary Spondylarthropathies Patients with Spondylarthropathies and predominantly clinical of peripheral arthritis which receive antiTNF therapy by peripheral symp tons. Patients with Spondylarthropathies and other associated diseases that hinders or modify the clinical evaluation of the patient (fibromyalgia, chronic inflammatory disorders…) Patients with bowel inflammatory disease Patients under chronic therapy with antiTNF therapy who received the patterns of reduction that will be explored in the experimental group, or low doses or most spaced that those in the experimental group before study inclusion</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Spondylarthropathies</keyword>
	<keyword>Persistent clinical remission with anti-TNF therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Standardized protocol for dose reduction anti-TNF therapy</keyword>
</DOC>