<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02100657</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study of Plitidepsin (Aplidin®) to determine the recommended dose (RD) of plitidepsin in Combination with Bortezomib and Dexamethasone in Patients with Relapsed and/or Refractory Multiple Myeloma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Plitidepsin (Aplidin®) in Combination With Bortezomib and Dexamethasone in Patients With Multiple Myeloma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Phase I Multicenter, Open-label, Dose-escalating Clinical and Pharmacokinetic Trial of Plitidepsin (Aplidin®) to determine the recommended dose (RD) of plitidepsin in combination with bortezomib and dexamethasone in patients with relapsed and/or refractory multiple myeloma (MM), to determine the efficacy of the combination plitidepsin/bortezomib/dexamethasone, to evaluate the safety and tolerability of the combination in patients with relapsing and/or refractory MM and to study the pharmacokinetics (PK) and pharmacodynamics (PDy) of plitidepsin in combination with bortezomib and dexamethasone.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years. Prior autologous transplantation (HSCT) patients are allowed. Patients must have received at least one previous treatment line of induction, chemotherapy, chemotherapy and transplantation or previous treatment with bortezomib or another proteasome drug Previous treatment with plitidepsin. Active or metastatic primary malignancy other than MM. Serious concomitant systemic disorders History of hypersensitivity reactions to bortezomib, polyoxyl 35 castor oil or mannitol Neuropathy Pregnant and/or lactating women HIV infection Active hepatitis B or C virus infection. Treatment with any Investigational Medicinal Product (IMP) in the 30 days before inclusion in the study Plasma cell leukemia at the time of study entry Contraindication for the use of steroids</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>multiple myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>plitidepsin</keyword>
	<keyword>APLIDIN</keyword>
</DOC>