<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02990546</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to investigate the role of oral midodrine in the recovery of septic shock. The investigators hypothesize that the oral drug can reduce central line days and ICU length of stay.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Midodrine in the Recovery Phase of Septic Shock</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators aim to investigate the use of midodrine in the recovery phase of septic shock in a randomized control trial. The investigators hypothesize that midodrine use initiated after stabilization or improving intravenous vasopressor requirement will lead to decreased length of ICU stay and length of time that intravenous vasopressors are required. The investigators plan to enroll and consent patients at the onset of septic shock. Once IV vasopressor requirement is stabilized or decreasing, males and females will be randomized in 1:1 fashion to receive either standard clinical care or standard clinical care plus oral midodrine. The investigators will analyze length of stay in the ICU, time on vasopressors, time needing a central line, and hospital length of stay.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Shock</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Shock, Septic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Midodrine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>• Patients aged 1899 years old Admitted to UVA medical ICU with diagnosis of septic shock. Pregnant females, patients with childbearing potential will have urine pregnancy testing after consent Patients &lt; 18 years Prisoners Patients already taking midodrine Patients with cirrhosis and ChildPugh Class C (ChildPugh score &gt; 9)_ Patients with Increased intraocular pressure and glaucoma Patients with allergy to midodrine NonEnglish speaking patients Patients without enteral access Patients where the attending physician does not feel MAP goal of &gt; 65 mmHg is physiologically acceptable.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>