<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02990091</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a Phase 2 clinical trial designed to obtain data on relationships between potentially therapeutic doses of n-3 HUFA (highly unsaturated fatty acids) and their bioactive molecular derivatives, synaptamide, 17-hydroxy-DHA, and D-series resolvins, on clinical outcomes after TBI.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Derivatives of Omega-3 PUFA as Biomarkers of Traumatic Brain Injury</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 1855 2. Documented/ verified TBI 3. Ability to swallow study agent within 24h of injury 4. If a sexually active female who is able to get pregnant, must be already taking birth control (prescription contraception) 5. Visual acuity/ hearing adequate for testing 6. Fluency in English or Spanish 7. Ability to provide informed consent for themselves 8. Coenrolled in PARCTBI protocol (IRB protocol #825783) or TRACKTBI (IRB protocol #825503) 9. GCS 1315 1. Unstable respiratory or hemodynamic status 2. Evidence of penetrating brain injury 3. Requirement for craniotomy or craniectomy 4. Evidence of serious infectious complications 5. Acute ischemic heart disease or abnormal heart rhythm 6. History of abnormality in liver function 7. History or evidence of active malignancy 8. History of diabetes 9. History of preexisting neurologic disorder, such as dementia, uncontrolled epilepsy, multiple sclerosis, strokes, brain tumors, prior severe TBI, or other disorder that confounds interpretation neuropsychological results 10. History of preexisting disabling Axis I psychiatric disorder, such as major depression, schizophrenia, bipolar disorder or dementia 11. Allergy to omega3 fatty acid ethyl esters or any ingredient of the study agent. 12. Known allergy to Safflower seed oil or ragweed plants 13. Consumption of fish or seafood 3 or more times per week on average or regular administration of omega3 supplements (e.g., cod liver oil, borage oil, fish oil or evening primrose oil) defined as an average of 250 mg/day of n3 HUFAs, over the previous 3 months. 14. Pregnancy or breastfeeding 15. Prisoners or patients in custody 16. Allergy, hypersensitivity, or intolerance to fish oils or omega3 fats which are found in fish. 17. Use of anticoagulant medications or aspirin more than once per week within the last three months 18. Enrollment in any concurrent research protocols that would interfere with participant safety or research data integrity.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>TBI</keyword>
	<keyword>DHA</keyword>
	<keyword>omega-3 highly unsaturated fatty acids</keyword>
	<keyword>synaptamide</keyword>
</DOC>