<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02990234</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Investigator's hypothesis is that capsular repair (after CAM or mixed Femoroacetabular Impingement (FAI) surgery) requiring moderate capsulotomy, would result in similar patient outcomes in the short, mid and long term, both clinically and radiographically, compared to those without capsular repair. The objective of this clinical trial is to evaluate the clinical efficacy with regards to pain, range of motion and return to work and activities of daily living. Secondary objective is to evaluate radiographic characteristics between both groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Capsular Repair in FAI Impingement Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hip Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female patients aged between 1651 years of age. 2. Healthy patients undergoing hip arthroscopy due to Cam or mixed FAI 3. No major osteoarthritic (OA) changes according to XRay and surgery observation (Tonnis 01) 4. No previous hip surgery 5. No other influential disabilities in lower limbs 6. No chronic use of NSAID, analgesics, steroids or chemotherapy drugs 7. Base line activity level (Tegner 3 and above) 1. Patients with concomitant disease that may affect joints 2. Patients with major ligamentous laxity 3. Patients who have undergone only minor vertical capsulotomy (as in small pincer only lesions) 4. Patients with extreme range of motion needs (such as ballet dancers) 5. Patients suffering from connective tissue disease 6. Patients suffering from bilateral symptomatic FAI that are being operated on for their first hip 7. Patients with relative or proven dysplastic hip determined by center edge angle and/or extreme version abnormalities as measured on apical CT/MR cuts and pelvic XR 8. Patients who needed IlioPsoas release 9. Patients whose cartilage hip status was defined as advanced OA during surgery 10. Patients who following surgery would be instructed to avoid full weight bearing on the operated hip for more than 4 weeks 11. Concomitant use of PRP (platelet rich plasma) or hyaluronic acid during the surgical procedure 12. Patients with preoperative hip stiffness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>51 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Capsular Repair</keyword>
	<keyword>FAI</keyword>
	<keyword>Hip</keyword>
</DOC>