<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00559156</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Giving a nutritional supplement containing arginine, omega-3 fatty acids, and nucleotides to patients undergoing chemotherapy and radiation therapy may stimulate the immune system and help the body build a stronger immune response. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well an arginine/omega-3 fatty acids/nucleotides nutritional supplement works in treating patients with stage III or stage IV head and neck cancer undergoing chemotherapy and radiation therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Arginine/Omega-3 Fatty Acids/Nucleotides Nutritional Supplement in Treating Patients With Stage III or Stage IV Head and Neck Cancer Undergoing Chemotherapy and Radiation Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Assess the effects of immunomodulator arginine/omega-3 fatty acids/nucleotides oral supplement (Oral IMPACT®) administered via percutaneous gastrostomy during adjuvant chemoradiotherapy in patients with stage III or IV epidermoid head and neck cancer. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients undergo radiotherapy 5 days a week for 6½ weeks. Patients receive cisplatin IV during weeks 1, 4, and 7 of radiotherapy. Patients also receive arginine/omega-3 fatty acids/nucleotides oral supplement (Oral IMPACT®) via percutaneous gastrostomy tube 3 times daily for 5 days before each chemotherapy treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of head and neck cancer meeting the following criteria: Epidermoid carcinoma Stage III or IV disease Must have percutaneous gastrostomy tube in place Must have undergone prior surgery for head and neck cancer within the past 68 weeks No cerebral metastases PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: WHO performance status (PS) 02 OR Karnofsky PS 60100% Life expectancy &gt; 3 months WBC &gt; 4,000/mm³ ANC &gt; 2,000/mm³ Platelet count &gt; 100,000/mm³ PTT ≥ 50% Creatinine &lt; 130 μmol/L Not pregnant or nursing Fertile patients must use effective contraception No severe sepsis No requirement for parenteral nutrition No preexisting digestive pathology that results in bowel obstruction, nausea, vomiting, and/or abdominal pain &gt; grade 1 PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the hypopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and oral cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic squamous neck cancer with occult primary squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent metastatic squamous neck cancer with occult primary</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the nasopharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the oropharynx</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the paranasal sinus and nasal cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III squamous cell carcinoma of the paranasal sinus and nasal cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV squamous cell carcinoma of the paranasal sinus and nasal cavity</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent salivary gland cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>salivary gland squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III salivary gland cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV salivary gland cancer</keyword>
</DOC>