<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02570724</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The injection of autologous blood Blood Patch (BP) into the epidural space is the standard treatment for headache associated with intracranial hypotension. It provokes cerebral vasoconstriction. It is cons-indicated in a number of situations (HIV positive, fever, sepsis, leukemia). The purpose of this study is to evaluate another technique using a patch made by injecting an epidural hydroxyethylstarch solution (HES 130, 0.4, 6%) instead of blood patch. This alternative technique is simple to implement and does not have some of the specific blood pressure contra-indications. The study aims at comparing the "Blood Patch" group versus the "HES Patch" in terms of clinical efficacy , tolerance, satisfaction of the anesthetist, ease of implementation and effect of the injection of epidural anesthesia on cerebral blood flow within 24 hours.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>HES Patch Versus Blood Patch</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypotension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intracranial Hypotension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxyethyl Starch Derivatives</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects older than 18 years.· Subjects with an intracranial hypertension syndrome secondary to an epidural, spinal or lumbar puncture (and therefore presumed iatrogenic) with a sub arachnoid space or subjects with intracranial hypertension syndrome of primitive origin requiring treatment with epidural Patch · subjects with a temporal window of sufficient quality to carry out the transcranial Doppler · Subjects haven read the informed consent, signed and dated prior to the start of any proceedings related to the tial· Subjects affiliated to health insurance· Subjects having been informed of the results of a prior medical consultation Subjects with a consindication to an epidural Patch: blood disorders constitutional or acquired coagulation with platelets Subjects under treatment with curative doses of antiplatelet drugs or anticoagulants subjects under shock and / or hypovolemia subjects under generalized sepsis or at the puncture site any other consindication to performing an epidural</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>