<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02570256</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study investigates the potential of customized robotic and visual feedback interaction to improve recovery of movements in stroke survivors. While therapists widely recognize that customization is critical to recovery, little is understood about how take advantage of statistical analysis tools to aid in the process of designing individualized training. Our approach first creates a model of a person's own unique movement deficits, and then creates a practice environment to correct these problems. Experiments will determine how the deficit-field approach can improve (1) reaching accuracy, (2) range of motion, and (3) activities of daily living. The findings will not only shed light on how to improve therapy for stroke survivors, it will test hypotheses about fundamental processes of practice and learning. This study will help us move closer to our long-term goal of clinically effective treatments using interactive devices.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Deficit Fields for Stroke Recovery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<criteria>STROKE SURVIVORS: adult (age &gt;18) Chronic stage stroke recovery (8+ months post) available medical records and radiographic information about lesion locations strokes caused by an ischemic infarct in the middle cerebral artery primary motor cortex involvement a FuglMeyer score (between 1550) to evaluate arm motor impairment level HEALTHY CONTROL PARTICIPANTS: adult (age &gt;18) healthy individuals with no history of stroke or neural injury bilateral paresis; severe sensory deficits in the limb severe spasticity (Modified Ashworth of 4) preventing movement aphasia, cognitive impairment or affective dysfunction that would influence the ability to perform the experiment inability to provide an informed consent severe current medical problems diffuse/multiple lesion sites or multiple stroke events hemispatial neglect or visual field cut that would prevent subjects from seeing the targets.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>upper extremity</keyword>
	<keyword>motor exploration</keyword>
	<keyword>error augmentation</keyword>
	<keyword>robotic rehabilitation</keyword>
</DOC>