<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02570542</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to study the impact of stem cell dose on outcome after autologous transplant.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of CD34+ Cell Dose on Progression-free Survival Following High-Dose Therapy and Autologous Stem Cell Transplantation for Relapsed and Refractory Diffuse Large B-cell Lymphoma (DLBCL)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Following enrollment, patients will be CD34+ stem cell mobilized at the discretion of the treating attending physician with the plerixafor for the achievement of &gt;6 x10^6 CD34+ cells/kg. The patients that fail to mobilize &gt;6 x10^6 CD34+ cells/kg will not be randomized and will subsequently be followed for disease progression and overall survival.. Patients with &gt;6 x10^6 CD34+ cells/kg cryopreserved on study will be admitted to the hospital for planned ASCT. Patients will be randomly infused with either 3-4 x 10^6 CD34+ stem cells/kg or 6-8 x10^6 CD34+ stem cells/kg on d0 per study randomization. The cell dose ranges within the two groups allows variability within aliquots of cells at the time of cryopreservation. Patients will receive standard supportive measures (including: growth factor support post-HDT/ASCT, antimicrobial prophylaxis, red blood cell and platelet transfusion and treatment for neutropenic fever) as per institutional guideline practices.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cytarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carmustine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Melphalan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>JM 3100</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years old with relapsed or refractory de novo DLBCL KPS ≥ 70 Complete or partial response by IWG Working Group or ICML Criteria to maximum of one salvage line of chemotherapy without preHDT/ASCT salvage radiotherapy. Eligible for highdose therapy and autologous stemcell rescue Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL, or if creatinine &gt;1.5 mg/dL, calculated creatinine clearance of ≥50 mL/min by 24 hour creatinine clearance or CKDEPI. Last cycle of most recent salvage therapy within 8 weeks of enrollment Direct bilirubin ≤2.0 mg/dL in the absence of suspected Gilbert's disease (if Gilbert's disease is suspected, the total bilirubin must be ≤3.0 mg/dL). Females of childbearing potential and males must agree to use an acceptable form of contraception per institutional practices. Disease progression by IWG Working Group or ICML Criteria since last therapy Prior autologous or allogeneic stem cell transplantation HIV infection Comorbid condition(s) which, in the opinion of the attending physician and/or MSKCC Principal Investigator, will preclude stem cell mobilization and/or highdose therapy with autologous stem cell rescue Treatment plan that includes posttransplant maintenance therapy Salvage therapy that includes involved field radiotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>CD34+ Cell Dose</keyword>
	<keyword>Autologous Stem Cell Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>15-193</keyword>
</DOC>