<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="12015">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02950519</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>201605155</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02950519</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Endotracheal Tube Cuff Pressures in Ventilated Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assessing Endotracheal Tube Cuff Pressures in Mechanically Ventilated Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Barnes-Jewish Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Barnes-Jewish Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There is no accepted standard for the frequency of monitoring endotracheal tube cuff
      pressures (ETCP). We plan on comparing two strategies for monitoring ETCP in mechanically
      ventilated patients. The two strategies will be the currently employed practice protocol as
      outlined in the Respiratory Therapy Protocol at Barnes-Jewish Hospital (BJH) which requires
      ETCP to be assessed immediately after the endotracheal tube is placed and after any
      manipulation of the endotracheal tube to include repositioning, manipulation of the cuff
      volume, or presence of an audible leak. We will compare this current practice to a more
      intensive monitoring of ETCP which is employed at some hospitals and includes the same
      elements as noted in the current practice plus monitoring ETCP every work shift (every 8
      hours or three times per day).
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      I.8 Provide a short summary of the purpose and procedures of the study proposed in this IRB
      application.

        -  DO NOT include information on studies not proposed in this application. (If your source
           of support proposal describes multiple aims, refer to the information button for an
           example on how to complete this question.)

        -  Use LAY terminology only. This must be easily understandable by IRB community members
           and nonscientists.

        -  DO NOT cut and paste technical abstracts from source of support applications that may
           not be understood by a general audience.

      There is no accepted standard for the frequency of monitoring endotracheal tube cuff
      pressures (ETCP). We plan on comparing two strategies for monitoring ETCP in mechanically
      ventilated patients. The two strategies will be the currently employed practice protocol as
      outlined in the Respiratory Therapy Protocol at Barnes-Jewish Hospital (BJH) which requires
      ETCP to be assessed immediately after the endotracheal tube is placed and after any
      manipulation of the endotracheal tube to include repositioning, manipulation of the cuff
      volume, or presence of an audible leak. We will compare this current practice to a more
      intensive monitoring of ETCP which is employed at some hospitals and includes the same
      elements as noted in the current practice plus monitoring ETCP every work shift (every 8
      hours or three times per day). The ETCP will be assessed using a standard manometer. The two
      practices will be compared between patients assigned to odd and even beds in the medical ICU
      (8400 ICU) with odd numbered patients having the current ETCP practice and those in even
      rooms having the addition of ETCP assessments every shift. It is important to note that the
      respiratory therapists carrying out the ETCP assessments are simply performing their jobs as
      therapists in a normal manner to include the assessment of ETCPs. The respiratory therapists
      come in to work in the ICU and carry out their jobs according to the current protocol in
      that unit. ETCP assessments are a routine part of their job. They will be simply carrying
      out their job according to protocol based on the room number the patient is in. Assessing
      ETCPs takes less than 1-2 minutes to carry out. The respiratory therapists working in the
      medical ICU will be carrying out their jobs in a normal way. Respiratory therapy practices
      and protocols are frequently changed over the course of time. The therapists will continue
      to carry out their jobs in a routine manner in the medical ICU.

      I.9 Specify your research question(s), study aims or hypotheses (do not indicate &quot;see
      protocol&quot;) Our hypothesis is that increased monitoring frequency of ETCP will not result in
      any reduction in the duration of mechanical ventilation for patients admitted to the medical
      intensive care unit (ICU) of BJH or reduction in ventilator-associated events.

      I.10 Background and significance and/or Preliminary studies related to this project.

      (do not indicate &quot;see protocol&quot;) Currently there is no accepted gold standard for the
      frequency of monitoring ETCP (1). There are widely different strategies reported for
      monitoring ETCP to include continuous monitoring. The goal of ETCP monitoring is to maintain
      the ETCP between 20-30 cmH2O in order to minimize cuff leaks and pressure injury to the
      tracheal mucosa. It is known that 20 to 30% of the time the ETCP may deviate above or below
      this threshold. However, the impact of such deviation on clinical outcomes is not well
      described in the medical literature (2). The two most common methods for assessing ETCP is
      the use of a manometer and performing a minimal leak, with the former being the most
      accepted method (3). However, the optimal frequency for conducting manometric monitoring of
      ETCP is unknown. One recent study suggests that the act of measuring ETCP frequently in
      order to achieve a desired pressure level results in the removal of air from the cuff and
      can result in under inflation of the cuff (4). However, a recent animal study suggests that
      the material used to manufacture the endotracheal tube cuff may play a more important role
      in determining the presence or absence of mucosal injury, with polyurethane being better
      than polyvinylchloride (5). The main problem with these studies is the failure to assess
      clinical outcomes at the bedside with the use of various strategies to maintain an
      appropriate endotracheal tube cuff seal. A recent survey of intensivists in Queensland
      Australia and accompanying systematic literature review made the following conclusions
      regarding ETCP monitoring &quot;Twenty-eight out of twenty-nine respondents reported routinely
      monitoring tracheal cuff function, primarily employing cuff pressure measurement (26/28).
      Target cuff pressures varied, with 3/26 respondents aiming for 10 to 20 cmH2O, 10/26 for 21
      to 25 cmH2O, and 13/26 for 26 to 30 cmH2O. Fifteen out of twenty-nine reported they had no
      current guideline or protocol for tracheal cuff management and only 16/29 indicated there
      was a dedicated area in the clinical record for reporting cuff intervention. Our results
      indicate that many ICUs across Queensland routinely measure tracheal cuff function, with
      most utilising pressure monitoring devices. Consistent with existing literature, the optimum
      cuff pressure remains uncertain. Most, however, considered that this should be a routine
      part of ICU care&quot;(6). Thus, the available literature on ETCP and their relationship to
      clinical outcomes is lacking.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single Blind (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ventilator Associated Condition (VAC) as defined by CDC</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours after intubation</time_frame>
    <description>Lung Condition that developed in association with mechanical ventilation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of stay (hospital)</measure>
    <time_frame>Time in days of hospital stay for patients admitted and discharged for a period up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Through hospital admission until hospital discharge for patients admitted and discharged for a period up to 6 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>Any time during hospitalization up to a period of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Through hospital admission until hospital discharge up to a period of 6 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ventilator Associated Pneumonia (VAP)</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hrs after intubation</time_frame>
    <description>Pneumonia that developed in association with mechanical ventilation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Pneumonia, Ventilator-Associated</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>As needed Cuff Pressure Checks</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cuff pressure checks upon intubation and after any manipulation of ET tube</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cuff Pressure checks every 8 hrs</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cuff pressure checks upon intubation, after manipulation of ET tube, and minimum of 8 hr interval</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>monitoring of cuff pressures</intervention_name>
    <description>Cuff pressure will be checked per standard and additionally a minimum of every 8 hours.</description>
    <arm_group_label>As needed Cuff Pressure Checks</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cuff Pressure checks every 8 hrs</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Mechanically ventilated patients intubated in a medical intensive care unit

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patient requiring prone positioning, lung transplant and neutropenic patients
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marin Kollef, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Washington University School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Peggy ` Watts, MS</last_name>
    <phone>3143623767</phone>
    <email>Peggy.Watts@bjc.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Patty Silver, MEd</last_name>
    <phone>3149549096</phone>
    <email>pcs4276@bjc.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Barnes-Jewish Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marin Kollef, MD</last_name>
      <phone>314-454-8764</phone>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Peggy Watts, MS</last_name>
      <phone>314 362- 3767</phone>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>October 31, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>October 6, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Barnes-Jewish Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Peggy Watts</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MS</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia, Ventilator-Associated</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We are undecided on this point.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
