<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01111591</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In extrahepatic bile duct cancer and pancreatic cancer, we will treat postoperatively with COX2 inhibitor and assess survival rate and recurrent rate.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cyclooxygenase-2 Inhibitor for Adjuvant Anticancer Effect in Patients With Biliary-pancreas Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients : total 220 patients - Extrahepatic bile duct cancer : 55 patients for administration of COX2 55 patients for control group - Pancreas cancer : 55 patients for administration of COX2 55 patients for control group Indication - After operation of extrahepatic bile duct cancer or pancreas cancer - Age : 19 - 70 years old - The patients who agree to consent sheet. Contraindication - Impossible of administration due to severe postoperative morbidities (bleeding, bowel obstruction, pancreatic fistula, biliary fistula) - Preexisting heart disease: Ischemic heart disease, Heart failure. Severe uncontrolled hypertension (systolic BP&gt;160) - Renal insufficiency: CCR &lt; 50 or serum creatinin &gt;3.0 - Hepatic insufficiency: Liver cirrhosis or active hepatitis - Preexisting allergic reaction history for NSAIDs or Sulfonamide - Current drug intake: Warfarin. Lithium, Fluconazole, Aspirin, Celecoxib - Preexisting Asthma. Especially aspirin-sensitive asthma. - Contraindications to aspirin, clopidogrel or celecoxib - The patients who refuse trial - The patients who has Psychogenic problem Allocation - We will allocate patients randomly, to administration group or control group Methods - From postoperative third day, administration will be started - celecoxib 200mg bid for 6 months for administration group - Follow up and assess recurrence rate and survival rate</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bile Duct Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Celecoxib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclooxygenase 2 Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancrelipase</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patients who underwent operation for extrahepatic bile duct cancer or pancreas cancer Between 19 and 70 years old Agreed to consent sheet The patients cannot administration of drug due to severe postoperative morbidities. Preexisting heart disease: Ischemic heart disease, Heart failure. Severe uncontrolled hypertension (systolic BP&gt;160) Renal insufficiency: CCR &lt; 50 or serum creatinin &gt;3.0 Hepatic insufficiency: Liver cirrhosis or active hepatitis Preexisting allergic reaction history for NSAIDs or Sulfonamide Current drug intake: Warfarin. Lithium, Fluconazole, Aspirin, Celecoxib Preexisting Asthma. Especially aspirinsensitive asthma. Contraindications to aspirin, clopidogrel or celecoxib When patients refused Patients has psychological problem</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cyclooxygenase-2 inhibitor (Celecoxib)</keyword>
	<keyword>Extrahepatic bile duct cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Pancreas cancer</keyword>
</DOC>