<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01111461</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the objective response rate (ORR: complete response + partial response [CR+ PR]) of E7080 in subjects with unresectable endometrial cancer and disease progression following platinum-based, first-line chemotherapy. .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Lenvatinib in Subjects With Advanced Endometrial Cancer and Disease Progression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Disease Progression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lenvatinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 1. Histologically confirmed diagnosis of endometrial carcinoma. 2. Radiographic evidence of disease progression according to modified RECIST 1.1 after 1 prior systemic, platinumbased chemotherapy regimen for recurrent metastatic or primary unresectable endometrial carcinoma for which no surgical or radiotherapy treatment option exists. 3. Measureable disease meeting the following criteria: At least 1 lesion of greater than 1.0 cm in the longest diameter for a nonlymph node or greater than 1.5 cm in the shortaxis diameter for a lymph node which is serially measureable according to modified RECIST 1.1 using computerized tomography / magnetic resonance imaging. Lesions that have had external beam radiotherapy (EBRT) or locoregional therapies such as radiofrequency ablation must show evidence of progressive disease based on modified RECIST 1.1 to be deemed a target lesion. 4. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status less than 2. 5. Adequate controlled blood pressure (BP) with or without antihypertensive medications, defined as BP less than 150/90 mmHg at screening and no change in antihypertensive medications within 1 week prior to the Screening Visit. 6. Adequate renal function defined as calculated creatinine clearance greater than 30 mL/min per the Cockcroft and Gault formula. 7. Adequate bone marrow, blood coagulation, and liver functions, as defined in the study protocol. 8. Negative serum or urine pregnancy test for women of reproductive potential. Exclusion criteria: 1. Brain or leptomeningeal metastases, including stable metastases. 2. More than 1 prior systemic chemotherapy regimen for recurrent metastatic or primary unresectable endometrial carcinoma or any treatment targeting vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF)directed angiogenesis. No restriction regarding prior adjuvant chemotherapy or hormonal therapy. 3. Prior systemic antitumor therapy within 3 weeks. 4. Not fully recovered from prior radiotherapy based on investigator judgement. 5. Participants with greater than 1+ proteinuria on urine dipstick testing to undergo 24hour urine collection for quantitative assessment of proteinuria. Participants with greater than 1 gm will be ineligible. 6. Significant cardiovascular impairment: history of congestive heart failure greater than New York Heart Association Class II; unstable angina; myocardial infarction or stroke within 6 months of the first dose of study drug; cardiac arrhythmia requiring medical treatment. 7. Prolongation of QTc interval greater than 480 msec. 8. Bleeding disorder or thrombotic disorders requiring anticoagulant therapy, such as warfarin, or similar agents requiring therapeutic INR monitoring (treatment with low molecular weight heparin [LMWH] allowed). 9. Active hemoptysis within 3 weeks prior to the first dose of study drug. 10. Females who are pregnant or breast feeding.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Advanced Endometrial Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>