<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02853968</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to study stained Castleman's Disease lymph nodes and perform flow cytometry and cell culture experiments on Castleman Disease blood samples to determine which cellular pathways and immune cell types are driving the disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Unlock the Cell: Castleman's Disease Flow Cytometry Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a University of Pennsylvania-sponsored project that is supported by the Castleman Disease Collaborative Network and the patients/loved one's group Castleman's Warriors (Castleman's Awareness and Research Effort). Castleman Disease (CD) is a rare and poorly understood lymphoproliferative disease. The multicentric CD subtype (MCD) involves enlarged lymph nodes in multiple regions of the body and can be fatal if untreated. MCD patients demonstrate acute inflammatory crisis due to upregulation of inflammatory agents most notably IL-6 and VEGF followed by multiple organ failure and death. Unlock the Cell aims to identify the pathways the disease takes through flow cytometry studies. The purpose of the CD Research study is to collect blood samples and/or buccal swabs or saliva samples and medical information of MCD patients and compare them to control samples so researchers can understand the causes of MCD, and design treatments based on our findings. In this study, the investigators will analyze inflammatory markers, cells, and signaling pathways in prospectively collected blood samples using biochemical and RT-PCR techniques, proteomics, genomics, immunohistochemistry, storage for future use, cell culture treated with external stimuli, flow cytometry, and other molecular tests. A secondary aim is to collect excess stored tissue samples (e.g., lymph node, bone marrow) from previous procedures and store these samples along with unused blood samples for future research purposes to be performed at the University of Pennsylvania or shared with other Castleman disease researchers and biobanks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Giant Lymph Node Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Person of any age with HHV8negative, idiopathic multicentric Castleman disease, who have negative staining for LANA1 on lymph node biopsy Patients without a pathology report that indicates Castleman Disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Unlock the Cell</keyword>
	<keyword>Castleman's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>CD</keyword>
	<keyword>Castleman Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>MCD</keyword>
	<keyword>iMCD</keyword>
	<keyword>Angiofollicular Lymph Hyperplasia</keyword>
	<keyword>multicentric Castleman's disease</keyword>
	<keyword>multicentric Castleman disease</keyword>
	<keyword>idiopathic multicentric Castleman disease</keyword>
</DOC>