<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="69369">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02202759</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>C26002</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>U1111-1155-9023</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2014-000804-88</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>REec-2014-1176</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02202759</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of MLN0264 in Patients With Cancer of the Stomach or Gastroesophageal Junction</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2 Trial of MLN0264 in Previously Treated Patients With Metastatic or Recurrent Adenocarcinoma of the Stomach or Gastroesophageal Junction Expressing Guanylyl Cyclase C (GCC)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Millennium Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Millennium Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to assess the efficacy, safety and tolerability of MLN0264 in
      patients with recurrent or metastatic guanylyl cyclase C (GCC)-positive adenocarcinoma of
      the stomach or gastroesophageal junction.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The drug being tested in this study is called MLN0264. MLN0264 is being tested to treat
      tumors in people who have metastatic or recurrent gastric or gastroesophageal junction
      malignancies expressing guanylyl cyclase C (GCC). This study will assess tumor size
      reduction in patients who are administered MLN0264.

      The study will enroll 42 to 81 patients. All participants will be administered MLN0264 at
      1.8 mg/kg as a single, 30-minute, intravenous (IV) infusion on Day 1 of each 3-week
      treatment cycle, followed by a rest period of 20 days. Participants will continue to receive
      MLN0264 for up to 1 year or until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity occurs.

      This multi-centre trial will be conducted worldwide. The overall time to participate in this
      study is approximately 19 months. Participants will make 3 to 6 visits to the clinic per
      treatment cycle, an end-of-treatment visit 30 days after the last dose of study medication,
      and follow-up assessments every 12 weeks until death or 6 months after the last patient
      completes treatment - whichever occurs first.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate (ORR) Based on Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST)</measure>
    <time_frame>From 21 days, every other cycle, starting with Cycle 2 until disease progression, death or study closure (up to 6 months after the enrollment of the last patient)</time_frame>
    <description>ORR is defined as the percentage of participants with a complete response (CR) or partial response (PR) using Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1. CR: Disappearance of all target lesions, non-target lesions, no new lesions, and normalization of tumor marker level. PR: At least a 30% decrease in the sum of diameters of target lesions, no progression in non-target lesion, and no new lesions.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Adverse Events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the first dose through 30 days after the last dose of study medication (Up to 13 months)</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a participant administered a pharmaceutical product; the untoward medical occurrence does not necessarily have a causal relationship with this treatment.
Serious adverse event (SAE) means any untoward medical occurrence that at any dose results in death, is life-threatening, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of an existing hospitalization, results in persistent or significant disability or incapacity, is a congenital anomaly/birth defect or is a medically important event. Relationship of each AE to study drug will be determined by the Investigator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Potentially Clinically Significant Laboratory Evaluation Findings</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 of each 21 day cycle and 30 days after the last dose of study medication (Up to 13 months)]</time_frame>
    <description>Participants with at least one post-baseline potentially clinically significant serum chemistry, hematology, coagulation or urinalysis result.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Potentially Clinically Significant Vital Signs Findings</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 of each 21 day cycle and 30 days after the last dose of study medication (Up to 13 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Participants with at least one potentially clinically significant post-baseline vital sign finding including measurements of diastolic and systolic blood pressure, heart rate, and oral temperature.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 21 of every other 21-day cycle starting with Cycle 2, 30 days after the last dose of study medication, and then every 12 weeks for up to an additional 6 months (approximately 18 months)</time_frame>
    <description>PFS is defined as the time from the date of first study drug administration to the date of first documentation of disease progression or death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response</measure>
    <time_frame>From first documented response until disease progression (Up to 18 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of response is defined as the time from the date of first documentation of a confirmed response to the date of first documentation of disease progression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Control Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 21 of every other 21-day cycle starting with Cycle 2, 30 days after the last dose of study medication, and then every 12 weeks for up to an additional 6 months (Approximately 18 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Disease control rate is defined as the percentage of participants with complete response (CR) or partial response (PR) or stable disease (SD) with a minimum of 12 weeks' duration. Duration of SD is defined as the time from the date of first study drug administration to the date of first documentation of disease progression for patients who achieved SD as the best overall response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>: Until death or 6 months after the last patient completes treatment—whichever occurs first</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival is defined as the time from the date of first study drug administration to the date of death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax: Maximum Observed Serum Concentration for MLN0264</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycles 1-3 predose and 10 minutes, 4 hours, and 3, 4, 8 and 15 days postdose. Cycles 4+ predose, 10 minutes, 4 hours, and 4 and 8 days postdose.</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum observed serum concentration (Cmax) is the peak serum concentration of a drug after administration, obtained directly from the serum concentration-time curve.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum Concentration Conjugated and Unconjugated Total Antibody</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycles 1-3 predose and 10 minutes, 4 hours, and 3, 4, 8 and 15 days postdose. Cycles 4+ predose, 10 minutes, 4 hours, and 4 and 8 days postdose.</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected and sent to a laboratory to be tested for conjugated and unconjugated antibodies.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum Concentration of Monomethyl Auristatin E (MMAE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycles 1-3 predose and 10 minutes, 4 hours, and 3, 4, 8 and 15 days postdose. Cycles 4+ predose, 10 minutes, 4 hours, and 4 and 8 days postdose.</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected and sent to a laboratory to be tested for MMAE.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Tumor Size</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 21 of each 21-day cycle, 30 days after the last dose of study medication, and then every 12 weeks for up to an additional 6 months (Approximately 18 months)</time_frame>
    <description>The best percentage of tumor reduction from baseline in the sum of the diameter will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Guanylyl Cyclase C (GCC) H-score Assessed by Immunohistochemistry (IHC)</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre-screening through end of study (approximately 20 months)</time_frame>
    <description>GCC H-score is based on the sum of the 0 to 300 H-score for cytoplasmic staining and the 0 to 300 H-score for apical staining for a total possible H-score 0 to 600. Separate consent is required to obtain archival tumor specimens for GCC expression assessment prior to screening.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of Antitherapeutic Antibodies (ATA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose of each 21 day cycle and 30 days after last dose of study medication (Up to 13 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected to assess the immunogenicity of MLN026 (ATA development) using a laboratory test. Neutralizing ATA assessment will be performed for ATA-positive samples only.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">81</enrollment>
  <condition>Adenocarcinoma of the Stomach</condition>
  <condition>Gastroesophageal Junction Expressing Guanylyl Cyclase C</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MLN0264 1.8 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>MLN0264 1.8 mg/kg, 30-minute intravenous (IV) infusion, Day 1 of each 21-day cycle, for up to 1 year or until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity occurs. The dose may be decreased, delayed or discontinued in participants who develop treatment-associated nonhematologic and hematologic toxicity to MLN0264.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MLN0264</intervention_name>
    <description>MLN0264 IV infusion</description>
    <arm_group_label>MLN0264 1.8 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Male or female participants 18 years of age or older when written informed consent is
             obtained.

          2. Histologically confirmed metastatic or advanced inoperable adenocarcinoma of the
             stomach or gastroesophageal junction with immunohistochemistry (IHC) evidence of
             guanylyl cyclase C (GCC) expression indicated by an H-score of 10 or greater.

          3. Treatment with 1 or more prior chemotherapies for advanced or metastatic
             adenocarcinoma of the stomach or gastroesophageal junction.

          4. Measurable disease as defined by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors
             (RECIST) version 1.1 guidelines. All scans and x-rays used to document measurable
             disease must be done within 28 days before enrollment (ascites and bone lesions are
             not considered measureable disease).

          5. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1 within 14 days
             before enrollment.

          6. Female participants who:

               -  Are postmenopausal for at least 1 year before the screening visit, OR

               -  Are surgically sterile, OR

               -  If they are of childbearing potential, agree to practice 2 effective methods of
                  contraception, at the same time, from the time of signing the informed consent
                  through 30 days after the last dose of study drug, or

               -  Agree to practice true abstinence, when this is in line with the preferred and
                  usual lifestyle of the participant. (Periodic abstinence [eg, calendar,
                  ovulation, symptothermal, postovulation methods] and withdrawal are not
                  acceptable methods of contraception.)

             Male participants, even if surgically sterilized (ie, status postvasectomy), who:

               -  Agree to practice effective barrier contraception during the entire study
                  treatment period and through 4 months after the last dose of study drug, or

               -  Agree to practice true abstinence, when this is in line with the preferred and
                  usual lifestyle of the participant. (Periodic abstinence [eg, calendar,
                  ovulation, symptothermal, postovulation methods for the female partner] and
                  withdrawal are not acceptable methods of contraception.)

          7. Voluntary written consent must be given before performance of any study-related
             procedure not part of standard medical care, with the understanding that consent may
             be withdrawn by the participant at any time without prejudice to future medical care.

          8. Adequate organ and hematological function as evidenced by the following laboratory
             values within 14 days before enrollment:

               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 x 10^9/L

               -  Platelet count ≥ 100 x 10^9/L

               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL

               -  Activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) ≤ 1.5 x the upper limit of the
                  normal range (ULN) per institutional laboratory normal range

               -  International normalized ratio (INR) ≤ 1.5 x ULN

               -  Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN

               -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN

               -  Albumin ≥ 3g/dL

               -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≤ 2.5 x ULN

               -  Serum lipase ≤ 3 x ULN and serum amylase within the normal range

          9. Resolution of all toxic effects of prior treatments except alopecia to Grade 0 or 1
             by National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI
             CTCAE) version 4.03.

         10. Willing and able to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plan, laboratory tests,
             and other trial procedures.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Radiotherapy within 4 weeks before enrollment.

          2. Concurrent treatment or treatment within 4 weeks of study entry with any other
             investigational agent or chemotherapy.

          3. Female participants who are lactating and breastfeeding or have a positive pregnancy
             test during the Screening period.

          4. Uncontrolled, clinically significant, symptomatic cardiovascular disease within 6
             months before enrollment, including myocardial infarction, unstable angina, Grade 2
             or greater peripheral vascular disease, cerebrovascular accident, transient ischemic
             attack, congestive heart failure, or arrhythmias not controlled by outpatient
             medication.

          5. Treatment with any medication that has a clinically relevant potential risk of
             prolonging the QT interval or inducing torsades de pointes that cannot be
             discontinued or switched to a different medication before starting study drug.

          6. Participants with electrocardiogram (ECG) abnormalities considered by the
             investigator to be clinically significant, or repeated baseline prolongation of the
             rate-corrected QT interval (QTc).

          7. Ongoing or clinically significant active infection as judged by the investigator.

          8. Signs of peripheral neuropathy (PN) ≥ NCI CTCAE Grade 2.

          9. Concomitant chemotherapy, hormonal therapy, immunotherapy, or any other form of
             cancer treatment.

         10. Use of strong cytochrome P450 (CYP) 3A4 inhibitors within 2 weeks before the first
             dose of study drug.

         11. Any preexisting medical condition of sufficient severity to prevent full compliance
             with the study.

         12. History of or current neoplasm other than gastric adenocarcinoma, except for
             curatively treated nonmelanoma skin cancer or in situ carcinoma of the cervix uteri.

         13. Known diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection (testing is not
             mandatory).

         14. Symptomatic brain metastases.

         15. Ongoing anticoagulant therapy (eg, aspirin, coumadin, heparin).
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director Clinical Science</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Millennium Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>St. Petersburg</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinatti</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Nasheville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Brugge</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Brussels</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Bruxelles</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Leuven</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Malaga</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Greater London</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Manchester</city>
        <state>Greater Manchester</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Sutton</city>
        <state>Surrey</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 3, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 7, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Drug therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
