<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00047073</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Chemotherapy drugs such as sirolimus use different ways to stop tumor cells from dividing so they stop growing or die. Giving a chemotherapy drug before surgery may shrink the tumor so that it can be removed during surgery. PURPOSE: Phase I/II trial to study the effectiveness of sirolimus in treating patients who have glioblastoma multiforme that did not respond to previous radiation therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sirolimus in Treating Patients With Glioblastoma Multiforme</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the maximum tolerated dose of sirolimus in patients with glioblastoma multiforme. - Determine the safety profile of this drug in these patients. - Determine the efficacy of this drug, in terms of 6-month progression-free survival and objective response, in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study. - Phase I: Patients receive oral sirolimus for 5-7 days before surgery. Patients then undergo surgical resection. Patients resume oral sirolimus once daily after full recovery from surgery. Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Cohorts of 3-6 patients receive escalating doses of sirolimus until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined. The MTD is defined as the dose preceding that at which at least 2 of 3 or 2 of 6 patients experience dose-limiting toxicity. - Phase II: Patients receive oral sirolimus as in phase I at the dose determined in that phase. Patients are followed for survival. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 3-12 patients will be accrued for phase I of the study within 3-12 months. A total of 32 patients will be accrued for phase II of the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Central Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed intracranial glioblastoma multiforme Disease progression by MRI or CT scan Confirmation of true progressive disease (not radiation necrosis) by positronemission tomography, thallium scanning, MRI, or surgical documentation required if patient received prior interstitial brachytherapy or stereotactic radiosurgery Failed prior radiotherapy Phase I patients: Eligible for salvage surgery No limits on prior therapy Phase II patients: Tumor progression by MRI or CT scan required within the past 14 days if recurrent disease is present No prior therapy for more than 3 relapses Recent resection of recurrent or progressive tumor allowed as long as all of the following conditions apply: Recovered from surgery MRI or CT scan performed no more than 96 hours since prior surgery OR within 46 weeks after surgery Baseline MRI or CT scan performed within 14 days of study entry PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 18 and over Performance status Karnofsky 60100% Life expectancy More than 8 weeks Hematopoietic WBC at least 3,000/mm^3 Absolute neutrophil count at least 2,000/mm^3 Platelet count at least 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin at least 10 g/dL (transfusion allowed) Hepatic Bilirubin less than 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) SGOT less than 1.5 times ULN Renal Creatinine less than 1.5 mg/dL Other Cholesterol less than 350 mg/dL Triglycerides less than 400 mg/dL No concurrent disease that would obscure toxicity or dangerously alter drug metabolism No other significant uncontrolled serious medical illness that would preclude study participation No other cancer except nonmelanoma skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix unless patient is in complete remission and off all therapy for that disease for at least 3 years No active infection No prior allergic reactions to compounds of similar chemical or biological composition to sirolimus No psychiatric illness that would preclude study participation Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective barrier contraception PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy At least 1 week since prior interferon Chemotherapy At least 2 weeks since prior vincristine At least 3 weeks since prior procarbazine At least 6 weeks since prior nitrosoureas Endocrine therapy At least 1 week since prior tamoxifen Radiotherapy See Disease Characteristics At least 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy Surgery See Disease Characteristics Other Recovered from prior therapy At least 1 week since prior noncytotoxic agents (except radiosensitizers)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent adult brain tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>adult glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult giant cell glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult gliosarcoma</keyword>
</DOC>