<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00047671</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This 11-week study aims to determine how genetic factors affect the way African Americans and Caucasians with major depression respond to antidepressant medication [citalopram (Celexa®)].</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ethnic Variations in Antidepressant Response</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Depressed patients vary substantially in their responses to antidepressants. Genetic factors may account for a large part of these differences in response. This study will include both African Americans and Caucasians to examine the role of genetic factors in treatment response. Participants receive citalopram (Celexa) for 8 weeks and a placebo for 1 week. Visits occur once a week for 11 weeks. A variety of interviews, scales, tests, and questionnaires are used to assess participants.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Citalopram</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antidepressive Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexetimide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DSMIV criteria for Major Depression AfricanAmerican or Caucasian ethnic background (both parents and 3 out of 4 grandparents) Schizophrenia, schizophreniform disorder, schizoaffective disorder, schizotypal disorder, psychotic depression, or bipolar disorder Current drug abuse or history of drug abuse within the past 6 months Unstable medical or neurological conditions that interfere with the treatment of depression Allergy to citalopram Failure to respond to adequate citalopram drug trial (40 mg for at least 6 weeks) Seizure disorder Pregnancy Psychotropic medications, including antidepressants and neuroleptics Suicidal ideation or other safety issues Fluoxetine (Prozac) or MAOIs (Nardil, Parnate) in the last 2 months Ongoing cognitive behavioral therapy or intensive psychotherapy. General talk therapy is acceptable</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Depressive Disorder</keyword>
</DOC>