<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00535652</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the tissue kinetics of ertapenem in colonic tissue from three hours up to six hours (25% of dosing interval) after administration of ertapenem.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Concentration of Ertapenem in Colorectal Tissue</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to determine the tissue kinetics of ertapenem in colorectal tissue from three hours up to six hours (25% of dosing interval) after administration of ertapenem before an elective surgical intervention (open or laparoscopic surgery) at the colon/rectum. Subjects are patients. Hospitalized patients 18 years or older requiring elective surgical intervention (open or laparoscopic surgery) at the colon will be eligible for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colonic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diverticulum</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diverticulosis, Colonic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ertapenem</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Hospitalized patients 18 years or older requiring elective surgical intervention (open or laparoscopic surgery) at the colon will be eligible for this study. Patients with benignant disorders (e.g. colonic diverticulosis) will be preferred. Pregnancy or lactation in women Emergency surgery, history of serious allergy or intolerance to βlactam antibiotics and other carbapenems Systemic antimicrobial therapy with ceftazidime (internal standard of highperformance liquid chromatography / mass spectrometry) within a 7 days period prior to study entry Ongoing intraabdominal infections Terminal illness Chronic immunosuppressive therapy Severe diseases of the liver, e.g. cirrhosis of the liver with ALT or AST &gt; 6 x upper limit of normal (ULN) and bilirubin &gt; 3 x ULN, severe renal insufficiency with a creatinine clearance ≤30 mL/min., neutrophil count &lt; 1000 cells/mm3, platelets &lt; 75000 cells/mm3 and coagulation studies (INR) &gt; 1.5 x ULN, ongoing therapy with valproin acid.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>