<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01405638</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Aim: To evaluate the effect of a lifestyle intervention delivered through telephone-based motivational interviewing (MINT) versus a patient navigation intervention on blood pressure reduction and CRC screening. Hypotheses: Among black men, aged &gt; 50 years with uncontrolled HTN and in need of CRC screening: 1. Hyp. 1: those randomized to the lifestyle intervention will have lower BP compared to those randomized to the patient navigation intervention at 6 months. 2. Hyp. 2: those randomized to the patient navigation intervention will have higher CRC screening rates compared to those randomized to the lifestyle intervention at 6 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Faith-based Approaches to Treating Hypertension and Colon Cancer Prevention</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary outcomes will be (1) within-patient change in systolic and diastolic BP from baseline to 6 months and (2) CRC screening rates as determined by colonoscopy report or fecal immunochemical test (FIT) result from the primary care provider at 6 months. Blood pressure will be assessed with an automated digital BP monitor based on American Heart Association guidelines.1 CRC screening will be assessed by self-report and verified with medical records and/or the actual colonoscopy or FIT report from participants' providers.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colonic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants must be age 50 years or older Participants must have a working telephone (a necessary criterion since much of the interventions are telephone based) Selfidentified as a black or African American and male Have uncontrolled hypertension defined as SBP&gt;135 mmHg or DBP&gt;85 mmHg and SBP &gt;130 mmHg or DBP &gt;80 mmHg (in those with diabetes) at the screening Have a need for CRC screening defined as: 1) no colonoscopy in the last 10 years; 2) no Flexible sigmoidoscopy, Digital Contrast Barium Enema or CTcolonoscopy in the last 5 years, or 3) no Fecal Immunochemical Test or Fecal Occult Blood Test in the last 12 months. All participants must be fluent in English. Certain measures used have not been verified in other languages. Inability to comply with the study protocol (either selfselected or by indicating during screening that he could not complete all requested tasks).</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>