<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03034265</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the concentration and interindividual variability of urinary exosomal sodium channels and of plasma angiotensins in patients with difficult-to-treat arterial hypertension and to investigate their dependency on clinical sampling conditions and other related laboratory parameters.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>New Biomarkers and Difficult-to-treat Hypertension</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: Difficult-to-treat hypertension is characterized by uncontrolled blood pressure despite 2 or more antihypertensive drugs. In many of these cases, abnormal renal Na and volume handling plays a central pathogenetic role. Arterial vasoconstriction and renal function are regulated by the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system (RAAS) and its effector hormones angiotensin II and aldosterone. Both control renal tubular function and Na excretion by specific cellular receptors. Blocking the renin-angiotensin-system pharmacologically is therefore a standard approach to treat hypertension. However, there is a great clinical need to improve the classification of hypertensive patients and to predict patient sensitivity to different therapeutic strategies more precisely by new and specific biomarkers. Ang fragments generated by non-canonical enzymatic pathways such as Ang III co-exist with Ang I and Ang II in plasma. Their profile could help reclassify hypertensive patients, for example by differentiating salt and RAAS-related mechanisms with greater predictive power than plasma renin and aldosterone alone. Furthermore, urinary exosomes are small membrane vesicles (&lt;0.1 μm) shed into the urine by tubular epithelial cells. They contain tubular Na channels known as targets of furosemide and thiazide drugs used to treat volume overload and hypertension by increasing tubular sodium excretion. Cellular Na channel concentration in the tubule is regulated by Ang II and aldosterone. Urinary exosomal Na channel abundance may therefore provide valuable information about tubular function otherwise not rendered by standard laboratory tests. These biomarkers could improve the classification of patients with difficult-to-control hypertension and inform treatment decisions. As a prerequisite for the design of future validation studies, however, their concentration and interindividual variability is still not known in this patient group. Study aim: This study aims to determine the concentration and interindividual variability of urinary exosomal sodium channels and of plasma angiotensins (candidate biomarkers) in patients with difficult-to-treat arterial hypertension and to determine their dependency on sampling conditions, dietary salt intake, and plasma renin and aldosterone concentrations. Candidate biomarker definition: - Plasma Ang peptides planned for determination in the study are Ang I and II and its metabolites Ang 2-10, 2-8, 3-8, 1-7, 2-7, 3-7, 1-5 (Ang peptide profile). - Urinary exosomal Na channel proteins planned for determination in the study are Na+-Cl− cotransporter (NCC), epithelial sodium channel subunits alpha, beta, gamma (ENaC) and Na-K-Cl cotransporter type 2 (NKCC 2). Study type: This is an investigator initiated, monocentric observational pilot study in 24 ambulatory patients with difficult-to-treat hypertension who meet the inclusion criteria and none of the exclusion criteria. Setting: The study is performed at the outpatient hypertension clinic of the University clinic for nephrology, hypertension and clinical pharmacology, Inselspital, Bern University Hospital, Bern, Switzerland. Objectives: - The primary objective of the study is to determine the concentration and interindividual variability of urinary exosomal Na channels and of plasma angiotensin peptides under standardized clinical sampling conditions in patients with difficult-to-treat hypertension. - The secondary objectives of the study are 1. to determine the association of these candidate biomarkers with urinary Na excretion, plasma renin and aldosterone concentrations, and aldosterone-to-renin ratios on clinical visit 2, 2. to assess the repeatability of biomarker determinations under spontaneous (visit 1) compared to standardized clinical sampling conditions (visit 2). Study plan and procedures: The concentration of the candidate biomarkers are determined in blood and spot urinary samples obtained on the first clinical visit (visit 1) and again under standardized laboratory conditions on the second clinical visit (visit 2) after stopping RAAS inhibitory drugs, diuretics and other interfering drugs for an appropriate period of 5-31 days. Determinations of candidate biomarkers are made in parallel with clinical blood and urine tests performed routinely on these two visits. The routine laboratory determination on visit 2 include supine and standing plasma renin and aldosterone measurements in the morning after 1 h rest and again after 1 hour walking. Furthermore, 24h urinary Na and K excretion are determined. Biological samples are processed according to standardized laboratory protocols. Plasma Ang peptides are determined by gas chromatography-mass spectrometry. Urinary exosomal proteins are determined by Western-Blot using specific antibodies. Clinical data and routine laboratory results for visits 1 and 2 are obtained from clinical patient files. Recruitment of participants: Consecutive ongoing participant recruitment is performed in daily clinic practice by the investigators who check referrals for potential eligibility. Duration of individual study participation: Individual study participation begins with study inclusion on visit 1 and ends with the completion of visit 2.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with ≥2 antihypertensive drugs for ≥3 months Reported blood pressure ≥140/90 mmHg and/or patient reported as having medically uncontrolled hypertension by the referring physician Age ≥18 years, capacity to provide and granted written informed consent Known comorbidity that may significantly bias outcome measures and/or generalisability including chronic stage 45 renal insufficiency; glomerulonephritis, liver insufficiency (ChildPugh B or C), chronic obstructive pulmonary disease Global Initiative for Obstructive Lung Disease grade 4; chronic heart failure New York Heart Association Class IV; except diabetes Known secondary hypertension Mandatory medication incompatible with study aims or with relevant impact on RAAS (e.g. converting enzyme inhibitors, angiotensin type 1 receptor blockers, diuretics) that cannot be paused between visit 1 and 2 Mean sitting office blood pressure &gt;190/110 mmHg measured 3x on visit 1 Normotension on visit 1 (mean sitting office blood pressure measured 3x &lt;140/90 mmHg) Insufficient knowledge of project language in the absence of an interpreter Pregnancy or lactation Scheduled clinical visit 2 outside routine workflow timeline (&lt;5 or &gt;31 days after visit 1) Inability to follow procedures (e.g. psychiatric disorders or dementia)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>hypertension; exosome; angiotensin; sodium channel; kidney; aldosterone; renin; urine</keyword>
</DOC>