<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03034681</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot "pre-post" quasi-experimental study evaluates for the first time the effectiveness of Vojta Therapy in treating lumbosciatic and compares it with the transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (TENS) procedure. Patients who agree will be distributed alternately in order of arrival to a Physiotherapy Unit, in such a way that half of the sample will be treated using TENS and the other half with Vojta.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lumbosciatic Syndrome: Vojta Therapy vs. TENS</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Lumbago/lumbosciatic (with or without radicular implication) is the second most frequent cause of primary medical care and the highest cause of disability in the entire world. This pathology is normally slight to moderate in the majority of cases, meaning that the therapeutical treatment tends to be conservative and thus the interest in increasing the range of non-invasive therapeutic possibilities is available. Reflex Locomotion or Vojta Therapy began being used in 1959 for the rehabilitation of children with motor alterations and infants with a risk of cerebral palsy. Years later it was successfully applied to adults with neurological and motor alteration problems. Until now, there have been no studies on its use in pathologies of the spine and, in particular at a lumbar level. A pre-/ post-intervention examination will be performed to obtain an objective clinical analysis (measurements of pain, disability, functionality and joint movement), by means of simple questionnaires completed by the patient (VAS scale, Oswestry and Roland-Morris questionnaires) and exploration techniques (Lasègue manoeuvre, Schöber test, fingertips to floor test and walking on heels and toes).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients diagnosed with acute, subacute or chronic lumbosciatic by a rehabilitation doctor were referred by said doctor to the Physiotherapy Unit, as candidates for either of the therapeutical procedures. Patients with lumbosciatic resulting from a specific pathology (infection, metastasis, neoplasia, osteoporosis, fracture or inflammatory arthropathy).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>