<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00182754</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Octreotide may be an effective treatment for malignant ascites. It is not yet known whether octreotide is more effective than a placebo in treating malignant ascites. PURPOSE: This randomized phase III trial is studying octreotide to see how well it works compared to placebo in treating patients with cancer-related malignant ascites.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Octreotide in Treating Patients With Cancer-Related Malignant Ascites</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Compare the efficacy of octreotide vs placebo, in terms of extending the time-to-paracentesis, in patients with cancer-related symptomatic malignant ascites. Secondary - Compare the number of paracenteses in patients treated with these drugs. - Determine the toxicity of octreotide in these patients. - Compare the quality of life of patients treated with these drugs. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to anticipated ongoing chemotherapy (yes vs no), frequency of prior paracentesis (never vs other), and prior chemotherapy (never vs only first-line chemotherapy vs second-line chemotherapy vs other). Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. - Arm I: Patients receive octreotide subcutaneously (SC) once on day 1. - Arm II: Patients receive placebo SC once on day 1. In both arms, treatment with intramuscular octreotide or placebo repeats monthly for up to 2 years in the absence of unacceptable toxicity. Quality of life is assessed at baseline, 2 weeks, and then monthly for up to 2 years during study treatment. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 6 months for up to 2 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ascites</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Octreotide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed cancer Diagnosis of malignant ascites, as determined by the treating oncologist Positive cytology not required Patient is symptomatic and views ascites as a problem No lymphoma or lymphomatous ascites Planning therapeutic paracentesis ≤ 3 days after study entry OR completed therapeutic paracentesis 2 days before study entry PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 18 and over Performance status Not specified Life expectancy At least 4 weeks Hematopoietic Not at high risk of bleeding from a procedure Hepatic No known cirrhosis or portal hypertension Renal No known history of chronic renal failure, defined as creatinine ≥ 2 times upper limit of normal Other Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception Prior cholecystitis allowed provided patient underwent cholecystectomy No uncontrolled diabetes mellitus No known allergy to octreotide No known allergy to latex No medical condition that would preclude study treatment PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy No concurrent bevacizumab Chemotherapy No concurrent intraperitoneal chemotherapy No concurrent firstline chemotherapy for any cancer except pancreatic cancer Concurrent secondline chemotherapy or laterline chemotherapy allowed Endocrine therapy No other concurrent octreotide Radiotherapy Not specified Surgery Not specified Other No concurrent therapeutic warfarin Concurrent prophylactic warfarin at a dose of 1 mg/day allowed No other concurrent treatment for ascites except paracentesis or ongoing diuretics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>unspecified adult solid tumor, protocol specific</keyword>
	<keyword>malignant ascites</keyword>
</DOC>