<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02454127</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A single-center randomized trial at an academic medical center in Boston, Mass, of overweight or obese adults with known hypertension, dyslipidemia, or fasting hyperglycemia. Participants were enrolled starting July 18, 2000, and randomized to 4 popular diet groups until January 24, 2002.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Four Popular Diet Strategies for Weight Loss and Cardiac Risk Reduction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objective: To assess adherence rates and the effectiveness of 4 popular diets (Atkins, Zone, Weight Watchers, and Ornish) for weight loss and cardiac risk factor reduction. Design, Setting, and Participants: A single-center randomized trial at an academic medical center in Boston, Mass, of overweight or obese adults with known hypertension, dyslipidemia, or fasting hyperglycemia. Participants were enrolled starting July 18, 2000, and randomized to 4 popular diet groups until January 24, 2002. Intervention: A total of 160 participants were randomly assigned to either Atkins (carbohydrate restriction, n=40), Zone (macronutrient balance, n=40), Weight Watchers (calorie restriction, n=40), or Ornish (fat restriction, n=40) diet groups. After 2 months of maximum effort, participants selected their own levels of dietary adherence. Main Outcome Measures: One-year changes in baseline weight and cardiac risk factors, and self-selected dietary adherence rates per self-report. Outcome measures included body weight, total cholesterol, LDL-C, HDL-C, triglycerides, hsCRP, insulin, glucose.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<criteria>BMI 2742; At least one metabolic cardiac risk factor Age under 18 years; Insulin therapy; Unstable chronic illness; Unwilling to follow dietary advice</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>popular diets</keyword>
	<keyword>weight loss</keyword>
	<keyword>lifestyle</keyword>
	<keyword>counseling</keyword>
</DOC>