<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02454972</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Multicenter Phase II Clinical Trial of Lurbinectedin (PM01183) in Selected Advanced Solid Tumors to assess the antitumor activity of lurbinectedin (PM01183) in terms of overall response rate (ORR), in the following advanced solid tumors small cell lung cancer (SCLC), head and neck carcinoma (H&amp;N), neuroendocrine tumors (NETs), biliary tract carcinoma, endometrial carcinoma, carcinoma of unknown primary site, germ cell tumors (GCTs), and Ewing's family of tumors (EFTs)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trial of Lurbinectedin (PM01183) in Selected Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years. Voluntary signed informed consent (IC) Pathologically proven diagnosis of any of the following malignancies: Small cell lung cancer (SCLC). Head and neck carcinoma (H&amp;N). Salivary glands tumors are excluded. Neuroendocrine tumors (NETs), grade 2 and grade 3 according to World Health Organization classification. Biliary tract carcinoma. Endometrial carcinoma. Carcinoma of unknown primary site. Germ cell tumor (GCTs), excluding immature teratoma, or teratoma with malignant transformation. Ewing's family of tumors (EFTs) Prior treatment. Patients must have received: SCLC, endometrial carcinoma: one prior chemotherapycontaining line. H&amp;N, NETs, biliary tract, CUP: one or two prior chemotherapycontaining lines GCTs: no limit of prior therapy EFTs: no more than two prior chemotherapycontaining lines in the metastatic/recurrent setting. Performance status ≤ 2 [Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG)] Adequate major organ function At least three weeks since the last chemotherapy Women of childbearing potential must have pregnancy excluded by appropriate testing before study entry Prior treatment with PM01183 or trabectedin Prior or concurrent malignant disease unless in complete remission for more than five years Known central nervous system (CNS) involvement Relevant diseases or clinical situations which may increase the patient's risk Pregnant or breastfeeding women and fertile patients (men and women) who are not using an effective method of contraception</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>