<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02454010</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the safety and tolerability in subjects who receive FF-21101(111In) for dosimetry and FF-21101(90Y) for treatment of advanced solid tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Dose Escalation Study of Radio-labeled Antibody for the Treatment of Advanced Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoconjugates</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and females ≥ 18 years of age Histologically or cytologically confirmed advanced solid tumor malignancy, refractory or relapsed from prior therapy, or for whom no alternative therapy is available At least 4 weeks beyond the last chemotherapy (or ≥ 5 halflives for targeted agents, whichever is shorter), radiotherapy, major surgery or experimental treatment and recovered from all acute toxicities (≤ Grade 1) Archival tumor sample available, or be willing to undergo a fresh tumor biopsy, prior to study At least one measurable disease site that meets target lesion requirements Adequate performance status: Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) ≤ 2 Life expectancy of ≥ 3 months Adequate hematologic parameters without ongoing transfusional support: Hemoglobin (Hb) ≥ 10 g/dL Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 x 10^9 cells/L Platelets ≥ 150,000 x 10^6 cells/L Adequate renal and hepatic function: Creatinine ≤ 1.5x the upper limit of normal (ULN), or calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 60 mL/minute x 1.73 m^2 per the CockcroftGault formula Total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 times ULN unless due to Gilbert's disease ALT/AST ≤ 2.5 times ULN, or &lt; 5 times ULN for subjects with liver metastases QT interval corrected for rate (QTc) ≤ 480 msec on the electrocardiogram (ECG) obtained at Screening (average of 3 readings) Negative serum pregnancy test Ability to provide written informed consent Previous radioimmunotherapy. Previous antibodybased therapy is allowed as long as ≥ 28 days has elapsed from last dose to study treatment. Prior radiation to &gt; 30% of the red marrow or to maximal tolerable level for any organ Serious cardiac condition within the last 6 months Concomitant medication(s) that may cause QTc prolongation or induce Torsades de Pointes, with the exception of antimicrobials that are considered to be essential for care of the patient History of retinal degenerative disease, history of uveitis, history of retinal vein occlusion (RVO), or any eye condition that would be considered a risk factor for RVO or has medically relevant abnormalities identified on screening ophthalmologic examination Active central nervous system (CNS) malignant disease in subjects with a history of CNS malignancy. Subjects with stable, prior, or currently treated brain metastases are allowed. Known positive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B virus surface antigen (HBsAg) or hepatitis C virus (HCV) Known autoimmune disease Active infection requiring intravenous (IV) antibiotic usage within the last week prior to the dosimetry portion of the study Corticosteroid use within 2 weeks of study treatment Any other medical intervention or other condition which, in the opinion of the Principal Investigator, could compromise adherence with study requirements or confound the interpretation of study results Pregnant or breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>