<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02454777</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized pilot clinical trial studies the feasibility of high-intensity interval training in improving cardiovascular fitness in patients with stage I-III breast cancer undergoing chemotherapy with trastuzumab. Trastuzumab helps patients live longer, but may cause side effects to the heart. Aerobic exercise may help the heart function better, which may help protect it against side effects from trastuzumab. Exercise may also help reduce fatigue and prevent cancer from coming back. High-intensity interval training involves short bursts of higher intensity efforts with longer periods of recovery. This may also allow patients who cannot exercise for a long period of time to still be physically active. This trial studies whether patients can tolerate high-intensity interval training, and how well it works in improving fitness in patients with breast cancer receiving trastuzumab.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>High-Intensity Interval Training in Improving Fitness in Patients With Stage I-III Breast Cancer Undergoing Chemotherapy With Trastuzumab</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. To assess the feasibility (completion of &gt; 80% exercise sessions) of utilizing high-intensity interval training (HIT). II. To determine the effects of HIT on aerobic exercise adaptation when compared to moderate-intensity, continuous training (MCT) and control (CON). III. To examine the effects of HIT on left ventricular function when compared to MCT and CON groups. OUTLINE: Participants are randomized to 1 of 3 groups. ARM I: Participants undergo HIT over 30 minutes, thrice weekly for 12 weeks. ARM II: Participants undergo MCT over 30 minutes, thrice weekly for 12 weeks. ARM III: Participants maintain their current sedentary activity level (&lt; 60 minutes of total exercise per week) for 12 weeks. Participants document their weekly activity in an exercise log. Following completion of all study visits, participants are given the option to complete the MCT exercise program as in Arm II. After completion of study, patients are followed up at weeks 13 and 25.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trastuzumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>English or Spanish speaking Diagnosed with early stage (IIII) breast cancer, without evidence of metastatic disease Planned (neo)adjuvant therapy with trastuzumab (Herceptin) plus chemotherapy Not currently pregnant or planning to become pregnant throughout the duration of cancer treatment Physician (oncologist) clearance to participate in exercise at moderate to high intensity Have read and signed study informed consent document (ICF) EXERCISE INCLUSION CRITERIA: Normal body temperature (=&lt; 100 degrees F) Normal resting electrocardiogram (ECG) Resting blood pressure and/or heart rate within normal limits Participants have not received intravenous or oral chemotherapy on the same day and prior to scheduled exercise session Advanced stage (stage IV) or metastatic breast cancer diagnosis (screening for metastases with scans only needed if there is clinical suspicion for metastases) Medical history of coronary heart or artery disease, chronic or acute congestive heart failure or history of systolic or diastolic insufficiencies Uncontrolled hypertension or other uncontrolled chronic disease (e.g. diabetes mellitus, thyroid disease, pulmonary disease, etc.) Moderate to highly active level of physical activity (e.g. currently participating in &gt;= 60 minutes of moderate aerobic activity weekly) Orthopedic or other restrictions or contraindications to highintensity (cycling) exercise EXERCISE EXCLUSION CRITERIA: Presence of fever (&gt;= 100 degrees F) Abnormal resting ECG Resting blood pressure and/or heart rate outside normal limits Participants have received intravenous or oral chemotherapy on the same day and prior to scheduled exercise session</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>