<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02677571</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose to compare paravertebral thoracic block (PVB) and pectorals nerves block as analgesic option for major breast surgery. 102 patients undergoing reconstruction breast surgery will be randomized into two groups: Group PVB (n=51) will receive US guided paravertebral thoracic block (between T2-T6) performed with 30ml of 0.25% levobupivacaine before general anesthesia (TCI-TIVA) induction. Morphine patient control analgesia (PCA) with loading dose i.v. titrated by the PACU nurse if pain &gt; 5/10 at rest Group PECS (n=51) will receive US guided pectorals nerves block performed with 30ml of 0.25% levobupivacaine before general anesthesia (TCI-TIVA) induction. Morphine PCA with loading dose i.v. titrated by the post-anesthesia care unit (PACU) nurse if pain &gt; 5/10 at rest Primary Outcome Measures: Morphine consumption (mg) (Time Frame: 24 hours) in two Groups Secondary Outcome Measures: Pain at rest and during movement quantified as Numerical Rating Scores (0-10) during the first 24 hours postoperatively. Eventual side effects such as nausea/vomiting. Time necessary to perform the procedure. Pain during procedure execution quantified as Numerical Rating Scores (0-10) Hypnotic and opioids intraoperative consumption to ensure general anesthesia with Bispectral Index between 40 and 60.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PVB vs PECS Block in Breast Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levobupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age&gt; 18 years ASA score I II III undergoing elective reconstruction breast surgery signed informed consent chronic therapy with opioids/ antidepressants urgent/emergent surgery postoperative transfer to the intensive care unit known allergy to any drug medication local skin infection epilepsy alcohol or drug abuse</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>