<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02677363</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Strength training can increase muscle mass and strength while improving bone density and reducing risk for osteoporosis and related fractures. Strength training can also lead to reduced risk for diabetes, heart disease, arthritis, depression, and obesity; and improves self-confidence, sleep and vitality. Research demonstrates that strength training is extremely effective in helping aging adults with chronic conditions prevent further onset of disease and, in many instances, actually reverse the disease process. In Stay Strong, Stay Healthy Program elderly subjects perform resistance exercise training (RET) twice every week. Past literature suggests that resistance training improved muscle activity, muscle strength, muscle mass, and bone mineral density and total body composition, and adiponectin, insulin sensitivity, fasting blood-glucose (BG), HbA1c1 (long-term marker of BG), blood pressure (BP), blood triglycerides (TGs) and low density lipoproteins (LDL) in healthy and diabetic subjects. The purpose of this study is to measure the changes in the above discussed variables after 8-weeks of resistance exercises.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Functional Outcomes of Stay Strong Stay Healthy Program</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants will perform resistance exercise for 8 weeks and measurements (anthropometric, electromyography, pulse wave velocity, strength test, dual x-ray absorptiometry, blood enzymes/hormones, and sleep, diet, memory surveys) will be performed pre- and post-exercise program.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Memory Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 60 or above Enrollment in Stay Strong Stay Healthy Program Strength training &lt; 2 hours/week for past 3 months Not enrolled in Stay Strong Stay Healthy Program Strength training &gt; 2 hours/week for past 3 months Donated more than 463 ml of blood in past 8 weeks Physician discouraged to participate</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Elderly</keyword>
	<keyword>Older</keyword>
	<keyword>Adults</keyword>
	<keyword>Resistant Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>Strength Training</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognitive function</keyword>
</DOC>