<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT01944462</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>The overall goal program measure impact pharmacist pneumococcal vaccine education program ( PPVP ) use senior center model care provide pneumococcal vaccine eligible participant . Hypotheses 1 . PPVP result improve knowledge awareness old minority senior center setting ( primary hypothesis ) ; 2 . Participants vaccinate project experience increased trust receive vaccine pharmacist ; 3 . Participants satisfy trust PV information provide pharmacist PPVP ; 4 . PPVP efficient approach educate patient senior center base cost ; 5 . Participating pharmacist activate implement PPVP learning practice .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact Cost Pharmacist Pneumococcal Vaccination Program With PNEUMOVAX® 23 Urban Senior Center</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heptavalent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>A. Inclusions PPVP : 1 . Age ≥ 50 year old 2 . Can attend 1.5hour session CIP 3 . Cognitively intact base response Abbreviated Mental Test Score ( AMTS ) ≥7 ( see Appendix AMTS instrument ) 4 . Can speak read English ≥4th grade level evidence ability read brief passage 5 . Access telephone B. Inclusions receive optional pneumococcal vaccination : Patient meet ≥1 follow criterion receive first pneumococcal vaccination : 1 . All adult age 65 year old vaccine previously 2 . Age 5064 year follow condition : 1 . Cigarette smoker age 19 year old 2 . Chronic cardiovascular disease ( e.g. , congestive heart failure , cardiomyopathy ; exclude hypertension ) 3 . Chronic pulmonary disease ( include COPD emphysema , adult age 19 year old , asthma ) 4 . Diabetes mellitus 5 . Alcoholism 6 . Chronic liver disease , cirrhosis 7 . Candidate recipient cochlear implant 8 . Functional anatomic asplenia ( e.g. , sickle cell disease , splenectomy ) 9 . Immunocompromising condition immunosuppressive therapy 10 . Chronic renal failure nephrotic syndrome OR Patient meet ≥1 follow criterion receive booster dose pneumococcal vaccination : 1 . Adults age 65 year old receive first dose indication young age 65 year . 2 . Adults age 5064 receive vaccine ≥5 year one follow condition : 1 . Functional anatomic asplenia ( include person sickle cell disease splenectomy patient ) ; 2 . Chronic renal failure ( include dialysis patient ) nephrotic syndrome ; 3 . Immunocompromising condition immunosuppressive therapy A. Exclusions PPVP program : none B. Exclusions receive optional pneumococcal vaccine : 1 . Participant history allergic reaction pneumococcal vaccine 2 . Participant history allergic reaction component vaccine 3 . Participant moderate severe illness ( individual advise speak doctor regard vaccine )</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>pneumococcal vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacist vaccination</keyword>
	<keyword>Pneumovax 23</keyword>
	<keyword>pneumococcal vaccine polyvalent</keyword>
</DOC>