<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01381003</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic Granulomatous Disease (CGD) is a rare inherited disorder in which patients suffer from severe infection and inflammation. The first indication of disease usually appears in early childhood. The basic defect found to be lie in specialised white blood cells called phagocytic cells, which are responsible for engulfing and destroying germs. In CGD, there is a defect in an enzyme (known as NADPH-oxidase) that is responsible for generating bleach like substances that are important for killing some important germs. In the form of the disease known as X-CGD (which accounts for two thirds of patients), there are defined mistakes in a gene called gp91-phox, which is a key part of the NADPH-oxidase. In many cases, patients can be protected from infection by constant intake of antibiotics. However, in others potential life-threatening infections break through. In some cases patients also develop serious inflammation requiring high doses of drugs such as steroids. CGD can be cured by bone marrow transplant, but the best results are available when there is matched donor available. Transplant from unmatched donor have a much worse outcome. Gene therapy of CGD can be performed by introducing a normal copy of human gp91-phox gene into the blood forming stem cells of patients' bone marrow by using a gene carrier (in this study called lentiviral vector). After treatment of the bone marrow cells in a specialised laboratory are given back to the patient and will grow into functional phagocytic cells.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Lentiviral Gene Therapy for X-Linked Chronic Granulomatous Disease (X-CGD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Granulomatous Disease, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Granuloma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>History of at least one severe infection requiring hospitalisation despite standard antimicrobial prophylaxis and/or inflammation complications including one of the following: Oesophageal obstruction, gastric outlet obstruction, bladder outlet obstruction or colitis Molecular diagnosis confirmed by DNA sequencing and supported by laboratory evidence for absent or significantly reduced biochemical activities of the NADPHoxidase Parental/Guardian and where appropriate Child's signed consent/assent 10/10 HLA identical (A,B,C,DR,DQ) family or unrelated or cord blood donor unless there is deemed to be an unacceptable risk associated with an allogeneic procedure Contraindication for leukapheresis (anaemia Hb &lt;8g/dl, cardiovascular instability, severe coagulopathy) or for administration of conditioning medication</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Granulomatous Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Gene therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>X-CGD</keyword>
	<keyword>NADPH-oxidase</keyword>
	<keyword>gp91-phox</keyword>
</DOC>