<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01167686</DOC>
	<brief_summary>General:Prospective, randomized, double blind controlled trial of the food supplement GOLDTRAIN PLUS, to assess its safety and efficacy in comparison to placebo in subjects with upper respiratory infection. Hypothesis: The food supplement GOLDTRAIN PLUS will be superior to placebo in shortening the time to recovery from the disease symptoms. Study design and outcome measures:Study population of 182 generally healthy subjects with acute respiratory infection randomized in 1:1 ratio to active supplement versus placebo treatment, with randomization stratified by site. The study supplement administration will be continued for 7 days, and patient global assessment (PGA) will be the main primary measurement tool, based on a self-reporting questionnaire filled and monitored every 12 hours for 7 consecutive days. Throat and nasal swabs determining type of viral infection, will be taken at inclusion of patient and a number of blood tests at the end of treatment to look for any adverse effects of the medication. Analysis and conclusion: All data-from the filled questionnaires, clinical follow up and laboratory studies will be analyzed by multivariate analysis to determine the efficacy of the supplement and its correlation to the clinical and laboratory parameters.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Gardemont S.A Food Supplement on Upper Respiratory Illness</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Signed Informed Consent 2. Age eligible (18 ≤ Age ≤ 90) 3. Respiratory infection with or without fever 1. Evidence of the bacterial infection 2. Symptoms suggestive of other than respiratory system illness (i.e. diarrhea, abdominal pain, skin rash, urinary symptoms). 3. Hospitalisation is planned 4. Surgery within previous 2 months 5. Pregnancy (women at childbirth age should have a urine betaHCG test performed) 6. Subject with known renal dysfunction (creatinine ≥ 2 mg/dL) 7. Subject has history of debilitating liver dysfunction with elevation of liver enzymes and bilirubin levels to ≥ ULN 8. Participation in the active followup phase of another clinical study of an investigational drug or device 9. Known hypercalcemia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Respiratory infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Viral infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Food supplement</keyword>
	<keyword>Goldtrain Plus (GT+)</keyword>
</DOC>