<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01167335</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess the efficacy of BGG492 as adjunctive treatment in patients with refractory partial onset seizures</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluate the Efficacy of BGG492 as Adjunctive Treatment in Patients With Refractory Partial Onset Seizures</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Seizures</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anticonvulsants</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Outpatients ≥ 50 kg (110 lb) of weight A diagnosis of epilepsy (≥ 2 years prior to screening) with partial seizures with or without secondarily generalized seizures Uncontrolled partial seizures despite having been treated with at least two different AEDs within the last 2 years prior to screening. Treated with a stable dose of 12 AEDs At least 4 partial seizures during the 4week baseline period and at least 4 partial seizures during the 4 weeks prior to the baseline period. No 28day seizurefree period during the 8 weeks preceding randomization Positive biomarker screening Presence of only nonmotor simple partial seizures History of psychogenic seizures Absences, myoclonic seizures e.g. in the context of primary generalized epilepsy; Previous history of LennoxGastaut syndrome Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women Status epilepticus or seizure clusters, according to the judgement of the investigator, occurring within 52 weeks prior to randomization Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>partial onset seizure</keyword>
	<keyword>seizure frequency</keyword>
	<keyword>nervous system diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>central nervous system diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>CNS</keyword>
	<keyword>brain diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>neurologic manifestations</keyword>
	<keyword>adjunctive treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>AEDs</keyword>
	<keyword>antiepileptic drug</keyword>
</DOC>