<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02817061</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Aim: Investigate whether transcranial photobiomodulation (tPBM) using near-infrared light exposure to the head, can improve frontal lobe executive function, working memory and overall mood in normal volunteer participants. Hypothesis: The investigators predict that tPBM will increase cognitive functioning, as measured by Cambridge Cognition cognitive testing in study subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Light for Enhancement of Cognition by Transcranial Repeated Application (ELECTRA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Photobiomodulation (PBM), also called low-level light therapy (LLLT), uses optical power densities less than 100 mW/cm², and usually in the red (600-700 nm) or near infrared (NIR) 780-1000 nm wavelength range. Different light sources (coherent lasers or non-coherent LEDs) used for PBM have been shown to produce beneficial cellular effects and to be responsible for preservation and recovery of tissue function in controlled trials in a wide range of disorders typified by stress injury or degeneration. During PBM, absorption of red or near-infrared photons by cytochrome c oxidase in the mitochondrial respiratory chain causes an increase in cellular respiration that continues for much longer than the light is present when delivered at appropriate fluence and exposure durations. Primary cellular effects include increases in mitochondrial activity and ATP levels, production of low levels of reactive oxygen species, induction of transcription factors (including the pro- survival NF-kB), and inhibition of apoptosis. Over the past decade several studies have reported that a single, transcranial PBM treatment at 810 nm delivered to the head had significant, beneficial effect when used to treat acute ischemic stroke in several different animal models and also in human clinical trials. A similar approach was used to treat acute traumatic brain injury (TBI) in mice and in humans. Pathological examination of the mouse brains demonstrated up- regulation of brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) and stimulated neurogenesis in the hippocampus and increased synaptogenesis in the cortex. A clinical trial is currently in progress at MGH to treat persons with acute moderate TBI. Several studies have shown improvement of cognitive function in persons with chronic TBI. Studies have also been conducted in animal models and in persons with Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's disease, depression and anxiety. Only a very limited number of studies have so far been carried out to test NIR photobiomodulation in normal experimental rodents and in normal human volunteers. In this study, an LED array light source will be used that has been cleared by the FDA for other human uses.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Age: 1825 or 6585 Women of childbearing potential, must use a doublebarrier method for birth control (e.g. condoms with spermicide) if sexually active during the study and for 30 days post treatment of any kind. Subject Informed Consent obtained in writing in compliance with local regulations prior to enrollment into this study. The subject (and caregiver, if applicable) is willing to participate in this study for at least 12 weeks. Inability to speak or read English (necessary for cognitive testing software use). Pregnancy or lactation History of stroke or traumatic brain injury Substance dependence or abuse in the past 6 months Diagnosis with major psychiatric disease (Psychotic disorder or psychotic episode, bipolar affective disorder) Diagnosed with a neurodevelopmental condition (autism or ADHD) A traumatic event that resulted in PTSD Any unstable medical illness (defined as any medical illness which has not been wellcontrolled with standardofcare medications) A significant skin condition (i.e., hemangioma, scleroderma, rash, open wound) or medical implant (e.g. metal plate, implantable shunt or valve) on the head. Inability to understand or participate in the consent and performance of the study. Those with Parkinson's Disease, End Stage Renal Disease, and/or End Stage Liver Disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>no keywords for disease type and/or category</keyword>
</DOC>