<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02817178</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators recently identified promiscuous HLA-DR-derived epitopes from the human telomerase reverse transcriptase (TERT) called universal cancer peptides (UCP), to study tumor-specific CD4+ T cell responses. The investigators found high frequency of naturally occuring UCP-specific TH1 cells in long term survival of metastatic colorectal cancer (CRC) previously treated by 5 fluoro-uracil -oxaliplatin (Folfox) +/- bevacizumab regiment (Godet et al. OncoImmunology 2012 and unpublished data). Epitopes-CRC02 is a French prospective multicenter study which will evaluate the post chemotherapy and post surgery modulation of host tumor-specific CD4 TH1 cell responses in metastatic colorectal cancer patients and their correlation with progression-free survival.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study for Validation of Immunological Biomarkers in Patients With Metastatic Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Performance status ECOGWHO 0, 1 or 2 Metastatic colorectal cancer Histologically proved signed written informed consent previous treatment (chemotherapy, targeted therapy, surgery) for metastatic disease history of autoimmune disease patients under immunotherapy systemic treatment or immunosuppressive drugs or stopped for less than 6 months to the enrollment in this study. corticoids ≥ 1mg/kg acute or chronic infectious disease during treatment or stopped for less than six months other malignancy within the last 5 years, except for adequately treated carcinoma in situ of the cervix or squamous carcinoma of the skin, or adequately controlled limited basal cell skin cancer. pregnancy, breastfeeding or absence of adequate contraception for fertile patients patient with any medical or psychiatric condition or disease which would make the patient inappropriate for entry into this study. patient under guardianship, curator or under the protection of justice.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>