<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03066609</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if secukinumab is effective and safe in the treatment of plaque type psoriasis</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Efficacy and Safety of Secukinumab in Subjects With Moderate to Severe Chronic Plaque-type Psoriasis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subjects must give a written, signed and dated informed consent. 2. Men or women at least 18 years of age at time of screening. 3. Chronic plaquetype psoriasis present for at least 6 months and diagnosed before Baseline. 4. Moderate to severe psoriasis as defined at Baseline by: PASI score of 12 or greater, and IGA mod 2011 score of 3 or greater (based on a static scale of 0 4), and Body Surface Area (BSA) affected by plaquetype psoriasis of 10% or greater. 5. Candidate for systemic therapy. This is defined as a subject having moderate to severe chronic plaquetype psoriasis that is inadequately controlled by topical treatment and/or, phototherapy and/or, previous systemic therapy. 1. Forms of psoriasis other than chronic plaquetype (e.g., pustular, erythrodermic and guttate psoriasis) at Screening or Baseline. 2. Druginduced psoriasis. 3. Ongoing use of prohibited treatments. 4. Previous exposure to secukinumab (AIN457) or any other biologic drug directly targeting IL17 or the IL17 receptor. 5. Use of other investigational drugs at the time of enrollment, or within 5 halflives of enrollment, or within 30 days until the expected pharmacodynamic effect has returned to baseline, whichever is longer; or longer if required by local regulations. 6. Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women, where pregnancy is defined as the state of a female after conception and until the termination of gestation, confirmed by a positive hCG laboratory test.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Plaque psoriasis, Secukinumab</keyword>
</DOC>