<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03066778</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety and efficacy of pembrolizumab plus standard of care (SOC) chemotherapy (etoposide/platinum [EP]) in participants with newly diagnosed extensive stage small cell lung cancer (ES-SCLC) who have not previously received systemic therapy for this malignancy. The primary study hypotheses are that pembrolizumab+EP prolongs Progression-free Survival (PFS) per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 by blinded independent central review (BICR) and Overall Survival (OS) compared with placebo+EP in adult participants with ES-SCLC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Pembrolizumab (MK-3475) in Combination With Etoposide/Platinum (Cisplatin or Carboplatin) for Participants With Extensive Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer (MK-3475-604/KEYNOTE-604)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Has a documented new diagnosis of SCLC by histology or cytology from brushing, washing, or needle aspiration of a defined lesion. Participants who do not have histology samples (defined as core or excisional biopsy, or resections) will need to undergo a new biopsy to provide a tissue sample. Has extensivestage disease defined as Stage IV (T any, N any, M 1a/b) by the American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC), Seventh Edition Has ≥1 lesion that meets the criteria for measurable, as defined by RECIST 1.1, and is appropriate for selection as a target lesion, as determined by local site investigator/radiology assessment Has provided archival tumor tissue sample or newly obtained core or excisional biopsy of a tumor lesion not previously irradiated Has Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 or 1 Has a life expectancy of ≥3 months Has adequate organ function Female and male participants of childbearing potential must be willing to use an adequate method of contraception, starting with the first dose of study treatment through 120 days after the last dose of study treatment and up to 180 days after last dose of chemotherapeutic agents Has received prior systemic therapy for the treatment of SCLC Is currently participating and receiving study treatment or has participated in a study of an investigational agent and received study treatment or used an investigational device within 4 weeks of the first dose of treatment for another healthrelated problem Is expected to require any other form of antineoplastic therapy for SCLC, including radiation therapy, while on study. (Prophylactic cranial irradiation will be possible for those participants with stable disease or better at the completion of the 4 cycles of chemotherapy with or without pembrolizumab.) Has known active central nervous system (CNS) metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis. Has had major surgery within 3 weeks prior to receiving the first dose of study treatment or has not recovered adequately from toxicity and/or complications from an intervention prior to receiving the first dose of study treatment. Has a history of (noninfectious) pneumonitis that required steroids or has current pneumonitis Has a known history of interstitial lung disease Has a known additional malignancy that is progressing or requires active treatment. Exceptions include early stage cancers (carcinoma in situ or Stage 1) treated with curative intent, basal cell carcinoma of the skin, squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, in situ cervical cancer, or in situ breast cancer that has undergone potentially curative therapy. Has active autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment in the past 2 years. Replacement therapy is not considered a form of systemic treatment. Has a known history of, or active, neurologic paraneoplastic syndrome Has clinically active diverticulitis, intraabdominal abscess, gastrointestinal obstruction, and/or abdominal carcinomatosis Has a history of a severe hypersensitivity reaction to treatment with another monoclonal antibody Is taking chronic systemic steroids (in doses exceeding 10 mg daily of prednisone equivalent) within 7 days prior to the first dose of study treatment Has a diagnosis of immunodeficiency or is receiving any form of immunosuppressive therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of study treatment Has received a live vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of study treatment Has received prior therapy with an antiprogrammed cell death protein1 (antiPD1), antiprogrammed cell deathligand 1 (antiPDL1), or antiprogrammed cell deathligand 2 (antiPDL2) agent or with an agent directed to another coinhibitory Tcell receptor (i.e., cytotoxic Tlymphocyteassociated protein 4 [CTLA4], tumor necrosis factor receptor superfamily member 9 [TNFRSF9, OX40, CD137]) or has previously participated in a Merck pembrolizumab (MK3475) clinical trial Has severe hypersensitivity (Grade ≥3) to pembrolizumab and/or any of its excipients Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy Has a known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection Has a history of or known active Hepatitis B or Hepatitis C virus Has a known history of active TB (Bacillus Tuberculosis) Has symptomatic ascites or pleural effusion. A participant who is clinically stable following treatment for these conditions (including therapeutic thoraco or paracentesis) is eligible. Is pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father children within the projected duration of the study starting with the screening visit through 120 days after the last dose of study treatment through and up to 180 days after last dose of chemotherapeutic agents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Extensive stage small cell lung cancer (ES-SCLC)</keyword>
	<keyword>Programmed cell death protein-1 (PD-1)</keyword>
	<keyword>Programmed cell death-ligand 1 (PD-L1)</keyword>
	<keyword>PD1</keyword>
	<keyword>PDL1</keyword>
</DOC>