<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02269163</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Phase 3, Multinational, Multicenter, Open-Label Study of the Safety, Tolerability, Efficacy, and Pharmacokinetics of ProMetic BioTherapeutics Immune Globulin Intravenous (Human) 10% in Adults and Children with Primary Immunodeficiency Diseases (PIDD) to assess the tolerability, safety, efficacy and pharmacokinetics of ProMetic's IGIV in subjects with PIDD. IGIV is intended for the treatment of children and adults with Primary Immunodeficiency Diseases (PIDD) who require IgG (Immunoglobulin G) replacement therapy</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 3, Multinational, Multicenter, Open-Label Study of ProMetic BioTherapeutics IVIG</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>gamma-Globulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rho(D) Immune Globulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subject is male or female between the ages of 2 and 80 years at Screening. For Russian sites, only subjects 18 years of age and older, treated with commercially licensed immune globulin product will be enrolled. For Cohort 1, all subjects will be aged ≥17 to 80 years. For Cohort 2, subjects will be aged 2 to &lt;17 years 2. Subject or parent(s)/legal guardian has given written informed consent/assent (as applicable). Pediatric subjects are defined as 2 to 17 years of age at study entry and will require assent forms as appropriate. 3. Subject or parent(s)/legal guardian agrees to comply with the requirements of the protocol. 4. Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative urine pregnancy test documented at the visit which they receive the first infusion of IMP and must agree to employ adequate birth control measures, as determined by their IRB/IEC, for the duration of the study. 5. The subject must have established one of the following three diagnoses (isolated PIDD of other types will be excluded): Common variable immunodeficiency (CVID) Xlinked agammaglobulinemia (XLA) HyperIgM syndrome and documented low IgG levels (&lt;4.5 mg/mL [450 mg/dL]). 6. Subjects must have been treated with a stable dose of immune globulin administered intravenously (IGIV) or subcutaneously (IGSC), as defined below. For IGIV, a stable dose is defined as administration of a dose of 200800 mg/kg with no more than 25% change during at least 3 consecutive treatments at 21day (±4 days) or 28day (±4 days) dosing intervals. For IGSC, a stable dose is defined as administration of a dose of 300900 mg/kg/month IV (or Subcutaneous equivalent), regardless of dosing schedule, with no more than 25% change during at least 12 weeks. 7. Subjects who are receiving IGSC when they enter the study must have received at least one previous documented IGIV infusion without an associated serious adverse event. 8. Documented trough or steady state levels Subjects who are receiving IGIV when they enter the study have at least 2 documented serum IgG trough levels of ≥ 5 mg/ mL measured in the prior 6 months. One of these can be the serum IgG level at Screening. Subjects who are receiving IGSC have at least 2 documented serum IgG steady state levels of ≥ 5 mg/mL in the prior 24 weeks. One of these can be the serum IgG level at Screening. 9. Authorization to access personal health information. 1. Subject has secondary immunodeficiency or has been diagnosed with dysgammaglobulinemia or isolated IgG subclass deficiency. 2. Subject has ever had a history of severe anaphylactic or anaphylactoid reaction to immunoglobulins or other blood products. 3. Subject has a known history of immunoglobulin A (IgA) deficiency and known antiIgA antibodies. (Note that subjects with IgA deficiency without known antibodies to IgA may be enrolled.) 4. Subject has had a thrombotic event, such as deep vein thrombosis, myocardial infarction, cerebrovascular accident, pulmonary embolism, at any time. 5. Subject has received blood products except IGIV, IGSC, or albumin within the previous 12 months. 6. Subject has participated in another study (except for IGIV, IGSC studies) within the previous 4 weeks. 7. Subject has had cancer in the past 5 years, except for basal cell or squamous cell cancers of the skin. 8. Subject has current or prior diagnosis of malignancies of lymphoid cells such as lymphocytic leukemia, nonHodgkin's lymphoma, or immunodeficiency with thymoma. 9. Subject has known hypoalbuminemia (&lt;3 gm/dL), proteinlosing enteropathy, or nephrotic syndrome. 10. Subject has had a documented active infection within 7 days prior to Screening, or subject is on continuous prophylactic antibiotics. Subjects receiving a course of antibiotic treatment for a recent bacterial infection, which is controlled, can be enrolled into the study. 11. Subject is positive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)1 or HIV2. 12. Subject has a positive hepatitis C virus (HCV) or hepatitis B virus (HBV) nucleic acid test (NAT) performed either by qualitative or quantitative polymerase chain reaction (PCR) in the past 12 months. 13. Subject has levels of alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt;2.5 times the upper limit of normal (ULN). 14. Subject has serum creatinine &gt;1.5 times the ULN or a severe chronic condition such as renal failure with proteinuria. 15. Subject has anemia with a hemoglobin level ≤8 g/dL. 16. Subject has severe neutropenia with neutrophil count ≤1000 per mm3 or has lymphopenia with &lt;500 per/ mm3. 17. Subject is taking prednisone at a dose ≥0.15 mg/kg/day. (Topical steroids for skin conditions, steroid eye drops, chronic use of inhaled steroids for asthma, and intranasal steroids for rhinitis are allowed.) Exception: A brief course of systemic steroids above this threshold (i.e., a steroid burst) is allowed for treatment of a shortterm condition such as an asthma exacerbation or poison ivy exposure. 18. Subject is receiving other immunosuppressive drugs or chemotherapy. 19. Subject has known atrial fibrillation requiring anticoagulant therapy; congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association Class III/IV); cardiomyopathy; or cardiac arrhythmia associated with thromboembolic events, unstable or advanced ischemic heart disease, or hyperviscosity. 20. Subject has known decreased Protein C and/or Protein S levels. 21. Subject is positive for antibodies to β2GPI and/or β2GPIDI at Screening. 22. Female subject who is pregnant, breastfeeding, or planning a pregnancy during the course of the study. 23. A history of epilepsy or multiple episodes of migraine (defined as at least one episode within 6 months of enrolment) not completely controlled by medication, or any condition that is likely to interfere with evaluation of the IMP or satisfactory conduct of the study in the Investigator's opinion.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>