<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03105713</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study develop safety checklists for patients to use before, under and after in-hospital surgery. Patients and Healthcare personnel experiences and risk assesment are used to develop the checklists. The checklist intervention will be sequentially rolled out in a randomized order.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Development and Implementation of Patient Safety Checklists Before, During and After In-hospital Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Focus group interviews of surgical patients and Healthcare personnel are used to reveal risk factors and to develop Patients Safety Checklists. Development will follow the steps in the Healthcare Failure Mode and Effects Analysis. The checklist intervention will be pilot tested and validated before is is rolled out. Patients safety checklists for patients to use are intended to enhance and increase patient involvement in surgical treatment. Further, using the checklists could contribute to reduced complications associated to surgery.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>In study 1 and 2 the investigators include surgical patients with experience from included surgical departments in the two hospitals. Patients must be at age over 18 years old, use Norwegian language, and have been operated 24 weeks before the focus group interview. The studies 1 and 2 includes a strategic sample consisting of gender mix, variation in age and in surgical procedures. For healthcare personnel the studies also require variation in clinical experience from the included surgical clusters.In study 3 the inclusion consists of surgical patients undergoing elective surgery. Inclusion criteria are reiterated from study 1 and 2. In study 1 and 2 the investigators exclude patients that are less than 18 years of age, do not speak Norwegian, have low cognitive function. Patients must be able to consent for participation in focus group interviews. In study 3 the exclusion criteria patients not undergoing surgery. Exclusion criteria are reiterated from study 1 and 2.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Checklist</keyword>
	<keyword>Patient Checklist</keyword>
	<keyword>Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Patient Involvement</keyword>
</DOC>