<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03105440</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to evaluate the effects and validate news physiotherapy techniques: robotic rehabilitation, virtual reality, vibration therapy, canoeing and hand cycling in the secondary clinical complications of the breast cancer, through the Biomedical Instrumentation. It will be realized the double-blind longitudinal clinical study. Will participate in the study 100 women post breast cancer surgery, the volunteers will be allocated in the respective modalities treatment; and 20 healthy volunteers, will be only the control group. The volunteers conducted 10 physiotherapy session, and it will be evaluated after, during and before of the treatment, to evaluated myoelectric activity, scapular and hand muscle strength, range of motion, circumference of the upper limbs and quality of life. Expected to Positive Results With regard to the minimization of pain intensity and lymphedema, favoring the improvement of range of motion of the shoulder joint, myoelectric activity, increased muscle strength, and consequently improves the quality of life.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Innovation Oncological Rehabilitation: Applicability of the Different Techniques Physiotherapeutic Post Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The brest cancer is considered a public health problem worldwide. In Brazil, there was increased survival due to advances in early diagnosis and the therapeutic approaches each more accurate and effective, however these women require care and attention for short and long time, due to the consequences physical and psychosocial, que undertake their quality of life. The innovative techniques physiotherapy treatment can contribute to the prevention and treatment of complications, with the intention to facilitate the early return of women to their daily activities. The aim of this study is to evaluate the effects and validate news physiotherapy techniques: robotic rehabilitation, virtual reality, vibration therapy, canoeing and hand cycling in the secondary clinical complications of the breast cancer, through the Biomedical Instrumentation. It will be realized the double-blind longitudinal clinical study. Will participate in the study 100 women post breast cancer surgery, the volunteers will be allocated in the respective modalities treatment; and 20 healthy volunteers, will be only the control group. The volunteers conducted 10 physiotherapy session, and it will be evaluated after, during and before of the treatment, to evaluated myoelectric activity, scapular and hand muscle strength, range of motion, circumference of the upper limbs and quality of life. Expected to Positive Results With regard to the minimization of pain intensity and lymphedema, favoring the improvement of range of motion of the shoulder joint, myoelectric activity, increased muscle strength, and consequently improves the quality of life.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphedema</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Conservative or nonconservative breast cancer surgery; Acceptance of the Informed Consent. Patients who still have chest drain; Volunteers who need any aiding device to remain in orthostatism; Patients don't accepted of the Informed Consent; Patients who ar afraid of water.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>lymphedema</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>range of motion</keyword>
	<keyword>tecnologic innovation</keyword>
	<keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
</DOC>