<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02619890</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This registry aims to collect clinical and radiologic information including detailed clinical, conventional MR and advanced MR imaging data of patients with brain gliomas. Advanced MR imaging may include diffusion-weighted imaging, perfusion-weighted imaging (dynamic susceptibility contrast, arterial spin labeling, dynamic contrast enhancement), and chemical exchange saturation transfer (CEST) imaging. This registry will describe course of disease and long-term outcomes of brain gliomas.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Brain Glioma Registry Combining Clinical and Imaging Information</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Though the cure for brain glioma- from low grade to glioblastoma- is yet to be found, seeking for curable treatment option is actively developing. Multimodal advanced MR imaging (contrast-enhanced T1 weighted imaging, diffusion-weighted imaging, chemical exchange saturation transfer imaging, and perfusion imaging) on 3 Tesla have shown potential in patients with glioma to monitor treatment response with quantitative assessment. To find suitable imaging biomarker for treatment response, assessing clinical and radiologic outcome for long-term is essential. The creation of a registry for brain glioma in long-term follow up provides an overview of the clinical, relevant treatment standards, advanced MR imaging information, and survival data of patients and thus create opportunities for imaging biomarker research.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients must have radiologically and histologically confirmed diagnosis of Brain Glioma Life expectancy of greater than 3 months Must receive a first or secondline therapy Signed informed consent No brain gliomas Patients who have any type of bioimplant activated by mechanical, electronic, or magnetic means (e.g., cochlear implants, pacemakers, neurostimulators, biostimulates, electronic infusion pumps, etc), because such devices may be displaced or malfunction Patients who are pregnant or breast feeding; urine pregnancy test will be performed on women of child bearing potential</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Adult Glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>MRI</keyword>
</DOC>