<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02619357</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The prevalence, low cost, and low burden of wearable devices that provide quantitative and qualitative feedback on a subject's activity level present an opportunity for the use of these devices in clinical and observational studies. However, the accuracy and reproducibility of any given device may vary with device design and algorithm implementation. Therefore, validation of emerging technologies against known standards such as analysis of exhaled breath and currently available medical devices is critical. This is a single center, two-cohort, single period, open-label, methodology study. No investigational product will be used in this study. Eligible subjects will wear 2 generations of SenseWear Armband devices, 2 ActiGraph GT9x devices (one on the wrist and one on the waist) and a Garmin Vivofit 2 activity tracker wristband for up to 24 hours per day. Subjects who consent to participate in an optional sub-study will wear a SOMNOwatch Plus EEG-6 device while sleeping. Subjects will perform a variety of laboratory and field-based exercise tests and strength exercises using Latex-Free Therabands.The co-primary objectives of this study are firstly to compare the outputs of the test devices (SenseWear Armband Gecko and Actigraph GT9x) to those of the SenseWear Armband MF and secondly to assess the sensitivity and accuracy of the test devices in subjects with COPD or asthma while performing laboratory-based exercise testing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Method Validation Study to Explore the Sensitivity of SenseWear Armband Gecko for Measuring Physical Activity in Subjects With Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) &amp; Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Cohort 1 (COPD) &gt;=45 years and &lt;=70 years Cohort 2 (Asthma) &gt;=18 years and &lt;=70 years. Cohort 1; subjects with a confirmed diagnosis of COPD (Gold stage 2 and 3, COPD patients will be classified according to Global Initiative for Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease [GOLD] Guidelines) as defined by postbronchodilator spirometry FEV1 &gt;=40% and &lt;80% predicted, and FEV1/FVC &lt;0.7 Cohort 2; subjects with documented, physiciandiagnosed asthma. BMI within the range 19 to 32 kilogram(kg)/m^2 (inclusive) Male or female; A female of childbearing potential is eligible to enter and participate in the study if she has a negative pregnancy test at screening and day 1. Capable of giving written informed consent, which includes compliance with the requirements and restrictions listed in the consent form. Women who are pregnant or lactating or are planning on becoming pregnant during the study. Alpha1antitrypsin deficiency: Subjects with a diagnosis of alpha1antitrypsin deficiency as the underlying cause of COPD, if known. Other respiratory disorders: Subjects with tuberculosis, lung cancer, significant bronchiectasis, sarcoidosis, lung fibrosis, pulmonary hypertension, interstitial lung diseases or other active pulmonary diseases. Pneumonia or other respiratory tract infection that has not resolved at least 14 days prior to screening. In addition, any subject that experiences pneumonia during any period between the screening visit and the study visit will be excluded. COPD or asthma exacerbation (in this case defined as a change in symptoms requiring increased doses of current medicines or the prescription of new medicines, e.g., corticosteroids or antibiotics) that has not resolved at least 28 days prior to screening. COPD or asthma exacerbation during any period between the screening visit and the study visit will be excluded. Presence of severe and/or poorly controlled asthma that in the opinion of the investigator renders participation in the study unsafe Any comorbid medical condition that in the opinion of the investigator would make participation in the study unsafe or unfeasible, including conditions that prohibit completion of exercise testing: orthopaedic, neurological, cardiovascular or other complaints that significantly impair normal biomechanical movement patterns and limit the ability to walk/cycle as judged by the investigator. Resting oxyhemoglobin saturation &lt;94%. Use of supplemental oxygen therapy during the day or night. Drug/alcohol abuse: Subjects with a known or suspected history of alcohol (males &gt;21 units per week and females &gt;14 units per week) or drug abuse within the last 2 years. One unit is equivalent to 8 gram (g) of alcohol: a halfpint (~240 milliliter [mL]) of beer, 1 glass (125 mL) of wine or 1 (25 mL) measure of spirits. Inability to abstain from smoking during the period in which the subject is admitted to the Clinical Unit. A history of allergy or hypersensitivity to metal, particularly stainless steel. Clinically significant abnormality on electrocardiogram (ECG) as determined by the investigator. Any vital sign indicator, e.g., hypertension or tachycardia at rest that at the discretion of the investigator would make participation in the study unsafe or unfeasible.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>wearable physical activity monitor</keyword>
	<keyword>step counts</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>energy expenditure</keyword>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
	<keyword>indirect calorimetry</keyword>
</DOC>