<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02619266</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trail will be carried out to evaluated the effect and safety of acupuncture for the anorexia in patients with gastrointestinal tract and lung cancers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Safety and Effect Study of Acupuncture for Anorexia in Patients With Gastrointestinal Tract and Lung Cancers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Acupuncture used for anorexia related to cancer, but there were lack of powerful evidence. The 160 eligibilities will be randomly divided into 3 groups(Acupuncture and Placebo group, Megestrol acetate and Sham Acupuncture group, Placebo and Sham Acupuncture group).The effect will be investigated baseline, the 2,5,8 and 15days. The safety issue will be recorded every section during the acupuncture.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anorexia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cachexia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Megestrol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Megestrol Acetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosed gastrointestinal tand lung cancers; 2. Age ≥18 years; 3. Appetite score≤ 6 (0= worst appetite), and the symptom lasted 2 weeks at lest at screening; 4. Had a history of weight loss ≥5% within 6 moths; 5. Maintained oral intake; 6. Signed the informed consent. 1. Patients with dementia, delirium, intestinal obstruction, pregnancy or lactation; 2. Had uncontrolled symptoms that could impact appetite or caloric intake such as nausea, pain, or depression(The score of the symptoms≤ 3, 0= worst) ; 3. Patients with untreated vitamin B12 deficiency or endocrine abnormalities(thyroid dysfunction and hypoadrenalism); 4. Patients on melatonin supplements or medications with potential appetitestimulating activity(Chinese herb,thalidomide) 5. Less than one week before the screening or there will be a surgery ,radiotherapy and chemotherapy the acupuncture; 6. Lifetime expected less than 3 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cancer Anorexia Cachexia Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Acupuncture</keyword>
	<keyword>Megestrol acetate</keyword>
	<keyword>Poor Appetite</keyword>
	<keyword>Anorexia</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized Controlled Trial</keyword>
</DOC>