<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02619825</DOC>
	<brief_summary>First, investigators must determine the physiological standards across age classes of myocardial stiffness estimated by Elastography in ultrafast (estimated right ventricular stiffness [VD] and left ventricular [LV]). This will be done in groups of children without heart condition, age group (10 children per group, four age groups [0-1mois, 1 month-1 year 1 year-5 years, 5 years-15years]). Secondly, investigators will evaluate myocardial stiffness Elastography (RV and LV) on different groups of children (same age group) with cardiomyopathy and examine correlations with the conventional parameters of systolic and diastolic function of both ventricles and with myocardial strain values. The total population of the study will be 120 children (40 healthy, 80 patients).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Non-Invasive Evaluation of Myocardial Stiffness by Elastography in Pediatric Cardiology (Elasto-Pédiatrie)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Monocenter Prospective, open-label, non-randomized. All patients included in the study have a specific consultation built around a clinical examination and echocardiography, in two stages, with estimates of the stiffness of the myocardium ShearWave Elastography (Aixplorer®) and measures of all echocardiographic parameters estimated in children with a clinical ultrasound machine (Philips and General Electric). Following this consultation, clinic and electrocardiographic monitoring period will be observed for 30 minutes, to ensure the safety of our procedure. Required subjects: 40 healthy volunteers + 80 = 120 persons</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertrophy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathy, Dilated</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathy, Hypertrophic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Group 1. Healthy Age criteria met by group [01mois, 1 month1 year 1 year5 years, 5 years15years] consultation for heart murmur Recipient of a social protection scheme or entitled (excluding AME) Signed informed consent by the holders of parental authority Group 2. Patients MHC nonobstructive: Age criteria met by group [1 month1 year 1 year5 years] Diagnostic criteria of nonobstructive HCM validated by the medical team of pediatric cardiology center (Necker) Recipient of a social protection scheme or entitled (excluding AME) Signed informed consent by the holders of parental authority Group 3. Patients primitive CMD: Age criteria met by group [1 month1 year 1 year5 years] Diagnostic criteria of primary CMD validated by the medical team of pediatric cardiology center (Necker) Recipient of a social protection scheme or entitled (excluding AME) Signed informed consent Group 1. Healthy Patients: Age&gt; 15 years Heart and Systemic Pathology identified metabolic and tissue pathology. known genetic pathology may have cardiac involvement. No echogenicity, Allergy echocardiography gel. Group 2. Group CMH primitive Patients No echogenicity,, Allergy echocardiography gel. Arrhythmia. Pacemaker or defibrillator Group 3. Patients primitive CMD: No echogenicity,, Allergy echocardiography gel. Arrhythmia. Pacemaker or defibrillator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Child</keyword>
</DOC>