<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00666926</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Phase 1 safety, pharmacokinetics, and pharmacodynamics trial of the focal adhesion kinase (FAK) inhibitor PF-00562271 in patients with positive Positron Emission Tomography [PET] scans due to advanced non-hematologic malignancies, including pancreatic, head and neck, and prostatic neoplasms, and patients with other malignancies appropriate for serial biopsy. Screening consists of a Fluorodeoxyglucose Positron Emission Tomography [FDG-PET] and tumor imaging, medical history, physical examination, Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group [ECOG] performance status, blood draws, a pregnancy test for female patients of childbearing potential. Treatment consists of PF00562271 tablets continued until progression of disease, unacceptable toxicity, or patient request. Evaluations for bioactivity are measured by serial FDG-PET and blood tests for biomarkers related to FAK and PYK2 kinase activities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Of PF-00562271, Including Patients With Pancreatic, Head And Neck, Prostatic Neoplasms</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pancreatic, head and neck, and prostatic neoplasms, and patients with nonhematologic malignancies who have tumor appropriate for serial biopsy. Adequate organ function, including bilirubin less than 1.5 x ULN, and [Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group] ECOG performance status of 02. Clinically significant gastrointestinal abnormalities, requirement for systemic anticoagulants or potent CYP 3A4 inhibitors, and history of clinically significant cardiac or pulmonary disorders.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pancreatic Neoplasm</keyword>
	<keyword>Head and Neck neoplasm</keyword>
	<keyword>Prostatic neoplasms; Focal Adhesion Kinase</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase 1</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacodynamics</keyword>
	<keyword>FDG-PET</keyword>
</DOC>