<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="24580">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02786771</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2016P000508</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02786771</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Exploring the Effects of Muse and Spire on Stress Management</brief_title>
  <acronym>Stressless</acronym>
  <official_title>Exploring the Effects of Muse and Spire on Stress Management</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of Spire and Muse on stress
      management. The study will be implemented as a 2-arm randomized controlled pilot study to
      assess the effect of either device on stress management from the end of baseline to
      closeout.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Both Muse and Spire are recent technologies that could improve our understanding of stress
      management and enhance quality of healthcare. The goal of this study is to evaluate if Spire
      and Muse help individuals self-manage stress. Spire has been designed as a discrete clip-on
      tracker that monitors changes in respiration rate. With the companion app, this device
      displays breathing rates in real time and alerts the user through push notification in times
      of tension. Studies show that controlled breathing reduces stress. On the other hand, Muse
      is a headset device that uses EEG (electroencephalogram) sensors that measures electric
      brain frequencies. Muse guides the user in a form of simplified meditation by giving
      feedback in real time (i.e. calm, neutral, active) and audio clues to improve concentration.
      Previous studies have shown that engaging in meditation has the potential to reduce anxiety
      and stress.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in stress episodes (as assessed by the Spire device)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in number of stress episodes in both groups from baseline (2 weeks) to the end of the study (week 9).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose response of engagement on reducing stress episodes (as assessed by the Spire device)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Dose-response of using apps on stress measured by stress levels and participant engagement with the devices.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Health-related quality of life: this will be assessed using the 12 item Short Form health survey (SF-12) scale at the beginning and end of the intervention period for both Groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Focus</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Focus: this will be assessed using the Spire Device which determines focus based off an algorithm that uses breathing rates.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resilience</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Resilience: this will be assessed at baseline and at closeout using the 25 item Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Usability and satisfaction with the app</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Usability and satisfaction with the apps: this will be measured via questionnaires specifically designed for this current project.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">126</enrollment>
  <condition>Stress</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive a Spire device with user-feedback switched off within 4 days of enrollment in the study (shipped within 2 business days after they finish enrollment survey). Participants will be given 4 days, after enrollment, to set up their device before the 2 weeks of baseline. The 2 week baseline will start 4 days after enrollment. After two weeks of baseline with user-feedback off (and a 3 day transition period), participants will turn on the user-feedback for the Spire device which would provide a relaxation aid for the participant for the 6 remaining weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group will also receive Spire device to assess two weeks of baseline stress levels (with user-feedback off). Participants will be given 4 days, after enrollment, to set up their device before the 2 weeks of baseline. The 2 week baseline will start 4 days after enrollment. After these two weeks, participants will continue to use the Spire device with user feedback off for the remaining 6 weeks while they use the Muse device to manage stress through meditation. They will receive the Muse device 3 days before the end of baseline period with set up instructions and will utilize the three last days of baseline to set up their Muse device, Meditation will begin at the end of baseline (week three) and will continue for the remaining 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Spire</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Muse headband</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>InteraXon</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Registered for Partners HealthCare Connected Health Symposium 2016

          -  Over 18 years old

          -  Able to read and speak English

          -  Own a smartphone and have internet connection

          -  Willing to wear a Spire device during all hours (except sleep)

          -  Willing to use the Muse device (Group 2 ONLY)

          -  Willing to participate in a research study and sign the consent form

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Not Registered for Partners HealthCare Connected Health Symposium 2016

          -  Under 18 years old

          -  Not able to read and speak English

          -  Do not own a smartphone and have internet connection

          -  Not willing to wear a Spire device during all hours (except sleep)

          -  Not willing to use the Muse device (Group 2 ONLY)

          -  Not willing to sign the consent form
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <link>
    <url>http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2380326</url>
    <description>12. Morajevi, N, &quot;You can't force calm: designing and evaluating respiratory regulating interfaces for calming technology&quot;</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cohen S, Janicki-Deverts D, Miller GE. Psychological stress and disease. JAMA. 2007 Oct 10;298(14):1685-7.</citation>
    <PMID>17925521</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ellis JG, Gehrman P, Espie CA, Riemann D, Perlis ML. Acute insomnia: current conceptualizations and future directions. Sleep Med Rev. 2012 Feb;16(1):5-14. doi: 10.1016/j.smrv.2011.02.002. Epub 2011 May 18. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21596596</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kassel JD, Stroud LR, Paronis CA. Smoking, stress, and negative affect: correlation, causation, and context across stages of smoking. Psychol Bull. 2003 Mar;129(2):270-304. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>12696841</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Herman JP. Neural pathways of stress integration: relevance to alcohol abuse. Alcohol Res. 2012;34(4):441-7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23584110</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tully PJ, Baker RA, Turnbull D, Winefield H. The role of depression and anxiety symptoms in hospital readmissions after cardiac surgery. J Behav Med. 2008 Aug;31(4):281-90. doi: 10.1007/s10865-008-9153-8. Epub 2008 Apr 9.</citation>
    <PMID>18398676</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Michels N, Sioen I, Braet C, Eiben G, Hebestreit A, Huybrechts I, Vanaelst B, Vyncke K, De Henauw S. Stress, emotional eating behaviour and dietary patterns in children. Appetite. 2012 Dec;59(3):762-9. doi: 10.1016/j.appet.2012.08.010. Epub 2012 Aug 20.</citation>
    <PMID>22918173</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Edmondson D, Green P, Ye S, Halazun HJ, Davidson KW. Psychological stress and 30-day all-cause hospital readmission in acute coronary syndrome patients: an observational cohort study. PLoS One. 2014 Mar 12;9(3):e91477. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0091477. eCollection 2014.</citation>
    <PMID>24621575</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nerurkar A, Bitton A, Davis RB, Phillips RS, Yeh G. When physicians counsel about stress: results of a national study. JAMA Intern Med. 2013 Jan 14;173(1):76-7. doi: 10.1001/2013.jamainternmed.480.</citation>
    <PMID>23403892</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Avey H, Matheny KB, Robbins A, Jacobson TA. Health care providers' training, perceptions, and practices regarding stress and health outcomes. J Natl Med Assoc. 2003 Sep;95(9):833, 836-45.</citation>
    <PMID>14527051</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Paulus MP. The breathing conundrum-interoceptive sensitivity and anxiety. Depress Anxiety. 2013 Apr;30(4):315-20. doi: 10.1002/da.22076. Epub 2013 Mar 6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23468141</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vlemincx E, Van Diest I, Van den Bergh O. A sigh following sustained attention and mental stress: effects on respiratory variability. Physiol Behav. 2012 Aug 20;107(1):1-6. doi: 10.1016/j.physbeh.2012.05.013. Epub 2012 May 23.</citation>
    <PMID>22634279</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Grossman P, Niemann L, Schmidt S, Walach H. Mindfulness-based stress reduction and health benefits. A meta-analysis. J Psychosom Res. 2004 Jul;57(1):35-43.</citation>
    <PMID>15256293</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carmody J, Baer RA. Relationships between mindfulness practice and levels of mindfulness, medical and psychological symptoms and well-being in a mindfulness-based stress reduction program. J Behav Med. 2008 Feb;31(1):23-33. Epub 2007 Sep 25.</citation>
    <PMID>17899351</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cohen S, Kamarck T, Mermelstein R. A global measure of perceived stress. J Health Soc Behav. 1983 Dec;24(4):385-96.</citation>
    <PMID>6668417</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Leon KA, Hyre AD, Ompad D, Desalvo KB, Muntner P. Perceived stress among a workforce 6 months following hurricane Katrina. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2007 Dec;42(12):1005-11. Epub 2007 Oct 11.</citation>
    <PMID>17932611</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gandek B, Ware JE, Aaronson NK, Apolone G, Bjorner JB, Brazier JE, Bullinger M, Kaasa S, Leplege A, Prieto L, Sullivan M. Cross-validation of item selection and scoring for the SF-12 Health Survey in nine countries: results from the IQOLA Project. International Quality of Life Assessment. J Clin Epidemiol. 1998 Nov;51(11):1171-8.</citation>
    <PMID>9817135</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Connor KM, Davidson JR. Development of a new resilience scale: the Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC). Depress Anxiety. 2003;18(2):76-82.</citation>
    <PMID>12964174</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 4, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 23, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kamal Jethwani</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Senior Director for Connected Health Innovation at Partners HealthCare</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Stress Management</keyword>
  <keyword>Mindfulness</keyword>
  <keyword>Meditation</keyword>
  <keyword>Stress Resilience</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Alprostadil</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
