<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01065363</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators propose a project of preventive medicine with concern of local context in Taiwan. The target population includes all staff and faculty members, students, and alumni of a university in Northern Taiwan, with chronic hepatitis B infection. The intervention of this project includes standardized lectures, sports courses, nutrition courses, and an information platform. The investigators will evaluate the efficacy after the intervention, like the reduction of hepatitis B viral load and the associated anthropometric parameters. The results of this project will be initially served as a pilot study for this cohort, and applicated as a promising basis for health promotion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Health Promotion and Management for Hepatitis B Carriers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants were recruited from students, alumni, faculty and staff members with chronic HBV infection (positive HBsAg serostatus ≥6 months) in a university of northern Taiwan from August 1, 2009 to July 01, 2010. Only participants aged 18 and older were included. Excluded were: (a) those who had been diagnosed as chronic liver diseases like chronic hepatitis C infection (AntiHCV (+)), autoimmune hepatitis, Wilson disease, alcoholic liver diseases, drugrelated hepatitis, decompensated liver diseases, cirrhosis, or malignant hepatic tumors; (b) those who had undergone liver transplantation or major operations for liver except cholecystectomy; (c) men who consumed more than 30 gram of alcohol per week or women who consumed more than 20 gram of alcohol per week; (d) women who were pregnant; (e) those who had current medications for any types of chronic diseases except for hyperglycemia, elevated blood pressure, or dyslipidemia within six months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hepatitis B virus DNA</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic factor</keyword>
	<keyword>Body mass index</keyword>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>Lifestyle factor</keyword>
	<keyword>Preventive Medicine</keyword>
	<keyword>Health Promotion</keyword>
</DOC>