<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02345148</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the pharmacokinetics, safety, and tolerability of intranasally administered esketamine in elderly participants (greater than equal to [&gt;=] 75 years of age) and younger healthy adult participants (18 to 55 years of age, inclusive).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetic, Safety, and Tolerability Study of Intranasally Administered Esketamine in Elderly and and Healthy Younger Adult Participants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single-center, 2-cohort, single-dose, open-label study. The duration of study will be approximately 42 days per participant. The study consists of 3 parts: Screening (that is, 28 days before study commences on Day 1) and open-label Treatment (Day 1) and Follow-up (up to Day 13). Esketamine will be administered by intranasal route (delivery of medications through the nasal mucosa) on Day 1. Participants' safety will be monitored throughout the study.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>For Cohort 1, be a man or woman, &gt;= 75 years of age who are either healthy or who present with stable, wellcontrolled, chronic conditions which frequently occur in the elderly, such as: hyperlipidemia; controlled hypertension; impaired fasting glucose, impaired glucose tolerance or type 2 diabetes mellitus controlled with diet, and/or metformin monotherapy, dipeptidyl peptidase4 (DPP4) inhibitor monotherapy or a combination of metformin and DPP4 inhibitor, who have glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) levels less than 8 percent; degenerative joint disorders and osteoporosis; kidney function decline appropriate for age. Inclusion of participants with other chronic, wellcontrolled and stable conditions to Cohort 1 should be reviewed and agreed between the Investigator and the Sponsor For Cohort 2, be a man or woman, 18 to 55 years of age, inclusive For women of childbearing potential in Cohort 2, must have a negative serum betahuman chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) pregnancy test at screening; and a negative urine pregnancy test on Day 1 If a man, must agree to use an adequate contraception method as deemed appropriate by the investigator and to not donate sperm during the study and for 3 months after receiving the study drug Body mass index (BMI) (weight [kg]/height^2 [m]^2) between 18 and 32 kg/m^2 (inclusive), and body weight not less than 50 kg Diagnosed with a current or previous psychiatric disorder including but not limited to psychotic, bipolar, major depressive, or anxiety disorder Clinically significant medical illness Severe renal impairment Clinically significant abnormal values for hematology, clinical chemistry, or urinalysis at screening or at admission to the study center (Day 1) as deemed appropriate by the investigator History of drug or alcohol abuse disorder within the past 1 year, or a reason to believe a participant has such a history</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Healthy</keyword>
	<keyword>Esketamine</keyword>
	<keyword>JNJ-54135419</keyword>
</DOC>