<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02345694</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this randomised controlled study is to determine the impact of continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP) versus sub-therapeutic CPAP (placebo) on the control of gait upon severe sleep apnea patients, based on stride time variability.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Non-automatic Control of Gait and Posture in Obstructive Sleep Apnea Syndrome (CIH-Gait)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>As severe sleep apnea patients exhibit gait abnormalities, this is the first randomised controlled trial to our knowledge to assess the impact of CPAP upon gait and postural control in severe sleep apnea patients. Based on a dual-task paradigm, posture and gait analysis will be perform before and after 8 week of intervention. Beside gait parameters, the cerebral metabolism will be assessed using a Near Infrared Spectroscopy (fNIRS) device during normal walking and during walking while dual-tasking, using a visual and a verbal task.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Normally weighted or overweighted patients (BMI &lt; 30 kilograms/m²) Newly diagnosed Obstructive Sleep Apnea Syndrome (OSAS) (i.e. no previous treatment) Severe OSAS as defined by the American Academy of Sleep Medicine (AHI ≥ 30) Epworth sleepiness scale &gt;10 To speak and understand french To be affiliated to social welfare Age criteria : &lt;18 year old and &gt;65 year old Obesity (BMI ≥ 30 kilograms/m²) Pathological conditions thought to be responsible of gait unsteadiness and postural sway or requiring an walking device : nervous system disease (Parkinson disease, chronic stroke), cerebellum syndrome, vestibular syndrome, orthopaedic and rheumatic diseases, Lower limb sensitivity impairment, Cognitive disorder (Folstein test score &lt; 24), Ophthalmology disorder : uncorrected refractive disorder, disturbance of color vision, Psychotropic treatment intake, Alcoholism, Member of an atrisk occupation (car, bus, truck drivers...) mandating effective continuous positive airway pressure introduction.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obstructive Sleep Apnea Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Gait</keyword>
	<keyword>Posture</keyword>
	<keyword>Continuous Positive Airway Pressure</keyword>
</DOC>