<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01888718</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the bioequivalence of Fexofenadine Hydrochloride Orally Disintegrating Tablets 30 mg of Dr. Reddy's Laboratories Limited, India comparing with that of Allegra® (containing fexofenadine hydrochloride) Orally Disintegrating Tablets 30 mg of Sanofi - aventis U.S. LLC, Bridgewater, NJ 08807 in healthy, adult, human subjects under fasting conditions. To monitor adverse events and ensure the safety of subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bioequivalence Study of Fexofenadine Hydrochloride Orally Disintegrated Tablets 30 mg Under Fasting Condition</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>An open Label, Balanced, Randomized, Two-treatment, Two-period, Two-sequence, Single Dose, Crossover, Oral Bioequivalence Study of Fexofenadine Hydrochloride Orally Disintegrating Tablets 30 mg of Dr. Reddy's Laboratories Limited, India Comparing With That of Allegra ® (Containing Fexofenadine Hydrochloride) Orally Disintegrating Tablets 30 mg of Sanofi - Aventis U.S. LLC, Bridgewater, NJ 08807 in Healthy, Adult, Human Subjects Under Fasting Conditions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fexofenadine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Terfenadine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>i. Provide written informed consent. ii. Must be healthy, adult, human beings within 18 and 45 years of age (both inclusive) weighing at least 50 kg. iii. Having a body mass index between 18.5 and 24.9 (both inclusive), calculated as weight in Kg/height in m2. iv. Must be of normal health as determined by medical history, physical examination and laboratory investigation performed within 28 days prior to the commencement of the study. (Laboratory values must be within normal limits or considered by the physician / investigator to be of no clinical significance). v. Female Subjects of child bearing potential practicing an acceptable method of birth control for the duration of the study as judged by the investigator(s), such as condoms, foams, jellies, diaphragm, intrauterine device (IUD), or abstinence. surgically sterile (bilateral tubal ligation, bilateral oophorectomy, or hysterectomy has been performed on the subject) Exclusion Criteria i.Incapable of understanding the informed consent. ii. Systolic blood pressure less than 90 mm of Hg or more than 140 mm of Hg. iii. Diastolic blood pressure less than 60 mm of Hg or more than 90 mm of Hg. iv. Oral temperature is below 95.0°F or above 98.6°F. v. Pulse rate below 50/min or above 100/min. vi. History of hypersensitivity or idiosyncratic reaction to investigational drug product or any other related drugs. vii. Any evidence of impairment of renal, hepatic, cardiac, lung or gastrointestinal function. viii. Consumption of grapefruit for the past ten days prior to the checkin, in each period. ix. Regular smoker who has a habit of smoking more than nine cigarettes per day and has difficulty in abstaining from smoking during sample collection period. x. Habit of tobacco chewing. xi. Habit of alcoholism and difficulty in abstaining from alcohol during the sample collection period. xii. Difficulty in abstaining from xanthine containing food or beverages (like tea, coffee, chocolates and cola drinks) during the sample collection period. xiii. Intake of over the counter (OTC) or prescribed medications and enzyme modifying medication or systemic medication for the last 30 days before dosing. xiv. Clinically significant abnormalities and / or with significant diseases. xv. Confirmed positive in alcohol screening. xvi. Confirmed positive in selected drug of abuse. xvii. Participated in any other clinical investigation using experimental drug/donated blood in past 90 days before the date of start of study. xviii. Confirmed positive in urine pregnancy test. xix. Female detected to be pregnant, breast feeding or who is likely to become pregnant during the study.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>