<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01888315</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study is aiming to document the long-term safety and effectiveness of renal denervation in patients with hypertension and other diseases characterized by elevated sympathetic drive. Catheter-based renal denervation will be performed using CE marked, percutaneous, systems.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Influence of Catheter-based Renal Denervation in Diseases With Increased Sympathetic Activity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Inclusion Criteria 1. Individual is 18 years of age. 2. Individual agrees to have all procedures performed, and is competent and willing to provide written, informed consent to participate in the registry. 3. Patient scheduled for renal sympathetic denervation using market-released device. Exclusion Criteria 1. In the eyes of the treating physician, the renal artery anatomy would interfere with safe cannulation of the renal artery or meets local standards for surgical repair. 2. Individual has any serious medical condition, which in the opinion of the treating physician may adversely affect the safety and/or effectiveness of the participant (i.e., patients with clinically significant peripheral vascular disease, abdominal aortic aneurysm, bleeding disorders such as thrombocytopenia, hemophilia, significant anemia, etc.).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arrhythmias, Cardiac</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 1. Individual is 18 years of age. 2. Individual agrees to have all procedures performed, and is competent and willing to provide written, informed consent to participate in the registry. 3. Patient scheduled for renal sympathetic denervation using marketreleased device. Exclusion Criteria 1. In the eyes of the treating physician, the renal artery anatomy would interfere with safe cannulation of the renal artery or meets local standards for surgical repair. 2. Individual has any serious medical condition, which in the opinion of the treating physician may adversely affect the safety and/or effectiveness of the participant (i.e., patients with clinically significant peripheral vascular disease, abdominal aortic aneurysm, bleeding disorders such as thrombocytopenia, hemophilia, significant anemia, etc.).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Heart Failure</keyword>
	<keyword>Sympathetic activity</keyword>
</DOC>