<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00812955</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose of this study is to test the effect and safety of three different doses of ABT-143 compared to simvastatin in subjects with elevated levels of low density lipoprotein cholesterol ("bad cholesterol") and triglycerides.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study Comparing ABT-143 to Simvastatin in Subjects With Elevated Levels of Low Density Lipoprotein Cholesterol ("Bad Cholesterol") and Triglycerides</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There are 4 treatment groups in the study: ABT-143 capsules 20/135 mg, ABT-143 capsules 10/135 mg, ABT-143 5/135 mg, and simvastatin capsules 40 mg. The primary outcome measure only compares 2 of these groups: ABT-143 capsules 20/135 mg and the simvastatin capsules 40 mg groups, therefore there are only results for these 2 groups and not all 4 groups for this outcome measure . Secondary outcome measure (mean percent change in LDL-C comparing ABT-143 capsules 10/135 mg to simvastatin capsules 40 mg) only compares these 2 groups: ABT-143 capsules 10/135 mg and simvastatin capsules 40 mg, therefore there are only results for these 2 groups and not all 4 groups for this outcome measure. Secondary outcome measure (mean percent change in LDL-C comparing ABT-143 capsules 5/135 mg to simvastatin capsules 40 mg) only compares these 2 groups: ABT-143 capsules 5/135 mg and simvastatin capsules 40 mg, therefore there are only results for these 2 groups and not all 4 groups for this outcome measure. For the other pre-specified outcome measures, median percent change in triglycerides from baseline to the final visit and mean percent change in HDL-C from baseline to the final visit for the full analysis sets, all 3 ABT-143 capsules 20/135 mg, 10/135 mg, and 5/135 mg groups were compared to the simvastatin capsules 40 mg group, therefore there are results for all 4 treatment groups for these outcome measures.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypercholesterolemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyslipidemias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertriglyceridemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Simvastatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria Participants with hypercholesterolemia and hypertriglyceridemia. Participants had the following fasting lipid results following a greater than or equal to 12 hour fasting period (measured at the Screening Visit(s)): Triglycerides level greater than or equal to 150 milligrams/deciliter (mg/dL) and less than 400 milligrams/deciliter, and Lowdensity lipoprotein cholesterol greater than or equal to 160 milligrams/deciliter and less than or equal to 240 milligrams/deciliter. Exclusion Criteria Participants with certain chronic or unstable medical conditions. Participants receiving coumarin anticoagulants, systemic cyclosporins, or certain other medications. Pregnant or lactating women, or women intending to become pregnant. Participants with diabetes mellitus that is poorly controlled. Participant was of Asian ancestry (having Filipino, Chinese, Japanese, Korean, Vietnamese, or AsianIndian origin).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dyslipidemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypercholesterolemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypertriglyceridemia</keyword>
</DOC>