<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01626586</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this research study the investigators want more about how being in a group about diabetes helps your family versus individual treatment. The investigators are asking youth with diabetes and their parents to be in the research, because the investigators want to see if this diabetes group and/or individual therapy is helpful to your coping, adjustment, and family communication about diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Diabetes Adolescent and Family Group Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this research study is to find out what effects the Group Therapy Project has on parents and child's management of Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus (T1DM) from both a group versus an individual therapy modality. We want to start a group and individual therapy program that looks at youth and family adjustment and coping at the Cincinnati Children's Hospital with patients who have T1DM. There has been research before on this group therapy and we want to look at it in a "typical" clinical setting at Cincinnati Children's Hospital for both group and individual therapy. This research is being done to understand how a peer and family-based group versus individual therapy can be helpful by looking at survey data as well as medical data before and after participating in the diabetes therapy program. This information will help us further develop prevention and intervention programs for other youth with T1DM and their families.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of Type 1 Diabetes, Aged 10.0 17.9 years of age, At least one parent/caregiver to participate with them, Diagnosed for at least 6 months. Potential participants will be excluded if: They have a coexisting diagnosis of mental retardation, pervasive developmental disorder, substance abuse, eating disorders, psychosis, or other acute psychiatric or medical needs, such as suicidality They are not fluent in the English language.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Youth</keyword>
	<keyword>Family</keyword>
	<keyword>Group Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-Management</keyword>
</DOC>