<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01626170</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This laboratory study is looking into mechanisms of radiation therapy resistance in samples from younger patients with rhabdomyosarcoma. Studying samples of tissue from patients with cancer in the laboratory may help doctors learn more about changes that occur in DNA and identify biomarkers related to cancer. It may also help doctors find better ways to treat cancer</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Studying Mechanisms of Radiation Therapy Resistance in Samples From Younger Patients With Rhabdomyosarcoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Observational Study Model: Cohort Time Perspective: Retrospective Biospecimen Retention: Samples with DNA Biospecimen Description: Tissue Study Population Description: Primary care clinic Sampling Method: Non-probability sample OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the molecular response/resistance signatures with radiotherapy and standard chemoradiation treatments using the xenograft model of the Pediatric Preclinical Testing Program (PPTP). II. Validate these novel pathways/biomarkers by their detection within clinically annotated patient tumor tissue samples and testing their associations with clinical response, local control rates, and overall survival rates. OUTLINE: Archived tissue samples of matched primary-relapsed and non-matched primary are analyzed for genomic DNA, DNA methylation profiles, RNA sequencing, differences between alveolar rhabdomyosarcoma (ARMS) and embryonal rhabdomyosarcoma (ERMS), gene expression profiles, target-of-rapamycin complex 1 (TORC1) and TORC2 pathway intermediates, and paired box 3 (PAX3)/forkhead box O1 (FOXO1) translocation by microarray, immunohistochemical staining, and fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rhabdomyosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhabdomyosarcoma, Embryonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Tissues requested from the Children Oncology Group (COG) sarcoma banking protocol COGD9902 All subtypes of rhabdomyosarcoma specimens Matched primaryrelapsed specimens (from same patient, separated by time): Frozen tissue if available Scrolls of formalinfixed paraffinembedded tissue (if frozen not available) 10 unstained formalinfixed paraffinembedded thin sections All other general (primary or relapsed) cases 10 unstained formalinfixed paraffinembedded thin sections</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>