<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02841280</DOC>
	<brief_summary>It is estimated that in the United States there are approximately 8 million individuals who have moderate to severe chronic kidney disease (CKD). Among them hypertension is common and is often poorly controlled due to an expanded volume state; diuretics are frequently prescribed. Loop diuretics are potent and effective in lowering blood pressure (BP) but their use is associated with acute kidney injury. Thiazide diuretics, on the other hand, are less potent, their use may be associated with less acute kidney injury, but as yet there are no firm data to support that thiazide diuretic therapy can improve BP among subjects with advanced CKD. The investigators found 13 studies on the use of thiazide diuretics in advanced CKD either alone or in combination with loop diuretics and concluded that thiazides may be useful. Thiazides cause a negative Na balance, increase Na excretion by 10-15% and weight loss by 1-2 kg in observational studies. Observational data show that thiazides lead to an improvement in seated clinic BP of about 10-15 mmHg systolic and 5-10 mmHg diastolic whereas randomized trials show about a 15 mmHg reduction in mean BP. Randomized trials had only between 7 and 23 subjects each; accordingly, larger studies are needed to evaluate their safety and efficacy in moderate to advanced CKD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Chlorthalidone in Chronic Kidney Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a two-center, placebo-controlled, double-blind, randomized controlled trial of chlorthalidone (CTD) in patients with CKD and poorly controlled hypertension</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorthalidone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age greater than 18 years. 2. Calculated glomerular filtration rate (GFR) by 4component Modification of Diet in Renal Disease (MDRD) formula &lt; 30 ml/min/1.73m2 but ≥15 mL/min/1.73m2. The hospital laboratory uses isotope dilution mass spectrometry (IDMS) calibrated creatinine and the appropriate formula is used to estimate GFR. 3. Hypertension. This is defined as BP of either ≥130 systolic or ≥80 mmHg by 24hour ambulatory BP monitoring. 4. Treatment with antihypertensive drugs: This would require the use of at least one antihypertensive drug. One of the drugs should be either an angiotensin converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitor or angiotensin receptor blocker (ARB). If these are contraindicated then use of a betablocker is required prior to randomization. 1. Use of thiazide or thiazidelike drugs in the previous 12 weeks. 2. Use of furosemide in a dose &gt;200 mg/d. 3. BP of either ≥160 systolic or ≥100 mmHg by 24hour ambulatory BP monitoring. 4. Expected to receive renal replacement therapy within the next 3 months. 5. Myocardial infarction, heart failure hospitalization, or stroke ≤3 months prior to randomization. 6. Pregnant or breastfeeding women or women who are planning to become pregnant or those not using a reliable form of contraception (oral contraceptives. condoms and diaphragms will be considered reliable). 7. Known hypersensitivity to thiazide or sulfa drugs. 8. Organ transplant recipient or therapy with immunosuppressive agents.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>