<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01344941</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objectives of this study is to - Define the envelope-specific B-cell and T-cell responses in humans who have received a St. Jude HIV-1 vaccine. - Describe mechanisms of HIV-1 envelope processing and consequent B-cell and T-cell activities.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Human Immune Responses Toward HIV-1 Envelope Antigens</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The goal of this protocol is to understand how human lymphocytes respond to HIV-1 antigens in the context of vaccination or infection. This protocol will support understanding of the immune response by providing a source of lymphocytes and serum from selected individuals to study in laboratory based investigations. Blood samples from individuals who have received an HIV-1 vaccine, individuals who are HIV-1-infected, and individuals who are HIV-1-uninfected are requested to: (1) test previously vaccinated volunteers for HIV-1 envelope-specific B-cell and T-cell immune activities, and (2) increase understanding of how the human immune system processes and responds to HIV-1 envelope proteins.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participant is greater than or equal to 18 years of age. Participant is in good general health. Participant weighs ≥ 110 pounds. Participant has hemoglobin &gt; 12 gm/dL within last 12 weeks. Group 1 (Vaccinees) only Participant has previously received one of the St. Jude HIV1 vaccines via enrollment in prior St. Jude HIV vaccine studies. Group 2 (HIV positive) only Participant is HIV1 positive by medical record review. Group 3 (HIV negative) only Participant is HIV1 negative as determined by HIV ELISA. Participant is unable or unwilling to give written informed consent. Participant is pregnant female. Group 2 (HIV positive) only Participant is enrolled in other clinical trials that include any blood sampling such that the cumulative blood draws would exceed that established as constituting minimal risk (e.g., more than 550 ml in an 8 week period with collection more frequently than 2 times per week)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vaccine response</keyword>
	<keyword>Human Lymphocytes</keyword>
</DOC>