<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02917421</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This protocol is for patients with newly diagnosed breast cancer with an indication for post-operative radiotherapy after neo-adjuvant chemotherapy and surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Accelerated Radiation Therapy (ART) to the Breast and Nodal Stations</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Protocol has two cohorts. Cohort 1 will receive radiation to breast and chest wall. Prone whole breast or chest wall 3D-CRT or IMRT at 2.7 Gy x 15 fractions (40.50 Gy) with a concomitant boost of 0.50 (7.5 Gy) to the original tumor bed in post-segmental mastectomy patients or mastectomy scar in post-mastectomy patients. Patients who have undergone reconstruction will not receive concomitant boost. Cohort 2 patients will receive radiation to breast, chest wall and LevelII/SCV nodes. In addition to receiving radiation to the original tumor bed, patients will also receive radiation to Level III axillary nodes and Supraclavicular nodes: 3D-CRT or IMRT at 2.7 Gy X 15 fraction (40.50 Gy). Patients will complete treatment in three weeks (15 fractions). All patients will be followed at 3 months after the completion of treatment then yearly for the next 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Pre or postmenopausal women with Stage IIII breast cancer Status post neoadjuvant systemic therapy Status postchemotherapy breast surgery Original biopsyproven invasive breast cancer, excised with negative margins of at least 1 mm Status post segmental mastectomy or mastectomy, with either negative sentinel node biopsy and/or axillary node dissection (at least 6 nodes removed). Patient needs to be able to understand and demonstrate willingness to sign a written informed consent document Previous radiation therapy to the ipsilateral breast and/or nodal area Active connective tissue disorders, such as lupus or scleroderma requiring flare therapy Pregnant or lactating women Concurrent chemotherapy, with the exception of anti HER2neu therapies Inadequate axillary dissection in a setting of positive sentinel node</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>