<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00569868</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate changes in coagulation (blood clotting) factors and platelet function in multiple myeloma participants undergoing VELCADE treatment for the first time.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>UARK 2005-05, Coagulation-Related Effects of Velcade Treatment in Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Multiple Myeloma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cardiovascular complications during the treatment of patients with multiple myeloma are not uncommon, (10%) and the frequency clearly increases with the use of regimens containing thalidomide in combination with glucocorticosteroids or chemotherapy especially adriamycin. Even with prophylactic anticoagulation, DVT still occurs in 10% of such patients. The use of full anticoagulation raises considerable concern of bleeding especially during the post chemotherapy thrombocytopenic period. We observed no thromboembolic episodes when Velcade was added to thalidomide and adriamycin containing chemotherapy. Therefore, we would like to investigate this protective antithrombotic effect of VELCADE in a malignancy associated with a hypercoagulable state in a group of 10 patients with Relapsed/Refractory Multiple Myeloma.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with myeloma who had relapsed after one prior treatment and who have demonstrated resistance to their last treatment, who are candidate to receive Velcade and had normal PT and PTT, will be evaluated for inclusion in the present study. Previous history of venous thromboembolism, myocardial infarction, stroke, TIA Hypercoagulable state (deficit ATIII, Factor V Leiden, deficit protein S, deficit protein C, prothrombin gene mutation), antiphospholipid syndrome. Von Willebrand disease, inherited platelet abnormalities. Familiar history of hypercoagulable state. Anticoagulant therapy, aspirin, nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs, beta blockers, tricyclic antidepressant, hormone replacement therapy, BCPs, and all other agents able to interfere with platelet function in the previous two weeks. Nonsecretory MM, unless the patient has measurable lesions on CT, MRI and/or PET.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>PLASMACYTOMA</keyword>
</DOC>