<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00906503</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Imaging procedures, such as fludeoxyglucose F 18 (FDG)-PET/CT scan, done before and after steroid therapy may help doctors assess a patient's response to treatment and help plan the best treatment. PURPOSE: This phase I trial is studying fludeoxyglucose F 18 PET scan performed before and after ultra short-term dexamethasone therapy to see how well it measures changes in nodules in patients with lung nodules.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fludeoxyglucose F 18-PET/CT Scans in Patients Receiving Ultra Short-Term Dexamethasone For Lung Nodules</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - To determine whether ultra short-term steroid therapy (24-48 hours) can be used to increase the accuracy of fludeoxyglucose F 18 positron emission tomography/computed tomography (FDG-PET/CT) imaging in categorizing nodules in patients with pulmonary nodules. - To calculate the overall sensitivity and specificity of the nodules group, based on FDG uptake, for predicting malignancy. - To gather effect-size estimates that will be used to improve the quality of a larger follow-up study. OUTLINE: Patients receive oral dexamethasone at 40, 28, 16, and 4 hours before imaging. Patients undergo fludeoxyglucose F 18 (FDG)-positron emission tomography/computed tomography (PET/CT) imaging at baseline and upon completion of steroid therapy. After completion of study therapy, patients are followed for 6 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Pulmonary Nodules</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorodeoxyglucose F18</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Presence of ≥ 1 measurable pulmonary nodule (1.03.0 cm) suggestive of malignancy or chronic inflammatory process on positron emission tomography (PET) scan No lesions consistent with malignancy or inflammation according to history, PET findings, or biopsy Baseline scan average time between injection and start of scan within 5070 min Mean liver standardized uptake value (SUV) of baseline scan normal No sign of significant partial paravenous tracer administration in the images of baseline scan No lung nodule(s) suggestive of lymphoma No lung lesions suggestive of tuberculosis PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: ECOG performance status 02 Blood glucose levels ≤ 150 mg/100 mL Not pregnant or nursing Fertile patients must use effective contraception Able to tolerate PET/CT imaging No history of diabetes No poorly controlled hypertension No prior malignancy other than basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, carcinoma in situ, or other cancer from which the participant has been disease free for &lt; 3 years No active malignancy within the past 5 years PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: More than 5 years since prior chemotherapy or radiotherapy No concurrent steroids</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>pulmonary nodule</keyword>
</DOC>