<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02606305</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase 1b study to assess the safety, tolerability, and preliminary anti-tumor activity of IMGN853 when administered with chemotherapy. Patients will be assigned to one of four regimens: IMGN853 administered with bevacizumab, IMGN853 administered with carboplatin, IMGN853 administered with pegylated liposomal doxorubicin or IMGN853 administered with pembrolizumab.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Mirvetuximab Soravtansine in Comb. With Bevacizumab, Carboplatin, PLD or Pembrolizumab in Adults With FRa + Adv. EOC, Primary Peritoneal, Fallopian Tube, or Endometrial Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The dose escalation part of the study will assess safety and tolerability and determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) for each regimen. The dose expansion of the MTD will assess safety, tolerability and preliminary anti-tumor activity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peritoneal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Glandular and Epithelial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liposomal doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosed with advanced epithelial ovarian cancer, primary peritoneal cancer, fallopian tube cancer, or endometrial cancer Folate receptor alpha positive tumor expression as defined in the protocol Willing to undergo tumor biopsy Primary platinum refractory Diagnosis of clear cell or low grade ovarian cancer Serious concurrent illness or clinically relevant active infection, including known diagnosis of HIV and hepatitis B or C, as defined in the protocol Active autoimmune disease requiring systemic therapy in past 2 years (IMGN853 and pembrolizumab only) Women who are pregnant or breast feeding</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Epithelial ovarian cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Fallopian tube cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary peritoneal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Endometrial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>IMGN853</keyword>
	<keyword>ADC</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibody drug conjugate</keyword>
	<keyword>ImmunoGen</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibody</keyword>
	<keyword>Phase 1</keyword>
	<keyword>Folate receptor alpha</keyword>
</DOC>