<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02132936</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose is to compare the efficacy of treatment with LEO 90100 at Week 4 to that of calcipotriol plus betamethasone dipropionate (BDP) gel at Week 8 in subjects with psoriasis vulgaris</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>LEO 90100 Aerosol Foam Compared to Calcipotriol Plus Betamethasone Dipropionate Gel in Subjects With Psoriasis Vulgaris</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Betamethasone benzoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Betamethasone-17,21-dipropionate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Betamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Betamethasone Valerate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Betamethasone sodium phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcipotriene</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcitriol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 years or above Psoriasis vulgaris on the trunk and/or limbs (excluding psoriasis on the genitals and skin folds) involving 230% of the Body Surface Area (BSA) A Physician's Global Assessment of disease severity (PGA) of at least mild on trunk and limbs A modified Psoriasis Area Severity Index (PASI) score of at least 2 on the trunk and limbs. Current diagnosis of guttate, erythrodermic, exfoliative or pustular psoriasis Systemic treatment with biological therapies, whether marketed or not, with a possible effect on psoriasis vulgaris within the following time periods prior to randomisation: etanercept within 4 weeks prior to randomisation adalimumab, infliximab within 8 weeks prior to randomisation ustekinumab within 16 weeks prior to randomisation other products within 4 weeks/5 halflives prior to randomisation (whichever is longer) Systemic treatment with all other therapies with a possible effect on psoriasis vulgaris (e.g. corticosteroids, retinoids, methotrexate, ciclosporin and other immunosuppressants within 4 weeks prior to randomisation) Subjects who have received treatment with any nonmarketed drug substance (i.e. a drug which has not yet been made available for clinical use following registration) within 4 weeks/5 halflives (whichever is longer) prior to randomisation. Psoralen combined with Ultraviolet A (PUVA) therapy within 4 weeks prior to randomisation Ultraviolet B (UVB) therapy within 2 weeks prior to randomisation Topical antipsoriatic treatment on the trunk and limbs (except for emollients) within 2 weeks prior to randomisation Topical treatment on the face, scalp and skin folds with corticosteroids, vitamin D analogues or prescription shampoos within 2 weeks prior to randomisation Females who are pregnant, wishing to become pregnant during the trial or are breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>