<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02132390</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Compare the potential benefits of adjuvant toremifene with or without goserelin in premenopausal women with stage I-IIIA, hormonal receptor positive breast cancer accompanied with or without chemotherapy induced amenorrhoea.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adjuvant Toremifene With or Without Goserrelin in Premenopausal Women With Stage I-IIIA, Hormonal Receptor Positive Breast Cancer Accompanied With or Without Chemotherapy Induced Amenorrhoea</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a single center, randomized, controlled study. Patients undergo surgical resection with standard Doxorubicin/Cyclophosphamide Followed by Docetaxel (AC-T). Chemotherapy begins within 4 weeks after surgery for patients randomized to arm I-IV. Arm I: patients who didn't have CIA receive oral toremifene daily. Treatment continues for 5 years in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Arm II: patients who had CIA receive toremifene as in arm I. Arm III: patients without CIA receive oral toremifene and goserelin for ovarian function suppression. Arm IV: patients with CIA receive oral toremifene and goserelin for ovarian function suppression. Patients are followed every 6 months for 5 years and annually thereafter.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amenorrhea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Goserelin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Toremifene</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Written informed consent must be obtained and documented according to the local regulatory requirements prior to beginning specific protocol procedures Age of at least 18 and at most 45 years Spontaneous and regular menstrual periods before study entry with FSH below 15 mlU/ml in follicular phase Histologically confirmed primary breast cancer with the need for anthracyclinebased chemotherapy Steroid receptor (estrogen and progesterone) positive tumor (diagnosis according to hospital standardprocedures) No clinical evidence of local recurrence or distant metastases. Complete staging workup within 3 months prior to registration. All patients must have (bilateral) mammography or breast MRI, chest Xray; other tests may be performed as clinically indicated KarnofskyIndex &gt;80% Life expectancy of at least 10 years, disregarding the diagnosis of cancer Adequate organ function including normal red and white blood count, platelets, serum creatinine, bilirubin, and transaminases within normal range of the institution Patients underwent standard Doxorubicin/Cyclophosphamide Followed by Docetaxel (ACT) Patients must be available for and compliant to treatment and followup. Patients registered on this trial must be treated and followed up at the participating center. Known hypersensitivity reaction to the investigational compounds or incorporated substances Prior cytotoxic treatment for any reason Suspected (primary or secondary) ovarian insufficiency Pregnant or lactating patients. Patients of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test (urine or serum) within 14 days prior to registration and must implement adequate nonhormonal contraceptive measures during study treatment; prior use of hormonal contraceptives has to be discontinued before first Goserelin injection Other serious illness or medical condition that may interfere with the understanding and giving of informed consent and the conduct of the study Prior or concomitant secondary malignancy (except nonmelanomatous skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the uterine cervix) Concurrent treatment with other experimental drugs or any other anticancer therapy Concurrent treatment with sex hormones. Prior treatment must be stopped before study entry</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemotherapy induced amenorrhea</keyword>
	<keyword>Goserelin</keyword>
</DOC>