<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00416091</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Tourette's disorder (TD) is a childhood-onset neuropsychiatric disorder, manifesting motor and vocal tics with increased likelihood of comorbid with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) and other psychiatric disorders. Literature documents the comorbid condition with ADHD predicts an increased functional deficit among individuals with ADHD. The information about neuropsychological functioning among individuals with TD adn/or ADHD is little in Asian population. This study aims to validate the diagnoses of TD, ADHD, and TD comorbid ADHD by symptomatology, neuropsychological measures, and social adjustment. This is a case-control study with a sample of 30 subjects with TD, 60 with ADHD, 30 with TD+ADHD, and 60 controls aged from 6 to 18. All subjects will receive comprehensive assessment including standard psychiatric diagnostic interviews using (K-SADS-E), behavioral assessments (SNAP-IV, CPRS:R-S, CTRS:R-S, CBCL, YBOCS, YGTSS), social adjustment (SAICA, GCAS), parenting (PBI, APGAR) and neuropsychological assessment (CPT, CANTAB, WISC-III). We anticipate that this study will provide the primitive data to validate the TD and ADHD using neuropsychological and clinical measures.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neuropsychological Functioning Among Children With Tourret's Disorder and ADHD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tourette Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients aged 816 without the diagnosis of ADHD, and/or Tourette's disorder IQ &gt; 80 both children/adolescents and their parents consent to participate and have the ability to complete selfadministered measures in this study diagnosis of psychotic disorders, bipolar affective disorders, pervasive developmental disorder, seizure, or major physical disorders. in addition, control subjects will be excluded from the control group if have a history of the following condition as defined by DSMIV: ADHD, ODD, or CD in addition to the above exclusion criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tourette disorder, ADHD, comorbidity, neuropsychological</keyword>
</DOC>