<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00967317</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of Auris-Sedina in the symptomatic control of otalgy in patients with and without acute external otitis compared with use of Otosynalar®.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase III Open Study, Prospective, Multicenter, Randomized, Comparative to the Positive Control for Evaluating the Efficacy and Safety of Auris-Sedina in the Symptomatic Control of Otalgy in Patients With or Without Acute External Otitis.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Phase III open Study, multicenter, prospective, randomized entrance of a total of 188 patients, 94 patients will receive medication test and 94 patients will receive Otosynalar®. Patients will be assessed until the clinical condition has been resolved or a maximum of 3 days. 188 patients of either gender or race, who have at least two of the following symptoms: pain, discharge, tinnitus, ear fullness, subjective hearing loss temporary dizziness or vertigo. And with a clinical or non-acute external otitis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Otitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Otitis Externa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with otalgy or not, with acute external otitis ; Patients with at least two symptoms of otalgy (pain, discharge, tinnitus, ear fullness, subjective hearing loss temporary dizziness or vertigo) with the Visual Analogic Scale score between 4 and 8 (mild to moderate); The patient must present otalgia in one ear; Children above 6 years of age; Adults over 18 years of age; Patients who consent to participate in the study; Patients who are female and are of childbearing age should use reliable method of contraception and have negative pregnancy test. Patients with sensitivity to any component of the formula; Patients pregnant or lactating; Non visualization of the tympanic membrane of obstruction by cerumen; Patients with evidence of any wound or scratch on the ear (ulcerative lesion); Patients who are making use of any other medication that might interfere with the evaluation of effectiveness of study (such as antibiotics, antiinflammatory, solutions ear); Patients who have severe classification in the Visual Analogic Scale score 9 or 10 in any of the symptoms listed in the questionnaire; Patients with otalgy not otological origin; Patients with otitis, except acute external otitis ; Patients who have epiglottitis; The patient with infection; Patients who can not follow the procedures clarified in this protocol.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Auris-Sedina</keyword>
	<keyword>Otitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Tolerability</keyword>
</DOC>