<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01979445</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There are two separate objectives in this study: 1. to demonstrate the pharmacodynamic profile when patients treated with cangrelor are switched to oral prasugrel administered 30 min after cangrelor infusion is discontinued and 2. to demonstrate the pharmacodynamic profile when patients treated with cangrelor are switched to clopidogrel 600mg administered during or immediately after the infusion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cangrelor to Clopidogrel or Prasugrel Transition Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clopidogrel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cangrelor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ticlopidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prasugrel Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Greater than / equal to 18 and less than 75 years of age, of either sex, and of any race. 2. Stable coronary artery disease defined by the following criteria: 1. Previous myocardial infarction defined by admission to the hospital with elevation of markers of injury or the presence of pathologic Qwaves on at least 2 contiguous electrocardiogram (ECG) leads. OR 2. Previous revascularization by PCI or CABG, and 3. Treatment with ASA 81 mg daily. 1. Known intolerance or contraindication to cangrelor or prasugrel, or any ingredients of the respective formulation. 2. Any antiplatelet (other than aspirin) or anticoagulant medication with the previous 30 days. 3. Acute coronary syndrome within the previous 12 months. 4. History of bleeding diathesis or known coagulopathy such as; impaired hemostasis: known international normalized ratio (INR) &gt;1.5; past or present bleeding disorder (including congenital bleeding disorders such as von Willebrand's disease or hemophilia), acquired bleeding disorders, and unexplained clinically significant bleeding disorders; thrombocytopenia (platelet count less than 100,000/µL), or history of thrombocytopenia or neutropenia associated with clopidogrel. 5. Anemia (ie, hematocrit less than 35%). 6. Prior stroke (any type), prior cerebral anteriovenous malformation or intracranial aneurysm; recent (&lt;1 month) trauma or major surgery (including bypass surgery). 7. Known or suspected pregnancy, or lactating females. 8. Known severe renal insufficiency (glomerular filtration rate [GFR] less than 30 mL/min). 9. Inability to provide informed consent. 10. Moderate or severe hepatic impairment as per investigator discretion (elevation of liver function tests [LFTs]). 11. Inability to swallow oral medication at time of randomization. 12. Any clinically significant disease or condition affecting a major organ system, including but not limited to gastrointestinal, renal, hepatic, endocrinologic, bronchopulmonary, neurological, or metabolic disease. 13. Any surgical or medical condition which, in the judgment of the Investigator, might interfere with the pharmacokinetics, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of the study drug (if applicable). 14. Treatment with other investigational medicinal products or devices within 30 days or 5 halflives, whichever is longer, prior to the administration of the drug, or planned use of investigational medicinal products or devices. 15. Subjects who, for any reason, are deemed by the Investigator to be inappropriate for this study, including subjects who are unable to communicate or to cooperate with the Investigator. 16. Subject is the Investigator or his/her deputy, research assistant, pharmacist, study coordinator, other staff or relative thereof directly involved in the conduct of the study. 17. Active pathological bleeding, or a history of transient ischemic attack.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>CAD</keyword>
</DOC>