<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01979081</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Physical Functioning Inventory (PFI) is a standardized patient reported outcome measure that assesses preclinical disability. Preclinical disability is a functional state in which people are still able to complete daily living tasks (e.g., walking, bathing) but are changing the frequency or modifying the way that they complete the tasks. The investigators have done some preliminary research using the PFI as an online monitoring tool (Richardson 2012), but further study is required to examine its psychometric properties and its suitability for use as a primary outcome measure. This measurement study has been designed to identify the optimal number of items on the PFI and to determine the reliability, validity, and responsiveness of the PFI when administered to a sample of adults and older adults both with and without chronic conditions. This project will also allow us to evaluate the use of self-monitoring of physical function and the added value of rehabilitation professionals to support self-monitoring. Using the results of the PFI, the investigators aim to develop a "tailored" population-based rehabilitation self-management intervention delivered through a secure messaging system in the patient's electronic personal health record (myOSCAR) that focuses on the early detection and prevention of preclinical disability.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Detecting and Addressing Preclinical Disability</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Greater than or equal to 44 years of age Able to communicate in English Have had at least 3 physician visits in the last year Are able to access an email address independently Have a chronic disease Any evidence of cognitive impairment Unable to travel to the clinic Awaiting longterm care Planning to relocate Experiencing an acute illness Are receiving palliative care</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>44 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>