<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02598388</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety, tolerability and immunogenicity of different vaccination schedules of Ad26.ZEBOV and MVA-BN-Filo administered intramuscularly (IM) as heterologous prime-boost regimens in healthy and in HIV-infected adults.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety, Tolerability and Immunogenicity Study of 2 Prime-boost Regimens for Ebola Vaccines Ad26.ZEBOV/MVA-BN-Filo</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, observer-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group, multicenter, 2-part, Phase 2 study Ad26.ZEBOV and MVA-BN-Filo in healthy and HIV infected adults. In part 1, prime vaccination with MVA-Bn-Filo will be followed by boost vaccination with Ad26 14 days later in the US. In part 2, two regimens will be investigated. The first regimen will be Ad26 prime vaccination followed by MVA-BN-Filo boost 28 days later and the second regimen will be MVA-BN-Filo prime vaccination followed by MVA-BN-Filo boost 14 days later in Africa. The study consists of a Screening phase of up to 8 weeks (starting from the moment the participants signs the ICF), a Vaccination Phase, in which participants will be vaccinated at baseline (Day 1) followed by a boost vaccination on Day 15 or 29, and a post-boost follow-up phase of maximum 1 year post-boost vaccination. Upon completion of 6-month post boost visit those participants who received active vaccine will enter long-term follow-up until the 1 year post boost vaccination visit to assess long-term safety and immunogenicity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhagic Fever, Ebola</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhagic Fevers, Viral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participant must be healthy in the Investigator's clinical judgment on the basis of medical history, physical examination and vital signs performed at Screening Participant must be healthy on the basis of clinical laboratory tests and electrocardiogram (ECG) (only in participants &gt;50 years) performed at Screening. If the results of the laboratory screening tests and ECG are outside the institutional normal reference ranges, the participant may be included only if the Investigator judges the abnormalities or deviations from normal to be not clinically significant or to be appropriate and reasonable for the population under study A woman of childbearing potential must have a negative urine βhuman chorionic gonadotropin [betahCG] pregnancy test at Screening and a negative urine [betahCG] pregnancy test immediately prior to each study vaccine administration A man who is sexually active with a woman of childbearing potential must be willing to use condoms for sexual intercourse beginning prior to prime vaccination until at least 3 months after the boost vaccination, unless a vasectomy was performed more than 1 year prior to Screening Participant must pass the test of understanding (TOU) Additional Inclusion Criteria for HIVinfected participants a) participants must have a positive HIV1 and/or 2 serology test within 6 months of screening, including the day of screening; b) participants must have a Screening CD4+ cell count &gt;200 cells/microliter (mcL); c) in part 1, all participants must be on a stable highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART) regimen for 4 weeks prior to Screening, in part 2 participants with screening CD4+ cell count &lt;350 cells/mcL must also be on a stable HAART regimen for 4 weeks prior to Screening Has received any candidate Ebola vaccine Diagnosed with Ebola virus disease, or prior exposure to EBOV, including travel to epidemic Ebola areas less than 1 month prior to Screening Has received any experimental candidate Ad26 or MVAbased vaccine in the past or received any other investigational drug or investigational vaccine or used an invasive investigational medical device within 3 months prior to Screening Known allergy or history of anaphylaxis or other serious adverse reactions to vaccines or vaccine products Presence of significant conditions (eg, history of seizure disorders, (auto)immune disease or deficiency, any spleen disease, active malignancy, ongoing tuberculosis treatment, other systemic infections) or clinically significant findings during screening of medical history, ECG (only in participants &gt;50 years), physical examination, vital signs or laboratory testing for which, in the opinion of the investigator, participation would not be in the best interest of the participants (eg, compromise the safety or wellbeing) or that could prevent, limit, or confound the protocolspecified assessments</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Healthy</keyword>
	<keyword>Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Ebola viruses</keyword>
	<keyword>Ebola virus disease (EVD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Filoviruses</keyword>
	<keyword>Hemorrhagic fever</keyword>
	<keyword>Monovalent vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Human adenovirus serotype 26 (Ad26) expressing the Ebola virus Mayinga variant glycoprotein (Ad26.ZEBOV)</keyword>
	<keyword>Modified Vaccinia Virus Ankara - Bavarian Nordic (MVA-BN) Filo-vector</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunogenicity</keyword>
</DOC>