<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02598141</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study was to compare the diagnostic capability (sensitivity and specificity) of standard bacteriological analysis made from one or other of the two sampling processing techniques and perioperative management of samples : the Ultra Turrax method that uses grinding versus the standard method.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Grinding Versus Standard Methods for the Treatment of Per-operative Bacteriological Samples Associated With Osteo-articular Sepsis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The secondary objectives of this study are to: A. Compare the two techniques in terms of bacterial species identified. B. Compare the diagnostic capabilities (sensitivity and specificity) of the two sample processing techniques depending on the type of analyzed samples (soft tissue, bone tissue) (subgroup analysis). C. Compare the diagnostic capabilities (sensitivity and specificity) of the two sample processing techniques depending on the type of joint (subgroup analysis). D. Compare the diagnostic capabilities (sensitivity and specificity) of the two sample processing techniques depending on the type of implanted materials (prosthesis versus other equipment) (subgroup analysis). E. Develop a culture collection of bacteria isolated from infection osteo-articular protheses.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Bacterial Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient must be insured or beneficiary of a health insurance plan The patient is cared for in the operating theater because of a suspicion of an osteoarticular infection involving any type of material (protheses, screws, plates) and requiring bacteriological sampling The patient has not taken any antibiotics within the past 15 days The patient is participating in another study The patient is in an exclusion period determined by a previous study The patient is under judicial protection It is impossible to correctly inform the patient The patient is pregnant, parturient, or breastfeeding The subject presents with an osteoarticulaire infection without material Systematic samplings from reversals of aseptic prostheses Second intervention for the same patient</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Protheses, nails, screws or plates</keyword>
</DOC>