<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01800838</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase I trial studies the side effects and best dose of silicon phthalocyanine 4 and photodynamic therapy in treating patients with stage IA-IIA cutaneous T-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Photodynamic therapy (PDT) uses a drug, silicon phthalocyanine 4, that becomes active when it is exposed to a certain kind of light. When the drug is active, cancer cells are killed. This may be effective against cutaneous T-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Funding Source - FDA OOPD</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Silicon Phthalocyanine 4 and Photodynamic Therapy in Stage IA-IIA Cutaneous T-Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Determine the safety and maximum tolerated dose (MTD) that can be utilized for a single treatment of Pc 4-PDT (silicon phthalocyanine 4 photo dynamic therapy) on subjects with mycosis fungoides (MF)/cutaneous T-cell lymphoma (CTCL) stage IA-IIA, by evaluating an accelerated dose escalation protocol consisting of a single exposure to PDT using topically-applied Pc 4 and visible light at a wavelength of 675 nm, followed by assessment of skin biopsies to analyze cellular and molecular changes induced by Pc 4-PDT. (Cohort I) II. Determine safety and tolerability of repeated light (PDT) exposures after a single application of Pc 4 to a MF/CTCL plaque, using topically-applied Pc 4 and visible light at a wavelength of 675nm, followed by assessment of skin biopsies to analyze cellular and molecular changes induced by Pc 4-PDT. (Cohort II) III. Identification of targets for assessment of efficacy to assist in planning for a Phase II study. OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study. Patients receive silicon phthalocyanine 4 topically and then undergo PDT. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 24 hours, 1 week, 2 weeks, and 30 days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycoses</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycosis Fungoides</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sezary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Cutaneous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Silicon phthalocyanine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Silicon</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosed with early stage MF (CTCL stage IAIIA) Has at least 2 evaluable plaques Has been off systemic therapies for at least 4 weeks Has been off topical therapies for at least 2 weeks Has been off phototherapies for at least 2 weeks All skin phototypes will be included Subjects must have the ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent form Women of childbearing potential must agree to utilize a birth control which results in a failure rate of less that 1% per year during the study; accepted forms of birth control for this study include: injections such as DepoProvera and Lunelle, implants such as Norplant, and intrauterine devices Sexually active males must agree to use a medically acceptable form of birth control for the duration of the study and for at least 3 months after the last dose of the study medication; appropriate birth control methods are using a condom with a spermicide or surgical sterilization Active history of photosensitivity (e.g. xeroderma pigmentosum, lupus erythematosus, porphyria, severe polymorphous light eruption, solar urticaria) Any medical condition that could be aggravated or may cause extreme discomfort during the study period Lesions only on the face, scalp or other sites that would make biopsies not cosmetically acceptable Women of childbearing potential who are pregnant or attempting to become pregnant are excluded from this study History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition to silicon phthalocyanine (Pc 4) or other agents used in this study Patients with uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>