<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01800279</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether kinesitherapy techniques and a myofascial therapy protocol are effective in the treatment of temporomandibular joint dysfunction in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physiotherapy and Deontology in the Temporomandibular Joint Dysfunction in Patients With Fibromyalgia Syndrome.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Design: randomized clinical trial. Objective: to compare the therapeutic effects of physiotherapy and deontology protocol to improve pain, quality of life, physical function, quality of sleep, depression, anxiety, clinical severity, clinical improvement, and diagnostic criteria for research temporomandibular joint dysfunction in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome (FMS). Background: the results on physiotherapy benefits for temporomandibular joint dysfunction in patients with FMS are controversial. Descriptive data and intervention studies are still scarce. Methods and measures: sixty patients will be randomly assigned to experimental or control group. The experimental group will receive 24 sessions (twice a week) of kinesitherapy and myofascial release protocol, whereas the control group will undergo to deontology therapy (porting a deprogramming occlusal splint every night, an average of 8 hours per day, for 12 weeks of the treatment). Pain levels, impact of FMS symptoms, quality of sleep, depression, anxiety, clinical severity, clinical improvement and diagnostic criteria for research of temporomandibular joint dysfunction will be collected in both groups at baseline and 12 weeks after 48-hr the last intervention in the experimental and control groups, by an assessor blinded to the treatment allocation of the patients. Baseline demographic and clinical variables will be examined between both groups independent Student t-test for continuous data and χ2 tests of independence for categorical data. Separate 2x2 mixed model ANCOVAs with time (pre-post) as the within-subjects factor, group (experimental, control) will be to determine the effects of the treatment on pain, function, quality of sleep,depression, anxiety, clinical severity, clinical improvement and diagnostic criteria for research of temporomandibular joint dysfunction as the dependent variables.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibromyalgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myofascial Pain Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temporomandibular Joint Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temporomandibular Joint Dysfunction Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Joint Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of fibromyalgia syndrome. Agreement to attend evening therapy sessions. A chief complaint of acute pain (duration &lt;6 months) in the temporomandibular joint on at least one side. The presence of joint clicking during jaw opening that was eliminated on protrusive opening. History of recent trauma. Therapeutic cointerventions during treatment. Indication for surgical treatment of temporomandibular joint. Edentulism. Physical or mental illness that precludes attendance at therapy sessions.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fibromyalgia Syndrome, Temporomandibular Joint, Pain.</keyword>
</DOC>