<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02684305</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Induction of labor is one of the most common obstetrical medical procedures performed today. Iatrogenic stimulation of uterine contractions prior to the onset of spontaneous labor is undertaken for various maternal and fetal indications and spans 20% of deliveries today. 1. During the past years there has been an additional rise due to elective inductions 2. Induction is undertaken when potential risks of prolonging pregnancy outweigh the risks of induced delivery, particularly those associated with post-term pregnancy, rupture of membranes, oligohydramnios and additional fetal and maternal conditions that pose risks to mother and fetus. In many circumstances of women with an unfavorable cervix (Bishop score of 7 or less) sequential induction with more than one agent is necessary. To date, no trial has compared the optimal subsequent ripening method after the preliminary use of dinoprostone (prostaglandin E2). In this trial investigators aim to compare the obstetrical outcomes of subsequent induction in women admitted for induction of labor with Bishop score &lt;7 or less 24 hours after the insertion of vaginal prostaglandin insert (Propess). Two methods of routine induction of labor will be compared: An additional Propess induction for another 24 hours vs. intravenous oxytocin infusion combined with intra-cervical balloon insertion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Stepwise Labor Induction Following Failure of Prostaglandin Vaginal Insert for Labor Induction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Induction of labor is one of the most common obstetrical medical procedures performed today. Iatrogenic stimulation of uterine contractions prior to the onset of spontaneous labor is undertaken for various maternal and fetal indications and spans 20% of deliveries today 1. During the past years there has been an additional rise due to elective inductions 2. Induction is undertaken when potential risks of prolonging pregnancy outweigh the risks of induced delivery, particularly those associated with post-term pregnancy, rupture of membranes, oligohydramnios and additional fetal and maternal conditions that pose risks to mother and fetus. In many circumstances of women with an unfavorable cervix (Bishop score of 7 or less) sequential induction with more than one agent is necessary. To date, no trial has compared the optimal subsequent ripening method after the preliminary use of dinoprostone (prostaglandin E2). In this trial investigators aim to compare the obstetrical outcomes of subsequent induction in women admitted for induction of labor with Bishop score &lt;7 or less 24 hours after the insertion of vaginal prostaglandin insert (Propess). Two methods of routine induction of labor will be compared: An additional Propess induction for another 24 hours vs. intravenous oxytocin infusion combined with intra-cervical balloon insertion.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Polystyrene sulfonic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxytocin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Maternal age of 18 years or greater 2. Singleton gestation 3. Bishop score of 7 or less 24 hours after the insertion of Propess 4. Pregnancies at 36+0/7 weeks of gestation and beyond 5. Normal fetal heart rate tracings and normal sonogram at admission (ie Vertex, appropriate for gestational age, biophysical score of 8/8, normal amniotic fluid index) 6. No contraindication for prolongation of pregnancy (e.g. intrauterine infection, placental abruption, etc.) 1. Situations preventing continuation of induction process in any arm patient refusal, maternal of fetal conditions necessitating prompt delivery. 2. Rupture of membranes (ROM) after initial Propess insertion.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>