<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02684331</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will be performed as a cross-sectional survey. 300 Type 2 diabetes patients (T2DM), with or without known cardiovascular disease, will be recruited from the diabetes outpatient clinic, Slagelse Hospital. The patients will undergo echocardiography, Cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (CMR), clinical examination and will be asked to fill out questionnaires. This study project sets out to answer the following hypotheses: 1. Patients with T2DM have an increased risk of developing diastolic dysfunction. Using CMR, the investigators wish to measure left ventricle peak filling rate and passive atrial emptying fraction as a measure of cardiac diastolic function. The investigators hypothesize that classic T2DM markers such as levels of urinary albumin excretion, retinopathy, autonomic neuropathy, hypertension, dyslipidemia, elevated HgbA1c, T2DM duration, etc. are associated with pathological findings by CMR. 2. Patients with T2DM have impaired left ventricle myocardial perfusion as determined by gadolinium contrast CMR. The investigators hypothesize that the classic markers and risk factors mentioned above, are associated with left ventricle myocardial hypoperfusion as determined by gadolinium contrast CMR.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CMR in Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patient fully capable of informed consent Informed consent T2DM Age 1880 (both years included) Contraindications to CMR (pacemakers/ICDunits, cochlear implants) Lack of consent Atrial fibrillation eGFR &lt; 30 ml/min/1,73m2 (only exclusion criteria for gadolinium contrast study) Women of childbearing potential who are not on acceptable contraception Severe claustrophobia (only contraindication for CMR but can undergo echocardiography and other examinations) Contraindications to adenosine: history of significant bronchial asthma, 2nd or 3rd degree AVblock, severe hypotension, long QTsyndrome, unstable angina pectoris, sinus node dysfunction, incompensated heart failure Contraindications to glycopyrrolate: closedangle glaucoma, prostate hyperplasia, tachycardia, bladder atony, cardia insufficiency, noncongenital pylorus stenosis and gastroparesis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>