<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02244853</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Cardiovascular disease research using Linked Bespoke studies and Electronic Records (CALIBER) e-health database was the data resource for this study. CALIBER links patient records from four different data sources: Clinical Practice Research Database (CPRD), MINAP (Myocardial Ischaemia National Audit Project registry) Hospital Episodes Statistics (HES), the Office for National Statistics (ONS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Heart Rate and Cardiovascular Diseases Prognosis in People With Stable Coronary Artery Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is part of the CALIBER (Cardiovascular disease research using linked bespoke studies and electronic records) programme funded over 5 years from the NIHR and Wellcome Trust. The central theme of the CALIBER research is linkage of the Myocardial Ischaemia National Audit Project (MINAP) with primary care (GPRD) and other resources. The overarching aim of CALIBER is to better understand the aetiology and prognosis of specific coronary phenotypes across a range of causal domains, particularly where electronic records provide a contribution beyond traditional studies. CALIBER has received both Ethics approval (ref 09/H0810/16) and ECC approval (ref ECC 2-06(b)/2009 CALIBER dataset).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angina, Stable</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Death, Sudden</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Death, Sudden, Cardiac</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged &gt;=30 years at study entry &gt;=1 year registration prior to the 'index date' Free from previous atherosclerotic events No heart rate measurement after their 'index date' of eligibility to entry the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>