<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03081182</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Coordinating and Data Management Center (CDMC) at MD Anderson Cancer will be responsible for the coordination and data management for the Pediatric Longitudinal Cohort Study of Chronic Pancreatitis (INSPPIRE 2), which is part of the NIH U01 funded Consortium for the Study of Chronic Pancreatitis, Diabetes, and Pancreatic Cancer (CPDPC). All patient recruitment will occur at external sites that are a part of the CPDPC. The data management systems, auditing, and monitoring effort are supported by the MD Anderson Cancer Center Clinical Research Support Center (CRSC).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pediatric Longitudinal Cohort Study of Chronic Pancreatitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pancreatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. All patients/parents must sign an informed consent and/or assent indicating that they are aware of the investigational nature of this study. 2. Patients/parents must have signed an authorization for the release of their or their child's protected health information. 3. All children providing samples should fit the ARP or CP inclusion criteria defined below. 4. All children must be 18 y/o or younger at the time of enrollment. Acute pancreatitis (AP): AP is defined as requiring 2 of the following: 1. Abdominal pain compatible with AP, 2. Serum amylase and/or lipase values ≥3 times upper limits of normal, 3. Imaging findings of AP, such as gland enlargement, acute inflammatory changes, fluid collections. ARP is defined as: At least 2 episodes of acute pancreatitis with complete resolution of pain and a &gt;1 month painfree interval between episodes. Chronic Pancreatitis: Children with at least: 1. one irreversible structural change* in the pancreas with or without abdominal pain and ONE of the two conditions below: 2. exocrine pancreatic insufficiency 3. diabetes *irreversible structural changes: Ductal calculi, dilated side branches, parenchymal calcifications found in any imaging (abdominal ultrasound (abd US), magnetic resonance imaging/magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography (MRI/MRCP), computerized tomography (CT), endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography (ERCP), endoscopic US (EUS). Ductal obstruction or stricture/dilatation/irregularities that are persistent (for &gt;2 months) on any imaging. Parenchymal atrophy, irregular contour, accentuated lobular architecture, cavities alone are not diagnostic findings for CP. Surgical or pancreatic biopsy specimen demonstrating histopathologic features compatible with CP (acinar atrophy, fibrosis, protein plugs, infiltration with lymphocytes, plasma cells, macrophages). 1. Patients must not have any significant medical illnesses that in the investigator's opinion cannot be adequately controlled with appropriate therapy or would compromise the patient's ability to tolerate study interventions.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pediatric Chronic Pancreatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Data management</keyword>
	<keyword>Regulatory compliance</keyword>
	<keyword>Protocol monitoring</keyword>
</DOC>