<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03081078</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will determine whether community-based caring contact via a mobile app connection with or without volunteer support in addition to treatment as usual (psychiatric and psychosocial treatments) has an effect on suicidal ideation and treatment compliance among post-discharge self-harm young adults.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Community-based Caring Contact on Post-discharge Young Adults With Self-harm</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The proposed study will determine whether community-based caring contact via a mobile app connection with or without volunteer support in addition to treatment as usual (TAU; psychiatric and psychosocial treatments) is effective in reducing suicidal ideation, enhancing treatment compliance, reducing thwarted belongingness and perceived burdensomeness and hopelessness among post-discharge self-harm young adults, and if personalized contact by volunteers has additional effects reducing suicidal ideation among post-discharge self-harm individuals. 108 participants aged 18-39 with an index self-harm episode will be recruited from the Accident &amp; Emergency Department (AED) of 4 local public hospitals, and randomized into the TAU, mobile app group with, and without volunteer support. Each participant will complete a questionnaire at the 4 measurement time points at baseline, during the 6-month observation (3 and 6 months) and at post-intervention (9 months from baseline). The primary outcomes include Suicidal ideation, hopelessness, thwarted belongingness &amp; perceived burdensomeness, treatment (TAU) compliance, and suicidality.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Suicide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Self Mutilation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Individuals with an index episode of selfpoisoning or selfinjury with or without suicide intent, based on the ICD10 codes for selfharm with and without suicide intent (i.e., X60 to X84 and R45.8) Admission to the AEDs at the 4 collaborating public hospitals in Hong Kong (United Christian Hospital, North District Hospital, Queen Mary Hospital, and Pamela Youde Nethersole Eastern Hospital) Mentally well assessed by a psychiatrist or Consultation Liaison Nurses (CLNs) Capable of providing written Informed Consent Form Individuals with DSMIVTR Axis II disorder; or Individuals with severe psychotic mental illness or bipolar disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>39 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>