<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01970605</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This web based e-Registry will be international, multi-center and prospective. Silver Graft e-Registry to assess the long term clinical benefit of Silver Graft in an unselected patient population</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Silver Graft All Comers Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To assess the long term clinical benefit of Silver Graft in an unselected patient population with Peripheral Artery Occlusive Disease (PAOD) fulfilling one of the the following criteria: 1. Any suitable patient in need of an infrarenal vascular reconstruction with Fontaine class IIb or indicated vascular reconstruction aneurysm repair. or 2. Any suitable patient with an increased risk for early graft failure except those mentioned under (3). These may include - diabetics - Fontaine class&gt; IIb - patients of advanced age (≥75 y) - patients with renal insufficiency (creatinine ≥ 1.50 mg/dl or ≥130 µmol/l) - patients with COPD or documented coronary artery disease (prior PCI, prior CABG, documented myocardial ischemia) - patients with major amputation - immunosuppressed patients - patients with autoimmune disease, malignancy or 3. Any suitable patient with graft infection or present infection in the anatomical position of indicated vascular reconstruction.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Any suitable patient in need of an infrarenal vascular reconstruction with Fontaine class IIb or indicated vascular reconstruction aneurysm repair. 2. Any suitable patient with an increased risk for early graft failure except those mentioned under (3). These may include diabetics Fontaine class&gt; IIb patients of advanced age (≥75 y) patients with renal insufficiency (creatinine ≥ 1.50 mg/dl or ≥130 µmol/l) patients with COPD or documented coronary artery disease (prior PCI, prior CABG, documented myocardial ischemia) patients with major amputation immunosuppressed patients patients with autoimmune disease, malignancy 3. Any suitable patient with graft infection or present infection in the anatomical position of indicated vascular reconstruction. Any patient with common contraindications for vascular surgery may not be included in this registry. Any patient with an estimated life expectancy less than the first followup period, i.e. 12 months is excluded from data entry. Any patient with a known and documented allergy to silver or silver ions.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>