<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02969356</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this clinical study is to assess whether AbobotulinumtoxinA (Dysport®) injections in upper and lower limbs accompanied with a personal exercise plan called "Guided Self-rehabilitation Contract" (GSC) can improve voluntary movements in subjects with hemiparesis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate Effects of DYSPORT® Injected in Lower and Upper Limb Combined With Guided Self-Rehabilitation Contract (GSC)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Muscle Spasticity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paresis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemiplegia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>abobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins, Type A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>onabotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>incobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects aged at least the national legal adult age. Subjects with hemiparesis due to acquired brain injury (ABI) presenting with muscle overactivity impeding motor function based on investigator's judgement including, but not limited to, at least one of the following requiring botulinum neurotoxin (BoNT) treatment: typical clenched fist; flexed wrist; flexed elbow; or plantar flexed foot pattern. At least 12 months since the ABI. Naïve or nonnaïve to BoNT treatment; if nonnaïve, at least 4 months after the last BoNT injection, of any serotype. Upper limb active function with an overall score between 2 and 7, as assessed by MFS, if the primary TT limb is the UL. A 10metre maximal WS barefoot between 0.2 and 1.4 m/s, if the primary TT limb is the LL. Maximal WS barefoot will be performed without walking aids. However, a cane may be permitted if absolutely necessary (although this may prevent detection of treatmentinduced improvements). In this case, the same aid will have to be used for all WS assessments during the study. Subjects must provide written informed consent to participate in the study prior to any studyrelated procedures. Female subjects of childbearing potential (not surgically sterile or 2 years postmenopausal) must use a medically accepted method of contraception and must agree to continue use of this method for the duration of the study until the last visit of the subjects and for at least 12 weeks post injection. Acceptable methods of contraception include total abstinence, male partner has had a vasectomy, double barrier method (e.g. male condom plus spermicide, or female diaphragm plus spermicide), intrauterine device, or hormonal contraceptive (oral, transdermal, implanted and injected). Subjects must be willing and able to comply with study restrictions and to remain at the clinic for the required duration during the study period and willing to return to the clinic for the followup evaluation as specified in the protocol Inability to understand protocol procedures and requirements, which, in the opinion of the investigator, could negatively impact on protocol compliance, in particularly inability to exercise according to the GSC. Previous surgery on the affected muscles and ligaments, tendons, nerve trunks, or bones of the treated upper or lower limb. Previous treatment with phenol and/or alcohol in any of the treated limbs any time before the study. Any medical condition (including severe dysphagia or breathing difficulties) that may increase, in the opinion of the investigator, the likelihood of adverse events (AEs) related to BoNT A treatment. Current, planned or received within the last 4 weeks prior to study treatment, treatment with any drug that interferes either directly or indirectly with neuromuscular function (for example, aminoglycosides). Major neurological impairment other than spastic paresis (including major proprioceptive ataxia or apraxia on the paretic side) that could negatively impact on the functional performance of the subject. Known disease of the neuromuscular junction (such as LambertEaton myasthenic syndrome or myasthenia gravis). Known sensitivity to BoNTA or any excipient of Dysport. Infection at the injection site(s). Current pregnancy or lactation. A pregnancy test will be performed at the start of the study for all female subjects of childbearing potential (i.e. not surgically sterile or 2 years postmenopausal). Mental condition rendering the subject unable to understand the nature, scope and possible consequences of the study and/or evidence of an uncooperative attitude. Abnormal baseline findings or any other medical condition(s) that, in the opinion of the investigator, might jeopardise the subject's safety. Anticoagulant treatment with international normalised ratio (INR) &gt;3.5 within a week prior to injection. Subjects who have participated in any therapeutic clinical study/received any investigational agent within 30 days of enrolment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>