<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02969148</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate the clinical efficacy and safety of laparoscopic bursectomy and D2 lymphadenectomy (LBDL group) versus laparoscopic D2 lymphadenectomy (LDL group) in advanced gastric cancer by prospective randomized controlled clinical trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Laparoscopic Bursectomy and D2 Lymphadenectomy vs.Laparoscopic D2 Lymphadenectomy in Advanced Gastric Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To compare the LBDL group and LDL group in the advanced gastric cancer. A prospective randomized controlled trial will be performed in the GI department, Guangdong provincial hospital of Chinese Medicine from November 2016 to November 2024. The sample size，100 cases with advanced gastric cancer, will be needed after calculated by the statistics. The 100 cases will be randomly divided into two groups: LBDL group and LDL group. Primary outcomes are the 3 years' Disease-free survival (DFS) rate, The secondary outcomes are the 3 years' and 5 years' Disease-free survival (DFS) rate, the 3 years and 5 years Overall survival（OS）rate, operative time, the total blood loss, the intra-operative complication and the post-operative complication, the number of lymph nodes dissected, the number of conversion to open laparotomy, and the other outcomes are the average time of ground activities, the hospital stay. The data in two groups will be compared.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. The age limits is 1880 years old; 2. T3T4 resectable gastric carcinoma,confirmed by CT and pathology. 3. The preoperative imaging confirmed that the tumor did not involve adjacent organs; 4. American Society of anesthesiologists (ASA) score less than or equal to Level 3; 5. Criteria of performance status karnofsky is greater than or equal to 60. 1. The patients' age limits is Less than 18 years old, or more than 80 years old; 2. The preoperative imaging confirmed that the tumor involve adjacent organs; 3. The tumor have been finding distant metastases; 4. American Society of anesthesiologists (ASA) score more than 3; 5. Criteria of performance status karnofsky is lower than 60; 6. There is a laparoscopic surgery contraindications.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Laparoscopic</keyword>
	<keyword>Bursectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>D2 lymphadenectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>Gastric Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>