<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00512382</DOC>
	<brief_summary>GER and respiratory symptoms are both common phenomenon in children. Both can coexist in the same patient by chance alone. Research reveals increased incidence for both to coexist leading to suspect a temporal association and possible causality. Therefore we conducted an observational study To determine the primary cause (RS or GER)using for the first time both PH-Impedance as measurements of GER and Wheezy monitoring (WEEM) that records simultaneously wheeze and cough noises. Both modalities will be recorded for 12-24 hours. If GER precedes cough/wheeze recordings it points to GER being the possible precipitating factor and vice versa.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Nature of Reflux-respiratory Symptoms Association in Difficult to Treat Wheezing\Coughing Babies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>GER and respiratory symptoms are both common phenomenon in children. Both can coexist in the same patient by chance alone. Research reveals increased incidence for both to coexist leading to suspect a temporal association and possible causality. Therefore we conducted an observational study To determine the primary cause (RS or GER)using for the first time both PH-Impedance as measurements of GER and Wheezy monitoring (WEEM) that records simultaneously wheeze and cough noises. Both modalities will be recorded for 12-24 hours. If GER precedes cough/wheeze recordings it points to GER being the possible precipitating factor.However, If cough/wheeze precedes GER recordings it points to cough/wheeze being the possible precipitating factor. The recordings will be investigated 1 minute before and one minute after each event.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Sounds</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Signs and Symptoms, Respiratory</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children 1 month 18 years old Difficult to treat asthma Difficult to treat cough Difficult to treat other respiratory symptoms Children on artificial ventilation Children not compliant with PHMetria and/or WEEM</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>GER Gastrointestinal reflux</keyword>
	<keyword>Aspiration</keyword>
	<keyword>ASHTMA</keyword>
	<keyword>COUGH</keyword>
	<keyword>WHEEZE</keyword>
	<keyword>PH-IMPEDANCE</keyword>
	<keyword>WEEM Wheezy Monitor</keyword>
</DOC>