<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00512590</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this pilot study was to test the effects of a 10-week relaxation and guided imagery intervention on pain perception, functional status, self-efficacy and levels of distress in Hispanic adults diagnosed with fibromyalgia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pilot Study: Relaxation and Guided Imagery in Hispanic Persons Diagnosed With Fibromyalgia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Fibromyalgia (FM), a chronic widespread pain condition with an unknown pathogenesis and no known cure, affects 2 to 4 million persons in the adult US population. One of the most common conditions seen in rheumatology clinics world wide, including the US, Mexico, and Spain, FM is accompanied by various co-occurring symptoms such as fatigue, disturbed sleep, stiffness and depression. While studies of fibromyalgia in Hispanics have been reported in Spain, Brazil and Argentina, very few such studies have been reported in the United States. This gap exists despite data indicating that there are a reported 16 million Hispanics with rheumatic diseases in the US and that Hispanics (self-identified) form the fastest growing minority group in this country.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibromyalgia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myofascial Pain Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>ages 18 and older diagnosis of fibromyalgia based on the American College of Rheumatology criteria and documented by the patient's primary physician a minimum of a 6th grade education level an ability to understand and sign the consent form and understand and complete the intervention (pencil and paper) assignments. presence of other systemic rheumatologic conditions such as rheumatoid arthritis, lupus, and/or Sjogren's Disease adequate functional status as indicated by a Fibromyalgia Impact Questionnaire score &lt; 20 inadequate cognitive status as evidenced by a MiniMental State Exam score &lt; 25 history of epilepsy major communicative disorder.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>fibromyalgia</keyword>
	<keyword>relaxation</keyword>
	<keyword>imagery</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>functional status</keyword>
	<keyword>self efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>minority health</keyword>
</DOC>