<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00512694</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Lupus is a systemic autoimmune disease that can present with many varied symptoms, including joint pain, fevers, kidney disease, and rashes. Lupus can affect anyone, but it is most common in younger women. The Duke Lupus Registry will collect information and blood samples from patients with lupus (systemic lupus erythematosus or cutaneous lupus) seen in the Duke Rheumatology clinics. The goal of this Registry is to understand how lupus changes over time so that we can improve the treatment of patients with lupus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Duke Lupus Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Duke Lupus Registry is a prospective cohort comprised of patients with lupus seen in the Duke Rheumatology clinic. The Duke Lupus Registry has two main purposes: 1. Improved patient care. By following disease activity scores and medication usage, we expect to improve our care of the patients seen in clinic. 2. Future research on lupus outcomes. This may encompass a broad array of areas, including but not limited to cardiovascular health, pregnancy and fertility, infections, medication use, quality of life, and depression. At each office visit, patients will complete a questionnaire, physicians will measure lupus activity, and patients may be asked to provide a small blood sample. Patients will not be required to make extra visits to Duke in order to participate -- all paperwork and blood draws will occur during a regularly scheduled office visit with the physician.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of Systemic Lupus Erythematosus or Cutaneous Lupus Patient of a rheumatologist at Duke University Medical Center Inability to travel to Duke for followup visits Inability to speak English Not able to provide informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lupus</keyword>
	<keyword>Systemic Lupus Erythematosus</keyword>
	<keyword>Cutaneous Lupus</keyword>
</DOC>