<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02440893</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study goal was to understand the effect of Metformin on Corus® CAD (henceforth "Corus") in pre-diabetic patients who are medication naive. This study provided data to determine if the Corus gene expression signature was different in pre-diabetic patients when metformin was newly prescribed and taken.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Metformin and Corus CAD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study goal was to understand the effect of Metformin on Corus® CAD (henceforth "Corus") in pre-diabetic patients who are medication naive. This study provided data to determine if the Corus gene expression signature was different in pre-diabetic patients when metformin was newly prescribed and taken. The primary aim of this study was to evaluate whether metformin used in pre-diabetic patients to prevent progression to type II diabetes had a significant effect on the gene expression levels measured in Corus. This was a prospective study. Subjects were enrolled from participating sites as applicable inclusion/exclusion criteria were met. The study aimed to enroll approximately fifty (50) patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 21 years of age Any of the following: Chest pain syndrome, stable angina, or anginal equivalent suggesting myocardial ischemia Lowrisk unstable angina, or Asymptomatic individuals with a high probability of CAD Clinician diagnosis of prediabetes, per ADA guidelines, such that metformin therapy is prescribed: HgA1C: &gt;5.7% &lt;6.4%, BMI&gt; 35 kg/m2 Age&lt; 60 yrs Prior Gestational Diabetes Mellitus FPG: &gt;100mg/dl &lt;126mg/dl OGTT: &gt;140mg/dl &lt;200mg/dl Willingness to comply with metformin therapy, for at least seven (7) days (P.O., per physician's dosage discretion) Willingness to maintain a drug diary for duration of study, for full followup period (7 + 7 days) Willingness and ability to provide two (2) samples for Corus (baseline, 7 (+ 7) days post medication start) Provide written informed consent History of or current level of HbA1C &gt;6.5 History of or current prescription of metformin or any other diabetic medication History of myocardial infarction (MI) or prior revascularization Current MI or acute coronary syndrome (ACS) Current New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III or IV congestive heart failure symptoms Current systemic infectious or systemic inflammatory conditions Subjects currently taking steroids, immunosuppressive agents or chemotherapeutic agents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>