<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02770768</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the present study is to understand the neurobiological mechanisms of action underlying sexual desire building on prior work Dr. Stephanie Cacioppo has done in which desire was not manipulated. In the present project, Dr. Stephanie Cacioppo is manipulating desire through Flibanserin (Addyi) vs. placebo and she will be measuring subjective sexual desire as a manipulation check. The investigators will address this goal using a double-blind randomized outpatient design and determine the pre-post neurobehavioral change in the Flibanserin group and investigate the extent to which Flibanserin normalizes brain activity in premenopausal women with HSDD and the extent to which regional brain activation is associated with changes in symptoms and behavior (as measured with self-report measures of sexual desire and/or eye-tracking movements).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Flibanserin on the Pre- and Post-menopausal Female Brain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Hypoactive sexual desire disorder (HSDD) is the most common sexual complaint in women. Over the past 8 years, Dr. Stephanie Cacioppo has developed and validated the Desire Intention task, in which individuals are instructed to indicate as rapidly and as accurately as possible whether or not each visually presented stimulus (e.g., attractive persons of the opposite sex) is sexually desirable to them at the moment of the experiment. Flibanserin (Addyi) is a new medication approved by the FDA for the treatment of HSDD in pre-menopausal women. The investigators propose a study using the DIT to determine the extent to which Flibanserin normalizes brain activity in women with HSDD and the extent to which regional brain activation is associated with changes in symptoms and behavior.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypokinesia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sexual Dysfunctions, Psychological</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female Ages 2145 or 5174 Pre or Postmenopausal DSM5 diagnosis of hypoactive sexual desire disorder (HSDD) Righthanded Male Pregnant women Nursing women Postmenopausal women Women who report not being able to stop drinking alcohol during the duration of the study Currently taking psychotropic medication History of seizures or neurological disorders Under hormonal therapy Current or past diagnosis of cancer Any unstable medical illnesses Lifetime history of bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, or psychotic disorder Current or recent (past 3 months) substance abuse or dependence Current or recent (past 3 months) clinical depression Currently taking any medications that have/may have unfavorable interactions with Flibanserin</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>74 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>HSDD (Hypoactive Sexual Desire Disorder)</keyword>
	<keyword>EEG (Electroencephalogram)</keyword>
</DOC>