<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02770170</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall purpose of the study is to assess the efficacy of three different doses of BI 655064 against placebo as add-on therapy to standard of care (SOC) treatment for active lupus nephritis in order to characterize the dose-response relationship within the therapeutic range, and select the target dose for phase III development.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose Finding, Efficacy and Safety of BI 655064 in Patients With Active Lupus Nephritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Nephritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lupus Nephritis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Males and females 1870 years. Women of childbearing potential must be ready and able to use highly effective methods of birth control per international Conference on Harmonisation M3 (R2) that result in a low failure rate of less than 1% per year when used consistently and correctly. Diagnosis of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) by American College of Rheumatology criteria 1997, at least 4 criteria must be documented, one of which must be a positive antidsDNA antibody Lupus Nephritis Class III or IV (International Society of Nephrology (ISN)/Renal Pathology Society (RPS) 2003 classification) with either active or active/chronic disease, coexisting class V permitted, proven by renal biopsy within 3 months prior to screening or during screening if induction therapy has not yet been started Active renal disease evidenced by proteinuria &gt;= 1.0 g/day (Uprot/Ucrea &gt;= 100 mg/mmol) Signed and dated written informed consent Exclusion criteria: Clinically significant current other renal disease Glomerular Filtration Rate &lt;30ml/min/1.73m² Acute presence of Oliguria (&lt;500 mL/day) Dialysis within 12m of screening Antiphospholipid syndrome Diabetes mellitus poorly controlled or known diabetic retinopathy or nephropathy Evidence of current or previous clinically significant disease, medical condition or finding in the medical examination that in the investigator's opinion would compromise the safety of the patient or the quality of the data Any induction therapy for Lupus Nephritis within the last 6 months prior to randomisation except induction with Mycophenolate Mofetil and high dose steroids started within 4 weeks prior to randomisation Treatment with any biologic Bcell depleting therapy (e.g. antiCD20, antiCD22, antiBLyS) within 12 months prior to randomisation Treatment with abatacept within 12 months prior to randomisation Treatment with tacrolimus or cyclosporin within 4 weeks prior to randomisation Treatment with cyclophosphamid within 6 months prior to randomisation Treatment with investigational drug within 6 months or 5 halflives, whichever is greater before randomisation Contraindication for MMF or corticosteroids Chronic or relevant acute infections, including but not limited to HIV, Hepatitis B and C and tuberculosis (including a history of clinical tuberculosis (TB) and/or a positive QuantiFERON TBGold test Any active or suspected malignancy or history of documented malignancy within the last 5 years before screening, except appropriately treated carcinoma in situ and treated basal cell carcinoma. Live vaccination within 6 weeks before randomisation Patients unable to comply with the protocol in the investigator's opinion. Alcohol abuse in the opinion of the investigator or active drug abuse . Women who are pregnant, nursing, or who plan to become pregnant while in the trial Impaired hepatic function, defined as serum Aspartate Transferase/Alanine Transferase, bilirubin or alkaline phosphatase levels &gt; 2 x Upper Limit of Normal</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>