<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="192831">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00581958</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>07-158</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00581958</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT00899886</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Radiation Biodosimetry in Patients Treated With Total Body Irradiation (TBI)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Radiation Biodosimetry in Patients Treated With Total Body Irradiation (TBI)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Georgetown University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Standards and Technology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to develop blood tests and urine tests that can tell doctors
      how much radiation a person has been exposed to. Doctors know how much radiation patients
      are exposed to in certain medical situations. An example of this would be radiation
      treatment for cancer. Radiation treatment machines are programmed to give exact doses of
      radiation.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      MSKCC patients undergoing TBI as part of a hematopoietic stem cell transplant (HSCT) will
      have blood drawn and urine collected for use in the validation and refinement of new methods
      for rapid high-throughput radiation biodosimetry. These blood and urine samples will be
      collected before, and at defined times after TBI. Blood sampling will occur in the same
      manner that it does during routine patient care during HSCT.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To develop, validate and refine high-throughput platforms for radiation biodosimetry using metabolomic assays.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>The approach involves profiling blood and urinary metabolites that are specific for radiation exposure and dose.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing HSCT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Research subjects will have blood and/or urine sampled at three time points in the Department of Radiation Oncology. Participating patients will have at least a total two samples collected at each time point. The first sampling will occur before the first TBI treatment is given. The second sampling will occur before the second TBI treatment, usually 3 to 8 hours after the first treatment (in the case of multifraction TBI). If a patient is being treated with single fraction TBI, then the second sampling will occur approximately 3-8 hours after the first TBI treatment. The third and final sampling will occur at the next morning blood draw, prior to the fourth TBI treatment (in the case of multifraction TBI), 24 hours after the first TBI treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blood Samples</intervention_name>
    <description>blood (approximately two 4 ml; equivalent to less than 2 tablespoon) and urine (a cup of urine) samples or testing a total of three times. Blood will be drawn and urine will be collected once before radiation treatment and twice after first radiation treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing HSCT</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients greater than 4 years of age at Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center

          -  Must be undergoing hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (either autologous or
             allogenic) in conjunction with a conditioning regimen that includes TBI (single or
             multiple fraction)

          -  Functional central venous catheter

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  No subjects will be excluded from the proposed research study for demographic
             reasons. Treatment with growth factors, such as keratinocyte growth factor (KGF),
             will not be grounds for exclusion.

          -  Subjects who will receive radiation therapy within 5 days prior to TBI will be
             excluded.

          -  Subjects who will receive systemic antineoplastic chemotherapy within 7 days prior to
             TBI not have research bloods collected. Only urine will be collected from these
             patients.

          -  Based on current knowledge, we will not a priori exclude patients based on disease
             status (ie, patients in or out of remission will be included in this study), type of
             disease(ie, chromosomal breakage syndromes), or previous therapies (unless exclusion
             criteria is met).
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christopher Barker, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christopher A. Barker, MD</last_name>
    <phone>212-639-8168</phone>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christopher Barker, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-639-8168</phone>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Marcel VandenBrink, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>646-888-2304</phone>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christopher Barker, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mskcc.org</url>
    <description>Memorial Sloan Kettering Web Site</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>October 13, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 21, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>total body irradiation</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Hematopoietic System</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
