<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00394433</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to determine if the combination of docetaxel, cisplatin, irinotecan and bevacizumab will help shrink metastatic esophageal or gastric cancer and how the cancer responds to this combination. Bevacizumab is a new drug that is believed to stop the formation of new blood vessels that carry nutrients to tumors. Bevacizumab is approved for use in metastatic colon and rectal cancer. Docetaxel, cisplatin and irinotecan are traditional chemotherapy agents that have been tested together in another clinical trial for esophageal and gastric cancer. It is hoped that adding bevacizumab to this regimen will make the treatment more effective.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Docetaxel, Cisplatin, Irinotecan and Bevacizumab (TPCA) in Metastatic Esophageal and Gastric Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary To determine the 10-month progression-free survival rate for the combination of TPC and Bevacizumab in patients with metastatic esophageal or gastric cancer Secondary - To determine the response rate (RECIST) and median duration of response - To determine overall survival - To determine toxicity Exploratory - To explore if 7/7 and 7/6 UGT1A1 polymorphisms correlate with grade III/IV irinotecan-related diarrhea and neutropenia when irinotecan is given at relatively low dose to patients with esophageal and gastric cancer - To correlate expression of tumoral and serum VEGF with response and survival - To correlate TGF alpha levels and tumor microvessel density with clinical activity - To examine circulating endothelial cells (CECs) as surrogate markers of antitumor activity of bevacizumab DESIGN This trial will use a single stage design to differentiate a &gt;/= 50% rate of 10-month progression-free survival from a &lt;/= 30% rate. The proposed regimen would be promising if at least 15 of 35 patients were alive and progression-free at 10 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed, unresectable esophageal or gastric carcinoma (carcinoma=adenocarcinoma or squamous cell carcinoma) Measurable disease greater than or equal to 1 cm (longest diameter) by spiral computed tomography (CT) scan or 2 cm or greater by other radiographic technique Lesions must be measurable in at least one dimension Bone lesions, ascites, and effusions are not measurable 18 years of age or older ECOG performance status 0 or 1 Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks Adequate bone marrow function Adequate renal function Adequate liver function Prior chemotherapy (except as part of pre or postoperative therapy, completed more than 1 year prior to start day of this protocol) History of severe hypersensitivity to bevacizumab, docetaxel, cisplatin, irinotecan, or drugs formulated with polysorbate 80 Current, recent (within 4 weeks) or planned participation in an experimental drug study Major surgical procedure, open biopsy, or significant traumatic injury within 28 days prior to Day 0, or anticipation of need for major surgical procedure during the course of the study Minor surgical procedures, such as fine needle aspirations, portacath placement, or core biopsies within 7 days prior to Day 0 of study Myocardial infarction or stroke in past 6 months Blood pressure of &gt; 150/100 mmHg Unstable angina New York Heart Association (NYHA) grade II or greater congestive heart failure Clinically significant peripheral vascular disease Persistent bleeding from primary tumor, while off anticoagulants, requiring repeated transfusions Evidence of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy Uncontrolled serious medical or psychiatric illness Uncontrolled diarrhea Peripheral neuropathy &gt; grade 1 Clinically apparent central nervous system metastases or carcinomatous meningitis Other active malignancy other than nonmelanoma skin cancer or in situ cervical carcinoma. Urine protein: creatinine ratio of 1.0 or greater at screening History of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation, or intraabdominal abscess within 6 months prior to Day 1 Serious nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture Pregnant or breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>TPCA</keyword>
	<keyword>Taxotere</keyword>
	<keyword>Platinum</keyword>
	<keyword>Avastin</keyword>
	<keyword>Camptosar</keyword>
	<keyword>gastric cancer</keyword>
</DOC>