<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02234284</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This proposed study will examine whether health coaches can improve the management of COPD in a population of vulnerable patients cared for in 'safety-net' clinics. The study is designed as a randomized controlled trial for patients with moderate to severe COPD. Patients will be randomized into a health coaching group and a usual care group. Those in the health coaching group will receive 9 months of active health coaching. Outcome variables will be measured at baseline and after 9 months</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aides in Respiration Health Coaching for COPD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>None as would duplicate information recorded elsewhere</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient at one of the participating primary care clinics (at least 1 visit in past 12 months) Age 40 and older Speaking English or Spanish Plan to continue to be seen at current clinic and to not leave the area for &gt;2 months anytime in the next 9 months or to be absent at 9 or 15 months COPD defined as ever having had a postbronchodilator Forced Expiratory Volume in 1 second/Forced Vital Capacity (FEV1/FVC) &lt;.70 Willingness to attempt spirometry At least moderate COPD, defined as at least one of the following: Ever Forced Expiratory Volume in 1 second (FEV1) &lt; 80% predicted 1 or more emergency department (ED) visit for COPD exacerbation in past 12 months 1 or more hospital stays for COPD exacerbation in past 12 months 1 or more prescriptions for oral prednisone for at least 40 mg per day for at least 5 days in past 12 months Ever on home oxygen therapy Ever outpatient percutaneous oxygen saturation of &lt;/=88% Ever outpatient partial pressure of oxygen (ppO2) by arterial blood gas (ABG) of &lt;/=55mm Hg At least 3 outpatient visits for COPD in past 12 months AND a current COPD Assessment Test (CAT) score of &gt;/=10 or an modified Medical Research Council (mMRC) score of &gt;/=2. Currently using tiotropium inhaler or combination inhaled corticosteroid and longacting beta agonist Unable to participate in the study due to mental or physical impairment Severe or terminal illness that precludes focus on COPD No phone</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>95 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Health Coaching</keyword>
	<keyword>Health Disparities</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-management</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Disease Model</keyword>
</DOC>