<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02234687</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study, we propose to employ a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, outpatient clinical trial to test the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of a 160 mg and 40 mg challenge of the mGlu2/3 agonist pomaglumetad methionil relative to placebo in modulating fear-potentiated startle response and behavior in adults with post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) (N=30). Each participant will receive a single dose of the study drug (40 mg vs 160 mg vs placebo in a 1:1:1 ratio).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A mGlu2/3 Agonist in the Treatment of PTSD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and women between 18 and 60 years of age, any race Primary, current Axis I diagnosis of post traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) according to Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders IV (DSMIV) criteria Able to provide written informed consent Past or current presence of psychotic symptoms, or diagnosis of a lifetime psychotic disorder including schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder, bipolar disorder History of moderate or severe traumatic brain injury (TBI) with loss of consciousness Lifetime history of seizure disorder Current diagnosis of obsessivecompulsive disorder (OCD) Current diagnosis of bulimia nervosa or anorexia nervosa; or substance use disorder Alcohol or drug abuse in the past 90 days, or dependence in the past year. Individuals with a cumulative lifetime history of intravenous substance abuse longer than 1 year. Severe dissociation, defined as a Clinician Administered Dissociative States Scale (CADSS) score greater than 60 at baseline Patients with creatinine clearance &lt;60 milliliters (mL)/min (moderate renal impairment) Current pregnancy or breast feeding; medical conditions that could interfere with correct interpretation of study data, i.e., individuals with the following medical conditions will be excluded: cancer in the past year, stroke, heart attack, angina, neurological disease (multiple sclerosis, epilepsy, Parkinson's disease), central nervous system (CNS) lesions including TBI with loss of consciousness, dementing illness, and/or liver or kidney disease. Patients with QT interval &gt;450 msec (males) and &gt;470 msec (females). Participants who have started new medication regimen for PTSD within 3 months prior to study start and subjects taking fluoxetine Current suicidality defined by emergent Columbia Suicide Severity Rating Scale (CSSRS)defined suicidal behavior, a suicidal ideation score of 5 (indicating active suicidal ideation with specific plan and some level of intent) or 4 (indicating active suicidal ideation with some intent to act, without specific plan) on the CSSRS or in the absence of a CSSRS suicidal ideation score of 5 or 4 or CSSRSdefined suicidal behavior, if the investigator determines the patient to have a significant shortterm risk for a suicide attempt. Individuals with active suicidal risk, active selfmutilation or aggressive behavior with threatening behavior toward others within the past year, as judged by the Principal Investigator Pregnant or lactating women Legal and Financial: Current legal proceedings resulting from the traumatic events. People whose continued receipt of financial benefits is contingent upon maintaining PTSD symptoms or who are waiting for a decision concerning the receipt of financial benefits based upon PTSD symptoms</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>post-traumatic stress disorder</keyword>
</DOC>