<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02851823</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the present study was to compare the effectiveness of combined Er:YAG and Nd:YAG laser therapy to that of scaling and root planning with hand instruments in nonsurgical treatment of chronic periodontitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combined Use of Er:YAG and Nd:YAG Laser</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of the present study was to compare the effectiveness of combined Er:YAG and Nd:YAG laser therapy to that of scaling and root planning with hand instruments in nonsurgical treatment of chronic periodontitis.Twenty-ﬁve systemically healthy patients with moderate-to-advanced periodontal destruction were selected for this study. The quadrants were randomly allocated in a split-mouth design to either combined Er:YAG (160 mj/pulse, and 10 Hz) and Nd:YAG laser (100 mJ/pulse, and 20 Hz) therapy (test group) or scaling root planning using hand instruments (control group). At baseline, 1 month, and 3 months after treatment, clinical measurements, including plaque index (PI), gingival index (GI), probing depth (PD), clinical attachment level (CAL), and bleeding on probing (%) (BOP), were performed and gingival crevicular fluid and subgingival plaque samples were taken. The gingival crevicular fluid levels of interleukin-1β (IL-1β) and tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α) were analyzed by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. Total antioxidant status (TAS)/total oxidant status (TOS) were analyzed by high-performance liquid chromatography and a novel automatic colorimetric method. Quantitative analysis of Porphyromonas gingivalis (Pg), Tannerella forsythia (Tf), and Treponema denticola (Td) was performed using real-time polymerase chain reaction (PCR) procedures.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patients had ≥4 teeth per quadrant with probing depth (PD) of ≥5 mm, clinical attachment level (CAL) of ≥4 mm, and radiographic signs of alveolar bone loss. These individuals also had bleeding on probing (BOP) at &gt;80% of the proximal sites. Periodontal treatment received for the last 1 year; systemic diseases that could influence the outcome of the therapy, pregnancy, smoking, immunosuppressive chemotherapy; and use of antibiotics and antiinflammatory drugs for the last 6 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Er-YAG lasers</keyword>
	<keyword>Nd-YAG lasers</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic periodontitis</keyword>
	<keyword>nonsurgical periodontal debridement</keyword>
</DOC>