<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02876640</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase Ib trial studies how well retinoid 9cUAB30 works in producing a biologic effect in patients with early stage breast cancer. Chemoprevention is the use of drugs to keep breast cancer from forming or coming back. The use of retinoid 9cUAB30 may slow disease progression in patients with early stage breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Retinoid 9cUAB30 in Producing a Biologic Effect in Patients With Early Stage Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Compare molecular analysis of pre- and post-treatment tissue samples of breast cancers of patients treated with 14-28 days of oral retinoid X receptor (RXR)-selective retinoid 9cUAB30 (9 c-UAB30) to demonstrate significantly reduced proliferation. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. Determine if 14-28 days of oral RXR-selective 9c-UAB30 treatment increases apoptotic index, as measured by TUNEL assay. II. Examine the differences in gene expression from baseline to post-exposure breast cancer samples using a custom gene panel from Nanostring Technologies. OUTLINE: Patients receive retinoid 9cUAB30 orally (PO) once daily (QD) for 14 to 28 days. Patients then undergo tumor resection surgery. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 7 days and 4-5 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status =&lt; 1 or Karnofsky &gt;= 70% Invasive breast cancer between 0.5 cm and 5 cm in size diagnosed by needle core biopsy, estrogen receptor positive or negative, Her2neu positive or negative, tumor grade 2 or 3 White blood cells (WBC) &gt;= 3000/mm^3 Platelets &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin &gt; 10 g/dL Bilirubin =&lt; upper limit of institutional normal Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; upper limit of institutional normal Creatinine within institutional normal limits Sodium =&lt; upper limit of institutional normal Potassium =&lt; upper limit of institutional normal Chloride =&lt; upper limit of institutional normal Bicarbonate =&lt; upper limit of institutional normal Fasting triglycerides =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) Fasting cholesterol =&lt; 1.5 x ULN Participants must agree to discontinue all vitamin supplements while taking study medication and for thirty days past the last dose of study medication Have not been treated with chemotherapy, biological therapy or breast radiotherapy Have never used tamoxifen, raloxifene, or other antiestrogen compounds Have not used exogenous hormone replacement therapy or oral contraception in the year prior to diagnosis Only postmenopausal women and some premenopausal women (as outlined below) will be eligible; should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while participating in this study, she should inform her study physician immediately Women will be considered postmenopausal if one of the following is met: Prior bilateral oophorectomy 60 years of age or older Age less than 60 years; amenorrheic for 12 or more months; and follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) and plasma estradiol in the postmenopausal range Premenopausal women without childbearing potential are eligible to participate if one of the following criteria is met: Prior hysterectomy Prior fallopian tubal ligation (cut, tied, or sealed) Prior placement of permanent intratubal contraceptive devices (e.g. Essure) Premenopausal participants must have a negative pregnancy test within 7 days before starting drug Participants must have the ability to understand, and the willingness to sign, a written informed consent document Participant taking medications that might interact with 9cUAB30 Participant taking lipidlowering agents Participant receiving any other investigational agents within 30days of enrollment nor during study participation Participant with a history of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition of retinoids Participant with an uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements Participant who is breastfeeding or planning to breastfeed for a month post last dose of study agent Participant known to be human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)positive Participant with a history of a second cancer diagnosis or reoccurrence &lt; 5 years from study entry with the exception of a history of squamous or basal cell carcinoma of the skin &lt; 5 years from study entry will not be excluded from this study Participant's core biopsy slides suggest that later resectioning will not contain sufficient tumor to allow for an adequate evaluation of Ki67 and TUNEL assays, at a minimum</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>