<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02876848</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: In women with hormone receptor positive (HR+) breast cancer, adjuvant endocrine therapy (AET) is associated with a significant survival advantage. Nonadherence is a particular challenge in older women, even though they stand to benefit the most from AET. Therefore, a novel e-health tool (OPTIMUM) that integrates real-time analysis of health administrative claims data was developed to provide point-of-care decision support for clinicians.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Novel E-Health Approach in Optimizing Treatment for Seniors (OPTIMUM Study)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objectives: 1) To determine the effectiveness of a patient-specific, real-time e-health alerts delivered at point-of-care in reducing rates of AET discontinuation and to understand patient-level factors related to AET discontinuation. 2) To assess integration of e-health alerts regarding deviations from best practices in administration of AET by cancer care teams. Methods: A prospective, two group controlled comparison pilot study will be conducted at two urban, McGill University-affiliated hospitals, the Royal Victoria Hospital and St. Mary's Hospital. A minimum of 43 patients per study arm will be enrolled through site-level allocation. Follow-up is 1.5 years. Healthcare professionals at the intervention site will have access to the e-health tool which will report to them in real-time: medical events with known associations to AET discontinuation, AET adherence monitor, and a discontinuation alert.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Selective Estrogen Receptor Modulators</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Must be ≥ 65 years old, 2. Have been diagnosed with incident (nonmetastatic) breast cancer, 3. Have a histologicallyconfirmed breast adenocarcinoma, 4. Have undergone breast surgery for stages IIII disease, 5. Have medical insurance with the Régie de l'Assurance Maladie du Québec (RAMQ) for at least 1 year prior to surgery, 6. Have HR positive disease, 7. Have no history of AET use prior to the diagnosis of breast cancer, 8. Expected to initiate AET or have only recently initiated AET (&lt;6 months) but are free of previous discontinuation events, 9. Have the ability to consent for herself. male gender</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Administrative Claims, Healthcare</keyword>
	<keyword>Aromatase Inhibitors</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast Neoplasms</keyword>
	<keyword>Health Services for the Aged</keyword>
	<keyword>Medical Informatics Applications</keyword>
	<keyword>Medication Adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>Outcome and Process Assessment (Health Care)</keyword>
	<keyword>Selective Estrogen Receptor Modulators</keyword>
	<keyword>Telemedicine</keyword>
</DOC>