<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02641860</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluate the safety and efficacy of Allogenic Adipose Tissue-Derived Mesenchymal Progenitor Cells Therapy for Knee Osteoarthritis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trial of Allogenic Adipose Tissue-Derived Mesenchymal Progenitor Cells Therapy for Knee Osteoarthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Phase I, Randomized, Single-centered, Double-blinded Clinical Trial of Allogenic Adipose Tissue-Derived Mesenchymal Progenitor Cells Therapy for Knee Osteoarthritis. This is a randomized,single-blind, double-blinded,phase I clinical trial. Subjects who are with a clinical diagnosis of knee osteoarthritis cartilage defects and will be randomly distributed 1:1:1 to different dosage group after signing the ICF and screening tests.The treatment will accept Allogenic ReJoinTM at the first and fourth week.The duration of the therapy is 48 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Object has an allergic history or is of an allergic constitution. Subjects who understand and sign the consent form for this study. Age: 1870, males and females. Clinical diagnosis of degenerative arthritis by Radiographic Criteria of KellgrenLawrence:Duration of pain over Grade 4(11point numeric scale)&gt; 4 months. Course of Knee osteoarthritis:6 months to 10 years; The VAS score :38 points.(the data acquisition time is to stop using all analgesic at least 3 days ). The subject has an allergic history of medicine or food。. The subject'BMI is over 30. The subject has uncontrolled or hardtocontrol diseases of cardiovascular, liver, kidney or lung， endocrine system. The subject has an history malignant tumour. The subject has complications or diseases of: systemic or rheumatoid arthritis, Chondrocalcinosis articularis， Hemochromatosis，inflammatory arthropathy，avascular necrosis of femoral head，Paget's disease，hemophilic arthropathy，infectional arthritis，Charcot's disease，villonodular synovitis or synovial chondromatosis. The subject has severe generalized infectious diseases or local knee infection in the 3 months prior to this trial. The subject has disease of lower limbs which may be interfered knee evaluation, for example fibromyalgia, osphyalgia, lumbar disc protrusion and so on. The subject has coagulation disorders. The subject has received arthroscopic surgery or intraarticular operations in the 6 months prior to this trial. The subject has received other intraarticular injections for KOA in the 6 months preceding the trial. The subject has received aminoglucose or chondroitin sulfate in the 6 months preceding the trial. The subject has plan of knee prosthesis within the trial. The subject has contraindication of MRI, included but not only: the subject installed heart pacemaker、defibrillator、heart bracket、heart valve prosthesis、metal clip after aneurysm surgery、drug infusion device implanted in vivo、any electronic device implanted in the body（nerve stimulator、bone growth stimulator）、endovascular coil、strainer、ECG monitor、metal suture、shrapnel or sand of body, plate fixation and steel nail after fracture Page 4 of 4 [DRAFT] surgery、artificial limb or joint、audiphone、artificial cochlea、middle ear shift plant、metallic intraocular foreign body etc； claustrophobia、pregnancy within 3 months、critically ill patients. The subject tests positive for: HIV, hepatitis virus, syphilis or other infectious diseases. The subject has history of alcoholism, drug abuse, or mental illness in the 3 years prior to this trial. The subject has participated in any other clinical trial in the 3 months prior to this trial. The subject is pregnant, lactating or planning to conceive within the next 6 months. The subject has any other unsuitable or adverse condition to be determined by the investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>