<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02641067</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the effect of severe renal impairment on the pharmacokinetics of doravirine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Evaluating the Pharmacokinetics of Doravirine in Participants With Severe Renal Impairment (MK-1439-051)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants with renal impairment: is a nonsmoker or moderate smoker has a body mass index (BMI) ≥ 18.5 and ≤ 40.0 kg/m^2 other than renal impairment, participant is judged to be in good health based on medical history, physical examination, vital signs, and laboratory safety tests female informed of the risks of pregnancy, agree not to become pregnant while participating in this study. Female of childbearing potential must either be sexually inactive for 14 days prior to dosing and throughout the study, or uses one acceptable birth control method female of nonchildbearing potential must have undergone sterilization procedures at least 6 months prior to dosing. has baseline estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt; 30 mL/min/1.73m^2 Participants with renal impairment: is mentally or legally incapacitated or has significant emotional problems has a history or presence of clinically significant medical or psychiatric condition or disease has history or presence of alcoholism or drug abuse within the past 2 years has history or presence of hypersensitivity or idiosyncratic reaction to the study drug, any inactive ingredients, or related compounds has history or presence of renal artery stenosis has had a renal transplant or nephrectomy has rapidly fluctuating renal function as determined by historical measurements female is pregnant or lactating has positive results for the urine or saliva drug and urine or breath alcohol screen at screening or checkin has positive results at screening for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), or hepatitis C virus (HCV) is unable to refrain from or anticipates the use of any drug, including prescription and nonprescription medications, herbal remedies, or vitamin supplements beginning 14 days prior to dosing and throughout the study. Certain medications including those to treat kidney disease will be permitted. Other medications may be permitted following consultation with the Sponsor Clinical Monitor. is unable to refrain from or anticipates the use of inducers of cytochrome P450 3A (CYP3A) or permeability glycoprotein (Pgp) transporters for at least 28 days prior to dosing and throughout the study. has been on a diet incompatible with the onstudy diet, within 28 days prior to dosing, and throughout the study has donated blood or had significant blood loss within 56 days prior to dosing has donated plasma within 7 days prior to dosing has participated in another clinical trial within 28 days prior to dosing</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>