<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01117649</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the efficacy of target controlled fluid therapy with a hyper-oncotic balanced HES solution compared to an iso-oncotic HES solution in patients undergoing elective surgery of the pancreatic head. A third group receiving a balanced electrolyte solution (without colloidal volume replacement) will serve as a control for descriptive analysis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Plasma Volume Replacement (PVR) Therapy With Colloid and Crystalloid Solutions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion: patients scheduled to undergo elective surgery of the pancreatic head patients who are willing to give of voluntary consent to participate in the study, following a full explanation of the nature and purpose of the study, by signing the informed consent form approved by the Institutional Ethics Committee (IEC) prior to all evaluations. Exclusion: patients of American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) class &gt; III heart failure defined as New York Heart Association (NYHA) class&gt;2 aneurysm of the ascending and thoracic aorta patients with Zenker's diverticle local oesophageal disease (oesophageal stricture, oesophageal varices, previous oesophageal surgery in past 6 months before study inclusion, pharyngeal pouch) patients receiving haemodialysis patients with known bleeding diatheses any bleeding disorder known from patient's history patients with a haematocrit &lt;= 25% despite preoperative transfusion renal insufficiency (serum creatinine &gt; 130 µmol/l or &gt;1.5 mg/dl) or oliguria or anuria impaired hepatic function defined as Mayo EndStage Liver Disease (MELD) &gt; 10 or liver cirrhosis ChildPugh B or C additional contraindications for investigational products</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>PVR</keyword>
	<keyword>HES 130</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreatic head</keyword>
	<keyword>goal-directed</keyword>
	<keyword>intraoperative PVR in elective surgery of the pancreatic head</keyword>
</DOC>