<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01117857</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the study is to determine if an eight-week intervention with duloxetine significantly reduces depressive symptoms in symptomatic menopausal women. It is hypothesized that an eight-week trial with duloxetine promotes significant improvement in depression symptoms in menopausal women. The secondary aim of the study is to examine if an eight-week intervention with duloxetine significantly reduces vasomotor symptoms in symptomatic menopausal women. It is hypothesized that an eight-week trial with duloxetine promotes significant improvement in vasomotor symptoms in menopausal women.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Duloxetine for Menopausal Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Duloxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women age 40 years old or older Menopausal symptoms of at least 3 months duration, including irregular periods and/or hot flushes Minimum score of 15 on the Hamilton Rating Scale for Depression (17item), Patients will meet criteria for a major depressive episode, verified using the Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI). Subjects will be able to be treated on an outpatient basis, and Subjects will be able to provide written informed consent Subjects presently taking antidepressant medication, Subjects currently using hormone replacement therapy, Other Axis I disorders, except Generalized Anxiety Disorder or Panic Disorder, according to the Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI) "uncontrolled" narrow angle glaucoma known hypersensitivity to duloxetine or any of the inactive ingredients treatment with a monoamine oxidase inhibitor (MAOI) within 14 days of randomization or potential need to use an MAOI during the study or within 5 days of discontinuation of study drug. Presence of psychotic symptoms, History of mania or hypomania, HAMD suicide item score &gt; 3, End stage renal disease or severe renal impairment Abnormal uterine bleeding (heavy or prolonged uterine bleeding, menstrual periods occurring more frequently than every 3 weeks, bleeding after sexual intercourse, spotting between periods) that has not been evaluated by a gynecologist. Subjects with serious or unstable medical illness, including alcohol or substance abuse, cardiovascular, hepatic, respiratory, endocrine, neuralgic, or hematologic disease, history of seizure disorder Subjects taking medications that may interact with duloxetine</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>