<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01102816</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the feasibility, effectiveness and safety of acupuncture for pain management in hemodialysis patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acupuncture for Pain Management of Hemodialysis Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Pain is one of the most common symptoms experienced by end-stage renal disease (ESRD) patients, which subsequently debilitates patient's quality of life. Although reducing pain is crucial to successful patient care in hemodialysis population, symptoms are often undertreated.Conventional pharmacological approaches are limited in dialysis population , given their altered pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamic profiles and increased potential for adverse reactions. Acupuncture has been known to be beneficial in various chronic pain condition. As a non-pharmacologic intervention, it might be valuable for pain management in hemodialysis patients whose analgesic use are limited due to altered pharmacokinetics. However, little is known for the benefits of acupuncture for pain management in dialysis population. This study aims to determine whether acupuncture is a feasible, effective and safe therapeutic intervention for pain management in hemodialysis patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>started hemodialysis at least 3 months ago receiving hemodialysis 3 times a week regularly equilibrated Kt/V ≥ 1.2 pain occurred at least 3 months ago MYMOP2 symptom 1 score ≥ 3 willingness to participate in this study acute/chronic liver disease events of lifethreatening cardiovascular disease within 6 months events of lifethreatening neurological disorder within 6 months current/past history of neoplasm (in past 5 years) hemorrhagic disorder drug abuse/alcoholism other infectious disease history of the use of acupuncture, moxibustion or herbs within 1 month</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>hemodialysis</keyword>
	<keyword>end-stage renal disease</keyword>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>acupuncture</keyword>
</DOC>