<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01102075</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether electroacupuncture is effective on waist circumference in obesity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Electroacupuncture on Obesity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Many studies have reported on the beneficial effects of acupuncture for obesity, although some negative reports also existed.(Wang F. et al. 2008)Recently conducted systematic review of Pittler and Ernst reported that there was insufficient, but not conclusive evidence to support the efficacy of acupuncture and acupressure for weight loss. However, most of these studies had methodological limitation, such as lack of adequate control group or unclear specific effect of electroacupuncture alone because auricular acupuncture was administered as well. In this sudy, we had three-arm randomized controlled trial(with sham control group) to investigate whether electroacupuncture is effective in the treatment of obesity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Waist circumference: Male&gt;= 90 cm, Female &gt;= 85 cm BMI over than 25kg/m2 Secondary obesity caused by endocrine disease, e.g., polycystic ovary syndrome, diabetes mellitus, Cushing's syndrome, hypothyroidism etc. Heart disease,e.g.,arrhythmia, heart failure, myocardial infarction, and patient with pacemaker Hypertension, hyperlipidemia or hypercholesterinemia patients on medication Stroke or otherwise unable to exercise Pregnant or lactating women Childbirth within 6 months Management for weight control within 3 months Any other conditions deemed unsuitable for trial as evaluated by the physicianincharge</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Electroacupuncture</keyword>
	<keyword>Sham electroacupuncture</keyword>
	<keyword>Waist circumference</keyword>
	<keyword>Thickness of subcutaneous fat</keyword>
</DOC>