<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01102959</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The hypothesis of this study focuses on obtaining accurate information on the effectiveness of photographic educational material on orientation of carbohydrate counting for adolescents with diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effectiveness of Photographic Educational Material on Carbohydrate Counting for Adolescents With Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The adolescents with diabetes at the Pediatric Endocrinology and Diabetes outpatient clinic, will be randomly distributed between two groups: those who will receive orientation on carbohydrate counting through photographic educational material and those through a list of foods equivalent. Research will follow 3 steps: First, data will be collected on age, gender, BMI, HbA1C, schooling, type of educational material and parents grade level; answer sheets will be applied to evaluate previous knowledge on carbohydrate counting; orientation will be provided on counting with photo material or list. Second, after a month of using the educational material, a quiz by phone will be conducted with the sole intent to reinforce orientation. Third, two days later, adolescents will be directed to the experimental kitchen to see portions of real food and provide answers on amount or choice of carbohydrate. Statistical tools will be applied to evaluate results.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adolescents with diabetes aged 11 years to 19 years who count carbohydrates in their diet. Adolescents with more than 6 years of study . There is no restriction ethnic, social, gender, nutrition status, type of diabetes. Adolescents with diabetes aged 11 years to 19 years who not count carbohydrate counting in your diet. Adolescents with less than 6 years of study. Adolescents who don't want to participated in this research.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>11 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>EDUCATION</keyword>
	<keyword>DIABETES MELLITUS</keyword>
	<keyword>ADOLESCENT</keyword>
	<keyword>DIABETIC DIET</keyword>
</DOC>