<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01040572</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main aim of this study is to analyze and report traditional, patient-centered, and composite intermediate-term outcomes after laparoscopic revision Roux-en-Y gastric bypass surgery for weight recidivism.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Laparoscopic Revision Gastric Bypass for Weight Recidivism</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There is lack of standardization of primary and revisional bariatric surgery compounded by a scant long-term outcome data. The treatment of inadequate weight loss, weight recidivism, and most severe technical complications after primary bariatric surgery remains refractory to non-operative treatment. Failure rates have been reported up to 20% and 35% for the morbidly obese (MO) and super obese (SO), respectively at 2 to 3 years after surgery. The indication for further surgical intervention remains controversial, as does what type of revisional procedure, both operative and endoscopic, to recommend. Furthermore, there is no standardization of the limb lengths, pouch size or the use of prosthetic reinforcement. Therefore the approach to these patients must be as individualized as their original operations. We formally analyze our experience with all laparoscopic revisional strategies for weigh regain after failed gastric bypass.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obesity, Morbid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients that underwent laparoscopic revisional "RYGB" for failed "RYGB" with weight recidivism or weight regain "WR" pattern failed RYGB with an Inadequate Initial Weight Loss "IIWL" pattern patients with prior major bariatric conversion or esophagogastric surgeries RYGB patients revised by an open surgical approach RYGB patients who underwent laparoscopic revisional RYGB surgery somewhere else and continue their followup care with our program missing records and/or unreachable patients with scant information for analysis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obesity recidivism</keyword>
	<keyword>Weight Regain</keyword>
	<keyword>Weight recidivism</keyword>
	<keyword>Morbidity</keyword>
	<keyword>Complication</keyword>
	<keyword>Late complications</keyword>
	<keyword>Revisional gastric bypass</keyword>
	<keyword>Re-operative gastric bypass</keyword>
	<keyword>Revisional bariatric surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Re-operative bariatric surgery</keyword>
</DOC>