<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01040286</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to assess efficacy and safety of Flurbiprofen Chip versus Chlorhexidine chip (Periochip®) in therapy of adult chronic periodontitis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Efficacy and Safety of Flurbiprofen Chip Versus Chlorhexidine Chip (Periochip®) in Therapy of Adult Chronic Periodontitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Flurbiprofen</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorhexidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorhexidine gluconate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Signed and dated informed consent form 2. Good general health 3. Male or female subjects aged &gt;21 years old 4. Availability for the 9 week duration of the study 5. Chronic periodontal disease on natural teeth characterized by the presence of at least 2 teeth with periodontal pockets of 59 mm in depth (potential target teeth) demonstrating bleeding on probing without involving the apex of the tooth and confirmed by dental Xray. 6. Females of childbearing potential must be nonpregnant and nonlactating at entry and agree to use an adequate method (Oral or parenteral hormonal contraceptive; Intrauterine device; barrier and spermicide) of birth control during the study. 1. An existing aggressive periodontitis. 2. Presence of oral local mechanical factors that could (in the opinion of the investigator) influence the outcome of the study. 3. Presence of orthodontic appliances, or any removable appliances, that impinge on the tissues being assessed. 4. Soft or hard tissue tumours of the oral cavity. 5. Presence of dental implant adjacent to target tooth. 6. Presence of more than 2 adjacent periodontal pockets on the same potential target tooth. 7. Periodontal pockets of more than 9 mm in depth, and/or with class 2 or 3 furcation involvement, on the potential target tooth. 8. Systemic antibiotic therapy or periodontal/mechanical/local delivery therapy within 6 weeks prior to study entry and throughout the study duration. 9. History of allergy to chlorhexidine, flurbiprofen or to other nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs). 10. Subjects taking Phenytoin, calcium channel blockers drugs (CCBs) and/or cyclosporine, which might influence the pattern of tissue response. 11. Subjects treated with nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) within 14 days prior to entry into the study and throughout the study duration. 12. Presence of the following conditions: Type 1 diabetes, major recurrent aphtae, stomatitis, abscesses and related oral pathologies. 13. The presence of any medical or psychiatric condition that in the opinion of the investigator could affect the successful participation of the subject in the study. 14. Subject participates in any other clinical study 30 days prior to the start of the study and throughout the study duration. 15. Subject uses chlorhexidine oral rinses/ mouthwashes on a regular basis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Subjects, age&gt;21, with Chronic periodontal disease on natural teeth characterized by the presence of at least 2 teeth with periodontal</keyword>
	<keyword>pockets of 5-9 mm in depth demonstrating bleeding on probing without involving the</keyword>
	<keyword>apex of the tooth and confirmed by dental X-ray.</keyword>
</DOC>