<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02665845</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The role of steroids in the treatment of severe ulcerative colitis (UC) exacerbation is well established and recommended by professional societies. Similarly, 5-aminosalycilates (5-ASA) agents in the form of mesalamine/mesalzine are well established proven therapy in mild-moderate UC, and the combination of oral 5-ASA with topical (per-rectal enema) 5-ASA was shown to be superior to oral 5ASA alone in patients with mild moderate UC. Thus, in most cases, when a patient with UC experiences a flare while taking 5-ASA therapy, treatment is usually optimized by maximizing the oral dose to 4gr/day and adding topical therapy until the flare is controlled. If this is unhelpful, or if the flare is severe to begin with, corticosteroids are usually prescribed. However, there are very scarce data comparing steroids versus 5-ASA in the treatment of severe UC exacerbation. The aim of this study is to compare the efficacy of steroids alone vs. combination of steroids + 5-ASA in the treatment of moderate-severe UC exacerbation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combination Corticosteroids+5-aminosalicylic Acids Compared to Corticosteroids Alone (for Ulcerative Colitis).</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The role of steroids in the treatment of severe ulcerative colitis (UC) exacerbation is well established and recommended by professional societies. This recommendation is based on pivotal studies carried 50-60 years ago, by Truelove &amp;Witts. Similarly, 5-aminosalycilates (5-ASA) agents in the form of mesalamine/mesalzine are well established proven therapy in mild-moderate UC, and the combination of oral 5-ASA with topical (per-rectal enema) 5-ASA was shown to be superior to oral 5ASA alone in patients with mild moderate UC. Thus, in most cases, when a patient with UC experiences a flare while taking 5-ASA therapy, treatment is usually optimized by maximizing the oral dose to 4gr/day and adding topical therapy until the flare is controlled. If this is unhelpful, or if the flare is severe to begin with, corticosteroids are usually prescribed. However, there are very scarce data comparing steroids versus 5-ASA in the treatment of severe UC exacerbation. In 1962 truelove et al compared topical and systemic corticosteroid therapy with sulphasalazine, and found steroids to be superior to sulfasalazine. Importantly, there are no data investigating whether the addition and/or continuation of 5-ASA agents as combination therapy with systemic corticosteroids is superior to corticosteroids alone in patients with moderate-severe active UC. This knowledge gap is pronounced in patients admitted to the hospital for intravenous corticosteroid treatment with moderate severe UC flare, in whom it is currently unknown if the addition of 5-ASA (Oral and/or topical) to corticosteroids will confer additional benefit and improve patients outcomes. Thus, in practical terms, the decision whether to stop or continue 5-ASA treatment or whether to add 5-ASA to steroids in the treatment of moderate-severe UC exacerbation is taken on an arbitrary basis. This is important shortcoming and knowledge gap in current medicine, as patients admitted with moderate-severe UC flare who do not respond to corticosteroids and require salvage therapy with infliximab, cyclosporine, or even urgent colectomy. This makes it prudent to explore any avenue for possible improvement of response to corticosteroids in this setting, for instance by addition of 5ASA. The aim of this study is: To compare the efficacy of steroids alone vs. combination of steroids + 5-ASA in the treatment of moderate- severe UC exacerbation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aminosalicylic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mesalamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>UC known and diagnosed by established clinicalendoscopic and histological criteria or newlydiagnosed UC, based on clinical and endoscopic findings, and about to start treatment with corticosteroids. Current hospitalization with Severe UC exacerbation as defined by a Lichtiger score of &gt;10 Age &gt;18 Has not been on oral systemic corticosteroids more than 14 days prior to hospitalization If taking a thiopurine, the dose need to be stable for the last 2 months before admission Pregnant women Allergy / unable to take prednisone / hydrocortisone/ 5ASA. Active infection either enteric or elsewhere Severe renal, liver or cardio respiratory comorbidity Toxic megacolon, or clinical features suggestive of a need for imminent colectomy Treatment with an antiTNF within the prior 3 months Prior treatment with cyclosporine or tacrolimus within the prior 3 months Alcohol dependency Unable or unwilling to provide informed consent Participating in other clinical trial within the 2 months prior to admission</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>