<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03035669</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present study will investigate the effects of a mindfulness training on emotion regulation and social cognition, using several psychological, behavioral, psychophysiological and neuroimaging methods.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Mindfulness Training on Emotion Regulation and Social Cognition.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of the present study is to evaluate the impact of a mindfulness intervention, particularly the mindfulness-based stress reduction (MBSR), on the capacities of emotion regulation and social cognition, in caring/helping professions which are vulnerable to stress. In the context of a longitudinal intervention study, a randomized controlled trial, the efficacy of the MBSR to increase the capacity for self-emotion regulation, empathic attunement, and compassion capacities will be measured. For doing this, several psychological, behavioral, psychophysiological and neuroimaging brain measurements will be used.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stress, Psychological</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy volunteers: Men or women Righthanded Normal or correctedtonormal visión German as a first language No history of neurological or psychiatric problems, or use of controlled medication that might interfere with emotion or attention. No symptoms of claustrophobia Written informed consent form to participate in the study and neuroimaging experiment. Chemical dependence, including nicotine and alcohol Dementia or psychotic condition. Depression or use of antidepressants Pregnant or breastfeeding women Prior MBSR class or regularly practicing mindfulness meditation (or yoga) for three or more months. Noncontrolled severe medical disease that might interfere with the performance of the study, such as neoplasias, cardiopathies, digestive pathologies, diabetes mellitus type I or type II Neoplasias in the central nervous system Tremor or dystonia in cephalic segment that hinders the performance of the MRI study (tremor equal to or higher than 3 in each corporal segment, according to the UPDRS scale) Fulfillment of any criterion of contraindication for the MRI exam (for instance, metallic implants, claustrophobia, pregnancy, use of pacemaker; intracranial aneurism clip; cochlear implants). Presence of odontological devices that might disturb the magnetic field or any sources of variation of the magnetic susceptibility Any other conditions the investigator might deem problematic for the inclusion of the volunteer in a trial of this nature will also be considered.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>