<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03035721</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study aimed to evaluate the tolerance and safety of a low-protein formula in healthy full-term infants by investigating effects on growth and gastrointestinal tolerance and by identifying any adverse effects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Evaluation of a Low Protein Content Formula in the First Months of Life: a RCT</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Infants were randomized to receive either a standard protein formula or a low-protein formula. The composition of the low-protein formula vs the standard formula was: energy (65 vs. 68 kcal/100 mL), protein (1.2 vs. 1.7 g/100 mL). To investigate the safety of the low-protein formula without any bias, a 4-month intervention period was selected during which the infants were fed only formula. Anthropometric parameters (weight, length, and head circumference) and body composition were assessed at enrollment, at 2 and 4 months' of age. Parents were asked to keep a diary on the occurrence of gastrointestinal symptoms or any other symptoms and were contacted every two weeks either by clinic visits or phone calls. The reference group was constituted by a cohort of healthy, exclusively breastfed, full-term infants.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Nutrition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Infant Nutrition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>healthy singleton fullterm infants (gestational age 37/0 to 41/6 weeks) birth weight adequate for gestational age (&gt;p10 and &lt;p90 for gestational age) according to the World Health Organization growth charts. presence of congenital diseases presence of chromosomal abnormalities presence of conditions that could interfere with growth, such as brain, metabolic, cardiac and gastrointestinal diseases, perinatal infections. being born to mother affected by endocrine and/or metabolic diseases having a family history of allergic disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>3 Weeks</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Full term healthy infants</keyword>
	<keyword>Low protein content formula</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Growth</keyword>
	<keyword>Body composition</keyword>
</DOC>