<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01248091</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Increasing accessibility of long-acting reversible contraceptive methods, like intrauterine devices (IUDs), is an important strategy to reduce the risk of unintended pregnancy. Unfortunately, fear of IUD insertion in women who have not had children is common among health care providers and women alike, and this limits IUD use. To increase acceptance of this highly effective contraceptive, there is need to investigate novel, low cost, easily applied and accessible techniques to improve the insertion experience. This is a pilot study to evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of nitroprusside gel applied intracervically as an intervention to improve the IUD insertion experience for both patient and provider.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Nitroprusside on Intrauterine Device (IUD) Insertion</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Subjects who are have already scheduled an IUD insertion will be asked to join this study assessing whether or not nitroprusside gel helps with IUD insertion process. Only healthy, nulliparous women between the ages of 18 and 45 will be recruited. Nulliparous women report much more pain associated with IUD insertion than parous women so the possibility of being able to measure the effect of nitroprusside vs placebo is more likely. The primary outcome, pain with IUD insertion, and the secondary outcomes, such as satisfaction and provider ease of IUD insertion, will be compared between the study groups as well.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pelvic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neck Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nitroprusside</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age 1845, Generally Healthy. requesting LNGIUS for contraception as the primary indication previous pregnancy beyond 20 weeks, previous IUD placement or attempted placement, allergy to nitroprusside, history of migraines, history of heart disease.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>IUD, Insertion, Decrease, Pain</keyword>
</DOC>