<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01248637</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study involves the administration of a hypoxia marker, pimonidazole hydrochloride, taken orally approximately 24 hours before surgical resection of a pancreatic tumor in order to identify areas of lower oxygen content on tumor samples.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Intratumoral Hypoxia Using Pre-operative Administration of Pimonidazole</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Intratumoral hypoxia (low oxygen concentration or pO2) occurs when oxygen consumption exceeds its delivery by the vascular system. Hypoxia is associated with adverse patient outcome in many human cancers and this association is hypothesized to be due to a combination of treatment resistance and aggressive tumor biology. The study of hypoxia is also important as new cancer drugs are being developed that are specifically active on cancer cells in area of tumors with lower oxygen levels. his study involves administering the hypoxia probe pimonidazole hydrochloride to patients prior to resection of pancreatic adenocarcinoma to evaluate the extent, molecular context and clinical relevance of hypoxia in clinical pancreatic cancer samples and the subsequently derived primary xenograft tumors. We propose accrual of patients over a 5-year period to evaluate hypoxia within 100 clinical tumor specimens and corresponding primary xenograft tumours where available. The complementary techniques of wide-field multicolor fluorescence image analysis microscopy and high level flow cytometry will be used to identify potential relationships between intratumoral hypoxia and cell proliferation, differentiation, and the expression of putative cancer stem cell markers.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anoxia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age &gt; 18 provisional diagnosis of pancreatic cancer scheduled resection at UHN consented to ICGC Pancreatic Cancer Genome Project surgery planned for &gt;2 days away (drug administration has to be 1620hrs before surgery) not participating in ICGC contraindications to pimonidazole (allergy) surgery scheduled for same or next day (not enough time to arrange for drug administration)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>pancreas</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreatic cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>pancreatic tumor</keyword>
	<keyword>pimonidazole</keyword>
	<keyword>hypoxia</keyword>
	<keyword>whipple's resection</keyword>
</DOC>