<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01248832</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study tested the effects of telephone counseling for smokers from three Asian language speaking groups: Chinese, Korean, and Vietnamese. The specific aims were to: 1) test the efficacy of a culturally appropriate counseling protocol for smokers calling the California Smokers' Helpline on the Chinese, Korean and Vietnamese lines, 2) examine whether intervention effects varied by cognitive and behavioral predictors of cessation success, 4) examine whether family involvement plays a role in quitting success, and 5) assess differences in counseling effect across the three ethnic groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Smokers' Quitline for Asian Language Speakers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Asian Americans are among the least studied groups in smoking research, which has created a knowledge gap in understanding their behavior and in developing methods to help them quit. No efficacy data have been reported for telephone counseling of smokers who prefer to use Asian languages, although telephone intervention holds promise for these groups because of its convenience and its potential to reach large numbers of smokers. In this two-arm design subjects are stratified by language (Chinese, Korean, and Vietnamese) and randomized to telephone counseling (plus materials) or self-help materials only, which serves as the control. The study is significant in several ways. First, it provides timely information on a cessation approach for a traditionally under-served population (Asian language speakers). Second, effective telephone counseling can be widely applied because of the proliferation of quitlines with centralized services in recent years. Third, by targeting Asian language speakers this study addresses the issue of ethnic disparities, which has been identified by many (including the NCI Bypass Budget) as a research priority.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1875 years old, daily smoker, ready to quit within one month, first time caller, valid phone number, valid address, California (CA) resident, gave consent to participate in study and evaluation, called the Chinese, Korean or Vietnamese line used other form of tobacco, major medical or psychiatric complication (e.g. lung cancer, major depressive disorder, antipsychotic medicine, recent stroke, impending surgery)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>tobacco cessation</keyword>
	<keyword>smoking cessation</keyword>
	<keyword>telephone</keyword>
	<keyword>self-help</keyword>
	<keyword>smoking abstinence</keyword>
	<keyword>tobacco use disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>disparity</keyword>
</DOC>