<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01248845</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Exploration of the effects on diaphragmatic electrical activity (EMG) and on respiratory pattern of various level of assistance delivered by the ventilator in intubated spontaneously breathing patients in pressure support (PS) and in Neurally Adjusted Ventilatory Assist (NAVA) by step by step increasing of the level of assistance. Flow, airway pressure, transesophageal EMG signal and transcutaneous EMG signal will be recorded.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparative Effects on Diaphragmatic Electrical Activity and Respiratory Pattern of Various Levels of Assistance</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Exploration of the effects on diaphragmatic electrical activity (EMG) and on respiratory pattern of various level of assistance delivered by the ventilator in intubated spontaneously breathing patients in pressure support (PS) and in Neurally Adjusted Ventilatory Assist (NAVA) by step by step increasing of the level of assistance. Flow, airway pressure, transesophageal EMG signal and transcutaneous EMG signal will be recorded. Aims of the study: 1. To study the electrical diaphragmatic signal variations and the ventilatory profile variations under various level of assistance (delivered by the ventilator) in PS and in NAVA in intubated spontaneously breathing patients 2. To compare a non invasive technique of diaphragmatic electrical activity recording under various levels of assistance with the invasive reference technique</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients admitted to the ICU, intubated for acute respiratory failure, and ventilated in PS mode will be eligible for inclusion in the study. Severe hypoxemia requiring an FIO2 &gt; 0.5 hemodynamic instability (defined as the need for high doses of catecholamines namely ≥ 0.5 μg/kg min and/or high need in volume resuscitation namely more than two litres of crystalloids in two hours) oesophageal problem such as hiatal hernia, oesophageal varicosities, oesophageal surgery; active upper gastrointestinal bleeding; known coagulation disorder; any other contraindication to the insertion of a nasogastric tube; poor short term prognosis (death expected within the next seven days) age &lt; 18 years old.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Mechanical ventilation</keyword>
	<keyword>Electrical diaphragmatic activity</keyword>
</DOC>