<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02150356</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Very few studies have evaluated the effect of aleurone-enriched grains on cardiovascular risk factors. Price et al.(2010) have shown that 4-week supplementation of aleurone-enriched products (27 g/day of aleurone) increased betaine concentration in plasma whereas reduced homocysteine and LDL-cholesterol levels. Interestingly, aleurone had no effect on total antioxidant status or endothelial function, whereas an improvement of C-reactive protein was observed (Price RK et al, 2012). It is not known whether consumption of more than 27g/day of aleurone-enriched products with higher ferulic acid biodisponibility and longer time of treatment could influence these parameters in individuals with metabolic syndrome. Noteworthy, no studies have investigated the effect of aleurone-enriched products on fasting and postprandial glycemic homeostasis and lipid metabolism. In addition, mechanisms by which aleurone may act in vivo are still unknown. The aim of this study is to investigate whether 8 weeks supplementation with aleurone-enriched products may influence glucose and lipid metabolism, incretin hormones levels, satiety, inflammation, oxidative stress and endothelial function in overweight/obese subjects with high cardiovascular risk.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Aleurone-enriched Products on Cardiovascular Risk Factors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Overweight/obese subjects of both gender Age range between 20 and 70 years High cardiovascular and metabolic risk profile will be enrolled in the study Waist circumference &gt; 102 cm for men, and &gt; 88 cm for women At least one of the characteristics of the metabolic syndrome according to the NCEP/ATP III criteria: Fasting triglycerides ≥150 mg/dl Highdensity lipoprotein cholesterol &lt;40 mg/dl (men)/&lt;50 mg/dl (women) Blood pressure ≥ 130/85 mmHg Fasting glucose ≥100 mg/dl Age &lt;20 and &gt;70 years Fasting triglycerides ≥400 mg/dl Fasting cholesterol &gt;270 mg/dl Cardiovascular events (myocardial infarction or stroke) during the 6 months prior to the study; established diabetes mellitus or any chronic disease Renal and liver failure (creatinine &gt;1.7 mg/dl and ALT/AST &gt;2 times than normal values, respectively) Anaemia (Hb &lt;12 g /dl) Any chronic disease People treated with antihypertensive drugs will have to keep the type and dosage of medication unchanged during the whole study period</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>