<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02749617</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot study will investigate the impact of dexamethasone (DEX) on anti-Xa levels in participants taking apixaban 2.5 mg twice a day by mouth (PO BID). Investigators propose a prospective, cohort study of 24 participants with multiple myeloma, in whom a lenalidomide-dexamethasone (LEN-DEX)-based myeloma treatment regimen is indicated. Eligible participants will initiate thromboprophylaxis with apixaban prior to starting their DEX-containing regimen and continue until the end of cycle 3. Anti-Xa levels, D-Dimer and plasma drug concentration will be measured. This pilot study looks to investigate this potential interaction between apixaban and dexamethasone to see if it warrants further investigation in a larger study. The sample size of 24 provides 90% power to detect a primary outcome of ≥ 50% reduction in peak anti-Xa levels from baseline. Secondary outcomes include changes in plasma apixaban levels, D-dimer, and symptomatic venous thromboembolism (VTE) and bleeding during a 3-month treatment period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pilot Study Investigating Apixaban and Dexamethasone InterAction in Multiple Myeloma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Apixaban</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with diagnosis of multiple myeloma according to criteria of the International Myeloma Working Group Patients in whom a LENDEXbased treatment regimen is indicated Adult patients ≥ 19 years of age who are able to freely provide informed consent Concomitant antiplatelet or anticoagulant use Calculated creatinine clearance &lt; 30 mL/min by CockcroftGault formula Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt; 3 times upper limit of normal (ULN) Total bilirubin &gt; 2 x ULN Thrombocytopenia &lt; 50 x 10 gigalitres (Gl) High bleeding risk or spontaneously prolonged prothrombin time or activated partial thromboplastin time &gt; 1.5 x ULN Body weight &lt;50 or &gt;120 kg Concomitant use of CYP3A4 or pglycoprotein inducers or inhibitors Use of Ginkgo biloba or St. John's Wort within 14 days before first dose of study drug Dexamethasone use within last 3 months Women of Childbearing potential without proper contraceptive measures, pregnancy or breast feeding Life expectancy less than 3 months Inability to swallow or issues with malabsorption Any other medical, social, logistical, geographical or psychological factors, which in the opinion of the investigator, would prohibit followup, compliance and study completion</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>