<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02749825</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research study looks at Testosterone levels in patients receiving Trelstar versus those receiving Lupron or Zoladex. These drugs have been approved for treatment of Prostate Cancer by the FDA.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Trelstar Versus Lupron or Zoladex in Advanced Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients who are currently receiving Lupron or Zoladex will be consented and then randomized to receive either continued treatment with the drug they have been on, or will be randomized to Trelstar for a period of 3 months. At the end of that period, testosterone and prostate serum antigen (PSA) levels will be drawn and compared to their previous levels to determine if Trelstar is as effective as the previous treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leuprolide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Goserelin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Triptorelin Pamoate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Advanced Prostate Cancer Currently taking Lupron or Zoladex Stable PSA Baseline testosterone below castration level Life expectancy &gt; 6 months Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of 02 Signed, approved informed consent. Known hypersensitivity to any leuteinizing hormone releasing hormone (LHRH) agonist Ongoing therapy with hyperprolactinemic agents Antiandrogen therapy within 28 days prior to study start Prior Orchiectomy, hypophysectomy or adrenalectomy Chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or prostatectomy within 28 days prior to study start Use of any investigational agent 3 months prior to enrollment Use of systemic corticosteroids within 28 days or during study Other malignancies within 2 yrs prior to study start, except curatively treated skin cancers Severe kidney or liver failure, based on adequate lab values Other medical conditions which would be likely to interfere with compliance or completion of study requirements</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Prostate</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Trelstar</keyword>
</DOC>