<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02410538</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The intervention consists of the delivery of a list of 21 questions to the relative of each patient admitted in ICU, intubated and mechanically ventilated during the first 48 hours of the stay. A formal interview is scheduled for relatives at Day 3 of inclusion. The information comprehension at Day 5 (± 1) will be compared between families that received the list of "FAQ" and families that received information as usual (without providing the list of FAQ</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Frequently Asked Questions for ICU Patients' Families</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Half of the families of ICU patients do not understand the information provided by doctors and nurses. Receiving clear, loyal and appropriate information is one of their main expectations. We have previously reported that relatives had difficulty asking questions that allow them to improve their understanding regarding ICU issues. In a preliminary study, we developed a list of questions considered as important by families, ICU doctors and nurses. The aim of this prospective, randomized and controlled trial is to test the effectiveness of a list of frequently asked questions to relatives of ICU patients on their understanding of the provided information. The intervention consists of the delivery of a list of 21 questions to the relative of each patient admitted in intensive care, intubated and mechanically ventilated in the first 48 hours of ICU stay. A formal interview is scheduled for relatives at Day 3 of inclusion. The information comprehension at Day 5 (± 1) will be compared between families that received the list of "FAQ" and families that received information as usual (without providing the list of FAQ).</detailed_description>
	<criteria>The subjects that will be included are relatives of patients. The patients must be 1. Adults 2. Receiving invasive mechanical ventilation 3. Intubated in the first 48 hours of ICU admission 4. For an expected duration of mechanical ventilation &gt; 48 hours 5. With a life expectancy of at least 5 days and a SAPS 2 at baseline &lt; 75 6. Who received a visit within 24 hours after intubation. Only one relative will be included. person unable to read French</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>