<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02410369</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this clinical study, the investigators evaluate the efficacy and safety of S-588410 in patients who underwent an adjuvant chemotherapy after the complete resection of non-small-cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of S-588410 After Adjuvant Chemotherapy for Completely Resected Non-small- Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this phase II trial, the investigators evaluate the efficacy and safety of S-588410 containing oncoantigens-derived HLA-A*2402-restricted epitope peptides in patients with HLA-A*2402 who underwent an adjuvant chemotherapy after the complete resection of non-small-cell lung cancer.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients who received platinumbased adjuvant chemotherapy after the complete resection of lung cancer. 2. Pathologically determined nonsmallcell lung cancer excepting the large cell neuroendocrine carcinoma and mixed type. 3. Patients with HLAA*24:02. 4. Neither recurrence nor metastasis of nonsmallcell lung cancer demonstrated by imaging tests within 6 weeks prior to the registration. 5. Possible to receive S588410 within 12 weeks after the last adjuvant chemotherapy. 6. ECOG performance status 0 or 1 within 2 weeks prior to the registration. 7. Age over 20 years at time of consent acquisition. 8. The written informed consent provided by the patient. 1. Other malignant diseases requiring treatment, excepting the cured cancer insitu. 2. Concurrent treatment with anticancer drug, steroids, immunosuppressive agent, radiotherapy, immunotherapy, hyperthermia, or surgery. 3. Active and uncontrolled infectious disease. 4. Severe hepatic dysfunction, kidney dysfunction, cardiac disease, pulmonary disease, hematological disorder, or metabolic disease. 5. Coronary artery stenting within 6 months prior to registration. 6. Autoimmune disease. 7. HIV infection. 8. Registration within 4 weeks after the last adjuvant chemotherapy. 9. Laboratory values defined in the protocol within 2 weeks prior to registration. 10. Residual uncontrolled adverse events by adjuvant chemotherapy. 11. Eosinophilia within 28 days prior to registration. Past or active eosinophilic pneumonia or interstitial pneumonitis. 12. Past history of severe allergic reaction against drug, vaccine and biological agents. 13. Female patient in nursing or pregnancy. 14. Refusal of pregnancy conception. 15. Treated with the same peptide vaccines as S588410. 16. Treated with another investigational drug within 28 days prior to registration or the period of 5 times of the drug halflife. 17. Decision of nonenrollment of the patients by principal investigator or physicianincharge from the view point of patient's safety.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>