<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02747303</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective is to to compare 2 mm vs 0 mm PTV margins with respect to local PFS and risk of radionecrosis when treating intact brain metastases with LINAC-based frameless SRS</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Clinical Relevance of Margins in Frameless Stereotactic Radiosurgery for Intact Brain Metastases: a Randomized Trial of 0 vs 2 mm Margins</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVE The primary objective is to evaluate the non-inferiority of frameless LINAC-based SRS using 0 mm GTV to PTV margins (experimental arm) compared to 2 mm GTV to PTV margins (standard arm) in local PFS at 6 months in the treatment of intact brain metastases. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES To evaluate the superiority of frameless LINAC-based SRS using 0 mm margins compared to 2 mm margins in reducing rates of radiation necrosis and pseudoprogression. EXPLORATIVE OBJECTIVES - To compare rates of local PFS at 1 year and 2 years - To compare rates of local failure at 6 months, 1 year and 2 years - To compare rates of OS at 6 months, 1 year and 2 years - To compare rates of acute (within 90 days of SRS) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v5.0 central nervous system (CNS) Grade 2+ and Grade 3+ toxicities. - To compare rates of late (greater than 90 days from SRS) CTCAE v5.0 CNS Grade 2+ and Grade 3+ toxicities. - To compare rates of distant intracranial failure. - To compare rates of salvage therapy for any intracranial failure. - To determine association between V10Gy and V12Gy all tissue, whole brain and normal brain parameters and risk of radionecrosis or pseudoprogression.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Second Primary</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>i. Adult patients (≥ 18 years old) with an ECOG Performance Status 02 and a life expectancy of 3 months or more. ii. Histologically confirmed systemic malignancy with gadolinium contrastenhanced MRI scan demonstrating 15 intraparenchymal brain metastases. iii. Wellcircumscribed, measureable intraparenchymal brain lesion(s) with maximum tumor diameter ≤3.0 cm. If multiple lesions are present, the other(s) must not exceed 3.0 cm in maximum diameter. At least one lesion must be ≥1.0 cm in maximum diameter and ≥0.5 cm in a perpendicular diameter to be considered measurable disease. iv. Negative urine or serum pregnancy test done ≤ 14 days prior to SRS, for women of childbearing potential only. v. Ability to understand and willingness to sign a written informed consent document. i. Diagnosis of germ cell tumor, small cell carcinoma or hematologic malignancy. ii. Metastases in the brain stem, midbrain, pons, medulla, or within 7 mm of the optic apparatus (optic nerves, chiasm and optic tracts). iii. Diagnosis of leptomeningeal disease. iv. Prior history of radiation therapy involving the brain. v. Chemotherapy (including oral agents and targeted agents) or immunotherapy given within 14 days of SRS. Hormonal therapy is permitted. For Her2+ breast cancer patients, antiHer2 therapy cannot be given within 14 days of SRS. Patients who are scheduled to receive trastuzumab emtansine after SRS cannot be enrolled. vi. Contraindications to gadolinium contrastenhanced MRI (eg, noncompatible pacemaker, eGFR&lt;30, gadolinium allergy).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>brain metastases</keyword>
	<keyword>Stereotactic Radiosurgery</keyword>
</DOC>