<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02747550</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study was to evaluate the efficacy and safety of the temporary simultaneous two-arterial occlusions (TESTO) on operative blood loss during laparoscopic myomectomy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Temporary Simultaneous Two-arterial Occlusions During Laparoscopic Myomectomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Significant hemorrhage is major perioperative concern in myomectomy, and can result in need of blood transfusion, conversion to hysterectomy, development of hypovolemic shock and postoperative anemia, and delayed recovery. Therefore, methods to decrease operative blood loss during myomectomy in women wishing to preserve their uterus and fertility are important and must be developed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Methyltestosterone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone 17 beta-cypionate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone enanthate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone undecanoate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>women with symptomatic myomas such as menorrhagia, pelvic pressure/pain, or infertility women who were planning to undergo laparoscopic myomectomy women who had ≤ 4 myomas, with the largest myoma ≤ 10 cm women with regular menstrual bleeding (defined as cycle length between 21 and 45 days) women who were not pregnant at the surgery women between 19 and 45 years of age. women who underwent concomitant complex surgical procedures at the time of laparoscopic myomectomy, such as severe adhesiolysis or resection for severe endometriosis women who were in postmenopausal or climacteric status women with a history of oophorectomy or salpingooophorectomy women with any suggestion of malignant uterine or adnexal diseases women with major medical comorbidities or psychiatric illnesses, which could affect followup and/or compliance women who refused to participate or give consent to the procedures</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>