<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01574131</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to learn the following: whether long-term treatment (6 months) with fenofibrate will decrease burn related sugar and fat increased in the blood and help prevent muscle loss and improve wound healing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Acute and Long-Term Outcome Investigations of Fenofibrate on Severely Burned Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Following severe burn injury in human patients the mitochondrial fat oxygenation capacity is decreased in muscle. This is associated with a corresponding progression in the severity of the resistance to the action of insulin on glucose disposal and protein synthesis and breakdown in muscle, regenerating wound and liver. Fatty acids or their active intracellular products ( e.g. DAG, acyl- Coenzyme A(CoA) or acylcarnitine) are the direct inhibitors of insulin action, rather than tissue triglycerides(TG) itself. In other words, impaired mitochondrial fatty acid oxygenation is the mechanism that causes altered lipid metabolism that ultimately contributes to insulin resistance. Accumulation of active fatty acid products, such as DAG, acyl-CoA or acylcarnitine esters in muscle cells is due to the rate of uptake of plasma free fatty acids(FFA) exceeding the rate of oxygenation within muscle due principally to a reduced capacity of mitochondria to oxidize fatty acids. Decreasing insulin sensitivity in muscle is related to impaired insulin signaling. This will be reflected by increased activity of protein kinase C (PKC). Because PKC is thought to exert its regulatory effect primarily on either tyrosine kinase activity on the insulin receptor or downstream kinase insulin receptor substrate (IRS) phosphorylation, these elements of the insulin signaling cascade will be decreased. In turn, elements of insulin signaling related to the response of muscle glucose (PI3 Kinase) and protein (P70S6k)metabolism will be reduced. The investigators propose that increased tissue PKC activity will be associated with increased tissue concentration of DAG, acyl-CoA or acylcarnitine. The investigators hypothesize that the treatment of patients with the peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor (PPAR) alpha antagonist fenofibrate will improve mitochondrial capacity to oxidize fatty acids. Insulin sensitivity in muscle, skin and liver in terms of both glucose and protein metabolism will be improved by fenofibrate treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fenofibrate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>≥40% Burn ages 420years body weight ≥10kg &lt;40% burn ages &lt;4&gt;20 years body weight &lt;10kg Respiratory insufficiency Multiple fractures History of cancer in last 5 years Bilirubin&gt;3mg/dL Serum Creatinine&gt;3mg/dL after fluid resuscitation GlutamylOxaloacetic Transaminase(GOT) &gt;40 Units/L GlutamylPyruvate Transminase(GPT) &gt;51 Units/L Associated head injuries requiring therapy Associated injuries to the chest or abdomen requiring surgery Receipt of any experimental drug other than the ones supplied within two months of study Any metal in body including rods, neurofibrilators, pacemaker, etc Orthopedic casting which would prevent placement in MRI Hepatitis Abnormal EKG Electrical burns</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>20 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Burn</keyword>
	<keyword>Fenofibrate</keyword>
	<keyword>PPAR alpha agonist</keyword>
	<keyword>insulin sensitivity</keyword>
	<keyword>mitochondrial</keyword>
</DOC>