<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02533063</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This proposed prospective study will evaluate whether a novel exercise approach, seated vibration therapy, can improve function in the target population of older adults. Therefore, the primary aim of this pilot is to examine the effect of vibration therapy on muscle function (balance, muscle power and strength) and muscle mass.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Semi-Recumbent Vibration Therapy in Older Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>There are four study visits; screening/baseline followed by eight weeks of training three times a week, visit 1 at eight weeks followed by 4 weeks of washout, Visit 2 at 12 weeks followed by eight weeks of training three times a week, and a final Visit 3 at 20 weeks. At the screening visit, volunteers will be asked to perform tests included in the short physical performance battery (SPPB) (gait speed, chair rise, balance). If the participants score is ≤ 9 or ≤ 2 in any of the three tests included in the SPPB they will be eligible for the intervention phase. At the baseline visit several questionnaires will be obtained and participants then will proceed with muscle function tests (SPPB, jumping mechanography, grip strength, timed-up-and-go test). Participants will then be randomized into one of two groups. The first group will receive vibration + loading treatment for the first 8 weeks, the second group will receive sham treatment (loading only). After 8 weeks both groups will go through a 4 week wash-out period and then crossover will occur. The first group will now receive sham treatment (loading only) while the second group will receive vibration + loading treatment. The participants will train for 10 minutes, 3 times a week, during the active 16 total weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcopenia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Men and women age ≥ 70 years 2. Able and willing to sign informed consent 3. Able to stand without assistance 4. Able and willing to train for 10 minutes, 3 times per week 5. Total SPPB score of ≤ 9 or ≤ 2 in any of the three tests included in the SPPB 1. Cognitive impairment to the degree that it limits the ability of signing informed consent 2. Unable to sit upright for 10 minutes 3. History of injury or surgery within the prior six months which limits the ability to ambulate 4. Major illness that might cause missed training sessions or visits.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>70 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>