<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02312414</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Anemia is a common disorder in CKD patients. It is largely attributed to decreased erythropoietin (EPO) production and iron deficiency. Therefore, besides EPO, therapy includes iron replenishment. However, the latter induces oxidative stress. Haptoglobin (Hp) protein is the main line of defense against the oxidative effects of Hemoglobin/Iron. There are 3 genotypes: 1-1, 2-1 and 2-2. Hp 2-2 protein is inferior to Hp 1-1 as antioxidant. So far, there is no evidence whether haptoglobin genotype affects iron-induced oxidative stress in CKD patients. In this proposed study we wished to examine whether Hp genotype influences intravenous iron administration (IVIR)-induced oxidative stress in CKD patients, and its impact on the response of these patients to L-Carnitine therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Carnitine on Oxidative Stress to IVIR Administration to CKD Patients:Impact of Haptoglobin Genotype</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will include at least 25 anemic CKD patients (stages 3-4) that will be given a weekly IVIR (Sodium ferric gluconate, [125 mg/100 ml] for 8 weeks, and during weeks 5-8 also received Carnitine (20mg/kg, IV) prior to IVIR. Weekly blood samples will drawn before and after each IVIR for Hp genotype, C-reactive protein (CRP), advanced oxidative protein products (AOPP), neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin (NGAL), besides complete blood count and biochemical analyses.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ferric gluconate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients that have been diagnosed as suffering from chronic kidney diseases at stages 34 and confirmed by MDRD. 2. CKD patients with Hb of less than 10 g%. 3. At age ≥18 y. 1. Pregnant women. 2. Patient with CKD stage 5 on Dialysis. 3. Patients with severe liver diseases. 4. Patients with severe CHF. 5. Intercurrent illness such as fever. 6. Allergic rhinitis.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>