<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02312401</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to better understand prostate cancer changes after radiation treatment, through magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). MRI is an imaging test that allows doctors to see prostate gland without any operation procedures. It can help identifying the tumors in the prostate. For patients with newly diagnosed prostate cancer, MRI may help doctors manage treatment better and sooner.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Treatment Response Using Multiparametric MRI After Prostate Radiotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Patients with biopsy proven (completed and/or reviewed at MSK) adenocarcinoma of the prostate, who will undergo external beam radiotherapy using conventional fractionation IGRT, low rate brachytherapy alone, low dose rate brachytherapy combined with IGRT, SBRT, or proton radiotherapy. Age ≥ 18 years old Baseline MPMRI, which is obtained at MSKCC Main Campus on the 3Tesla Philips MRI unit as part of the standard (clinical) staging assessment demonstrates at least one dominant or visible lesion which measures &gt; 0.5 cm in maximum axial diameter as assessed on T2weighted images. No prior history of androgen deprivation therapy within the last month. However patients who will receive neoadjuvant and concurrent and adjuvant hormonal therapy will be eligible. Willing to come to MSK Main Campus for baseline and followup MPMRIs. History of radical prostatectomy Patients who are unwilling or unable to undergo MRI including patients with contraindications to MRI such as the presence of cardiac pacemakers or noncompatible intracranial vascular clips, claustrophobia, inability to lie flat for the duration of the study etc. Patients with a metallic hip implant, metallic implant or device in the pelvis or ferromagnetic fiducial beacons (Calypso) that might distort local magnetic field and compromise quality of MPMRI Patients in which gadolinium contrast is contraindicated. Metastatic disease</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>14-172</keyword>
</DOC>