<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00340132</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Pima Indians of Arizona have the highest prevalence and incidence of type 2 diabetes of any population in the world. Prospective analyses in this population have identified insulin resistance and a defect in early insulin secretion as risk factors for the development of the disease. A recent longitudinal analysis which tracked the development of diabetes in 17 Pima Indians demonstrated that both insulin action and early insulin secretion deteriorate as individuals progress from normal to impaired glucose tolerance and then to diabetes. These results suggest that both inherent (apparent in normal glucose tolerant subjects who progress to diabetes and likely to have a genetic basis) and acquired (evident as individuals progress from NGT to IGT to diabetes and possibly environmental in origin) defects in insulin action and secretion contribute to the pathogenesis of type 2 diabetes. To identify the genetic and environmental determinants of diabetes we plan to study Pima Indian families to determine: (1) if there are genes that segregate with metabolic risk factors for diabetes which might therefore be genetic markers for type 2 diabetes and (2) the mechanisms mediating genetic and environmental determinants of insulin resistance and impaired insulin secretion. Volunteers for this study will be admitted to the clinical research ward where they will undergo several tests to determine body composition, oral and intravenous glucose tolerance and in vivo insulin action. In addition, in selected subjects, adipose and/or skeletal muscle tissue will be obtained by percutaneous biopsy for in vitro studies of gene expression and insulin action in these tissues. A transformed lymphocyte cell line will be established for each subject as a permanent source of DNA for genetic studies. Genetic markers for type 2 diabetes and insulin resistance will be sought by typing each individual at positional and functional candidate loci in the hopes of finding an association between these loci and obesity, insulin secretion, insulin resistance and/or type 2 diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cross-Sectional and Longitudinal Studies of "Pre-Diabetes" in the Pima Indians</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Insulin resistance and a defect in early insulin secretion are risk factors for the development of type 2 diabetes mellitus. A recent longitudinal analysis which tracked the development of diabetes demonstrated that both insulin action and early insulin secretion deteriorate as individuals progress from normal to impaired glucose tolerance and then to diabetes. These results suggest that both inherent (apparent in normal glucose tolerant subjects who progress to diabetes and likely to have a genetic basis) and acquired (evident as individuals progress from NGT to IGT to diabetes and possibly environmental in origin) defects in insulin action and secretion contribute to the pathogenesis of type 2 diabetes. To identify the genetic and environmental determinants of diabetes we are continuing to determine: (1) if there are genes that segregate with metabolic risk factors for diabetes which might therefore be genetic markers for type 2 diabetes and (2) the mechanisms mediating genetic and environmental determinants of insulin resistance and impaired insulin secretion. &lt;TAB&gt; Volunteers for this study will be admitted to the clinical research ward where they will undergo several tests to determine body composition, oral and intravenous glucose tolerance and in vivo insulin action. In addition, in selected subjects, adipose and/or skeletal muscle tissue will be obtained by percutaneous biopsy for in vitro studies of gene expression and insulin action in these tissues. A transformed lymphocyte cell line will be established for each subject as a permanent source of DNA for genetic studies. Genetic markers for type 2 diabetes and insulin resistance will be sought by typing each individual at positional and functional candidate loci in the hopes of finding an association between these loci and obesity, insulin secretion, insulin resistance and/or type 2 diabetes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prediabetic State</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucose Intolerance</mesh_term>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Volunteers from all racial and ethnic backgrounds will be invited to participate if they are: Ages: 18 55 years old Gender: male or female. Each subject who volunteers will be assigned to the clinical research ward physician who made the initial contact and he/she will be responsible for completion of all tests (see below) and compilation of data. This physician will consult with the subject's personal physician or other health care personnel involved with the patient in Sacaton. This includes sending a carefully written discharge summary to appropriate health care workers at the time of discharge. All medications and alcohol consumption are to be stopped for two weeks prior to admission. A urine drugscreening test for drugs such as narcotics, marijuana, and barbiturates will be performed on everyone to exclude from the study people whose urine show active or recent drug use. A positive drug test could confound the results of the study in an unpredictable manner. The results of this test will become a part of the patient s medical records and may be released if requested (please see page 6 of the consent for details regarding medical records release). EXCLUSION CRITERIA: Subjects will be excluded who are on chronic medications for problems such as seizure disorders. Exclusions for occasional medications will be at the discretion of the interviewing physician. Women who are currently breastfeeding will be excluded from the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 16, 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-Insulin Dependent Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin Resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin Secretion</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucose Tolerance</keyword>
	<keyword>Adipose Tissue</keyword>
	<keyword>Preadipocytes</keyword>
</DOC>