<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01322646</DOC>
	<brief_summary>There is clear, converging evidence from multiple prospective studies with well-diagnosed adolescents with ADHD and comparison, non-ADHD adolescents, that teen drivers with ADHD have more accidents and other adverse driving outcomes. Available research indicates parental monitoring and limit-setting for adolescent drivers is one of the most effective interventions for preventing negative driving outcomes. For children with ADHD, interventions to promote parenting capacity to effectively oversee and intervene in teen driving will likely need to be intensive and require multiple treatment components. The present proposal aims to compare the standard care for teen drivers (driver's education classes and driving practice) to the Supporting a Teen's Effective Entry to the Roadway (STEER) program, that includes a parent-teen intervention, adolescent skill building, parent training on effective adolescent management strategies, joint parent-teen negotiations sessions, practice on a driving simulator, parental monitoring of objective driving behaviors, and the targeting of safe teen driving via contingency management strategies (i.e., parent-teen contracts). To facilitate teen and parent engagement the intervention will be preceded by a motivational interview. The specific aims of the proposal are to investigate the efficacy of the STEER program relative to a standard care group in a randomized clinical trial (N=172) on measures of objective driving outcome and parenting capacity. It is hypothesized that the STEER program will result in improved outcomes relative to the standard care group at the end of intervention and 6 and 12 month follow-up assessments.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomized Trial of Interventions for Teenage Drivers With Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical Diagnosis of ADHD, Combined Type At least 16 years old Has a driving Permit No parent willing to be involved Seizure disorder, eating disorder, psychotic disorder, current diagnosis of substance/alcohol dependence Prior Driver's education class</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>ADHD</keyword>
	<keyword>Driving</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavior modification</keyword>
</DOC>