<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01322594</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Phase I study to evaluate the safety and tolerability of single ascending intravenous doses of MEDI2338 in subjects with stable, mild to moderate chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety of MEDI2338 in Subjects With Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged ≥ 40 years at time of screening. Females of nonchildbearing potential defined as surgically sterile or at least 2 years postmenopausal. Males, unless surgically sterile, must use 2 highly effective methods of birth control from screening through end of trial. A diagnosis of mild to moderate COPD. Cigarette smoking history of ≥10 pack years. Ability to understand and comply with protocol requirements, instructions and restrictions. COPD symptoms adequately controlled on a therapeutic regimen that has not changed in the 4 weeks prior to screening. Current diagnosis of any respiratory condition other than COPD. Active or history of any disease or condition that would, in the opinion of the investigator and/or medical monitor, place the subject at an unacceptable risk to participate in this study. History of or suspected history of alcohol misuse or recreational substance abuse. Treatment with oral or IV corticosteroids within 8 weeks prior to screening. Concurrent enrolment in another clinical study. Receipt of any investigational drug therapy of use of any biologicals within 6 months prior to screening. Known history of allergy or reaction to any component of the investigational product.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
</DOC>