<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00662857</DOC>
	<brief_summary>28 subjects to be enrolled for a screening period, 3 dosing visits &amp; a follow-up visit. Visits 2 and 3 dosing of TI Inhalation Powder, cross over between two 15 U cartridges and one 30 U cartridge. Visit 4 dosing will be a sc injection of 10 IU of RAA (rapid-acting insulin analogue).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Designed to Compare 2 Dose Strengths of TI Inhalation Powder in Adults With Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus and to Compare One of Those Formulations (30Units) With an Injection of Insulin Lispro</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>28 eligible subjects were planned to be enrolled to determine bioequivalence and safety parameters of two 15 U TI Inhalation Powder cartridges versus one 30 U TI Inhalation Powder cartridge, according to a randomized, 2-way crossover design. Additionally, bioavailability of one 30 U TI Inhalation Powder cartridge to a single subcutaneous injection of 10 IU of RAA will be compared.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Lispro</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and Females &gt; 18 and &lt; 60 years of age Clinical diagnosis of type 1 diabetes mellitus with stable antidiabetic regimen for at least 90 days prior to Screening BMI of &lt; 30 kg/m2 Nonsmokers (never smoked or former smokers (&gt; 6 months since cessation) Pulmonary Function Testing (FEV1 &gt; 70%, FEV1/FVC &gt; 70%, TLC &gt; 80% DLco [unc] &gt; 70% of Predicted Written Informed consent Two or more severe hypoglycemic episodes within 6 months of Screening/Visit 1 Severe complications of diabetes Previous exposure to any inhaled insulin product other than TI inhalation Powder or similar formulation Inability to perform PFT maneuvers meeting recommended American Thoracic Society (ATS) standards of acceptability and repeatability criteria Respiratory tract infection within 8 weeks prior to Screening/Visit 1 History of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), clinically proven asthma, and/or any other clinically important pulmonary disease (eg. Obstructive sleep apnea), confirmed by pulmonary function testing, and/or radiologic findings Major organ system diseases including seizures, heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, cancer within the past 5 years, liver disease, anemia or autoimmune disorder Clinically significant abnormalities on screening laboratory evaluation Female subjects who are pregnant, lactating, or planning to become pregnant during the clinical trial period or not practicing adequate birth control Unable and/or unlikely to comprehend how to use the investigational device in this study or to follow study instructions</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetic adult male, diabetic adult female</keyword>
</DOC>