<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00662038</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label, multi-center, extension study for patients with IPF who complete a qualifying InterMune clinical trial of pirfenidone. The purpose of this study is to obtain additional safety data for pirfenidone 2403 mg/day in patients with IPF who complete a qualifying InterMune clinical trial of pirfenidone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-Label Study of the Long Term Safety of Pirfenidone in Patients With Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis (IPF)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-label, multi-center, extension study for patients with IPF who complete a qualifying InterMune clinical trial of pirfenidone. Eligible patients must complete the final visit for their qualifying study, have not permanently discontinued study drug in their qualifying study, and meet all of the eligibility criteria noted in this protocol. Since data from the qualifying study may remain blinded during patient enrollment in PIPF-012, all patients will be treated as if they were taking placebo in their qualifying study. At the start of PIPF-012 participation, each patient will escalate the dose of pirfenidone. The duration of treatment for each patient will vary and will continue until pirfenidone is commercially or otherwise available in his/her geographic region or the study is terminated by the sponsor for reasons outlined in the protocol.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Idiopathic Interstitial Pneumonias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pirfenidone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Completes the qualifying clinical study final visit In the opinion of the principal investigator (PI), has been generally compliant with study requirements during the qualifying study, or must be considered eligible to enroll in PIPF012 by the InterMune medical monitor Is able to provide informed consent and comply with the requirements of the study Is pregnant or lactating Has known hypersensitivity to any of the components of the study drug Starts participation in another interventional clinical trial between the end of participation in the qualifying InterMune clinical trial and entry into PIPF012 Receives concomitant and/or excluded medications as defined in the protocol Permanently discontinues study drug during the qualifying study for any reason before study completion</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>84 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>idiopathic</keyword>
	<keyword>pulmonary</keyword>
	<keyword>fibrosis</keyword>
</DOC>