<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT01822483</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>The purpose study investigate mycophenolic acid exposure area curve renal transplant recipient treat mycophenolate mofetil conversion mycophenolate sodium .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Prospective Study Investigate Mycophenolic Acid ( MPA ) Exposure Through Area Under Curve ( AUC ) Renal Transplants Recipients Treated With Mycophenolate Mofetil ( MMF ) After Conversion Mycophenolate Sodium ( EC-MPS )</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A grow body evidence show mycophenolate acid ( MPA ) exposure assessment dosage adjustment necessary patient treat mycophenolate mofetil ( MMF ) , still limited information dose-exposure-effect relationship enteric-coated mycophenolate sodium ( EC-MPS ) formulation quite different physicochemical property ( TETT et al. , 2011 ) . Pharmacokinetically guide exposure-controlled area concentration-time curve ( AUC ) approach helpful limit interpatient variability MPA exposure improve clinical outcome organ transplant recipient ( TETT et al. , 2011 ) . MPA area concentration-time curve value 30 60 μg h/mL early post-transplant period reduces risk acute rejection seem appropriate renal allograft recipient take mycophenolate sodium ( MPS ) calcineurin inhibitor ( GRINYÓ et al. , 2009 ; SOMMERER et al. , 2010 ) . Among benefit therapeutic drug monitoring MPA evaluation interaction MPA proton pump inhibitor association donor-specific antibody reduction .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Calcineurin Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 year time screening ; Subjects sixth month post renal transplant ; Subjects receive mycophenolate mofetil ; Women childbearing potential ( CBP ) negative pregnancy test screening ( urine serum ) ; Women CBP men sexual partner CBP must agree use medically acceptable method contraception throughout study . Subjects , opinion investigator , able complete study ; Recipients multiple organ transplant ( i.e. , prior concurrent transplantation nonrenal allograft ; Use investigational drug treatment 4 week enrollment ; Subjects calculate GFR &lt; 30ml/min ( abbreviate MDRD formula ) ; Subjects screen total white blood cell count ( WBC ) ≤ 2000/mm3 , hemoglobin ≤ 10g/dL platelet count ≤ 100000/mm3 ; TGO/AST , TGP/ALT bilirubin value three time high reference value ; History malignancy within 3 year enrollment adequately treat basal cell squamous cell carcinoma skin ; Subjects know human immunodeficiency virus ( HIV ) , hepatitis B hepatitis C ; Chronic hepatic failure ; Planned treatment immunosuppressive therapy describe protocol ; Recipients require desensitization protocol .</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Renal transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>mycophenolic acid</keyword>
	<keyword>mycophenolate mofetil</keyword>
	<keyword>mycophenolate sodium</keyword>
	<keyword>area curve</keyword>
</DOC>