<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02003547</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Single Centre, Placebo-Controlled, Double-Masked, Sequential Designed Study to Evaluate 3 Ophthalmic Formulations of AMA0076 in Healthy Subjects</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Single Centre Study to Evaluate 3 Ophthalmic Formulations in Healthy Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Each subject will receive the following treatments: - Period 1: Formulation A (n = 14) or placebo (n = 7) twice daily for 7 days - Period 2: Formulation B (n = 14) or placebo (n = 7) twice daily for 7 days - Period 3: Formulation C (n = 14) or placebo (n = 7) twice daily for 7 days There will be a minimum washout of 7 days between each treatment period (last dose of previous period to first dose of subsequent period</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ocular Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eye Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy males and nonpregnant, nonlactating females, aged 35 to 65 years. Body mass index of ≤35kg/m2. IOP between 15 and 24 mmHg (inclusive) in both eyes at Screening Visits 1 and 2. Women of childbearing potential who have a positive pregnancy test. Any subject deemed by the investigator to have uncontrolled systemic hypertension Use of systemic, inhaled or ocular corticosteroid treatment within 90 days of screening or likely to require their use during the study period. Any screening laboratory abnormality that, in either the investigator's or the medical monitor's judgment, is considered to be clinically significant or a safety risk. History of any clinically significant disease or disorder which, in the opinion of the investigator, may either put the subject at risk because of participation in the study, or influence the results of the subject's ability to participate in the study, or interfere with interpretation of the subject's study results. Participation in any other clinical study within 1 month of screening or during the study. Receipt of another investigational drug within 90 days of dosing in this study Diagnosis of any form of glaucoma. IOP &gt;24 mmHg in either eye at any screening visit. Use of any ocular drops (including lubricating drops/artificial tears) during screening period or need for ocular drops during duration of study participation. In the opinion of the investigator, clinically significant eye trauma within 6 months of screening. Any intraocular ophthalmic procedure within 6 months of screening. Any ocular inflammation within 90 days of screening or a history of recurrent uveitis in either eye. Subjects with any known ocular disease and who are under care of a hospital ophthalmologist. Any condition preventing valid applanation tonometry measurement. Unable to discontinue contact lens wear during the study Visual acuity (VA) worse than 20/80 in either eye Subjects who are study site employees, or immediate family members of a study site or sponsor employee. History of any drug or alcohol abuse in the past 2 years. Regular alcohol consumption. Positive drugs of abuse test result. Positive hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), hepatitis C virus antibody (HCV Ab) or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) results Serious adverse reaction or serious hypersensitivity to any drug or the formulation excipients Presence or history of clinically significant allergy requiring treatment, as judged by the investigator. Hayfever is allowed unless it is active.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>