<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01282151</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is: - A multicenter, prospective, randomized, phase 3 trial. - To prove non-inferiority of Taxotere/Cisplatin compared to Pemetrexed/Cisplatin as a front line treatment of patients with non-squamous cell lung cancer. - 276 patients will be recruited.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>TaxoteRe Plus Cisplatin Versus AlImta Plus Cisplatin in 1st Line Non-squamous Cell Type Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Docetaxel is being used in 60mg/m2 3 weekly dosage in Japan and several east Asian institutions. Docetaxel 60mg/m2 and Cisplatin 70 mg/m3 3 weekly regimen will be compared to Pemetrexed 500mg/m2 and Cisplatin 70 mg/m2 3 weekly regimen in first line NSCLC with non-squamous histology.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt;= 18 years old ECOG performance status 02 Nonsquamous cell type nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC) Stage IV, Stage IIIB cannot be treated with curative intent or Relapsed after surgery or radiation therapy No prior chemotherapy except adjuvant chemotherapy and concurrent chemoradiation treatment. The last dose of adjuvant chemotherapy should be at least 6 months earlier from randomization, and the regimen should not contain docetaxel or pemetrexed. No prior immunotherapy, biologic therapy Measurable lesion with Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1 Hemoglobin &gt;=9.0g/dl, Platelet &gt;=100,000/uL, neutrophil &gt;=1,500 /uL Creatinine &lt;=1.5 x upper normal limit or creatinine clearance &gt;=60 mL/min Bilirubin &lt;=1.5 x upper normal limit, Transaminases &lt;=2 x upper normal limit Alkaline phosphatase &lt;=2 x upper normal limit Written informed consent Pregnancy, Lactating woman Woman in child bearing age who refuses to do pregnancy test Moderate or greater than grade 1 motor or sensory neurotoxicity Hypersensitivity to taxane Comorbidity or poor medical conditions Other malignancy (except cured basal cell carcinoma or uterine cervical carcinoma in situ) Concurrent treatment with other investigational drugs within 30 days before randomization Active treatment with other anticancer chemotherapy EGFR mutation (exon 19 deletion, L858R, L861Q, G719A/C/S)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
	<keyword>Non Squamous cell</keyword>
	<keyword>Docetaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>Pemetrexed</keyword>
</DOC>