<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02839018</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Little is known about nutritional Parameters that potentially influence the course of intensive-care unit acquired weakness (ICU - AW). The investigators aim to elucidate the nutritional profiles in blood, urine and muscle in respective patients at risk.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nutrient Pattern Analysis in Critically Ill Patients (NAChO)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Critical Illness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Muscle Weakness</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paresis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥18 years Written informed consent obtained from the patient's legal representative and later from the patients (as soon as possible) Individuals diagnosed with severe head trauma or intracerebral hemorrhage ("central nervous system group") or with severe sepsis/ septic shock ("Sepsis group") at any time from ICU admission until day 5 (i.e. day of screening) Patient on the ICU for ≥ 5 days ("ICU long stayer") Language other than German or French Institutionalized Individuals (e.g. prisoners, severe preexisting mental incapacity) Patients with known preexisting neurological or psychiatric disease that will make informed consent likely impossible Patients with known pregnancy or known to be lactating will not be included to the investigation. Due to the observational/ diagnostical nature of the study, a pregnancy test will not be performed. Patients on extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO) Clinical signs of preexisting malnutrition (Body mass index &lt;18) Preexisting evidence for history of anorexia or bulimia Parenteral nutrition received within last 5 days (for more than 12 hours) or evidence for parental nutrition needed within next 7 days Terminal disease (i.e. life expectancy &lt;14 days) Patients with active malignancy Patients on biologicals interfering with metabolism (e.g. infliximab) Patients on chronic steroid medication (i.e. prednisone equivalent dose &gt;10mg/day) Patients on neuromuscular blocking agents on a regular basis (i.e. on a repetitive basis within last 48 hours or evidence for need within next 7 days) At screening (day 5): prescribed caloric intake substantially higher (i.e. &gt; 150% of caloric need of indirect calorimetry) than indirect calorimetric results (in intubated patients) or i.e. standardofcare (25 Kcal/kg body weight/day) Severe adipositas defined as BMI &gt;40 Known preexisting allergy to standard enteral formulae Subject previously enrolled to an interventional trial that is not considered standardofcare (e.g. investigation of new medication/drug or medical devices)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>