<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02839265</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Based on promising data from our laboratory demonstrating synergy between ablative local radiotherapy and FLT3 ligand immunotherapy in murine NSCLC models, investigators are performing a phase II study combining FLT3L immunotherapy and SBRT for patients with advanced NSCLC that has progressed following standard systemic therapy. All patients will receive daily subcutaneous injections of CDX-301 (75 µg/kg) for 5 days, beginning on the first day of SBRT. SBRT will be delivered to a single pulmonary lesion. Depending on the size and location of the target lesion, the SBRT regimen will be 34 Gy x 1 (peripheral tumors smaller than 2 cm and not adjacent to the chest wall), 18 Gy x 3 (peripheral tumors not eligible for 34 Gy x 1), or 10 Gy x 5 (central tumors). The primary endpoint will be progression-free survival at 4 months, defined using immune-related response criteria (irRC). A total of 29 patients will be enrolled.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>FLT3 Ligand Immunotherapy and Stereotactic Radiotherapy for Advanced Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary Objective - To explore the efficacy of combining stereotactic body radiotherapy (SBRT) with FLT3 ligand immunotherapy for advanced non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). Secondary Objectives - To establish the feasibility and safety of combining SBRT with FLT3 ligand immunotherapy for advanced NSCLC. - To quantify and evaluate potential surrogate outcomes for clinical efficacy of this treatment approach, including radiographic responses, immunologic responses, and circulating tumor cell levels.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Flt3 ligand protein</mesh_term>
	<criteria>AJCC stage 3 or 4 histologically proven NSCLC not amenable to curative therapy Age &gt;= 18 years Prior treatment with at least one standard chemotherapy regimen or targeted agent prior to enrollment Radiological assessment within 21 days prior to study entry demonstrating measurable disease that includes at least one pulmonary lesion . 1 cm in greatest dimension that would be amenable to SBRT and at least one measurable lesion that would be outside of the SBRT treatment fields History/physical examination within 30 days prior to registration ECOG performance status 02 Signed, written informed consent Less than 21 days between registration and the last receipt of chemotherapy, biotherapy, immunotherapy, radiotherapy (excluding palliative radiotherapy), or major surgery. Prior receipt of immunomodulatory therapy (eg: nivolumab) is permitted, as long as there has been a 21 day washout period following the most recent treatment. Untreated central nervous system metastases. Patients with a history of brain metastases must have had no CNSdirected therapy within the past 60 days and radiological assessment within 30 days of study entry demonstrating a lack of progressive CNS disease Ongoing or recent (within 21 days prior to study entry) use of high dose oral corticosteroids (.2 mg of dexamethasone daily or equivalent). Intranasal and/or inhaled corticosteroid use is permitted. Any unresolved CTCAE grade &gt;2 toxicity from previous anticancer therapy. Patients with irreversible toxicity that is not reasonably expected to be exacerbated by study therapy (eg, hearing loss)may be enrolled after discussion with the principal investigators. History of allogeneic organ transplant or autoimmune disease Active malignancy, other than NSCLC, for which systemic therapy is indicated. History of adequately treated local basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, cervical carcinoma in situ, superficial bladder cancer, asymptomatic prostate cancer without known metastatic disease and with no requirement for therapy asides from hormonal therapy, adequately treated stage 1 or 2 cancer currently in complete remission, or any other cancer that has been in complete remission for &gt;= 5 years is permitted. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situation that would limit compliance with study requirements as judged by the treating physicians The following laboratory results, within 10 days of first study drug administration: Hemoglobin . 9.0 g/dL, Absolute neutrophil count . 1.5 x 109/L, Platelet count . 100 x 109/L Serum creatinine . 1.5 x ULN and creatinine clearance (by CockcroftGault formula) &lt; 60 mL/min Women of child bearing potential: positive pregnancy test (serum)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>