<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02731690</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label multi center study to evaluate the safety of Aceneuramic Acid Extended Release (Ace-ER) Tablets for patients with GNE Myopathy.The primary objective of this Phase 2 study is to evaluate the safety of open-label 6 g/day Ace-ER in GNEM subjects with severe ambulatory impairment. The study will also assess efficacy to ensure that the full spectrum of patients with GNEM are evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety of Aceneuramic Acid Extended Release (Ace-ER) Tablets in GNE Myopathy (GNEM) (Also Known as Hereditary Inclusion Body Myopathy (HIBM)) Patients With Severe Ambulatory Impairment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>GNEM (or HIBM), is a rare, severely debilitating disease of adult onset myopathy and progressive muscle weakness caused by a defect in the biosynthetic pathway for sialic acid (SA). Substrate replacement is a potential therapeutic strategy based on the success of replacing reduced SA and the resulting reduction of muscle disease in a relevant mouse model of the human disease. The primary objective of this Phase 2 study is to evaluate the safety of open-label 6 g/day Ace-ER in GNEM subjects with severe ambulatory impairment. The study will also assess efficacy to ensure that the full spectrum of patients with GNEM are evaluated.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Muscular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Distal Myopathies</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female, aged ≥ 18 years old Willing and able to provide written, signed informed consent after the nature of the study has been explained, and before any researchrelated procedures are conducted Have a documented diagnosis of GNEM, HIBM, distal myopathy with rimmed vacuoles (DMRV), or Nonaka disease due to previously demonstrated mutations in the gene encoding the GNE/MNK enzyme (genotyping will not be conducted in this study). Should meet the criteria for severe ambulatory impairment defined below: Unable to rise from a seated position to standing without help from another person, assistive device(s), stationary object, or other support AND Unable to walk without the assistance of another person OR if able to walk (use of assistive device(s) permitted), requires at least 2 minutes to walk 40 meters (one full lap of the 6MWT course) AND Use of wheelchair or scooter for activities outside of the home or unable to leave the home independently Willing and able to comply with all study procedures Participants of child‐bearing potential or with partners of childbearing potential who have not undergone a bilateral salpingo‐oophorectomy and are sexually active must consent to use highly effective method of contraception as determined by the site investigator (i.e. oral hormonal contraceptives, patch hormonal contraceptives, vaginal ring, intrauterine device, physical doublebarrier methods, surgical hysterectomy, vasectomy, tubal ligation or true abstinence (when this is in line with the preferred and usual lifestyle of the subject) which means not having sex because the subject chooses not to), from the period following the signing of the informed consent through 30 days after last dose of study drug Females of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test at Screening and be willing to have additional pregnancy tests during the study. Females considered not of childbearing potential include those who have been in menopause for at least two years, have had tubal ligation at least one year prior to Screening, or who have had a total hysterectomy or bilateral salpingooophorectomy Ingestion of NacetylDmannosamine (ManNAc), SA, or related metabolites; intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG); or anything that can be metabolized to produce SA in the body within 60 days prior to the Screening Visit Prior participation in a clinical trial involving treatment with AceER/placebo and/or Sialic Acid immediate release (SAIR) in the past year Has had any hypersensitivity to SA or its excipients that, in the judgment of the investigator, places the subject at increased risk for adverse effects Has serum transaminase (i.e. aspartate aminotransferase [AST] or gammaglutamyl transpeptidase [GGT]) levels greater than 3X the upper limit of normal (ULN) for age/gender, or serum creatinine of greater than 2X ULN at Screening Pregnant or breastfeeding at Screening or planning to become pregnant (self or partner) at any time during the study Use of any investigational product or investigational medical device within 30 days prior to Screening, or anticipated requirement for any investigational agent prior to completion of all scheduled study assessments Has a condition of such severity and acuity, in the opinion of the investigator, that it warrants immediate surgical intervention or other treatment or may not allow safe participation in the study Has a concurrent disease, active suicidal ideation, or other condition that, in the view of the investigator, places the subject at high risk of poor treatment compliance or of not completing the study, or would interfere with study participation or would affect safety</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>GNE Myopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>Nonaka</keyword>
	<keyword>GNEM</keyword>
	<keyword>Hereditary Inclusion Body Myopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>HIBM</keyword>
	<keyword>DMRV</keyword>
	<keyword>QSM</keyword>
</DOC>