<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02126267</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Evaluate and compare the effectiveness in a clinical and microbial perspective one stage full-mouth disinfection technique in relation to scaling and root planing per quadrant associated with chlorhexidine or azithromycin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Techniques for Scaling and Root Planing and One Stage Full Mouth Disinfection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Seventy -seven systemically healthy subjects with chronic periodontitis were randomly included in 6 different predefined groups. The following periodontal parameters were evaluated: probing depth , clinical attachment level , plaque index, gingival index and percentage of areas affected by periodontal disease. Microbiologically were evaluated the bacterial load and specific load of five bacterias: The quantification of the bacteria was performed by real-time Polymerase Chain Reaction . The clinical and microbial baseline evaluations were performed ( periodontal pre- therapy) , 90 and 180 days after treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Periodontitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Periodontal Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gingival Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorhexidine gluconate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chlorhexidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of slightmoderate chronic periodontitis Those who were making regular use of antibiotics or antiinflammatory drugs or had done up to three months before the beginning of the study; those who were making regular use (twice a day) of oral rinses with chlorhexidine or essential oils or have made regular use within three months prior to study entry; individuals with a history of sensitivity to chlorhexidine or azithromycin; subjects undergoing periodontal therapy include dental scaling procedures in the 12 months preceding the start of the study; subjects with impaired bifurcation or trifurcation class III; who required antibiotic prophylaxis for conducting clinical periodontal examination subjects with removable partial dentures and removable or fixed orthodontic appliance.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>periodontal disease</keyword>
	<keyword>therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>anti-bacterial agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized Controlled Trials</keyword>
</DOC>