<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02126605</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Even though there is growing interest in and use of trained Diabetes Alert Dogs (DADs) as a way to monitor blood glucose in type 1 diabetes (T1D), no scientific studies have confirmed the ability of DADs to accurately detect extreme high and low blood sugar. The current project is the first preliminary investigation into the accuracy of DADs, using scientifically rigorous research methods similar to those required to demonstrate accuracy in blood glucose meters. The primary aim of the project is to test the hypotheses that DADs are accurate at detecting extreme blood sugar levels in adults and children with T1D. The proposed project has several other secondary aims, which include determining: 1) the glycemic thresholds and time course for hypo- and hyperglycemic DAD alerts, 2) the degree to which alert accuracy is consistent across different DADs, and 3) whether or not DAD owners appear to experience better psychosocial status and quality of life compared to other individuals with T1D.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Accuracy of Blood Glucose Detection by Diabetes Alert Dogs</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In the proposed project, DAD alerts will be compared to blood glucose (BG) readings from a continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) device, as well as a BG meter. CGM, BG meter, and DAD alert data will be collected over a 4-wk period. CGM devices will be "blinded" so that BG readings will not be shown. This will allow for a direct comparison between objective glucose readings generated by approved BG monitoring devices and DAD alerts. This study will also utilize two methods for measuring DAD alerts: (1) use of the event recorder mechanism of the CGM device, and (2) collection of more detailed and qualitative data on DAD alerts using diaries (Daily DAD Diaries) to collect information concerning the occurrence, timing, and type of DAD alerts.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The participant must have had type 1 diabetes for at least 1 year and been taking insulin since diagnosis The participant must have a DAD placed in their home for a minimum of 6 months. Participants must not currently be using a continuous glucose monitor (CGM) in their diabetes management. Participants must be capable of performing all tasks involved in the study protocol, including filling out questionnaires and diaries in English. Participants must have an internetconnected computer compatible with study software. Willingness to avoid consumption of acetaminophencontaining products for the duration of the study. Pregnant womenself reported Current use of a CGM History of a systemic deep tissue infection with methicillinresistant staph aureus or Candida albicans</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>diabetes alert dogs</keyword>
	<keyword>hypoglycemia</keyword>
</DOC>