<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02126163</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Excessive alcohol use is associated with a range of serious and costly health, social, and economic consequences at the individual and societal level. This program of research serves as a venue by which to produce and test an innovative, science-based, and cost-effective means to intervene in a private, convenient, and individualized way with employed adults who report non-dependent levels of risky drinking. Responsible Drinking offers computer-tailored intervention sessions directed at increasing readiness to limit drinking to national guidelines for low-risk drinking and a complementary dynamic web portal providing additional information, activities, and strategies designed to activate and reinforce the change process. The primary objective is to complete and enhance the development of Responsible Drinking and test it in an effectiveness trial. In Phase II the program capabilities and innovation will expand to integrate the e-Health components (CTI and e-Workbook) with m-Health (mobile health) technologies. The e-Health components will be enhanced to offer a more interactive and engaging user experience. In addition, m-Health technologies (text messaging and mobile device browsing optimization) will be integrated to support engagement in the program and flexible delivery options. 996 employed adults will be recruited to participate in the randomized trial. The treatment group will receive three intervention sessions during the course of six months and group differences on a number of outcomes will be evaluated at 12 and 18 month follow-up assessments.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Promoting Responsible Drinking: An Internet-based, Interactive Computer Tailored Intervention</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Polydipsia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. English speaking 2. 21 years of age or older 3. not enrolled fulltime in college 4. employed part or full time 5. not pregnant 6. consumed alcohol in the past 30 days 7. exceeded the NIAAA genderspecific lowrisk drinking guidelines in the last 30 days 8. not currently interested in or ever having received treatment for substance abuse or dependence 9. not ever having received a physician recommendation to avoid or reduce alcohol use 10. scoring 9 or less on the Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test (AUDITC).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Excessive Drinking</keyword>
	<keyword>Hazardous Drinking</keyword>
</DOC>