<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02617888</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Purpose 1. To investigate the effects of cardiac imaging radiation on the induction of DNA double-strand breaks by enumerating gamma-H2AX foci in blood lymphocytes and plucked hair follicle cells. 2. To estimate whether the use of breast shields in cardiac computed tomographic angiography (CCTA) limits the effective radiation exposure of breast tissue.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Heart Imaging Radiation on DNA Double-Stranded Breaks in Blood Lymphocytes and Hair Follicle Cells</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective of the study is to analyze blood and hair samples from patients undergoing cardiac imaging to estimate radiation exposure levels as well as their biological effects (i.e. to determine the degree of genotoxicity by measuring the amounts of DNA double-strand breaks). The secondary objective is to investigate whether the use of in-plane breast shielding in female patients undergoing CT angiography (CCTA) limits the radiation exposure of breast tissue and subsequent DNA damage in blood lymphocytes and hair follicle cells.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chest Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bismuth</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult male and female adult subjects (age greater than 18 years) Referred for cardiac computed tomography angiography (CCTA), myocardial perfusion scintigraphy (MPS), or diagnostic invasive coronary angiography (ICA). Female patients that identify themselves as pregnant or have a positive pregnancy test prior to cardiac imaging. History (present or past) of leukemia or lymphoma. History of radiation therapy Xray examination or scintigraphy within the last 72 hours. History of coronary revascularization (coronary artery bypass grafting or percutaneous coronary intervention) Patients undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention at completion of diagnostic left heart catheterization</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>radiation</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiac computed tomography</keyword>
	<keyword>CCTA</keyword>
	<keyword>breast shielding</keyword>
	<keyword>Myocardial perfusion scintigraphy</keyword>
	<keyword>MPS</keyword>
	<keyword>Invasive coronary angiography</keyword>
	<keyword>ICA</keyword>
</DOC>