<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02618590</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multi-center retrospective study, designing to access the best treatment strategy in non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) patients harboring EGFR mutant type after first/second line EGFR-TKI failure. The study end point is Progression Free Survival 2 (PFS2), which is defined as the time period from Progression Disease 1(PD1) to Progression Disease 2(PD2). PD1 is defined as the first tumor progression time from taking EGFR-TKI evaluated by Recist 1.1 criterion, and PD2 as the second tumor progression time after EGFR-TKI failure no matter what second/third line treatment was, PD2 is also evaluated by Recist 1.1 criterion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Retrospective Study About Treatment Strategy After First/Second Line EGFR-TKI Failure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who was confirmed stage IV (according to International Association for the Study of Lung Cancer（IASLC） TNM staging, 2009) nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC) by histology or cytology between year 2009 to 2013, harboring EGFR mutant type (19 and/or 21 exon mutation). Appraisable disease, that is there must be at least one lesion with the longest diameter&gt;10mm according to Recist 1.1 criterion (by contrast CT). Patients who take EGFRTKI as first/second line therapy. Patients who has taken EGFRTKI before. Patients who take EGFRTKI as third or more line. Patients who take EGFRTKI concurrent with chemotherapy or other antitumor drug. The evaluated lesions has treated with radiotherapy before or concurrent with EGFRTKI. Patients whose EGFR expression is positive by immunochemical and/or EGFR amplification is positive by Fluorescence In Situ Hybridization(FISH), without mutation detection evidence.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>EGFR mutant type</keyword>
	<keyword>first/second line EGFR-TKI</keyword>
</DOC>