<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01209442</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out whether Hypofractionated Intensity-Modulated Radiation Therapy (Hypo-IMRT) combining with temozolomide chemotherapy can be safely given with a targeted agent, bevacizumab, and how effective this study treatment will be in controlling your brain tumor.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Hypofractionated Intensity-Modulated Radiation Therapy With Temozolomide and Bevacizumab for Glioblastoma Multiforme</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a pilot phase II trial of the combination of concurrent hypofractionated IMRT (60 Gy/2 weeks), temozolomide and bevacizumab followed by 6 cycles of adjuvant bevacizumab and temozolomide in patients with grade IV malignant gliomas (glioblastoma and gliosarcoma). The study will have survival and toxicity endpoints.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed diagnosis of WHO grade IV primary malignant glioma (GBM or gliosarcoma). Age ≥ 18 years at the time of study registration Karnofsky Performance Scale ≥ 60% Absolute Neutrophil Count (ANC) ≥ 1,500 cells/mm3, hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dl, platelets ≥ 100,000 cells/ mm3 Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dl, serum glutamate oxaloacetate transaminase (SGOT) and bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal Signed informed consent approved by the Institutional Review Board Craniotomy or intracranial biopsy site must be adequately healed, free of drainage or cellulitis, and the underlying cranioplasty must appear intact at the time of study entry. Study treatment should be initiated &gt; 28 days following the last surgical procedure (including open biopsy, surgical resection, wound revision, or any other major surgery involving entry into a body cavity) Life expectancy of less than 12 weeks Prior treatment, including radiation therapy or chemotherapy, for GBM with the exception of surgery (Gliadel Wafers are allowed at the time of surgery) Active malignancy, with the exception of superficial basal cell and/or superficial squamous (skin) cell, or carcinoma in situ of the cervix Active infection requiring IV antibiotics Pregnant or breast feeding International normalized ratio (INR) &gt; 1.5 and activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) &gt; 1.5 × the upper limit of normal (ULN) (except for subjects receiving anticoagulation therapy) in the absence of therapeutic intent to anticoagulate the subject. Therapeutic anticoagulation is permitted Evidence of ≥ Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Effects (CTCAE) v.3 grade 2 CNS hemorrhage (CNS hemorrhage when medical intervention indicated), but grade 1 CNS hemorrhage (asymptomatic radiographic findings on the baseline brain CT or MRI only) is allowed. Punctate hemorrhage or the presence of hemosiderin is not considered a Grade 1 event for the purpose of this study. ) Inadequately controlled hypertension (defined as systolic blood pressure &gt;150 mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure &gt; 100 mmHg) Prior history of hypertensive crisis or hypertensive encephalopathy Current New York Heart Association (NYHA) Grade II or greater congestive heart failure History of myocardial infarction or unstable angina within 6 months prior to enrollment History of stroke or transient ischemic attack within 6 months prior to enrollment Significant vascular disease (e.g., aortic aneurysm, requiring surgical repair or recent peripheral arterial thrombosis) within 6 months prior to enrollment History of hemoptysis (≥ 1/2 teaspoon of bright red blood per episode) within 1 month prior to enrollment Evidence of bleeding diathesis or significant coagulopathy (in the absence of therapeutic anticoagulation) Major surgical procedure, open biopsy, or significant traumatic injury within 28 days prior to enrollment or anticipation of need for major surgical procedure during the course of the study Core needle biopsy or other minor surgical procedure, excluding placement of a vascular access device, within 7 days prior to enrollment History of abdominal fistula or gastrointestinal perforation within 6 months prior to enrollment Serious, nonhealing wound, active ulcer, or untreated bone fracture Proteinuria as demonstrated by a Urine proteincreatinine ratios (UPC) ratio ≥ 1.0 at screening (Appendix A). Known hypersensitivity to any component of bevacizumab</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Glioblastoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiforme</keyword>
</DOC>