<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01209897</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The topic of this research is cigarette smoking cessation. We designed four smoking cessation booklets. These booklets are designed for smokers who differ in their motivation to quit smoking. We will compare different ways of matching booklets to smokers who vary in their motivation to quit smoking.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Testing Different Theories of Smoking Cessation: An Intervention Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The topic of the proposed research is adult cigarette smoking cessation. The PI has designed a set of four smoking cessation booklets. These booklets cover different aspects of the smoking cessation process, and are designed to help smokers who differ in their levels of motivation to quit smoking. The purpose of the study is to compare different ways of matching booklets to smokers who vary in their motivation to quit smoking. Adult smokers (N=1,826) will be recruited via newspaper ads, fliers, and possibly other methods, depending on response rates. Participants will enroll in the study by telephoning the research staff in response to the advertisements. The smoking cessation booklets and surveys will be sent via US Mail. Smokers will be assigned randomly to one of three intervention conditions. Participants at baseline will answer a series of survey items regarding their motivation and plans (or lack thereof) for quitting smoking. The three intervention conditions differ in that each employs a different method of matching smokers to one of the four booklets. Essentially, we are comparing different strategies for allocating booklets to smokers. Participants will be surveyed two weeks and two months after receiving their smoking cessation booklet.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>must be a current smoker who smokes at least three cigarettes per day must have smoked at least 100 cigarettes in their lifetime. must be able to read English so that they can read the intervention booklets and complete questionnaires in English. must have a mailing address so that they can receive booklets and questionnaires in the mail. must be age 18 or older. must live in Hawaii not a current smoker smokes fewer than three cigarettes per day has not smoked at least 100 cigarettes in their lifetime cannot read English has no mailing address is under 18</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Smoking</keyword>
</DOC>