<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01209260</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized controlled trial examining whether a mechanical needle versus a needle that uses radiofrequency energy is better at puncturing through a thin wall in the heart (called "transseptal puncture") as measured by procedure time, during an electrical procedure/study of the heart .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Transseptal Needle Versus Radiofrequency Energy for Left Atrial Access</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Transseptal puncture is a commonly performed procedure allowing access to the left atrium for catheter ablation. Historically, a conventional Brockenbrough needle has been used for this procedure to mechanically puncture the fossa ovalis, which has been well described in the literature.1, 2 Although generally safe, serious complications such as perforation of the atrial wall or aorta can occur.3, 4 Previous studies have evaluated the feasibility and safety of radiofrequency (RF) energy applied to a conventional needle as a technique to access the left atrium, particularly in patients with a repeat procedure, fibrotic septum or aneurysmal septum.5, 6 As a result of this earlier work, a special proprietary device has been designed. The NRG RF needle (Baylis Medical Inc., Montreal, Canada), uses radiofrequency energy emitted from the needle tip to aid in transseptal access. Despite limited literature to support its superiority and safety7-9compared to the conventional approach, the new device has become adopted in some electrophysiology procedures involving a transseptal puncture.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients undergoing radiofrequency ablation within the left atrium through a transseptal approach Patients greater than 18 years of age Patients unable to grant informed, written consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Transseptal Puncture</keyword>
	<keyword>Radiofrequency Energy</keyword>
	<keyword>Left Atrium Access</keyword>
	<keyword>Left Atrial Catheterization</keyword>
	<keyword>Ablation</keyword>
	<keyword>Transseptal Catheterization</keyword>
	<keyword>Electrocautery</keyword>
	<keyword>Catheter Ablation</keyword>
	<keyword>Atrial Fibrillation</keyword>
</DOC>