<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00652171</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study reports a clinical trial evaluating lamotrigine safety and efficacy as an antidepressant augmentation agent in treatment resistant depression, therefore adding more empirical evidence to the limited number of studies on the use of lamotrigine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Antidepressant Augmentation With Lamotrigine</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objective: This study reports a clinical trial evaluating lamotrigine safety and efficacy as an antidepressant augmentation agent in treatment resistant depression, therefore adding more empirical evidence to the limited number of studies on the use of lamotrigine. Method: A double-blind pilot study was conducted with 34 nonbipolar, nonpsychotic patients who had DSM-IV major depressive disorder and were resistant to at least 2 antidepressants. The subjects were on taking antidepressant therapy and were randomly assigned to receive placebo or lamotrigine as an adjunct therapy for 8 weeks. They were evaluated on a biweekly basis in order to access assess the efficacy and the safety of the drug.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lamotrigine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anticonvulsants</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antidepressive Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>They were selected according to a clinical interview based on DSMIV criteria for major depressive disorder in single or recurrent episodes, with moderate to severe intensity. Besides They also had a history of treatmentresistant depression stage II or above according to the criteria of by Thase and Rush11 failure to respond to treatment with at least 2 antidepressants of different classes at the maximum tolerated dose for at least 6 weeks and absence of psychotic symptoms Pregnant or lactating women or those capable of getting pregnant that who were not using contraceptive methods were excluded as well as patients with severe clinical diseases or organic mental disorder Further exclusion criteria were acute depression with risk of suicide psychosis and bipolar disorder as well as personality disorders and disorders related to alcohol and other drugs</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Augmentation</keyword>
	<keyword>Resistant depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Lamotrigine</keyword>
</DOC>