<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00652730</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To compare the single-dose bioavailability of Par and Bristol-Myers Squibb Buspirone HCl Tablets</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bioavailability Study of (Buspar) Buspirone HCl Tablets Under Fasting and Fed Conditions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To compare the single-dose bioavailability of Par and Bristol-Myers Squibb (Buspar) 15 mg buspirone HCl tablets, following administration of a 30 mg dose, under fed conditions. In addition, the bioavailability of the Par product was compared under fed and fasting conditions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Buspirone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy male volunteers, 1845 years of age Weighing at least 60 kg, who are within 10% of their ideal weights (Table of "Desirable Weights of Adults", metropolitan Life Insurance Company, 1983) Physical examination and laboratory tests of hematologic, hepatic and renal functions. Medically healthy subjects with clinically normal laboratory profiles will be enrolled in the study History or presence of significant cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic, renal, hematologic, gastrointestinal, endocrine, immunologic, dermatologic, neurologic or psychiatric disease. In addition, the presence of alcoholism or drug abuse within the past year: hypersensitivity or idiosyncratic reaction to buspirone HCl. Subjects who have been receiving monoamine oxidase inhibitors. Subjects who have been on an abnormal diet (for whatever reason) during the 28 days preceding the study. Subjects who, through completion of the study, would have donated in excess of 500 mL blood in 14 days, or 500750 mL blood in 14 days (unless approved by the Principal Investigator, 1000 mL blood in 90 days, 1250 mL blood in 120 days, 1500 mL blood in 180 days, 2000 mL blood in 270 days, 2500 mL blood in 1 year. Subjects who have participated in another clinical trial with 28 days of study start.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>bioequivalence</keyword>
	<keyword>buspirone HCl</keyword>
	<keyword>fed</keyword>
</DOC>