<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01139294</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to non-invasively study the reflective changes in cardiac output as response to fluid therapy in the pediatric moderate hypovolemia/dehydrated pediatric patients using sub-q rehydration using Hylenex augmented subcutaneous infusion of fluids and electrolytes compared to intravenous methods.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Descriptive Study of Cardiac Output During Rehydration With Recombinant Human Hyaluronidase in Pediatrics</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is an open-labeled, single-center Phase IV clinical trial. The study will consist of patients with moderate hypovolemia/dehydration requiring parenteral rehydration. It is expected that this study will describe the onset or change in cardiac output using Hylenex augmented subcutaneous rehydration from ages 2 months up to 3 years and at a flow rate satisfying clinical needs, especially in reference to changes in cardiac output observed in standard intravenous rehydration.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dehydration</mesh_term>
	<criteria>patients presenting to the ED with moderate dehydration (gorelick dehydration classification : presence of 36 moderate signs and symptoms) requiring parenteral rehydration. Patient has not successfully received oral or IV fluids immediately prior to enrollment patient's legally authorized representative has signed the informed consent and is willing for the patient to receive Hylenex augmented subq rehydration patient in shock or a lifethreatening situation immunocompromised, history of abscess or cellulitis, abscess &amp;/or cellulitis caused by MRSA, family history of abscess or cellulitis requires IV therapy for another indication has an indwelling catheter has already received rehydration therapy by IV route within the last 48 hours or substantial oral fluid in the immediate time period of enrollment has a condition precluding subq injection or infusion site evaluation in the upper middle back area or at another elected site of infusion has a reason for hospital admission or extended ED stay other than dehydration has an known hypersensitivity to hyaluronidase or another ingredient in the formulation of Hylenex has a know hyponatremia &lt; 130 mEq/L or hypernatremia &gt;155 mEq/L has a know hypokalemia &lt;3.0 mEq/L has a medical condition likely to interfere with the patients ability to fully complete the study protocol or the ability to have the protocolspecified assessments has a medical history, screening physical exam finding or historical clinical lab result that in the opinion of the investigator would preclude the patients safe participation in the is study or which might adversely effect the interpretation of the study results patient participated in a study of any investigational drug or device within 230 days prior to enrollment in this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>3 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>cardiac output</keyword>
	<keyword>dehydration</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatrics</keyword>
</DOC>