<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01366820</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether NNZ-2566 is safe and effective in the treatment of Traumatic Brain Injury (TBI).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of NNZ-2566 in Patients With Traumatic Brain Injury Under EFIC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Moderate to severe traumatic brain injury frequently results in persistent problems with memory, attention span, mood and more complex brain functioning such as planning and organizing. There are currently no drugs available to reduce the brain damage or the persisting symptoms that result from TBI. The longer term goal of this study is to provide physicians with a safe and effective treatment for TBI</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Nonpenetrating TBI. Age 1675 years. Admission to hospital. Post resuscitation GCS 412. Have at least one reactive pupil. Able to receive investigational product within 8 hours of injury. Hemodynamically stable after resuscitation (systolic blood pressure (SBP) &gt;100 mm Hg). Able to read and write English and have sufficient motor dexterity prior to injury to undertake the neuropsychological and activities of daily living (ADL) testing, in the opinion of the investigator, at 1 month (defined as 46 weeks) and 3 months (defined as 1214 weeks) post injury. Penetrating brain injury. Spinal cord injury. Presence or known history of prior cerebral injury requiring hospitalization that would, in the opinion of the Investigator, interfere with or bias the assessment of efficacy. Nontraumatic brain injury. Known history of any medical or psychiatric disorder, or any severe concomitant disease that would, in the opinion of the Investigator, interfere with or bias the assessment of efficacy. Significant noncentral nervous system (CNS) injuries sustained at the time of the TBI would, in the opinion of the Investigator, interfere with or bias the assessment of efficacy. Weight &gt;150 kg. Participation in another clinical trial within the previous 4 weeks. Clinical state requiring greater than 6 L blood, colloid or crystalloid fluid resuscitation prior to randomization. Pregnant or nursing mothers. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative urine or blood test prior to randomization. Prior enrollment in this study. QTc Exclusions. The study will use the exclusion criteria as defined in ICH Guideline E14 to exclude patients with a risk of QT/QTc prolongation, as follows: A marked baseline prolongation of corrected QT/QTc interval &gt;450 ms. History of risk factors for torsade de pointes (e.g. heart failure, hypokalemia (serum potassium at screening &lt;3.0 mmol/L)or family history of long QT syndrome).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>