<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02987881</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate whether the use of the Jawbone wristband monitor, in connection with home-based exercise and nutritional counseling can be safely completed and improve cardiorespiratory fitness (heart and lung health) in women with early stage endometrial cancer who have undergone surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Endometrial Cancer Diet and Exercise</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ages &gt; 18 years. Localized endometrial cancer (stage I and II); no evidence of stage III or IV disease. At least 2 months was passed since the hysterectomy and enrollment. Karnofsky performance status &gt; 70%. Body mass index of 30.0 49.9 and body weight &lt; 300 pounds. No plan for adjuvant endometrial cancer therapy. Able to exercise safely on a treadmill. No absolute contraindications to exercise testing as recommended by the American Thoracic Society. No recent (&lt;6 months) acute cardiac event unstable angina, uncontrolled dysrhythmias causing symptoms or hemodynamic compromise, symptomatic aortic stenosis, uncontrolled symptomatic heart failure, acute pulmonary embolus, acute myocarditis or pericarditis, suspected or known dissecting aneurism and acute systemic infection. The subject is not participating in regular physical exercise (more than 60 minutes of moderate intensity or 30 minutes of vigorous intensity exercise per week) or weight reduction dieting. Able to provide informed consent. Have reliable transportation to the testing facilities. Subjects must be able to speak and understand English to participate in this study. Subjects must have a personal mobile device compatible for the activity monitor Compatible devices for the activity monitors are below: Android o Activity monitor is compatible with most Android devices equipped with Bluetooth 4.0 and running Android 4.3 (Jelly Bean) or later. iOS iPhone 4s (or newer) iPod touch (5th generation or newer) iPad (3rd generation or newer) iPad mini (1st generation or newer) iPad Air (1st generation or newer)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>