<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02987283</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators will perform a diagnostic accuracy study comparing tracheal breath sound recordings in awake individuals to the STOP-Bang screening questionnaire, using the apnea-hypopnea index (AHI) score determined by polysomnography as the gold standard.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluating Accuracy of Breath Sound Recordings and STOP-Bang Screening For Obstructive Sleep Apnea While Awake</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) is a breathing disorder with numerous health effects including a greater risk of peri-operative anesthetic complications. Numerous screening tools exist but are not without limitations. Diagnostic overnight sleep studies are resource-intensive and difficult to obtain in the short time period between pre-operative clinic assessment and the day of surgery. This project aims to test the diagnostic performance of a new screening technology, Awake-OSA, for screening of obstructive sleep apnea (OSA). "Awake-OSA" uses a small external microphone placed on the neck, to record and analyze tracheal breath sounds at the bedside while the patient is awake. Using polysomnography (PSG) as a gold standard, the investigators will compare Awake-OSA (breath sound recording) and the STOP-Bang screening questionnaire in their ability to accurately identify patients with OSA, as well as classify OSA in terms of severity. Early, point-of-care diagnosis has the potential to provide a low-cost, convenient alternative to traditional screening questionnaires and enable more selective use of PSG. Our goal is to improve peri-operative patient safety while improving use of resources and streamlining patient care.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Sounds</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years and older. Referred for diagnostic sleep study. Willing and able to consent. Under the age of 18 yrs. Unwilling or unable to give consent. Expected to have an abnormal EEG (epilepsy, brain tumour, deep brain stimulator). Significant craniofacial abnormality (ex. unrepaired cleft lip/palate).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>