<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02987569</DOC>
	<brief_summary>12 month study testing mobile delivery of health information and connections to professionals and peers to improve health of teen/young adult HPN users.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Teen Connections for Support From Multidisciplinary Professionals &amp; Peers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This research study will test the effect of in-home/mobile HPN support delivered to teen and young adult home parenteral nutrition (HPN) patients and family members over handheld personal computers. Effects on health status, QoL, and fatigue will be assessed over time between groups of study subjects from the ages of 13 through 30 randomized to one of two groups. Group One (intervention group) will receive mConnect, integrated evidence-based interventions (skill-building games, restorative naps &amp; peer support) via mobile iPad and Internet delivery plus two real-time audiovisual encrypted connections with multidisciplinary professionals and peers. Group Two (control group) will receive healthy activity information via mobile iPad and Internet delivery plus one real-time audiovisual encrypted connection with professionals and peers.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Short Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malabsorption Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Total parenteral nutrition (TPN) patients/users and family members/caregivers (defined as those individuals involved in daily home HPN care) age 13 and older TPN users (also called HPN users) must be receiving intravenous nutrition for a nonmalignant short bowel disorder Read, write, speak English and provide informed consent Be able to participate in group clinic visits Enteral nutrition dependency only Less than 13 years of age 13 through 17 years of age without parental consent Currently enrolled in an intervention study or HPN management program Severe cognitive impairment Disability disorders (e.g. blindness which cannot be accommodated for active participation in the group clinics</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Home Parenteral Nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>HPN</keyword>
	<keyword>Total Parenteral Nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>TPN</keyword>
	<keyword>mConnect</keyword>
	<keyword>SBS</keyword>
	<keyword>short bowel disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>telehealth</keyword>
	<keyword>telemedicine</keyword>
</DOC>