<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02698878</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present study aimed to investigate whether a daily intake of lupin protein and a neuromuscular electrical stimulation training twice a day can improve local glucose uptake into m. soleus during a 60 day unloading phase with a special unloading device, the HEPHAISTOS orthosis (HEP).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Unloading Induced Effects on Local Glucose Uptake Into m. Soleus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The 60 day unloading intervention with the HEPHAISTOS unloading device had the following key objectives: primary hypothesis: - Assesment and evaluation of insulin sensitivity and local glucose uptake in the unloaded m. soleus and whether it can be improved by dietary supplementation of lupin seeds and neuromuscular electrical stimulation. secondary hypotheses: - Assesment and evaluation of unloading-induced reductions in muscle mass and whether they can be mitigated by dietary supplementation of lupin seed and neuromuscular electrical stimulation. - Assesment and evaluation of whole-body glycemic effects of the interventions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucose Metabolism Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male volunteers Age: between 20 and 45 years Body mass index (BMI): 20 26 kg/m2 Agreement and signed consent before the study Smoker Competitive Athletes Diabetes mellitus Rheumatic disease Muscle or joint disease Bone fractures in the period up to one year before study start Herniated disc Flatfeet (pes planus) Allergy to nuts or legume Vascular diseases Epilepsy Severe hyperlipidemia Anemia (&lt; Hb standard values; standard values healthy men: 13.5 17.5 g/dl) * Increased thrombosis risk * Kidney disorder: deviations from normal values for creatinine in plasma. (Normal value: Creatinine &lt; 1.20 mg/dl)* Lesions of the cruciate ligaments, or orthopedic surgery in the past 10 years on the side of the Hephaistos orthosis Achilles tendon injury, or rupture in the past 10 years on the side of the orthosis hyper/hypocalcaemia (abnormal levels of calcium in the blood, normal level: 2.15 2.64 mmol/l) Intake of antiinflammatory drugs during the study Abuse of drugs or alcohol (&gt; than 2030g alcohol/day) Participation in another clinical study within the last 2 months before the start of this study Increased bleeding tendency (hemophilia, regular use of anticoagulants) History of intolerance to local anesthetics Imprisoned during study Any other condition classed as unsuitable for study participation by the medical executive director prior convictions (objectionable criminal record) Additional Exclusion Criteria for MRI Metal implants or other osteosynthesis material Pacemaker Claustrophobia</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lupin Protein</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucose Metabolism</keyword>
	<keyword>GLUT4</keyword>
	<keyword>Muscle Unloading</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuromuscular Electrical Stimulation</keyword>
</DOC>