<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02698696</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates the effect of a new cognitive remediation program designed for patients suffering from a bipolar disorder, on cognitive functions, psychosocial functioning and neural processes. In this double-blind (patient, outcomes assessor) controlled randomized trial the investigators compare patients receiving the ECo program for bipolar disorders, to patients benefiting from the broadly used cognitive remediation program CRT and to patients receiving supportive psychotherapy. Patients are treated for 3 months and monitored for 9 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Validation of a Cognitive Remediation Program for Bipolar Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Type I or type II Bipolar Disorder diagnosis, according to DSMIVTR criteria 2. No Manic or Major Depressive episode during the last three months 3. No or few residual depressive symptoms (HDRS17 ≤ 12) 4. No or few residual manic symptoms (YMRS ≤ 8) 5. Stable dose of medication for the last two months 6. Cognitive complaint expressed by the patient and impairment observed by the patient's regular psychiatrist 7. Informed consent form read, initialed and signed 8. Patient registered on the social welfare system 1. Other diagnosis than Bipolar Disorder on axis I of the DSMIVTR 2. Rapid Cycling Bipolar Disorder diagnosis 3. Addiction or substance abuse (except tobacco) during the twelve last months 4. Physical or neurological disorder that can lead to cognitive impairment 5. Engagement in a research protocol either currently or over the last month 6. Neuropsychological assessment or Rorschach Inkblot Test evaluation during the last six months 7. Ineligibility for Magnetic Resonance Imaging [MRI] (e.g. claustrophobia, metallic implants, pacemaker, etc.)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cognitive Remediation</keyword>
	<keyword>Mood disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Neuropsychology</keyword>
</DOC>