<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00065806</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is: 1. To assess the efficacy of a lipid-lowering agent (atorvastatin) on the development of atherosclerosis that predisposes children with SLE to cardiovascular events in adulthood. 2. To assess the safety of intermediate-term (36 months) treatment of children and young adults with atorvastatin. 3. To further characterize the course of SLE in children and young adults, by establishing a cohort of pediatric SLE patients to be followed prospectively. 4. To establish a mechanism for conducting clinical trials in rare pediatric rheumatic diseases using the Children's Arthritis and Rheumatology Research Alliance (CARRA).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Atherosclerosis Prevention in Pediatric Lupus Erythematosus (APPLE)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Children and adolescents with SLE represent 15% of all SLE patients. Children with SLE suffer high morbidity that affects many organ systems, reduces their quality of life, and shortens their lifespan. As more children with SLE survive into adulthood, atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease has emerged as a major concern. SLE is a significant risk factor for myocardial infarction and death in young premenopausal women with SLE, even after controlling for traditional cardiovascular risk factors. Acceleration of atherogenesis in SLE most likely reflects SLE-associated vascular immune and inflammatory changes. Although limited, the data on cardiovascular and lipid abnormalities in children with SLE implicate atherosclerosis as an important cause of long-term morbidity and mortality. The 3-hydroxy-3-methlglutaryl-coenzyme A (HMG CoA) reductase inhibitors, or statins, reduce mortality and morbidity from atherosclerosis in adults and have intrinsic anti-inflammatory and immune modulatory properties. These anti-inflammatory and immune modulatory activities may have particular benefit in the prevention and treatment of atherosclerosis in SLE. This trial will evaluate atorvastatin in children with SLE in the largest cohort of pediatric SLE patients ever studied prospectively. Children in this study will be randomized to receive either atorvastatin or a placebo. All children will be followed for 3 years, during which they will have 15 study visits. Study visits will generally last 2 hours and will include medical interview, medication review and pill count, physical examination, and blood and urine tests. Cardiovascular-specific outcome measures will include assessments of high sensitivity CRP; fasting lipid profile; homocysteine level; apolipoprotein A, B1, and Lp(a); carotid intima media thickness (IMT); and tensor diffusion/MRI.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atorvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxychloroquine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Meets American College of Rheumatology (ACR) revised diagnostic guidelines for SLE Weight of 25 kg (55 lbs) or more Outpatient Ability to complete selfreport questionnaires in either English or Spanish Willingness to comply with recommended diet Acceptable methods of contraception Druginduced lupus Liver disease (ALT or aspartate aminotransferase greater than 2 X normal value) Myositis (CK greater than 3 X normal value) Inability to obtain adequatequality IMT images Current use of oral or parenteral tacrolimus or cyclosporine Dialysis or serum creatinine reater than 2.5 mg/dL Active nephrotic syndrome (urinary protein greater than 3 g/24 h and serum albumin less than 2.3 g/dl) Total cholesterol greater than 350 mg/dL Xanthoma Familial hypercholesterolemia Pregnant or breastfeeding Use of estrogencontaining contraceptives (e.g., LoOvral) Unable to adhere to study regimen Lifethreatening nonSLE illness that would interfere with ability to complete the study Current drug or alcohol abuse Anticipated poor compliance Participation in another drug intervention study within 30 days of study enrollment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pediatric lupus</keyword>
	<keyword>Atherosclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>SLE</keyword>
	<keyword>HMG CoA reductase inhibitor</keyword>
</DOC>