<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01118416</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary aim of this study is to test a brief 4-session risk reduction intervention, based on Motivational Enhancement Therapy (MET) to reduce the co-occurrence of club drug use and sexual risk taking behaviors among non-treatment seeking young men who have sex with men (YMSM) in NYC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Risk Reduction Intervention for Vulnerable Young Adult Males</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a randomized clinical trial. A sample of 300 non-treatment seeking YMSM (ages 18-24) who report risky sex and club drug use in the past 90 days are being enrolled using active and passive community-based recruitment strategies in NYC. After baseline assessment, participants are being randomly assigned to one of two study arms: a Brief Risk Reduction Intervention Condition - a four session MET intervention piloted for feasibility and acceptability among YMSM, designed to increase readiness to change club drug use and unprotected sex; or an Education Comparison Condition - four sessions of facilitated education regarding the effects of club drugs and unprotected sex. Participants undergo follow-up assessments 3, 6, 9, and 12 months after baseline.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>At least 5 days of drug use (cocaine, ketamine, ecstasy, methamphetamine, or GHB) in the past 90 days; At least 1 instance of unprotected anal sex in the past 90 days; Biological male; HIVnegative; Residential stability; Ability to communicate in written English. Unstable, serious psychiatric symptoms; Currently suicidal/homicidal; Evidence of gross cognitive impairment; Reports current enrollment in a drug or HIV related intervention or research study.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>29 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>sexual risk</keyword>
	<keyword>substance use</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>prevention</keyword>
	<keyword>intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Motivational Enhancement Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>young men who have sex with men</keyword>
</DOC>