<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01118078</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research study is studying biomarkers in tissue samples from patients with high-risk Wilms tumor. Studying samples of tissue from patients with cancer in the laboratory may help doctors to learn more about changes that occur in DNA and identify biomarkers related to cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Biomarkers in Tissue Samples From Patients With High-Risk Wilms Tumor</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: I. To assess genomic gains and losses in high risk renal tumors, including up to 80 favorable histology Wilms tumors that relapse (RFHWT), 50 anaplastic Wilms tumors (UHWT), 15 clear cell sarcomas of the kidney (CCSK), and 40 rhabdoid tumors (RT) using a high density genetic platform to survey for recurrent copy number variations and allelic imbalances. II. To define transcription patterns within 80 RFHWT, 50 UHWT, 15 CCSK, and 40 RT using a high throughput platform for global gene expression. III. To define DNA methylation patterns within 80 RFHWT, 50 UHWT, 15 CCSK, and 40 RT using a high throughput platform. IV. To identify genetic mutations involved in the pathogenesis of Wilms tumor, and in the development of relapse and anaplasia through the study of 80 RFHWT, 50 UHWT, 15 CCSK, and 40 RT using next generation sequencing tools. V. To facilitate the integration of the above databases and allow meaningful access by investigators through the infrastructure provided by TARGET, including its data portal and associated caBIG tool. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Archived tumor tissue samples are analyzed for DNA copy number determination, gene expression, DNA methylation, and genomic re-sequencing by array-based methods, including PCR analysis, methylation-specific reverse transcriptase-PCR (RT-PCR), and quantitative RT-PCR.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Wilms Tumor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhabdoid Tumor</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma, Clear Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of highrisk Wilms tumor meeting ≥ 1 of the following criteria: Relapsed disease Anaplastic disease Clear cell sarcomas of the kidney Rhabdoid tumors Registered on NWTS4, NWTS5 (now COGQ9401), or participation in AREN03B2 protocols with clinical followup &gt; 3 years Banked frozen tumor samples and paired normal DNA available with clinical data points, including the following: Age, race, and gender Stage and reason for stage Tumor weight Associated precursor lesions (rests) Histologic subtype Site and time of recurrence Days of followup Time and reasons for death (e.g., tumor, toxicity, infection, or other)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>