<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02576795</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being conducted by Biomarin Pharmaceutical Inc. as an open label, dose escalation study in order to determine the safety and efficacy of BMN 270 (an Adenovirus-Associated Virus based gene therapy vector in participants with severe Haemophilia A.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Gene Therapy Study in Severe Haemophilia A Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hemophilia A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Factor VIII</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males that are 18 years or older with established severe haemophilia A as evidenced by their medical history. Patients will be considered as severe if their FVIII baseline level is 1 IU/dL or less Treated/exposed to FVIII concentrates or cryoprecipitate for a minimum of 150 exposure days (EDs) Greater or equal to 12 bleeding episodes only if receiving ondemand therapy over the previous 12 months. Does not apply to patients on prophylaxis Able to sign informed consent and comply with requirements of the trial No history of inhibitor, or no inhibitor on 2 consecutive occasions within the past 12 months using a modified Nijmegen Bethesda assay higher than 0.6 Bethesda Units (BU) Sexually active patients must be willing to use an acceptable method of contraception such as double barrier, including hormonal contraception for at least 6 months posttreatment. Detectable preexisting immunity to the AAV capsid as measured by AAV transduction inhibition and AAV total antibodies Any evidence of active infection or any immunosuppressive disorder. Patients that are HIV positive are excluded. Significant liver dysfunction as defined by abnormal elevation of ALT (alanine transaminase) to 3 times the upper limit of normal, bilirubin, alkaline phosphatase, or an INR (international normalized ratio) of 1.4. Potential participants who have had a liver biopsy in the past 3 years are excluded if they had significant fibrosis of 3 or 4 as rated on a scale of 04. Evidence of any bleeding disorder not related to Haemophilia A Platelet count of &lt; 100 x 10e9/L Creatinine ≥ 1.5 mg/dL Liver cirrhosis of any etiology as assessed by liver ultrasound Hepatitis B if surface antigen is positive Hepatitis C if RNA is positive Treatment with any IP within 30 days prior to the screening visit Any disease or condition at the physician's discretion that would prevent the patient from fully complying with the requirements of the study. The physician may exclude patients unwilling or unable to agree on not using alcohol for the 16week period following the viral infusion. Receipt of any vector or gene transfer agent.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Haemophilia A</keyword>
	<keyword>Gene Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Clotting Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Blood Disorder</keyword>
</DOC>