<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02576561</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to test the safety and effectiveness of the investigational study vaccine, called TVGV-1. The study will test the vaccine in women with high grade HPV cervical infection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of TVGV-1 Vaccine to Treat HPV Induced Cervical HSIL</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of the Phase 2a Study VAX 02-01 is to assess the safety and activity of TVGV-1 vaccine construct in achieving the absence of histologic HSIL (CIN2/3) (regression to LSIL or less) as assessed by biopsy at last study Visit 11, Day 270. The objective of the TVGV-1 program is to develop a non-surgical alternative that is reliable, safe, and would avoid potential surgical risks such as preterm birth, perinatal mortality, risk of infertility, incontinence and disfigurement, as well as reduced cost and inconvenience for an otherwise economically productive young subject population.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Squamous Intraepithelial Lesions of the Cervix</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Female age 18 to 55 years 2. Written informed consent in accordance with institutional guidelines 3. Negative pregnancy test (urine and blood tests) 4. Women of child bearing potential must agree to use contraception through one menstrual cycle post end of study or if early withdrawal, through what would have been visit 11. Methods include intrauterine device or double barrier method, hormonal contraceptive in combination with a double barrier method. 5. Patients who have ONLY HPV 16 OR HPV 16 AND 18 and no other HighRisk HPV by Cobas test will be included. 6. Histologically confirmed, positive HSIL of CIN2+ or higher (only CIN2+/3 subjects will be selected) cervical biopsy, confirmed by external (independent) pathologist panel within the 12 weeks prior to enrollment. If the standard care biopsy is not available for evaluation by the independent pathologist, a fresh biopsy and endocervical curettage will be required. The extent of colposcopic HSIL disease should not involve more than two quadrants of the cervix. Biopsies should be taken from each affected quadrant 7. Adequate visualization of entire cervix, cervical lesion(s) and squamouscolumnar junction 8. Normal electrocardiogram (ECG), laboratory values (chemistry, complete blood count) and urinalysis, as judged Grade 01 by per National Cancer Institute Common Toxicity Criteria (NCICTC) 9. Agrees to Loop Electrosurgical Excision Procedure (LEEP), Cold Knife Conization (CKC) or Hysterectomy being performed at the end of study according to the standardofcare 1. History of cancer (excluding basal cell carcinoma of the skin) including cervical cancer 2. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status &gt;2 (See Appendix G) 3. Administration of any blood product within 3 months of enrollment 4. Active infection requiring antimicrobial treatment that would interfere with interpretation of adverse events, cutaneous reactions or efficacy. Treatment of minor concurrent infections should be limited to less than 10 days. 5. Administration of any vaccine within 8 weeks of enrollment and within 4 weeks for flu vaccine. 6. Participation in any study with an investigational compound or device within 30 days prior to signing informed consent 7. Any hematologic disorder involving platelets or clotting abnormalities or any condition requiring treatment with transfusions, anticoagulants except platelet inhibitors (NSAIDs as needed for pain are permitted) 8. Active drug or alcohol use or dependence that, in the opinion of the Site Investigator, would interfere with adherence to study protocol 9. Skin conditions that require consistent use of topical corticosteroids or other local or systemic therapy that may interfere with interpretation or description of skinrelated adverse events linked to vaccination 10. The standard criteria for prospective clinical trials of medications developed by DrugInduced Liver Injury Network (established by The National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases) will be used to assess the laboratory test abnormalities. Normal range for these labs will typically be 5 40 IU/L for AST; 7 56 IU/L for ALT; 0.2 1.2 mg/dL for bilirubin. Subjects will be excluded if values are x 2x 2.5 the upper limit 11. Evidence of hematopoietic, cardiovascular, hepatic, renal, neurologic, psychiatric, dermatologic, immune disorder, or other disease that may interfere with assessment of safety or efficacy of vaccine activity as indicated in study objectives 12. Any known allergic reaction to vaccine components 13. Any other medical condition(s) that, in the judgment of the Site Investigator, might interfere with the study or require treatment that might interfere with the study 14. Family member of the investigation study staff 15. Pregnant or breastfeeding 16. Inability to provide informed consent 17. A subject with a history or expectation of noncompliance with medications or treatment protocol 18. Receipt of (e.g. Gardasil® or Cervarix®) HPV preventative vaccines within 8 years of study enrollment 19. Excessive use of acetaminophen or other potentially hepatotoxic drugs</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>human papillomavirus</keyword>
	<keyword>Cervical Intraepithelial Neoplasia</keyword>
	<keyword>Cold Knife Conization</keyword>
	<keyword>hysterectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>Loop Electrosurgical Excision Procedure</keyword>
	<keyword>LEEP</keyword>
	<keyword>HSIL</keyword>
	<keyword>High-Grade Squamous Intraepithelial Lesion</keyword>
</DOC>