<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02576990</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study, participants with relapsed or refractory primary mediastinal large B-cell lymphoma (rrPMBCL) or relapsed or refractory Richter Syndrome (rrRS) will receive pembrolizumab (MK-3475). The efficacy of pembrolizumab in the treatment of rrPMBCL and rrRS will be evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Pembrolizumab (MK-3475) in Participants With Relapsed or Refractory Primary Mediastinal Large B-cell Lymphoma or Relapsed or Refractory Richter Syndrome (MK-3475-170/KEYNOTE-170)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Treatment with pembrolizumab will continue for a maximum of 35 administrations (approximately 2 years) or until documented disease progression by investigator assessment, unacceptable adverse event(s) (AEs), intercurrent illness that prevents further administration of treatment, participant withdraws consent, pregnancy of the participant, noncompliance with study treatment or procedure requirements, or administrative reasons.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>PMBCL: Diagnosis of relapsed or refractory primary mediastinal large Bcell lymphoma. Previously exposed to rituximab as part of prior lines of treatment. RS: Pathologic diagnosis per local institutional review of Richter syndrome that transformed from CLL. Relapsed or refractory Richter syndrome and has received ≥1 previous treatment for RS. All Participants: Radiographically measureable disease. Performance status of 0 or 1 on the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Scale. Life expectancy &gt;3 months. Adequate organ function. Female participants of childbearing potential must be willing to use an adequate method of contraception for the course of the study through 120 days after the last dose of study drug. Male participants of childbearing potential must agree to use an adequate method of contraception, starting with the first dose of study drug through 120 days after the last dose of study drug. Is currently participating and receiving study therapy or has participated in a study of an investigational agent and received study therapy or used an investigation al device within 4 weeks of the first dose of study drug. Is receiving systemic steroid therapy &lt;3 days before the first dose of study drug or receiving any other form of immunosuppressive medication. Known history of immunosuppression or receiving systemic steroid therapy or any other form of systemic immunosuppressive therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of study drug. Prior monoclonal antibody within 4 weeks prior to study Day 1 (2 weeks for RS participants) or who has not recovered (i.e. ≤ Grade 1 or at baseline) from adverse events due to agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier (2 weeks for RS participants). Prior chemotherapy or targeted small molecule therapy within 2 weeks prior to study Day 1 or prior radiation therapy within 4 weeks prior to study Day 1. Allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation within the last 5 years. Has a known additional malignancy (except underlying CLL for RS) that is progressing or requires active treatment. Exceptions include basal cell carcinoma of the skin, squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, or in situ cervical cancer that has undergone potentially curative therapy. Known clinically active central nervous system involvement. Active autoimmune disease requiring systemic treatment in past 2 years. History of (noninfectious) pneumonitis that required steroids, or current pneumonitis. Active infection requiring intravenous systemic therapy. Is pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father children within the projected duration of the study, starting with the prescreening or screening visit through 120 days after the last dose of study drug. Has received prior therapy with an antiprogrammed cell death 1 (antiPD1), antiprogrammed cell death ligand 1 (antiPDL1), antiPDL2, antiCD137, or anticytotoxic Tlymphocyteassociated antigen4 (CTLA4) antibody (including ipilimumab or any other antibody or drug specifically targeting Tcell costimulation or checkpoint pathways). Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), or Hepatitis B or C. Has received a live vaccine within 30 days prior to first dose of study drug.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>PD1</keyword>
	<keyword>PD-1</keyword>
	<keyword>PDL1</keyword>
	<keyword>PD-L1</keyword>
</DOC>