<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01646281</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Atrial fibrillation (AF) is associated with decreased atrial contractility which is associated with stroke. Decreased contractility becomes apparent after cardioversion of atrial fibrillation, a short period (weeks) during which stroke risk is increased. Improved contractility immediately after cardioversion may prevent arrhythmia progression. In addition, it may reduce the stroke risk. Vernakalant is a new antiarrhythmic drug able to convert atrial fibrillation to sinus rhythm and at the same time increase atrial contractility. The latter has not yet been shown in humans and is subject of the present investigation. Our hypothesis is that in humans the contractility of the atria is higher after administration of vernakalant compared to flecainide. If indeed vernakalant improves atrial contractility after cardioversion further studies into the effect on long-term arrhythmia progression and stroke prevention may follow.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vernakalant Versus Flecainide: Atrial Contractility</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Flecainide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>persistent AF or paroxysmal AF eligible for treatment with vernakalant or flecainide infusion to restore sinus rhythm receiving adequate anticoagulant therapy (or having an episode of AF lasting &lt; 24 hours) refusal or inability to give informed consent to participate in this study atrial flutter contraindications for receiving vernakalant or flecainide according to MUMC+ protocol (unstable hemodynamic condition, LVEF &lt; 40%, inadequate potassium levels, acute ischaemia, sinus node dysfunction) age &lt; 18 years</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Atrial fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>Vernakalant</keyword>
	<keyword>Flecainide</keyword>
	<keyword>Echocardiography</keyword>
</DOC>