<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02523859</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study investigates the use of remimazolam as a sedative/hypnotic in general anesthesia. Remimazolam or propofol will be administered together with fentanyl/sufentanil/remifentanil as opioid analgesics and a neuromuscular blocker. In total, 530 patients will be randomized. This group of 530 patients will be split randomly into 2 groups as follows: • 106 patients will be randomized to induction with propofol plus fentanyl or sufentanil or remifentanil and a neuromuscular blocker. Throughout maintenance, the patients will receive propofol and remifentanil until weaning from the mechanical ventilation on the ICU or PACU within 24 hours after induction. Afterwards, sedation with propofol as study medication has to be ended. If necessary, the sedation is to be continued with the hospital's own supplies (propofol or other sedative). • 424 patients will be randomized to induction with remimazolam 6.0 mg/kg/hr together with fentanyl or sufentanil or remifentanil and a neuromuscular blocker. Throughout maintenance, the patients will receive remimazolam and remifentanil until weaning from the mechanical ventilation on the ICU or PACU within 24 hours after induction. The primary endpoint is successful sedation is defined as a Narcotrend index of 60 or less during at least 85% of the maintenance time and no rescue sedative medication administered. The maintenance starts at arrival at the operation theater and ends with the completion of the last skin suture.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Evaluating the Efficacy and Safety of Remimazolam in General Anesthesia in Adult Patients Undergoing Cardiac Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Propofol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients scheduled for major nonemergency cardiac surgery assumed to require more than 2 hours of maintenance of general anesthesia and to require the use of extracorporeal circulation, including coronary bypass(es), valve replacement(s) and associated procedures and onpump minimal invasive surgery Scheduled to receive mechanical ventilation via tracheal intubation (oropharyngeal or nasotracheal) Body Mass Index (BMI) 18 to ≤ 40 kg/m2 Redo cardiac surgery Surgical procedures that comprise the use of drugs and/or devices that are not approved for marketing Severe tricuspidal insufficiency Planned cooling below 32ºC History of or planned stop of circulation, e.g. due to repair of type A dissection of aorta or removal of thrombi from pulmonary artery Planned to receive epidural/spinal anesthesia together with general anesthesia Evidence of uncontrolled hepatic, central nervous system, respiratory, or metabolic dysfunction, or other clinically significant findings at screening that, in the investigator's or medical monitor's opinion, should exclude them from the study. Poorly controlled hypertension (e.g. systolic blood pressure ≥160 mmHg under antihypertensive medication at screening) Severe renal insufficiency or endstage renal disease (creatinine clearance below 30 mL/min or estimated glomerular filtration rate below 30 mL/min/1.73 m2). Clinically uncontrolled coagulation abnormalities, or coagulation abnormalities not under adequate treatment Scheduled for heart or lung transplantation Infectious cardiac disorders (e.g. endocarditis, myocarditis) Sepsis Emergency surgery, status of shock or coma Ejection fraction from left ventricle of less than 20% Acute right heart failure</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>