<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00549497</DOC>
	<brief_summary>GW870086X is a novel inhaled steroid that has an improved safety profile over other steroids but is also less potent. This study will look at higher doses to confirm the improved safety profile.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomized Study Evaluating Steroid Hormone Levels, Safety And Tolerability Of GW870086X In Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose ascending, 3-cohort parallel group study to measure the systemic cortisol profile and evaluate the safety, tolerability and pharmacokinetics of GW870086X, administered as single doses (12mg and 15mg),and repeat doses over 3 days (6mg, 12mg and 15mg) in healthy male subjects.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Healthy male subjects Liver function tests normal 18 45 years old Non smoker Can provide written informed consent Available to complete the whole trial Can use the inhalation device correctly Able to read, understand and write English Exclusion criteria: Deemed suitable healthy subject History to sensitivity to the study medication Any history of breathing problems in adult life Participated in another trial within 30 days or 5 halflives of the new chemical entity Exposed to more than 4 new chemical entities within 12 months Donated &gt;500 mL blood within 2 months of screening Haemoglobin level &lt; 13g/dl Use of prescription or nonprescription drugs within 7 days of first dose Taking drugs that significantly inhibit cytochrome P450 subfamily enzyme CYP3A4 Drinks more than 4 units a day or 28 units a week Cannot use DISKHALER device correctly Positive HepB, HepC within 3 months of screening Positive HIV test Positive pre study drug/alcohol screen Significant cardiac conduction abnormalities Risk of noncompliance</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>GW870086X, inhaled, asthma, cortisol, pharmacokinetics, osteocalcin</keyword>
</DOC>