<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00549809</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objectives: to compare intermittent mandatory ventilation (IMV) with synchronous intermittent mandatory ventilation associated with pressure support (SIMV/PS) related to duration of mechanical ventilation/weaning and length of stay in PICU (LS). Design: randomized clinical trial. Setting: Pediatric intensive care unit at a university-affiliated hospital.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison Between IMV and SIMV/PS for Ventilatory Support of Children: a Randomized Clinical Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objectives: to compare intermittent mandatory ventilation (IMV) with synchronous intermittent mandatory ventilation associated with pressure support (SIMV/PS) related to duration of mechanical ventilation/weaning and length of stay in PICU (LS). Design: randomized clinical trial. Setting: Pediatric intensive care unit at a university-affiliated hospital. Patients: children between 28 days and 4 years old, admitted between 10/2002 and 06/2004, and receiving mechanical ventilation (MV) for more than 48 hours. Patients were randomly assigned into two groups: IMV (IMVG; n=35) and SIMV/PS (SIMVG; n=35). Children with acute respiratory distress syndrome and tracheostomy were excluded. Ventilation and oxygenation data were recorded at admission and beginning of weaning. Results: Groups were not statistically different for age, gender, MV indications, PRISM score, COMFORT scale, sedatives, and ventilation and oxygenation parameters. Median of MV duration was 5 days for both groups (p&gt;0.05). Also, there were no statistical differences for duration of weaning [IMVG: 1 day (1 - 6) vs. SIMVG: 1 day (1 - 6); p&gt;0.05] and LS [IMVG: 8 days (2 - 22) vs. SIMVG: 6 days (3 - 20); p&gt;0.05]. Conclusion: There was no statistically significant difference between IMV and SIMV/PS in these children related to MV and weaning duration, and PICU length of stay.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children aged between 28 days and four years, who were consecutively admitted to the PICU and required MV for more than 48h were included. Children who had chronic respiratory failure, tracheostomy, those transferred from the hospital, or died were excluded as were patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>4 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>mechanical ventilation; respiratory failure</keyword>
</DOC>