<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01990612</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Among nulliparous women with singleton uncomplicated term pregnancies, elective induction of labor at 39 weeks, compared with expectant management, reduces the risk of severe neonatal morbidity and perinatal mortality.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Randomized Trial of Induction Versus Expectant Management</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>1. Nulliparous no previous pregnancy beyond 20 weeks 2. Singleton gestation. Twin gestation reduced to singleton, either spontaneously or therapeutically, is not eligible unless the reduction occurred before 14 weeks project gestational age. 3. Gestational age at randomization between 38 weeks 0 days and 38 weeks 6 days inclusive based on clinical information and evaluation of the earliest ultrasound. 1. Project gestational age at date of first ultrasound is &gt; 20 weeks 6 days 2. Plan for induction of labor prior to 40 weeks 5 days 3. Plan for cesarean delivery or contraindication to labor 4. Signs of labor (regular painful contractions with cervical change) 5. Fetal demise or known major fetal anomaly 6. Heparin or lowmolecular weight heparin during the current pregnancy 7. Placenta previa, accreta, vasa previa 8. Active vaginal bleeding greater than bloody show 9. Ruptured membranes 10. Cerclage in current pregnancy 11. Known oligohydramnios, defined as amniotic fluid index (AFI) &lt; 5 or maximum vertical pocket (MVP) &lt; 2 12. Fetal growth restriction, defined as Estimated Fetal Weight (EFW) &lt; 10th percentile 13. Known HIV positivity because of modified delivery plan 14. Major maternal medical illness associated with increased risk for adverse pregnancy outcome (for example, any diabetes mellitus, lupus, any hypertensive disorder, cardiac disease, renal insufficiency) 15. Refusal of blood products 16. Participation in another interventional study that influences management of labor at delivery or perinatal morbidity or mortality 17. Delivery planned elsewhere at a nonNetwork site</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>