<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01990872</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This winter-based placebo-controlled, single-dose vitamin D randomized controlled trial (RCT) aims to examine the impact of various levels of habitual calcium intake on dietary vitamin D requirements in older adults stratified by calcium intake. This will provide new data on the impact of different levels of calcium intake, ranging from low/moderate to high, on winter serum 25(OH)D levels, and their utilization and catabolism in adults.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Inter-relationship Between Vitamin D Requirements and Calcium Intake in Older Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of this study is to perform a randomised controlled vitamin D3 intervention study in apparently healthy, free-living adults (aged 50+ y) to investigate whether different levels of habitual calcium intake, ranging from low-moderate to high, influence serum 25(OH)D concentrations and indices of vitamin D activation and catabolism during winter, when vitamin D intake is adequate versus inadequate. This research will provide new data and scientific understanding in relation to the impact of different levels of dietary calcium intake on vitamin D requirements in the older adult population. As such, this new data will inform dietary reference values for vitamin D.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium, Dietary</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Consenting white men and women aged ≥ 50 y Unwilling to discontinue consumption of vitamin Dcontaining supplements 4 wks before the initiation of the study and throughout the study. Planning to take a winter vacation (during the course of the 15wk intervention) to a location at which either the altitude or the latitude was predicted to result in significant cutaneous vitamin D synthesis from solar radiation (e.g., a winter sun coastal resort or a mountain ski resort) Use of tanning facilities of any type. Pregnancy or planning to become pregnant during the study A severe medical illness, hypercalcaemia, Known intestinal malabsorption syndrome, Excessive alcohol use, Taking medications known to interfere with vitamin D metabolism</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vitamin D status</keyword>
	<keyword>25-hydroxyvitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitamin D3</keyword>
	<keyword>RCT</keyword>
	<keyword>Calcium intake</keyword>
	<keyword>Dietary requirement</keyword>
</DOC>