<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02202876</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Cystic fibrosis-related diabetes (CFRD) occurs in almost 20% of teens and 50% of adults. The investigators' long term goal is to determine the cause of CFRD in order to translate this knowledge into therapies aimed at preventing CFRD. Since CFRD and type 2 diabetes share several clinical features and since oxidative stress is a key factor in the development of type 2 diabetes, the investigators explored the role of oxidative stress in CFRD. The investigators discovered a unique CF biochemical signature that they believe could be implicated in the development of CFRD. The investigators found that glucose ingestion in CF teens and young adults causes an acute and profound systemic redox imbalance to the oxidizing state. The degree of redox imbalance was quite severe and would be expected to damage the insulin producing cells as these cells are particularly vulnerable to oxidative stress. Thus, these findings could prove to be a critical factor in the pathogenesis of CFRD. This proposal will test the hypothesis that glucose-induced redox imbalance is an intrinsic, metabolic defect in CF. In addition, because CF people are required to consume a high calorie diet to maintain their weight, the investigators also hypothesize that certain high caloric foods will recapitulate the redox imbalance induced by ingesting glucose and thus hasten the development of CFRD. Specifically, the investigators aim to: - Determine whether young children with CF have glucose-induced redox imbalance - Determine whether eating a meal with a high glycemic index induces acute redox imbalance</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Redox Imbalance and the Development of Cystic Fibrosis Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aim 1: For CF children 1. CF diagnosed by pilocarpine electrophoresis sweat test; 2. CF Transmembrane Conductance Regulator (CFTR) mutation analysis showing two Class I to III mutations; 3. Aged 1 to 9 years; 4. On a clinically stable medical regimen for at least three weeks; 5. No IV antibiotics for a respiratory exacerbation for at least three weeks; and 6. No hospitalization for at least six weeks. For agematched controls 1. No acute illness for at least six weeks; 2. Never been hospitalized except at birth following a full term delivery; 3. Aged 1 to 9 years; and 4. Without any chronic illness requiring prescription medications. For CF children 1. Current or past diagnosis of CFRD; or 2. Parents unwilling to have an IV inserted for blood draws. For controls 1. Parents unwilling to have an IV inserted for blood draws. Aim 2: 1. CF diagnosed by pilocarpine electrophoresis sweat test; 2. CFTR mutation analysis showing two Class I to III mutations; 3. Aged 12 years or older; 4. Normal OGTT done within 6 months prior to study visit; 5. On a clinically stable medical regimen for at least three weeks; and 6. No IV antibiotics for a respiratory exacerbation for at least three weeks. 1. Current or past diagnosis of CFRD; or 2. Current or past diagnosis of CF prediabetes by OGTT. 3. Allergy or intolerance to egg or dairy products</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>