<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00194272</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study examines the safety and acceptability of a novel "two dose" regimen of methotrexate to treat ectopic pregnancy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Two-Dose Methotrexate for Ectopic Pregnancy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The regimen is an attempt to create a middle ground between the 2 commonly used regimens - "single dose" and "multi dose". The "multi dose" regimen is more effective, but the "single dose" regimen is more convenient for patients and has fewer side effects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiac Complexes, Premature</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pregnancy, Ectopic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Confirmed diagnosis of ectopic pregnancy via D&amp;E without products of conception identified on frozen pathology or VABRA without products of conception identified with pathologic evaluation or Ultrasound visualization of a gestational sac in the adnexa, with definitive visualization of a yolk sac or fetal pole the subject is hemodynamically stable without signs of hemoperitoneum laparoscopy has not been performed the subject is able to return for frequent followup care normal renal and liver function have been documented within 2 days normal white blood count and platelet count have been documented as per laboratory standard normal chest xray was obtained if the subject has a history of pulmonary disease no history of allergy or sensitivity to methotrexate or any component of its formulation breastfeeding laboratory evidence of immunodeficiency alcoholism or chronic liver disease the concomitant use of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs blood dyscrasia such as leukopenia, thrombocytopenia, or severe anemia active pulmonary disease hepatic, renal, or hematological dysfunction adnexal mass &gt; or = 3.5 cm presence of fetal cardiac motion active major psychiatric disorder such as major depression, bipolar disease, psychotic disorder, or drug addiction subjects unable or unwilling to comply with study procedures or illiterate</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Ectopic pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>Methotrexate</keyword>
</DOC>