<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02949037</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Multi-site feasibility study designed to assist type-2 diabetes patients in self-care activities. The study includes Bluetooth-enabled medical devices (i.e. scales, blood pressure cuffs, glucometers, and activity monitors) for both intervention and control groups. Those in the intervention group will have the devices linked too a mobile health care environment that provides key benefits that include: device data trending, reinforcing tailored behavioral messages, and enhanced communication with the clinic.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Enhancing mHealth Technology to Activate Chronic Care Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Multi-site phased study, conducted within the Military Health System that includes a user-centered design phase and a patient centered medical home (PCMH)-based feasibility trial. In Phase I the investigators will assess both patient and clinician preferences and usability regarding the enhancement of the enabling technology capabilities for Type 2 diabetes chronic self-care management. The data from the experience will be coded and analyzed by the research team and the technology will be adapted accordingly before Phase II. Phase II research is a single-blinded 12-month feasibility study that seeks to include the enabling technology to support diabetes self-care management with tailored behavioral messaging aimed at reinforcing and encouraging self-care behavior based on patients' readiness. We have included safety thresholds that alert patients and clinical team under certain conditions.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and women age 18 years or older, Ability to understand and read English, Be empanelled to one of the target PCMH sites, and Diagnosed with type 2 diabetes. pregnant women, nonEnglish speaking patients, receiving hospice care, active cancer and treatment with chemotherapy or radiation therapy, taking Coumadin, recipient of gastric bypass or similar procedure, diagnosis of uncontrolled hypothyroidism, known Cushing's syndrome, being treated with oral steroids, known liver disease, current diagnosis of cognitive impairments which would interfere with use of technology, congestive heart failure NYHA class 3 or 4, inability to use a mobile device due to cognitive or physical impairments, and PAM® score = 4 during initial screening.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>