<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01874444</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether rTMS are effective in the treatment of tinnitus</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Verify the Effectiveness rTMS Using MEG</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) of the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex (DLPFC) has an add-on effect for primary auditory cortex rTMS in improving tinnitus-related distress. We aimed to investigate whether rTMS of the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex and primary auditory cortex are capable of reducing tinnitus loudness. Linked to a neuronavigation system that is guided by magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the frontal and temporal, rTMS can suppress areas of cortical plasticity. This cortical reorganization can be demonstrated by magnetoencephalography (MEG)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tinnitus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of chronic tinnitus Chronic subjective tinnitus for more than 6 months Pure tone average &lt;50 dB HL in the ear where tinnitus is perceived Dominant tinnitus frequency measured between 4 and 8 kHz Subject is naive regarding rTMS Other concurrent treatments: A fourweek washout from any other tinnitus treatment or management program is required prior to entering this study Stable enough to complete this study per the opinion of the Study Physician No restrictions, provided the dosages have been in place for at least 3 months A three month washout from any other tinnitus treatment or management program is required prior to entering this study. Objective tinnitus or tinnitus with treatable cause Absolute thresholds &gt; 60 dB on individual frequencies up to 8 kHz Presence of intracranial or intraocular ferromagnetic materiel or particles Cardiac pacemaker or other electronic implants (including cochlear implant) Serious heart disease or other unstable major medical condition Personal history of central nervous system disorder, head injury, stroke or seizures Familial history of epilepsy; Concomitant medication with antidepressants and antipsychotics Pregnant women Severe depression Severe anxiety Others known contraindications to rTMS or brain MRI</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>