<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01874457</DOC>
	<brief_summary>On a previous study conducted in Brazil. The MMR vaccine from 2 different producers had a mumps seroconversion much lower (71%) than the expected 95%, according to the package insert. This could indicate that a substantial proportion of children was not protected after MMR dose.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Serological Study in Children 12 to 23 Months Vaccinated With MMR (Measles, Mumps and Rubella)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Given the above and considering: (1) future clinical study with the MMR vaccine produced entirely in Bio-Manguinhos/Fiocruz from technology transfer from GlaxoSmithKline (GSK), (2) the importance to the National Immunization Program (NIP) to provide the population a MMR vaccine to ensure high protection against mumps, similar to what occurs with measles and rubella components, it was considered essential to conduct a preliminary immunogenicity assessment of the MMR vaccine produced by BioManguinhos.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Measles</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rubella</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mumps</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children of both sexes; Age between 12 months to 23 months and 29 days; Child in good health, with no significant past medical history; Have completed blood sampling before vaccination; Have not been vaccinated with MMR. Agreement by parents/tutors with the child's participation in the study and signing of the Informed Consent Form (ICF); Parents/Tutors provide name, address, telephone number and other information for the contact if necessary; Parents/Tutors able to understand the risks of the experiment, although minimal; Parents/Tutors able to understand and sign the informed consent form. Availability of return for collecting postvaccination samples. Exclusion criteria: Children with a history of measles, rubella and / or mumps. Having received MMR vaccine previously, as documented in vaccination card. Having received a transfusion of blood or blood products, including immunoglobulins, within last 12 months. Skin lesions at sites of venipuncture. Child subject to abnormal bleeding after injections. Use within 6 months of corticosteroids (excluding topical or aerosol) and immunosuppressants.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>