<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02865369</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A study on regression of liver fibrosis assessed by transient elastography after Daclatasvir and Asunaprevir combined treatment in advanced fibrotic/cirrhotic patients with chronic hepatitis C genotype 1b Infection</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Regression of Liver Fibrosis After Daclatasvir and Asunaprevir Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The measurement of liver stiffness by transient elastography (TE) has been shown to correlate with the hepatic fibrosis stage and to have considerable accuracy for the diagnosis of cirrhosis in patients with chronic hepatitis C. Previous studied reported that liver stiffness is significantly reduced in SVR patients with pegylated interferon (IFN) and ribavirin treatment. Once a patient achieve sustained virological response (SVR), and resultingly lower liver stiffness score than baseline value, it is believed that he will have a better long-term outcome due to the improvement of liver fibrosis. Daclatasvir(DCV) and Asunaprevir(ASV) combined treatment showed a greater SVR rate in CHC compared to IFN based therapy. The investigators hypothesize that DCV and ASV combined treatment may achieve the improvement of liver stiffness measured by TE and a more favorable clinical outcomes in patients with advanced liver fibrosis. The investigators will also compare the change of fibrosis stage assessed by TE between this study subjects and those treated with other DAA agents during same observational period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronically infected with Hepatitis C virus genotype 1b HCV RNA ≥ 10^4 IU/mL (10,000 IU/mL) Chronic Hepatitis C with advanced fibrosis or cirrhosis (defined as ≥F3, ≥8 kilopascals) Treatmentnaïve or those who previously failed to treatment with peginterferon alfa and ribavirin Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) and men, who use effective methods of birth control Patients with baseline key NS5A RAVs (Y93 and/or L31) Estimated GFR &lt; 30mL/min without hemodialysis Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt; 100 IU/L Coinfection with other hepatitis virus or human immunodeficiency virus A daily alcohol intake &gt;30 g Decompensated liver disease or hepatocellular carcinoma, liver or any other organ transplantation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>chronic hepatitis C</keyword>
	<keyword>Daclatasvir</keyword>
	<keyword>Asunaprevir</keyword>
	<keyword>fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>transient elastography</keyword>
</DOC>