<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01687231</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In the transplant community, there is debate regarding the most appropriate food services for stem cell transplant patients. Recommendations regarding the use of low bacterial diets have been based on theoretical concepts of reducing the risk of contracting infections from pathogens found in food sources rather than clinical trials. The evidence for the use of a neutropenic diet is weak. To date, there have been little to no randomized controlled studies addressing the question whether a neutropenic diet in addition to prophylactic antibiotics is necessary as infection prevention in myeloablative stem cell transplant patients. For this reason, our research is aimed at providing data to substantiate the use of neutropenic diets in preventing infections in recipients of myeloablative stem cell transplants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Infection Rates of Myeloablative Allo SCT Recipients Receiving Neutropenic Diets Versus Non-Neutropenic Diets</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In the proposed pilot study, a randomized design will be used to address the primary and secondary aims. Subjects will be randomized to either the experimental group receiving a non-neutropenic diet without restriction, or to the control group receiving the standard neutropenic diet. While randomization will occur prior to, or on the day of their inpatient admission and the subjects will begin study procedures upon admission to the Adult Stem Cell Transplant Inpatient Unit at Duke University Medical Center. The diet will continue until 1) the subject is no longer neutropenic, and/or 2) discharged from the inpatient unit to continue their care in the Adult Stem Cell Transplant Outpatient Clinic. By limiting the study to the time of care on the inpatient unit, we will minimize the opportunity for deviation from the assigned diet. Absence of neutropenia will be defined as an absolute neutrophil count of greater than 500/uL (manual differential) and a total white blood cell count of 1000/uL for three consecutive days. All subjects enrolled will follow the standard prophylactic antibiotic regimen. Other supportive care will also be consistent in the two groups.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Scheduled to undergo a myeloablative allogeneic stem cell transplant for any cancer or noncancer illness from any related or unrelated donor source including bone marrow, peripheral blood progenitor cell, or umbilical cord blood 2. Age 2070 years of age 3. Karnofsky Performance Scale KPS&gt; 80 4. Ability to read and write English 1. Autologous stem cell transplant recipients 2. Nonmyeloablative or reduced intensity stem cell transplant recipients 3. Pregnant women 4. Patients with a documented active infection prior to starting their preparative regimen. This includes grade 3 or higher viral, bacterial, or fungal infection.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neutropenic Diet, Non-Neutropenic Diet, Allogeneic SCT</keyword>
</DOC>