<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00608673</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Discoid lupus erythematosus lesions are commonly treated with corticosteroids, but corticosteroids may induce side effects such as thinning of the skin or scarring. Therefore, an alternative medication with the same efficacy, but without the side-effects is sought after. Pimecrolimus is a newer drug specially designed to treat inflammatory diseases of skin. Its efficacy in treating discoid lupus erythematosus has not been studied extensively yet. However studies performed till now show promising results. Long-term topical use of this medication has not shown any serious side-effects in other skin diseases. In this study we aimed at comparing pimecrolimus efficacy with that of a common therapeutic choice, betamethasone valerate 0.1% cream, to see if pimecrolimus can be used as an alternative medication in treating discoid lupus erythematosus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparing the Therapeutic Efficacy of Pimecrolimus Cream With Betamethasone Cream for Discoid Lupus Erythematosus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Discoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Betamethasone benzoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Betamethasone-17,21-dipropionate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pimecrolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Betamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Betamethasone Valerate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Betamethasone sodium phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients harboring discoid lupus erythematosus lesions on their face or neck Patients with discoid lupus erythematosus in the setting of systemic lupus erythematosus Patients having a more disseminated disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>discoid lupus erythematosus</keyword>
	<keyword>pimecrolimus 1% cream</keyword>
	<keyword>betamethasone valerate 0.1% cream</keyword>
</DOC>