<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00608530</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This double blind, randomized, parallel groups, two arm, six month clinical trial. Patients will have chronic low back pain of non-neoplastic origin. Patients will be randomized to one of two conditions, either Cognitive Behavioral Training or Rogerian psychotherapy; both conditions are home-based, telephone supported, with 10 hours of contact time delivered over 8 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Telehealth Outreach for Chronic Back Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Chronic low back pain (CLBP) is a major medical problem for the VA, affecting up to 15% of all veterans in primary care. Furthermore, prior surveys indicate CLBP is a leading cause of medical discharge of active duty personnel, and of medical disability costs. Given current demands on military personnel it is likely the burden of chronic pain will increase. The VA has adopted the Agency for Health Care Policy and Research Guidelines for evaluation of back pain but these guidelines do not provide specifics for true rehabilitation. It is acknowledged that most back pain patients are not surgical candidates, that medications provide only limited analgesia, and that symptom control and improved function require a comprehensive approach addressing the cognitive, affective, and behavioral aspects of chronic pain. Fortunately, structured, specific interventions to both address the multidimensional nature of pain and operationalize treatment principles in primary care settings are available. These interventions, which reflect the VA emphasis on patient-centered care, can be effective in reducing disability and pain, but are a frequently overlooked component of effective care. One reason is that most clinics lack appropriately trained specialists. Moreover, even when specialists are available, the prevailing clinic-based service model is either too resource-intensive, or presents barriers to access. One approach to addressing some these barriers is the use of "telehealth" outreach. Studies in diverse medical disorders and some chronic pain syndromes suggest that care can be delivered efficiently and effectively with minimal therapist contact in home-based treatment models, using telephone consultation to replace clinic visits. These approaches are fully congruent with recent VA telehealth initiatives to improve access and cost efficiency. In VA Pain Clinic settings our face-to-face, 8-week, 8-hours contact time Cogntive Behavioral Self-Managment Skills Training (CBSST) program appears to be effective in reducing disability and pain, and improving mood in chronic back pain. We propose a double blind, randomized assignment, two-arm, parallel groups, six month clinical trial. Patients with CLBP will be recruited from VA San Diego primary care clinics and the community. Subjects will receive either CBSST (N = 65) or Rogerian Psychotherapy (N=65) in a home-based, telephone delivered format for a total of 10 hours of therapist contact time. Assessments will be conducted at baseline and at end of treatment, and at one, three and six months post-treatment. The primary data analytic strategy will be an intent-to-treat analysis (last observation carried forward) of all participants as randomized. The primary end point will be physical function (Roland &amp; Morris Disability) at end of 8-week treatment; secondary end points will be pain intensity (Numeric Rating Scale) and patient-reported clinical global impression of change. Supplemental analyses will be conducted to test for durability of therapeutic effect at one, three, and six month post-treatment. Rigorously controlled clinical trials of the type we propose could contribute to more effective and more cost-efficient back pain treatment. Key Words: Back Pain, Cognitive-Behavioral Treatment, Clinical Trial</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Ages 1875 inclusive; 2. chronic musculoskeletal low back pain (pain "on a daily basis" for at least six months) as the primary pain problem; 3. not eligible for back surgery; 4. presently lives in the San Diego area and will do so six months after baseline examination; 5. Englishspeaking, literate, with stable residence and phone. 1. Major medical illness (e.g., insulindependent diabetes mellitus with neuropathy or "poor control", heart disease with New York Heart Association Functional Class III or IV, or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease requiring supplemental oxygen which might confound effects of pain on function); 2. candidate for spine surgery; 3. back pain associated with pregnancy, rheumatoid arthritis, neoplastic disease, osteomyelitis, or neural arch lesions, since their treatment and prognosis differs from the usual back pain population, or spinal stenosis, since increased physical activity would be contraindicated; 4. history of Diagnostic and Statistical Manual (DSM)IV bipolar disorder, dementia, or schizophrenia; 5. current active DSMIV diagnosed alcohol or nonprescribed substance dependence; 6. current active DSMIV major depressive episode or posttraumatic stress disorder since specialty mental health care would be indicated; 7. nonopioid and opioid analgesics are permitted, except we will exclude patients on a hospitalinitiated opioid treatment "contract," since at this medical center "contracting" identifies patients with history of opioid diversion, multiple VA and nonVA opioid prescribers, and repeated dose escalation in the absence of evidence of disease progression.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>pain</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic pain</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic back pain</keyword>
	<keyword>randomized clinical trial</keyword>
</DOC>