<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02735044</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: To compare the efficacy of HOE901-U300 to Lantus in terms of glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) Secondary Objectives: - To compare HOE901-U300 and Lantus in terms of: - Percentage of patients reaching target HbA1c and fasting plasma glucose (FPG). - To assess the safety of HOE901-U300 including analysis of events of hypoglycemia, events of hyperglycemia with ketosis, and development of anti-insulin-antibodies.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of the Safety and Efficacy of HOE901-U300 With Lantus in Children and Adolescents With Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study duration per patient will be approximately 58 weeks that consists of a 2 week screening period, a 6-month comparative efficacy and safety treatment period, a 6-month comparative safety extension period, and a 4-week post treatment follow up period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Glargine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria : Children and adolescents with type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM) for at least 1 year confirmed by typical symptoms at diagnosis and/or by antibody testing (presence of antiGAD (glutamic acid decarboxylase) or antiIA2 (islet antigen 2/tyrosine phosphatase) or antiislet cell antibodies) and/or clinical features (eg, history of ketoacidosis). Signed written informed consent obtained from parent(s)/legal guardian and written or oral assent obtained from patient. Exclusion criteria: Age &lt;6 years and ≥18 years at randomization. Less than 1 year on insulin treatment prior to screening visit. Less than 6 months on basal plus mealtime insulin and selfmonitoring of blood glucose prior to screening visit. Patients using premix insulins in the last 3 months before screening visit or patients using human regular insulin as mealtime insulin in the last 3 months before screening visit. Use of an insulin pump in the last 6 months before screening visit or plans to switch to pump within the next 6 months after screening visit. No willingness to inject insulin glargine (Lantus or HOE901 [U300]) once daily. HbA1c &lt;7.5% or &gt;11% at screening. Initiation of any glucoselowering medications in the last 3 months before screening visit. Hospitalization or care in the emergency ward for diabetic ketoacidosis or history of severe hypoglycemia (as defined by need for glucagon or IV glucose) and accompanied by seizure and/or unconsciousness and/or coma in the last 3 months prior to screening visit. Postmenarchal girls not protected by highlyeffective method(s) of birth control and/or who are unwilling or unable to be tested for pregnancy. Abstinence from sexual intercourse will be considered as an acceptable form of birth control. Pregnant or breastfeeding adolescents, or adolescents who intend to become pregnant during the study period, or who are at risk of getting pregnant due to any psychosocial reason during the study period. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>