<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02735135</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to compare the AIRSOFT DUO and the SENTRY 1200 constant pressure mattresses in terms of peak skin pressures measured at the sacral area.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of 2 Mattresses for the Prevention of Bedsores by Measuring Skin Pressure in the Sacral Area</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The secondary objectives of the study are to compare the two devices in terms of: A. body contact surface area. B. peak pressure at the heel area (combining right and left heels) C. occurrence of pressure ulcers anywhere on the body for 1 month D. patient comfort rated at 1 month (visual analog scale varying from 0-10) E. noise (Likert Scale). F. sleep quality (visual analog scale varying from 0-10).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pressure Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient must have given his/her informed and signed consent The patient must be insured or beneficiary of a health insurance plan The patient spends more than 12 hours in bed and verticalisation is possible The patient has a stable medical condition (no complication in the last 10 days) and no visible pressure ulcers The patient is at risk for pressure ulcers as assessed by a score ≤ 15 on the Braden Scale The patient weighs less than 120 kg The patient is in an exclusion period determined by a previous study The patient is under judicial protection, under tutorship or curatorship The patient refuses to sign the consent It is impossible to correctly inform the patient The subject has a contraindication for a strictly supine position The patient has a knee flexion deformity &gt; 10 ° The patient is in a state of agitation or refuses to cooperate The patient's weight is greater than 120 Kg The length of stay is less than one month</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>bedridden</keyword>
</DOC>