<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02735499</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Instillation treatment with onabotulinumtoxin A (BOTOX速) in the urinary bladder</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Instillation of Botox in the Bladder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Pilot study to evaluate the effect of instillation treatment with onabotulinumtoxin A (BOTOX速) in the urinary bladder using Electromotive Drug Application (EMDA) in women with overactive bladder. 15 women with therapy-resistant OAB will be included. All patients must be qualified for conventional cystoscopic Botox injection. The study is not randomized or blinded. Follow-up time is six months with voiding charts and three questionnaires.(UDI-6, IIQ-7, ICIQ-UI SF) as well as a satisfaction with treatment VAS.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Overactive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>onabotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Botulinum Toxins, Type A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>abobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>incobotulinumtoxinA</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent form signed OAB/urgency incontinence of at least 3 months duration Conservative treatment (medicines, electrical stimulation) has been tried without sufficient benefit There is indication for cystoscopic injection treatment with Botox速 More than 3months since any previous treatment with Botox速 Detrusor overactivity documented by cystometry is desirable, but not obligatory Age below 18 years Mixed incontinence with predominant stress component Insuffcient understanding of Norwegian and / or unable to fill out the necessary forms Ongoing urinary tract infection (UTI) (defined as positive urine stix (nitrite and leucocytes) with symptoms of UTI) must be treated before inclusion. Any contraindication stated in the SPC for Botox</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>onabotulinum toxin A</keyword>
	<keyword>Urinary bladder</keyword>
	<keyword>EMDA</keyword>
	<keyword>iontophoresis</keyword>
	<keyword>electrophoresis</keyword>
	<keyword>Urinary incontinence</keyword>
</DOC>