<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02170168</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The overall aim of this project is to deliver better health care services through improved coordination of cancer care within specialist care (at the local hospital Orkdal Hospital) and community care (13 municipalities in the Orkdal region, Norway), and between these two levels in the health care system. "The Orkdal model" is developed and will be implemented and evaluated within cancer care. Cancer patients living in one of the 12 municipalities participating in the formal collaboration "Samhandlingsenheten i Orkdalsregionen" (SIO), or the municipality of Oppdal, having metastatic and/or loco-regional disease will be included in the study. Carers and health care providers will be included as well. Results from this project will be transferable to other parts of Norway and/or to other countries as well as to patients with other diagnoses causing complex conditions, such as chronic heart-, lung- and neurological disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Orkdal Model. Collaboration Between Specialist and Community Care Within Palliative Cancer Care</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will be a prospective controlled observational pre-post study. The intervention consists of three parts: a standardised care pathway, an educational programme and information to general public, patients and their carers. Data from patients, carers and health care providers (physicians, nurses and nurse assistants) will be collected before the model is implemented (pre-intervention part) and after final implementation (post-intervention part). In addition, a comparison with a similar patient population, carers and health care providers will be conducted. A local hospital in the county of Romsdal and community care in the same region will be used as control.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria (Patients): Advanced locoregional disease and/or metastatic cancer disease For the intervention group in the Orkdal region: Inhabitant of one of the following thirteen districts: Surnadal, Halsa, Rindal, Hemne, Orkdal, Frøya, Hitra, Snillfjord, Agdenes, Meldal, Rennebu, Skaun, and Oppdal For the intervention group in the Romsdal region: Inhabitiant of one of the following nine districts: Aukra, Molde, Eide, Vestnes, Sunndal, Fræna, Midsund, Nesset, Rauma Acceptance of participation, based on information about the study and that participation is voluntary. Documented by a signed consent form. Able to comply with the study procedures Able to read and write Norwegian Inclusion criteria (Carers) (a carer a person identified as such by the patient) the patient is eligible for the study the patient has given his or her consent to allow the study nurse to approach the carer to participate in the study the patient has identified the carer to be approached acceptance of participation, based on information about the study and that participation is voluntary. Documented by a signed consent form. Inclusion Criteria (Health care providers) has accepted to participate in the study Acceptance of participation, based on information about the study and that participation is voluntary. Documented by an electronically signed consent form. Exclusion Criteria (Patients): Receiving anticancer treatment with curative intent Exclusion Criteria (Carers) not able to complete the assessments</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Community health services</keyword>
	<keyword>Models, organizational</keyword>
	<keyword>Referral and consultation</keyword>
	<keyword>Palliative medicine</keyword>
	<keyword>Terminal care</keyword>
</DOC>