<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02972580</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Longitudinal prospective observational study. This is a 24-month study with the possibility of extending the data time points. Initially baseline, then 12 and 24 months follow up studies will be completed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Characterization of Clinical Skeletal and Cardiac Impairment in Carriers of DMD and BMD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Three cohorts are enrolled in this study. The target population is the cohort of genetically confirmed DMD/BMD female carriers (Cohort A). This cohort will consist of 150 DMD/BMD mothers who are somatic carriers of a mutation in the DMD gene. The data collected for this cohort will be compared to two control groups; Control Group B is a cohort of 50 DMD/BMD mothers who are NOT somatic carriers and Control Group C is a cohort of 50 age-matched healthy controls. The inclusion of a Control Group B allows for a comparison to a group of mothers that share the emotional and cognitive burden of caring for an affected male without having the physical or cognitive risks of being a female carrier. The Control Group C offers robust data from an age-matched healthy cohort for purposes of comparison.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Muscular Dystrophies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Muscular Dystrophy, Duchenne</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt;18 years Cohort A requires a genetically confirmed mutation in the DMD gene with an affected son Cohort B includes DMD/BMD mothers with NO somatic mutation in the DMD gene Cohort C agematched healthy controls with a normal CK level Able to complete testing in English Able to consent Subjects with a contraindication to cardiac or skeletal muscle MRI Subjects on heart failure medication at time of enrollment Subjects on steroid treatment Presence of an inherited neurologic disease or comorbidity that may affect their ability to complete this study Has a medical condition or extenuating circumstance that, in the opinion of the investigator, might compromise the subject's ability to comply with the protocol required testing or procedures or compromise the subject's wellbeing, safety, or clinical interpretability</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>