<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02972528</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Allogenic defibrinated platelet rich plasma lysate will be injected in patients diagnosed with Diabetic Foot Ulcer (DFU).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Use of Allogenic Platelet Rich Plasma for the Treatment of Diabetic Foot Ulcer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this study, allogenic, defibrinated platelet rich plasma lysate will be used as a direct injection into the periphery of diabetic chronic foot ulcers which have not healed using standard of care. Investigators anticipate a significant response in treated individuals measured by the percentage of skin restoration achieved.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetic Foot</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Foot Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Persons with type 1 or type 2 diabetes between the ages of 18 and 70 with an ulcer of at least 4 weeks duration 2. HemoglobinA1C (HbA1c) &lt; 12 3. Index foot ulcer located on the plantar, medial, or lateral aspect of the foot (including all toe surfaces); and wound area (length x width) measurement between 2 cm2 and 20 cm2, inclusive. 4. Wounds located under a Charcot deformity had to be free of acute changes and must have under gone appropriate structural consolidation. 5. The index ulcer had to be clinically noninfected and full thickness without exposure of bone, ligaments, or tendons. 6. The protocol requires that post debridement the ulcer would be free of necrotic debris, foreign bodies or sinus tracts. 7. Non invasive vascular testing ankle brachial index (ABI). 8. Physical examination (including a SemmesWeinstein monofilament test for neuropathy) 9. Blood tests to be obtained Complete Blood Count and HbA1c. 10. Approved, informed, signed consent. 11. Negative test for Hepatitis C (HC), Hepatitis B (HB), Human Immunodeficiency Virus 1 and 2 (HIVI and II), Venereal Disease Research Laboratory (VDRL). 1. Patient currently enrolled in another investigational device or drug trial or previously enrolled (within last 30 days) in investigative research of a device or pharmaceutical agent. 2. Ulcer decreased ≥50% in area during 7day screening period. 3. Ulcer is due to nondiabetic etiology. 4. Patient's blood vessels are noncompressible for ABI testing. 5. Evidence of gangrene in ulcer or on any part of the foot. 6. Patient has radiographic evidence consistent with diagnosis of acute Charcot foot. 7. Patient is currently receiving or has received radiation or chemotherapy within 3 months of randomization. 8. Patient has received growth factor therapy within 7 days of randomization. 9. Screening hemoglobin &lt;10.5 mg/dL. 10. Screening platelet count &lt; 100 x 109/L. 11. Patient is undergoing renal dialysis, has known immune insufficiency, known abnormal platelet activation disorders — ie, gray platelet syndrome, liver disease, active cancer (except remote basal cell of the skin), eating/ nutritional,hematologic, collagen vascular disease, rheumatic disease, or bleeding disorders. 12. History of peripheral vascular repair within the 30 days of randomization 13. Patient has known or suspected osteomyelitis. 14. Surgical correction (other than debridement) required for ulcer to heal. 15. Index ulcer has exposed tendons, ligaments, muscle, or bone. 16. Patient is known to have a psychological, developmental, physical, emotional, or social disorder, or any other situation that may interfere with compliance with study requirements and/or healing of the ulcer 17. History of alcohol or drug abuse within the last year prior to randomization. 18. Patient has inadequate venous access for blood draw. 19. Positive test for HC, HB, HIVI and II, VDRL.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>DFU</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetic Foot Ulcer</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Platelet Rich Plasma</keyword>
</DOC>