<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00057759</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Sildenafil may be effective in helping patients who have undergone treatment for prostate cancer to have an erection for sexual activity and may improve sexual satisfaction and quality of life. PURPOSE: Randomized clinical trial to study the effectiveness of sildenafil in treating erectile dysfunction in patients who have undergone radiation therapy and hormone therapy for prostate cancer in clinical trial RTOG-9910.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sildenafil in Treating Erectile Dysfunction in Patients With Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Compare the effect of sildenafil vs placebo on erectile dysfunction in patients with prostate cancer treated with radiotherapy and antiandrogens on RTOG-9910. - Compare the overall sexual function and satisfaction of patients treated with these regimens. - Compare sexual satisfaction of partners of patients treated with these regimens. - Compare patient and partner marital adjustment after treatment with these regimens. - Determine factors that may predict response to sildenafil, including age, pretreatment sexual function, tobacco use, and comorbidities in these patients. OUTLINE: This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to prior use of sildenafil after treatment on RTOG-9910 and level of response (No vs yes [unsatisfactory] vs yes [satisfactory]), International Index of Erectile Function (IIEF) Question #1 score (0-1 vs 2-3), and RTOG-9910 treatment arm (I vs II). Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. - Arm I: Patients receive oral sildenafil 1 hour prior to desired sexual intercourse. - Arm II: Patients receive oral placebo 1 hour prior to desired sexual intercourse. Treatment on both arms continues for 12 weeks. Patients then cross over to treatment on the other arm for 12 weeks. Quality of life, including sexual function, marital adjustment, and partner's satisfaction, is assessed at baseline, at 12 and 25 weeks, and at 1 year. Patients are followed at 1 year. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 332 patients (166 per treatment arm) will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erectile Dysfunction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Radiation Injuries</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sildenafil Citrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citric Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Prior treatment on RTOG9910 for intermediate relapserisk stage II or III prostate cancer as determined by any of the following combinations of factors: T1b4, Gleason score 26, and prostatespecific antigen (PSA) greater than 10 ng/mL but no greater than 100 ng/mL T1b4, Gleason score 7, and PSA less than 20 ng/mL T1b1c, Gleason score 810, and PSA less than 20 ng/mL Radiotherapy completed within the past 6 months to 5 years Pretreatment (before enrollment on this study) erectile dysfunction as measured by International Index of Erectile Function Question #1 Erectile dysfunction before starting prostate cancer therapy allowed Patients without partners or without partners willing to participate allowed PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 18 and over Performance status Zubrod 02 Life expectancy Not specified Hematopoietic Not specified Hepatic Not specified Renal Not specified Cardiovascular No myocardial infarction within the past year Other No other invasive cancer within the past 5 years except localized basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer (stage 0II) No anatomical genital abnormalities or concurrent conditions that would prohibit sexual intercourse or preclude study participation No other major medical or psychiatric illness that would preclude study participation PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy Not specified Chemotherapy Not specified Endocrine therapy More than 6 months since prior androgen suppression (e.g., leuprolide or goserelin), antiandrogen (e.g., bicalutamide, flutamide, or nilutamide), or estrogenic (e.g., diethylstilbestrol) agents Radiotherapy See Disease Characteristics Surgery No prior penile implant No prior bilateral orchiectomy Other No concurrent sildenafil No concurrent participation in another medical research study to treat prostate cancer No concurrent organic nitrate or requirement for nitrates (e.g., nitroglycerin as needed) No concurrent ketoconazole, itraconazole, or erythromycin No concurrent use of mechanical (vacuum) devices or intracorporeal, intraurethral, topical, or oral agents for erectile dysfunction</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>sexual dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>sexuality and reproductive issues</keyword>
	<keyword>radiation toxicity</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIB prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IIA prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>psychosocial effects of cancer and its treatment</keyword>
</DOC>