<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00199732</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Serum HBV DNA is a referent but insufficient marker of therapeutic follow-up in chronic hepatitis B treatment. Intra hepatic cccDNA disappearance reflects HBV eradication in the liver. Intra lymphocyte cccDNA could be a new marker of HBV eradication after treatment. The major interest of this marker is that it can be measured by a simple blood test instead of a liver biopsy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of cccDNA and Total HBV DNA Kinetics in Lymphocytes, Total Blood and Serum in Chronic Hepatitis B Patients Treated With Adefovir Dipivoxil and Peg Interferon Alpha 2a</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>- Studying intra lymphocyte and blood cccDNA: before inclusions, D0 then each month during the first three months each three months during treatment and follow-up. - Viral kinetics:Before inclusions, at D0, then monthly till the end of treatment and follow-up: Evolution of quantitative viraemia in serum Evolution of quantitative viraemia in circulating lymphocytes Evolution of quantitative viraemia in total blood - Studying viral genotypes</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adefovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adefovir dipivoxil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2a</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female patients &gt;18 years of age and &lt;70 years of age Patients AgHbs+ and AgHbe+ or AgHbe, and B viral DNA &gt;104 copies/ml PCR COBAS MONITOR Patients treated with adefovir dipivoxil and peg interferon alpha 2a Chronic liver disease consistent with chronic hepatitis B infection on a biopsy obtained within the past 24 months Naïve patients or patients having a relapse or a therapeutic failure after monotherapy lamivudine or interferon, or bitherapy interferon alphalamivudine Coinfection HIV, HCV</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2005</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic hepatitis B</keyword>
	<keyword>CCC DNA kinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Total HBV DNA kinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>Adefovir-Dipovixil</keyword>
	<keyword>Peg interferon alpha 2a</keyword>
</DOC>