<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00199901</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this trial is to assess whether treatment with NY-ESO-1 ISCOMATRIX® vaccine improves outcomes for people with Malignant Melanoma which has been removed, but is at high risk of relapse.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of NY-ESO-1 ISCOMATRIX® in Patients With High-risk, Resected Melanoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>NY-ESO-1 protein is an immune target found in many cancers including melanoma. ISCOMATRIX® adjuvant enhances immune responses. This trial compares NY-ESO-1 ISCOMATRIX® vaccine with ISCOMATRIX® adjuvant alone to assess whether treatment with NY-ESO-1 ISCOMATRIX® vaccine improves outcomes for participants with Malignant Melanoma which has been removed, but is at high risk of recurrence. Eligible participants are randomly allocated to a treatment arm. Treatment involves four intramuscular (into a muscle) injections (1 injection every 4 weeks x 3, plus 1 injection at 6 months). Participants are assessed for recurrence of melanoma, safety and immune responses (by blood test) over the 18 month study period. Off study, their own doctor will follow them for melanoma recurrence and survival.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically proven malignant melanoma. Tumor expression of NYESO1 antigen by immunohistochemistry. Fully resected AJCC stage IIc, IIIb, IIIc or IV melanoma. Within six months of surgery for melanoma. Full recovery from surgery. No immunotherapy or systemic adjuvant therapy for melanoma since most recent relapse and/or resection. (Previous adjuvant therapy accepted providing pt relapsed and resected after this.) Age 18 years or older. Able to give written informed consent. Vital laboratory parameters within normal range, or protocol specified ranges. Other serious or significant illnesses. Resected cerebral metastases. Ocular melanoma. Other malignancy within last 3 years, except for treated nonmelanoma skin cancer and cervical cancer in situ. Using immunosuppressive drugs. Anticoagulation. Known HIV positivity. Chemotherapy or radiation therapy in last four weeks (6 weeks for nitrosourea drugs). Not available for immunological and clinical followup assessments. Participation in prior clinical trial involving an investigational agent within last 4 weeks. Previous isolated limb perfusion (ILP). Pregnancy or breastfeeding. Refusal or inability to use effective means of contraception for women of childbearing potential. Mental impairment that may compromise ability to give informed consent and to comply with study requirements.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Phase II</keyword>
	<keyword>Randomized Controlled Trial</keyword>
	<keyword>Double-Blind</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>NY-ESO-1 protein, human</keyword>
	<keyword>ISCOMATRIX, immunological adjuvant</keyword>
</DOC>