<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00199082</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study evaluates the efficacy and tolerability of alternating short cycles of high-dose and conventional chemotherapy in combination with rituximab in CD20 positive patients, followed by local radiation therapy in the case of initial mediastinal or central nervous system (CNS) involvement or a residual tumor after chemotherapy. A dose-reduced regimen is offered for patients estimated to be over 55 years, biologically.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial for the Treatment of Newly Diagnosed Mature B-Cell Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia (B-ALL), Burkitt's Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma (NHL) and Other High-grade Lymphoma in Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Burkitt Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mediastinal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large-Cell, Anaplastic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cytarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ifosfamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxorubicin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vincristine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vindesine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Burkitt's leukemia or Burkitt's lymphoma or primary mediastinal large Bcell lymphoma or Bprecursor lymphoblastic lymphoma or large cell anaplastic lymphoma Age &gt; 15 years Written informed consent Serious secondary diseases, including psychiatric conditions, under which the required therapy compliance is not to be expected HIV infection Secondary lymphoma following prior chemotherapy/radiotherapy or active second malignancy Known severe allergy to foreign proteins Pretreatment other than 1 cycle CHOP or similar; &lt; 1 week of another chemotherapy. Pregnancy or nursing Participation in other studies that interfere with study therapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>High-grade NHL</keyword>
	<keyword>De novo</keyword>
	<keyword>Mature B-ALL</keyword>
	<keyword>Burkitt'S NHL</keyword>
	<keyword>Chemotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Rituximab</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary mediastinal diffuse large cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>B-precursor lymphoblastic lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>