<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02224703</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate the potential antiepileptic effects of cannabidiol (GWP42003-P) in children and young adults with Dravet syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>GWPCARE2 A Study to Investigate the Efficacy and Safety of Cannabidiol (GWP42003-P) in Children and Young Adults With Dravet Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is a 1:1:1 randomized, double-blind, 14-week comparison of two Dose Levels of GWP42003-P versus placebo. A 28-day screening period prior to randomization (to establish baseline parameters) will precede the treatment period, which will consist of a two-week titration period followed by a 12-week maintenance period. The study will aim to determine the efficacy, safety and tolerability of GWP42003-P compared with placebo. The High Dose Level will be as recommended by the Data Safety Monitoring Committee (DSMC) after assessment of safety and pharmacokinetic data from Part A of study GWEP1332. The Low Dose Level will be defined as 50% of the High Dose Level. The first subject will not enroll into this study until the DSMC has reviewed the safety data from Part A of study GWEP1332. Following study completion, all subjects will be invited to continue to receive GWP42003-P in an open label extension (OLE) study (under a separate protocol).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epilepsies, Myoclonic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Subject must be male or female aged between 2 and 18 years (inclusive). Subject must have a documented history of Dravet syndrome which is not completely controlled by current antiepileptic drugs. Subject must be taking one or more antiepileptic drugs at a dose which has been stable for at least four weeks. All medications or interventions for epilepsy (including ketogenic diet and vagus nerve stimulation) must have been stable for four weeks prior to screening and subject is willing to maintain a stable regimen throughout the study. Key Subject has clinically significant unstable medical conditions other than epilepsy. Subject has had clinically relevant symptoms or a clinically significant illness in the four weeks prior to screening or randomization, other than epilepsy. Subject is currently using or has in the past used recreational or medicinal cannabis, or synthetic cannabinoid based medications (including Sativex®) within the three months prior to study entry and is unwilling to abstain for the duration for the study. Subject has any known or suspected hypersensitivity to cannabinoids or any of the excipients of the investigational medicinal products. There are plans for the subject to travel outside their country of residence during the study. Any history of suicidal behavior or any suicidal ideation of type four or five on the ColumbiaSuicide Severity Rating Scale (Children's) at screening.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cannabidiol</keyword>
	<keyword>CBD</keyword>
	<keyword>GWP42003-P</keyword>
</DOC>