<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02224573</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate the potential antiepileptic effects of cannabidiol (GWP42003-P) in children and young adults with Dravet or Lennox-Gastaut syndromes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An Open Label Extension Study of Cannabidiol (GWP42003-P) in Children and Young Adults With Dravet or Lennox-Gastaut Syndromes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multi-center, open label extension study for patients with Dravet syndrome or Lennox-Gastaut syndrome who have previously participated in double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical studies of GWP42003-P (Core Studies). The first subject will not enroll into the open label extension study until the Data Safety Monitoring Committee has reviewed the safety data from Part A of study GWEP1332.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lennox Gastaut Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epilepsies, Myoclonic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key • Subject has completed all scheduled visits in the treatment phase of their Core Study. Key Subject is currently using recreational or medicinal cannabis, or synthetic cannabinoid based medications (including Sativex®) other than the investigational medicinal product (IMP) and are unwilling to abstain for the duration for the study. Any history of suicidal behavior or any suicidal ideation of type four or five on the CSSRS at Visit 1. Subject has been part of a clinical trial involving an IMP during the interstudy period. Female subject is of child bearing potential or male subject's partner is of child bearing potential, unless willing to ensure that they or their partner use effective contraception, for example, oral contraception, double barrier, intra uterine device, during the study and for three months thereafter (however a male condom should not be used in conjunction with a female condom). Subject has significantly impaired hepatic function at the 'End of Treatment' visit of their Core Study or at Visit 1 if reassessed: i) Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt;5 × upper limit of normal (ULN). ii) ALT or AST &gt;3 × ULN and (total bilirubin [TBL] &gt;2 × ULN or international normalized ratio [INR] &gt;1.5). iii) ALT or AST &gt;3 × ULN with the presence of fatigue, nausea, vomiting, right upper quadrant pain or tenderness, fever, rash, and/or eosinophilia (&gt;5%). This criterion must be confirmed prior to entering the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cannabidiol</keyword>
	<keyword>CBD</keyword>
	<keyword>GWP42003-P</keyword>
</DOC>