<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01276262</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A crossover study to assess the effect of repeated doses of fostamatinib on the levels of oral contraceptive (Microgynon® 30) in the blood of healthy female subjects. The study will consist of a screening period of up to 35 days, followed by 2 treatment periods (28 days each) of an oral contraceptive (Microgynon® 30) in the absence and presence of fostamatinib. The study will also evaluate the safety and tolerability of fostamatinib in combination with an oral contraceptive</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Administration of Fostamatinib on Blood Concentrations of an Oral Contraceptive in Healthy Female Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Contraceptives, Oral</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethinyl estradiol, levonorgestrel drug combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethinyl Estradiol-Norgestrel Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Contraceptive Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female subjects of age 18 to 45 years, inclusive, who are healthy, nonpregnant, not planning pregnancy within the study period Willing to use a highly effective method of birth control, ie, double barrier method contraception (condom and diaphragm with spermicide) from the first day of Period 1 until 28 days after the last dose Body weight of at least 50 kg and body mass index (BMI) between 18 and 30 kg/m2 inclusive Two negative pregnancy tests at least 7 days apart History of any clinically significant disease or disorder History or presence of Gastrointestinal, hepatic, or renal disease Any condition listed as a contraindication in the Microgynon® 30 labelling Absolute neutrophil count less than 2.5 x 109/L.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Phase 1, healthy female volunteers, oral contraceptive, pharmacokinetics, Rheumatoid arthritis, RA, fostamatinib</keyword>
</DOC>