<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01740076</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To determine the effect of a whole soy food, dietary soy nuts, on blood pressure, lipid levels, inflammation and menopausal symptoms in postmenopausal women.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Soy Nuts and Cardiovascular Risk in Postmenopausal Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The present study examines the effect of a whole soy food, soy nuts (dry roasted soybeans), added to the Therapeutic Lifestyle Change diet on blood pressure, lipids, inflammation and menopausal symptoms in postmenopausal hypertensive and normotensive women in a randomized crossover trial during an 8-week period. We sought to determine whether dietary soy had an additional benefit to the currently recommended heart healthy diet.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Calcium Carbonate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women with absence of menses for at least 12 months or irregular periods and hot flashes. were current cigarette smoking or smoking in the previous year; clinical coronary artery disease, peripheral artery disease, or cerebrovascular disease; known diabetes mellitus or a fasting glucose level of 126 mg/dL or greater; a history of breast cancer; a fasting triglyceride level greater than 400 mg/dL; systolic BP of 165 mm Hg or greater or diastolic BP of 100 mm Hg or greater; untreated hypothyroidism; systemic or endocrine disease known to affect lipid, mineral, or bone metabolism; and consumption of more than 21 alcoholic drinks per week. Use of lipidlowering drugs, hormone therapy, medications for osteoporosis, and soy products was discontinued for 2 months before entering the study. Participants took a multivitamin but no additional vitamin or mineral supplements or other soy products during the study.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>isoflavones, hypertension, soy, diet, nutrition, women, inflammation, hot flashes</keyword>
</DOC>