<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00916071</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To understand whether a relationship exists between eating disorders and ADHD, we seek to clarify the prevalence of ADHD in individuals with eating disorders. To this end, we will estimate the prevalence of ADHD, and other neuropsychiatric disorders, in outpatients with history of an eating disorder diagnosis. Secondarily, we will identify patterns of cognitive deficits in outpatients with history of an eating disorder diagnosis. We will also examine whether ADHD in this population is associated with functional and familial correlates associated with ADHD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Association Between Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder and Bulimia Nervosa in Outpatients With Eating Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Feeding and Eating Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bulimia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bulimia Nervosa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male and female outpatients between, and including, 18 and 55 years of age with a history of eating disorder diagnosis. Any clinically unstable psychiatric conditions such as: acute psychosis, acute panic, acute obsessive compulsive disorder, acute mania, acute suicidality, acute substance use disorders (alcohol or drugs), and sociopathy. Any metabolic, neurological, hepatic, renal, cardiovascular, hematological, opthalmic, or endocrine disease that would confound ability to participate in valid assessments. Mental retardation (IQ &lt;75). Organic brain disorders. NonEnglish speaking subjects will not be allowed into the study because the assessment instruments are unavailable and have not been adequately standardized in other languages.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bulimia Nervosa</keyword>
	<keyword>Eating Disorder NOS</keyword>
	<keyword>Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>ADHD</keyword>
</DOC>