<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00916279</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will enroll patients with angiographic evidence of in-stent restenosis of a previously placed bare-metal stent. Subjects will be treated with a Lutonix Catheter. The purpose is to investigate the feasibility, safety, and efficacy of the Lutonix Catheter in the native coronary system. Angiographic and clinical outcomes will be assessed.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PERVIDEO I Registry, The Lutonix Paclitaxel-Coated Balloon Catheter for the Treatment of Coronary In-Stent Restenosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or nonpregnant/nonbreast feeding Female ≥18 Years of age. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test within 7 days of the procedure; Documented stable angina pectoris Canadian Cardiovascular Society Classification (CCSC) 14, unstable angina pectoris with documented ischemia (Braunwald III) or documented silent ischemia; Previous history of native coronary bare metal stenting ≥60 days; LVEF ≥25%; Patient is an acceptable candidate for PTCA, stenting, and emergent CABG; Patient is willing to provide informed consent and comply with followup visits and testing schedule; Target lesion is in a native coronary with previous single bare metal stent; Stenosis is ≥50% and &lt;100% by visual estimate or QCA prior to defined predilatation; Reference Vessel Diameter (RVD) is ≥2.5 and ≤3.25; Target lesion is ≤40 mm in length and can be treated in its entirety by no more than 2 contiguous Lutonix Catheters; Guidewire is able to cross lesion(s) and be placed in distal vessel prior to enrollment; Enrollment permitted after successful treatment of 1 to 2 nonstudy lesions in a single other nonstudy vessel. Successful treatment is defined as ≤30% residual stenosis with TIMI III flow and no evidence of dissection. History of Stroke within past 6 months; History of MI or thrombolysis within 72 hours of randomization; History of previous target vessel perforation; Prior vascular brachytherapy; Angiographic evidence of thrombus or dissection within the target vessel; Intervention of another coronary lesion &lt;60 days before index procedure day or planned following index procedure; Target lesion is in the Left Main or vessel ostium and has excessive calcification or tortuosity or involves bifurcation disease of vessel ≥2.5 mm; Target lesion is planned to be treated with something other than PTCA (i.e. stent, cutting balloon, atherectomy, VBT, etc.); Uncontrollable allergies to procedure medications, materials, or contrast; Patient has previous stent procedure with any drugcoated or drug eluting stent device in the target coronary vessel; Known sensitivity to paclitaxel or other antimitogenic agent; Patient has a stent sandwich (a stench previously deployed within another stent; Preprocedure CKMB &gt;2x ULN or positive Troponin; Creatinine &gt;2.0 mg/dl; Leukocyte &lt;3500/mL; Platelet &lt;100,000 mL or &gt;750,000 mL; Currently taking or must resume warfarin; Patient is contraindicated for antiplatelet therapy or it will need to be withdrawn for a planned procedure; The patient is currently participating in another investigational drug or device study that has not completed its primary endpoint or that clinically interferes with the endpoints of this study;</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bare Metal In-Stent Restenosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Paclitaxel Coated Balloon Catheter</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Coated Balloon</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Disease</keyword>
</DOC>