<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02609061</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present study was designed to evaluate the combined efficacy of PRF and 1% ALN in the treatment of mandibular degree II furcation defects when compared with PRF and open flap debridement (OFD) alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Platelet Rich Fibrin+1% Alendronate in Treatment of Mandibular Degree II Furcation Defects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: Various regenerative materials have been introduced and tested in the treatment of furcation defects. Platelet-rich fibrin (PRF) is a reservoir of growth factors and cytokines which are the key factors for regeneration of bone and maturation of the soft tissue. Alendronate (ALN), a potent member of bisphosphonate group is known to promote tissue regeneration by inhibiting osteoclastic bone resorption and promoting osteoblastogenesis. The present study was designed to evaluate the combined efficacy of PRF and 1% ALN in the treatment of mandibular degree II furcation defects when compared with PRF and open flap debridement (OFD) alone. Methods: Seventy two mandibular furcation defects were treated with either OFD alone (Group 1), OFD with PRF (Group 2), and OFD with PRF+1% ALN (Group 3). Clinical parameters; site specific plaque index (PI), modified sulcus bleeding index (mSBI), probing depth (PD), relative vertical attachment level (RVAL) and relative horizontal attachment level (RHAL), intrabony defect depth (IBD) were recorded at baseline before surgery and 9 months post-operatively. Percentage radiographic defect fill was evaluated at baseline and 9 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Furcation Defects</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alendronate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Presence of buccal Class II furcation defects in endodontically vital, asymptomatic mandibular first and second molars with a radiolucency in the furcation area on an intraoral periapical radiograph with probing depth (PD) ≥ 5mm and horizontal ≥ PD 3mm after phase I therapy i.e, scaling and root planing (SRP); No history of antibiotic or periodontal therapy in the preceding 6 months. Systemic conditions known to affect the periodontal status; Medications known to affect the outcomes of periodontal therapy; Hematological disorders and insufficient platelet count (&lt;200,000/mm3); Pregnancy/lactation; Smoking and tobacco use in any form Immunocompromised individuals; Those having unacceptable oral hygiene (plaque index [PI] &gt;1.5). Teeth with furcation involvement, nonvital teeth, and carious teeth indicated for restorations and mobility of at least grade II Aggressive periodontitis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>