<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00636506</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the American Medical System's IPP 2005 inflatable penile prosthesis implant in subjects receiving the implant for erectile dysfunction for ease of patient operability and use, as well as ease of surgery for the physician.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluate Improvement of Erectile Dysfunction After Placement of the AMS IPP 2005 Inflatable Penile Prosthesis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Erectile dysfunction, the inability to attain or sustain a penile erection sufficient to permit satisfactory sexual intercourse, affects an estimated ten to 30 million men in the United States. Erectile dysfunction can be caused by many organic abnormalities, including diabetes mellitus, hypertension, vascular disease, neurogenic disorders, and other chronic diseases. Erectile dysfunction can be effectively treated with a variety of methods, including the implantation of an inflatable penile prosthesis. A multi-center trial is to be conducted to assess the AMS IPP 2002 Inflatable Penile Prosthesis including handling during IPP implantation procedures and short-term follow-up experience of subjects. The study will collect pre-operative information comparing the pump operation using scrotal models of the current pump with the study pump, and baseline erectile function history. Surgical data will be collected to assess device design and procedure enhancements. Patient and physician assessment of study device function, ease of use, ease of training/learning, and adverse events will be gathered post-operatively.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Erectile Dysfunction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The subject has been diagnosed with erectile dysfunction and has made an informed decision to be implanted with the AMS IPP 2005 Inflatable Penile Prosthesis Cylinder, Pump, and Reservoir. The subject has not had a previous penile prosthesis, is willing and able to comply to study protocol. No known sensitivity to rifampin, minocycline or other tetracyclines. Does not have systemic lupus erythematosus. Inadequate reading level for for reading and understanding the Informed Consent, patient questionnaires, and other study materials. Has Urinary Tract Infection (UTI), urogenital infection, or active skin infection in the region of surgery. Has a compromised immune system. Diagnosed with severe fibrosis due to priapism Does not have the manual dexterity or mental ability to operate the pump.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Erectile dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Impotence</keyword>
</DOC>