<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02154022</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: - Certain drugs even when they are meant to help people cause side effects. These are unwanted effects of the drug. There are many reasons why a drug might cause side effects in one person and not in another. It may be because of how much of the drug is in the person s blood at one time. Researchers want to study the blood of people having drug side effects to better understand why they happen. Objective: - To obtain blood samples from patients being treated with an investigational or FDA approved drug at the National Cancer Institute who are having bad side effects that are thought to be due to large amount of the drug in their blood. The samples will be used to assess the cause of the side effects. Eligibility: - People 2 years and older with cancer who are currently enrolled in clinical trials at the National Cancer Institute. Design: - Participants will give blood samples.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Collection of Pharmacokinetic Samples From People With Unanticipated Response or Toxicity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: - Pharmacology is the study of pharmaceutical compounds , and encompasses several parameters, including how the body handles the substance (pharmacokinetics, PK), what the substance does to the body at the molecular level (pharmacodynamics), overall efficacy (response), and any adverse events or toxicity encountered. - The Clinical Pharmacology Program (CPP) within the Center for Cancer Research (CCR) of the National Cancer Institute (NCI) has sensitive, state of the art bioanalytical instrumentation that can accurately and precisely quantitate drug concentrations in plasma. - Currently, the CPP can only analyze samples from clinical trials that have explicit instructions (within the Pharmacokinetics section) to do so in the IRB approved protocol. - However, clinical trial protocols without a Pharmacokinetics section may still need occasional pharmacokinetic plasma samples drawn and drug concentration measurements performed to help explain unexpected AEs or toxicity. Objectives: - To obtain PK plasma samples from patients being treated with an investigational agent or FDA approved therapy at the NCI who are exhibiting toxicity that is believed to be due to high drug concentration in order to assess the cause of the toxicity and adverse events. Eligibility: - Any cancer patients who are currently enrolled in IRB approved clinical trials at the National Cancer Institute are eligible. Design: - The CPP will measure the drug plasma concentration (or send the sample out to a third party if the assay is commercially available). - The accrual ceiling for this study is 100 patients. The anticipated accrual rate for this protocol is less than 10 patients per year, and based on the accrual ceiling, the duration of accrual and the total study duration is 5 years.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA Any cancer patients greater than or equal to 2 years of age who are currently enrolled in IRB approved clinical trials at the National Cancer Institute are eligible. Ability of subject or a Legally Authorized Representative (LAR) to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document. EXCLUSION CRITERIA None anticipated at this time.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2, 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>PK</keyword>
</DOC>