<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02154698</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the usefulness of two needles (used for obtaining a lung tissue sample : (1) standard 22-gauge, and (2) ProCore 22-gauge) for endobronchial ultrasound</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>22-gauge ProCore Needle v. Standard 22-gauge (P00030500)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to compare the usefulness of two needles used for obtaining a lung tissue sample: (1) standard 22-gauge, and (2) ProCore 22-gauge. Both of these needles are used to get biopsies (samples) of lung tissue. The standard needle has one bevel (angled side of the needle formed when it is sharpened to make a point), while the ProCore needle has 2 bevels. The standard needle is more commonly used and we are doing this study to see if the ProCore needle would be more useful. The investigator in charge of this study is Dr. Nichole T. Tanner. This study is being done at four sites and will involve approximately 200 volunteers.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>1. Subjects with known or suspected lung cancer with mediastinal adenopathy as defined by a mediastinal lymph node &gt;1 cm in short axis or a normal sized lymph node with uptake on FDGPET scan that is higher than background PET activity. 2. Participants must be at least 18 years old or older, lack bleeding disorders, and be able to provide informed consent. The latter two criteria will be assessed from the patient's history and the consenting interview. 1. Subjects who refuse to participate, or demonstrate inability to give informed consent 2. Subjects who are less than 18 years of age 3. Subjects who lack fitness for flexible bronchoscopy as determined by the physician performing the bronchoscopy before the procedure 4. Subjects with suspected sarcoidosis, lymphoma, or metastatic cancer from other sites (i.e. those without a known or suspected lung primary) 5. Subjects on anticoagulation (other than Aspirin) whom cannot have their anticoagulation held for the procedure due to other clinical reasons (i.e. recent cardiac stent placement).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>