<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02117076</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will compare the safety, effectiveness and tolerability of gabapentin (Neurontin) versus gabapentin enacarbil (Horizant) as treatment restless leg syndrome.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Blinded, Randomized Study of Gabapentin (Neurontin®) and Gabapentin Enacarbil (Horizant™) in Restless Leg Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will compare the safety, effectiveness and tolerability of gabapentin (Neurontin) versus gabapentin enacarbil (Horizant) as treatment restless leg syndrome. Subjects will be randomized to gabapentin (IR) or Horizant™ (ER). Dosing will be blinded to both patient and study team members. Once study medication dosing has been optimized, subjects will then remain on a stable dose for six weeks until study endpoint, after which subjects will be down-titrated off of study medications.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychomotor Agitation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Restless Legs Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gabapentin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>gamma-Aminobutyric Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Outpatients with a diagnosis of primary restless leg syndrome using the International Restless Legs Syndrome Study Group (IRLSSG) diagnostic criteria8. 2. RLS symptoms ≥ 15 nights of the month prior to study enrollment and for ≥ 4 of 7 consecutive nights in the week prior to study enrollment (if untreated). 3. Age 18 years to 80 years. 4. International Restless Legs Scale (IRLS) Total severity score of ≥ 15 (moderate to severe severity). 8 5. Had significant sleep disturbance on item 4 of IRLS.8 6. Women of childbearing potential must use a reliable method of contraception. 7. Informed consent. Subject must be willing and able to complete all study procedures. 1. Any illness that in the investigator's opinion preclude participation in this study. 2. Subjects with nonRLSrelated sleep disorders (e.g., sleep apnea) 3. Subjects with neurological diseases or movement disorders other than RLS (e.g., diabetic neuropathy, Parkinson's disease, multiple sclerosis, dyskinesias, and dystonias) 4. Pregnancy or lactation. 5. Concurrent participation in another clinical study. 6. Dementia or other psychiatric illness that prevents the patient from giving informed consent (MiniMental State Examination scores less than 27). 7. Legal incapacity or limited legal capacity. 8. History of RLS symptom augmentation or earlymorning rebound with previous dopamineagonist treatment. 9. Clinically significant abnormalities in renal function. 3,8,10 10. Presence of severe cardiovascular or pulmonary disease, bronchial asthma, renal, hepatic or endocrine disease. 11. Concomitant treatment with drugs known to affect sleep/wake, RLS or periodic limb movements, including antidepressants. Subjects receiving treatment for RLS at screening will be required to discontinue and wash out for a minimum of 5 halflives. 12. Body mass index greater than 34 kg/m2.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Restless leg syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>RLS</keyword>
	<keyword>gabapentin</keyword>
	<keyword>gabapentin enacarbil</keyword>
	<keyword>Neurontin</keyword>
	<keyword>Horizant</keyword>
</DOC>