<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02117453</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess whether rosuvastatin could reduce the subclinical markers of atherosclerosis and the incidence of major cardiovascular events in patients with primary necrotizing vasculitides.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicenter, Prospective, Randomized, Controlled, Double-blind Trial on the Impact of Rosuvastatin on Subclinical Markers of Atherosclerosis in Patients With Primary Necrotizing Vasculitides</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Previous studies demonstrated the presence of subclinical atherosclerosis in patients with ANCA-associated systemic necrotizing vasculitis. Since statins lower levels of inflammatory proteins and cholesterol, we hypothesized that people with ANCA-associated systemic necrotizing vasculitis but without indication for statin treatment according to recommandations might benefit from statin treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vasculitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rosuvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient &gt; 18 years. ANCAassociated vasculitis: granulomatosis with polyangiitis (GPA), microscopic polyangiitis (MPA) and eosinophilic granulomatosis with polyangiitis (EGPA, ChurgStrauss syndrome). Patients will fulfill the Chapel Hill Consensus Criteria and the American College of Rheumatology criteria, in remission of vasculitis. Patients in remission of vasculitis after induction therapy (for first flare or relapse), including corticosteroids associated or not with immunosuppressive agents according to Good Clinical Practice for the treatment of vasculitis, between 6 months and 10 years after the beginning of induction therapy. Patients with informed and signed consent Other systemic vasculitis. Secondary vasculitis (paraneoplastic or infectious). Patient with active vasculitis after induction therapy, requiring salvage therapy. Inability to sign informed consent. Inability to take the experimental treatment. Hypersensitivity to rosuvastatin or to any of the excipients. Pregnancy. Chronic HCV, HBV and/or HIV infection. Patient receiving other statin or other hypolipemic agent. Patient requiring treatment with statin according to Afssaps recommandations published in 2005 as primary or secondary prevention. Subclinical atherosclerosis that confers a high cardiovascular risk before patient randomization : Carotid stenosis greater than 50% in diameter Ectasia of the abdominal aorta Intimamedia thickening greater than 1.2 mm Diffuse atherosclerosis lesions Heterogeneous or hypoechoic prominent plaques greater than 2 mm</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>ANCA vasculitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Statin</keyword>
	<keyword>Subclinical markers of atherosclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular events</keyword>
	<keyword>Myocardial infarction</keyword>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Arterial revascularization</keyword>
	<keyword>Unstable angina</keyword>
	<keyword>Death</keyword>
</DOC>