<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00353912</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the blood pressure lowering effects of a valsartan/amlodipine combination treatment and amlodipine monotherapy for the treatment of Black stage II hypertensive patients (MSSBP ≥ 160 mmHg).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy &amp; Safety of Orally Administered Valsartan/Amlodipine Combo Therapy vs Amlodipine Monotherapy in Black Patients With Stage II Hypertension</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Valsartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amlodipine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years of age or older. Moderate to severe high blood pressure. This is defined as a systolic pressure (the top number) greater than or equal to 160 mmHg and less than 200 mmHg. History of allergy or hypersensitivity to ARBs, CCBs, thiazide diuretics Inability to stop all prior blood pressure medications safely Systolic BP ≥ 200 mmHg and/or diastolic BP ≥ 120 mmHg Controlled blood pressure (systolic BP &lt; 140 mmHg) taking more than 3 antihypertensive medications at screening Systolic BP ≥ 140 mmHg and &lt; 180 mmHg taking more than two antihypertensive medications at screening Systolic BP ≥ 180 mmHg taking more than one antihypertensive medication at screening History of autoimmune diseases History of multiple drug allergies Liver disease Pancreatic injury within 1 year of screening Evidence of kidney impairment or history of dialysis Any surgical or medical condition which might alter the absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of any drug. This could include currently active gastritis, ulcers, or gastrointestinal/rectal bleeding, or urinary tract obstruction. Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP), defined as all women physiologically capable of becoming pregnant, would be excluded UNLESS they are postmenopausal, surgically sterile OR are using acceptable methods of contraception. The use of hormonal contraceptives is not allowed Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women History of malignancy of any organ system within the past five years Any severe, lifethreatening disease within the past five years History of drug or alcohol abuse within the last 2 years. History of stroke, angioplasty, coronary artery bypass graft surgery, heart attack or unstable angina Type 1 diabetes Poorly controlled Type 2 diabetes History of heart failure Arrhythmia Significant valvular heart disease Active gout Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Blood</keyword>
	<keyword>Venous</keyword>
	<keyword>Systolic</keyword>
	<keyword>Diastolic</keyword>
	<keyword>Pulse</keyword>
	<keyword>Pressure</keyword>
</DOC>