<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00353288</DOC>
	<brief_summary>As measles-mumps-rubella (MMR) vaccination is established as routine childhood practice in most industrialised countries and varicella vaccination is now being introduced in many countries during the second year of life, a combined measles-mumps-rubella-varicella vaccine was developed for administration convenience and improved compliance to vaccination. To account for situations where children have received a first dose of MMR vaccine without varicella, this study will evaluate the effect of the combined measles-mumps-rubella-varicella vaccine given in place of the second dose of MMR vaccine. A second dose of the monovalent varicella vaccine will be given to all children participating to this trial since there is a current debate on the need of a second dose to induce a full protection against varicella.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunogenicity, Safety of Measles-mumps-rubella-varicella Vaccine (MeMuRu-OKA) Compared to Priorix™ Given With Varilrix™</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Measles</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rubella</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mumps</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chickenpox</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Herpes Zoster</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children must be healthy to participate Immunosuppressive (including HIV) conditions, allergic diseases, neurological disorders, known anaphylactic reaction to MMR vaccine, and fever (axillary temperature ³ 37.5°C at the time of vaccination) are excluding factors. Children must have received one dose (but not more) of MMR at least 6 weeks before entering the study. They must not receive or have received other nonregistered drug or vaccine within 30 days prior to study start, or immunosuppressants for more than 14 days. Immunoglobulins or any blood products are prohibited during the 6 months before and during the study, as well as vaccine other than that foreseen by the protocol, 30 days before until 56 days after vaccination. Children must not have been vaccinated against varicella. They must not have had measles, mumps, rubella or varicella, or have been exposed to those diseases within 30 days prior to study start. Newborn infants (&lt; 5 weeks of age), pregnant women without previous exposure to chickenpox, and immunodeficient persons cannot live in the same household as the vaccinated child.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>