<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01490918</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary objective To evaluate the efficacy of Acarbose added on top of Metformin and Sitagliptin that were combinedly administered to subjects with type-II diabetes, along with placebos. Secondary objectives 1. To compare a Metformin-Sitagliptin combination and a Sitagliptin-Acarbose combination in efficacy 2. To evaluate the 6-month efficacy of Acarbose added on top of the Metformin-Sitagliptin combination</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Efficacy of Acarbose,Metformin,Sitagliptin Combination Treatment in DM Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>1) Primary Endpoint With changes in HbA1c measured at the baseline and the 16th week, descriptive statistics (mean, standard deviation, median, minimum value, maximum value and 95% confidence interval) should be worked out. HbA1c, measured at the baseline, should be included in covariates, and a comparison should be made between Group-1 and Group-2 with the analysis of covariance (ANCOVA). 2) Secondary Endpoints 1. Changes in CGMS, mixed meal tolerance test (active GLP-1, total GLP-1, GIP and insulin) and oxidative stress markers (8-OHdG, nitro tyrosine and CML) in Group-1 and Group-2: With the values measured at the baseline and the 16th week, mean, standard deviation, median, minimum value and maximum value should be calculated. To analyze the difference of two groups, perform an ANCOVA with baseline value as a covariate. 2. Changes in HbA1c, FPG and PPG in Group-1 and Group-2: With the values measured at the baseline, the 16th week and the 24th week and at the 16th week and the 24th week, mean, standard deviation, median, minimum value and maximum value should be calculated. To analyze the difference of two groups, perform an ANCOVA with baseline value as a covariate. 3. Changes in HbA1c, FPG and PPG in Group-1 and Group-3: With the values measured at the baseline, the 16th week and the 24th week and at the 16th week and the 24th week, mean, standard deviation, median, minimum value and maximum value should be calculated. To analyze the difference of two groups, perform an ANCOVA with baseline value as a covariate. 4. Changes in SMBG in Group-1 and Group-2 and in Group-1 and Group-3: With the values measured at the 4th week, the 16th week and the 24th week and at the 16th week and the 24th week, mean, standard deviation, median, minimum value and maximum value should be calculated. To analyze the difference of two groups, perform an ANCOVA with baseline value(4wk) as a covariate. 5. Changes in 1,5-AG in Group-1 and Group-2 and in Group-1 and Group-3: With the values measured at the 16th week, mean, standard deviation, median, minimum value and maximum value should be calculated. To analyze the difference of two groups, perform an ANCOVA with baseline value as a covariate.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acarbose</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sitagliptin Phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subjects with typeII diabetes mellitus; 2. Subjects aged between 20 and 80; 3. Subjects whose HbA1c ratio is between 7.0% and 10.0%; 4. Subjects who took Metformin and Sitagliptin for at least 12 weeks; 5. Subjects who were given the explanation about this clinical study and signed the consent form. 1. Subjects who have taken drugs that are likely to affect blood glucose or who need to take such drugs, e.g., glucocorticoid; 2. Subjects with severe renal diseases (men: Scr&gt;1.5 / women: Scr&gt;1.4); 3. Subjects with severe liver diseases or whose AST and ALT are at least 2.5 times higher than the upper limits of normal (ULN); 4. Subjects having the case history of lactic acidosis; 5. Subjects who have the case history of myocardial infarction or unstable angina or who underwent the coronary artery bypass graft 6 months before the screening test or who have arrhythmia to be treated; 6. Subjects with congestive heart failures to be treated; 7. Subjects who fall into New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III or IV; 8. Subjects having the case history of acute or chronic metabolic acidosis including ketoacidosis; 9. Subjects who have been pregnant or who are in the period of lactation; 10. Subjects diagnosed with malignant tumors within 5 years; 11. Subjects who are hypersensitive to Metformin, Sitagliptin and Acarbose or their ingredients; 12. Subjects with inflammatory bowel diseases or intestinal ulcers or enterostenosis (includes Subjects who are vulnerable to enterostenosis) or chronic enteric diseases related to digestion and absorption or whose symptoms are likely to worsen due to intestinal gas; 13. Subjects who participated in other clinical studies as Subjects within 60 days before this study (or before taking the investigational drugs); 14. Subjects judged unfit for this study by investigators.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type-II diabetes mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Acarbose</keyword>
	<keyword>ACADEMIC</keyword>
</DOC>