<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01005329</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This phase II trial is studying the side effects of giving intensity-modulated radiation therapy together with cisplatin and bevacizumab followed by carboplatin and cisplatin and to see how well it works in treating patients who have undergone surgery for high-risk endometrial cancer. Specialized radiation therapy that delivers a high dose of radiation directly to the tumor may kill more tumor cells and cause less damage to normal tissue. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as cisplatin, carboplatin, and paclitaxel, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Monoclonal antibodies, such as bevacizumab, can block tumor growth in different ways. Some block the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Others find tumor cells and help kill them or carry tumor-killing substances to them. Bevacizumab may also stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking blood flow to the tumor. Giving intensity-modulated radiation therapy together with chemotherapy and bevacizumab after surgery may kill any tumor cells that remain after surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intensity-Modulated Radiation Therapy, Cisplatin, and Bevacizumab Followed by Carboplatin and Paclitaxel in Treating Patients Who Have Undergone Surgery for Endometrial Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVE: I. To assess the treatment-related, grade 3+, non-hematologic adverse-event rate within 90 days from the start of treatment with concurrent intensity-modulated radiotherapy, cisplatin, and bevacizumab followed by carboplatin and paclitaxel in patients with high-risk endometrial cancer. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. To evaluate treatment-related adverse events occurring within 1 year from the start of treatment. II. To evaluate all treatment-related adverse events. III. To evaluate disease-free and overall survival. IV. To evaluate local, regional, and distant failure. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients undergo pelvic intensity-modulated radiotherapy (IMRT) once daily, 5 days a week, for 5 weeks. Patients may also undergo optional nodal boost radiotherapy and/or vaginal brachytherapy boost. Patients also receive concurrent cisplatin IV over 1 hour on days 1 and 29 and bevacizumab IV over 30-90 minutes on days 1, 15, and 29. Beginning 4-6 weeks after completing IMRT, cisplatin, and bevacizumab, patients receive carboplatin IV over 1 hour and paclitaxel IV over 3 hours on day 1. Treatment with carboplatin and paclitaxel repeats every 21 days for 4 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 3 months for 1 year, every 6 months for 2 years, and then annually thereafter.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystadenocarcinoma, Serous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenomyoepithelioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma, Clear Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Uterine Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Adenosquamous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed endometrial cancer, including 1 of the following cellular types: Endometrioid endometrial adenocarcinoma Clear cell carcinoma Papillary serous adenocarcinoma Adenosquamous cell carcinoma Other adenocarcinoma variant No carcinosarcoma Meets 1 of the following criteria: Grade 3 carcinoma with &gt; 50% myometrial invasion (stage IC or IIA) (all papillary serous or clear cell carcinoma will be considered grade 3) Grade 2 or 3 carcinoma with any cervical stromal invasion (stage IIB) Known extrauterine disease confined to the pelvis (stage III or IVA) Patients with stage III or IVA disease must have undergone CT scan or PET/CT scan of the abdomen and pelvis within the past 56 days Has undergone hysterectomy (i.e., total abdominal, vaginal, roboticassisted, radical, or laparoscopicassisted vaginal hysterectomy) and bilateral salpingooophorectomy within the past 56 days No positive common iliac or positive paraaortic nodal disease (defined as lymph nodes ≥ 2 cm in any dimension on CT scan or biopsy) or positive peritoneal cytology No evidence of metastatic extrauterine disease, gross or residual disease (not including pelvic nodal disease), or distant metastases Zubrod performance status 01 Absolute Neutrophil Count (ANC) ≥ 1,500/mm^3 (without growth factor support) Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dL (transfusion allowed) Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and Alanine amino transferase (ALT) ≤ 2 times ULN Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL Urine protein:creatinine ratio ≤ 0.5 OR urine protein &lt; 1,000 mg on 24hour urine collection international normalized ratio (INR) &lt; 1.5 (for patients treated with warfarin within the past 14 days) Not nursing No neuropathy ≥ Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) grade 1 No ototoxicity &gt; CTCAE grade 2 No serious, active comorbidity, including any of the following: Unstable angina and/or New York Heart Association (NYHA) class IIIV congestive heart failure requiring hospitalization within the past 12 months Transmural myocardial infarction within the past 12 months Acute bacterial or fungal infection requiring IV antibiotics Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease exacerbation or other respiratory illness requiring hospitalization or precluding study therapy Hepatic insufficiency resulting in clinical jaundice and/or coagulation defects AIDS based upon current Center for Disease Control (CDC) definition (HIV testing is not required) Active gastrointestinal (GI) ulcers, GI bleeding, inflammatory bowel disease, or GI obstruction Inadequately controlled hypertension, defined as systolic BP (blood pressure) &gt; 150 mm Hg and/or diastolic BP &gt; 90 mm Hg on antihypertensive medications Significant vascular disease, including aortic aneurysm, aortic dissection, or arteriovenous malformation within the past 12 months Serious cardiac arrhythmia on medication (wellcontrolled atrial fibrillation on medication allowed) Serious nonhealing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture No history of hypertensive crisis or hypertensive encephalopathy No stroke/cerebrovascular event within the past 12 months No arterial thromboembolic events, including transient ischemic attack or clinically symptomatic peripheral artery disease within the past 12 months No abdominal fistula, GI perforation, or intraabdominal abscess within the past 6 months No other invasive malignancies within the past 3 years other than nonmelanomatous skin cancer No significant trauma within the past 28 days No mental status changes or bladder problems that would preclude the ability to comply with bladderfilling instructions No mental or psychiatric illness that would preclude giving informed consent No known hypersensitivity to Chinese hamster ovary cell products or other recombinant human antibodies No prior allergic reaction to bevacizumab, cisplatin, carboplatin, or paclitaxel No concurrent erythropoietin, St. John's wort, therapeutic anticoagulants, aminoglycoside antibiotics, or amifostine No prior organ transplantation No prior externalbeam radiotherapy to the pelvis resulting in overlapping of radiotherapy fields No prior systemic chemotherapy for uterine cancer Prior chemotherapy for a different cancer is allowed No prior therapy with antivascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) compounds More than 28 days since prior major surgical procedure requiring open biopsy incision No concurrent surgery (except for vascular access device placement or procedures that do not require significant incision) No concurrent warfarin at doses &gt; 1 mg/day Concurrent prophylactic low molecular weight heparin allowed</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>