<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01005719</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will determine differences between Proton Pump Inhibitors (PPI) formulations relative to their effects on gastric acidity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Compare Gastric Inhibition of Two Proton Pump Inhibitors (CL2008-18)(P07815)(COMPLETED)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lansoprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexlansoprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Omeprazole</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Proton Pump Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Omeprazole, sodium bicarbonate drug combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy nonAsian, male or nonlactating, nonpregnant female participants who are 1865 years of age. Clinical laboratory test must be within normal limits or clinically acceptable to the Investigator/Sponsor. Participants must have normal or clinically acceptable physical exam and ECG. Participants must be free of any clinically significant disease that requires a physician's care and/or would interfere with study evaluations, procedures, or participation. Able to understand and comply with study procedures required and able and willing to provide written informed consent prior to any study procedures being performed. History of hypersensitivity, allergy or intolerance to omeprazole, or other proton pump inhibitors History of peptic ulcer disease or other acid related gastrointestinal symptoms or heartburn with a frequency of more than one/month. Positive H. pylori breath test at screening. Participation in any study of an investigational treatment in the 30 days before Screening or participation in another study at any time during the period of this study Any significant medical illness that would contraindicate participation in the study Gastrointestinal disorder or surgery leading to impaired drug absorption Any significant mental illness, such as schizophrenia or bipolar disorder History (in the past year) suggestive of alcohol or drug abuse or dependence, or excessive alcohol use (&gt;2 units per day on average; for example &gt;2 bottles of beer, &gt;2 glasses of wine, &gt;2 ounces of liquor/spirits), or excessive alcohol use during the study Any abnormal Screening laboratory value that is clinically significant in the investigator's opinion Currently using or use of any prescription or over the counter (OTC) medications that affect gastrointestinal function, including first generation antihistamines (e.g. diphenhydramine) and anticholinergic agents within 7 days prior to 1st treatment administration. Currently using, or use within 14 days of first treatment administration, or having a history of frequent use of antacids, OTC or Prescription (Rx) H2 receptor antagonists, or OTC or Rx use of proton pump inhibitors. Positive urine drug/alcohol test at Screening.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>