<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02080364</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of azeliragon in patients with mild Alzheimer's disease. Patients will receive either azeliragon or placebo with a patient's participation lasting approximately 18 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Efficacy and Safety of Azeliragon (TTP488) in Patients With Mild Alzheimer's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholinesterase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of probable Alzheimer Disease (AD) with documented evidence of progression of disease Mini Mental State Examination (MMSE) score of 2126, inclusive Clinical Dementia Rating global score of 0.5 or 1 RosenModified Hachinski Ischemia Score less than or equal to 4 Brain magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) consistent with the diagnosis of probable AD Concurrent use of cholinesterase inhibitor or memantine with stable dose for at least 3 months prior to randomization Caregiver willing to participate and be able to attend clinic visits with patient Ability to ingest oral medications Significant neurological or psychiatric disease other than Alzheimer's disease Participants with evidence or history of severe drug allergies (resulting in dyspnea or severe rash). Any contraindications to MRI (e.g., clinically significant claustrophobia, nonremovable ferromagnetic implants). Patients with contraindications to MRI may undergo computed tomography (CT) on approval by sponsor. Any contraindications to the FDGPET study (e.g. allergy to any component of the FDG dose) in the cohort undergoing a PET scan. Previous exposure to investigational or noninvestigational therapies for Alzheimer's disease within 6 months of screening History of cancer within the last 5 years except adequately treated cervical carcinoma insitu, cutaneous basal cell or squamous cell cancer, or nonprogressive prostate cancer not requiring treatment Women of childbearing potential Uncontrolled blood pressure and/or blood pressure above 160/100 Prescription medical food intended for dietary management of the metabolic processes associated with Alzheimer's disease. Diagnosis or history of cerebrovascular stroke, severe carotid stenosis, cerebral hemorrhage, intracranial tumor, subarachnoid hemorrhage. Patients with unstable, uncontrolled diabetes (HbA1c &gt; 7.7%) and those requiring insulin.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Alzheimer's disease</keyword>
	<keyword>RAGE</keyword>
	<keyword>ADAS-cog</keyword>
	<keyword>CDR-sb</keyword>
</DOC>