<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01912495</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Prospective open label proof of concept feasibility interventional clinical trial in which 60 acute HCV genotype 1 patients co-infected with HIV will receive 12 weeks of boceprevir in addition to Standard Of Care Peginterferon + Ribavirin if they show a Rapid Viral Responds at week 4. The primary hypothesis of this study is that the subset of patients with a Rapid Viral Responds after 4 weeks of triple therapy with boceprevir, peginterferon alpha-2b (P) and ribavirin (RVR4) can be successfully treated with a shorter 12-week triple therapy regimen.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dutch Acute HCV in HIV Study (DAHHS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Documented recent HCV genotype 1 infection (≤26 weeks old at the time of the baseline visit) according to definition mentioned below. 2. Plan to start a Standard Of Care therapy for acute HCV consisting of 24 weeks of Peginterferon + Ribavirin. HCV RNA plasma viral load at screening &gt;1000 IU/ml. 3. A previously performed HCV RNA plasma measurement can be used for screening if &lt;4 weeks old. 4. On HAART at the time of screening. 5. Minimum age 18 years. 1. Disallowed comedication that cannot be stopped or replaced: Several potentially lifethreatening drugdrug interactions (DDI) are possible when boceprevir is combined with other drugs. Therefore ALL comedication, including overthecounter drugs should be checked for potential DDI with DDI table in the Dutch summary of product characteristics (SPC, appendix A). If the comedication is not mentioned in the SPC DDI table, www.HCVdruginteractions.org should be used. 2. Contraindications for the use of full dose of peginterferon alpha2b or ribavirin: neutrophils &lt;0,75×109/l or thrombocytes &lt; 100.000×109/l or a Hb &lt;6.2mmol/L, creatinine clearance &lt;50ml/min). 3. History of liver cirrhosis or &gt;F1 fibrosis on fibroscan. Inclusion of patients with a chronic wellcontrolled HBV (HBVDNA below the limit of detection) with tenofovir, lamivudine or emtricitabine therapy is allowed if fibroscan excludes &gt;F1 fibrosis. Fibroscan reports &lt;2 years old can be used for screening. Fibroscan is not required for other patients at screening. 4. HAART was started &lt;4 weeks before baseline visit. 5. Inability to switch to a HAART regimen consisting of 2 nucleoside/tide reverse transcriptase inhibitors + Raltegravir (Isentress®) 400mg BID or rilpivirine 25mg QD or atazanavir (Reyataz®) 300mg QD + ritonavir (Norvir®) 100mg QD. 6. Patient that virologically failed HAART in the past</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>