<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01912209</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of BEHHS is first to assess the baseline sub-clinical disease in a population of Baptist Health Employees who have Metabolic Syndrome, a known contributor to cardiovascular disease. Second, the investigators wish to encourage a healthy lifestyle through personalized nutrition and fitness advice, delivered as part of a web based program, which will in turn lead to increases in heart healthy behaviors such as increased consumption of heart healthy foods, increased exercise initiation, and more positive attitudes about health. To assess this, the investigators plan to randomize 200 employees with Metabolic Syndrome to either the new web-based diet and lifestyle program, or to care-as-usual, which is the currently offered MyWellnessAdvantage and WebMD websites. The investigators hypothesize that the web-based group will show greater improvements in physical health (such as weight loss, cholesterol reduction, etc.) as well as increased consumption of heart healthy foods, exercise initiation, and quality of sleep as measured by surveys administered at the 4,8, and 12 month follow-up appointments.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Web-based Approach to Treating Cardiovascular Disease Risk in Employees With Metabolic Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome X</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Employee of Baptist Health Access to Internet Has a smart phone (Android or Apple supported) with data plan Has an email address Diagnosis of three or more of the following: 1. Waist circumference &gt;=40 inches in and male and &gt;= 35 inches in a female 2. Fasting triglyceride level &gt; 150 mg/dl* 3. HDLC &lt; 40 mg/dl in men or &lt; 50 mg/dl in women* 4. BP &gt; 130/85 mm Hg* 5. Fasting blood glucose &gt; 110 mg/dl Or currently on medication to treat the abnormal condition 1. Prior history of major cardiovascular events (angina, myocardial infarction, prior coronary revascularization 2. Any woman of childbearing potential who is pregnant, breastfeeding/currently lactating, seeking to become pregnant or suspects that she may be pregnant** 3. Active treatment for cancer 4. Known history of a bilateral mastectomy 5. Known history of diabetes (already being treated as highrisk group, would not qualify as having Metabolic Syndrome for purposes of our study) 6. Known history of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease 7. Currently in atrial fibrillation 8. Known history of hypotension 9. Known history of heart failure 10. Known history of aortic valve stenosis 11. Known history of heart block 12. Chest CT scan in the last year 13. Cognitive inability as judged by the interviewer</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>employees</keyword>
	<keyword>metabolic syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>sub-clinical cardiovascular disease</keyword>
	<keyword>weight loss</keyword>
	<keyword>diet</keyword>
</DOC>