<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01912612</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Early stage breast cancer is typically treated with surgery, chemotherapy, radiation therapy, and/or endocrine therapy. Following treatment, 25-60% of breast cancer survivors have reported chronic pain, which can be difficult to manage. Duloxetine is a serotonin norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor that is FDA approved for treatment of depression, anxiety, fibromyalgia, diabetic neuropathic pain, knee arthritis, and low back pain. Pilot data suggest that duloxetine is effective in management of endocrine therapy-associated musculoskeletal pain, and a randomized placebo controlled trial of duloxetine has demonstrated efficacy for treatment of chemotherapy-induced neuropathic pain. In this mechanistic study of duloxetine versus placebo, we will investigate the change in pain sensitivity with treatment in order to evaluate both why duloxetine is effective for management of pain for some patients, as well as predictors of who is likely to benefit from duloxetine. A total of 84 women with early stage breast cancer who have chronic pain following treatment, as well as 48 women who are pain free, will be enrolled. All subjects will undergo assessment of pain sensitivity and complete questionnaires. Subjects with pain will be treated with duloxetine for a total of 7 weeks, with pain sensitivity assessments before treatment and after 4 weeks of full-dose treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Mechanistic Study of Duloxetine Versus Placebo in Breast Cancer Patients With Chronic Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Duloxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Female patients at least 25 years of age 2. Diagnosis of stage 0III breast cancer within 12 years prior to enrollment. All indicated surgery, chemotherapy, and/or radiation therapy must have been completed at least 12 weeks prior to enrollment. Concomitant endocrine therapy and trastuzumab are permitted. 3. Pain that developed or worsened since breast cancer diagnosis and is not due to identifiable traumatic event or fracture 4. Patientreported worst pain score between 5 and 10 (inclusive) on a 010 scale (assessed verbally) 5. Female patients must be at least 1 year postmenopausal or surgically sterile; or must agree to use a medically acceptable form of contraception 6. Willing to withdraw from selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors and tricyclic antidepressants prior to treatment initiation 7. Patients who are currently taking nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs and/or opioid pain medications must remain on a stable dosage throughout the duration of the study 8. Able to provide informed consent and willing to sign an approved consent form that conforms to federal and institutional guidelines. 1. Prior use of duloxetine or milnacipran. 2. Prior use of venlafaxine specifically for treatment of pain (prior use for treatment of other indications, such as hot flashes, is permitted) 3. Patients must not be taking any contraindicated medications listed on the duloxetine package insert including the following: phenothiazines, propafenone, flecanide, linezolid, or anticoagulation medication (e.g., heparin, warfarin); treatment with MAO inhibitor within 14 days prior to registration. 4. Thumbnail abnormalities on either hand (such as due to chemotherapy or trauma, or artificial nails) that are likely to alter pain perception during testing 5. Peripheral sensory neuropathy at the thumbs bilaterally that interferes with function and/or activities of daily living 6. Significant risk of suicide based on the Investigator's judgment 7. History or behavior that would, in the Investigator's judgment, prohibit compliance for the duration of the study. 8. History of alcohol or other substance abuse or dependence within the year prior to registration 9. Known chronic liver disease, end stage renal disease, or creatinine clearance &lt;30 mL/min as defined by CockcroftGault equation 10. Uncontrolled narrowangle glaucoma. 11. Clinically significant coagulation disorder 12. History of seizure disorder 13. Pregnant or breastfeeding. Urine pregnancy test will be assessed at the baseline visit in women of childbearing potential with chronic pain. 14. Unable to take oral medications or any medical condition that would interfere with the absorption of study medication capsules. 15. Currently taking SSRI, SNRI, or TCA regimen for treatment of major depressive disorder or generalized anxiety disorder (without approval and involvement of the patient's treating psychiatrist). Controls are patients without chronic pain who otherwise meet the following eligibility criteria (inclusion #1, 2, 8, exclusion #1, 2, 4, 5, worst pain score 01, and not currently on medication for pain)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain sensitivity</keyword>
</DOC>