<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02083770</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Hispanic Americans are underrepresented in cancer clinical trials. The purpose of this study is to develop and test programs designed to reduce barriers and increase facilitators associated with cancer clinical trials participation for Hispanic Americans.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Trials Education Program for Hispanic Americans</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Hispanic Americans are underrepresented in cancer clinical trials. The purpose of this study is to develop and test education programs designed to reduce barriers and Increase facilitators associated with cancer clinical trials participation for Hispanic Americans. Focus groups were conducted with Hispanic American men and women to obtain culturally-linked attitudes related to clinical trials participation. This information was used to create a prototypic educational program anticipated to increase participation in clinical trials. It was then vetted and honed via additional focus groups. Simultaneously, a validation study was conducted with Hispanic Americans for a packet of psychosocial instruments that could be used for a subsequent randomized controlled trial to evaluate the impact of the clinical trials education program. The finalized clinical trials education program was tested via a randomized controlled trial. Participants assigned to the experimental group received the clinical trials education program, while participants in the control arm were administered a comparable, but non-relevant education program. Recruitment to this study has been completed.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Selfidentified as Hispanic American At least 21 years of age Sufficiently literate to comprehend written and spoken testing materials in English or Spanish Living in southern California Mentally competent to complete the informed consenting process</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hispanics</keyword>
	<keyword>Patient Participation</keyword>
	<keyword>Refusal to Participate</keyword>
	<keyword>Education</keyword>
	<keyword>Clinical Trials</keyword>
</DOC>