<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01630148</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The use of prophylaxis for venous thromboembolism (VTE) remains grossly underused for women who undergo gynecologic surgery for benign conditions world wide and especially in developing countries including our region. Having a research in our locality for the first time might raise awareness of the importance of VTE prophylaxis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bemiparin as a Thromboprophylaxis After Gynaecological Surgeries</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Deep vein thrombosis (DVT) and pulmonary embolism (PE), also referred to as venous thromboembolic events (VTE), are two major complications after gynaecological surgeries that can result in significant morbidity and mortality. The incidence of VTE after gynaecologic surgery varies depending on the method used for diagnosis. The rate of clinical DVT is estimated to be 3% after gynaecological surgery if no thromboprophylaxis was used. The rate of VTE assumed to decrease to 0.4% if Low molecular weight heparin was used as a thromboprophylaxis. According to our knowledge there are no published researches on the effect of the new second generation Low molecular Weight Heparin Bemiparin as a thromboprophylaxis after benign gynaecological surgery in comparison to a control group.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Embolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Embolism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Venous Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heparin, Low-Molecular-Weight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>female undergoing Benign gynecological surgeries. Having moderate,high and very high risk factors for venous thromboembolism. No contraindications for the use of Heparin. Having mild risk factors for thromboembolism. Active vaginal bleeding. Thrombocytopaenia. any patient who is already on anticoagulant. Sever renal or Liver diseases.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Thromboprophylaxis</keyword>
	<keyword>Bemiparin</keyword>
	<keyword>Low Molecular Weight Heparin</keyword>
	<keyword>Major Gynaecological Surgeries</keyword>
	<keyword>Benign Gynaecological Surgeries</keyword>
</DOC>