<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01250119</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess the prevalence of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) mutations in newly diagnosed patients with locally advanced or metastatic non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). Patients with positive EGFR mutation results will enter an open-label, single arm study to evaluate progression-free survival and quality of life with first-line Tarceva (erlotinib) therapy. Patients will receive Tarceva at a dose of 150 mg orally daily. Anticipated time on study treatment is until progressive disease or unacceptable toxicity occurs. Patients with negative EGFR mutation results will be offered treatment as per the centre's standard of care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess the Incidence of EGFR Mutation in Patients With Newly Diagnosed Locally Advanced or Metastatic Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer in the UK, And of Tarceva (Erlotinib) as First-Line Therapy in EGFR Mutation Positive Patients.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endothelial Growth Factors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients, &gt;/= 18 years of age Locally advanced or metastatic (stage IIIB/IV) nonsmall cell lung cancer (NSCLC) ECOG performance status 03 Treatment phase: histologically confirmed EGFR exon 19 deletion or exon 21 mutation in the diagnostic phase of the study Adequate haematological, liver and renal function Female patients must be postmenopausal, surgically sterile, or agree to use a barrier method of contraception Male patients must be surgically sterile or agree to use a barrier method of contraception Previous treatment for NSCLC with chemotherapy or therapy against EGFR, either with antibody or small molecule (tyrosine kinase inhibitor) Symptomatic cerebral metastases Pregnant or lactating women Any other concomitant anticancer therapy (until disease progression and discontinuation of Tarceva therapy)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>