<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00339144</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of this study is to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) or the maximum administered dose (MAD) of Dasatinib (BMS-354825) in patients in Japan.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Dasatinib (BMS-354825) in Patients With Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dasatinib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Performance status (general conditions) specified by the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group: 02 Histologic or cytologic diagnosis of a solid tumor which has progressed on or following standard therapies (including relapsed disease) or for which no standard therapy exists. men and women, ages 20 and over women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must be using an adequate method of contraception to avoid pregnancy throughout the study and for up to 3 months after the study in such a manner that the risk of pregnancy is minimized Adequate hepatic function Participants who are eligible and willing to undergo transplantation at pre study. Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding with known brain metastasis or symptoms of brain metastasis Uncontrolled or significant bleeding disorder unrelated to a primary tumor Dementia or mental illness that would prohibit understanding or giving informed consent. Severe allergy to drugs required for appropriate supportive care of patients in this study. History of gastrointestinal surgery or of any digestive disorder which has the potential to inhibit absorption of the study drug. Pleural effusion &gt; Grade 1 Patient with dysphagia Does not agree to blood/blood products transfusion(s) Donated blood over 200 mL within 4 weeks prior to the start of study therapy Medication that known to have a risk of causing Torsade de pointes Participants who are compulsorily detained for legal reasons or treatment of either a psychiatric or physical (e.g., infectious disease) illness must not be enrolled into this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Solid tumors (including relapsed disease) that are refractory to standard therapies or for which no effective standard therapy exists</keyword>
</DOC>