<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01526174</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators plan to conduct an open-label intratympanic injection proof-of-concept trial of golimumab, a TNF-alpha inhibitor, assessing for hearing loss progression in patients with autoimmune inner ear disease (AIED). This specific aim will be achieved using a two-arm approach. First, the investigators propose to dose 3 individual subjects with a single intratympanic injection of golimumab and follow each for 30 days, closely examining them for adverse events. If there are no serious adverse events, with FDA approval, the investigators propose to dose 14 subjects, each with 4 intratympanic injections of golimumab.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intratympanic Injection for Autoimmune Inner Ear Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ear Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Labyrinth Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Labyrinthitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of autoimmune inner ear disease (AIED) by the principal investigator Idiopathic, bilateral sensorineural hearing loss History of, or audiograms showing, rapid progression of hearing loss Bilateral loss of at least 30 dB in one or more frequencies (0.25 6 kHz) Hearing responsive on highdose oral steroids and steroiddependent, as determined by history and the principal investigator. The subject can be taking oral steroid, at the maintenance level, if enrolled in the First Arm and, if enrolled in the Second Arm, will begin taper after the first injection. Provided written informed consent for participation in the clinical study Positive MRI for vestibular schwannoma Positive FTA (syphilis) Significant middle ear disease (e.g., otitis media) Positive blood test for Lyme disease Positive tuberculosis test Concurrent or past treatment or use of medications and/or substances known to cause ototoxicity(for example, aminoglycosides [e.g., gentamicin], cisplatin, loop diuretics, Yorgason et al., 2006) Known adverse reaction to golimumab, adalimumab, etanercept, infliximab, rituximab, ustekinumab, or other biologic immunomodulators Concurrent (within the past 3 months prior to enrollment) live viral intranasal vaccine (flu) Positive test for HIV Positive test for Hepatitis B and C Presence of a demyelinating disease, such as multiple sclerosis Women of childbearing potential only: Positive serum pregnancy test prior to the only/first injection Active infections</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>autoimmune</keyword>
	<keyword>hearing loss</keyword>
	<keyword>bilateral hearing loss</keyword>
	<keyword>steroid-dependent</keyword>
</DOC>