<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01526265</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Using the NIH-funded Way to Health platform, the investigators will conduct this smoking cessation randomized controlled trial (RCT) among CVS employees. The investigators will be able to determine the comparative and absolute efficacy and effectiveness of 4 different incentive structures that are each grounded in behavioral economic principles. Additionally, the investigators will measure rates of and reasons for acceptance of each incentive structure, and examine participant characteristics that modify the efficacy and acceptance of different incentive structures.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Way to Quit - Comparative Efficacy, Acceptance and Effectiveness of Health Incentive Structures</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Specific Aim I: Compare the efficacy and effectiveness of 4 financial incentive structures for improving "quit rates" (rates of prolonged smoking abstinence for 6 months): (a) individual financial rewards, (b) individual deposit contracts, (c) cooperative rewards, and (d) competitive deposit contracts H1: Compared with usual care, all 4 incentive structures will increase quit rates significantly. H2: Compared with individual financial rewards of equivalent size and schedule, individual deposit contracts, cooperative rewards, and competitive contracts will each increase quit rates significantly. H3: Group-oriented structures will increase quit rates significantly more than individual-oriented structures. Specific Aim II: Compare smokers' acceptance of these 4 financial incentive structures for smoking cessation H4: Uptake rates of reward-based structures will be higher than of structures involving deposit contracts. H5: Uptake rates of group-oriented structures will be higher than of individual-oriented structures. Specific Aim III: Identify individual characteristics that modify incentive structures' efficacy and acceptance H6: Incentives will promote relatively greater quit rates among participants with fewer substitute reinforcers. H7: Incentives will promote relatively greater quit rates among participants with lower incomes. H8: Higher-income persons will be relatively more likely to accept incentives requiring deposit contracts.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tobacco Use Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Active smoker of 5 cigarettes per day for at least 6 months; At least 18 years old; Current full or parttime employee of CVS or be a family member or friend of a current full or parttime employee of CVS. Use a form of tobacco other than cigarettes while participating in the study (as this may influence biochemical testing); Are unable or unwilling to access the internet; Are unable to provide informed consent. Due to the webbased nature of this study, people without reliable computer and internet access will also be excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Smoking Cessation</keyword>
	<keyword>Work-site</keyword>
	<keyword>Incentives</keyword>
	<keyword>Health Behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>Smoking</keyword>
</DOC>