<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01526668</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to investigate the effect of four different follow-up strategies on postoperative recovery following vaginal or abdominal hysterectomy for benign conditions. Furthermore the investigators aim to examine associations between preoperative thresholds for pain (thermal and pressure) and postoperative pain and development of chronic pelvic pain after benign hysterectomy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Follow-up Strategies for Improved Postoperative Recovery After Benign Hysterectomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Contact sponsor if detailed information is requested.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Genital Diseases, Female</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women between 18 and 60 years of age. Women who are scheduled for vaginal or abdominal total or subtotal hysterectomy for benign gynecological diseases (including cervical dysplasia). Women who understand and speak Swedish fluently. Women who gives signed informed consent to participate in the study. Women who have access to a telephone and/or internet. Women where the hysterectomy is carried out in association with surgery for genital prolapse Women with genital malignancies (does not include cervical dysplasia). Women where the operation is planned or expected to comprise more than the hysterectomy with or without unilateral salpingooophorectomy and appendectomy en passant. Women with previous bilateral salpingooophorectomy. Women who are physically disabled to a degree so that mobilization postoperatively cannot be expected as for a normal individual. Women who are mentally disabled to a degree so she cannot complete the forms in the study or understand the tenor of the participation or it is considered doubtful from an ethical point of view to participate. Women with psychiatric disease or is on medication for severe psychiatric disease so that the physician consider participation in the study unsuitable. Women with current drug or alcohol abuse.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Benign gynecological disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Postoperative follow-up strategy</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain threshold</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic pelvic pain</keyword>
	<keyword>[E04.950.300.399]</keyword>
	<keyword>[C13.351.500]</keyword>
	<keyword>[F02.463.593.710.560]</keyword>
	<keyword>[N02.421.585.722.700]</keyword>
	<keyword>Postoperative Care</keyword>
</DOC>