<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01526408</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The specific aim of this study is to determine the efficacy of treatment with famciclovir in unilateral Meniere's Disease patients, specifically whether hearing can be improved. The investigators will determine the percentage of unilateral Meniere's Disease patients experiencing an absence of hearing fluctuation after 3 months of treatment with famciclovir as compared to the placebo arm.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Famvir for Treatment of Hearing in Unilateral Meniere's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Meniere Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Famciclovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>2-Aminopurine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Unilateral Meniere's Disease 2 vertigo episodes of at least 20 minutes Fluctuating hearing by subjective history and/or audiometric documentation. Audiometric documentation is defined as affected ear puretone average change from an audiogram at Time 1 to Time 2 (less than one year apart) of greater than 15 dB. Less than 45 dB 4frequency puretone average in the affected ear Tinnitus and/or aural fullness Willing to undergo the clinical trial procedures Signed informed consent Acute or chronic middle ear disease in either ear Only hearing ear 4frequency puretone average &gt; 45 dB in either ear Known allergy to famciclovir or any of the ingredients in the formulation Taking oral steroids or receiving IT steroids at time of enrollment. If the subject has been on oral steroids/IT steroids, 3 months must elapse from last dose to start of treatment in the study Must not have had previous inner ear surgery History of immunodeficiency diseases such as HIV History of renal insufficiency or other kidney diseases A female of childbearing potential who is pregnant History of noncompliance to medical regimens Unwilling to or unable to comply with the protocol, including scheduling study evaluations</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Meniere's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Vertigo</keyword>
	<keyword>Hearing loss</keyword>
	<keyword>Tinnitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-viral</keyword>
	<keyword>Famciclovir</keyword>
</DOC>