<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01526460</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effect of a loading dose of two different statins on platelet reactivity (atorvastatin, metabolized by CYP3A4, and rosuvastatin, which is rather independent of this enzyme)in patients at least 5 days in therapy with aspirin and clopidogrel (with or without an undergoing treatment with statins) undergoing PCI for coronary disease with chronic stable angina and/or evidence of inducible myocardial ischemia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Platelet Function After Statin Loading Dose in Patients Before Percutaneous Coronary Intervention</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>An initial assessment of platelet reactivity in response to the TRAP (thrombin receptor agonist), ADP and arachidonic acid (respectively, indicative of the response to clopidogrel and aspirin) will be performed with impedance aggregometry (Multiplate® analyzer system). Patients with a increased residual platelet reactivity to ADP test (AUC &gt; 47) will receive a different antiplatelet therapy and will then be excluded from the study, the other will be randomized to 3 groups of treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atorvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rosuvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: 1875 years Patients with chronic stable angina Patients with coronary artery disease or with de novo stent restenosis of native vessels. Patients who are able to understand the significance of this study and to adhere to recruitment by signing the informed consent. Acute Coronary Syndromes with an enzymatic movement (STEMI, NSTEMI). Allergy or intolerance to atorvastatin, rosuvastatin, aspirin, clopidogrel. Altered basal level of transaminase or CPK. Patient with history of hepatitisacute/chronic. Patients already receiving highdose statins. Contraindications to antiplatelet therapy. Patients with acute inflammatory disease and/or underlying chronic (hepatitis, pneumonia, urinary tract, rectum ulcerative colitis etc.). Patients with anemia (haemoglobin &lt;8.5 mg/dl), leukocytosis (WBC&gt; 12.000 mm3), leukopenia (WBC &lt;3000 mm3), platelet count &lt;100.000; hypersplenism. Patients with malignant disease. Patients enrolled in other studies not yet completed. Patients with known allergy / intolerance to statins. Pregnant women and women who are breastfeeding. Patients with myopathy (muscle pain and unexplained repeated)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Platelet</keyword>
	<keyword>Atorvastatin</keyword>
	<keyword>Rosuvastatin</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiplate</keyword>
	<keyword>reactivity</keyword>
</DOC>