<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00481143</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the effects of iron chelation using deferasirox in low and INT-1 risk (referring to the international prognostic scoring system, IPSS) MDS patients who show signs of iron overload due to repeated blood transfusions. This trial is not recruiting patients in the United States.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Deferasirox in Patients With Myelodysplastic Syndrome and Transfusion-dependent Iron Overload</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron Overload</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deferasirox</mesh_term>
	<criteria>MDS patients presenting with low or intermediate1 IPSS risk and transfusional iron overload Patients of either gender and age ≥ 18 years History of at least 20 units of red blood cell transfusions or 100mL/kg of prepacked red blood cells (PRBCs) Patients can be either naïve to iron chelation or have had prior treatment with deferoxamine (DFO) or deferiprone (L1) Females of childbearing potential must use doublebarrier contraception, oral contraceptive plus barrier contraceptive, or must have undergone clinically documented total hysterectomy and/or oophorectomy, tubal ligation or be postmenopausal defined by amenorrhea for at least 12 months. Nontransfusion related iron overload Treatment with deferasirox (ICL670) before study start Patients with a concomitant malignant disease Patients with out of range lab values History of nephrotic syndrome Patients with a previous history of clinically relevant ocular toxicity related to iron chelation Systemic diseases (cardiovascular, renal, hepatic, etc.) which would prevent the patient from undergoing study treatment Patients treated with systemic investigational drugs within the past 4 weeks or topical investigational drug within the past 7 days Any other surgical or medical condition which might significantly alter the absorption, distribution, metabolism or excretion of any drug. Patients with active uncontrolled infectious disease Pregnancy or breast feeding Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Myelodysplastic Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>MDS</keyword>
	<keyword>iron overload</keyword>
	<keyword>chelation</keyword>
	<keyword>chelators</keyword>
	<keyword>ICL670</keyword>
	<keyword>Deferasirox</keyword>
	<keyword>serum ferritin</keyword>
	<keyword>LIC</keyword>
	<keyword>transfusional hemosiderosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Refractory Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>RA</keyword>
	<keyword>Refractory Anemia with Ringed Sideroblasts</keyword>
	<keyword>RARS</keyword>
	<keyword>blood transfusions</keyword>
	<keyword>Mydelodysplastic Syndrome(s)</keyword>
</DOC>