<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03058926</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The data management systems, auditing, and monitoring effort are supported by the MD Anderson Cancer Center Clinical Research Support Center (CRSC). The The Coordination and Data Management Center (CDMC) will provide high quality, efficient and consistent leadership and services in all aspects of data quality and assurance; data harmonization and management; while providing assistance to the projects in disseminating and interpreting those data. The CDMC PI will provide statistical (study design, analysis plans, data analysis, and interpretation), data management, and data monitoring/auditing (data quality assurance and harmonization) expertise for the proposed projects. The Cancer Center will have access to identifiable data from studies; analysis of this data will not be conducted under this protocol. Any future analysis conducted on data or specimens as part of CPDPC protocols will be conducted under a separate IRB approved data or lab protocol. The CDMC will leverage existing support, infrastructure, and resources from the Data Management and Coordinating Center for the Global Cancer Early Detection and the clinical expertise of the Division of Pathology/Lab Medicine at MDACC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Coordinating and Data Management Center for the Consortium for the Study of Chronic Pancreatitis, Diabetes, and Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants with chronic pancreatis, diabetes, and pancreatic cancer recruited through Consortium.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Pancreatitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Data Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Protocol compliance</keyword>
	<keyword>Regulatory compliance</keyword>
	<keyword>Consortium studies</keyword>
</DOC>