<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03058393</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to analyze how using the teach-back communication technique can improve patient:provider communication surrounding the discussion of knee replacement options, specifically Total Knee Arthroplasty(TKA) or a Unicompartmental Knee Arthroplasty(UKA). Orthopedic residents, fellows, physician assistants, and attendings that agree to participate will be consented and patients that have a clinical indication for a TKA and a UKA will be recruited from participating providers clinical schedules. Patient:provider interactions will be recorded and then the providers will attend a 1 hour education lecture about how to use teach-back. After attending the lecture, additional patient:provider interactions will be recorded and analyzed via a qualitative approach. Additionally, providers will participate in a semi-structured interview to capture their perceptions of teach-back and what challenges and benefits they may derive from using it.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Teach-Back for Knee Replacement Discussions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Joint Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria (Patient Participants): Age 18 years and older Clinical indication for either a TKA or UKA Exclusion Criteria (Patient Participants): NonEnglish speaking Minors or nonconsenting other individuals (spouses, friends, family members, children) in the patient room during the clinical visit Inclusion Criteria (Provider Participants) Age 18 years and older A resident, fellow, physician assistant, or attending in the Duke Department of Orthopaedic Surgery A provider who is involved in the treatment of individuals requiring a TKA or UKA Exclusion criterion (Provider Participants): • NonEnglish speaking</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>