<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03058757</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of neoadjuvant intravesical mitomycin-C instillation in non-muscle invasive bladder cancer patients</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effectiveness and Safety of Neoadjuvant Intravesical Mitomycin-C Instillation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Design: Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment Masking: Open Label Primary Outcome Measures: Recurrence-free survival in neoadjuvant intravesical mitomycin-C 40mg/20ml instillation group and control group. Secondary Outcome Measures: Progression-free survival in neoadjuvant intravesical mitomycin-C 40mg/20ml instillation group and control group. Time to recurrence in neoadjuvant intravesical mitomycin-C 40mg/20ml instillation group and control group. Change of tumor size after neoadjuvant intravesical mitomycin-C 40mg/20ml instillation. Safety of neoadjuvant intravesical mitomycin-C 40mg/20ml instillation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitomycin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitomycins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The subjects who will undergo transurethral resection of the tumor after diagnosis of bladder cancer Male or female aged 18 or over 18 years and not more than 85 years who were diagnosed as bladder cancer Normal bone marrow function: Hemoglobin &gt;10 g/dL, ANC &gt;1,500/mm3, platelet count&gt;100,000/mm3 Normal renal function: serum creatinine ≤ 1.4 mg/dL Normal liver function: Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times of upper normal limit AST/ALT ≤ 1.8 times of upper normal limit Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 1.8 times of upper normal limit Subjects who voluntarily decided to participate and signed the written informed consent Nonurothelial carcinoma Muscle invasive bladder cancer Subjects who underwent intravesical mitomycinC instillation after diagnosis of bladder cancer within 3 years Prior hypersensitivity reaction history to mitomycinC Neurogenic bladder Subjects who underwent chemotherapy due to any cancer within 6 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>84 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>