<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01454791</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the effect of Diclofenac Sodium Topical Gel (DSTG) on injection site reaction following self-administer glatiramer acetate in people with Multiple Sclerosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Diclofenac Sodium Topical Gel to Reduce Injection Site Discomfort in Patients Taking Glatiramer Acetate</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A 4 week study with active or placebo medication at randomization and switch treatment at 2-week crossover visit (2 weeks on each arm). There will be a total of 3 visits to the clinic. Subjects will receive instruction on how to apply the DSTG/placebo at the injection site and keep a daily injection site reaction diary.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diclofenac</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glatiramer Acetate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of Multiple Sclerosis (MS) made at least 3 months prior based on McDonald or Poser criteria. Age 18 or more Ongoing treatment with glatiramer acetate (Copaxone) for three months or more. No MS exacerbation for 60 days prior to screening. Mean score of greater than or equal to 1.0 on screening Local Injection Site Reaction scale of last 3 days. Written informed consent. Regular use of any nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug (NDAID), except Asprin (&lt;325 mg daily), between screening and end of study. Any contraindication to Diclofenac Sodium Topical Gel (DSTG) allergy to DSTG or any NSAID. history of asthma, urticaria, or other allergic reaction after taking any NSAID. Females who are breast feeding, pregnant or have potential to become pregnant during the course of the study(fertile and unwilling/unable to use effective contraceptive measures). Cognitive deficits that would interfere with the subject's ability to give informed consent or preform study testing. Any other serious and/or unstable medical condition.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>multiple sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>diclofenac</keyword>
	<keyword>subcutaneous injection</keyword>
	<keyword>glatiramer acetate</keyword>
	<keyword>Copaxone</keyword>
</DOC>