<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01965249</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The major long term complication of abdominal wall closure after a median laparotomy is the development of an incisional hernia. Several suture technique and suture material have been used but the incidence of this complication still lies between 9 -20%. Synthetic suture material which have become available over the last decades have the advantage that they are degraded by the body system and fully absorbed within 70-180 days; however they loss 50% of their initial strength already after 14-30 days and may not be the optimal suture material for abdominal wall closure. A new suture material (Monomax®) was developed with an extra-long absorption profile, high elasticity and with a superior initial strength. Therefore, the ESTOIH-Study was designed to investigate the influence of the stitch length on the occurrence of incisional hernia using the extra-long term absorbable, elastic, monofilament suture (Monomax®).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Stitch Technique on the Occurrence of Incisional Hernia After Abdominal Wall Closure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Age ≥18 years Patients undergoing an elective, primary median laparotomy with an incision length of ≥ 15 cm Expected survival time longer than 1 year ASA IIII Written informed consent Emergency surgery Pancreatic tumour patients Patients who will be operated due to an abdominal aortic aneurysm Peritonitis Coagulopathy Current immunosuppressive therapy (more than 40 mg of a corticoid per day or azathioprin) Chemotherapy within the last 2 weeks before operation Radiotherapy of the abdomen within the last 6 weeks before operation Pregnant women (pregnancy test has to be performed) Severe neurologic and psychiatric disease Lack of compliance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Laparotomy</keyword>
	<keyword>short stitch</keyword>
	<keyword>long stitch</keyword>
	<keyword>MonoMax</keyword>
</DOC>