<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00711009</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the safety, tolerability, and antiviral activity of the lopinavir/ritonavir tablet when administered in combination with reverse transcriptase inhibitors to lopinavir/ritonavir tablets when administered in combination with a human immunodeficiency virus type 1 ( HIV-1) integrase inhibitor in antiretroviral naive HIV-1 infected subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Comparing Lopinavir/Ritonavir (LPV/r) + Emtricitabine/Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate (FTC/TDF) With a Nucleoside Sparing Regimen Consisting of Lopinavir/Ritonavir + Raltegravir (RAL)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lopinavir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine, Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Emtricitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Raltegravir Potassium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participants must provide written, voluntary informed consent to participate in the study. Participants must be naive to antiretroviral treatment with HIV RNA greater than or equal to 1,000 copies/mL at screening, and in the investigator's opinion, require antiretroviral therapy. Participant's vital signs, physical examination, and laboratory results must not exhibit evidence of acute illness. Participant has not been treated for an active acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS)defining opportunistic infection within 45 days of initiating study drug. Participants who are on stable maintenance therapy for an opportunistic infection may be enrolled after consultation with the Sponsor. Participant does not require and agrees not to take any drugs that are contraindicated or have significant pharmacokinetic interactions with study drugs during the course of the study. Participant agrees not to take any medication during the study, including overthecounter medicines, vitamins, minerals, herbal preparations, alcohol, or recreational drugs without the knowledge and permission of the principal investigator. Female participants must be either postmenopausal for at least one year, surgically sterile, or must use a nonhormonal method of birth control that is acceptable to both the participant and investigator. All female participants must have a urine pregnancy test performed at screening visit and on Day minus 1/baseline, and results of both tests must be negative. Female participants may not be breastfeeding. Participants have received no prior treatment with an HIV1 integrase inhibitor. Participants must not have history of an allergic reaction or significant sensitivity to the study drugs. Participants may not have an ongoing history of substance abuse or psychiatric illness that could preclude protocol adherence. Participant cannot have resistance to lopinavir/ritonavir, tenofovir, or emtricitabine based on the HIV1 drug resistance genotypic test results at the screening visit. Participant may not have significant medical history of concomitant illness or disease that would adversely affect his/her participating in the study. Participants may not have received any investigational drug or investigational vaccine within 30 days prior to study drug administration. Participants may not have any of the following abnormal screening results: Hemoglobin &lt;= 8.0 grams/deciliter, absolute neutrophil count &lt;= 750 cells/microliter, Platelet count &lt;= 50,000 per milliliter, alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamicpyruvic transaminase [SGPT]) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase [SGOT]) &gt;= 3.0 x upper limit of normal (ULN), calculated creatinine clearance &lt; 50 milliliter/minute, hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) is positive. The investigator considers the participant to be an unsuitable candidate for the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Human Immunodeficiency Virus infection</keyword>
</DOC>