<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00711659</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study proposes that a workshop-based educational experience which utilizes a standardized preceptor training session, a standard skills assessment checklist, and videotaped feedback will improve student comfort and confidence in performing the pediatric physical examination and will provide information to improve the curriculum offerings.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Standardizing Educational Opportunities on the Complete Pediatric Physical Exam</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The baseline clinical experience of third year medical students rotating through the clerkship varies, depending on previous clerkships and volunteer opportunities previously encountered. The less experienced third year medical student may require more time and feedback to develop competency. The availability and experience of clinical preceptors and background of the patient may also play a role in the development of pediatric physical examination skills. Other institutions have offered standardized approaches to teaching the health maintenance physical exam. To address these issues, we propose a workshop-based educational experience to (1)determine whether offering a workshop that standardizes exposure to physical exams for junior medical students will improve opportunities to practice physical exam skills in a non-threatening environment, (2)promote immediate feedback to the student that allows for self-reflection by viewing a videotape of their performance, (3)delineate how physical exam skills change in junior medical students throughout the year, and (4)evaluate the inter-rater variability of preceptors teaching health maintenance exams to students rotating through the pediatric clerkship.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>third year medical students will participate in the physical exam skills workshop as a requirement of their pediatric clerkship; data obtained from review of videotapes of students who consent for data use will be included data from students who do not consent to use of data will not be used for analysis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Physical exam</keyword>
	<keyword>Pediatric clerkship</keyword>
	<keyword>Medical students</keyword>
</DOC>