<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00711412</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as capecitabine and oxaliplatin, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Radiation therapy uses high-energy x-rays to kill tumor cells. Giving chemotherapy and radiation therapy before surgery may make the tumor smaller and reduce the amount of normal tissue that needs to be removed. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well giving capecitabine and oxaliplatin together with radiation therapy works in treating patients with esophageal or gastroesophageal junction cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Capecitabine, Oxaliplatin, and Radiation Therapy in Treating Patients With Esophageal or Gastroesophageal Junction Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Determine the pathologic complete response in patients with adenocarcinoma of the esophagus or gastroesophageal junction treated with neoadjuvant therapy comprising capecitabine, oxaliplatin, and radiotherapy. Secondary - Determine the clinical response rate in patients treated with this regimen. - Determine the recurrence rate, time to progression, and patterns of failure in patients treated with this regimen. - Characterize the toxicity profile of this regimen in these patients. OUTLINE: - Induction therapy: Patients receive oral capecitabine twice daily on days 1-14 and oxaliplatin IV over 2 hours on days 1 and 8. Treatment repeats every 21 days for 2 courses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. - Combination chemoradiotherapy: Patients then receive oxaliplatin IV over 2 hours once weekly for 6 weeks. Patients also receive concurrent oral capecitabine twice daily and undergo radiotherapy once daily 5 days a week for 5½ weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. - Surgery: Patients undergo surgical resection at 4-8 weeks after completion of chemoradiotherapy. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 3 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically or cytologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the esophagus or gastroesophageal junction Stage IIVA disease No distant metastatic disease (other than regional lymph nodes) No evidence of CNS metastases CNS metastases stable for &gt; 3 months allowed PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: ECOG performance status 02 Consuming ≥ 1,500 calories daily ANC ≥ 1,500/mm³ Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm³ Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) SGOT ≤ 2.5 times ULN Creatinine ≤ 1.5 times ULN OR creatinine clearance ≥ 50 mL/min Not pregnant or nursing Negative pregnancy test Fertile patients must use effective contraception No preexisting neuropathy No prior unanticipated severe reaction to fluoropyrimidine therapy No known hypersensitivity to fluorouracil No known DPD deficiency No known hypersensitivity to any of the components of oxaliplatin No significant active infection or other severe complicated medical illness No clinically significant cardiac disease (e.g., congestive heart failure, symptomatic coronary artery disease, or cardiac arrhythmias not well controlled with medication) No myocardial infarction within the past 12 months No history of uncontrolled seizures, CNS disorders, or psychiatric disability judged by the investigator to be clinically significant, precluding informed consent, or interfering with compliance of oral drug intake No malabsorption syndrome No other active malignancy within the past 3 years except cervical carcinoma in situ or nonmelanoma skin cancer PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: More than 4 weeks since prior participation in any investigational drug study No prior pelvic or thoracic radiotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma of the esophagus</keyword>
	<keyword>stage I esophageal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage II esophageal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III esophageal cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV esophageal cancer</keyword>
</DOC>