<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02428218</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective of the study is to assess the efficacy of oral BG00012 as compared with placebo in pediatric subjects with relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis (RRMS). The secondary objectives of this study are to evaluate the safety and tolerability of BG00012 and to compare the effect of BG00012 with placebo on additional clinical and radiological measures of disease activity.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Placebo-Controlled Study of the Efficacy and Safety of BG00012 in Pediatric Subjects With Relapsing-Remitting Multiple Sclerosis (RRMS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis, Relapsing-Remitting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dimethyl Fumarate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Key Informed consent and assent as appropriate Must have a body weight of ≥30 kg Must have a diagnosis of RRMS as defined by the revised consensus definition for pediatric multiple sclerosis (MS) Must be ambulatory with a converted Krutzke Baseline Expanded Disability Status Scale (EDSS) score between 0 and 5.0, inclusive Key Primary progressive, secondary progressive, or progressive relapsing MS. History of disorders mimicking MS, such as other demyelinating disorders (e.g., acute disseminated encephalomyelitis), systemic autoimmune disorders (e.g., Sjögren disease and lupus erythematosus), metabolic disorders (e.g., dystrophies), and infectious disorders. History of severe allergic or anaphylactic reactions, or known drug hypersensitivity to dimethyl fumarate (DMF) or fumaric acid esters. Prior treatment with any of the following medications within 12 months prior to randomization: mitoxantrone, cyclophosphamide, rituximab. Prior treatment with any of the following medications or procedures within 6 months prior to randomization: fingolimod, teriflunomide, natalizumab, cyclosporine, azathioprine, methotrexate, mycophenolate mofetil, laquinimod, intravenous (IV) immunoglobulin, plasmapheresis or cytapheresis. NOTE: Other protocol defined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Randomized</keyword>
	<keyword>Ages 10-17</keyword>
	<keyword>Pediatrics</keyword>
	<keyword>Placebo controlled</keyword>
	<keyword>Relapse-Remitting</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiple Sclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>BG00012</keyword>
</DOC>