<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02915731</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess total body vitamin A pool size, as well as liver vitamin A stores, by means of stable isotope dilution in preschool children from a South African community where liver, an exceptionally rich source of vitamin A, is frequently eaten, and the children exposed to vitamin A fortified staple foods, as well as a vitamin A supplementation programme.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Total Body Vitamin A Before and After Vitamin A Supplementation in a Community Where Liver is Frequently Eaten</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Serum retinol, the most commonly used indicator to assess vitamin A status, is homeostatically controlled and, although it is able to detect deficiency, it does not necessarily reflect liver stores or measure excessive vitamin A intake. The stable isotope dilution method is able to measure total vitamin A body pool size over the vitamin A status continuum, including the sub-toxic range,and would add valuable information about the vitamin A status in a community where liver (an exceptionally rich source of vitamin A) is frequently eaten, and children also exposed to other vitamin A interventions. Total body vitamin A will be assessed before and 4 weeks after a high dose vitamin A supplement given to the children as part of the national vitamin A supplementation program. The confounding effect of infection/inflammation on the biomarkers of vitamin A status will also be examined, as well as how serum retinol and retinol binding protein relate to each other, and to vitamin A pool size.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypervitaminosis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Retinol palmitate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Living in the study area; Must not have received a vitamin A supplement in the preceding month Severe anaemia (haemoglobin &lt; 9 g/dL); Fever (body temperature &gt; 38°C)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>36 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vitamin A stores</keyword>
	<keyword>Stable isotope dilution</keyword>
	<keyword>Multiple vitamin A interventions</keyword>
</DOC>