<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02290158</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluates the effects of a finishing protocol in orthodontic outcomes using ABO-OGS scores. Patients who finish orthodontic treatment and fulfill the inclusion and exclusion criteria receive a treatment using a finishing protocol and their scores are compare with 40 patients who don't receive a finishing protocol</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of a Finishing Protocol Implementation in Orthodontic Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The phase of finishing is the most demanding and detailed of all phases of the orthodontic treatment. American Board of Orthodontics- Objective Grading system is a detailed and objective method that evaluates the quality of the final outcome of orthodontic treatment. In order to evaluate and compare the effects of a protocol implementation on the ABO-OGS scores, standardize cast models and Pan X-Ray from by convenience patients of Orthodontic Postgraduate Program of University of Antioquia who finish orthodontic treatment and receive the protocol are digitized, eight variables are evaluate and ABO-OGS score is calculate. A comparison with 40 no-protocol ABO-OGS scores by convenience-selected patients is done. The protocol includes an educate residents program about finishing problems , an standardized clinical and X-ray assessment , brackets reposition and frequent clinical evaluation. The percentage of the protocol implementation is calculate in every patient and reliability test is make . The descriptive analysis and the ABO-OGS score comparison is done by Pearson or Spearman correlation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malocclusion</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who finish orthodontic treatment by orthodontic criteria Receive finishing protocol Accept and sign inform consent Records ( Panoramic Xray and cast models) taken immediately or 7 days after orthodontic appliances are remove Patients who don't accept being at the study Bad quality records Prosthodontic, periodontic and surgical needs treatment after orthodontic treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>treatment outcomes</keyword>
	<keyword>Malocclusion/therapy</keyword>
</DOC>