<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02290860</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) is defined as a hyperglycemia with onset or first recognition during pregnancy. GDM complicates 5 to 25% of pregnancies, depending on the diagnostic criteria used and the population being studied. GDM is an important red flag: up to 70% women with GDM will develop type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) during their lifetime. Accordingly, professional associations recommend T2DM postpartum screening (T2DM-pP-S), 6-to-24 weeks after delivery. A 75g oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT) should be performed for diagnosis (gold standard). Nevertheless, this T2DM-pP-S recommendation has failed worldwide for the same reasons: the presently impractical pattern of the testing. A solution is direly needed. Our overall goal is to improve detection of pre-diabetes and diabetes and more specifically, to facilitate the recommended T2DM-pP-S in women diagnosed with GDM. We hypothesize that, in GDM women, results of an OGTT performed after delivery, before hospital discharge (OGTT-1) predict results of the recommended OGTT at 6-to-12 weeks postpartum (OGTT-2). Our aims are: 1. To validate in Caucasian women the predictive threshold value of the 2hr-glucose of OGTT-1 established by our Stage-1 study. 2. To determine, in a multiethnic non-Caucasian cohort, the threshold value for the 2hr-glucose of OGTT-1 that is predictive of abnormal glucose tolerance at OGTT-2. 3. To define the OGTT time preference of women (before hospital discharge vs. 6-to-12 weeks postpartum). If our results are in line with our Stage-1 data, most redundant 6-to-24 weeks postpartum OGTT will be avoided. Medical practice will change.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Screening Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus on the 2nd Day After Delivery in Women With Gestational Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes, Gestational</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women aged between 18 and 45 years; Having a positive diagnosis of gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) (IADPSG or CDA criteria or patient followed for GDM); Treated with diet, insulin or oral hypoglycemic agents; Have given birth to a child at term (gestational age ≥ 37 weeks); Have signed the consent form. History of glucose intolerance or diabetes before the pregnancy; Have presented another obstetrical pathology during the pregnancy; Severe gestational high blood pressure with proteinuria; Delayed intrauterine development syndrome; Pregnancy with more than a foetus; Drug addiction; Had complications during the delivery such as: Moderate to severe postpartum bleeding; Surgery in postpartum (curettage, hysterectomy, etc.).</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>