<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02563938</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This first-in-human study will evaluate the safety and tolerability of single doses of AK001 across a range of potentially active doses. Early signals of pharmacodynamic activity will also be evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics, and Pharmacodynamics of AK001</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>AK001 is a monoclonal antibody which may be useful in the treatment of patients with severe allergic diseases.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>BMI between 1830 Determined to be in good health Clinical laboratory values within limits of normal values Normal 12lead ECG Stool sample negative for parasites Nonsmoker Consumed an average of no more than 2 drinks per day within 6 months Subjects of reproductive age must use a highly effective method of contraception Positive skin test in certain cohorts Elevated total eosinophil counts in certain cohorts Clinically significant medical history conditions or laboratory values Receipt of investigational drug, biologic or medical device within 30 days prior to Screening New drug therapy within 1 week of study drug administration Antihistamine use within 2 weeks prior to Screening Consumption of alcohol within 48 hours of study drug administration Positive urine drug test or cotinine test at Screening or Day 1 History, within the last 2 years, of alcohol abuse, illicit drug use, or significant mental illness Demonstration of veins unsuitable for repeated venipuncture or IV infusion Recent treatment with alternative therapies which may confound clinical or laboratory assessments Donation or loss of more than 500 mL of blood within 56 days prior to study drug administration History of malignancy within last 5 years History of severe allergic or anaphylactic reactions Females who are pregnant or breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>