<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02563548</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase 1b study evaluating a combination of PEGPH20 and pembrolizumab for subjects with relapsed/refractory advanced or metastatic Non Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC) who have failed at least 1 platinum-based chemotherapy regimen and subjects with relapsed/refractory locally advanced or metastatic gastric adenocarcinoma after failing at least 1 chemotherapy regimen.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 1b Open-Label Study of PEGPH20 With Pembrolizumab</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a phase 1b study for subjects with relapsed/refractory advanced or metastatic NSCLC who have failed at least 1 platinum-based chemotherapy regimen and subjects with relapsed/refractory locally advanced or metastatic gastric adenocarcinoma after failing at least 1 chemotherapy regimen. This study will consist of a Phase 1b dose escalation portion to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of either 1.6, 2.2, 2.6, 3.0, 4.0 ug/kg (or higher doses if necessary) of PEGPH20 in combination with Pembrolizumab. Once the recommended phase 2 dose has been identified in the escalation portion, additional patients selected for high-HA tumors will be enrolled in the dose expansion portion</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically confirmed and documented, previously treated stage IIIB or IV Non Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC) having failed at least 1 previous platinum containing chemotherapy regimen for locally advanced or metastatic disease or relapsed/refractory locally advanced or metastatic gastric adenocarcinoma having failed at least 1 previous chemotherapy regimen for locally advanced or metastatic disease. Subjects with NSCLC who are known to be epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)mutation positive must have received an EGFR inhibitor and subjects known to be anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK)mutation positive must have received an ALK inhibitor. Prior to enrollment, confirmation of the following must be obtained: Dose escalation For subjects in the dose escalation portion of the study, it is preferred that there is available archived tumor tissue in a formalinfixed paraffinembedded (FFPE) block or 510 unstained core biopsy slides that meet specific tissue sample requirements, however it is not mandatory for enrollment in this portion of the study. Dose expansion For subjects in the dose expansion portion of the study, it is mandatory that available archived tumor tissue in FFPE block or minimum 10 unstained consecutive core biopsy slides from 1 archival block that meet specific tissue requirements are available. One or more tumors measurable on CT scan/MRI scan per RECIST v 1.1. Previously irradiated tumors may be eligible if they have clearly progressed in size. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 or 1. Life expectancy ≥3 months. Previous treatment with pembrolizumab, nivolumab, or other programmed cell death1 antibody (anti PD1) or PD1 ligandantibody (antiPDL1) agents. New York Heart Association Class III or IV (Appendix D) cardiac disease or myocardial infarction within the past 12 months before screening, or preexisting atrial fibrillation. Prior history of cerebrovascular accident or transient ischemic attack. NSCLC subjects with known brain metastases (certain exceptions allowed) Gastric adenocarcinoma subjects with brain metastases History of active bleeding within the last 3 months requiring transfusion AntiVEGF therapy within the last month Patients with known interstitial fibrosis or interstitial lung disease. Previous history of pulmonary embolism or pulmonary embolism found on screening exam. Active autoimmune disease requiring systemic treatment within the past 3 months or documented history of clinically severe autoimmune disease, or syndrome that requires systemic steroids or immunosuppressive agents. History of another primary cancer within the last 3 years that required treatment, with the exception of nonmelanoma skin cancer, earlystage prostate cancer, or curatively treated cervical carcinoma in situ.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>