<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02563093</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to evaluate the safety and immunogenicity of the 2015-2016 formulations of Fluzone Quadrivalent and Fluzone Intradermal Quadrivalent vaccines in adults 18 to &lt; 65 years of age, and of the 2015-2016 formulations of Fluzone Quadrivalent and Fluzone High-Dose vaccines in adults ≥ 65 years of age. Primary Objective: - To describe the safety of the 2015-2016 formulations of Fluzone Quadrivalent and Fluzone Intradermal Quadrivalent vaccines in adults 18 to &lt; 65 years of age and the safety of the 2015-2016 formulations of Fluzone Quadrivalent and Fluzone High-Dose vaccines in adults ≥ 65 years of age. Observational Objectives: - To describe the immunogenicity of the 2015-2016 formulations of Fluzone Quadrivalent and Fluzone Intradermal Quadrivalent vaccines in adults 18 to &lt; 65 years of age and the immunogenicity of the 2015-2016 formulations of Fluzone Quadrivalent and Fluzone High-Dose vaccines in adults ≥ 65 years of age. - To evaluate the compliance, in terms of immunogenicity, of each study vaccine (Fluzone Quadrivalent, Fluzone Intradermal Quadrivalent, and Fluzone High-Dose) in the applicable age group with the historical requirements of the Committee for Human Medicinal Products (CHMP) Note for Guidance (NfG) Committee for Propriety Medicinal Products (CPMP) - CHMP NfG CPMP/BWP/214/96.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Fluzone® Quadrivalent, Fluzone® Intradermal Quadrivalent, and Fluzone® High-Dose, Influenza Vaccines in Adults</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Adults age 18 to &lt; 65 years will be randomly assigned to receive either Fluzone Quadrivalent or Fluzone Intradermal Quadrivalent vaccine and adults age ≥ 65 years will be randomly assigned to receive either Fluzone Quadrivalent or Fluzone High-Dose vaccine. All subjects will receive a single dose of their randomly assigned vaccine. They will be followed from Visit 1 to Visit 2 for evaluation of safety outcomes. Solicited adverse reactions will be collected for 7 days after vaccination. Unsolicited non-serious adverse events (AEs) and serious adverse events (SAEs) will be collected from Visit 1 to Visit 2.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is ≥ 18 years of age on the day of inclusion Informed consent form has been signed and dated Able to attend all scheduled visits and to comply with all trial procedures. History of serious adverse reaction to any influenza vaccine Receipt of any vaccine within 30 days before receiving study vaccine, or plans to receive another vaccine before Visit 2 Participation in another interventional clinical trial investigating a vaccine, drug, medical device, or medical procedure in the 30 days preceding the first study vaccination or during the course of the study, unless no intervention for the other study occurred within the 30 days prior to the first study vaccination and none are planned before the subject would complete safety surveillance for the present study Thrombocytopenia, which may be a contraindication for intramuscular vaccination, at the discretion of the Investigator Prior vaccination with any 20152016 formulation of influenza vaccine Known systemic hypersensitivity to eggs, chicken proteins, or any of the vaccine components, or a history of a lifethreatening reaction to Fluzone Quadrivalent, Fluzone Intradermal Quadrivalent, or Fluzone HighDose vaccine or to a vaccine containing any of the same substances (the complete list of vaccine components is included in the Prescribing Information) Receipt of immune globulins, blood, or bloodderived products in the past 3 months Bleeding disorder or receipt of anticoagulants in the 3 weeks preceding inclusion, which may be a contraindication for intramuscular vaccination, at the discretion of the Investigator Subject is pregnant, or lactating, or of childbearing potential (to be considered of nonchildbearing potential, a female must be postmenopausal for at least 1 year, surgically sterile, or using an effective method of contraception or abstinence from at least 4 weeks prior to vaccination and until at least 4 weeks after vaccination) Any condition that in the opinion of the Investigator would pose a health risk to the subject if enrolled or could interfere with the evaluation of the vaccine Personal history of GuillainBarré syndrome Known or suspected congenital or acquired immunodeficiency; or receipt of immunosuppressive therapy, such as anticancer chemotherapy or radiation therapy, within the preceding 6 months; or longterm systemic corticosteroid therapy (prednisone or equivalent for more than 2 consecutive weeks within the past 3 months) Chronic illness that, in the opinion of the Investigator, is at a stage where it might interfere with trial conduct or completion Seropositivity for human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C, as reported by the subject. Deprived of freedom by an administrative or court order, or in an emergency setting, or hospitalized involuntarily Current alcohol or drug addiction that, in the opinion of the Investigator, might interfere with the ability to comply with trial procedures Moderate or severe acute illness/infection (according to Investigator judgment) or febrile illness (temperature ≥ 100.4°F) on the day of vaccination. A prospective subject should not be included in the study until the condition has resolved or the febrile event has subsided Identified as an Investigator or employee of an Investigator or study center with direct involvement in the proposed study, or identified as an immediate family member (i.e., parent, spouse, natural or adopted child) of an Investigator or employee with direct involvement in the proposed study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Influenza</keyword>
	<keyword>Fluzone® Quadrivalent, Influenza Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Fluzone® Intradermal Quadrivalent, Influenza Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Fluzone® High Dose, Influenza Vaccine</keyword>
</DOC>