<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02563496</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a prospective, open-label, multicenter, non-comparative, single arm study of pediatric subjects with Plasmodium vivax (P. vivax) malaria, aged 6 months to &lt;16 years of age. A total of 60 subjects will be enrolled. Potential subjects who are slide-positive for P. vivax will be started by the site on chloroquine (CQ) per local/national guidelines. Sites will have up to 48 hours to obtain consent. Once full consent is provided, all subjects will be screened and, if eligible, receive Tafenoquine (TQ), given as a single dose on Day 1. All study medication should be taken with food. After the treatment period, subjects will attend up to 7 follow-up visits through Day 120 (Days 3, 8, 15, 29, 60, 90 and 120). The main cohort will consist of subjects aged &gt;=2 years to &lt;16 years with no restriction on gender. Subjects will be dosed according to four weight bands. Within the total of 60 enrolled pediatric subjects, a second cohort of up to 6 infants aged &gt;=6 months to &lt;2 years (weighing &gt;=5 kilogram [kg]) will be recruited following completion of a planned first interim analysis. An interim analysis will be conducted once sufficient data from 16 subjects is available to assess pharmacokinetic (PK) and safety parameters. If needed, a second interim analysis will be conducted after a total of 32 subjects have enrolled. The primary objective of this PK bridging study is to adequately characterize the systemic TQ exposure in the pediatric population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Pharmacokinetics, Safety and Efficacy Study of Tafenoquine (TQ) in Pediatric Subjects With Plasmodium Vivax (P. Vivax) Malaria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malaria, Vivax</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chloroquine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chloroquine diphosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tafenoquine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is &gt;=2 years to &lt;16 years of age at the time of signing of the assent and/or informed consent. An additional cohort of subjects aged &gt;=6 months to &lt;2 years may be recruited following the first interim analysis. The subject has a positive malarial smear for P. vivax. The subject has a history of fever within 48 hours prior to enrollment. The subject has a glucose 6phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) value (measured by a quantitative spectrophotometric phenotype assay) &gt;=70% of the site median value for G6PD normal adult males. The subject has a screening Hb value &gt;=8 gram per decilitre (g/dL). The subject has a body weight &gt;=5 kg. Males and females are eligible to enter the study. A female is eligible to enter and participate in this study if she is nonpregnant, nonlactating and if she is of: Nonchildbearing potential (i.e., premenstrual); or Childbearing potential, has a negative pregnancy test at screening, and agrees to comply with one of the following during the treatment stage of the study and for a period of 90 days after stopping study medication: Complete abstinence from intercourse for 2 weeks prior to administration of study medication, throughout the study and for a period of 90 days after stopping study medication; Use of combined oral contraceptive consisting of spermicide with either condom or diaphragm; Use of intrauterine device with a documented failure rate of &lt;1% per year; Use of depo provera injection; Male partner who is sterile prior to the female subject's entry into the study and is the sole sexual partner for that female. The subject and/or the subject's parent(s)/legal guardian(s) agree to G6PD genotyping in the context of a subsequent hemolytic anemia AE. The subject and parent(s)/legal guardian(s) are willing and able to comply with the study protocol. In accordance with regional/local laws and regulations, the parent(s)/legal guardian(s) has given written informed, dated consent; and the subject has given written assent, if applicable, to participate in the study. The subject has a mixed malaria infection (identified by a malarial smear or rapid diagnostic test). The subject has a condition that may affect absorption of study medication, such as severe vomiting (no food or inability to take food during the previous 8 hours). The subject has a liver alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt;2 time the upper limit of normal (ULN). The subject has a clinically significant concurrent illness (for example; pneumonia, meningitis, septicaemia, coagulopathy, severe hemorrhage), preexisting condition (e.g., renal disease, malignancy, malnutrition, known preexisting human immunodeficiency virus [HIV]), febrile convulsions prior to consent, or clinical signs and symptoms of severe cardiovascular disease (for example; congenital heart disease). The subject has a history of porphyria, psoriasis, or epilepsy. The subject has taken antimalarials (for example; artemisininbased combination therapies, mefloquine, primaquine, or any other 4 or 8aminoquinoline) or drugs with antimalarial activity within 30 days prior to study entry. The subject has received treatment with any investigational drug within 30 days of study entry, or within 5 halflives, whichever is longer. The subject has taken or will likely require during the study the use of: histamine2 blockers, antacids, antidiabetic drugs of the biguanide class (i.e., phenformin, buformin), antiarrhythmic agents dofetilide, procainamide, pilsicainide. The subject has a serum creatinine above the ULN and is currently taking metformin. The subject has a history of allergy or intolerance to chloroquine, mefloquine, tafenoquine, primaquine, or to any other 4 or 8aminoquinoline. The subject has previously enrolled in this study. The subject has severe P. vivax malaria as defined by world health organization (WHO) criteria</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetic</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatric</keyword>
	<keyword>Tafenoquine</keyword>
	<keyword>Plasmodium vivax Malaria</keyword>
	<keyword>G6PD deficiency</keyword>
</DOC>