<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03054909</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a single center, randomized phase II study of an IL-15Rα-Fc super-agonist complex (ALT-803) given as maintenance therapy after the completion of 1st line IV/IP chemotherapy for the treatment of advanced ovarian, fallopian tube, and primary peritoneal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>QUILT-2.021: Phase I of IP Followed by SQ ALT-803 for Ovarian Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this study all patients receive four 8 week cycles of ALT-803 consisting of 4 weekly doses followed by a 4 week rest (no treatment). As it is not known how intraperitoneal (IP) administration (a route of drug administration frequently used for gynecologic cancers) of ALT-803 compares to subcutaneous (SQ) administration, both routes of administration will be tested. The primary objective of this trial is to select one method of delivery for further testing.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peritoneal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of epithelial ovarian, fallopian tube or primary peritoneal carcinoma, has received at least 3 cycles of first line IV/IP cisplatin and paclitaxel chemotherapy and has stable disease or better as defined by measurable/evaluable tumor and/or CA125 levels Able to begin study therapy within 3 weeks (+/ 1 week) of final IV/IP chemotherapy Functioning intraperitoneal catheter ≥ 18 years of age GOG performance status ≤ 2 (appendix II) Adequate organ function within 14 days of registration defined as: Hematology: hemoglobin &gt; 8 g/dl, platelets &gt; 50 x 109/L Creatinine: ≤ 2.0 mg/dL Hepatic: SGOT and SGPT &lt; 3 x upper limit of institutional normal (ULN) Ability to be off prednisone and other immunosuppressive drugs (&lt; 1 mg/day) for at least 3 days prior to and while receiving ALT803 Available archived tumor (formalinfixed, paraffinembedded tissue block) for genomic and proteomic analysis Voluntary written consent prior to the performance of any research related procedures Received any investigational agent within the 14 days before the start of ALT803 Class II or greater New York Heart Association Functional Classification criteria (appendix II) or serious cardiac arrhythmias likely to increase the risk of cardiac complications of cytokine therapy (e.g. ventricular tachycardia, frequent ventricular ectopy, or supraventricular tachyarrhythmia requiring chronic therapy) Marked baseline prolongation of QT/QTc interval (e.g. demonstration of a QTc interval greater than 500 milliseconds) Uncontrolled bacterial, fungal or viral infections including HIV1/2 or active hepatitis C/B chronic asymptomatic viral hepatitis is allowed Active autoimmune disease requiring systemic immunosuppressive therapy History of severe asthma and currently on chronic systemic medications (mild asthma requiring inhaled steroids only is eligible)</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>