<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02394262</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Currently, cardiac computed tomography angiography (CCTA) is a well-implemented non-invasive diagnostic imaging modality in patients with stable chest pain. Besides conventional CT-reading, CCTA is also capable to identify several morphologic and geometric characteristics of atherosclerotic plaques. Recently, the investigators showed that the use of semi-automated plaque quantification algorithm identified parameters predictive for acute coronary syndrome on top of clinical risk profiling and conventional CT-reading. In addition, several atherotrombosis biomarkers, like high-sensitivity cardiac troponins, are described as related to coronary artery disease and cardiovascular events. Prospective data with sequential analysis of atherosclerotic plaques combined with different atherothrombosis biomarkers are currently lacking, but will provide important clues about the pathophysiology of plaque progression and atherothrombosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sequential Coronary CT-angiography and Biomarkers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with a recent history of (a)typical chest pain, who underwent a coronary calcium score scan as well as CCTA. Age older than 18 years and competent to perform written informed consent. At least 2 coronary segments with plaques: 1 proximal lesion. At least one coronary plaque consisting of a noncalcified or mixed component. Unstable angina. Renal insufficiency: calculated estimated glomerular filtration rate &lt;45mL/min. Iodine allergy. Pregnancy. Known history of atrial fibrillation. Inconclusive baseline computed coronary CTangiography. Patients which are currently on oral vitamin K antagonists. Patients which are currently using selective anticoagulants. Previous PCI. Previous or planned coronary artery bypass grafting. Patients whereby the baseline CCTA was performed by a retrospective ECGgated 'helical' protocol due to a high (&gt;90bpm) or irregular heart rate.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Biological Markers</keyword>
	<keyword>Multidetector Computed Tomography</keyword>
</DOC>