<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02273323</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Research indicate that people who regularly drink tea have a reduced risk of stroke or heart disease. In a number of studies in which people that normally do not drink showed that their blood vessels function improved when the drunk tea. The current study tests whether a specific black tea improves vessel function in non-tea drinking hypertensive subjects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Flow Mediated Dilation in Response to Black Tea</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Epidemiological studies indicate that regular consumption of three cups of black tea per day reduces the risk of stroke or myocardial infarction. In a number of previous nutrition intervention studies tea has been shown to improve vascular function as assessed by Flow Mediated Dilation in various populations. The current confirmatory study tests a specific black tea against a placebo in a population of in non-tea drinking hypertensive subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dilatation, Pathologic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and post menopausal (&gt; 1 year) females, not on hormone replacement therapy Aged &gt;18 and &lt; 65 years Body mass index (BMI) of &gt;=18.0 and =&lt;35.0 kg/m2 Hypertension as previously diagnosed by primary care or hospital physician. If untreated, office BP between 140/90 mmHg and 160/100 mmHg on screening If treated, a controlled blood pressure (&lt;160/100) on stable medication for at least 4 weeks Tea drinkers: having typically consumed &gt; 1 cup of black tea per week. Current smoker or has stopped smoking less than 6 months before start of study Self reported alcohol intake of &gt;21 units/week Established cardiovascular disease other than hypertension Clinically significant arrhythmia Diabetes mellitus Chronic Kidney Disease &gt; stage 2 10year cardiovascular risk equivalent to 20% or greater using the QRisk2 calculator Abnormality of laboratory blood tests considered clinically significant Any other significant intercurrent condition/disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Flow mediated dilation</keyword>
	<keyword>tea</keyword>
	<keyword>blood pressure</keyword>
</DOC>