<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01388361</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted in Europe and North America. The aim of this trial is to compare the efficacy and safety of adding liraglutide versus addition of insulin aspart with the largest meal to insulin degludec in subjects with type 2 diabetes. Eligible subjects with an HbA1c equal to or above 7% at end of treatment in NN1250-3643 (NCT01193309) trial will be randomised to receive treatment intensification while subjects with an HbA1c below 7% at end of treatment in NN1250-3643 (NCT01193309) may continue to receive insulin degludec treatment. Subjects are to continue their pre-trial metformin treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of the Efficacy and Safety of Two Intensification Strategies in Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes Inadequately Controlled on Basal Insulin and Metformin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Long-Acting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Aspart</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent obtained before any trialrelated activities. (Trialrelated activities are any procedure that would not have been performed during normal management of the subject). The subject must have completed the end of treatment visit of NN12503643 with Insulin degludec once daily + metformin. Ability and willingness to adhere to the protocol including self measurement of plasma glucose according to the protocol Participated in NN12503643 and treated with insulin glargine Previous treatment with glucacon like peptide (GLP1) receptor agonists (e.g. exenatide, liraglutide) Impaired liver function, defined as alanine aminotransferase (ALAT) 2.5 times the upper limit of normal at end of treatment in NN12503643 Impaired renal function defined as serumcreatinine = 125 µmol/l (= 1.4 mg/dl) for males and = 110 µmol/L (= 1.3 mg/dl) for females or according to local label for metformin [For France: glomerular filtration rate below 60 ml/min, calculated by the Cockroft &amp; Gault formula] at end of treatment in NN12503643.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>