<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01388933</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether Daikenchuto(TU-100)is effective in the treatment of Crohn's disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Safety and Efficacy Study of Daikenchuto (TU-100) to Treat Crohn's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Crohn's disease, a chronic condition resulting in inflammation of the gastrointestinal tract (GI), causes a person to experience persistent symptoms of inflammatory bowel disease, including abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, rectal bleeding, diarrhea, and constipation, with infrequent bowel movements that are at times accompanied by a sensation of incomplete emptying after having a bowel movement. Tsumura's TU-100 is a modern herbal product that has been approved as a prescription drug in Japan. Several lines of evidence indicate that TU-100 attenuates intestinal inflammation in Crohn's disease by increasing intestinal blood flow and stimulating a protective lining of intestinal mucus which produces an anti-inflammatory effect. TU-100 may attenuate pathological changes in the intestine and reduce symptoms in patients with Crohn's disease.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>provide written informed consent ability to orally ingest study medication male or female between 18 to 75 inclusive diagnosed with Crohn's disease for at least 3 months CDAI score of 220300 at screening sexually active participants of childbearing potential must agree to birth control no clinically significant conditions which the doctor would feel exclusionary stable medication (including probiotics) history of any bowel condition that may interfere with the evaluation of the study drug positive stool cultures currently pregnant or lactating receiving total parenteral nutrition history of alcohol or drug abuse within one year history of malignancy within 5 years current use of anticholinergic agents, antidepressants during the study, warfarin, prokinetics, antipsychotic agents or narcotic analgesics treatment with AntiTNF agents 12 weeks before screening treatment with corticosteroids four weeks prior to screening treatment with cyclosporine or tacrolimus eight weeks prior to screening presence of a poorly controlled medical condition history of allergic reaction to ginseng, ginger or sichuan pepper any use of supplemental ginger, ginseng and Sichuan powder 2 weeks prior to and through course of the trial current use of any of the following herbal medications: Boswellia, Cat's claw (Uncaria tomentosa), Cayenne pepper, Echinacea, Horsetail (Equisetum), Hops, Lady's mantle (Alchemilla), Marshmallow root (Althaea), Slippery elm (Ulmus rubra) Turmeric and White Willow (Salix alba) history of celiac disease current diagnosis of lactose intolerance history of any other investigational medication within 30 days of enrolling in study unsuitability as determined by the study doctor</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Crohn's Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>natural</keyword>
	<keyword>herbal</keyword>
	<keyword>Kampo</keyword>
	<keyword>inflammatory bowel disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Adult ages 18 to 75</keyword>
	<keyword>Male and female subjects</keyword>
</DOC>