<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="29607">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02721277</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB201600068</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02721277</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SMOFlipid to Lessen the Severity of Neonatal Cholestasis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Compassionate Use of an Intravenous Fat Emulsion Comprised of Soy Oil, Medium Chain Triglycerides, Olive Oil, and Fish Oil for Neonates With Parenteral Nutrition Induced Liver Injury</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Florida</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Florida</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Parenteral nutrition (PN) provides intravenous nutritional supplementation for infants
      unable to absorb adequate enteral nutrients secondary to insufficient intestinal length or
      function. In early PN-associated cholestasis, the dose of traditional soy based lipid is
      limited to 1 g/kg/day which often limits the growth capacity of parenteral
      nutrition-dependent infants. Inadequate growth is directly related to poor neurological
      outcomes, failure to facilitate mechanical ventilation, and less growth of the neonate's
      already damaged intestine. Ultimately, these outcomes can lead to severe disability and
      death. To mitigate these deleterious effects and optimize growth, parenteral
      nutrition-dependent infants with cholestasis who are not adequately growing on 1 g/kg/day of
      soy-based lipid emulsion must have a greater intake of lipids to meet their needs for
      weight, length, and head circumference growth.

      SMOFlipid contains a mixture of 4 different lipid sources: soybean oil which provides
      essential fatty acids, olive oil which is high in monounsaturated fatty acids that are less
      susceptible to lipid peroxidation than polyunsaturated fatty acids, medium-chain
      triglycerides which show a faster metabolic clearance than long-chain triglycerides, and
      fish oil which provides the supply of omega-3 fatty acids. The utility of Omegaven and
      soy-based lipid emulsion is limited as these are restricted to 1 g/kg/day in cholestatic
      infants. SMOFlipid is safe to be provided at the usual goal infusion amount of 3 g/kg/day.
      Because this product includes both omega-6 and omega-3 lipids, it provides the benefits of
      the omega-3s for the liver and provides more than enough omega-6s to meet essential fatty
      acid requirements. Its use in situations in which growth is inadequate in babies who must be
      restricted to 1 g/kg/day can be expected to improve their growth and likely markedly
      increase their chances of both a good neurological outcome and survival.

      The aim of this research study is to determine if the unique formulation of SMOFLipid will
      cause less hepatic inflammation compared to soy only intralipids.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The neonates who are being treated at the University of Florida Health Neonates Intensive
      Care Unit and are anticipated to need more than 21 days of intravenous nutrition will be
      considered as potential subjects. These subjects will receive the unique formulation of
      SMOFLipid

      The following data will be collected from the subject's EMR by members of the research team:

        -  Lab values that evaluate liver function

        -  Growth parameters like head circumference, length, weight

        -  Medical/surgical history

        -  Time to resolution of bilirubin, time to liver transplant, time to death

        -  Length of hospital stay

        -  Rates of blood infections

      Subjects will remain on SMOFlipid until weaned from PN.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Inflammation of the liver between the groups</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammation of the liver will be evaluated by comparing direct bilirubin values between the two groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measurement of head circumference for growth increase</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Growth increase will be measured by head circumference of participants.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measurement of weight for growth increase</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Growth increase will be measured by weight of participants.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measurement of length for growth increase</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Growth increase will be measured by length of participants.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects requiring surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of concomitant medications received</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of IV nutritional therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects receiving formula diet</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Enteral administration of formula will be noted</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects receiving breast milk diet</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Enteral administration of breast milk will be noted</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with adverse events related to treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory values will be used to determine adverse events.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Carbon Dioxide Total</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory value that determines acid-base balance</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total protein</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory value that evaluates liver function</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Albumin</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory value that evaluates liver function</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Aspartate aminotransferase</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory value that evaluates liver function</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Alanine aminotransferase</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory value that evaluates liver function</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total Bilirubin</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory value that evaluates liver function</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum Glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory values that evaluates glucose in the blood</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Alkaline phosphatase</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory value that evaluates liver function</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Triglyceride</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory value that evaluates liver function and metabolism of fat</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of days on mechanical ventilation via endotracheal tube</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Length of therapy with mechanical ventilation</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of days on oxygen via continuous positive airway pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Length of therapy with nasal continuous positive airway pressure</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of days on oxygen via nasal cannula</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Length of therapy with nasal cannula</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of days with central venous catheter</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of blood infections</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>A review of the subject's medical record will determine the presence of bacterial, viral, or fungi colony-forming units (CFU) in the blood.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Numbers of blood infection obtained from a venipuncture</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>A review of the subject's medical record will determine the location from which positive blood cultures were obtained.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Numbers of blood infection obtained from a central venous catheter</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>A review of the subject's medical record will determine the location from which positive blood cultures were obtained.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">2</enrollment>
  <condition>Cholestasis</condition>
  <condition>Jaundice, Obstructive</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SMOFlipid</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects with cholestasis will receive 3 G/kg/day of intravenous SMOFlipid daily until parenteral nutrition (PN) is discontinued. In addition, the following monitoring for effects of SMOFlipid will be performed: total days of parenteral nutrition, maximum conjugated bilirubin, time to resolution of bilirubin, time to liver transplant, time to death, positive blood cultures, rates of increase in weight, length, and head circumference, time dependent changes in liver function tests, including triglycerides, and length of hospital stay.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SMOFlipid</intervention_name>
    <description>SMOFlipid contains a mixture of 4 different lipid sources: soybean oil which provides essential fatty acids, olive oil which is high in monounsaturated fatty acids that are less susceptible to lipid peroxidation than polyunsaturated fatty acids, medium-chain triglycerides which show a faster metabolic clearance than long-chain triglycerides, and fish oil which provides the supply of omega-3 fatty acids.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SMOFlipid</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Parenteral nutrition (PN)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Greater than 14 days old and less than 1 year of age.

          -  Greater than 1 kg.

          -  Mild cholestasis, defined as a conjugated bilirubin between 0.5-1.9 mg/dL

          -  Currently standard therapy with soy-based Intralipid

          -  Evidence of growth of weight, head circumference or length below our standards for
             post-menstrual age for at least 1 week.

          -  Be expected to require intravenous nutrition for at least an additional 21 days

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Have a congenitally lethal condition.

          -  Have clinically severe bleeding or clinical liver failure not able to be managed with
             routine measures.

          -  Have evidence of a viral hepatitis or primary liver disease as the primary etiology
             of their cholestasis.

          -  Have other health problems such that survival is extremely unlikely even if the
             infant's cholestasis improves
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>23 Weeks</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>1 Year</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Josef Neu, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Florida</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32610</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>December 21, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 23, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Parenteral nutrition, Total</keyword>
  <keyword>Infant, newborn</keyword>
  <keyword>Cholestasis</keyword>
  <keyword>Enterocolitis, Necrotizing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Cholestasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Jaundice</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Jaundice, Obstructive</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
