<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01807351</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Retrospective cohort of all the patients with elevated blood sugar (but no Diabetes) attending the study sites from 2002 to 2007. We retrieval their records to see how many of them actually developed diabetes. The patient's record will be followed up to 6 years after their first abnormally high blood sugar checked. We will measure their parameters including sex, age, pay code and whether they have hypertension or not to see what factors will increase risk of DM development.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Progression From Impaired Fasting Glucose to Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus Among Subjects With and Without Hypertension in Primary Care Setting</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>We aim at find out the progression of impaired fasting glucose (IFG) to type 2 Diabetes Mellitus (T2DM) among patients in general practice setting. We can understand the progress of the target patients so as to improve patient education, improve patient motivation in lifestyle modification.We are going to find out the annual incidence of Type 2 DM developement among the patients with and without hypertension Hypertensive patients with impaired fasting glucose are more likely to develop type 2 diabetes mellitus compare with normal tensive patients</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prediabetic State</mesh_term>
	<criteria>We include all subjects age ≥18 attended the study centers with laboratory diagnosis of IFG by blood sugar 6.1 mmol/l to 6.9 mmol/l checked from 2002 to 2007 in the 6 study centres. We excluded the subjects who have diagnosis of T2DM the years prior to the year of blood taken. We define T2DM by physician coding ICPC2 of T90 Diabetes noninsulin dependent or prescription of antidiabetic drugs (British National Formulary(23) (BNF) section 6.1 and 6.2). We exclude the patients who had been admitted to Hong Kong Hospital Authority (HKHA)or attended HKHA specialty Clinic, or attended any GOPC with dispensing history of drug used in diabetes in BNF Section 6.1.1 insulins or 6.1.2 antidiabetic drugs, or with ICPC coded with T90) during 1 Jan 2005 31 Dec 2006 (i.e. 2 year prior to starting of study period). We also excluded patient with the date of diagnosis of DM by above criteria earlier than the date of laboratory test results of IFG.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>Impaired Fasting Glucose</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary Health Care</keyword>
	<keyword>Chinese</keyword>
</DOC>