<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01807468</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate feasibility and efficacy of haploidentical stem cell transplantation in patients with high-risk solid tumors who failed after tandem high-dose chemotherapy and autologous stem cell transplantation. To evaluate feasibility and efficacy of NK cell infusion after haploidentical stem cell transplantation in patients with high-risk solid tumors who failed after tandem high-dose chemotherapy and autologous stem cell transplantation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Haploidentical Stem Cell Transplantation and NK Cell Therapy in Patients With High-risk Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>HaploSCT following reduced-intensity conditioning (RIC) regimen will be performed in patients with high-risk solid tumors. Both parents will be evaluated for their KIR genotype and phenotype and the one with the greatest degree of KIR-L mismatch with the patient will be selected as the donor. In addition, ex-vivo expanded NK cells derived from the donor will then be administered after haploSCT to increase the GVT effect. Low-dose IL-2 will be given after expanded NK cell infusion to enhance NK cell alloreactivity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma, Ewing</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Osteosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhabdomyosarcoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age &lt; 21 years old Patients with highrisk solid tumors who failed prior HDCT/autoSCT Patients with a suitable haploidentical donor Highrisk solid tumors include highrisk neuroblastoma, metastatic or relapsed Ewing sarcoma, relapsed osteosarcoma, highrisk brain tumors, relapsed germ cell tumors, relapsed soft tissue sarcoma, relapsed rhabdomyosarcoma, and etc. stable disease with salvage chemotherapy after relapse organ dysfunction(NCI common toxicity criteria grade &gt; 2) progression of disease despite salvage chemotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>haploidentical stem cell transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>natural killer cell therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>pediatric solid tumor</keyword>
</DOC>