<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01807520</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To demonstrate the efficacy of secukinumab versus placebo on nail psoriasis and to assess long-term efficacy, safety and tolerability of secukinumab.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Safety, Tolerability, and Efficacy of Secukinumab in Subjects With Moderate to Severe Nail Psoriasis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Benzocaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects with chronic moderate to severe plaque type psoriasis for at least 6 months prior to randomization, including significant nail involvement, defined as Nail Psoriasis Severity Index (NAPSI) score ≥16 AND number of fingernails involved ≥4 AND Psoriasis Area and Severity Index (PASI) score ≥12 AND Body Surface Area (BSA) score ≥10% Candidates for systemic therapy, i.e. psoriasis inadequately controlled by topical treatment (including super potent topical corticosteroids) and/or phototherapy and/or previous systemic therapy Forms of psoriasis other than chronic plaque type psoriasis (e.g., pustular psoriasis, palmoplantar pustulosis, acrodermatitis of Hallopeau, erythrodermic and guttate psoriasis) Druginduced psoriasis (e.g. new onset or current exacerbation from βblockers, calcium channel inhibitors or lithium) Ongoing inflammatory skin diseases other than psoriasis or any other disease affecting the fingernails which may potentially confound the evaluation of study treatment effects Ongoing use of prohibited treatments (e.g. topical or systemic corticosteroids (CS), UV therapy). Washout periods do apply Prior exposure to secukinumab (AIN457) or any other biological drug directly targeting IL17 or the IL17 receptor Exposure to any investigational drugs within 4 weeks prior to study treatment initiation or within a period of 5 halflives of the investigational treatment, whichever is longer History of hypersensitivity to constituents of the study treatment Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria do apply</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Moderate nail psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Severe nail psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Secukinumab</keyword>
</DOC>