<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01106573</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Diabetes Mellitus (DM) is frequently appearing in patients with cardiovascular disease and these patients, as a consequence herby, has a lesser prognosis. DM is often related to increased arterial stiffness and hypertension. The investigators thesis is that DM and pre-diabetes is prevalent in patients undergoing cardiovascular surgery and to some extend is under-diagnosed. At the same time the investigators imagine that DM is closely related to the degree of arterial stiffness, and that these parameters are closely related to a new biochemical marker, fibulin-1. The investigators aim to describe the prevalence of type 2 DM and dysmetabolism in patients admitted to the hospital to undergo cardiovascular surgery and besides that to investigate if there is a connection between the degree of the dysmetabolism and arterial disease, by studying arterial stiffness and by measuring a new biochemical marker, fibulin-1, which the investigators newly have identified. The results of this project will give us a measure for the quantity of unknown DM in patients undergoing cardiovascular surgery and furthermore tell us more in terms of the connections between a newly identified plasma arterial marker, arterial stiffness and diabetes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Associations Between Diabetes, Arterial Stiffness and Fibulin-1 in Patients Undergoing Heart- and Vascular Surgery?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aortic Aneurysm</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arteriosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carotid Stenosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aortic Aneurysm, Abdominal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>&gt;18 years of age undergoing heart or vascular surgery Physical or mental disability not enabling participation in the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
	<keyword>Arteriosclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Intima media thickness</keyword>
	<keyword>arterial stiffness</keyword>
	<keyword>pulsewave velocity</keyword>
	<keyword>fibulin-1</keyword>
</DOC>