<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02294474</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: To demonstrate non-inferiority of SAR342434 versus Humalog in glycated hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) change from baseline to Week 26 in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) also using insulin glargine. Secondary Objectives: To assess the immunogenicity of SAR342434 and Humalog in terms of positive/negative status and antibody titers at baseline and during the course of the study; To assess the relationship of anti-insulin antibodies with efficacy and safety. To assess the efficacy of SAR342434 and Humalog on: proportion of patients reaching target HbA1c &lt;7.0% and ≤6.5%, fasting plasma glucose (FPG) and self-measured plasma glucose (SMPG) profiles, and insulin dose. To assess safety of SAR342434 and Humalog.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of SAR342434 to Humalog as the Rapid Acting Insulin in Adult Patients With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus Also Using Insulin Glargine</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study will consist of a: up to 2 weeks screening period, 26-week treatment period, and 1-day follow-up period. The maximum study duration will then be 28 weeks per patient and a 1-day safety follow-up.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Lispro</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Short-Acting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Glargine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Patients with T2DM diagnosed for at least 12 months and treated with insulin glargine and Humalog®/Liprolog® or NovoLog®/NovoRapid® (at least 3 times daily, before each meal) in the 6 months prior to the screening visit. Signed written informed consent. Exclusion criteria: At screening visit, age under legal age of adulthood. HbA1c &lt;6.5% or &gt;10.0% at screening. Diabetes other than T2DM. Pregnancy and lactation. Women of childbearing potential not protected by highly effective contraceptive method of birth control. Use of insulin pump in the 6 months before screening visit. Use of insulin other than insulin glargine and Humalog or NovoLog/NovoRapid in the 6 months prior to screening visit. Liprolog® is an EU approved insulin lispro and is allowed in those countries where it is marketed. Use of Humalog/Liprolog or Novolog/NovoRapid less than 3 times daily, before each meal. Use of noninjectable peptides (eg, GLP1receptoragonists or other peptides) in the 6 months prior to screening visit. Body mass index (BMI) ≥40kg/m² at screening visit. Hospitalization for diabetic ketoacidosis in the last 6 months before screening visit. Unstable proliferative diabetic retinopathy or any other rapidly progressive diabetic retinopathy or macular edema likely to require treatment (eg, laser, surgical treatment, or injectable drugs) during the study period. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>