<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01432353</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This multicenter, open-label, dose-escalating study will assess the safety and efficacy of DFRF4539A in patients with relapsed or refractory multiple myeloma. Cohorts of patients will receive multiple ascending doses of intravenous DFRF4539A every 3 weeks or weekly. Patients exhibiting acceptable safety and evidence of clinical benefit may receive DFRF4539A for up to 17 cycles. Anticipated time on study treatment is 1 year or until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity occurs.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of DFRF4539A in Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Multiple Myeloma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients; &gt;/= 18 years of age Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0, 1, or 2 Relapsed or refractory multiple myeloma for which no effective standard therapy exists One of the prior therapies must have included a proteosome inhibitor or an immunomodulatory drug Measurable disease as defined by protocol Prior use of monoclonal antibody within 4 weeks before Cycle 1, Day 1 Treatment with radiotherapy, thalidomide, lenalidomide, bortezomib, any chemotherapeutic agent, or treatment with any investigational anticancer agent within 2 weeks prior to Cycle 1, Day 1 Toxicities from any previous treatment must be resolved prior to Cycle 1, Day 1, except for neuropathy Completion of autologous stem cell transplant within 100 days prior to Cycle 1, Day 1 Prior allogeneic stem cell transplant History of severe allergic or anaphylactic reactions to monoclonal antibody therapy (or recombinant antibodyrelated fusion proteins) Grade &gt; 1 peripheral neuropathy Active infection at screening or any major episode of infection requiring treatment with IV antibiotics or hospitalization within 4 weeks prior to Cycle 1, Day 1 Positive for hepatitis B, hepatitis C or HIV infection Pregnant or lactating women or women who intend to become pregnant within the period of time of this study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>