<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01432509</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to identify in prediabetic subjects, physiopathological changes involved in the evolution to type 2 diabetes mellitus and to identify new biomarkers of type 2 diabetes risk in this population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prospective Follow-up of a Cohort of Pre-diabetics in the North of France (DiabeNord)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Type 2 diabetes (T2D) is a real public health issue, with an exponential incidence. Before its diagnosis, several physiopathological changes are already taking place, such as insulin resistance of target tissues and the progressive inability of pancreatic beta cells to produce insulin. The objective of this study is a better understanding of the prediabetic stage and mechanisms involved in the possible development of T2D, by way of a five-year follow-up cohort study in 207 prediabetic subjects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prediabetic State</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Previous history (within 2 months prior to enrollment visit) of fasting blood glucose ≥ 1,10 g/l and &lt; 1,26 g/l OR fasting blood glucose ≥ 1 g/l and &lt; 1,10 g/l with HbA1c ≥ 6,5%. Fasting glycemia ≥ 1.26 g/l History of treatment with oral antidiabetics History of treatment with insulin, except gestational diabetes Subject with any history or presence of significant hematologic (coagulation, thrombopenia, …), hepatic, renal, or psychiatric disorders Subject unable to follow the study during the 5 years of followup Subject in exclusion period of a previous study or simultaneously participating to any other clinical trial on metabolism</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pre-diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Type 2 diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
	<keyword>Cohort</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes Risk Score</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucose Intolerance</keyword>
	<keyword>Prediabetic State</keyword>
	<keyword>Glucose Metabolism Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Metabolic Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Endocrine System Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperglycemia</keyword>
</DOC>