<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01432639</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main purposes of this study is to analyze, in a randomized controlled trial, the effects of an exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation program (i) on biomarkers of endothelial function, (ii) on biomarkers of inflammation, (iii) on autonomic function, and (iv) on arterial stiffness in coronary artery disease patients (CAD). Additionally, the investigators aim to analyze the (v) contribution of age and the changes in traditional risk factors to the modification of the endothelial dysfunction and inflammation, and (vi) the contribution of the changes in inflammatory and endothelial function biomarkers to the modification of autonomic function and arterial stiffness. The investigators hypothesize that exercise training will improve the autonomic function, arterial stiffness and mitigate the endothelial dysfunction and inflammation in CAD patients even in the absence of significant changes in traditional risk factors. Thus, the investigators expect with the present study to promote, develop and expand the knowledge in this field by assessing the impact of exercise on a pool of markers that provide a wide picture of the pathophysiological processes underlying CAD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Exercise Training on Endothelial Function, Inflammation, Arterial Stiffness and Autonomic Function in CAD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arteritis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>acute myocardial infarction ventricular tachyarrhythmia uncontrolled hypertension (systolic blood pressure &gt;180 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;100 mmHg) significant valvular disease unstable angina pectoris reduced left ventricular function (ejection fraction &lt; 45%) abnormal hemodynamic response myocardial ischemia and/or severe ventricular arrhythmias during baseline exercise testing uncontrolled metabolic disease (e.g. uncontrolled diabetes or thyroid disease) presence of pulmonary and renal comorbidities peripheral artery disease and/or orthopedic limitations</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Myocardial infarction</keyword>
	<keyword>Autonomic function</keyword>
	<keyword>Arterial Stiffness</keyword>
	<keyword>Endothelial function</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehabilitation program</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
</DOC>