<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00942747</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open-label trial investigating the efficacy of temsirolimus in recurrent or refractory primary CNS lymphoma (PCNSL) after initial chemotherapy with a high-dose methotrexate containing regimen. 37 patients are planned to be treated with weekly infusions of 25mg Temsirolimus (first 3 patients) or 75mg Temsirolimus (all other patients) up to a maximum of 12 months. The trial is designed in two stages, if less than one of the first 12 patients responds to treatment, the trial is stopped. In addition to efficacy, safety and penetration of temsirolimus into the cerebrospinal fluid will be investigated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Temsirolimus in Recurrent Primary Central Nervous System (CNS) Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Primary CNS lymphoma diagnosed histologically or by cerebrospinal fluid cytology; absence of systemic lymphoma manifestations Relapse or lymphoma progression after/during highdose methotrexate containing firstline chemotherapy or alternative therapy in the case of contraindications against highdose methotrexate ECOG performance score ≤ 2 Age ≥18 years and ≤ 75 years Life expectancy of at least 3 months Absence of active infection Negative HIV serology Adequate renal function (GFR &gt;30ml/h) Adequate bone marrow reserve (neutrophils &gt; 1500/µl, platelets &gt; 80,000/µl) Bilirubin &lt;1.5x upper limit of normal (ULN), ALT and AST &lt;3x ULN At least 3 weeks interval from prior cytostatic treatment Negative pregnancy test Patient accessible for treatment and followup Patient compliance Signed informed consent Secondary CNS lymphoma Primary intraocular lymphoma Patient eligible for highdose chemotherapy and autologous stemcell transplantation Concurrent treatment within another clinical trial Concurrent other malignant disease Symptomatic congestive heart failure (≥NYHA II) Active or uncontrolled chronic infection Severe concomitant disease incompatible with study conduct History of cerebral bleeding Concomitant treatment with strong CYP3A4/5inductors or inhibitors Premenopausal women without highly effective contraception (defined as Pearl index &lt;1) Pregnant or lactating women Refusal to record and pass on pseudonymized disease and treatment related data as part of the treatment protocol Concurrent admission to a psychiatric institution by public order</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>temsirolimus, primary CNS lymphoma, PCNSL, salvage treatment</keyword>
</DOC>