<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT03060993</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>A grow body physiological evidence exist support potential role inhale cannabis medical management adult chronic obstructive pulmonary disease ( COPD ) , particularly may relate improve pulmonary function , alleviate symptom breathlessness improve exercise endurance . The purpose randomized double-blind crossover trial evaluate efficacy physiological mechanism ( ) action inhale vaporized cannabis target relief physical activity-related breathlessness exercise endurance symptomatic patient severe-to-very severe COPD .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CAN BREATHE COPD Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases , Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease , Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyspnea</mesh_term>
	<criteria>GOLD stage III IV COPD ( i.e. , postβ2agonist FEV1 50 % predict less ) Selfreported cigarette smoke history ≥10 pack yr Currently take longacting beta2 agonist longacting antimuscarinic agent ( LABA/LAMAs ) without inhale corticosteroid Willing abstain cannabis smoke ≥15 day prior study participation ( applicable ) Willing abstain nonstudy related cannabis smoking throughout study period ( applicable ) No change medication dosage frequency administration , exacerbation hospitalization precede 4 week Presence active and/or uncontrolled cardiopulmonary and/or musculoskeletal disease COPD could contribute breathlessness exercise intolerance Hepatic renal impairment Psychiatric history ( depression and/or anxiety ) History epilepsy convulsion ; Lung cancer History sensitivity cannabis Use levodopa , sildenafil and/or fentanyl Use ketoconazole Use regular high dose opioids ( i.e. , 30 mg oral morphine equivalents/day ) Known suspect history addiction/substance abuse base CAGEAID SISAP score ( *note , patient may recruit history smoke cannabis ) Positive urine toxicology cannabinoids screen Positive pregnancy urine test Subject arrange accompany home family member and/or friend treatment visit .</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cannabis</keyword>
	<keyword>Marijuana</keyword>
</DOC>