<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00600405</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the efficacy of the α-adrenergic antagonist tamsulosin in the treatment of adult emergency department (ED) patients with ureteral colic secondary to lower ureteral calculus. We hypothesize that there will be no difference in outcomes for subjects treated with and without tamsulosin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Efficacy of Tamsulosin in the Treatment of Ureteral Stones in Emergency Department Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This prospective, randomized controlled trial seeks to compare outcomes for adult emergency department patients with lower ureteral calculus. Subjects will be randomized to receive treatment with ibuprofen and oxycodone alone (standard therapy) or standard therapy plus tamsulosin 0.4mg orally once daily for ten days.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calculi</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nephrolithiasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Calculi</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ureteral Calculi</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ureterolithiasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tamsulosin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxycodone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ibuprofen</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 years of age or older; able to read, write, and speak English; able to use the NRS pain scale; and computed tomography diagnosed single lower ureteral calculus allergy or sensitivity to the study drug (tamsulosin hydrochloride [Flomax]); sulfa/sulfonamide allergy; inability to provide informed consent; lithiasis of the ureteral intramural tract; acute or chronic renal failure; fever; presence of multiple ureteral stones; peptic ulcer disease; liver failure; concomitant treatment with alphalytic drugs, calcium antagonists, nitrates, or vardenafil (Levitra); pregnancy; breastfeeding; or a history of urinary surgery or endoscopic treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Nephrolithiasis</keyword>
	<keyword>Ureteral Calculi</keyword>
</DOC>