<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02197650</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Early Access Program to provide L-asparaginase encapsulated in Erythrocyte (GRASPA®) for patient unable to receive any other form of Asparaginase.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Expanded Access Program: Safety of Erythrocytes Encapsulating L-asparaginase (GRASPA®) in Combination With Polychemotherapy in Patients Under 55 Years Old With Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia (ALL) at Risk to Receive Other Formulation of Asparaginase</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Some patients can not be eligible to other clinical trials / program sponsored by Erytech Pharma but could have a benefit to be treated with GRASPA. Following discussion with French regulatory authorities, it has been suggested to propose access to GRASPA to patients unable to receive any other form of L-asparaginase and not eligible to the ongoing study or other program. This exploratory study should allow it in an "Expended Access Program" framework.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Asparaginase</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with ALL de novo or in relapse or refractory Eligible to a chemotherapy treatment including Lasparaginase Known contraindication and/or at risk of toxicity to other Lasparaginase formulation according to investigator opinion based on information available Patient under 55 years old Patient informed and consent provided (the 2 parents need to consent for children). Patient unable to receive GRASPA due to general or visceral conditions Absence of documented serological test for HIV, B and C hepatitis History of grade 3 transfusional incident or any contraindication to receive blood transfusion Patient under concomitant treatment likely to cause hemolysis Presence of specific antierythrocyte antibodies preventing from getting a compatible erythrocyte concentrate for the patient. Patient undergoing yellow fever vaccination. Patient under phenytoin treatment. Women of childbearing potential without effective contraception as well as pregnant or breast feeding women. Patient already included in another clinical trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>ALL l-asparaginase encapsulated erythrocytes</keyword>
</DOC>