<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02197572</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to characterize the effect of a single dose of 40 mg MLN0128 on the electrocardiographic QT/QTc interval in participants with advanced solid tumors.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of MLN0128 on the QTc Interval in Participants With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The drug being tested in this study is called MLN0128. MLN0128 is being tested to determine the effect of a single 40 mg dose on the electrocardiographic measure of the time between the start of the Q wave and the end of the T wave in the electrical cycle of the heart (QT)/rate corrected QT (QTc) interval in patients with advanced solid tumors. This study will look at electrocardiogram (ECG) results before and after a single dose of MLN0128. The study will enroll approximately 30 patients. All participants will receive a single 40 mg dose of MLN0128 capsules on Day 1. To avoid nausea and vomiting, participants will also be administered 0.25 mg palonosetron on Day 1 as an antiemetic agent. Participants may continue to receive MLN0128 for up to 1 year at a dose of up to 30 mg once weekly if a clinical benefit is being derived. This multi-centre trial will be conducted in the United States. The overall time to participate in this study is up to 14 months. Participants will make 6 visits to the clinic including and end of study visit 30 to 40 days after last dose of study drug for a follow-up assessment. Participants that continue treatment with MLN0128 will continue to make additional visits to the clinic once or twice every 4 weeks and the end of study visit 30 to 40 days after last dose of study drug for a follow-up assessment.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria 1. Men or women participants 18 years or older. 2. Must have a radiographically or clinically evaluable solid tumor Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1. 3. Female participants who: Are postmenopausal for at least 1 year before the screening visit, OR Are surgically sterile, OR If they are of childbearing potential, agree to practice 2 effective methods of contraception, at the same time, from the time of signing the informed consent through 3 months after the last dose of study drug, OR Agree to practice true abstinence, when this is in line with the preferred and usual lifestyle of the participant. (Periodic abstinence (eg, calendar, ovulation, symptothermal, postovulation methods] and withdrawal are not acceptable methods of contraception.) 4. Male participants, even if surgically sterilized (ie, status postvasectomy), who: Agree to practice effective barrier contraception during the entire study treatment period and through 3 months after the last dose of study drug, or Agree to practice true abstinence, when this is in line with the preferred and usual lifestyle of the participant. (Periodic abstinence [eg, calendar, ovulation, symptothermal, postovulation methods for the female partner] and withdrawal are not acceptable methods of contraception.) 5. Voluntary written consent must be given before performance of any studyrelated procedure not part of standard medical care, with the understanding that consent may be withdrawn by the participant at any time without prejudice to future medical care. 6. Ability to swallow oral medications, willingness to perform mucositis prophylaxis, and suitable venous access for the studyrequired blood sampling. Exclusion Criteria 1. Female participants who are lactating and breastfeeding or have a positive serum pregnancy test during the screening period. 2. Any serious medical or psychiatric illness that could, in the investigator's opinion, potentially interfere with the completion of treatment according to this protocol. 3. Treatment with any investigational products within 14 days before the first dose of study drug and systemic anticancer therapy within 28 days before the first dose of study drug. 4. Untreated brain metastasis or history of leptomeningeal disease or spinal cord compression. 5. Tumors with involvement of the mediastinum. 6. Failure to recover from the reversible effects of prior anticancer therapies with the exception of alopecia, and aftereffects associated with prior tyrosine kinase inhibitor therapy such as hair depigmentation, hypothyroidism, and/or splinter hemorrhage. 7. Systemic corticosteroid (inhalers are allowed) within 7 days before the first dose of study drug. 8. Manifestations of malabsorption due to prior gastrointestinal (GI) surgery, GI disease, or for an unknown or other reason that may alter the absorption of MLN0128. 9. Diagnosis of diabetes mellitus; participants with a history of transient glucose intolerance due to corticosteroid administration may be enrolled if all other inclusion/exclusion criteria are met. 10. Significant active cardiovascular or pulmonary disease at study entry ◦ History of arrhythmia requiring an implantable cardiac defibrillator 11. Clinically significant comorbidities such as uncontrolled pulmonary disease, active central nervous system disease, active infection, serious infection within 14 days before the first dose of study drug, or any other condition that could compromise study participation by the participant.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug therapy</keyword>
</DOC>