<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02293902</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: To demonstrate that sarilumab added to MTX reduce signs and symptoms of rheumatoid arthritis (RA) in Japanese RA patients with an inadequate response to MTX. Secondary Objective: To assess the safety of sarilumab added to MTX in Japanese RA patients with an inadequate response to MTX.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Assessing the Efficacy and Safety of Sarilumab Added to MTX in Japanese Patients With Moderately to Severely Active Rheumatoid Arthritis (SARIL-RA-KAKEHASI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The total duration of study is expected up to 62 weeks (screening period of 4 weeks, treatment period of 52 weeks, and a 6 week post treatment observation).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin B Complex</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Diagnosis of RA, according to the American College of Rheumatology/The European League Against Rheumatism (ACR/EULAR) 2010 Rheumatoid Arthritis Classification Criteria with ≥3 months disease duration. Moderately to severely active RA defined as: At least 8 of 68 tender joints and 6 of 66 swollen joints at screening visit. High sensitivity CReactive Protein (hsCRP) ≥6mg/L at screening visit. Exclusion criteria: Patients &lt;20 or &gt;75 years of age. Treatment with any Diseasemodifying antirheumatic drug (DMARD) other than MTX or biologic agent without the appropriate offdrug period prior to to screening. Prior treatment with antiinterleukin6 (antiIL6) or antiinterleukin6 receptor (IL6R) antagonist therapies, including but not limited to tocilizumab or sarilumab. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>