<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01439750</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase I/II trial of bortezomib, cladribine, and rituximab in newly diagnosed and relapsed mantle cell lymphoma (MCL). The phase I component has three dose levels of cladribine (3 mg/m2, 4 mg/m2, and 5 mg/m2) and is designed as a traditional dose-escalation study in which cohorts of 3 patients are evaluated for the incidence of dose-liming toxicity (DLT) at each dose level. Once the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is determined, a phase II component with 2 arms will begin. One arm will enroll newly diagnosed MCL patients and one arm will enroll relapsed MCL patients. Each arm is a single-stage, fixed sample size study and will be accrued and analyzed separately. The phase I and II data will also be analyzed separately.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bortezomib (VELCADE), Cladribine and Rituximab (VCR) in Mantle Cell Lymphoma (PSHCI 10-011)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The phase I portion of the study is a standard dose-escalation schemed designed to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of the combination of bortezomib, cladribine, and rituximab therapy. The MTD is defined as the dose level in which ≤1 out of 6 patients have dose-limiting toxicity (DLT). Three patients are enrolled on a dose level. If 0 out of 3 patients have DLT, then the next set of 3 patients are enrolled at the next highest dose level. If ≥2 out of 3 patients have DLT, then the MTD will have been exceeded and dose escalation will cease. Three additional patients will be enrolled at the next lowest dose level if only 3 were treated previously at that level. If 1 out of 3 patients have DLT, then the next set of 3 patients will be treated at the same dose level. If ≤1 out of 6 patients treated at that dose level have DLT, then the next set of patients will be treated at the next higher dose level. If ≥2 out of 6 patients treated at that dose level have DLT, then the MTD will have been exceeded and dose escalation will cease. Three additional patients will be treated at the next lowest dose level if only 3 were treated previously at that level. This phase I study will use 3 dose levels of cladribine (3 mg/m2, 4 mg/m2, and 5 mg/m2), with 3 mg/m2 being the starting dose level. DLTs will be assessed at the completion of the first 2 cycles of cladribine and rituximab. Phase II Design: The phase II portion of the study is a two-arm, single-stage design with no interim analysis. One arm will accrue newly diagnosed patients, and one arm will accrue relapsed patients. In each arm, the progression-free survival rate at 2 years will be used as the primary endpoint for determining whether the treatment is sufficiently active in each arm. No comparisons will be made between the arms.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Mantle-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cladribine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Females that are postmenopausal for at least 1 year before the screening visit, surgically sterilized or if they are of childbearing potential agree to practice 2 effective methods of contraception from the time of signing the informed consent form through 30 days after the last dose. Male subjects must agree to practice effective barrier contraception during the entire study treatment period and through a minimum of 30 days after the last dose of study drug, or completely abstain from heterosexual intercourse. Patients with newly diagnosed and relapsed mantle cell lymphoma. ECOG performance status grade 3 or higher. Patient has a platelet count of &lt;50x10 9/L within 14 days before enrollment if not related to disease. Patient has an absolute neutrophil count less than 100 within 14 days before enrollment if not related to disease. Patient has a calculated or measured creatinine clearance of &lt;20 mL/minute within 14 days before enrollment. Patient has &gt; Grade 2 peripheral neuropathy within 14 days before enrollment. Patient has &gt; 1.5 x ULN total bilirubin. Myocardial infarction within 6 months prior to enrollment or has New York Heart Association Class II or IV heart failure, uncontrolled angina, severe uncontrolled ventricular arrhythmias, or electrocardiographic evidence of acute ischemia or active conduction system abnormalities. Patient has hypersensitivity to bortezomib, boron or mannitol. Female subject is pregnant or breastfeeding. Patient has received other investigational drugs within 14 days before enrollment. Serious medical or psychiatric illness likely to interfere with participation in this clinical study. Diagnosed or treated for another malignancy within 3 years of enrollment, with the exception of complete resection of basal cell carcinoma or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, an in situ malignancy, or lowrisk prostate cancer after curative therapy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>mantle cell lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>lymphoma</keyword>
</DOC>