<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01439152</DOC>
	<brief_summary>BAY94-9343 is an antibody-drug conjugate (ADC) directed against the cancer antigen mesothelin on tumor cells. This study will attempt to answer the following questions: - What are the side effects of BAY94-9343 when given at different dose levels and schedules? - What dose level and schedule of BAY94-9343 should be tested in future clinical research studies? - How much BAY94-9343 is in the blood at specific times after administration? - Does the treatment with BAY94-9343 show any effect on the tumor growth? - Are there specific biomarkers that might be able to explain why some patients respond to treatment and others do not?</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase I Study to Determine the Maximum Tolerable Dose of BAY94-9343 in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Maytansine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoconjugates</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All subjects must be ≥ 18 years at the first screening examination / visit Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 to 1 Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks Histologically or cytologically documented invasive epithelial ovarian, primary peritoneal, or fallopian tube cancer (tumors with pseudomyxomatous or mucinous histology are excluded) or advanced predominantly epithelioid peritoneal mesothelioma. Ovarian cancer must have relapsed &gt;0 months and ≤ 12 months of the prior platinumbased chemotherapy regimen (platinum resistant and partially platinum sensitive). All patients must provide the tumor tissue sample [Formalin Fixed Paraffin Embedded (FFPE) slides] from archival tissue or fresh biopsy collected any time before the general screening under the separate informed consent. Mesothelin expression in the tumor tissue from archival or fresh biopsy samples defined as the membrane intensity score of 2+ or 3+ (on the 03 scale) expressed on at least 30% of tumor cells. Mesothelin expression must be determined by the validated Investigational Use Only (IUO) assay for ovarian cancer or the prototype immunohistochemistry (IHC) assay for mesothelioma at Ventana at any time before the general screening in patients who had signed a separate informed consent for tumor tissue analysis for mesothelin expression. No more than 3 prior lines of systemic cytotoxic therapy for patients with advanced peritoneal or pleural mesothelioma No more than 5 prior lines of systemic cytotoxic therapy for patients with ovarian cancer Possible intraperitoneal administration of cytotoxics during surgery will not count as systemic cytotoxic therapy in either case. Measurable disease with at least one lesion that can be accurately measured in at least one dimension according to Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1. exclusion Criteria: More than 3 prior lines of systemic cytotoxic therapy for patients with advanced peritoneal or pleural mesothelioma More than 5 prior lines of systemic cytotoxic therapy for patients with ovarian cancer Other systemic anticancer therapies (moleculartargeted, immunotherapy etc.) may be acceptable after the consultation between the Investigator and the Bayer Medical Expert. Intraperitoneal administration of cytotoxic anticancer agents during tumor surgery will not count as systemic cytotoxic therapy in this context. Prior local radiotherapy is allowed if it is completed at least 4 weeks prior to the first dose of study drug and the subject has evaluable lesions not previously irradiated. Anticancer chemotherapy, experimental cancer therapy, or immunotherapy within 2 weeks of start of first dose. Anticancer therapy is defined as any agent or combination of agents with clinically proven anti tumor activity administered by any route with the purpose of affecting the malignancy, either directly or indirectly, including palliative and therapeutic endpoints. Radiotherapy to the target lesions within 4 weeks prior to the first BAY949343 infusion, if the subject has evaluable tumor lesions not previously irradiated. Use of strong inhibitors of Pglycoprotein (transporter) (Pgp) (e.g., ritonavir, cyclosporine, verapamil, and dronedarone) is prohibited from Day 14 and for the duration of the study. Impaired cardiac function or clinically significant cardiac disease [i.e., congestive heart failure (CHF) New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class III or IV]. Left ventriculat ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt;50 % [as measured at screening by Multiple Gated Acquisition scan (MUGA) or echocardiogram]. Uncontrolled hypertension defined as systolic blood pressure &gt; 150 mm Hg and/or diastolic blood pressure &gt; 90 mmHg, despite optimal medical management. Mild blurry vision, either agerelated or due to ocular or systemic disorder (e.g. diabetes, dry eyes, cataracts, uncorrected refraction abnormality) may be allowed at the discretion of the ophthalmologist if deemed as no constituting a predisposition to druginduced corneal deposits and blurry vision.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Oncology</keyword>
	<keyword>solid tumors</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibody drug conjugate</keyword>
	<keyword>Maximum tolerable dose</keyword>
	<keyword>mesothelin</keyword>
</DOC>