<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="193533">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00572624</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>488</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>P01HL013851-43</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>IRB# 03-0395</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>RDRC# 498F</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>GCRC# 915</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>22 3272 52136</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00572624</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Abdominal Obesity on Heart Metabolism and Function</brief_title>
  <official_title>Altered Myocardial Fatty Acid Metabolism In Obesity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Washington University School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Washington University School of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Obesity is one of the most widespread health problems of today, with more than 61 million
      adult Americans considered obese. Abdominal obesity (AO), in particular, is associated with
      an increased chance of cardiac diseases, such as coronary artery disease, and related risk
      factors, such as high blood pressure and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). Despite the known
      association between AO and cardiac disease, the mechanisms responsible for this relationship
      are still not well understood. Recent obesity studies have indicated that increased delivery
      of fats to the heart may play a role in heart function impairments. This study will evaluate
      the impact of AO on the human heart's use of fats for energy and on heart function.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Obesity is defined as having a high amount of excess body fat. Millions of people worldwide
      meet the criteria for obesity, making it one of the most pressing current health issues. The
      more body fat a person has, the more susceptible that person is to a number of life
      threatening diseases, including heart disease, type 2 diabetes, gallstones, certain cancers,
      and high blood pressure. A variety of factors can lead to obesity. These factors include
      family history and genetics, physical inactivity, metabolism, hormone imbalance, and
      environment. Past research suggests that an increased availability of fats in the body leads
      to increased fat uptake by the heart. The heart only needs a certain amount of fat for
      energy, which leaves the remaining fat in the heart tissue, possibly impairing proper heart
      function. However, more information on the mechanisms behind the effects of fats on heart
      metabolism is needed. This study will evaluate the impact of AO on the human heart's use of
      fats for energy and on heart function.

      This study will enroll both overweight and lean participants who will attend 4 to 7 study
      visits. Visit 1 will consist of various screening tests, including a medical history,
      physical exam, pregnancy test if applicable, routine blood test, and an echocardiogram
      (ECHO) performed before and during exercise.

      Visit 2 will consist of an abdominal fat and insulin sensitivity study. This will entail a
      magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) test to image the heart and stomach, a dual energy x-ray
      absorptiometry (DEXA) scan to measure total body fat and muscle content, and an insulin
      sensitivity test to measure how well the hormone insulin controls blood sugar. The latter
      test will require multiple blood draws over a 3-hour period.

      Visits 3 and 4 will occur over a 2-week period. Both visits will consist of an overnight
      stay at the General Clinical Research Center (GCRC) followed by a day of imaging studies.
      During Visit 3, participants will first undergo a 4-hour whole body metabolism study, which
      will include injection of a nonradioactive tracer through previously placed IVs, blood
      draws, and breathing into a machine for approximately 15 minutes. Participants will then
      undergo a positron emission tomographic (PET) heart metabolism study, which will also
      involve tracer injections and blood draws. A resting ECHO test will also be done during the
      PET study. Participants will be asked for permission to store a sample of their blood for a
      period of up to 10 years to be used in future research studies on the heart. During Visit 4,
      participants will undergo repeat tests from the third visit, except the PET study will
      evaluate the heart's ability to use sugars instead of fats. This will complete the study
      visits for all lean participants and some overweight participants and will entail 4 weeks of
      participation.

      Overweight participants may be asked to attend an additional three study visits during an
      8-month weight management program at Washington University School of Medicine. Participants
      will aim to lose 10% of their body weight over a 6-month period and to maintain that weight
      loss for another 1- to 2-month stabilization period. At the end of the stabilization period,
      participants will undergo repeat abdominal fat and insulin sensitivity studies during Visit
      5, repeat whole body metabolism and heart metabolism studies during Visit 6, and repeat
      whole body metabolism and glucose heart metabolism studies during Visit 7.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>June 2003</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Association between AO-related changes in myocardial fatty acid metabolism and abnormalities in left ventricular systolic and diastolic function</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Year 5</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of significant weight loss (10% of body weight) on myocardial fatty acid and glucose metabolism in relation to whole-body fatty acid and glucose kinetics</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Year 5</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Effects of changes in myocardial substrate metabolism that occur with weight loss on left ventricular systolic and diastolic function</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Year 5</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Alterations in the response of myocardial fatty acid and glucose metabolism to increased insulin availability and how the potential alterations relate to whole-body fatty acid and glucose kinetics</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Year 5</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of increased delivery of fatty acids on myocardial fatty acid and glucose metabolism in relation to whole body fatty acid and glucose kinetics</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Year 5</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Association between the myocardial metabolic response and changes in left ventricular systolic and diastolic function</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Year 5</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">136</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants characterized as overweight</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants characterized as lean</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Weight Loss Management Program</intervention_name>
    <description>Selected overweight participants will set a goal of 10% body weight loss over a 6-month period, followed by a 1- to 2-month weight loss stabilization period. After the stabilization period, participants will undergo repeat abdominal fat and insulin sensitivity studies and imaging tests.</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      1 tablespoon of blood with DNA
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population will include both overweight and lean subjects.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Class II abdominal obesity body mass index (BMI) between 35 kg/m2 and 39.9 kg/m2;
             waist circumference of greater than 90 cm in women and greater than 105 cm in men

          -  Diagnosis of type 2 diabetes

          -  Sedentary lifestyle

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  History of cardiovascular disease

          -  Regular exerciser

          -  Occupy a strenuously active job

          -  No evidence of inducible myocardial ischemia on resting/stress ECHO

          -  No risk factors of coronary artery disease, heart valve disease, or left ventricular
             dysfunction

          -  Left ventricular hypertrophy (based on measure in left ventricular mass index)

          -  No evidence of coronary artery disease based on clinical parameters or on rest/stress
             ECHO
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert Gropler, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Washington University Medical School</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Debi Delano, MSN</last_name>
    <phone>314-747-3876</phone>
    <email>delanod@mir.wustl.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kitty Krupp, RN</last_name>
    <phone>314-747-0183</phone>
    <email>kruppk@mir.wustl.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University Medical School</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Robert Gropler, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Linda Peterson, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Samuel Klein, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Pilar Herrero, MS</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Victor Davila, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Allison DB, Fontaine KR, Manson JE, Stevens J, VanItallie TB. Annual deaths attributable to obesity in the United States. JAMA. 1999 Oct 27;282(16):1530-8.</citation>
    <PMID>10546692</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hu FB, Stampfer MJ, Manson JE, Grodstein F, Colditz GA, Speizer FE, Willett WC. Trends in the incidence of coronary heart disease and changes in diet and lifestyle in women. N Engl J Med. 2000 Aug 24;343(8):530-7.</citation>
    <PMID>10954760</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Folsom AR, Prineas RJ, Kaye SA, Munger RG. Incidence of hypertension and stroke in relation to body fat distribution and other risk factors in older women. Stroke. 1990 May;21(5):701-6.</citation>
    <PMID>2339449</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carey VJ, Walters EE, Colditz GA, Solomon CG, Willett WC, Rosner BA, Speizer FE, Manson JE. Body fat distribution and risk of non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus in women. The Nurses' Health Study. Am J Epidemiol. 1997 Apr 1;145(7):614-9.</citation>
    <PMID>9098178</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2011</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 11, 2011</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 12, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Robert Gropler, MD</name_title>
    <organization>Washington University Medical School</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Abdominal Obesity</keyword>
  <keyword>Heart Metabolism</keyword>
  <keyword>Type II Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
  <keyword>PET</keyword>
  <keyword>Fatty Acid</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Obesity, Abdominal</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
