<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01203826</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical trial studies the long term safety and efficacy of asfotase alfa in children with HPP who completed the ENB-006-09 study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Extension Study of Protocol ENB-006-09 - Study of Asfotase Alfa in Children With Hypophosphatasia (HPP)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Asfotase alfa was formerly referred to as ENB-0040 Hypophosphatasia (HPP) is a life-threatening, genetic, and ultra-rare metabolic disease characterized by defective bone mineralization and impaired phosphate and calcium regulation that can lead to progressive damage to multiple vital organs, including destruction and deformity of bones, profound muscle weakness, seizures, impaired renal function, and respiratory failure. There are no approved disease-modifying treatments for patients with this disease. There is also limited data available on the natural course of this disease over time, particularly in patients with the juvenile-onset form.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypophosphatasia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Compliant and satisfactory completion of Enobiasponsored clinical trial ENB00609 Written informed consent by parent or other legal guardian prior to any study procedures being performed Parent or other legal guardian willing to comply with study requirements Clinically significant disease that precludes study participation, in the Investigator's opinion Treatment with an investigational drug other than Asfotase Alfa Enrollment in any study involving an investigational drug, device, or treatment for HPP</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>13 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Hypophosphatasia</keyword>
	<keyword>HPP</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Soft Bones</keyword>
	<keyword>Low Alkaline Phosphatase</keyword>
	<keyword>genetic metabolic disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>alkaline phosphatase</keyword>
	<keyword>tissue non-specific alkaline phosphatase</keyword>
	<keyword>rickets</keyword>
	<keyword>osteomalacia</keyword>
</DOC>