<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01968850</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a two-site, three-arm, open-label, pilot randomized controlled trial of bone anti-resorptive therapy during ART initiation in HIV-infected adults. Thirty (30) treatment-naïve HIV-infected adults initiating eligible first-line ART regimens will be randomized in a 1:1:1 fashion to one of the following three arms: 1. no bone anti-resorptive therapy (standard of care) 2. concomitant initiation of a 24 week course of co-formulated alendronate/vitamin D; 3. a 24 week delay in initiation of a 24 week course of alendronate/vitamin D Assessments (including clinical evaluation, questionnaires, adherence, basic laboratory evaluation, and BMD measurement) will be performed at baseline, 24 and 48 weeks. The primary objective will involve calculation of σ and ρ using all data; δ will be estimated by comparing the two alendronate arms pooled to the no-treatment arm.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bone Antiresorptive Therapy With Antiretroviral Initiation (BATARI) Pilot Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Alendronate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Documented HIV1 infection Adult (aged &gt;18 years or as per local guidelines) Premenopausal, if female Antiretroviralnaïve Starting firstline ART including tenofovir/emtricitabine with either efavirenz (coformulated as Atripla®) or elvitegravir, cobicistat (coformulated as Stribild®) Low (&lt;10%) tenyear fracture risk as assessed by the FRAX score validated for Canadian populations Presence of established osteoporosis at baseline as determined by BMD measurement Prior or current use of any bone antiresorptive therapy (eg. bisphosphonate, estrogens with the exception of oral contraceptive pills, etc.) Inability to communicate in English Creatinine clearance &lt;35 mL/min (using CockcroftGault formula) Hypersensitivity to alendronate, other bisphosphonates, or any component of the formulation Hypocalcemia Abnormalities of the esophagus which delay esophageal emptying such as stricture or achalasia Inability to stand or sit upright for at least 30 minutes Pregnancy, active plans to become pregnant, or lactation</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>osteoporosis</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>bone Mineral Density</keyword>
	<keyword>alendronate</keyword>
	<keyword>vitamin D</keyword>
</DOC>