<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03048695</DOC>
	<brief_summary>About 85% of patients with schizophrenia have cognitive impairments, executive functions being particularly affected. Executive dysfunction, and cognitive deficits in general, are important predictors of functional outcomes, including social problem solving, activities of daily living, life satisfaction, and the ability to return to work or school.The main objective of the current study is to examine the efficacy of group-based Goal Management Training (GMT) for patients with broad schizophrenia spectrum disorders or high risk individuals with executive deficits. The short term goals are to investigate whether GMT can improve participants' ability to organize and achieve goals in everyday life in addition to improving aspects of emotional health. A long-term goal would be to establish an evidence base for nonpharmacological interventions for patients with broad schizophrenia spectrum disorders or high risk for schizophrenia. Main research questions: (1) Does a RCT with GMT delivered to patients with broad schizophrenia spectrum disorders or high risk for schizophrenia result in improved executive functioning, measured by self-reported and/or objective measures of executive functions? (2) Does GMT result in improved goal attainment in everyday life, social- and real world functioning? (3) Does GMT have a positive impact on the patients' emotional health? (4) Are there specific characteristics in patients with broad schizophrenia spectrum disorders or high risk for schizophrenia that are associated with better treatment benefit from GMT?</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Goal Management Training for Patients With Schizophrenia or High Risk for Schizophrenia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neurocognitive Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Being consecutively referred to treatment for a DSMIV diagnosis of broad schizophrenia spectrum psychosis (schizophrenia, schizophreniform disorder and schizoaffective disorder) or high risk for psychosis or being treated for psychotic disorder for less than 5 years. Reporting executive problems through (a) structured interview, or (b) selfreport, i.e. BRIEF scale Tscore &lt; 55. Reported ongoing alcohol or substance abuse. Premorbid neurological disease or insult and/or comorbid neurological disease. ° Severe cognitive problems interfering with the capacity to participate. IQ below 70.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>67 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>