<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03048578</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial of liraglutide versus placebo over a follow-up period of 12 months in patients at least 18 months following Roux-en-Y gastric bypass (RYGB) who are experiencing weight regain. This study will assess the efficacy of liraglutide in improving cardiometabolic risk profile (as indicated by serum lipids, HbA1c, and waist circumference) and quality of life (as assessed by PHQ-9 (Patient Health Questionnaire), versus placebo in patients at least 18 months following RYGB who are experiencing weight regain as well as the safety of liraglutide in this patient population.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clinical Efficacy and Safety of Using 3.0mg Liraglutide to Treat Weight Regain After Roux-en-Y Gastric Bypass Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The specific aims of this study are to: - To evaluate the effects of liraglutide on body weight loss in patients who are experiencing weight regain following RYGB. - To evaluate the effects of liraglutide on cardiometabolic risk and quality of life in patients who are experiencing weight regain following RYGB. - To evaluate the safety of liraglutide in post-RYGB subjects. - To evaluate the changes in obesity-related comorbid conditions in patients who are experiencing weight regain following RYGB.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>≥18 months statuspost RYGB BMI 27 kg/m2 or greater in the presence of at least one weightrelated comorbid condition BMI 30 kg/m2 or greater Regain of ≥10% of maximum TBWL postRYGB Ability to provide informed consent before any trialrelated activities Express willingness to follow protocol requirements Pregnancy at time of enrollment Intention of becoming pregnant or breast feeding in the next 12 months Females of childbearing potential who are not using adequate contraceptive methods Presence of acute psychiatric problems or immaturity which would compromise cooperation with the study protocol Presence of biliary disease Known or suspected allergy to liraglutide or any product components Personal or family history of medullary thyroid carcinoma or multiple endocrine neoplasia syndrome type 2 History of pancreatitis History of alcoholism History of Type 1 DM (Diabetes Mellitus) History of previous bariatric surgery other than RYGB except h/o LAGB and band removal. &gt;10 years statuspost RYGB &lt; 25% TBWL at postRYGB weight nadir &gt;50% postoperative TBWL at time of screening Simultaneous use of any weight loss medications Use of insulin at the time of enrollment Current use of any GLP1 agonist medication History of taking any GLP1 agonist medication Participation in another ongoing clinical study Conditions that, in the opinion of the principal investigator, may jeopardize the patient's wellbeing and/or the soundness of this clinical study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Roux-en-Y gastric bypass (RYGB)</keyword>
</DOC>