<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02844842</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an observational prospective study to assess the tolerability and safety of treatment of SCIT Allergovac Poliplus polymerized in depot presentation. The study drug will be administered either by a 1 day Schedule or by a rapid Schedule (3 increasing weekly doses at initiation period till maintenance dose is reached) The study population is both: adult and child, polysensitized to at least 2 allergen sources with rhinitis or allergic rhinoconjunctivitis. Patients may also present a concomitant mild or moderate asthma. The assignment of a patient to a particular therapeutic strategy will not be decided in advanced by a trial protocol but will be determined by routine clinical practice. The decision of the investigator to prescribe a particular treatment will be clearly dissociated from the decision to include the patient in the study. The patients will not suffer any intervention, whether diagnostic or monitoring, other than the usual in clinical practice.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of Tolerability and Safety of "Allergovac Poliplus" in Polysensitized Patients With Rhinitis or Allergic Rhinoconjunctivitis With or Without Asthma: A Study in Daily Clinical Practice</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Conjunctivitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Conjunctivitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients aged between 5 and 60 years who present rhinitis or allergic rhinoconjunctivitis caused by IgEmediated sensitization to more than one allergen source with or without mild / moderate asthma. 2. Patients eligible for immunotherapy treatment with Allergovac Poliplus according to investigator criteria. 3. Patients must provide written informed consent. It is the case of children , the legal representative or tutor of the child must sign the inform consent form. 1. Patients that according to the investigator criteria may present difficulties for understanding the patient information sheet, completing the questionnaires and selfadministered scales. 2. Patients that according to the investigator may present difficulties to complete the patient diary. 3. Patients who are participating in another clinical trial or observational study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>mild or moderate</keyword>
</DOC>