<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02844504</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Breast cancer patients often suffer from long-term physical symptoms of weakness. In this study, investigators propose to compare how two different low intensity physical exercise training programs can improve handgrip strength for breast cancer patients with symptoms of weakness. Using brain imaging, the study will also investigate changes in brain structure, and muscle activity associated with handgrip.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neurophysiological Evaluation of Training Effect on Cancer-Related Weakness</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Participants will be randomized to either a no treatment group or one of two low intensity 6-week exercise training. Outcomes will be measured at baseline, post-intervention and 4 weeks post intervention.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Female aged 5075 yrs Right handed, as determined by the Edinburgh Inventory (Oldfield, 1971) Proficient in English Must be available for the familiarization, and testing sessions Symptoms for mild or severe depression as determined by a Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ8) score &gt;14 Significant cognitive impairments as defined by a score &lt;28 in the Folstein MiniMental Screening Examination (MMSE, Folstein et al .1975). Participated in any type of motor imagery or strength training program in the last 5 years, or plan to start any motor imagery or physical strength training program for the 3 months duration of the study Neurological, psychiatric, musculoskeletal or other types of disorder that may affect participants sensorimotor function and cognitive abilities Current medication believed to affect cognitive/psychomotor function (i.e., opioid, analgesics, anxiolytics or antidepressants) History of alcohol, smoking, and drug abuse Any contraindication for MRI</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Fatigue</keyword>
	<keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Force</keyword>
	<keyword>Motor imagery</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer Treatment</keyword>
</DOC>