<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00400400</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Treatment with the immunosuppressive drug mycophenolate mofetil (MMF) may result in gastrointestinal (GI) complications in some patients. This study will investigate the safety and tolerability of converting kidney transplant recipients with gastrointestinal symptoms from their current treatment of mycophenolate mofetil (MMF) to treatment with enteric-coated mycophenolate sodium (EC-MPS).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Enteric-coated Mycophenolate Sodium (EC-MPS) and Mycophenolate Mofetil (MMF) in Renal Transplant Patients With Gastrointestinal (GI) Intolerance</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Calcineurin Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Males and females aged 1875 years, Recipients of first or second cadaveric, living unrelated or living related kidney transplant Recipients who are at least 4 weeks post renal transplantation with stable renal function, Patients currently receiving MMF (all dosages are allowed) and either cyclosporine USP (MODIFIED) or tacrolimus with or without corticosteroids as part of their immunosuppressive regimen for at least 2 weeks prior to study start Patients with at least one mild and/or moderate and/or severe upper or lower gastrointestinal (GI) complaints clearly associated with MMF therapy as determined by the treating physician. Additional mild GI complaints may coexist Patients' immunosuppressive regimen other than steroids (doses and type) as well as medication for treatment of GI symptoms must be unchanged for at least 1 week prior to study start Females of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test prior to the inclusion period. The test should be performed locally at Baseline visit. If positive, the patient will not be included. Effective contraception must be used during the trial, and for 4 weeks following discontinuation of the study medication Patients who are willing and able to participate in the full course of the study and from whom written informed consent has been obtained. Exclusion criteria: Multiorgan transplant patients (e.g. kidney and pancreas) or previous transplant with any other organ different from kidney (second kidney transplant is allowed) History of GI disorder (diarrhea, Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease (GERD), dyspepsia, Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IBD) or Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) prior to transplantation Evidence of any GI disorder induced by an infection, underlying medical condition, or concomitant medication other than MMF, Modification of GI medication or MMF dose within last 1 week Evidence of graft rejection, treatment of acute rejection, or unstable renal function within 4 weeks prior to the Baseline visit, Patients who have received an investigational immunosuppressive drug within 4 weeks prior to study entry Patients with a history of malignancy within the last five years, except excised squamous or basal cell carcinoma of the skin Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women, Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) not using an acceptable method of contraception such as: surgical sterilization, hormonal contraception, or doublebarrier methods. Contraception should be maintained throughout the study and for 4 weeks after study drug discontinuation. Other protocol defined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>RenalTransplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>KidneyTransplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>MPA</keyword>
	<keyword>EC-MPS</keyword>
</DOC>