<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00400075</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the efficacy of systemic corticosteroids alone as first-line treatment of polyarteritis nodosa and microscopic polyangiitis without poor-prognosis factors as defined by the five-factor score (FFS=0), and to compare the efficacy and safety of azathioprine vs pulse cyclophosphamide as adjunctive immunosuppressive therapy to treat failure or relapse.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>CHUSPAN PAN BP Treatment of Polyarteritis Nodosa and Microscopic Polyangiitis Without Poor-Prognosis Factors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>All patients initially treated with systemic corticosteroids alone: optional IV methylprednisolone pulse (15 mg/kg) at treatment start followed by oral prednisone (1 mg/kg/day) according to a tapering schedule. Treating physicians allowed to treat minor relapses with corticosteroids without referring the patient for randomization, as long as the prednisone dose did not exceed 0.5 mg/kg for 1 month. Patients in whom prednisone doses could not be tapered below 20 mg, those who failed to enter remission and those who relapsed were randomized to receive either 6 months of oral azathioprine (2mg/kg/day) or 6 cyclophosphamide pulses (0.6g/m2 D1, D15, D30 then every month)</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Systemic Vasculitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Microscopic Polyangiitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polyarteritis Nodosa</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Azathioprine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Men and women with newly diagnosed polyarteritis nodosa or microscopic polyangiitis; absence of poor prognostic factors as defined by the fivefactor score (serum creatinine &gt; 140 μmol/l or 1.58 mg/dl, proteinuria &gt; 1 g/day, severe gastrointestinal tract involvement, specific cardiomyopathy and/or central nervous system involvement; written informed consent. Both genders eligible; age ≥ 15 years. age &lt; 15 years, previously treated systemic vasculitis; history of cancer; pregnant or breastfeeding women; psychiatric disorders that might compromise compliance with therapy; contraindication to study drug; other ongoing therapeutic trial; concomitant viral hepatitis B or C or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>Polyarteritis</keyword>
	<keyword>Vasculitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Cyclophosphamide</keyword>
	<keyword>Azathioprine</keyword>
</DOC>