<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00400894</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Emerging from a differential proteomic study of sample pairs of prostate cancer and benign tissue, annexin A3 (ANXA3) was chosen as a potential novel biomarker for the early and non-invasive diagnosis of prostate cancer. We wanted to show or investigate, that: - ANXA3 can be detected in urine after standard digital rectal examination. - ANXA3 has better specificities than tPSA, in particular in the grey zone of PSA - ANXA3 can help avoid unnecessary biopsies - ANXA3 can in the long run replace PSA as a marker</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Annexin A3 (ANXA3) as Protein-Based Marker for Non-Invasive Molecular Diagnostics of Prostate Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of this multi centre and double-blinded study was to investigate specificities and sensitivities of early detection of prostate cancer with a new protein biomarker, annexin A3, using urine after digital rectal examination/massage (exprimate urine) in direct comparison to the corresponding measurements of the gold standard, total PSA. The material obtained by this non-invasive procedure was moreover used to determine appropriate cut-off values and optimal fractions (e.g. after centrifugation) and calibrations for quantitative measurements of this novel marker. Patients (500-750) were (and are) continuously recruited from four clinical centres in Germany (Berlin, Tübingen, Ludwigshafen) and Austria (Innsbruck). The major aspect was: • Can annexin A3 provide a better specificity than tPSA, in particular in the grey zone of PSA (2-10 ng/ml) and can annexin A3 thus contribute to a significant reduction of invasive transrectal biopsies?</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma in Situ</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Intraepithelial Neoplasia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with a histological confirmation of adenocarcinoma of the prostate Patients with benign prostatic hyperplasia (confirmed by histology of lance biopsies or TURP) Patients with rectal extirpation Patients with renal or bladder tumors</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>annexin A3</keyword>
	<keyword>early detection</keyword>
	<keyword>exprimate urine</keyword>
</DOC>