<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01343485</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Planned Parenthood Federation of America's (PPFA) Medical Affairs Division will conduct a prospective, cluster randomized trial to determine which factors influence the acquisition of the second and third human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccine doses among young women ages 19 to 26. This descriptive and interventional study will provide data to assess impact of a computerized tool upon HPV vaccine series completion. The interventional aspect of this study includes determination of patient assistance and provider support programs applicable to each woman's situation as well as the implementation of a computer software system for customized patient reminders.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Innovative Tool to Increase Completion of Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Vaccine Series</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Female; Age 1926; Fluent in English; Seeking services for anything except pregnancy or abortion on the day of the visit No previous vaccinations for HPV No contraindication for HPV vaccine (includes a severe allergic reaction to yeast, amorphous aluminum hydroxyphosphate sulfate, and polysorbate 80.) Access to phone, text, mail, email, or facebook Not wanting to become pregnant in the next 8 months; Not planning on moving from the area in the next 8 months Willing to be contacted for followup over the next 8 months. Women below 19 or above 26. Male Women who have one or more of HPV vaccination. Women who have a contraindication for HPV vaccine. Women who do not have access by phone, mail, email, Twitter or Facebook for follow up. Women who are not fluent in English Pregnant women or those intending on becoming pregnant during the study period. Women who will be moving from the area and unable to return for follow up over the course of the study (approximately 8 months). Severe mental impairment and unable to give Informed Consent.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>26 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Gardasil vaccine</keyword>
</DOC>