<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01988896</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Phase Ib, open-label, multicenter study designed to assess the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics of coadministration of intravenous (IV) dosing of atezolizumab (an engineered anti-programmed death-ligand 1 [anti PD-L1] antibody) and oral dosing of cobimetinib in participants with metastatic or locally advanced cancer for which no standard therapy exists.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Atezolizumab in Combination With Cobimetinib in Participants With Locally Advanced or Metastatic Solid Tumors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Signed Informed Consent Form. Solid tumor that is metastatic, locally advanced or recurrent. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1. Life expectancy greater than or equal to 12 weeks. Measurable disease, as defined by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) v 1.1. Adequate hematologic and end organ function. Use of highly effective contraception. Histological tumor tissue specimen. Participants enrolling in the indicationspecific expansion cohorts in Stage 2 must consent to tumor biopsies and must have one of the following types of cancer: Metatastic colorectal cancer Nonsmall cell lung cancer Melanoma. Consent to undergo pretreatment and/or ontreatment tumor biopsies for biomarker analysis for participants in biopsymandated cohorts. Cancer specific exclusion criteria: Any approved anticancer therapy, including chemotherapy, or hormonal therapy within 3 weeks prior to initiation of study treatment. Treatment with any other investigational agent or participation in another clinical trial with therapeutic intent within 28 days prior to enrollment. Known active or untreated central nervous system (CNS) metastases. Leptomeningeal disease. Uncontrolled tumorrelated pain or uncontrolled pleural effusion, pericardial effusion, or ascites requiring recurrent (once monthly or more frequently) drainage procedures. Uncontrolled hypercalcemia or symptomatic hypercalcemia requiring continued use of bisphosphonate therapy or denosumab. General medical exclusion criteria: Pregnant and lactating women. History of severe allergic, anaphylactic, or other hypersensitivity reactions to chimeric or humanized antibodies or fusion proteins. Known hypersensitivity to Chinese hamster ovary cell products. Allergy or hypersensitivity to components of the atezolizumab formulation. History of autoimmune disease. Participants with prior allogeneic stem cell or solid organ transplantation. Positive test for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). Participants with active hepatitis B, hepatitis C, or tuberculosis. Severe infections within 4 weeks prior to Cycle 1 Day 1. Signs or symptoms of infection within 2 weeks prior to Cycle 1 Day 1. Received therapeutic oral or IV antibiotics within 2 weeks prior to Cycle 1 Day 1. Significant cardiovascular disease. Major surgical procedure other than for diagnosis within 28 days prior to Cycle 1 Day 1 or anticipation of need for a major surgical procedure during the course of the study. Administration of a live, attenuated vaccine within 4 weeks before Cycle 1 Day 1. Exclusion criteria unique to cobimetinib: History of prior significant toxicity from another mitogenactivated protein kinase (MEK) pathway inhibitor requiring discontinuation of treatment. Allergy or hypersensitivity to components of the cobimetinib formulations. History of congenital long QT syndrome or corrected QT interval (QTc) &gt;450 milliseconds at screening. Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) below institutional lower limit of normal (LLN) or below 50%, whichever is lower, as determined by echocardiogram or Multi Gated Acquisition Scan (MUGA) scan. History of or evidence of retinal pathology on ophthalmologic examination that is considered a risk factor for neurosensory retinal detachment, central serous chorioretinopathy (CSCR), retinal vein occlusion (RVO), or neovascular macular degeneration. History of malabsorption syndrome or other condition that would interfere with enteral absorption. Exclusion criteria related to medications: Prior treatment with clusters of differentiation (CD) 137 (CD137) agonists or immune checkpoint blockade therapies, systemic immunostimulatory agents, or systemic immunosuppressive medications.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>