<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01988558</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study objectives are to evaluate Tonsitin™ (10% Lactic Acid) safety, tolerability and preliminary efficacy, as a potent treatment for Recurrent Tonsillitis in children.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase I/II to Assess Safety, Tolerability and Efficacy of DL-lactic Acid Syrup in Children With Recurrent Tonsillitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Tonsillitis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children at the ages of 516. Patient is suffering from recurrent documented sore throat with at least 4 tonsillitis episodes during the preceding year (at least one verified by culture or rapid antigen testing for Streptococcus A). Patient with clinical presentation of irregular tonsils. Tonsils size graded between 2.54. Clinical diagnosis of bacterial known in recurrent pharyngealtonsillitis. Patient is willing to participate in the study and adhere to the study protocol Patient's guardian and/or Patient have signed informed consent. Clinical diagnosis of acute tonsillitis/pharyngitis caused by Streptococcus pyogenes (Positive RSAT or microbial culture). Subjects who are known as Streptococcus pyogenes carriers Subject's requiring any other medication (topical or systemic) that may affect the course of the disease during the study period (e.g. antibiotics, sedating antihistamines), and/or did not completed 14 days from end of antibiotics treatment. Subjects with known hypersensitivity to lactose. Subject is suffering from peritonsillar abscess. Subject suffers from an active peptic ulcer Subjects who are suffering from any concomitant disease which in the judgment of the investigator will interfere with the conduct or interpretation of the study results. Subject is currently participating in another clinical study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Recurrent Tonsillitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Streptococcus A</keyword>
</DOC>