<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02842528</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to specify the cognitive and genetic pattern associated with alcohol dependence. Results will help identifying more precisely vulnerability factors associated with this disorder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cognitive Vulnerability Factors in Alcohol-dependence</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Alcohol dependence involves both environmental and genetic vulnerability factors. Although it has a rather high degree of heritability (estimates range between 40% and 60%), vulnerability to alcohol dependence is broadly recognised as a complex polygenic phenotype. To clarify the risk factors involved in alcohol dependence, attempts have been made to identify endophenotypes in alcohol dependent patients and their relatives. Endophenotypes are defined as heritable traits associated with an increased risk for developing a disorder; they must be found in probands and their unaffected relatives at a higher rate than in the general population and must be associated with a specific genetic pattern. In the present study the investigators investigate the cognitive performance of alcohol dependent patients in comparison with a group of adult non-alcoholic offspring of alcohol-dependent patients and a group of participants without family history of alcohol dependence. The investigators also explore the relation between familial density of alcoholism and cognitive performance, particularly mental flexibility and inhibition. Genetic analysis will also be conducted to investigate the relationship between cognitive performance and genetic patterns (single nucleotide polymorphisms).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ethanol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Alcoholdependent patients : Males or females, aged 1865 years, with a diagnosis of alcohol dependence, according to the DSMIV criteria Patients withdrawn from alcohol at least 2 weeks Native French speaker, able to read French and complete study evaluations Caucasian Able to provide informed written and verbal consent Firstdegree relatives of alcoholdependent probands : Males or females, aged 1865 years Caucasian Native French speaker, able to read French and complete study evaluations Able to provide informed written and verbal consent Healthy Controls : Males or females, aged 1865 years Caucasian Native French speaker, able to read French and complete study evaluations Able to provide informed written and verbal consent Alcoholdependent patients DSMIV substance use disorder other than alcohol Severe chronic psychiatric disorders including Bipolar disorder and schizophrenia Mood episode diagnostic according to the DSMIV criteria in the last six months A significant general medical illness, including neurological disorders A sensorial impairment uncorrected (visual and/or hearing) Individuals who are not covered by national health insurance Firstdegree relatives of alcoholdependent probands : Past or recent alcohol and/or drug abuse or dependence Severe chronic psychiatric disorders including Bipolar disorder and schizophrenia Mood episode diagnostic according to the DSMIV criteria in the last six months A significant general medical illness, including neurological disorders Handling of psychotropics substances A sensorial impairment uncorrected (visual and/or hearing) Individuals who are not covered by national health insurance Healthy Controls : A personal or firstdegreerelative history of alcohol dependence Past or recent alcohol and/or drug abuse or dependence Total abstinence from alcohol Severe chronic psychiatric disorders including Bipolar disorder and schizophrenia Mood episode diagnostic according to the DSMIV criteria in the last six months A significant general medical illness, including neurological disorders Handling of psychotropics substances A sensorial impairment uncorrected (visual and/or hearing) Individuals who are not covered by national health insurance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>