<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01845441</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Dexmedetomidine is a unique sedative medication able to provide sedation without causing respiratory depression and maintaining neurological functions. Patients having an acute ischemic stroke and need to undergo endovascular therapy require constant assessment of their neurological status prior, during and after the interventional procedure. In this study the investigators will compare the efficacy of Dexmedetomidine to other standard sedative medications in providing optimal sedative effect while maintaining neurological function.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of Dexmedetomidine in Acute Stroke and Cerebral Vasospasm Interventions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Precedex is a unique FDA-approved intravenous medication for conscious sedation in that it allows for "arousable" sedation, which is particularly appealing for use in patients with compromised neurologic function. While Precedex has been shown to be equivalent, if not superior to, conventional sedation in the procedural setting, it has not yet been evaluated in the setting of endovascular treatment of acute stroke. This setting is particularly ripe for evaluation, as there is currently controversy over the best method for management of patient sedation in light of the auxiliary need to preserve neurologic function. In order to evaluate the benefit of Precedex in this setting, it must be compared to the usual standard of care. Through the investigators double blinded randomized trial, the investigators will obtain information on the comparison between two arms, one receiving Precedex and the other the usual standard of care at the investigators institution, for achieving and maintaining a pre-defined level of conscious sedation, while preserving baseline neurologic status. This assessment will optimistically serve as the basis for future large-scale studies and ultimately to the establishment of Precedex as a first-line sedative in the management of acute stroke and cerebral vasospasm patients undergoing endovascular intervention.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vasospasm, Intracranial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intracranial Hemorrhages</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Midazolam</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with acute ischemic stroke who require endovascular intervention with whom mNIHSS score can be obtained Patients with cerebral vasospasm suspiciousness with or without subarachnoid hemorrhage with whom mNIHSS score can be obtained. History of severe hepatic disease or severe renal disease (GFR&lt;20). Hemodynamic instability. Pregnancy. Known allergy to study drug. Evidence or history of cardiac electrophysiology instability including uncontrolled hemodynamically unstable complex atrial/ventricular arrhythmia or conduction block at the time of evaluation with the exception of atrial fibrillation, and heart rate less than 60 or systolic blood pressure less than 90. Respiratory compromise requiring intubation. Any medical (including history of cardiac conduction block, major hepatic or renal disease) or laboratory abnormality that may increase the risk associated with the trial participation or drug administration or may interfere with interpretation of trial results.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dexmedetomidine</keyword>
	<keyword>Endovascular procedure</keyword>
	<keyword>Stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>Vasospasm, intracranial</keyword>
	<keyword>Conscious sedation</keyword>
</DOC>