<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01845142</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Vitamin D receptors are expressed in activated different immune cells. It is not known, which immune cell type is targeted by exogenous vitamin D. Here, vitamin D-deficient individuals will receive once 100.000 I.U. vitamin D3 either intramuscular or subcutaneous in a double-blind placebo controlled setting. Immune cells will be monitored from the blood over time.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Immunologic Action of a Single Dose Cholecalciferol</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Vitamin D-deficient individuals will receive once - double-blind, placebo controlled 100.000 I.U.vitamin D3 - intramuscular or subcutaneous Blood will be taken over time and - immune cells (T cells, B cells, myeloid antigen presenting cells) are characterized by flow-cytometry - vitamin D-metabolites will be monitored</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>informed consent 1860 yrs 25hydroxyvitamin D serum below 50 nmol/L women only: effective contraception 25hydroxyvitamin D serum above 50 nmol/L bodymass index &lt;18 or &gt;30 kg per m2 planned UVexposure (UVindex &gt; 5) hypersensitivity to vitamin D history of hypercalcemia, kidney stones, kidney insufficiency, sarcoidosis, pseudohyperparathyroidism concomitant vitamin A and/or vitamin D treatment treatment with immunosuppressants, immunomodulators, phenytoin, barbiturate, thiazidediuretics, glycosides immobile patients out of normal range on screening visit (calcium,phosphate,creatinin,hematology) psychiatric hospitalization pregnancy / breastfeeding dependency / relationship on sponsor concomitant participation in other clinical trials (30 days before) drug or alcohol abuse lack of compliance</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>vitamin D</keyword>
	<keyword>vitamin D deficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>immune cells</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetic</keyword>
	<keyword>&lt; 50 nmol/L 25(OH)D serum concentration</keyword>
</DOC>