<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00366145</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and gather additional safety of Prochymal in subjects who have failed to respond to steroid treatment of Grades B-D acute GVHD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Adult Human Mesenchymal Stem Cells to Treat Steroid Refractory Acute Graft Versus Host Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Approximately 6300 patients receive allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplants in the United States each year (IBMTR, 2003). Nearly 50% (approximately 3,150) of these patients develop acute GVHD (Goker et al). A fraction of these patients (approximately 870) will progress to the severe stages of the disease, Grades III-IV. It is estimated that nearly 82% of those patients with severe acute GVHD will be steroid refractory (Przepiorka et al., 1995) and of these, only 50% of steroid-refractory patients wll respond to secondary and tertiary treatments (Greinix et al., 2000). Thus, roughly 350 patients each year face tremendous odds against survival. In addition, most patients who initially responded to secondary and tertiary treatments have a high risk of dying within the first year (Remberger et al., 2001; Anasetti et al., 1994). Development of new therapeutic agents and strategies to rescue patients with steroid refractory, acute GVHD would provide a significant benefit in an area of unmet medical need. Patients will receive standard of care in addition to adult mesenchymal stem cells or placebo.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Graft vs Host Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects must be 6 months to 70 years of age, inclusive Subjects who have failed to respond to steroid treatment: Failure to respond to steroid treatment is defined as any grade BD (IBMTR grading) of acute GVHD that shows: No improvement after 3 days and a duration of no greater than 2 weeks while receiving treatment with Methylprednisolone (greater than or equal to 1 mg/kg/day) or equivalent. Subjects must be treated within 4 days of randomization . In urgent situations 2nd line therapy may be started 24 hours prior to randomization , and Prochymal must be initiated within the following 3 days. Subjects who have received an increase in their steroid dose treatment prior to randomization will be eligible for enrollment. An increase in steroid dose will not be considered as second line therapy. Subjects must have adequate renal function as defined by: Calculated Creatinine Clearance of &gt;30mL/min using the Cockroft Gault equation For pediatric patients: Schwartz equation: (Patient population: infants over 1 week old through adolescence (&lt;18 years old) Subjects who are women of childbearing potential, must be nonpregnant, not breastfeeding, and use adequate contraception. Male subjects must use adequate contraception Subject must have a minimum Karnofsky Performance Level of at least 30 at the time of study entry Subject (or legal representative where appropriate) must be capable of providing written informed consent. Subject has started treatment with second line therapy &gt;24 hours prior to randomization. Subject has received agents other than steroids for primary treatment of acute GVHD Subject is participating in the CTN Protocol 0302 Subject has any underlying or current medical or psychiatric condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would interfere with the evaluation of the subject including uncontrolled infection, heart failure, pulmonary hypertension, etc. Subjects may not receive any other investigational agents (not approved by the FDA) concurrently during study participation or within 30 days of randomization. Subject has a known allergy to bovine or porcine products. Subject has received a transplant for a solid tumor disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>acute GVHD</keyword>
	<keyword>steroid refractory GVHD</keyword>
	<keyword>severe steroid refractory acute GVHD</keyword>
	<keyword>steroid refractory</keyword>
	<keyword>Steroid Refractory Acute Graft Versus Host Disease</keyword>
</DOC>