<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00366899</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety, tolerability and immunogenicity of a 13-valent pneumococcal conjugate (13vPnC) vaccine compared to Prevenar (7vPnC), when given concomitantly with routine paediatric vaccinations in Italy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study Evaluating a 13-valent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine in Infants</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heptavalent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: 1. Aged 3 months (75 to 105 days) at time of enrollment. 2. Available for entire study period and whose parent(s)/legal guardian(s) could be reached by telephone. 3. Healthy infant, as determined by medical history, physical examination, and judgment of the investigator. 4. Born at greater than 32 weeks gestational age and greater than 2000 grams. Regardless of gestational age and birth weight, all subjects must have met inclusion criterion number 3. 5. Parent(s)/legal guardian(s) had to be able to complete all relevant study procedures during study participation. Exclusion criteria: 1. Previous vaccination with licensed or investigational pneumococcal vaccine. 2. Previous vaccination with Hib conjugate, diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis, polio, or hepatitis B vaccines. 3. A previous anaphylactic reaction to any vaccine or vaccinerelated component. 4. Contraindication to vaccination with Hib conjugate, diphtheria, tetanus, pertussis, polio, or hepatitis B, or pneumococcal vaccines. 5. Bleeding diathesis or condition associated with prolonged bleeding time that would contraindicate intramuscular injection. 6. Known or suspected immune deficiency or suppression. 7. History of cultureproven invasive disease caused by S pneumoniae or Hib. 8. Major known congenital malformation or serious chronic disorder. 9. Significant neurological disorder or history of seizure, including febrile seizure, or significant stable or evolving disorders, such as cerebral palsy, encephalopathy, hydrocephalus, or other significant disorders. Did not include resolving syndromes due to birth trauma such as Erb palsy. 10. Receipt of blood products or gammaglobulin (including hepatitis B immunoglobulin and monoclonal antibodies; eg, Synagis® [MedImmune]). 11. Participation in another investigational trial. Participation in purely observational studies was acceptable. 12. Infant who was a direct descendant (eg, child or grandchild) of the study site personnel.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>75 Days</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>105 Days</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Vaccine</keyword>
	<keyword>Infants</keyword>
</DOC>