<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01741610</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study was conducted to evaluate the effects of rapid crystalloid (Lactated Ringer's solution) or colloid (hydroxyethyl starch; HES) cohydration with a second intravenous access line on the incidence of hypotension and ephedrine requirement during spinal anaesthesia for caesarean section.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Fluid Coloading and the Incidence of Hypotension</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: Spinal anaesthesia for caesarean delivery is often associated with hypotension. This study was conducted to evaluate the effects of rapid crystalloid (Lactated Ringer's solution) or colloid (hydroxyethyl starch; HES) cohydration with a second intravenous access line on the incidence of hypotension and ephedrine requirement during spinal anaesthesia for caesarean section. Methods: We studied 90 women with uncomplicated pregnancies undergoing elective caesarean section under spinal anaesthesia. Intravenous access was established in all with two peripheral intravenous lines, the first being used for the baseline volume infusion. Immediately after induction of spinal anaesthesia, Lactated Ringer's solution (Group L) or HES (Group C) infusions were started at the maximal possible rate via the second line in groups L and C respectively. The third group (Group E) patients received lactated Ringer's solution at a 'keep vein open' rate to maintain the double-blind nature. The incidence of hypotension, ephedrine requirements, total amount of volume and side effects were recorded.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypotension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ephedrine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>elective caesarean section under spinal anaesthesia Significant coexisting disease such as; preeclampsia and hepatorenal disease, Pregnancy preinduced hypertension, Being in active labour or requiring emergency caesarean section, Any contraindication to regional anaesthesia such as local infection or bleeding disorders.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>46 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anaesthesia Spinal</keyword>
	<keyword>Ephedrine</keyword>
	<keyword>Fluid Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypotension</keyword>
</DOC>