<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01885910</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This pilot study will explore if continuation of treatment of treatment with Aczone 5% gel following combination treatment with with doxycycline and Aczone 5% gel can maintain therapeutic response.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aczone 5% Gel as Maintenance Treatment of Acne Vulgaris Following Completion of Oral Doxycycline and Aczone 5% Gel</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a two-center, open-label pilot study. The study is apprised of 7 study visits: Baseline and Weeks 4, 8, 12, 16, 20 and 24. All subjects will receive Aczone 5% gel BID and doxycycline 100mg by mouth once daily at Baseline. Those subjects achieving treatment response (i.e., IGA of 0, 1 or 2) at Week 12 will continue treatment with Aczone 5% gel BID at Week 12. Subjects not achieving treatment response will discontinue study participation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Acne Vulgaris</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Doxycycline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dapsone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Outpatient, male or female subjects of any race, age 12 or older. Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative urine pregnancy test result at Baseline and practice a reliable method of contraception throughout the study; Facial acne vulgaris characterized by the following: IGA Score &gt;3 1050 facial inflammatory lesions (papules,pustules) 10100 facial noninflammatory lesions (open/closed comedones) Able to understand and comply with the requirements of the study and sign Informed Consent/HIPAA Authorization forms Female subjects who are pregnant (positive urine pregnancy test), breast feeding, or who are of childbearing potential and not practicing a reliable method of birth control. Allergy/sensitivity to any component of the test treatment (Section 5.2), lincomycin, tetracyclines, or sulfites. Subjects who have not complied with the proper washout periods for prohibited medications/procedures (Supplement 1)&gt; History of clinically significant anemia or hemolysis. History of enteritis (regional enteritis, ulcerative colitis, pseudomembranous colitis, or antibioticassociated colitis). Skin disease/disorder that might interfere with the diagnosis or evaluation of acne vulgaris Evidence of recent alcohol or drug abuse Medical condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, contraindicates the subject's participation in the clinical study History of poor cooperation, noncompliance with medical treatment or unreliability Participation in an investigational drug study within 30 days of the baseline visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>