<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01885936</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this study the study team proposes to investigate the efficacy of albuterol on motor function of individuals with Late Onset Pompe Disease (LOPD) who are receiving enzyme replacement therapy, given albuterol was well-tolerated in patients with Late Onset Pompe Disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Albuterol on Motor Function in Individuals With Late-onset Pompe Disease Receiving Enzyme Replacement Therapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Glycogen Storage Disease Type II</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albuterol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosis of Pompe disease by blood acid alphaglucosidase assay and acid alphaglucosidase gene sequencing, 2. Age: 18+ years at enrollment. 3. Receiving enzyme replacement therapy at standard dose (20 mg/kg every 2 weeks) for at least 52 weeks. 4. Subjects are capable of giving written consent. 1. Continuous invasive ventilation (via tracheostomy or endotracheal tube). 2. Clinically relevant illness within two weeks of enrollment including fever &gt; 38.2 C, vomiting more than once in 24 hours, seizure, or other symptom deemed contraindicative to new therapy. 3. Chronic heart disease (Myocardial infarction in the past 2 months, arrhythmia, cardiomyopathy). 4. History of seizure disorder. 5. History of diabetes. 6. Hypokalemia. 7. History of hyperthyroidism. 8. Pregnancy. 9. Patients on a nonstandard schedule for enzyme replacement therapy; for example, weekly infusions as opposed to infusions every two weeks. 10. AntirhGAA antibody titer &gt; 1:100,000 11. History of hypersensitivity to Beta 2agonist drugs such as albuterol, levalbuterol (Xopenex), bitolterol (Tornalate), pirbuterol (Maxair), terbutaline, salmeterol (Serevent).. 12. The use of the following medications: diuretics (water pill); digoxin (digitalis, Lanoxin); betablockers such as atenolol (Tenormin), metoprolol (Lopressor), and propranolol (Inderal); tricyclic antidepressants such as amitriptyline (Elavil, Etrafon), doxepin (Sinequan), imipramine (Janimine, Tofranil), and nortriptyline (Pamelor); Monoamine oxidase inhibitors such as isocarboxazid (Marplan), phenelzine (Nardil), rasagiline (Azilect), selegiline (Eldepryl, Emsam), or tranylcypromine (Parnate); or bronchodilators such as albuterol, levalbuterol (Xopenex), bitolterol (Tornalate), pirbuterol (Maxair), terbutaline (Brethine, Bricanyl), salmeterol (Serevent), isoetharine (Bronkometer), metaproterenol (Alupent, Metaprel), or isoproterenol (Isuprel Mistometer) within 12 weeks prior to enrollment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>LOPD</keyword>
	<keyword>Pompe Disease</keyword>
</DOC>