<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01885988</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The study will take part at The Men's Health Center It will involve men who have a diagnosis of erectile dysfunction and also have high blood pressure. High blood pressure can affect the lining of the arteries and cause stiffness in the arteries. The arteries and veins throughout the body have a lining called the endothelium which gives them the ability to stretch. If the lining of the penile arteries becomes impaired, it can decrease the stretching of the artery and decrease blood flow. Decreased blood flow in the penile arteries can cause problems obtaining an erection. The study medication Nebivolol controls blood pressure by relaxing smooth muscle around the lining of the arteries, thereby improving stretch and blood flow. The primary objective is to determine if treatment with nebivolol improves endothelial function and erectile function in men with pre-hypertension and stage 1 hypertension 70 men will be enrolled into the study. Half of the subjects will receive active medication and half will receive a placebo. All men will receive educational informational handouts about blood pressure and behavior modifications to improve blood pressure. The study will last for 3 months for each subject. The expected recruitment time is one year, with a 2 year study completion goal. Subjects will have approximately 5 study visits. Subjects will have initial/final blood work, a Rigiscan test (a take home penile erection test), two EndoPat tests to assess endothelium function, 3 SphygmoCor tests to assess central blood pressure, 2 sexual health questionnaires at 2 visits. Vital signs will be monitored at each visit to assess safety and effectiveness of the study medication.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nebivolol Effects on Endothelial Function and Erectile Function</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Randomized double-blind placebo-controlled study of 70 non-smoking pre-hypertensive men (BP 120-139 / 80-89) or with newly diagnosed stage 1 hypertension (BP &gt; 140 but &lt; 159/ 90-99) with erectile dysfunction receiving nebivolol (5-20mg) or placebo, along with lifestyle modifications, daily for 3 months to titrate BP to 120/80 or less.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Erectile Dysfunction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nebivolol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males 2565 Male Patients with ED (IIEF5 ) Score &gt; 13 and &lt; 21 o If a subject is using PDE5's( phosphodiesterase type 5 inhibitors), there must be a two week washout of PDE5 use, then in two weeks without PDE5 use; 4 attempts at sexual activity and an IIEF score &lt; 21 on at least 2 of the four efforts Treatment naïve patients with Prehypertension (BP 120139/8089) or Stage 1 hypertension (BP &gt; 140 but &lt; 159/ 9099) Patients in a stable, monogamous relationship Patients are able to comprehend and satisfactorily comply with protocol requirements Eugonadal Men : Total Testosterone 300 ng/dL1000 ng/dL or greater, as well as men who are eugonadal with treatment. Nonsmoker Men with concomitant Type 1 or Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus Normal RigiScan at Baseline Concomitant use of ACE/ ARB (angiotensin receptor blocker)/ Betablocking agents/CCB (calcium channel blocker) / alphablocker Concomitant use of PDE5'S Currently Smoking Meeting any exclusion criteria for beta blocker use as stated in the nebivolol package insert Patients who have a medical condition that, in the Investigator's opinion, would expose them to an increased risk of a significant adverse event or interfere with assessments of safety and efficacy during the course of the trial. Patients with any current malignancy, or any clinically significant hematological, endocrine, cardiovascular, renal, hepatic, gastrointestinal or neurological disease. If there is a history of such disease but the condition has been stable for at least the past year and is judged by the investigator not to interfere with the patient's participation in the study, the patient may be included. Patients who are unable to speak, read, and understand English or are judged by the investigator to be unable or unlikely to follow the study protocol and complete all scheduled visits.</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Erectile dysfunction</keyword>
</DOC>