<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01406938</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess the safety and efficacy of two different doses and two different dose regimens of subcutaneous secukinumab in patients that have moderate to severe, chronic, plaque-type psoriasis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Subcutaneous Secukinumab (AIN457) for Moderate to Severe Chronic Plaque-type Psoriasis Assessing Different Doses and Dose Regimens</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Moderate and severe plaquetype psoriasis diagnosed for at least 6 months. Severity of disease meeting all of the following three criteria: PASI score of 12 or greater, Investigator's Global Assessment (IGA) score of 3 or greater Total body surface area (BSA) affected of 10% or greater. Inadequate control by prior use of topical treatment, phototherapy and/or systemic therapy. Exclusion criteria: Current forms of psoriasis other than chronic plaquetype psoriasis (for example, pustular, erythrodermic, guttate). Current druginduced psoriasis. Previous use of secukinumab or any drug that targets IL17 or IL17 receptor. Significant medical problems such as uncontrolled hypertension, congestive heart failure or a condition that significantly immunocompromises the subject. Hematological abnormalities. History of an ongoing, chronic or recurrent infectious disease, or evidence of untreated tuberculosis. History of lymphoproliferative disease or history of malignancy of any organ system within the past 5 years. Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women. Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Psoriasis</keyword>
	<keyword>plaque</keyword>
	<keyword>inflammatory skin disease</keyword>
	<keyword>scaly patches</keyword>
	<keyword>AIN457</keyword>
	<keyword>secukinumab</keyword>
	<keyword>Moderate to Severe Plaque-type Psoriasis</keyword>
</DOC>