<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02967939</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A study demonstrates the non-inferiority of DA-2802 when compared with ㅍViread® in chronic hepatitis B patients</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of DA-2802 in Chronic Hepatitis B Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>1. DA-2802 319mg Group: Administration with DA-2802 319mg tablet qd and placebo tablet matching to Viread® 300mg for 0-48 weeks. 2. Viread® 300mg Group: Administration with Viread® 300mg tablet qd and placebo tablet matching to DA-2802 319mg for 0-48 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with chronic hepatitis B aged 18 years or older Subjects who have evidence to demonstrate a history of chronic hepatitis B for at least six months from the time of screening visit Subjects who have HBsAg positive test at screening visit Subjects who did not receive the hepatitis B treatment, including interferon or pegylated interferon, within 24 weeks of starting the screening test Subjects with an ALT of 80 units or more and 10 times lower than the normal upper limit at the time of screening Subjects infected with hepatitis C, hepatitis D or human immunodeficiency virus Subjects with creatinine clearance of less than 50 ml/min at the screening visit At the time of screening visit, alphafetoprotein level was higher than 50 ng/ml and related imaging test showed hepatocellular carcinoma Subjects with decompensated liver disease who meet the following criteria: 1. Total bilirubin levels greater than 2.5 mg/dl 2. Prothrombin time is at least 3 seconds longer than normal upper limit 3. Serum albumin value less than 30 g/l 4. Subjects with a history of ascites, jaundice, bleeding from varicose veins, hepatic encephalopathy, or other signs of liver failure.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>