<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01783704</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Hip fracture is a common problem among older individuals. This year in the United States approximately 350,000 people aged 65 and older will break a hip. Despite improvements in therapy, hip fracture can still result in decreases in the strength of bone and muscle, making it difficult to walk and perform daily activities. Activity and exercise are believed to be of benefit for reducing disability in older adults, yet the majority of older adults do not participate in regular exercise and is not active. This is especially true for older adults following hip fracture after they complete the usual rehabilitation program. This study is being done to compare two 16-week supervised multi-part physical therapy programs (interventions) initiated up to 26 weeks after hip fracture. The investigators want to test whether the interventions lead to improvements in a person's ability to walk on their own in the home and in the local community. With this knowledge the investigators hope to help a greater number of hip fracture patients enjoy a more complete recovery and improved overall health.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Community Ambulation After Hip Fracture</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Despite improvements in medical management, significant residual disability remains in older persons after a hip fracture. The goal of current clinical practice is independent, safe household ambulation two to three months after surgery. Hip fracture-acquired dependency in functional activities of daily living persists well beyond three months post-surgery. One year after hip fracture, 20% of patients need help putting on pants, 50% need assistance to walk, and 90% need assistance to climb stairs. This residual disability indicates that current standard Medicare-reimbursed post-hip fracture rehabilitation (i.e., usual care) fails to return many patients to pre-fracture levels of function. In contrast to stroke and heart disease, other commonly occurring acute conditions in the older population, there are few intervention trials focused on decreasing disability following hip fracture. None of the trials for hip fracture has examined the effect of early post-fracture intervention on the ability to ambulate at a level required for independent function in the community (i.e., community ambulation). Thus, there is a paucity of evidence to justify extending medical management beyond usual care in persons following hip fracture to achieve community, rather than merely household, ambulation. A randomized controlled trial (RCT) including 210 older adults who have experienced a hip fracture will be carried out at three clinical sites with half of the subjects receiving a specific multi-component intervention (PUSH) and the other half receiving a non-specific multi-component intervention (PULSE). Randomization of 210 participants meeting eligibility criteria will take place after post-acute rehabilitation ends, approximately 6 months (26 weeks) after admission to the hospital for hip fracture. The primary endpoint will be measured using the Six-Minute Walk Test (SMWT) at the end of the 16-week intervention period. The goal is to enable older adults who have experienced a hip fracture to recover sufficiently to become community ambulators. In version 11.0 of the protocol, we will eliminate several secondary and tertiary outcome measures. In the description of measures below, we identify the measures that will not be collected for participants consented under protocol version 11.0 or later.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hip Fractures</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Closed fracture of proximal femur Age 60 or older at time of randomization Minimal trauma fracture Nonpathologic fracture Surgical fixation of fracture Living in the community at time of fracture Ambulating without human assistance 2 months prior to fracture Unable to walk 300 m or more in 6 minutes without human assistance at time of randomization Not English speaking Does not live within reasonable distance of the clinical center End stage renal disease on dialysis Recent myocardial infarction Uncompensated congestive heart failure Lower extremity amputation Symptoms of angina pectoris Chest pain or shortness of breath (including from severe COPD) Participant plans to move out of area or otherwise be unavailable during the 16week intervention period Participation in another clinical trial Not communityresiding (e.g., resident of a skilled nursing facility) at time of randomization Not fully weightbearing on fractured leg or nonfractured leg at time of randomization Calculated creatinine clearance &lt; 15 ml/min Serum albumin &lt; 2.5 g/dl Hemoglobin &lt; 9 g/dl Receiving physical therapy for the hip fracture in the hospital or inpatient rehabilitation facility at time of randomization Severely diminished lower extremity sensation or ulceration Uncontrolled hypertension Denied medical clearance by appropriate medical provider Clinical site clinician thinks participant is not a good candidate for study (e.g., not likely to survive study period) Cognitive impairment (3MS score &lt;73) Development of chest pain or substantial shortness of breath or ambulating with severe pain during baseline SMWT Participant walks less than 4 meters in 40 seconds (&lt;0.1 m/sec) during baseline SMWT Not randomized by 26 weeks post admission for hip fracture Final signoff from study clinician and/or principal investigator is incomplete Incomplete baseline data Unable to contact participant Participant is unable to provide her/his own informed consent Participant refuses the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>hip fracture</keyword>
	<keyword>randomized controlled trial</keyword>
	<keyword>exercise</keyword>
</DOC>