<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01783522</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This randomized phase II trial studies glutamine in preventing peripheral neuropathy in patients with multiple myeloma who are receiving bortezomib. Glutamine may help prevent peripheral neuropathy in patients receiving chemotherapy</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Glutamine in Preventing Peripheral Neuropathy in Patients With Multiple Myeloma Receiving Bortezomib</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>PRIMARY OBJECTIVES: I. Estimate the objective effect size of glutamine compared to placebo as a prophylactic intervention to prevent bortezomib-induced peripheral neuropathy in multiple myeloma patients 4 months after their first dose of study drug. SECONDARY OBJECTIVES: I. Estimate whether glutamine delays or prevents the onset or worsening of any neuropathy as determined by National Cancer Institute (NCI)-Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v4.03 criteria. II. Determine if glutamine may improve adherence to bortezomib therapy. III. Assess response rate (RR) and clinical benefit response rate (CBR) according to uniform international response criteria and modified European Group for Blood and Marrow Transplantation (EBMT) criteria. IV. Determine if glutamine may improve quality of life (QOL) at 4 months. OUTLINE: Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. ARM I: Patients receive glutamine orally (PO) twice daily (BID). Courses repeat every 28 days for 4 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. ARM II: Patients receive placebo PO BID. Courses repeat every 28 days for 4 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bortezomib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with a diagnosis of multiple myeloma who received bortezomib at a dose of 1.3mg/m2 SQ weekly No evidence of severe preexisting peripheral neuropathy, NCICTCAE v4.03 =&lt; 2 Performance status =&lt; 2 on the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance scale Concurrent use of thalidomide, vincristine, platinum compound, or other agent known to cause significant neuropathy (concurrent lenalidomide will be allowed) Hospitalization with clinical evidence of active infections as manifested by recurrent fevers, positive blood culture results, or requiring intravenous antibiotic therapy Inadequate liver and renal function with liver transaminases 3x the upper limit of normal Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) according to CockcroftGault &lt; 30 mL/min Uncontrolled congestive heart failure Uncontrolled mood disorders Fasting blood glucose &gt;150mg/dL or blood sugar (nonfasting) &gt;200mg/dL if no history of diabetes. Uncontrolled diabetes with HgA1C greater 7% with last evaluation. Seizure disorder Monosodium glutamate (MSG) allergy or soy allergy Life expectancy of shorter than 3 months based on clinical laboratory parameters and the investigator's opinion Uncorrected Vitamin B12 or folate deficiency on last evaluation. Use of over the counter (OTC) supplements other than one multivitamin tablet a day Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>