<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02355080</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a randomized controlled clinical trial in which adults receiving drug abuse treatment will be recruited to participate in a HIV and hepatitis C (HCV) testing study. The purpose of this study is to test the efficacy of two HIV/HCV testing strategies on increasing receipt of test results: (1) on-site bundled rapid HIV/HCV testing (i.e., joint offer of HIV and HCV at the point of encounter), and (2) standard of care for HIV and HCV testing.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Bundled Rapid HIV/HCV Testing Intervention to Increase Receipt of Test Results</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized controlled clinical trial in which adults receiving drug abuse treatment will be recruited to participate in a HIV and hepatitis C (HCV) testing study. The purpose of this study is to test the efficacy of two HIV/HCV testing strategies on increasing receipt of test results: (1) on-site bundled rapid HIV/HCV testing (i.e., joint offer of HIV and HCV at the point of encounter), and (2) standard of care for HIV and HCV testing. Secondary outcomes include linkage to care and HIV and HCV risk behaviors. Participants will complete a baseline assessment to report their demographics, sexual risk behaviors, drug-using risk behaviors, utilization of drug abuse treatment services and will be randomized to one of two groups. At one-month post-randomization, participants will complete a follow-up assessment to determine whether or not they received their HIV or HCV test results. At three months post-randomization, participants will complete a follow-up assessment to assess linkage to care and changes, if any, in their HIV and HCV sexual risk behaviors.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Report being HIV and HCV negative, or report not knowing HIV and HCV status Not have received results of an HIV or HCV test initiated within the last 12 months Able and willing to provide informed consent Seeking or currently receiving drug (excluding alcohol only treatment) abuse treatment services at the participating treatment programs At least 18 years old Able to communicate in English Willing to sign a release form that will allow medical record review (to corroborate selfreports of receipt of test results) Able and willing to provide locator information (contact number and address) for followup surveys</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV</keyword>
</DOC>