<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02355366</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The present study aims to examine the effects of a 4 month, family focused therapy (FFT) intervention on the 1 year course of mood symptoms in offspring of parents with bipolar disorder (BD). The study will also examine the level of expressed emotion among families and how this impacts on FFT treatment outcomes. This study seeks to replicate a previous study by Miklowitz, Schneck, Singh, Taylor, George and colleagues (2013), which demonstrated the efficacy of FFT among BD offspring. Importantly, the present study will introduce biological measures that predict and reflect improvement in symptoms and expressed emotion. These markers reflect stress-related biological systems and include saliva samples to ascertain cortisol, interleukin-6 (IL-6) and salivary alpha amylase (sAA).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Family Focused Therapy for Teens at Risk for Bipolar Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Children of parents with bipolar disorder (BD) have increased risk of developing BD themselves. BD in youth is associated with increased risk for suicidality, psychosis, substance abuse and compromised psychosocial functioning. In addition, offspring of parents with BD have an increased vulnerability for developing other psychopathology (e.g. major depression). At present, research examining early intervention and treatment for this high risk population is limited. However, a recent study in symptomatic youth at risk for BD indicated that participation in a family focused therapy (FFT) intervention led to positive treatment outcomes. The present study aims to examine the effects of FFT in BD offspring in comparison to a brief educational treatment. Specifically, this study will examine whether FFT can have protective effects on individuals' mood symptoms and functioning by targeting the family environment. We will expand upon previous research by also measuring biological markers of stress (i.e., cortisol levels) and changes in family functioning over time. With this knowledge, the results of this study may help to shed light on the importance of early intervention and improve preventative treatment options for youth at high-risk for bipolar disorder.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Englishspeaking males and females of any race/ethnicity 2. 1319 years of age 3. Have at least 1 biological parent who meets diagnostic criteria for bipolar disorder (BD) type I or II, based on the Structured Clinical Interview for DSMIV Axis I Disorders (SCIDI) 4. Adolescent is experiencing current, significant mood symptoms indicated by a psychiatric status rating (PSR) score of 3 5. At least 1 parent/primary caregiver is available to attend sessions. All participants will complete rigorous diagnostic interviews to ensure that they meet these requirements. 1. Unable to provide informed consent (e.g., severe psychosis, developmental delay) 2. Have met the DSMIV criteria (based on the Schedule for Affective Disorders and Schizophrenia for School Age Children, Present and Life Version KSADSPL), for substance dependence in the past 3 months (excluding nicotine dependence) 3. Are victims of current sexual or physical abuse by parents or live among domestic violence 4. For offspring, already meet criteria for bipolar disorder (BD) type I or II.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Offspring</keyword>
	<keyword>significant mood symptoms</keyword>
</DOC>