<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02355028</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of 84 successive days of topically administered LHA510 compared to vehicle in reducing the number of patients requiring intravitreal (IVT) anti-vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) therapy (Lucentis®) for recurrence of active choroidal neovascularization (CNV).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>LHA510 Proof-of-Concept Study as a Maintenance Therapy for Patients With Wet Age-Related Macular Degeneration</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The standard of care for recurrence of active CNV is an IVT injection of an anti-VEGF agent. In this study, recurrence of CNV will be treated exclusively with IVT Lucentis®. On Day -1, patients will receive an IVT Lucentis® injection, and then will be randomized to receive either topical LHA510 ophthalmic suspension or vehicle in a 1:1 ratio.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Wet Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Sign written informed consent form; Wet AMD patient; IVT antiVEGF therapy for at least 6 months and a maximum of 7 years since the 3rd loading dose; BCVA 50 letters (approximate Snellen equivalent 20/100) or better in the study eye; Demonstrate ability to administer eye drops (patient or caregiver); CNV recently demonstrated high need for frequent antiVEGF therapy and sustained functional and clear anatomical response in the study eye; Other protocolspecified inclusion criteria may apply. Any active ocular or periocular infection or intraocular inflammation; Current or history of macular or retinal disease (if visually significant) other than wet AMD in the study eye; Current clinically significant vitreous hemorrhage or history of rhegmatogenous retinal detachment affecting the macula in the study eye; History of hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs or clinically relevant sensitivity to fluorescein dye or povidone iodine; Women of childbearing potential; History of a medical condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would preclude scheduled study visits, completion of the study or a safe administration of investigational product; Other protocolspecified exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>LHA510</keyword>
	<keyword>PoC</keyword>
	<keyword>Age-related macular degeneration</keyword>
</DOC>