<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01698268</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study measures the difference in pain after hernia &amp;/or hydrocele repair based on site of local anesthesia injection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Transverse Abdominis Plane (TAP) Block in Children Undergoing Hydrocelectomy and/or Hernia Repair Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This single-center, prospective, single blind, randomized study will enroll 50 subjects who are scheduled for elective hydrocelectomy and/or hernia repair. At Beaumont Health System, post-operative pain management in children is managed either via oral/parenteral opiates and opiate adjuncts, surgeon-administered field blocks (instillation of local anesthetics in the general area of incision), or via regional techniques (spinal, epidural, or peripheral nerve blocks). We have designed this study to determine if there is improved qualitative and quantitative post-operative pain control in patients receiving TAP block versus intraoperative peri-incisional, surgeon administered field block. Once informed consent has been given, each patient will be randomized (like flip of the coin) to either Transverse Abdominis Plane Block (TAP Block)or surgeon administered anesthesia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hernia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hernia, Inguinal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children 28 years of age Elective inguinal hernia repair, inguinal hernia repair with peritoneoscopy and/or hydrocelectomy to be performed in the Center for Children's Surgery, Beaumont Hospital, Royal Oak American Society of Anesthesiologists physical status classification 1 and 2 (patients that have either no systemic illness, or mild systemic disease that is well controlled, eg. mild asthma) History of allergy to study medications Enrollment in concurrent research study Pregnant patients* Students/trainees/staff* Mentally disabled/cognitively impaired*</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>8 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>