<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00746239</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Almost 80% of panic disorder patients report difficulty sleeping. Sleep disturbances in turn may exacerbate underlying anxiety/panic attacks. Moreover, individuals with insomnia (sleep disturbance) are at higher risk of developing a new anxiety disorder. Therefore it is expected that improving sleep quality with medications along with other medications to treat anxiety component of panic disorder might be helpful. However, there is lack of pharmacological studies examining the effects of improving sleep disturbances with medications in panic disorder patients, which is a critical problem for providing optimal care to these patients. The objective of this proposal is to determine the effects of ramelteon (FDA approved for insomnia) on sleep disturbances in Panic disorder patients who are on escitalopram for underlying anxiety.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ramelteon for Sleep Initiation Insomnia in Individuals With Panic Disorder Who Are Also on Escitalopram for Anxiety</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Panic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citalopram</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexetimide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1) Clinical diagnosis of panic disorder 2) Difficulty initiating sleep (subjective sleep latency (SL) of &gt;30 minutes) for at least 3 times per week in the preceding month. 1)Patients meeting DSMIV criteria (as determined by MINI) for a current anxiety disorder (other than panic disorder), or current major depressive disorder that is considered by the investigator to be primary (i.e., causing a higher degree of distress or impairment than panic disorder)., Patients with past history of DSMIV anxiety disorders or depressive disorder will not be excluded. 2) Patients with current psychotic disorder, current bipolar disorder, or substance use disorder (except nicotine dependence) or Subjects with significant suicide risk. 3) Candidates with known sensitivity to any selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRI) will be excluded. 4) CNS diseases: Candidates with seizure disorder (other than febrile seizure in early childhood), a history of other neurological disorder, and head trauma will be excluded. 5) Cardiovascular and respiratory diseases: Candidates with hypertension (systolic &gt;130; diastolic &gt; 85), arrhythmias, coronary artery disease, cardiac pacemakers, COPD, asthma, and other pulmonary diseases will be excluded. 6) Primary sleep disorders: Candidates with breathing related sleep disorder, restless leg syndrome, circadian rhythm sleep disorders, narcolepsy, and other major primary sleep disorders will be excluded. 7) Systemic diseases: Candidates with other medical problems, such as endocrinopathies, renal or hepatic failure, autoimmune diseases involving the CNS, obesity (BMI &gt; 30 kg/m2), or a history of pheochromocytoma will not be eligible. 8) Consumption of greater than 720 mgs. of caffeine daily. 9) History of shift work (11 PM to 7 AM) in the past 6 months. 10) Reproductive status: Women candidates who are pregnant (based on urine test) are not eligible. Women of child bearing age will be on birth control methods during the study period. 11) Individuals with personality, behavior, or medical disorders likely to interfere with study participation.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>insomnia</keyword>
	<keyword>sleep difficulty</keyword>
	<keyword>panic disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>nocturnal panic attacks</keyword>
	<keyword>anxiety</keyword>
</DOC>