<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00746551</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare the efficacy of body iron storage replenishment between low dose intravenous iron and oral iron in late pregnancy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intravenous Versus Oral Iron in Late Pregnancy: Results of Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Despite routine antenatal oral iron supplementation, the prevalence of iron deficiency anemia (IDA) in the 3rd trimester of pregnancy in developing countries remains high. Apparently, intravenous iron sucrose appears to be safe and efficient in treating within a short period. From literature review, no study of intravenous iron for IDA treatment has been carried out in the third trimester of pregnancy. This research aims to compare the efficacy of body iron storage replenishment at 3 weeks as labor may take place at this point in some women. In this study,500 mg intravenous iron has been given weekly instead of every other day for the sake of patient's convenience in the hope that parenteral iron may become another alternative for treatment of pregnant women with iron deficiency anemia who have difficulties or failures with oral iron.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Iron-Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pregnancy Complications</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ferrous fumarate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ferric oxide, saccharated</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age 1845 years old 2. Singleton pregnancy at 32 weeks gestation 3. Having anemia in the third trimester according to World Health Organization, namely, with a hemoglobin level of &lt; 11 g/dL or hematocrit of &lt; 33% 4. Having no underlying disease such as hypertension, gestational diabetes mellitus, heart disease, peptic ulcer, etc. 5. Having no history of allergy to iron containing medication 6. Having no history or other allergic conditions or asthma 7. Having no thalassemia disease, for examples: B thalassemia major, hemoglobin E/ B thalassemia, homozygous hemoglobin E, Hemoglobin H, AE Bart disease, and EF Bart disease. Pregnant women who have iron deficiency anemia and are thalassemia carriers such as Athalassemia 1, Bthalassemia, or less severe Hb E/ B thalassemia are able to enter the study. 8. Having no history of bleeding tendency 9. Having no history of blood transfusion within the prior 120 days 10. Having no history of delivery before 36 weeks gestation 11. Giving consent and having signed the consent form for this study 1. Stool exam revealed parasitic infestation 2. Creactive protein &gt; 3 mg/L 3. Serum ferritin &gt; 15 mcg/L</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>iron deficiency anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>third trimester</keyword>
	<keyword>intravenous iron</keyword>
	<keyword>efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>a randomized trial</keyword>
	<keyword>Female</keyword>
	<keyword>Ferric Compounds/therapeutic use*</keyword>
	<keyword>Infusions, Intravenous</keyword>
	<keyword>Hematologic/therapy*</keyword>
</DOC>