<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01610388</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This first time in human (FTIH) study will be the first administration of GSK1322322 as an intravenous formulation and will investigate safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics in healthy subjects. One cohort of subjects will undergo bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) for determination of GSK1322322 concentrations in lung with simultaneous comparison to plasma concentrations to evaluate drug penetration in the lung. The study will evaluate the absolute bioavailability of an oral tablet formulation as compared to the IV formulation.In addition, Amendment 01 will enable the investigation of an improved IV formulation (GSK1322322J mesylate salt) in an additional repeat dosing cohort and the supra-therapeutic cohort.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Investigate the Safety, Tolerability and Pharmacokinetics of Oral and Intravenous GSK1322322 in Healthy Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Bacterial Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy as determined by a responsible and experienced physician, based on a medical evaluation including [medical history, physical examination, laboratory tests and ECGs. A subject with a clinical abnormality or laboratory parameters outside the reference range for the population being studied may be included at the discretion of the Investigator only if the finding is unlikely to introduce additional risk factors and will not interfere with the study procedures. Male or female between 18 and 65 years of age inclusive, at the time of signing the informed consent. A female subject is eligible to participate if she is of: Nonchildbearing potential defined as premenopausal females with a documented tubal ligation or hysterectomy; or postmenopausal defined as 12 months of spontaneous amenorrhea Male subjects with female partners of childbearing potential must agree to use one of the contraception methods listed in the protocol. This criterion must be followed from the time of the first dose of study medication until the final follow up visit. Body weight greater than or equal to 50 kilograms and body mass index (BMI) between 18.529.9 (inclusive). Capable of giving written informed consent, which includes compliance with the requirements and restrictions listed in the consent form. QTcB less than 450 millisecond (msec); or QTcB less than 480 msec in subjects with Bundle Branch Block on Screening ECG A positive prestudy Hepatitis B surface antigen or positive Hepatitis C antibody result within 3 months of screening Current or chronic history of liver disease, or known hepatic or biliary abnormalities (with the exception of Gilbert's syndrome or asymptomatic gallstones). Contraindications to bronchoalveolar lavage including hypercapnia greater than 50 mm Hg, refractory hypoxemia, reactive airway disease or asthma, unstable angina or acute myocardial infarction in the last 6 months, heart failure, and severe hemostatic alterations (Cohort C only). A positive prestudy drug/alcohol screen. A positive test for HIV antibody. History of regular alcohol consumption within 6 months of the study The subject has participated in a clinical trial and has received an investigational product within the following time period prior to the first dosing day in the current study: 30 days, 5 halflives or twice the duration of the biological effect of the investigational product (whichever is longer). Exposure to more than four new chemical entities within 12 months prior to the first dosing day. Use of prescription or nonprescription drugs, including vitamins, herbal and dietary supplements (including St John's Wort) within 7 days (or 14 days if the drug is a potential enzyme inducer) or 5 halflives (whichever is longer) prior to the first dose of study medication, and within 5 days following discontinuation of GSK1322322 (for sensitive and narrow therapeutic index CYP3A4 substrates), unless in the opinion of the Investigator and GSK Medical Monitor the medication will not interfere with the study procedures or compromise subject safety. Use of antacids, H2 blockers, proton pump inhibitors, vitamins, and iron supplements within 7 days prior to the first dose of study medication and for the duration of the trial, including followup. History of sensitivity to any of the study medications, or components thereof or a history of drug or other allergy that, in the opinion of the investigator or GSK Medical Monitor, contraindicates their participation. History of sensitivity to medications used in study, ie Atropine, Midazolam, Fentanyl, Lidocaine, Codeine (Cohort C only) that, in the opinion of the investigator or GSK Medical Monitor, contraindicates their participation. Where participation in the study would result in donation of blood or blood products in excess of 500 milliliters within a 56 day period. Pregnant females as determined by positive [serum or urine] test at screening or prior to dosing. Lactating females. Unwillingness or inability to follow the procedures outlined in the protocol. Subject is mentally or legally incapacitated. History of sensitivity to heparin or heparininduced thrombocytopenia. Urinary cotinine levels indicative of smoking or history or regular use of tobacco or nicotinecontaining products within 6 months prior to screening. Consumption of red wine, seville oranges, grapefruit or grapefruit juice [and/or pummelos, exotic citrus fruits, grapefruit hybrids or fruit juices] from 7 days prior to the first dose of study medication. Exclusion criteria for screening ECG (a single repeat is allowed for eligibility determination): Heart rate: males less than 45 and greater than 100 beats per minute (bpm) and females less than 50 and greater than 100bpm. PR interval less than 120 and greater than 220msec, QRS duration less than 70 and greater than 120 msec, and QTcB greater than 450msec. Evidence of previous myocardial infarction (does not include ST segment changes associated with repolarization). Any conduction abnormality (including but not specific to left or right complete bundle branch block, AV block [2nd degree or higher], Wolf Parkinson White [WPW] syndrome), sinus pauses&gt; 3 seconds, nonsustained or sustained ventricular tachycardia (greater than or equal to 3 consecutive ventricular ectopic beats) or any significant arrhythmia which, in the opinion of the principal investigator and GSK medical monitor, will interfere with the safety of the individual subject.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>healthy subjects</keyword>
	<keyword>double-blind</keyword>
	<keyword>FTIH</keyword>
	<keyword>dose-escalation</keyword>
	<keyword>absolute bioavailability</keyword>
	<keyword>GSK1322322</keyword>
	<keyword>BAL</keyword>
</DOC>