<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02801253</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Management of prosthetic joint infections (PJI) is a challenging task. These infections include different clinical and microbiological settings calling upon various treatment strategies according to infection type (acute or chronic), bone quality, the involved micro-organism and the patient's general condition and willing. Treatment of PJI combines surgery and prolonged antibiotic therapy. In some patients with a high operative risk prolonged suppressive antibiotic therapy can be used. Lack of large prospective studies motivated the conception of this cohort with a long term follow up, regardless to PJI management procedures.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cohort of Prosthetic Joint Infections</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Large prospective cohort study in a French referral center for bone and joint infections. Population - all patients who consented to participate in the study with PJI treated with: - debridement-synovectomy for acute infection - with one-stage, two-stage exchange arthroplasty for chronic infection - other procedures (complete removal of the prosthesis) and antibiotic therapy - patients (non-operated or operated) receiving prolonged suppressive antibiotic therapy Outcome: - Follow-up at least 2 years - Events monitored: reinfection including relapse and new infection, joint revision for mechanical failure, PJI related or non-related death Study duration: 10 years. Recruitment period: 4 years. Maximal duration of data collection: 6 years. Investigator center: monocenter study. Mean patient inclusion per year: 100 patients per year.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Infectious</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient aged over 18 years old with hip, knee and or shoulder joint prosthesis who consented to participate in the study with: According to musculoskeletal infection society definition: PJI is present when one of the major criteria exists or four out of six minor criteria. Major Criteria: Two positive periprosthetic cultures with phenotypically identical organisms, OR A sinus tract communicating with the joint, OR Minor Criteria: Elevated serum Creactive protein (CRP) AND erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR) Elevated synovial fluid white blood cell (WBC) Elevated synovial fluid polymorphonuclear neutrophil percentage (PMN%) The presence of pus in the joint without known cause Positive histological analysis of periprosthetic tissue A single positive culture Or a PJI which meets the following three criteria: Medical story suggesting prosthetic joint infection. The presence of pain either with or without swelling for more than 3 months unrelated to a mechanical cause. Germ identification in a single sample of fluid aspiration or tissue culture. Or microbial growth in prosthesis sonication fluid culture greater than 50CFU/ml. Patient who does not meet eligibility criteria. Patient lawfully deprived of his liberty. Patient not insured under social security scheme.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>