<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02801357</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the relative exposures of lofexidine and its major metabolites in subjects seeking buprenorphine dose reduction.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Exposures of Lofexidine and Its Major Metabolites in Subjects Seeking Buprenorphine Dose Reduction</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 1, open-label, inpatient study in male and female subjects seeking at least a 4 mg reduction of their buprenorphine maintenance dose. The purpose of this study is to assess the relative exposures of lofexidine and its 3 major metabolites in subjects tapering from buprenorphine maintenance treatment. Lofexidine is an alpha-2 adrenergic agonist under development for the treatment of acute withdrawal from short-acting opioids.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Behavior, Addictive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Opioid-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Substance Withdrawal Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Buprenorphine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lofexidine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clonidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have current dependency such that the subject is maintained on a daily dose between 8 and 24 mg of buprenorphine and is seeking reduction of their buprenorphine dose by at least 4 mg. Urine toxicology screen positive for buprenorphine at Screening. Agree to collection of blood samples for genotyping of CYP2D6 metabolizer status. If female and of childbearing potential, subject must have been using birth control for at least 30 days and must agree to use an acceptable form of birth control through at least 30 days after the last dose of study drug. If male, must agree to use an acceptable form of birth control throughout the entire study period and for 90 days after the last dose of study drug. Must not donate sperm for 90 days after the last dose of study drug. Be a female subject who is pregnant or lactating. Have a very serious medical illness not under control. Have participated in an investigational drug study within the past 30 days. Received any drugs that are known strong, moderate or weak inhibitors of cytochrome P450 (CYP) enzymes CYP1A2, CYP2C19, or CYP2D6, within 14 days or 5 halflives (whichever is more) before Day 1. Abnormal cardiovascular exam at Screening. Subjects requiring the following will be excluded: Tricyclic antidepressants, which may reduce the efficacy of imidazoline derivatives; Betareceptor blockers, to avoid the risk of excessive bradycardia.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>substance withdrawal syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>opiate addiction</keyword>
	<keyword>opiate dependence</keyword>
	<keyword>opioid withdrawal syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>buprenorphine</keyword>
</DOC>