<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01453192</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to evaluate the incidence of acute renal graft rejection 6 months after transplantation in HIV-infected patients under three antiretroviral drugs regimen including Raltegravir.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Renal Transplantation and Raltegravir in HIV-Infected Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Antiretroviral treatment of HIV-1 Infection might interact with immunosuppressive treatments which increase rejection of renal graft incidence. In addition HIV infection may be modified together with cardiovascular risk. Patients participating to this study will receive after transplantation antiretroviral regimen including Raltegravir. Raltegravir treatment does not interact with immunosuppressive drugs and thus seems to be the treatment of choice to be associated with immunosuppressive drugs.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Raltegravir Potassium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Registration on the French national renal transplantation waiting list (Biomedicines Agency) for a living or cadaveric donor organ HIV1infected patients treated by a threedrug ARV regimen Immunovirologic criteria at renal transplantation: undetectable viral load (&lt;50 copies/mL) and CD4 &gt;200/mm3 for at least three months on stable ARV Age &gt;18 years and &lt;70 years Effective contraception for women Written informed consent Patient with social security coverage Permanent: Hepatic cirrhosis Serious psychiatric illness history EBV or HHV8 lymphoproliferation (lymphoma, systemic Kaposi's sarcoma or multifocal Castleman's disease) History of PML HTLV1 seropositivity Severe pulmonary or cardiovascular disease with poor shortterm vital prognosis Patient with AgHBs+ History of cryptosporidiosis History of fungal infection with multi resistant fungi not likely to respond to oral antifungal therapy Impossibility or refusal of Raltegravir switch, decision made by doctor or patient Temporary: Recent malignancy (between 2 and 5 years according to type) HPVrelated cervical or anal disease: carcinoma in situ, AIN III, CIN III in remission for less than three years Active infection HCV infection (PCRpositive)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Raltegravir</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV-1</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute renal graft rejection</keyword>
</DOC>