<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01453231</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Obesity is a chronic disease now considered a major public health concern in the global context, as it causes or exacerbates many diseases limitations in providing quality of life and higher treatment costs. The increase in the number of patients undergoing bariatric surgery and the excess skin and subcutaneous tissue adjacent to slimming collaborate in the search for growth by plastic surgery. Currently several techniques of thighplasty has been submitted but no studies were found that evaluated the characteristic clinical and emotional resulting from this procedure. This study has as a goal to evaluate the body image and quality of life in women submitted to thighplasty.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Quality of Life and Body Image in Women Underwent Thighplasty</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The patients have been evaluated for two different questionnaires, the Body Dysmorphic Disorder Examination (BDDE) and Impact Weight on Quality of Life - Lite (IWQoL-Lite). The sample consists of 50 patients with the desire to undergo to the thighplasty. However 25 are from study group and 25 control group. Just the study group was undergoing plastic surgery. The questionnaires have applied by signing the consent form, after 3 and 6 months both groups. This study is a clinical trial, control, primary, longitudinal, no random, analytical, held in a single center.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>abdominoplasty previous control of systemic disease Adults at the age of 35 and 50 years old had reached massive weight loss less by bariatric surgery or similar than 30 kg/m2 for a minimum of 12 months or more. gender: female For control group: it supposed to be on the waiting list for thighplasty For study group:they are supposed to be scheduled for thighplasty illiterate pregnant women and/or women who have been nursing for one year or less noncontroled of systemic disease</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>bariatric surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>plastic surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>thigh</keyword>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>body image</keyword>
	<keyword>quality of life</keyword>
</DOC>