<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02493517</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose is to compare the efficacy and safety of lanreotide autogel® 60mg, 90mg or 120mg with lanreotide 40mg PR in subjects with active acromegaly.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Lanreotide Autogel® 60, 90 or 120 mg With Lanreotide 40 mg Prolonged Release (PR) in Acromegaly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Acromegaly</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lanreotide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiopeptin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Somatostatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject has active acromegaly defined as elevated GH and IGF1 levels (measured at a central laboratory) as outlined below: A serum level for IGF1 ≥1.3 x upper limit of normal range (ULN) during the screening period (applicable to both treatment naïve subjects and subjects who have stopped treatment and undergone a washout period prior to Visit 1(Week 4). Subjects must have mean serum GH concentration ≥2.5 μg/L in a GH cycle (5 samples taken at 0, 30, 60, 90 and 120 minutes) during the screening period. The subject has undergone surgical removal of an adenoma for acromegaly at least 3 months prior to Screening, or is likely to require pituitary surgery in the future but not before completing at least 32 weeks of study treatment plus an additional follow up of 8 weeks for subjects taking part in the pharmacokinetics (PK) extension, or for whom pituitary surgery is not an option (due to contraindications, refusal etc.) and is therefore never likely to undergo pituitary surgery. The subject has been treated with radiotherapy within 10 years prior to Screening. The subject has been treated with lanreotide Autogel, lanreotide PR, pegvisomant, cabergoline or octreotide LAR within 3 months of Screening or octreotide immediate release (IR) or bromocriptin within 2 weeks of Screening. The subject has a history of or currently presents with clinically significant ventricular or atrial dysrhythmias ≥Grade 2, using the National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI CTCAE) v4.0. The subject has uncontrolled diabetes (glycosylated haemoglobin (HbA1c) &gt;8.5%).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>