<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02493790</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) is a respiratory disease starting point characterized by multiple systemic effects as cognitive dysfunction. This one seems to have an impact in activity daily living, considered mainly as a cognitive-motor dual task situations. Yet to date, no study has specifically focused in the cognitive-motor performance in patients with COPD or on the effects during a rehabilitation program. The main objective of this work was to evaluate the impact of cognitive dysfunction in COPD, comparing performance between COPD patients and healthy subjects in a single and dual task cognitive-motor situation. The secondary objective was to assess the impact of a rehabilitation program on these performances.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cognitive Dysfunction in COPD Patients : Role in the Performance of Cognitive-motor Dual Task Situation?</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cognition Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female about 40 to 80 years old COPD patient (Tiffeneau &lt;70%); stage moderate to severe (Stage 2,3 and 4) with or without oxygen therapy (&gt;15h/day) Written and informed consent of the subject Authorization to physical activity referring doctor in the clinic Comorbidities no dominating Subject with neurological pathology, cognitive or psychiatric Subject with pain and / or plantar injuries Subject has a prosthetic knee and / or hip. Subject requiring walking aid (cane, walker, etc.)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cognitive dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Activity of Daily Living</keyword>
	<keyword>interference</keyword>
	<keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>cognitive-motor dual task</keyword>
</DOC>