<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02393378</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of namilumab in combination with existing methotrexate (MTX) over 24 weeks in patients with moderate to severe early rheumatoid arthritis (RA), diagnosed within 6 months and inadequately controlled by MTX alone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Namilumab vs Adalimumab in Participants With Moderate to Severe Early Rheumatoid Arthritis Inadequately Responding to Methotrexate</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The drug being investigated in this study is Namilumab for the treatment of moderate to severe Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA). This study will evaluate the efficacy and safety of namilumab in participants diagnosed with RA within 6 months of entry into the study. The study will enroll approximately 36 participants, who will be randomly assigned in a 2:1 ratio to the following open label treatment groups: - Namilumab 300 mg subcutaneous (SC) administered at Week 0 followed thereafter by 150 mg SC administered at Weeks 2 through 22 (at the intervals specified in the protocol) as an add-on to weekly existing stable methotrexate (MTX) and folic acid: 24 subjects. - Active control, adalimumab 40 mg SC administered at Weeks 0 through 22 (at the intervals specified in the protocol) as an add-on to weekly existing stable MTX and folic acid: 12 participants. Sensitive imaging techniques, including Dynamic Contrast Enhanced Magnetic Resonance Imaging (DCE-MRI), will be used to measure changes in the dominant hand and the wrist. This multi-center trial will be conducted in Europe. The overall time to participate in this study is a maximum of 44 weeks, including follow-up period. Participants will make 16 visits to the site and will be followed up by telephone twice after end of treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin B Complex</mesh_term>
	<criteria>In the opinion of the investigator, the participant is capable of understanding and complying with protocol requirements. The participant or, when applicable, the participant's legally acceptable representative signs and dates a written, informed consent form and any required privacy authorization prior to the initiation of any study procedures. Is male or female and aged 18 years, or above. Diagnosed with adult onset RA as defined by the 2010 ACR/The European League Against Rheumatism criteria for the classification of RA within 6 months prior to Screening Visit; Has active disease defined as: 1. swollen joint count ≥4 and tender joint count ≥4 (referred to the 28 jointcount system) at Screening and Baseline Visits, and 2. Creactive protein ≥4.3 mg/L and erythrocyte sedimentation rate ≥28 mm/hr at Baseline Visits, and 3. imaging (ultrasound power doppler) evidence of moderate to severe inflammation of at least 1 joint of the dominant hand MCP and/or wrist) at Screening and Baseline Visits. A male participant who is nonsterilized and sexually active with a female partner of childbearing potential agrees to use adequate contraception from signing of informed consent throughout the duration of the study until the end of the safety follow up (18 weeks after last dose). A female participant of childbearing potential who is sexually active with a nonsterilized male partner agrees to use routinely adequate contraception from signing of informed consent throughout the duration of the study until the end of the safety follow up (18 weeks after last dose). Is receiving current treatment with MTX for RA: Received MTX for at least 3 months prior to the Screening Visit, AND Received treatment with MTX ≥15 to 25 mg/week at a stable dose via the same route of administration and formulation for at least 8 weeks prior to the Baseline Visit, OR Participants on a stable dose for at least 8 weeks of MTX of ≥7.5 mg/week, if the MTX dose has been reduced for reasons of documented intolerance to MTX. Is willing to continue or initiate treatment with oral folic acid (at least 5 mg/week) or equivalent and be treated during the entire trial (mandatory comedication for MTX treatment). Has a posterior, anterior, and lateral chest xray obtained within the last 3 months before Screening or at the Screening visit without any signs of clinically significant pulmonary disease. Participants &lt;18 years of age or less than the legal adult age in the country of the study site, whichever is higher. Has received any investigational compound within 30 days, or within 5 half lives of the compound (whichever is the longer) prior to the Screening Visit, or is participating or plans to participate in any other clinical trial during this study. Has received biologic diseasemodifying antirheumatic drugs for the treatment of RA. Have a history of or currently inflammatory joint disease other than RA (eg, gout, reactive arthritis, psoriatic arthritis, seronegative spondyloarthropathy, or Lyme disease) or other systemic autoimmune disorder (eg, systemic lupus erythematosus, inflammatory bowel disease, scleroderma, inflammatory myopathy, mixed connective tissue disease, or other overlap syndrome). Has any majorsystemic features of RA, for example, Felty's syndrome, vasculitis, or interstitial fibrosis of the lungs. Diagnosed with primary fibromyalgia that would make it difficult to appropriately assess RA activity for the purposes of this study or a diagnosis of any systemic inflammatory condition other than RA. Has a history of juvenile idiopathic arthritis or RA onset prior to age 16 years. Required to take excluded medications Not willing to take folic/folinic acid (as part of MTX regimen, according to countryspecific practices) in order to minimize toxicity. Has an underlying condition that predisposes to infections (eg, immunodeficiency, poorly controlled diabetes history, splenectomy). Has a history of clinically significant interstitial lung disease, for example, history of chronic or recurrent pulmonary infection where macrophages are important for the clearance of the infection, for example, pneumocystis carinii pneumonia, allergic bronchopulmonary aspergillosis, nocardia infections, Actinomyces infection. Presence or history of active tuberculosis (TB) or latent TB infection, where no antiTB treatment has been given or where successful completion of an appropriate course of antiTB therapy cannot be documented. A positive QuantiFERONTB Gold test and/or evidence of active or latent TB by chest xray at Screening Visit, not accompanied by initiation of an approved regimen of antiTB therapy at least 12 months prior to the Baseline Visit. Has a known history of infection with hepatitis B virus, hepatitis C virus, or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), or has serological findings at the Screening Visit which indicate active or latent hepatitis B, hepatitis C or HIV infection. Has a clinically relevant decrease in lung function at Screening, as defined by an oxygen saturation as measured by pulse oximetry (SpO2) &lt;94% at rest. Has evidence of clinically significant respiratory disease on the basis of review the data from subjects' respiratory assessments including chest xray, pulmonary function test (forced expiratory volume in 1 second [FEV1] and forced vital capacity [FVC]) by spirometry performed at Screening). The subjects must have SpO2 ≥94%, FEV1 and/or FVC ≥60% of predicted values at Screening or at Baseline and no uncontrolled lung disease. Participant's treatment that has been modified to control lung disease within 24 weeks prior to Screening is exclusionary. Has a history of severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and/or history of severe COPD exacerbation(s), or a history of asthma with exacerbations requiring hospitalization, within the last 12 months prior to the Screening Visit. Has an estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) of less than 60 mL/min/1.73m2.History of MTXassociated lung toxicity. Has a history or evidence of a clinically significant disorder (including but not limited to cardiopulmonary, oncologic, renal, metabolic, hematologic or psychiatric), condition or disease that, in the opinion of the investigator and Takeda physician, would pose a risk to subject safety or interfere with the study evaluation, procedures or completion. Has any significant cardiac disease (eg, coronary artery disease with unstable angina, coronary heart failure New York Heart Association Class III and IV, familial long QT syndrome). Has a history of cancer within the last 10 years except for basal cell or squamous cell carcinomas of the skin or in situ carcinoma of the cervix treated and considered cured. Has a severe psychiatric or neurological disorder. If female, the participant is pregnant or lactating or intends to become pregnant before, during, or within 18 weeks after the last treatment visit; or intends to donate ova during such time periods. If male, the participant intends to donate sperm during or within 18 weeks after the last treatment visit.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy</keyword>
</DOC>