<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02393248</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study will be to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and pharmacological activity of INCB054828 in subjects with advanced malignancies. This study will have three parts, dose escalation (Part 1), dose expansion (Part 2) and combination therapy (Part 3).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Open-Label, Dose-Escalation Study of INCB054828 in Subjects With Advanced Malignancies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholangiocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male or female subjects, age 18 years or older on day of signing consent 2. Part 1: Any advanced solid tumor malignancy; Part 2: Subjects with squamous nonsmall cell lung cancer, cholangiocarcinoma/gastric cancer, urothelial cancer, breast/endometrial cancer, multiple myeloma, or MPNs that have a tumor or malignancy that has been evaluated and confirmed to harbor genetic alterations in FGF or FGFR genes. A subject's fibroblast growth factor (FGF) or fibroblast growth factor receptor (FGFR) alteration may be based on local or central laboratory results. Part 3: Dose finding: subjects with solid tumor malignancies who qualify for combo therapy; doseexpansion: FGF/FGFR+ subjects qualified to receive combo therapy 3. Has progressed after prior therapy and there is no further effective standard anticancer therapy available (including subject refuses or is intolerant) 4. Life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks 5. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status: Part 1: 0 or 1 Part 2 and 3: 0, 1, or 2 1. Treatment with other investigational study drug for any indication for any reason, or receipt of anticancer medications within 21 days or 5 halflives before first dose of study drug 2. Prior receipt of a selective FGFR inhibitor 3. History of a calcium/phosphate homeostasis disorder 4. History and/or current evidence of ectopic mineralization/calcification 5. Current evidence of corneal disorder/keratopathy 6. Has a history or presence of inadequate liver, renal, hematopoietic and/or cardiac function parameters outside protocoldefined range 7. Prior radiotherapy within 2 weeks of study treatment</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>alterations in FGF or FGFR</keyword>
	<keyword>squamous non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>gastric cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>urothelial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>endometrial cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>multiple myeloma</keyword>
	<keyword>MPN</keyword>
</DOC>