<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02774447</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to investigate if day-case closure of ileostomy is feasible and safe.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Day-Case Closure of Loop Ileostomy in Rectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>For all patients that match the inclusion criteria a registration-protocol is completed. Then the patients are operated and a surgery-protocol is completed. The patients are observed for maximum 24 h and discharged if they meet the discharge-criteria. 30 days post-operative the investigators do a follow-up of complications.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Rectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adults not older than 80 planed for closure of ileostomy The patient should not have had the ileostomy for more than 1 year Informed written consent should be given The patient should have a phone Should have an adult supervision at home for the first 24 hours after discharge American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) classification 12 ASA classification 3 and above The preoperative investigation have shown anastomosis leakage or stricture Dementia or other cognitive dysfunction The need of an interpreter Patients assessed not being able to manage themselves at home postoperative Insulin treated diabetes Coagulopathy Other organ dysfunction Bleeding more than 300 ml If converted to laparatomy Other intraoperative difficulties leading to suspected increased risk of complication Discharge criteria: Stable vital parameters regarding circulation and respiration No sign of bleeding Pain relief possible through per oral administration Emptied urinary bladder Able to maintain per oral nutrition Mobilization possible Obtained oral and written information about symptoms of sepsis and bowel obstruction Obtained telephone number of a contactnurse Obtained time for woundinspection at the surgical unit</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>