<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01050426</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose is to assess the overall survival of patients receiving either UFT/LV + radiotherapy (RT) or UFT/LV + Cetuximab + RT after neo-adjuvant chemotherapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Study of UFT/Leucovorin, Radiotherapy With or Without Cetuximab Following Induction Gemcitabine Plus Capecitabine in Patients With Locally Advanced Pancreatic Cancer (PERU)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Locally advanced pancreatic cancer carries a poor prognosis with no survival advantage of CRT over chemotherapy alone. 4 Phase II- III studies patients without disease progression after 3 months of systemic chemotherapy and CRT had a longer survival than those continuing on chemotherapy. Therefore chemotherapy followed by CRT may be a better approach. Also the effect of blocking EGFR will be evaluated in locally advanced pancreatic cancer. Gemcitabine and capecitabine combination will be used as neo-adjuvant chemotherapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leucovorin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt;18 Histological or cytological diagnosis of adeno or undifferentiated nonsmall cell carcinoma of pancreas. Considered to be unresectable based on following: extensive peripancreatic lymph node involvement, encasement or occlusion of the SMV or SMV/portal vein confluence, direct involvement of SMA, coeliac axis, inferior vena cava or aorta. Performance status 02 No evidence of metastatic disease as determined by CT scan/ other investigations Adequate bone marrow function with platelets&gt;100^9/l; WBC&gt;3x10^9/l;neutrophils&gt; 1.5x10^9/l Serum bilirubin ,1.5 x ULN and transaminases &lt; 2.5 x ULN Calculated/measured GFR &gt;50ml/min No concurrent uncontrolled medical condition No active malignant disease other than nonmelanotic skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the uterine cervix over the last 10 years Life expectancy &gt; 3months Adequate contraceptive precautions Informed written consent medical or psychiatric conditions that compromise the patient's ability to give informed consent Presence of met. disease Concurrent uncontrolled medical conditions Any previous chemo/RT or any investigational treatment for advanced pancreatic cancer. Adjuvant chemo + fluoropyrimidine or gemcitabine within 12months of trial entry Adjuvant RT with/without chemo for pancreatic cancer. Pregnancy/breast feeding Patients with known malabsorption syndromes ro a lack of physical treatment of the upper GI tract. Patients with a known hypersensitivity to 5FU or with a DPD deficiency. Clinically significant CVD</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>