<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02385175</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Eustachian tube links the middle ear to the back of the nose and is designed to open to allow the pressure in the air-filled middle ear to be equal to external (atmospheric) pressure. In some people this system fails to work properly leading to abnormal pressure in the middle ear, and complications such as middle ear fluid ('glue ear') or damage to the ear drum. The abnormal function of the Eustachian tube is called 'Eustachian tube dysfunction'. An affected person may feel pressure, pain or other symptoms in their ear, and their hearing can be temporarily or permanently reduced. This study is designed to find out which of a number of simple tests is best at detecting if the Eustachian tube is performing normally. Both patient-completed questionnaires and clinical tests using specialist machines will be compared as a way of diagnosing Eustachian tube dysfunction. A group of adults aged 18 and above, and children aged 5-17 years with normal ears, and a similar group of people that are already known to have Eustachian tube dysfunction, will both take six different tests and complete four different questionnaires. The differences in the results between the group with ETD and the healthy group will be compared. The results for each test or questionnaire will be compared to see which is best at telling the healthy and Eustachian tube function groups apart, and therefore at diagnosing Eustachian tube dysfunction. The investigators will also look to see if a combination of one or more of the tests or questionnaires is best at diagnosing the disease. The results of this study hope to provide a test or combination of tests that can be used on a daily basis by ENT doctors. The assessment technique would also be helpful in researching and comparing new treatments for ETD.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Accuracy of Tests of Eustachian Tube Function</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Cases: Adults or children diagnosed with ETD: Patients will be assessed on a 'per ear' basis, with some patients being recruited bilaterally, and others only unilaterally. Inclusion will be based on expert assessment. 1. Children with middle ear effusion (or ventilation tube in situ for effusion), tympanic membrane retraction pockets, tympanic membrane perforations, recurrent acute otitis media. 2. Adult patients with otological disease caused by ETD middle ear effusion (or ventilation tube in situ for effusion), tympanic membrane retraction pockets, tympanic membrane perforations, cholesteatoma. 3. Adult patients with symptoms consistent with ETD. Controls: Separate adult and child control groups will be recruited. Controls will be a mix of otologically healthy individuals presenting to clinic for an unrelated issue (e.g. thyroid disease) and patients with an otological disorder not associated with ETD (e.g. Sensorineural hearing loss, Otosclerosis, Meniere's, Labyrinthitis, BPPV). Controls will be screened for ETD prior to inclusion. Cases: Current upper respiratory tract infection Discharging ear (active chronic suppurative otitis media) Severe bilateral nasal obstruction Nasopharyngeal mass or excised malignancy Radiation therapy to the head and neck Cleft palate or repaired cleft palate Craniofacial syndrome including Down syndrome Ciliary dysmotility syndrome Acute disease/symptom duration &lt;3months Controls, as above plus: No reported current symptoms or history of ETD or middle ear disease No rhinitis or nasal allergic symptoms No nasal polyposis No gastrooesophageal reflux disease or symptoms suggestive of laryngopharyngeal reflux.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Eustachian tube</keyword>
	<keyword>test accuracy</keyword>
	<keyword>clinical test</keyword>
	<keyword>questionnaire</keyword>
</DOC>