<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01748552</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this trial is to evaluate the safety of the study drug in healthy participants and participants with diabetes. It will investigate how much of the study drug gets into the blood stream and how long it takes the body to get rid of it. Information about any side effects that may occur will also be collected. The study consists of two parts. Part A will study healthy participants in up to 3 dosing periods over approximately 6 weeks. Part B will study participants with diabetes in up to 3 dosing periods over approximately 6 weeks.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of LY2922083 in Healthy Participants and Participants With Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>For all participants : Must be a male, or a female who cannot become pregnant, and who is either a healthy participant, or who has type 2 diabetes Have a screening body mass index (BMI) of at least 18.0 kilograms per square meter (kg/m^2) Have blood pressure, pulse rate, blood and urine laboratory test results acceptable for the study For participants with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus (T2DM): Do not have any change to their diabetes treatment (exercise with or without metformin) for at least 4 weeks prior to screening Have a glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) value of greater than or equal to 6% and less than or equal to 11% at screening For all participants : Are currently participating in another clinical study or completed one in the last 30 days Are allergic to LY2922083 or other related drugs Have a history of significant heart, lung, liver, kidney, stomach or brain disease, or have any medical problems which may cause an increased risk during the study Have electrocardiogram (ECG) readings that are not suitable for the study Have a history of hepatitis or jaundice Are infected with hepatitis B Are infected with hepatitis C Are infected with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) Have donated more than 450 mL of blood in the last 3 months or have donated any blood in the last month Have a regular alcohol intake greater than 21 units/week (male), or 14 units/week (female), or are unwilling to stop alcohol as required by the study restrictions (1 unit = 360 mL of beer, or 150 mL of wine, or 45 mL of spirits) Smoke more than 10 cigarettes per day or are not willing to abstain from smoking while at the clinic For participants with T2DM : Have had heart disease or stroke within 6 months before entering the study Have health complications due to poorly controlled diabetes as shown by blood and urine laboratory test results or based on physical examination and medical assessment as determined by the study doctor Have been hospitalized for poor control of diabetes (ketoacidotic episode) in the last 6 months Have used insulin to control diabetes in the last 1 year Show symptoms of high blood sugar e.g. frequent urination, always feeling thirsty, or unexpected weight loss</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>