<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01748630</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: The study aim was to compare the efficacy of dexmedetomidine versus midazolam for sedation during the early postoperative period in children who underwent scoliosis surgery. Methods: We performed a prospective, randomized trial in an intensive care unit (ICU) in a tertiary care center. In this study, 42 patients (American Society of Anesthesiology physical status I and II) who underwent scoliosis surgery were divided into 2 groups according to sedation protocols: group DEX (n = 22) and group MDZ (n = 20). Children (12-18 years) requiring mechanical ventilation underwent a continuous infusion of either dexmedetomidine (group DEX; starting dose, 0.4 μg•kg-1•h-1) or midazolam (group MDZ; starting dose, 0.1 mg•kg-1•h-1) with intermittent fentanyl, as needed. The efficacy of sedation was assessed using the Richmond Agitation Sedation Scale (RASS). Quality of pain relief was measured using the Numeric Visual Analog Scale (NVAS). During the arousal assessment, delirium was determined in patients in the RASS range of -2 to +1 using the Confusion Assessment Method for the ICU (CAM-ICU). Fentanyl consumption, incidence of delirium, NVAS scores, and hemodynamics were recorded postoperatively at 2, 4, 6, and 24 h in the ICU.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Dexmedetomidine on the Postoperative Experience in Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Midazolam</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>admittance to the ICU and a requirement of mechanical ventilation with an endotracheal tube. Patients who had a history of allergies to midazolam and/or dexmedetomidine; delirium, developmental delay, or mental retardation, as reported by parents; an American Society of Anesthesiologists classification greater than III; any known previous reactions to anesthesia; or a history of asthma or an anticipated difficult airway and concomitant disease (neuromuscular scoliosis or neurodegenerative disease) were excluded from the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>scoliosis, sedation, children, fentanyl consumption, pain</keyword>
</DOC>