<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01748097</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The investigators use bicarbonate injected to an intravenous line and the changes in the exhaled end-tidal carbon dioxide to verify whether the IV line is in the vein or surrounding tissue</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Intravenous Bicarbonate To Verify The Correct Position of IV Catheters in Oncological Patients Oncological Patients Receiving Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The method was proved useful in previous phase I, II studies. Now the investigators move on to assess the method in a phase III study in oncological patients. each patients which will be subjected to intravenous chemotherapy will be eligible ( see also inclusion/exclusion criteria). Once consent obtained the patient will have an IV line placed. each line placed will be categorized by the clinical team into 3 categories: 1. IV in place ready to use for chemotherapy ( good blood return) 2. Doubtful position ( no blood return/ little blood return bu flushes well). 3. IV not in place. Study design Category 1. IV bicarbonate 4.2% 20 cc and NS 20 cc in a randomized fashion Category 2. same as above Category 3. No injections</detailed_description>
	<criteria>age 1880 oncological disease requires intravenous chemotherapy 1. refusal to participate 2. lung disease acute or chronic sPo2 &lt; 92%, PaCO2 &gt; 50 3. renal failure Creatinine &gt; 2 mg% 4. metabolic alkalosis HCO3 &gt; 30 meq/L 5. medication that affect bicarbonate levels: Bicarbonate, Diamox, Fusid 6. obesity BMI &gt; 38 7. congestive heart failure EF &lt; 40 % or clinical signs of congestive heart failure</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>infiltration</keyword>
	<keyword>extravasation</keyword>
	<keyword>sodium bicarbonate</keyword>
	<keyword>capnography</keyword>
	<keyword>end tidal carbon dioxide</keyword>
	<keyword>chemotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>