<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01695525</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Syncope is a common problem that many clinicians may encounter in various outpatient settings. Neurocardiogenic syncope (NCS) is a benign condition characterized by a self limited episode of systemic hypotension. Patients are usually managed with education on syncope, anxiety management, and coping skills. It has been established that practice of Yoga could relieve stress and anxiety. In a different study, they also found that Yoga positively influences cardiovascular function by decreasing the heart rate and blood pressure. The main objective of Yoga is to achieve control over the autonomic nervous system and able to control functions like heart rate, blood pressure and respiratory rate. Based on the findings that Yoga relieves stress and reduces heart rate, the investigators propose to study if Yoga can decrease the frequency of NCS and also reduce the symptoms associated with these episodes.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Influence of Yoga in Patients With Neurocardiogenic Syncope</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syncope</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Syncope, Vasovagal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of recurrent Neurocardiogenic syncope At least one episode of syncope or presyncopal event in the last 3 months prior to enrollment Previously established diagnosis of any psychiatric illness. Previous history of Coronary Artery Disease, myocardial infarction, congestive heart failure, carotid sinus hypersensitivity Established diagnosis of tachy and/or brady arrhythmias, except cardioinhibiotry neurocardiogenic syncope. History of pacemaker, ICD or CRTD implantation. Other conditions where Yoga should be avoided are: 1. Pregnant women 2. Subjects with untreated or uncontrolled high blood pressure 3. Subjects with past history of Pnuemothorax. 4. Subjects with severe cervical spondylitis and cervical, thoracic or lumbar disc prolapse. 5. Subjects with carotid stenosis 6. Subjects with history of psychosis (evidence of acute episodes with deep and prolonged meditation) or substance abuse. 7. Subjects with the history of epilepsy ( evidence of acute episodes with deep and prolonged meditation) 8. Subjects with glaucoma 9. Subjects with history of Total Hip Replacement.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Neurocardiogenic Syncope</keyword>
	<keyword>Yoga</keyword>
</DOC>