<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01670240</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study wants to investigate the efficiency of biological treatment for chronic pouchitis. Chronic pouchitis is inflammation in a reconstruction after removal of the colon, a pouch. It is examined in patients with ulcerative colitis. The primary objective evaluation is to evaluate the clinically effect of biological therapy (adalimumab) in patients with chronic pouchitis. Secondary objective is to evaluate the effect of biological therapy on the endoscopical and histological inflammatory activity. It is a double-blinded randomized placebo controlled study.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Adalimumab in the Treatment of Chronic Pouchitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pouchitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Operated with proctocolectomy and construction of an IPAA Prior to surgery diagnosed with ulcerative colitis according to established clinically, radiologic, endoscopic and histological criteria. Diagnosed with chronic pouchitis as defined above PDAI ≥ 7, with the clinically part of PDAI &gt;2 and the endoscopic part of PDAI &gt;3 Age &gt;18 years Negative stool cultures for bacterial bowel pathogens and negative stool microscopy for parasites Serology negative for chronic hepatitis B Negative examination for tuberculosis (including xray of thorax and a interferon gamma test) Signed informed consent Treatment with glucocorticoids within the last 4 weeks Diagnosed with Crohn's disease Need of an interpreter or if patients do not understand oral or written information. Surgical complications as anal stenosis, leak of the anastomosis, or fistula arising from the pouch Abuse of medicine, alcohol or drugs Ongoing treatment with NSAID (non steroid anti inflammatory drug) Pregnancy or nursing A diverting stoma Malignancy or other severe chronic disease or expected longevity less than one year Patients diagnosed with immune deficiency Ongoing infectious disease Contraindications against treatment with tumor necrosis factoralpha antibody, such as heart disease, former cancer disease, in vivo vaccination within the last 4 weeks</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>IPAA</keyword>
	<keyword>Pouchitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Ulcerative colitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Pouch</keyword>
	<keyword>Adalimumab</keyword>
	<keyword>Humira</keyword>
</DOC>