<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00675285</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Leukotriene receptor antagonists (LTRAs) reduce fractional exhaled nitric oxide (FENO) concentrations in children with asthma, but the effect of LTRA withdrawal on FENO and lung function is unknown. We will aim to study the effect of treatment and withdrawal of montelukast, a LTRA, on airway inflammation as reflected by FENO and lung function in children with asthma. A double-blind, randomized, placebo controlled, parallel group study will be undertaken in 18 atopic children with mild persistent asthma who will be treated with oral montelukast (5 mg/day for 4 weeks) and 18 atopic children with mild persistent asthma who will receive matching placebo. A follow-up visit will be performed 2 weeks after montelukast or placebo withdrawal.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Montelukast in Children With Asthma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Montelukast</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Children 6 to 14 yrs old, step 1 and step 2 GINA (Global INitiative for Asthma) guidelines exhaled nitric oxide (NO) &gt;20 PPB at visit 2 symptoms more often than twice a day, FEV1 equal or higher than 80% of predicted value and reversibility equal or higher than 12% to salbutamol, or a positive provocation test with methacholine, or exercise no regular medication, inhaled shortacting beta2 agonists for symptom relief Patient is hospitalized Patient has FEV1 &lt; 80% predicted on visit 1 Patient has 2 or more nighttime awakenings for asthma per week or pef variability 30% or more upper respiratory infection in the previous 3 weeks treatment with glucocorticoids or LTRAs in the previous 4 weeks treatment with inhaled glucocorticoids for more than 4 weeks in the previous year</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>14 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>airway inflammation</keyword>
	<keyword>childhood asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>fractional exhaled nitric oxide</keyword>
	<keyword>leukotriene receptor antagonists</keyword>
	<keyword>lung function</keyword>
</DOC>