<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02411539</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and effect of an experimental human monoclonal antibody (mAb), VRC-HIVMAB060-00-AB (VRC01), in adults infected with HIV who are receiving antiretroviral therapy (ART).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluating the Safety, Tolerability, and Effect of a Human Monoclonal Antibody (VRC01) on Markers of HIV Persistence in HIV-Infected Adults Receiving Antiretroviral Therapy (ART)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) have been developed as treatment for a variety of conditions including cancer, autoimmune disorders, and infections. mAbs may also be a potential treatment for people infected with HIV. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of an experimental human mAb, VRC-HIVMAB060-00-AB (VRC01), in HIV-infected adults receiving ART. Study researchers will also evaluate the effect of VRC01 on the number of infected cells containing unspliced HIV-1 transcripts in the blood in participants. This study will enroll HIV-infected people 18 to 65 years old, who have been receiving ART for at least 2 years and who have a CD4+ count of 200 cells/mm^3 or greater. Participants will be randomly assigned to Arm A or Arm B. Participants in Arm A will receive an intravenous (IV) infusion of VRC01 at Day 0 and Week 3 and an IV infusion of placebo at Weeks 6 and 9. Participants in Arm B will receive an IV infusion of placebo at Day 0 and Week 3 and an IV infusion of VRC01 at Weeks 6 and 9. Participants will record their temperature and symptoms for 3 days after each infusion. Study visits will occur at study entry (Day 0), and Weeks 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 15, 18, and 30. Study visits will include physical examinations, clinical assessments, and blood collection.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>HIV1 infection, documented by any FDAapproved rapid HIV test or HIV enzyme or chemiluminescence immunoassay (E/CIA) test kit at any time prior to study entry and confirmed by a licensed Western blot or a second antibody test by a method other than the initial rapid HIV or E/CIA tests, or by HIV1 antigen, or plasma HIV1 RNA assay. More information on this criterion is available in the protocol. Receiving continuous ART for at least 2 years (defined as no interruptions longer than 14 consecutive days) and with no changes in the components of the ART for at least 90 days prior to study entry CD4+ cell count greater than or equal to 200 cells/mm^3 obtained within 60 days prior to study entry in a clinical laboratory improvement amendments (CLIA)certified laboratory Plasma HIV1 RNA below the limit of detection of the FDAapproved assays (limit of detection: 75, 50, 40 or 20 copies/mL) for greater than or equal to 2 years on ART. Participants must have at least one documented HIV1 RNA less than the limit of detection 1224 months prior to study entry and at least one HIV1 RNA less than the limit of detection within 12 months prior to study entry. All available HIV1 RNA measurements must be below the assay limit of detection during the 2 years prior to study entry except as allowed by the following note. NOTE: A single unconfirmed plasma HIV1 RNA greater than the limit of detection but less than 200 copies/mL within 624 months is allowed if followed by a subsequent value below the limit of detection. Plasma HIV1 RNA level of less than 40 copies/mL obtained by the Abbott Realtime HIV assay (m2000) or less than 20 copies/mL obtained by the Roche COBAS Taqman HIV1 v2.0 assay within 60 days prior to entry Men and women greater than or equal to 18 years of age and less than or equal to 65 years of age The following laboratory values obtained within 60 days prior to entry by any U.S. laboratory that has a CLIA certification or its equivalent. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) greater than or equal to 750 cells/mm^3 Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 11.0 g/dL for men and greater than or equal to 10.0 g/dL for women Platelet count greater than or equal to 100,000/mm^3 Creatinine clearance greater than or equal to 60 mL/min estimated by the CockcroftGault equation. NOTE: A program for calculating creatinine clearance by the CockcroftGault method is available on www.fstrf.org. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (SGPT) less than or equal to 2.0 times upper limit of normal (ULN) Hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody negative result within 60 days prior to study entry or, if the HCV antibody result is positive, a negative HCV RNA result within 60 days prior to study entry Negative HBsAg result obtained within 60 days prior to study entry Ability and willingness of participant to provide informed consent Females of reproductive potential (women who have not been postmenopausal for at least 24 consecutive months, i.e., who have had menses within the preceding 24 months, or women who have not undergone surgical sterilization, specifically hysterectomy, or bilateral oophorectomy and/or bilateral salpingectomy), will need a negative serum or urine pregnancy test within 48 hours prior to study entry. NOTE: Acceptable documentation of hysterectomy and bilateral oophorectomy, bilateral salpingectomy, tubal microinserts, partner who has undergone vasectomy, and menopause is participantreported history. All participants must agree not to participate in the conception process (e.g., active attempt to become pregnant or to impregnate, sperm donation, in vitro fertilization), and if participating in sexual activity that could lead to pregnancy, the participant/partner must use at least one reliable form of contraception (condoms, with or without a spermicidal agent; a diaphragm or cervical cap with spermicide; an intrauterine device (IUD); or hormonebased contraceptive), while receiving study treatment and for 12 weeks after stopping study treatment Documentation of the availability of the following stored samples from the screening visit: peripheral blood mononuclear cell (PBMC) for CD4+ Tcell associated HIV1 RNA, DNA assay and plasma for HIV1 SCA. Sites must receive confirmation from the processing lab via phone, email, or fax, that specimens have been entered into the AIDS Clinical Trials Group (ACTG) Laboratory Data Management System (LDMS). Previous receipt of humanized or human monoclonal antibody (licensed or investigational) Weight greater than 115 kg or less than 53 kg Acute or ongoing AIDSdefining illness within 60 days prior to study entry History of a severe allergic reaction with generalized urticarial, angioedema, or anaphylaxis within 2 years of study entry Currently breastfeeding or pregnant Active drug or alcohol use or dependence that, in the opinion of the site investigator, would interfere with adherence to study requirements Acute or serious illness that, in the opinion of the site investigator, requires systemic treatment and/or hospitalization within 60 days prior to entry Use of immunomodulators (e.g., interleukins, interferons, cyclosporine), HIV vaccine, systemic cytotoxic chemotherapy, or investigational therapy within 60 days prior to study entry. NOTE: Participants receiving stable physiologic doses of glucocorticoids, defined as the equivalent of prednisone less than or equal to 10 mg/day, will not be excluded. Stable physiologic glucocorticoid doses should not be discontinued for the duration of the study. In addition, participants receiving inhaled or topical corticosteroids will not be excluded. Treatment for hepatitis C within 24 weeks of study entry Vaccinations within 7 days prior to the screening, preentry, or study entry visits. NOTE: Participants are encouraged to get routine vaccinations, such as seasonal influenza vaccine more than 7 days prior to screening or between screening and preentry visits (outside of the 7day window above). Initiation of ART during acute HIV1 infection (as determined by the site investigator by history and/or available medical records)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>