<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00848978</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The Health Enhancing Strength Training in Nonagenarians (STRONG) is a randomised control trial to assess the effectiveness of an aerobic and strength training program for improving functional capacity and quality of life in nonagenarians. Sixty (51 women) nonagenarians (age range: 90-102 years) who live in a geriatric nursing home will be randomly assigned to either a usual care (control) group (n=30) or an intervention (training) group (n=30). Participants allocated in the usual care group will receive general physical activity guidelines and participants allocated in the intervention group will also enroll in three weekly non-consecutive individualized training sessions (~45-50 min each) during 8 weeks. The exercise program will consist of muscular strength [with a special focus on leg press at 30% (start of the program) to 70% 1 repetition maximum (end)] and aerobic exercises (cycle-ergometry during 3-5 to 15 minutes at 12-14 points in the rate of perceived exertion scale). Results from STRONG will help to better understand the potential of regular physical activity for improving the well-being of the oldest population groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Strength Training in Nonagenarians</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Age: 90 years or over. Planning to stay in the same nursing home during the study. Able to ambulate, with or without assistance. Able to communicate. Informed consent: Must be capable and willing to provide consent. Acute or terminal illness. Myocardial infarction in the past 3 months. Not capable to ambulate. Unstable cardiovascular disease or other medical condition. Upper or lower extremity fracture in the past 3 months. Severe dementia. Unwillingness to either complete the study requirements or to be randomised into control or training group. Presence of neuromuscular disease or drugs affecting neuromuscular function.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>90 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Functional capacity</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
	<keyword>Depression</keyword>
	<keyword>Falls</keyword>
	<keyword>Body composition</keyword>
	<keyword>Physical activity</keyword>
</DOC>