<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02367196</DOC>
	<brief_summary>CC-90002-ST -001 is an open-label, Phase 1, dose escalation and expansion clinical study in subjects advanced, refractory solid and hematologic cancers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase 1, Dose Finding Study of CC-90002 in Subjects With Advanced Solid and Hematologic Cancers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>CC-90002-ST-001 is an open-label, Phase 1, dose escalation and expansion, first in human (FIH) clinical study of CC-90002, administered by intravenous (IV) infusion, in subjects with advanced, refractory solid and hematologic cancers. The study will be conducted in two parts. Following completion of dose escalation (Part A), selected hematologic and solid tumor cohorts may be enrolled into an expansion phase (Part B).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hematologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Men and women, 18 years or older, with advanced, relapsed or refractory solid tumors, Multiple Myeloma (MM) or nonHodgkin's lymphoma (NHL). 2. At least one site of measurable disease in subjects with solid tumors and NHL. 3. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status (ECOG PS) of 0 or 1. 4. Subjects must have adequate hematopoietic, liver, renal and coagulation function as assessed by specific laboratory criteria. 5. Females and males must agree to contraceptive methods and avoid conceiving throughout the study, and for up to 8 weeks following the last dose of CC90002. 1. High grade lymphomas (Burkitts or lymphoblastic), plasma cell leukemia.2. High grade, rapidly proliferative solid tumors (eg, small cell lung cancer, germ cell tumors, neuroblastoma) with extensive tumor burden. 3. Symptomatic central nervous system involvement. 4. Impaired cardiac function or clinically significant cardiac disease. 5. Prior Red blood cell (RBC) transfusion &lt; 3 months prior to starting CC90002. 6. Prior autologous stem cell transplant ≤ 3 months prior to starting CC90002. 7. Prior allogeneic stem cell transplant with either standard or reduced intensity conditioning ≤ 6 months prior to starting CC90002. 8. Prior systemic cancerdirected treatments or investigational modalities ≤ 5 half lives or 4 weeks prior to starting CC90002, whichever is shorter. 9. Major surgery ≤ 2 weeks prior to starting CC90002. 10. Pregnant or nursing females. 11. Known HIV infection. 12. Known chronic hepatitis B or C (HBV/HCV) infection. 13. Ongoing treatment with chronic, therapeutic dosing of anticoagulants. 14. History of autoimmune hemolytic anemia or autoimmune thrombocytopenia. 15. History of concurrent second cancers requiring active, ongoing systemic treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>CC-90002</keyword>
	<keyword>Monoclonal</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibody</keyword>
	<keyword>CD47</keyword>
	<keyword>Advanced</keyword>
	<keyword>Solid Cancers</keyword>
	<keyword>Hematologic Cancers</keyword>
</DOC>