<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02109172</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study evaluated the safety and efficacy of once and twice daily TD-4208 and placebo when administered using a jet nebulizer for 7 days in a cross-over design to patients with moderate to severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A 7-Day Cross-over Study of QD (Once Daily) and BID (Twice Daily) TD-4208 in Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject must have a negative pregnancy test, and must be prepared to use effective contraception if of childbearing potential Subject is capable of performing reproducible spirometry maneuvers Subject has postbronchodilator FEV1/FVC (forced expiratory volume in 1 second/forced vital capacity) ratio &lt;0.7 Subject has moderatetosevere stable COPD (Stage 2 or 3 according to the Global Initiative for the Treatment of Obstructive Lung Disease (GOLD) Guidelines) Subject has a postbronchodilator FEV1 greater than or equal to 30% and less than 80% of predicted normal Subject demonstrates a postipratropium FEV1 response ≥ 12% and ≥ 200 mL of preipratropium FEV1 response Subject has a current or past smoking history of at least 10 packyears. Subject has a significant respiratory disease or disorder other than COPD that would affect the interpretation of data from this study Subject has a history of reactions or hypersensitivity to inhaled anticholinergic or betaagonist agents Subject suffers from any medical condition that would preclude the use of inhaled anticholinergic agents Subject has been hospitalized for COPD or pneumonia within 12 weeks. Subject requires longterm oxygen therapy (&gt;15 hours a day)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>COPD</keyword>
</DOC>