<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02109419</DOC>
	<brief_summary>While standard pencil-and-paper test have continued to be useful for the monitoring of cognition, mood, and life space (LS) in the elderly they do have considerable limitations. Use of these pencil-and-paper tests requires that individuals come to the clinic for assessments, which results in significant clinical costs and practical limitations in the conducting of assessments in large numbers of individuals, and provides a time consuming and non-automated means of quantifying and recording changes in brain function. It is increasingly recognized that there is a need to develop valid and reliable computer based assessments to allow for the remote assessment of cognition, mood, and LS. Development of computerized based assessments will significantly increase the scale, scope, and speed with which cognition, mood, and LS can be measured in the elderly. Helping Hands Technology LLC (HHT) has developed a number of web based assessments of cognition, mood, and LS. These new computerized assessments will be developed using new technology, and are based on the general principles found in existing pencil-and-paper based assessments of cognition, mood, and LS. In addition, HHT is developing proprietary means of reporting the results of the computerized assessments in an easy to use narrative format. This study will focus on quantifying the feasibility and validity of using HHT computerized assessments.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Feasibility and Validity of A Novel Computer Based Battery of Assessments in the Elderly</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>See Brief Summary Section.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Men and woman between the ages of 6085, inclusive Cognitive function/impairment within appropriate ranges for the study (MiniMental State Exam scores of 1030, inclusive) Unable to complete computerized and standard pencilandpaper based assessments</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>computerized assessments</keyword>
	<keyword>mood</keyword>
	<keyword>life space</keyword>
	<keyword>cognition</keyword>
</DOC>