<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02109016</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether lucitanib is safe and effective in the treatment of patients with advanced/metastatic lung cancer and fibroblast growth factor (FGF), vascular endothelial growth factor receptor (VEGF), or platelet derived growth factor (PDGF) related genetic alterations.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess the Efficacy and Safety of the VEGFR-FGFR Inhibitor, Lucitanib, Given to Patients With Advanced/Metastatic Lung Cancer and FGF, VEGF, or PDGF Related Genetic Alterations</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Lucitanib is an oral inhibitor of the tyrosine kinase activity of FGFR 1-3, VEGFR 1-3, and PDGFR α/β. Lucitanib has demonstrated potent anti-tumor and anti-angiogenic activity in vitro proliferation assays and in vivo using human tumor xenograft models, with a trend for stronger efficacy in those with genomic aberrancies of FGF or PDGF. Abnormalities in the FGF, VEGF, and PDGF-related genes are observed across lung cancer histologies. The first in human trial of lucitanib demonstrated that daily lucitanib is clinically active in patients with advanced solid tumors. Specifically, patients with FGFR1-amplification appeared to derive particular benefit from lucitanib. Based on these results, this study is designed to explore the safety and anti-tumor activity of daily lucitanib in lung cancer patients with FGF, VEGF, and PDGF genetic alterations.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed advanced/metastatic SCLC or NSCLC Any of the following tumor tissue based genetic alterations: FGFR1, FGFR2, FGFR3, VEGFA, or PDGFRα amplification; Any FGFR1, FGFR2, or FGFR3 gene fusion; FGFR1, FGFR2, or FGFR3 activating mutation Availability of tumor tissue sample suitable for the central confirmation of the genetic alteration and exploratory analyses Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) of 0 or 1 Measurable disease per RECIST 1.1 Documented radiographic disease progression following at least one line of therapy in the advanced/metastatic setting Tumors that are invading a major vessel; NSCLC tumors abutting to a major vessel Uncontrolled hypertension, defined as SBP ≥ 140 mmHg and/or DBP ≥ 90 mmHg with optimized antihypertensive therapy Uncontrolled hypothyroidism defined as serum thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH) higher than 5 mIU/mL while receiving appropriate thyroid hormone therapy Symptomatic and/or untreated central nervous system metastases Presence of another active cancer Ongoing adverse events from surgery or prior anticancer therapies, including radiation, targeted, or cytotoxic therapies Pregnant or breastfeeding women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>FGFR1 amplification</keyword>
	<keyword>FGF alteration</keyword>
	<keyword>VEGF alteration</keyword>
	<keyword>PDGF alteration</keyword>
	<keyword>Tyrosine kinase inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>VEGFR inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>FGFR inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>PDGFR inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>VEGFR-FGFR inhibitor</keyword>
</DOC>