<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00203645</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to examine whether problem gamblers who receive therapy calls in addition to a self-help manual will be more likely to quit or cut back on their gambling when compared with problem gamblers who receive just the manual.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Minimal and Brief Treatments for Pathological Gamblers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>With gambling becoming more accessible, the occurrence of problems related to gambling are on the rise. The costs of problem gambling are enormous.There are social and economic costs, the gambler can sometimes lose a significant relationship, job, or commit an illegal activity. Pathological gamblers are also at risk for developing a general medical condition related to stress. There is a high risk of suicide and problem gamblers also have increased rates of mental health disorders. Relatively few people choose to attend formal treatment programs so it's important to provide a range of options to make treatment more accessible. The present study examines the effectiveness of minimal and brief interventions delivered by the telephone. Comparison(s): The "Workbook Only Control" condition involves receiving the self-help booklet through the mail after a brief telephone assessment. The "Minimal Treatment" condition involves receiving the same workbook but also having a motivational enhancement intervention by telephone. The "Brief Treatment" condition provides the workbook, motivational enhancement, and follow-up support on six occasions spread over 36 weeks. The "Wait List Control" condition involves participants being assigned to a six week waiting list. Participants are assessed and after a six week waiting period they will have a reassessment at which time they will be sent the gambling self-help workbook.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Gambling</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Over age 17 Perception of a gambling problem and a score of 3 or higher (moderate risk) on the Canadian Problem Gambling Index. Not involved in treatment at present. Willingness to read a short book written in English as a major treatment. Willing to have telephone contacts recorded. Willing to provide followup data on gambling. Willing to provide the name of a collateral to help locate them for followup interviews. Must have gambled at least once in the past month Participants in the preliminary study will be excluded.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Problem gambling</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-help manual</keyword>
	<keyword>Motivation enhancement</keyword>
	<keyword>Telephone support</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Pathological gambling</keyword>
</DOC>