<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01624649</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this observational study is to explore the efficacy of methylphenidate hydrochloride in children and adolescents diagnosed with attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) by Kiddie-scheduled for affective disorders (SADS)-present and life time version (K-SADS-PL).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Examine the Progression of Attention-Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) Drug Treatment and to Analyze Associated Factors</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a 1-year open-label (all people involved know the identity of the assigned drug), multicenter, single arm, prospective, observational study to explore under natural setting the efficacy of drug treatment in children and adolescents diagnosed with ADHD by K-SADS-PL (K-SADS-PL is a tool used for ADHD diagnosis. Patient may be diagnosed with ADHD by using K-SADS-PL to check if he or she meets the criteria according to Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders &amp; edition (DSM-IV). After obtaining informed consent, investigator will prescribe stimulant or non-stimulant ADHD treatment medications (ie, Immediate release [IR]/extended release [ER]/osmotic release oral system (OROS) methylphenidate, atomoxetine). Efficacy and safety assessments will be performed at 4, 12, 24, 36, and 52 weeks after the first day of giving study drug. Progression of symptom improvement and adherence will be investigated and associated variables (ie, demographic, clinical, familial and treatment factors) will be analyzed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atomoxetine Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylphenidate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Has been diagnosed with attentiondeficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) by KiddieSADSpresent and life time version (KSADSPL) Have not received methylphenidate or atomoxetine within 3 months prior to screening. Has intelligence quotient (IQ) ≤70 assessed by comprehensive attention test (CAT) at screening diagnosed with congenital disorders Has had history of acquired brain damage (eg, cerebral palsy) Has had diagnosed with convulsive disabilities or other neurological disease or dysesthesia Has had developmental disabilities such as autistic spectrum disorder Has had history of schizophrenia, bipolar, or other pediatric psychotic disorder, and obsessive compulsive disorder Has had linguistic disability and had diagnosed with tic disorder that requires additional drug treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Developmental disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Atomoxetine</keyword>
	<keyword>Methylphenidate</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychiatric disorder</keyword>
</DOC>