<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="113973">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01619475</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>A2ALL Core Protocol</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>5U01DK062498-09</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01619475</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Adult-to-Adult Living Donor Transplant Cohort Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>A2ALL-2</acronym>
  <official_title>A2ALL: Adult-to-Adult Living Transplant Cohort Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beth Golden</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study is being conducted for the following reasons:

        1. To determine the prevalence, course, and predictors of poor Health Related Quality of
           Life (HRQOL) outcomes associated with living donor donation.

        2. To collect data and biosamples prior to, during, and after a living donor liver
           transplant (LDLT) among all donors and recipients for use by other adult-to-adult
           living donor liver transplant studies and future studies.

        3. To study the effects of pressure and flow on the outcomes of LDLT.

        4. To characterize the differences between living donor liver transplant and deceased
           donor liver transplant in terms of recipient post-transplant outcomes including patient
           and graft survival, surgical morbidity, and resource utilization.

        5. To compare the long-term histological outcomes in recipients of LDLT and deceased donor
           liver transplant (DDLT) with recurrent hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection.

        6. To understand the history of pain management and to measure quality of care in pain
           control in living donors following partial hepatectomy.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The procedure of adult-to-adult living donor liver transplant (LDLT) is an extraordinary
      surgical therapy that involves the removal of 70% of the volume mass of an adult donor liver
      and its implantation into an adult recipient. A critical shortage of deceased donor livers,
      resulting in premature mortality among candidates in need of liver transplantation, remained
      the single most compelling force driving the need for adult-to-adult LDLT. Patients awaiting
      living donor liver transplant will be asked to enroll in this protocol at the time of
      identification of a potential living liver donor. Donors identified for the living donation
      will also be asked to enroll in the protocol. Donors and recipients who have already
      participated in a liver donation/transplant will be approached to join the protocol based on
      their clinical history.

      Optimizing donors' health-related quality of life is a foremost goal for liver donor liver
      transplant programs and an overarching aim for this study. The proposed A2ALL-2 Health
      Related Quality of Life (HRQOL) Sub-Study will build upon the A2ALL HRQOL measures employed
      to date. There is a critical need to look at the important difficulties that liver donors
      appear to face not only in the early years but in the long-term after donation. Individuals
      who have enrolled in the study and are going to donate a portion of their liver will
      complete a HRQOL battery of tests conducted over the phone by experienced staff at
      Northwestern University or the University of Pittsburgh. The tests are a series of questions
      given to the upcoming donor at baseline (prior to the liver donation), at Month 3, and Month
      6, Year 1 and Year 2 following donation. The new donor will complete up to 5 interviews by
      the survey research team. Individuals who have already donated (long-term donors), and out
      three years since donation can be enrolled, but they have to have donated in 2002 or more
      recently. Long-term follow-up donors will complete up to 4 interviews by the survey research
      team.

      As LDLT moved from children to adults, it was observed early that the size of the graft was
      related to function in the recipient and that inadequate graft volume led to poor recipient
      outcomes. It has been found, that when the graft of the liver is too small, then the
      recipient can develop a number of symptoms including persistent ascites (fluid in the
      abdomen) and the graft becomes resistant to the passage of blood. This study hopes to
      develop and validate approaches that permit successful use of smaller donor livers and this
      is the principal goal of the surgical innovations portion of the study. The study will use
      standard surgical technique for the donor and recipient. Either right or left lobe donation
      and transplantation will be performed based on clinical parameters for graft selection.

      Biosample collection of serum aliquots and liver tissue samples will be collected from
      subjects during different timepoints in the study. The collection of patient biosamples and
      DNA samples provides a resource with which researchers can rapidly validate clinical
      hypotheses and algorithms for clinical decision making. The collections also advance the
      development of diagnostic and prognostic markers and therapeutics. In addition, collection
      and storage of DNA samples may increase the sample size and the resulting power of a study
      to identify genetic determinants of a disease. The samples will be stored in the National
      Institute of Diabetic, Digestive and Kidney diseases (NIDDK) Repositories.

      Hepatic C virus (HCV) recurrence after liver transplantation is universal in patients who
      have the virus pre-operatively. Chronic hepatitis evolves to a cirrhosis at a variable rate,
      but more rapidly than in non-transplant patients. The study will evaluate whether risk
      factors for aggressive HCV recurrence after DDLT also apply to LDLT recipients in long-term
      follow-up.

      Pain control in living donors following partial hepatectomy will be measured as quality of
      care. The transplant community has no objective information about pain management in live
      liver donors to use for quality improvement. A validated tool to measure quality of pain
      management will be used to assess multidimensional aspects of pain care.

      The following details the schedule of visits and the tests/procedures to be performed at
      each visit:

      Recipient (before the surgery)

        -  Provide blood samples for the NIDDK Biosample Repository.

        -  Undergo imaging studies either Computed Assisted Tomography (CAT) or a Magnetic
           Resonance Imaging (MRI) to measure the size of the liver and spleen.

        -  If one has liver cancer or hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), information will be
           collected about the tumor(s) and treatment.

      Recipient (day of surgery)

        -  Provide a sample of the new liver to the NIDDK Biosample Repository.

        -  Provide blood samples immediately before and during the transplant surgery to the NIDDK
           Biosample Repository.

        -  Allow the researchers to collect information about the transplant surgery.

        -  Allow the researchers to collect information about any complications that develop after
           the transplant.

        -  During the transplant operation, an ultrasound probe will be applied to the two vessels
           going to the transplanted liver and a measurement of how much blood flows through these
           vessels to the liver will be taken. After less than 5 minutes the probe will be
           removed. Additionally, measurements will be taken of the pressure in one of the
           vessels, the portal vein, with a very small needle inserted by the surgeon. These
           measurements will be recorded and analyzed as part of the study.

        -  During living donor transplant surgery, it is occasionally necessary to adjust the
           blood flow to the liver to improve the function. If the surgeon determines that the
           flow to the liver needs to be adjusted, the measurements described above will be
           repeated after the adjustments have been made. These measurements will be recorded and
           analyzed as part of the study.

        -  Additional tests which are standard of care may also be carried out at the site.

        -  If one has HCC,then information will be collected about the tumor(s).

      Recipient(immediately after the surgery)

        -  Provide blood samples during the first and second weeks after the transplant to the
           NIDDK Biosample Repository.

        -  Allow the researchers to collect information about the lab tests (liver function tests,
           blood counts,etc.).

        -  Undergo an ultrasound measurement of the blood flow through the portal vein on the day
           after the operation.

        -  Additional tests which are standard of care may be also carried out at the site.

      Recipient (throughout the course of the study)

        -  Provide blood samples to the NIDDK Biosample Repository at months 1, 3, and 12, and
           annually thereafter though August 2014. Approximately 10 teaspoons or 50 ccs of blood
           will be collected at each assessment.

        -  Undergo imaging studies at three months after the operation (either a CAT or MRI) of
           the liver and spleen to see how much the liver has grown since the transplant
           operation.

        -  Return to the transplant center for assessment at months 1,3, and 12, and annually
           thereafter through August 2014.

        -  Allow the researchers to collect information about any hospitalizations that occur
           after the transplant operation.

        -  Allow the researchers to collect information about any complications that develop after
           the transplant, through August 2014.

        -  Allow the researchers to collect information about any liver biopsies that are
           performed after the transplant.

        -  If the subject has Hepatitis C (HCV) and is post-transplant, and has had a liver
           transplant from a living donor or a deceased donor, the subject will be asked
           permission for review of the chart and collect information about the pre-transplant HCV
           treatment, the transplant operation, the immunosuppression medications, rejection
           episodes, and any HCV treatment received prior to consenting to this study.

        -  If the subject has HCV,and has given permission, the chart will be reviewed for liver
           biopsy results that occurred at least three years after the transplant.

        -  If a liver biopsy was not done at least three years after the transplant or if the
           recent liver biopsy was at least three years after the transplant but the most recent
           liver biopsy was more than one year the subject will be a asked to come to the center
           and get a liver biopsy done.

        -  If the study liver biopsy is done, or information on a previous biopsy has been
           collected the slides of the liver tissue obtained will be sent to the central
           pathologist to read. The name of the subject and any other identifying information will
           not be on the slides. It will have a code number on it that links back to the subject's
           clinical data.

        -  If the HCV subject is unwilling or unable to undergo a liver biopsy, then the subject
           will be asked to undergo a procedure called &quot;transient elastography&quot;. Transient
           elastography is a non-invasive procedure during which a sound wave is transmitted to
           the liver through an ultrasound probe, and the time it takes for the sound wave to
           travel through the liver is measured. Transient elastography is considered to be an
           experimental procedure. However, it has been well-studied, and there have been no
           adverse events or injuries with its use.

        -  If the subject has HCV, some blood will be collected for storage in the NIDDK
           Repository. Approximately 10 teaspoons or 50ccs of blood will be collected at that
           time.

      Donor (before the surgery)

        -  The subject will be called on the telephone by the survey researchers to answer
           questions about health, and well-being as well as views about the donation process.

        -  The survey questions may take up to 45 minutes to complete.

        -  Provide blood cell samples for the NIDDK Biosample Repository. Approximately 12
           teaspoons or 60 ccs of blood will be collected.

        -  Undergo an imaging study before the operation (either CAT or MRI) to measure the size
           of the liver and spleen.

        -  Additional tests which are standard of care may also be carried out at the site.

      Donor (day of the surgery)

        -  Provide samples of liver to the NIDDK Biosample Repository.

        -  Allow the researchers to collect information about the donation surgery.

        -  Allow the researchers to collect information about any complications that develop after
           the donation.

      Donor (immediately after the surgery)

        -  Two days after the surgery, the subject will be asked questions about their
           post-operative pain.

        -  Provide blood samples one week after the donation surgery to the NIDDK Biosample
           Repository. Approximately 5-6 teaspoons or 25-30ccs of blood will be collected.

      Donor (throughout the course of the study)

        -  Provide blood samples to the NIDDK Biosample Repository at week 1, month 1, month 3,
           and month 12. Approximately 10 teaspoons or 50 ccs of blood will be collected at each
           assessment.

        -  Return to the transplant center for assessment at month 3, and annually thereafter
           through August 2014.

        -  Undergo an imaging study at three months after the operation (CAT or MRI) to measure
           the size of the liver and spleen to see how much the liver has grown back since the
           donation operation.

        -  If the subject entered this study prior to undergoing surgery, questions will have to
           be answered by telephone about quality of life after donation at 3, 6, 12, and 24
           months following donation. These telephone interviews may take up to 45 minutes to
           complete.

        -  If the subject entered the study after living liver donation, questions will be asked
           over the telephone about quality of life upon study entry and then annually for three
           years. The telephone interviews may take 45 minutes to complete.

        -  Allow the researchers to collect information about any complications that develop after
           the donation operation, through August 2014.

        -  Allow the researchers to collect information about the hospitalizations that occur
           after the transplant operation.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>February 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recipient patient and graft survival starting from the time of transplantation in LDLT &amp; DDLT.</measure>
    <time_frame>Yearly follow-up starting at transplant, measured between enrollment and up to 4 years.</time_frame>
    <description>To characterize the differences between LDLT and DDLT in terms of recipient post-transplant outcomes for patient and graft survival.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number and severity of surgical complications and resource utilization after transplant.</measure>
    <time_frame>Yearly follow-up starting at transplant, measured between enrollment , and up to 4 years.</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of incidence of defined medical and surgical complications after transplant between LDLT and DDLT.
Comparison of resource utilization (hospitalization) between LDLT and DDLT.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Related Quality of Life (HRQOL) in living liver donors.</measure>
    <time_frame>Yearly assessment from donation up to 5 assessments.</time_frame>
    <description>To estimate the prevalence, course, and predictors of poor HRQOL outcomes associated with living liver donation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Blood/Tissue Samples from Donors and Recipients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Yearly samples starting at transplant/donation (donors until year 1, and recipients until year 4.)</time_frame>
    <description>To collect data and biosamples prior to, during, and after LDLT among all donors and recipients for use by other A2ALL protocols and future studies.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pressure and Flow Measurements during the transplant surgery in LDLT recipients.</measure>
    <time_frame>During the transplant (at completion of dissection, and after revascularization).</time_frame>
    <description>To establish normal hepatic blood flow and portal compliance in the human liver, to examine the relationships among hepatic flow and pressure, graft size and function, and clinical outcomes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Measures of liver fibrosis (Ishak score) in LDLT and DDLT recipients with recurrent HCV infection.</measure>
    <time_frame>Enrollment up to 4 years, with data collected at the time of each liver biopsy.</time_frame>
    <description>To assess whether recurrent Hepatitis C is histologically less severe in LDLT compared with DDLT recipients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain control in living donors following partial hepatectomy</measure>
    <time_frame>The first 48 hours after donation surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported pain and satisfaction with pain management during the first 48 hours after donation surgery.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1900</enrollment>
  <condition>Liver Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Cancer</condition>
  <condition>End Stage Liver Disease</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis C</condition>
  <condition>Liver Cirrhosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals approved as liver donors and recipients shortly Pre-donation/Pre-transplant at the study sites.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Long-Term Follow-up</arm_group_label>
    <description>Donors and recipients enrolled in the original A2ALL Cohort study.
Donors and LDLT recipients whose donation/transplant occurred during the period of time that began with the end of enrollment into the original Cohort study (Aug. 31, 2009) and ended with the opening of the enrollment in the current core protocol; this is referred to as the &quot;Gap Era.&quot;
LDLT recipients and donors who were not in the original Cohort study or from the Gap Era will enter the study at time proximate to time of living donation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HCV-Infected Liver Transplant Recipients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Male and female HCV-infected adult liver transplant recipients from those enrolled in the A2ALL-1 Cohort study and from those concurrently transplanted at the new A2ALL-2 centers (University of Toronto, University of Pittsburgh, Lahey Clinic).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      To collect biosamples prior to, during, and after LDLT among all donors and recipients.
      These biosamples include, liver biopsy,whole blood for genetic studies and DNA extraction,
      plasma, serum and peripheral cells to be retained in the bio-repository.
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The sample population will consist of the following:

          -  Donors and LDLT and DDLT recipients enrolled in the original A2ALL cohort study.

          -  Donors and LDLT recipients where the donation/transplant occurred during the period
             of time that began with the end of enrollment into the original Cohort study (August
             31, 2009) and ended with the opening of enrollment in the current core protocol; this
             is referred to as the &quot;Gap Era.&quot;

          -  Prospective donors and LDLT recipients for donation/transplant surgery.

          -  HCV-infected adult liver transplant recipients enrolled in the A2ALL-1 Cohort and
             from those currently transplanted at the new A2ALL-2 centers (University of Toronto,
             University of Pittsburgh, and Lahey Clinic).
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        Recipients

          1. Age 18 or older at the time of consent

          2. Has had a living donor identified and accepted and LDLT is planned

          3. Informed consent obtained

          4. Is listed for single organ (liver) transplantation

        Donors

          1. Age 18 or older at the time of consent

          2. Has undergone donor evaluation process and was accepted and donation surgery is
             planned

          3. Informed consent obtained

        Exclusion Criteria:
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert M Merion, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Michigan</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Averell Sherker, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Peg Hill-Callahan, BS, LSW</last_name>
    <phone>734-369-9674</phone>
    <email>Peg.Hill-Callahan@ArborResearch.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Diane Hilfinger, MA</last_name>
    <phone>734-369-9678</phone>
    <email>diane.hilfinger@ArborResearch.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94143</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dulce MacLeod</last_name>
      <phone>415-476-3170</phone>
      <email>Dulce.Macleod@ucsfmedctr.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Chris E. Freise, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Colorado Health Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80045</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Seda Carlton</last_name>
      <phone>303-724-1868</phone>
      <email>seda.carlton@ucdenver.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>James Burton, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Northwestern University, Division of Transplantation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60611</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Patrice Al-Saden</last_name>
      <phone>312-694-0232</phone>
      <email>palsaden@northwestern.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael M. Abecassis, MD, MBA</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lahey Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Burlington</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>01805</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Agnes Trabucco</last_name>
      <phone>781-744-3367</phone>
      <email>Agnes.Trabucco@Lahey.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elizabeth Pomfret, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tarek Mansour</last_name>
      <phone>212-305-3839</phone>
      <email>tm2598@columbia.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jean C Emond, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Debra McCorriston</last_name>
      <phone>215-662-2107</phone>
      <email>debra.mccorriston@uphs.upenn.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kim M. Olthoff, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Leslie Mitrik</last_name>
      <phone>412-682-1645</phone>
      <email>mitrikla@upmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Abhinav Humar, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Virginia Commonwealth University-Medical College of Virginia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Richmond</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23298</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>JoAnne L Davis</last_name>
      <phone>804-828-7921</phone>
      <email>jldavis4@vcu.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Robert A. Fisher, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Toronto</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5G 2N2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Erin Winter</last_name>
      <phone>416-340-4800</phone>
      <phone_ext>6093</phone_ext>
      <email>Erin.Winter@uhn.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David Grant, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Olthoff KM, Merion RM, Ghobrial RM, Abecassis MM, Fair JH, Fisher RA, Freise CE, Kam I, Pruett TL, Everhart JE, Hulbert-Shearon TE, Gillespie BW, Emond JC; A2ALL Study Group.. Outcomes of 385 adult-to-adult living donor liver transplant recipients: a report from the A2ALL Consortium. Ann Surg. 2005 Sep;242(3):314-23, discussion 323-5.</citation>
    <PMID>16135918</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Freise CE, Gillespie BW, Koffron AJ, Lok AS, Pruett TL, Emond JC, Fair JH, Fisher RA, Olthoff KM, Trotter JF, Ghobrial RM, Everhart JE; A2ALL Study Group.. Recipient morbidity after living and deceased donor liver transplantation: findings from the A2ALL Retrospective Cohort Study. Am J Transplant. 2008 Dec;8(12):2569-79. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-6143.2008.02440.x. Epub 2008 Oct 24.</citation>
    <PMID>18976306</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Trotter JF, Hill-Callahan MM, Gillespie BW, Nielsen CA, Saab S, Shrestha R, Talamantes MM, Weinrieb RM; A2ALL Study Group.. Severe psychiatric problems in right hepatic lobe donors for living donor liver transplantation. Transplantation. 2007 Jun 15;83(11):1506-8.</citation>
    <PMID>17565325</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Trotter JF, Wisniewski KA, Terrault NA, Everhart JE, Kinkhabwala M, Weinrieb RM, Fair JH, Fisher RA, Koffron AJ, Saab S, Merion RM; A2ALL Study Group.. Outcomes of donor evaluation in adult-to-adult living donor liver transplantation. Hepatology. 2007 Nov;46(5):1476-84.</citation>
    <PMID>17668879</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Berg CL, Gillespie BW, Merion RM, Brown RS Jr, Abecassis MM, Trotter JF, Fisher RA, Freise CE, Ghobrial RM, Shaked A, Fair JH, Everhart JE; A2ALL Study Group.. Improvement in survival associated with adult-to-adult living donor liver transplantation. Gastroenterology. 2007 Dec;133(6):1806-13. Epub 2007 Sep 14.</citation>
    <PMID>18054553</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Terrault NA, Shiffman ML, Lok AS, Saab S, Tong L, Brown RS Jr, Everson GT, Reddy KR, Fair JH, Kulik LM, Pruett TL, Seeff LB; A2ALL Study Group.. Outcomes in hepatitis C virus-infected recipients of living donor vs. deceased donor liver transplantation. Liver Transpl. 2007 Jan;13(1):122-9.</citation>
    <PMID>17192908</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fisher RA, Kulik LM, Freise CE, Lok AS, Shearon TH, Brown RS Jr, Ghobrial RM, Fair JH, Olthoff KM, Kam I, Berg CL; A2ALL Study Group.. Hepatocellular carcinoma recurrence and death following living and deceased donor liver transplantation. Am J Transplant. 2007 Jun;7(6):1601-8.</citation>
    <PMID>17511683</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Campsen J, Blei AT, Emond JC, Everhart JE, Freise CE, Lok AS, Saab S, Wisniewski KA, Trotter JF; Adult-to-Adult Living Donor Liver Transplantation Cohort Study Group.. Outcomes of living donor liver transplantation for acute liver failure: the adult-to-adult living donor liver transplantation cohort study. Liver Transpl. 2008 Sep;14(9):1273-80. doi: 10.1002/lt.21500.</citation>
    <PMID>18756453</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ghobrial RM, Freise CE, Trotter JF, Tong L, Ojo AO, Fair JH, Fisher RA, Emond JC, Koffron AJ, Pruett TL, Olthoff KM; A2ALL Study Group.. Donor morbidity after living donation for liver transplantation. Gastroenterology. 2008 Aug;135(2):468-76. doi: 10.1053/j.gastro.2008.04.018. Epub 2008 Apr 22.</citation>
    <PMID>18505689</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shaked A, Ghobrial RM, Merion RM, Shearon TH, Emond JC, Fair JH, Fisher RA, Kulik LM, Pruett TL, Terrault NA; A2ALL Study Group.. Incidence and severity of acute cellular rejection in recipients undergoing adult living donor or deceased donor liver transplantation. Am J Transplant. 2009 Feb;9(2):301-8. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-6143.2008.02487.x. Epub 2008 Dec 15.</citation>
    <PMID>19120082</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Trotter JF, Gillespie BW, Terrault NA, Abecassis MM, Merion RM, Brown RS Jr, Olthoff KM, Hayashi PH, Berg CL, Fisher RA, Everhart JE; Adult-to-Adult Living Donor Liver Transplantation Cohort Study Group.. Laboratory test results after living liver donation in the adult-to-adult living donor liver transplantation cohort study. Liver Transpl. 2011 Apr;17(4):409-17. doi: 10.1002/lt.22246.</citation>
    <PMID>21445924</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Olthoff KM, Abecassis MM, Emond JC, Kam I, Merion RM, Gillespie BW, Tong L; Adult-to-Adult Living Donor Liver Transplantation Cohort Study Group.. Outcomes of adult living donor liver transplantation: comparison of the Adult-to-adult Living Donor Liver Transplantation Cohort Study and the national experience. Liver Transpl. 2011 Jul;17(7):789-97. doi: 10.1002/lt.22288.</citation>
    <PMID>21360649</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 28, 2014</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>October 5, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Beth Golden</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Lead Clinical Monitor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Living Donor</keyword>
  <keyword>Liver Transplantation</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
  <keyword>Biosamples</keyword>
  <keyword>Liver Recipient</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>End Stage Liver Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
