<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="156263">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01065480</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>#6052/7087R</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01DA016950</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01065480</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Training Clinicians in Motivational Interviewing</brief_title>
  <acronym>MITraining</acronym>
  <official_title>Training Motivational Interviewing Using Live Supervision</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>New York State Psychiatric Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>New York State Psychiatric Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to train Substance Abuse Treatment Clinicians in the use of Motivational
      Interviewing techniques through live supervision.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      New evidence-based treatments have been slow to be adopted into the routine practice of
      addiction treatment, and traditional training methods are of limited effectiveness. In this
      study, we propose to continue development of methods for training clinicians in Motivational
      Interviewing (MI), based on the principle of live supervision. Live supervision (supervisor
      and trainee seeing a patient together) is common in basic training, but rarely used in
      continuing education. In the initial funding period we developed Teleconference Supervision
      (TCS), which implements live supervision by an expert through teleconferencing technology,
      harnessing the principles of context-dependent learning, differential reinforcement with
      immediacy of feedback, and modeling. Clinicians interview standard patients at their home
      clinics, while Supervisors listen via telephone. The clinician wears an earpiece, through
      which the Supervisor provides immediate feedback and coaching designed to differentially
      reinforce and shape MI skills. In a randomized controlled trial with community clinicians
      (N= 100), TCS produced superior overall MI skill, compared to control conditions where
      clinicians received Workshop only training, or standard tape-based supervision. Findings
      were encouraging yet the proportion of clinicians achieving expert proficiency was limited,
      and there were trends toward loss of skill at follow-up, suggesting longer training is
      needed to maximize and sustain MI skill.

      In the new funding period, we propose to build and improve upon TCS by testing an extended
      model of Teleconference Supervision (TCS-Plus), which will preserve the elements of live
      supervision from an expert supervisor but will also provide 4 sessions of enhanced tape
      review supervision on a bi-weekly basis after the initial TCS training. Using telephone
      technology, enhanced taped review allows the Supervisor and Clinician to listen to the taped
      session together before discussing the session. Practice sessions will increase from 5 to 9
      and be spread out from 8 to 16 weeks. Providing both TCS and enhanced tape review
      supervision maximizes supervision style advantages. While both offer context dependent
      learning, TCS provides for modeling and differential reinforcement with immediacy of
      feedback, and enhanced tape review provides ample time to role play and discuss technique.
      TCS-Plus will be compared to standard Tape Review supervision. The proposed project will be
      a StageI trial, intent on maximizing the gains already detected with the TCS model. We will
      assess if TCS-Plus produces superior MI skill to standard Tape Review supervision in a
      randomized trial with 130 community based-clinicians. It is hoped that, if successful,
      TCS-Plus could be a model for remote training and supervision at community treatment
      programs, promoting adoption of a variety of evidence-based treatments for substance use
      disorders into routine practice.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>March 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine whether Teleconference Supervision (TCS) is superior to Standard Supervision (audio-recording review) in fostering and sustaining MI skillfulness measured across follow-up assessment interviews.</measure>
    <time_frame>16, 24 and 32 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine if TCS, compared to standard Supervision, results in greater commitment language produced by their patients during follow-up assessment interviews, and to explore whether TCS is associated with improved clinical outcomes in those patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>16, 24 and 32 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">130</enrollment>
  <condition>Substance Abuse</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Clinicians/Therapists</arm_group_label>
    <description>Clinicians from participating substance abuse treatment programs who volunteer to be trained in motivational interviewing.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Substance Abuse Patients/Clients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients at participating substance abuse treatment programs can volunteer to take part in clinicians motivational interviewing test sessions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Motivational Interviewing</intervention_name>
    <description>Motivational interviewing is a directive, client-centered counseling style for eliciting behavior change by helping clients to explore and resolve ambivalence. Compared with nondirective counselling, it is more focused and goal-directed. The examination and resolution of ambivalence is its central purpose, and the counselor is intentionally directive in pursuing this goal.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Clinicians/Therapists</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Substance Abuse Patients/Clients</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Motivational Enhancement Therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>MI</other_name>
    <other_name>MET</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Substance Abuse Clinicians, Therapist and Counselors
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion/Exclusion Criteria: Clinician-Participants

        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Clinician, aged 18 to 75, employed in good standing at least 50% time at a licensed
             substance abuse treatment program.

          2. Carries a regular caseload of patients or clients for whom he/she serves as primary
             therapist.

          3. Interested in learning Motivational Interviewing and willing to follow treatment
             guidelines and training protocol, including random assignment to groups.

          4. Willing and able to attend a 2 day workshop, to tape subsequent sessions with
             patients for evaluation of MI skillfulness by Training Team members and raters, and
             to participate in supervision, including taping of sessions for review by Training
             Team members and raters and/or having supervisor listen to, and comment on, live
             sessions.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Planning to terminate employment at the current treatment program within the next six
             months.

          2. Has received credentialing as a Motivational Interviewing trainer, or served as a
             Motivational Interviewing or Motivational Enhancement Therapy therapist in a clinical
             trial which provided feedback on MI skill.

          3. Has received formal training in Motivational Interviewing within the last three
             months

        Inclusion/Exclusion Criteria: Patient-Participants

        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Males and females, age 18 to 70.

          2. Newly admitted to treatment for a substance use disorder at a licensed substance
             abuse treatment program, or patients not on the standing caseloads of participating
             counselors who otherwise meet inclusion-exclusion criteria.

          3. Treatment program to which admitted or seeking treatment is an outpatient program
             (drug free), or a methadone maintenance program, or a therapeutic community treatment
             program.

          4. Current active use of substances (other than nicotine) at least once per week in the
             past month, or, if incarcerated within the past month, was using substances regularly
             (at least once per week) in the month prior to incarceration.

          5. Willing to participate in the study, including willing to participate in sessions
             that are audio-taped for review by the treating clinician, supervisor and Training
             Team, and/or to participate in a session where a supervisor listens to the interview
             by telephone conference.

          6. Has a stable living arrangement with access to a telephone, and willing to be
             contacted by telephone by the research team for follow-up interviews.

          7. Able to provide written informed consent.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. In need of immediate acute care for a severe psychiatric disorder (e.g.
             schizophrenia, bipolar illness, or severe major depression) which would interfere
             with ability to participate, or in need of acute detoxification.

          2. In need of immediate acute care for a severe unstable, medical illness (e.g. acute
             infection, unstable diabetes mellitus, AIDS dementia complex or other organic mental
             syndrome) that would interfere with ability to participate.

          3. Likely to be incarcerated for more than four weeks within the next three months.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Edward V Nunes, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>New York State Psychiatric Institute/Columbia University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer L Smith, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>212-543-4980</phone>
    <email>smitjen@nyspi.columbia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jennifer E Lima, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>646-774-6165</phone>
    <email>limajen@nyspi.columbia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New York State Psychiatric Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 21, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 8, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Training</keyword>
  <keyword>Substance Abuse</keyword>
  <keyword>Counseling</keyword>
  <keyword>Motivational Interviewing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
