<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00392873</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to examine the effects of increased food intake on the menstrual cycle and bone health in physically active women who have irregular or absent menstrual cycles. This study will examine whether a 12 month period of increased food intake will cause menstrual cycles to resume and help bones get stronger.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Increased Calorie Intake to Reverse Energy Deficiency in Exercising Women: Impact on Bone and Menstrual Cyclicity</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Low levels of estrogen found in physically active, premenopausal women with irregular or absent menstrual periods is likely caused by insufficient energy (calorie) intake compared to energy expenditure. Premenopausal women with menstrual disturbances and amenorrhea suffer from reductions in bone mineral density, particularly in the lumbar spine. Bone loss observed in amenorrheic women may be serious enough to result in osteoporotic fractures, but is also associated with a high prevalence of stress fractures. Increased calorie intake should help improve energy status, menstrual status, and bone health. Comparison: Premenopausal women with irregular or absent menstrual periods will be assigned to either receive additional calories or serve as controls. A group of premenopausal women with normal menstrual periods will also be used for comparison.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria for Ovulatory Control Volunteers: 1835 years BMI 1625 kg/m2 At least 2 hr/wk of aerobic exercise Gynecological age &gt;/= 5 years Weight stable (+/ 2 kg) last 6 months History of regular menses for 6 months Inclusion Criteria for Women with Irregular or Absent Menses: 1835 years BMI 1625 kg/m2 At least 3 hr/wk of aerobic exercise Gynecological age &gt;/= 5 years Weight stable (+/ 2 kg) last 6 months No menses within past 3 months or 6 or less menses in last 12 months Low to normal bone mass (L1L4 Z score &lt;/=0) Exclusion Criteria for all participants: Hormonal contraceptives in last 6 months Smoking currently Current clinical diagnosis of an eating disorder Use of medications incompatible with measurement of reproductive or metabolic hormones, including thyroid medications that may interfere with any of the study outcomes. Dietary habits incompatible with prescribed diet for study Any metabolic, reproductive or bone disease Sedentary individuals with less than 120 minutes (2 hrs) of activity per week</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Amenorrhea</keyword>
	<keyword>Energy deficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Resting energy expenditure</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone metabolism</keyword>
	<keyword>Bone mineral density</keyword>
	<keyword>Exercise</keyword>
</DOC>