<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00392938</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Imaging procedures, such as PET scan, may help doctors predict a patient's response to treatment and help plan the best treatment. PURPOSE: This clinical trial is studying carbon-11 acetate and fludeoxyglucose F 18 PET scan of the bone in patients with metastatic prostate cancer that has spread to the bone.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Carbon-11 Acetate and Fludeoxyglucose F 18 PET Scan of the Bone in Patients With Metastatic Prostate Cancer That Has Spread to the Bone</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: Primary - Correlate pre-treatment and 3-month post-treatment carbon-11 (^11C) acetate and fludeoxyglucose F 18 positron emission tomography (^18F-FDG PET) images with changes in clinical response measures in patients with bone-dominant metastatic prostate cancer. Secondary - Compare ^11C acetate and ^18F-FDG PET scanning results with bone scintigraphy in these patients to determine which best predicts clinical response. - Correlate changes in ^11C acetate and ^18F-FDG PET with changes in prostate-specific antigen level. - Correlate changes in ^11C acetate and ^18F-FDG PET with clinical symptom parameters (pain scale scores and analgesic usage scales). - Correlate ^11C acetate and ^18F-FDG PET scan response with clinical time to progression. - Determine if PET scan response can predict duration of progression-free survival. OUTLINE: This is a pilot study. Patients are stratified according to hormone response (sensitive [stratum 1] vs refractory [stratum 2]). Patients undergo carbon-11 acetate and fludeoxyglucose F 18 positron emission tomography imaging prior to and 3 months after initiation of either androgen-deprivation therapy (stratum 1) or docetaxel (stratum 2). Pain and quality of life are assessed at baseline and at 3 months. Patients are followed every 3 months for up to 5 years. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 40 patients will be accrued for this study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Androgen Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Diagnosis of prostate cancer, meeting 1 of the following criteria: Metastatic hormonesensitive disease prior to initiation of firstline androgendeprivation therapy and meets the following criteria: Histologic confirmation of original diagnosis Hormonesensitive is defined as progressive disease in the absence of androgendeprivation therapy Presence of ≥ 3 convincing bone metastases, as defined by bone scintigraphy, CT scan (MRI if indicated), or plain xray Metastatic hormonerefractory disease prior to initiation of a firstline chemotherapy regimen that includes docetaxel and meets the following criteria: Histologic confirmation of original diagnosis Hormonerefractory is defined as development or advancement of metastatic disease with castrate testosterone levels (total testosterone &lt; 20 ng/dL) Presence of ≥ 3 convincing bone metastases, as defined by bone scintigraphy, CT scan (MRI if indicated), or plain xray Must have castrate testosterone levels (&lt; 20 ng/dL) from orchiectomy or undergoing maintenance with a luteinizing hormonereleasing hormone agonist Outside the window of a potential antiandrogen withdrawal response (either decline in prostatespecific antigen or objective response by imaging) PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks No serious underlying medical condition that would otherwise impair the patient's ability to receive treatment and undergo imaging studies No condition that would alter the patient's mental status, prohibiting the basic understanding and/or authorization of informed consent Able to lie still for the imaging Weight ≤ 300 lbs PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: See Disease Characteristics At least 6 weeks since prior bicalutamide or nilutamide At least 4 weeks since prior flutamide, ketoconazole, diethylstilbestrol, or estradiol More than 4 weeks since prior bisphosphonate therapy More than 4 weeks since prior radiotherapy to the bone More than 4 weeks since prior radiopharmaceutical treatment to the bone No concurrent radiotherapy</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>recurrent prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV prostate cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>bone metastases</keyword>
</DOC>