<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01753154</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To investigate the biocompatibility of the peritoneal dialysis (PD) solution balance in comparison to the conventional PD solution in APD(automated peritoneal dialysis) patients using the APD cycler sleep•safe.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Effect of Balance PD Solution on the Peritoneal Membrane in Patients on Automated Peritoneal Dialysis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Equivalence of the investigational PD solution balance regarding fluid status compared to the conventional PD solution. Effects of balance on inflammation and systemic advanced glycation end products formation. Effects of balance on peritoneal and total urea clearance, on peritoneal and total creatinine clearance and on ultrafiltration, on residual diuresis and on cholesterol levels. Safety of the investigational PD solution balance and the conventional PD solution as a control drug. The mesothelial cell mass assessed by Cancer Antigen 125 is affected by the use of the type of PD solution in APD patients using sleep•safe. Treating patients with the PD solution balance leads to not more than 1 litre difference in hydration in comparison to the conventional PD solution which is considered as clinically not relevant regarding blood pressure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Kidney Failure, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>APD patient ≥ 18 years Prevalent patient with at least 3 months experience on APD prior to inclusion Patient is trained on and being treated with the sleep•safe APD cycler Patient treated on APD exclusively with registered conventional PD solutions CAPD 2, CAPD 3, CAPD 4, CAPD 17, CAPD 18 or CAPD 19 for at least 8 weeks prior to inclusion Patient is on stable diuretic treatment e.g no change in diuretic treatment within the last 30 days prior to inclusion Informed consent signed and dated by study patient and investigator/authorised physician Ability to understand the nature and requirements of the study Peritonitis treatment £ 4 weeks preceding inclusion APD patients treated with IPD modality (intermittent peritoneal dialysis) Malignant disease without remission Patients with artificial joints, amputations, stents, or pacemaker Patients with congestive heart failure or coronary artery disease NYHA (New York Heart Association) III and higher Active HBV (hepatitis B virus)or HCV(hepatitis C virus)infection HIV positive Participation in an interventional clinical study during the preceding 30 days Any condition which could interfere with the patient's ability to comply with the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Peritoneal Dialysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Biocompatible dialysis solution</keyword>
	<keyword>Hydration status</keyword>
	<keyword>Residual renal function</keyword>
	<keyword>Body composition monitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Bioimpedance spectroscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>Cancer antigen 125</keyword>
</DOC>