<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01447628</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will establish whether intravenous iron replacement has clinical benefit in idiopathic pulmonary arterial hypertension. A 24-week double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, crossover study will investigate whether a single dose of 1g of Ferinject® or CosmoFer improves cardiopulmonary haemodynamics, exercise capacity and quality of life and is well-tolerated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>IV Iron Replacement for Iron Deficiency in Idiopathic Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension (IPAH) Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>IV iron formulation used in Europe - Ferinject IV iron formulation used in China - CosmoFer</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Familial Primary Pulmonary Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Iron-Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Males or females aged between 1675 years old 2. PAH which is idiopathic, heritable or associated with anorexigens. 3. Iron deficiency as defined by any one of the following criteria: sTfR levels &gt; 28.1 nmol/l (where sTfR analysis is available) or one of the following: Ferritin &lt; 37 ug/l; transferrin saturations &lt; 16.4%; iron &lt; 10.3 umol/l. 4. Documented diagnosis of PAH by right heart catheterisation performed at any time prior to Screening showing: resting mean pulmonary artery pressure &gt;25mmHg, pulmonary capillary wedge pressure =/&lt; 15 mm Hg and normal or reduced cardiac output; 5. 6 minute walking distance greater than 50m at entry; 6. Stable on an unchanged PAH therapeutic regime (any combination of endothelin receptor antagonist, phosphodiesterase inhibitor or prostacyclin analogue) for at least 1 month. 7. Able to provide written informed consent prior to any studymandated procedures 8. Female subjects of childbearing potential are eligible to participate if they agree to use one of the following contraception methods: Abstinence Contraceptive methods with a failure rate of &lt; 1%: Oral contraceptive, either combined or progestogen alone; Injectable progestogen; Implants of levonorgestrel; Estrogenic vaginal ring; Percutaneous contraceptive patches; Intrauterine device (IUD) or intrauterine system (IUS) that meets the &lt;1% failure rate as stated in the product label; Male partner(s) sterilization (vasectomy with documentation of azoospermia) prior to the female subject's entry into the study; Double barrier method: condom and occlusive cap (diaphragm or cervical/vault caps) plus vaginal spermicidal agent (foam/gel/film/cream/suppository). Exclusion criteria 1. Unable to provide informed consent. 2. Clinicallysignificant renal disease (Creatinine clearance &lt; 30 ml/min per 1.73 m2 calculated from CKDEpi http://www.qxmed.com/renal/CalculateCKDEPIGFR.php) or liver disease (including serum transaminases &gt; 3 times upper limit of normal). 3. Haemoglobin concentration &lt;10 g/dl. 4. Patients who meet any of the following criteria will be excluded: Iron&gt;27 umol/L, Ferritin&gt;300 ug/L or Transferrin saturations &gt;45% 5. Patients with moderate to severe hypophosphatemia as defined as &lt;0.65mmol/L 6. Known to have haemoglobinopathy e.g. sickle cell disease, thalassaemia. 7. Admission to hospital related to PAH or change in PAH therapy within 1 month prior to Screening. 8. Evidence of left ventricular disease or significant lung disease on highresolution CT scanning or lung function as judged by the investigator 9. Acute or chronic infection or inflammation. 10. Significant uncontrolled asthma as judged by the investigator, eczema or atopic allergies. 11. Females who are lactating or pregnant. 12. Individuals known to have HIV, Hepatitis B or C or CreutzfeldJakob disease. 13. Known hypersensitivity to Ferinject® or any of its excipients. 14. Evidence of disturbances in utilisation of iron. 15. Significant blood loss (e.g. GI bleed) within the last 3 months or history of menorrhagia. 16. Unable to perform a Cardiopulmonary Exercise Test i.e. due to syncope or musculoskeletal factors. 17. Patients who have received an investigational medicinal product within 30 days of entering the baseline visit</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Idiopathic pulmonary arterial hypertension (IPAH)</keyword>
	<keyword>Iron deficiency</keyword>
</DOC>