<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01631773</DOC>
	<brief_summary>We hypothesize that the miRNA expression in subjects with nasal polyps and Aspirin-exacerbated respiratory disease (AERD) differs from the miRNA expressed in subjects with nasal polyps but without Aspirin-exacerbated respiratory disease (AERD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Comparison of microRNA Samples in Patients With Nasal Polyps and Aspirin Exacerbated Respiratory Disease and Those With Nasal Polyps Only</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Nasal epithelial tissue will be collected from the inferior nasal turbinates of ten subjects with nasal polyps and AERD disease and from the inferior turbinates of ten subjects with nasal polyps but without AERD. A rhinoprobe™ will be used to collect this epithelial tissue. These samples will be analyzed by miRNA assay to determine if there is a difference in mircroRNA expression between the two subject groups.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Polyps</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiration Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nasal Polyps</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aspirin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Ages eligible for study: 18 to 70 years Genders eligible for study: male and female Signed and dated written informed consent is obtained prior to study Subjects have a physician diagnosis of nasal polyps without AERD or physician diagnosis of nasal polyps with AERD. The diagnosis of aspirin sensitive asthma must be present for a minimum of three months. If the medical history is indeterminate either an aspirin challenge will be required to confirm or rule out the diagnosis. An aspirin challenge is a protocol that can safely be performed as an out patient procedure with close supervision. Pregnant and/or lactating females. Current tobacco use. Severe psychiatric illness. Current illicit substance use or dependence and/or abuse of alcohol. Primary or secondary immunodeficiency. Any clinically significant uncontrolled medical condition that would put the patient at risk.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Aspirin-exacerbated respiratory disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Nasal polyp</keyword>
</DOC>