<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01727713</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of the current trial is to determine safety of Once-daily aripiprazole in reducing Total Tic Severity in children and adolescents with Tourette's Disorder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Tolerability of Once-daily Oral Aripiprazole in Children and Adolescents With Tourette's Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Tourette's Disorder is a neuropsychiatric condition that is characterized by the appearance of tics that can be simple or complex in nature. A tic is a sudden, rapid, recurrent, non-rhythmic, stereotyped motor movement or vocalization. There are a very limited number of medications approved for the treatment of Tourette's Disorder. The goal of the current trial is to obtain additional efficacy, safety, and tolerability data in a controlled condition of a Once-daily aripiprazole formulation in children and adolescents with Tourette's Disorder. The trial is a 52-week extension to the double-blind trial. The Once-daily tablet formulation that will be evaluated in this trial represents a daily dosage regimen that is intended to be administered to children and adolescents.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tourette Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aripiprazole</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Completed participation in Trial 3112293 Written ICF obtained from a legally acceptable representative &amp; informed assent at Baseline as applicable by trial center's IRB/IEC The subject, designated guardian(s) or caregiver(s) are able to comprehend and satisfactorily comply with the protocol requirements, as evaluated by the investigator Experienced AEs during the doubleblind trial (3112293) that would, in the investigator's judgment, preclude further exposure to aripiprazole. The subject had protocol violations during the doubleblind trial considered major in the judgment of the investigator which would deem the subject a poor candidate for the trial A positive drug screen Sexually active patients not using 2 approved methods of contraception Females breastfeeding or pregnant (positive blood pregnancy test prior to receiving trial drug) Risk of committing suicide Body weight lower than 16 kg Abnormal laboratory test results, vital signs and ECG results</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tourette Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Basal Ganglia Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Brain Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Central Nervous System Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Tic Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Tics</keyword>
	<keyword>Movement Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Mental Disorders</keyword>
	<keyword>Aripiprazole</keyword>
</DOC>