<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01727297</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is to determine, through continuous monitoring with the Reveal implantable cardiac monitor (ICM), the incidence of atrial fibrillation (AF) in patients suspected to be at high risk for having AF and to understand how physicians manage these patients after AF has been detected. This study will also seek to identify what patient characteristics are most predictive of developing AF.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>REVEAL AF: Incidence of AF in High Risk Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient meets the approved indications to receive the Reveal ICM Patient is suspected, based on symptomatology and/or demographics, of having atrial fibrillation or at high risk of having AF, as determined by the clinical investigator Patient has a CHADS2 score ≥ 3 OR has a CHADS2 score = 2 WITH at least one of the following documented: renal impairment (GFR 3060 ml/min), sleep apnea, coronary artery disease, or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Note: stroke/TIA criterion as part of the CHADS2 score for this trial is limited to either an ischemic stroke or TIA, which occurred MORE THAN one year prior to enrollment. Patient is 18 years of age or older Patient has a life expectancy of 18 months or more Patient, or legally authorized representative, is willing to sign and date the consent form Patient is willing and able to be remotely monitored (i.e., eligible for enrollment into the Medtronic CareLink Network) Patient has a documented history of AF or atrial flutter Patient had an ischemic stroke or TIA within past year prior to enrollment Patient has a history of a hemorrhagic stroke Patient is currently implanted with an IPG, ICD, CRTP, or CRTD device NYHA Class IV Heart Failure patient Patient had heart surgery within previous 90 days prior to enrollment Patient had an MI within the previous 90 days prior to enrollment Patient is taking chronic immunosuppressant therapy Patient is taking an antiarrhythmic drug Patient is contraindicated for long term anticoagulation medication Patient is taking a longterm anticoagulation medication Any concomitant condition which, in the opinion of the investigator, would not allow safe participation in the study (e.g., drug addiction, alcohol abuse, emotional / psychological diagnosis) Patient is enrolled in another study that could confound the results of this study, without documented preapproval from Medtronic study manager Patient has a creatinine clearance &lt;30 ml/min or is on dialysis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>