<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01324206</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: - Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) studies provide important information on the structure and function of various body systems, including the brain, muscles, joints, heart, and blood vessels. Scientific applications of MRI scans often use techniques that need to be modified or refined before they are used in clinical studies. To develop and modify these techniques for the new Philips 3T Achieva whole-body MRI scanner, researchers are interested in conducting trial MRI scans on healthy individuals and individuals with conditions that require imaging studies. Objectives: - To conduct preliminary trials of the 3T MRI facility to develop and refine MRI scanning procedures. Eligibility: - Individuals at least 18 years of age who are able to have magnetic resonance imaging. Design: - Participants will be screened with a full medical history and physical examination, as well as blood and urine tests. - Participants will have an MRI scan using the 3T scanner. Some scans may require the use of a contrast agent or radiotracer, which is a small amount of radioactive substance that will be injected before the start of the scan. Some participants may be asked to perform tasks of thinking and movement while in the scanner, in order to test the procedures required for a functional MRI scan. - No treatment will be provided as part of this protocol.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Development of 3T Magnetic Resonance Research Methods for NIA Studies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) studies yield important information on the structure and function of various body systems including the brain, muscles, joints, heart, blood vessels and other body areas. Unlike clinical MRI imaging, scientific applications often utilize techniques that either requires de-novo development or modification of existing research or commercially available protocols before implementation in clinical studies. The proposed protocol is intended to allow MRI scanning on human subjects for the development and refinement of MRI scanning procedures before implementation in larger scale clinical National Institute on Aging (NIA) research studies. We will evaluate a variety of MRI pulse sequences on normal volunteers and individuals with a variety of medical conditions to determine optimal protocols for use in normal volunteers and patient populations. In addition, participants can be recruited and scanned to provide additional data for already approved NIA studies.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>INCLUSION CRITERIA: Age 18 or older. Control subjects or persons identified by an investigator to have a condition of interest for exploratory studies related to the patient s illness or other feature that is relevant to other or future NIA studies Capable of providing informed consent EXCLUSION CRITERIA: Any condition or nonremovable device contraindicated for MRI, as assessed by the attached safety questionnaire. Weight greater than the specified limit of the scanner bed Pregnancy GFR &lt; 60 ml/min/1.73m(2), if receiving IV contrast Participants scheduled for an MRI with contrast will not be eligible for this MRI if the Investigator believes that their enrollment is not in their best medical interest. Participants requested to complete an exercise protocol will not be eligible for an exercise MRI if they do not meet the eligibility criteria for that particular exercise protocol. Examples include joint replacements that may be affected by the defined exercise protocol or which may prevent MRI analysis or any condition, in the opinion of the investigator, that would prevent successful completion of the exercise protocol such as, but not limited to reported osteoarthritis, rheumatoid arthritis and/or fibromyalgia.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 26, 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Whole-Body</keyword>
	<keyword>Development</keyword>
	<keyword>Exposure</keyword>
	<keyword>Magnetic</keyword>
	<keyword>Resonance</keyword>
</DOC>