<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT00595296</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>This post-approval study design determine performance FDA-approved GeneSearch™ BLN Assay compare site 's standard care permanent section histological evaluation , compare extensive histological evaluation assay use clinician make surgical decision complete axillary dissection ( ALND ) .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>GeneSearch™ Breast Lymph Node ( BLN ) Assay Post Approval Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective clinical study gather data estimate positive predictive concordance ( PPC ) GeneSearch™ BLN Assay histology routinely practice , i.e. , routine H &amp; E histology sentinel lymph node ( ) ( SLN ) , available , routine histology non-sentinel axillary lymph node ( ALN ) . This study provide information assay augment performance data gain pre-market validation study . In addition , assay use ALND decision-making , metastatic status non-sentinel axillary node take account performance measure , i.e. , patient 's sentinel non-sentinel node histologically positive , patient consider positive primary comparison assay result .</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Preoperatively establish diagnosis invasive carcinoma breast Scheduled axillary sentinel lymph node dissection per standard care clinical site newly diagnose breast cancer patient Patients GeneSearch™ BLN Assay use intraoperatively make decision axillary lymph node dissection 18 year age old Female male Willing able give inform consent participate study Previous diagnosis lymphoma Subjects participate research study would interfere full participation study Patients and/or condition 'interfering substance ' list IFU . Patients preoperative treatment breast cancer include neoadjuvant and/or hormonal intervention aromatase inhibitor tamoxifen</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>BreastCancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Sentinel Lymph Nodes</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastasis</keyword>
</DOC>