<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02325518</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate AZORGA® Ophthalmic Suspension compared to COSOPT® Ophthalmic Solution for IOP-lowering efficacy in subjects with open-angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Intraocular Pressure (IOP)-Lowering Efficacy and Safety of AZORGA® Ophthalmic Suspension and COSOPT® Ophthalmic Solution</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>After the screening examination, subjects were enrolled in the study and moved into the observation period. During the observation period, prostaglandin-analog (PGA) monotherapy was applied. After the observation period of 4 weeks or more, the baseline examination was performed. Subjects were then randomized and moved into the treatment period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glaucoma, Open-Angle</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ocular Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Maleic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brinzolamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dorzolamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Timolol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Understand the nature of the study and sign informed consent. Diagnosis of open angle glaucoma or ocular hypertension. Currently on PGA monotherapy or PGA + alpha1/beta blocker or PGA + alpha2 agonist at screening visit, and allowed to instill only PGA for 4 weeks until the baseline visit. Intraocular pressure (IOP) ≥ 15 mmHg (at least one same eye) at the baseline visit. Other protocolspecified inclusion criteria may apply. History of bronchial asthma, bronchospasm, or serious chronic obstruction pulmonary disease. Uncontrolled heart failure, sinus bradycardia, AV block (II, III grade), cardiogenic shock, right heart failure due to pulmonary hypertension or congestive heart failure. History of hypersensitivity to any of the excipients of the study medications. Severe renal function disorders, diabetic ketoacidosis and metabolic acidosis, uncontrolled diabetes, or hepatic disorders. Corneal disorder or history of chronic, recurrent or current severe inflammatory eye disease in either eye. History of ocular trauma in either eye within 6 months prior to the screening examination. Ocular infection or ocular inflammation in either eye. History of or current clinically significant or progressive retinal disease in either eye. Intraocular surgery in either eye within 6 months prior to the screening examination. Ocular laser surgery in either eye within 3 months prior to the screening examination. Any abnormality preventing reliable applanation tonometry of either eye. Bestcorrected visual acuity (BCVA) worse than 0.2 score (decimal visual acuity) in either eye. Severe visual field loss in either eye. Use of prohibited medication, as specified in the protocol. Pregnant, lactating, or intending to become pregnant during the study period. Currently on therapy or have been on therapy with another investigational agent within 30 days prior to the screening examination. History of or current evidence of a severe illness or any other condition which would make the subject, in the opinion of the investigator, unsuitable for the study. Other protocolspecified exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Open-angle glaucoma (OAG)</keyword>
	<keyword>Ocular hypertension (OHT)</keyword>
	<keyword>AZORGA®</keyword>
	<keyword>COSOPT®</keyword>
</DOC>