<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00254332</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a blood and tissue study to determine the effect of the drug called denileukin diftitox on the immune system cells that may be involved in patient response to their cutaneous t-cell lymphoma. Patients who are undergoing standard of care therapy with denileukin diftitox will be invited to participate. Blood and tissue samples will be obtained at baseline, day 5 and day 19 in up to the first 4 cycles of denileukin diftitox.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Denileukin Diftitox on Immune System in CTCL Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Although the etiology of CTCL is not fully understood, it is believed to be a malignancy proliferation of a "memory" T-cell in the context of Th2-type cytokine profile and suppressed cytotoxic T-cell (CTL) immunity. T-regulatory (T-regs) cells may be important in CTCL in the setting of immunotherapy. Removal of T-regs would result in enhanced immune responses in vitro, which may translate into augmentation of the anti-tumor immune response and durable clinical responses in vivo. We propose to evaluate effects of ONTAK on the T-reg cell subset in patients undergoing routine therapy with ONTAK. We will evaluate T-reg subsets in peripheral blood and tumor tissues from the patients both phenotypically using multi-color FACS analysis and confocal microscopy, and functionally in MLRs and ELISpot assays with baseline, day 5 and 19 blood samples in up to four cycles. Completion date provided represents the completion date of the grant per OOPD records</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycoses</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycosis Fungoides</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sezary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Cutaneous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Denileukin diftitox</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interleukin-2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 and older diagnosed with CTCL able and willing to provide informed consent will be receiving denileukin diftitox per standard guidelines prior history of receiving Ontak pregnancy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cutaneous T-cell Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Sezary Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Mycosis Fungoides</keyword>
	<keyword>Denileukin Diftitox</keyword>
</DOC>