<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01914874</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to evaluate the feasibility and initial efficacy of an enhanced mindfulness-based program that includes "mindful exposure" to reduce anxiety and avoidance of social situations, and the Buddhist practice of self-compassion aimed at reducing harsh judgment and self-criticism that is characteristic of people with social anxiety disorder.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy of a Mindfulness Meditation Program for Social Anxiety Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this pilot study is to evaluate the feasibility and initial efficacy of an enhanced mindfulness-based intervention for SAD (MIND-SAD) that incorporates the following components: training in classical mindfulness, including concentration and insight (vipassana) meditation; training in self-compassion; and mindful exposure. An exploratory aim of the study is to evaluate the effects of the mindfulness intervention on biological markers of stress reactivity, including salivary cortisoland salivary alpha-amylase. The study is a two-arm, parallel design, prospective study comparing 12 weekly sessions of MIND-SAD delivered in a group format versus a wait-list control (WLC).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Phobic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Primary diagnosis of Social Anxiety Disorder; Baseline score of 30 or higher on the Liebowitz Social Anxiety Scale; Baseline score of 4 or higher on the Clinical Global Impression of Severity Lifetime history of psychosis or bipolar disorder; substance abuse in the past 12 months; diagnosis of borderline or antisocial personality disorder; serious suicide risk; currently in psychotherapy; regular meditation or yoga practice in the past 12 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Community Sample</keyword>
</DOC>