<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02058446</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The antihypertensive effect of Amlodipine/Valsartan combination has been evaluated in worldwide populations including Asian patients. The study primarily aims to evaluate the effectiveness of Amlodipine/Valsartan combination in patients with essential hypertension in Taiwan using a prospective, open-label, non-randomized approach. The study also wants to investigate the safety of Amlodipine/Valsartan combination during the 6-week treatment period.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PMS Study of Amlodipine/Valsartan for the Treatment of Hypertension</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amlodipine, Valsartan Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Valsartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amlodipine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who are 2080 years of age Patients with essential hypertension (90 mmHg ≤ DBP ≤ 110 mmHg and/or 140 mmHg ≤ SBP ≤ 180 mmHg) whose BP is not adequately controlled with amlodipine (or another CCB) alone or with valsartan (or another ARB) alone, or with any antihypertensive monotherapy. Agree to and are able to follow the study procedures Understand the nature of the study, and have signed informed consent forms Patients with any of the following conditions: 1. Malignant (or history of malignant) hypertension 2. Secondary hypertension 3. Severe hypertension (mean sitting DBP ≥ 110 mmHg and/or mean sitting SBP ≥ 180 mmHg) 4. A history of hypertensive encephalopathy or cerebrovascular accident 5. Cerebrovascular accident, myocardial infraction within 3 months, or any type of revascularization 6. New York Heart Association class III IV congestive heart failure 7. Second or thirddegree heart block 8. Angina pectoris 9. Significant arrhythmia or valvular heart disease 10. Significant pancreatic, hepatic, or renal disease 11. Diabetes requiring insulin treatment or poorly controlled type 2 diabetes Patients with known contraindication or a history of allergy to CCBs or ARBs. Female patients who are pregnant or lactating. Male or female patients of childbearing potential who do not agree to use an effective method of contraception during the study Patients is currently participating in any other clinical trial within 30 days</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>