<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03104543</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Survivors of childhood cancer are known to be at higher risk of developing premature, serious cardiovascular disease compared with the general population. Hypertension, dyslipidemia, and diabetes increase this risk beyond that attributable to one's original cancer therapy exposures. Research has shown that childhood cancer survivors also have a high burden of underdiagnosis and undertreatment of these potentially modifiable conditions. The goal of this study is to: 1. To determine the prevalence of underdiagnosis and undertreatment of common cardiometabolic conditions (i.e., hypertension, dyslipidemia, diabetes) in survivors of childhood cancer at high-risk of future serious cardiovascular disease. 2. Among survivors who are found to be underdiagnosed or undertreated, to determine (via randomized clinical trial) the efficacy of a counseling/educational intervention to improve control of these cardiometabolic conditions. 3. Determine barriers on among survivors enrolled on the randomized trial and their primary healthcare providers that contribute to undertreatment of the study's targeted cardiometabolic conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Communicating Health Information and Improving Coordination With Primary Care</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Dyslipidemias</mesh_term>
	<criteria>CCSS participant who is age ≥18 years at time of consent High cardiovascular risk status based on CCSS risk prediction models for cardiomyopathy and ischemic heart disease Able to read, write, and speak English At least one abnormal CV condition identified on home visit: blood pressure ≥130/85 mmHg or ≥140/90 if preexisting hypertension; LDL ≥160 mg/dL; triglyceride ≥150 mg/dL; or glucose ≥100 mg/dL or HbA1c ≥5.7% (if not previously diabetic), HbA1c ≥7% (if known diabetic) Free of known selfreported ischemic heart disease or cardiomyopathy Have access to a telephone to receive a phonebased counseling session Participants who previously participated in a CCSSsponsored home visit or survivorship care planbased study are excluded Participants with known cardiomyopathy or ischemic heart disease based on prior CCSS surveys are excluded</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>survivor</keyword>
	<keyword>undertreatment</keyword>
	<keyword>adherence</keyword>
	<keyword>self-efficacy</keyword>
</DOC>