<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02982408</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Low birth weight (LBW), a marker of impaired fetal growth is an independent and strong risk factor for type 2 diabetes (T2D). A western lifestyle characterized by a surplus of calories, and/or a low physical activity level, associated with increased fat storage and altered lipid metabolism plays a central role in the pathogenesis of insulin resistance and T2D. Using state-of-the-art large-scale integrative physiology studies combined with basic studies of adipose and muscle tissue stem cell functions, the investigators aim to determine if LBW individuals exhibit decreased subcutaneous adipose tissue expandability, postprandial hyperlipidaemia and ectopic fat accumulation when exposed to 4 weeks of carbohydrate overfeeding. The investigators will subsequently examine if exercise training can revert and/or minimize the deleterious effects of carbohydrate overfeeding in a possibly birth weight differential manner.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Overfeeding and Following Exercise Training in Individuals With and Without Increased Risk of Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyslipidemias</mesh_term>
	<criteria>without known disease (approved health examination) caucasian born at term (weeks 3941) in Denmark recruited from the national Danish Birth Registry born with either low or normal birthweight (see previous) family history of diabetes in two generations (1st and 2nd degree relatives) selfreported high physical activity level (&gt;10hrs /week). weight loss/gain &gt;3 kg within the past 6 months alcohol intake of more than general recommendations substance abuser intake of medication know to affect outcomes</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>