<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02982226</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this clinical trial is to evaluate both the safety and efficacy of the ReNu™ injection on pain and inflammation in subjects diagnosed with plantar fasciitis as compared to a Corticosteroid Injection which is considered standard of care.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ReNu™ vs. Corticosteroids for the Treatment of Plantar Fasciitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a two (2) arm evaluation in 150 subjects with plantar fasciitis. Patients will be treated with ReNu™(study treatment) or Corticosteroids (control). At each follow-up visit, concomitant medications and adverse events shall be collected from each subject, and each subject shall complete following questionnaires: - AOFAS Ankle-Hindfoot Score (AOFAS-AHS) - Visual Analog Score (VAS) - Single Answer Numeric Evaluation (SANE) - Subject Satisfaction Score (at the 6 Month Follow Ups ONLY) The subjects will be assessed at Baseline (pre-injection) using these scales and again at all subsequent study follow-up visits.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fasciitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fasciitis, Plantar</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Ages 18 to 75 inclusive 2. BMI less than 40 3. Actively practicing a contraception method, abstinent, surgically sterile, or postmenopausal (defined as no menses for a minimum of 12 months) 4. Reporting heel pain of &gt;6 on a verbally administered 110 pain scale where 1 is no pain and 10 is extreme pain 5. Diagnosed with plantar fasciitis in either foot 6. Completed a minimum of two months of conservative, noninjection treatment/therapies (i.e., activity modification, icing, NSAIDs, orthotics, physical therapy, etc.) Exclusion Criteria 1. Prior surgery on the affected foot 2. Prior injection treatment for plantar fasciitis within the past 6 months with steroids or tissue engineered materials just in the site seeking treatment 3. Clinical signs and symptoms of infection of foot in question 4. Evidence of significant neurological disease of either foot 5. Nonambulatory 6. Presence of comorbidities that can be confused with or can exacerbate the condition including, but not limited to the following: Calcaneal stress fracture Nerve entrapment syndrome, such as Baxter's Nerve Entrapment or Tarsal Tunnel Syndrome Plantar Fascial rupture Systemic disorders associated with enthesiopathy, i.e., Gout, Reiter's syndrome, rheumatoid arthritis, etc. Achilles tendonitis Fat Pad Atrophy Fibromyalgia Diabetic Neuropathy 7. Pregnant, pregnant within the past six (6) months, breast feeding and/or desire to become pregnant during the course of the study, as verified by urine pregnancy test within one week prior to injection. 8. Has taken NSAID medication within the past 14 days, or other pain medication in the past day 9. History of more than two (2) weeks treatment with immunosuppressants, including systemic corticosteroids or cytotoxic chemotherapy within one month prior to initial screening, or has receive such medications during the screening period, or are anticipated to require such medications during the course of the study. 10. Taking any investigational drug(s) or therapeutic device(s) within 30 days preceding screening 11. History of radiation therapy of the affected foot 12. Known history of having Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (AIDS) or HIV 13. Involved in a Worker's Compensation Claim of any kind 14. Unable to understand the objectives of the trial 15. Presence of any condition(s) which, in the opinion of the investigator, would compromise the subject's ability to complete this study 16. Having a known history of poor adherence with medical treatment. 17. Express an unwillingness to receive human allograft tissue</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Plantar Fasciitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Jogger's Heel</keyword>
	<keyword>ReNu</keyword>
</DOC>