<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02425579</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the safety of inhaled carbon monoxide (iCO) in intubated patients with sepsis-induced ARDS.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Study of Inhaled Carbon Monoxide to Treat Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is a syndrome of severe acute lung inflammation and hypoxemic respiratory failure with an incidence of 180,000 cases annually in the U.S.Despite decades of research and recent advances in lung protective ventilator strategies, morbidity and mortality remain unacceptably high. Furthermore, no specific effective pharmacologic therapies currently exist. The lack of specific effective therapies for sepsis-related ARDS indicates a need for new treatments that target novel pathways. Carbon monoxide (CO) represents a novel therapeutic modality in ARDS based on data obtained in experimental models of ARDS and sepsis over the past decade. CO has been shown to be protective in experimental models of Acute Lung Injury (ALI), including hyperoxia and endotoxin exposure, bleomycin, ischemia/reperfusion, and ventilator-induced lung injury (VILI). At low doses, CO has been shown to confer tissue protective effects in these ALI models. In addition, CO has been shown to decrease inflammation, enhance phagocytosis, and improve mortality in models of sepsis including endotoxemia, hemorrhagic shock, and cecal ligation and puncture (CLP). CO has also been shown to have beneficial therapeutic effects in pre-clinical models of disease including pulmonary hypertension, vascular injury, and transplantation. Furthermore, multiple human studies have demonstrated that experimental administration of several different concentrations of CO is well tolerated and that low dose inhaled CO can be safely administered to subjects in a controlled research environment. The purpose of this study is to assess the safety of inhaled CO therapy in mechanically ventilated patients with sepsis-induced ARDS.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carbon Monoxide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients with sepsis are defined as those with suspected or documented infection: Suspected or proven infection: Sites of infection include thorax, urinary tract, abdomen, skin, sinuses, central venous catheters, and central nervous system 2. ARDS is defined when all four of the following criteria are met: A PaO2/FiO2 ratio ≤ 300 with at least 5 cm H2O positive endexpiratory airway pressure (PEEP) Bilateral infiltrates consistent with pulmonary edema on frontal chest radiograph A need for positive pressure ventilation by an endotracheal or tracheal tube No clinical evidence of left atrial hypertension for bilateral pulmonary infiltrates. 3. ARDS onset is defined as the time the last of criteria 14 are met. ARDS must persist through the enrollment time window of 120 hours. 4. Infiltrates considered "consistent with pulmonary edema" include any infiltrates not fully explained by mass, atelectasis, or effusion or opacities known to be chronic (greater than 1 week). Vascular redistribution, indistinct vessels, and indistinct heart borders alone are not considered "consistent with pulmonary edema" and thus would not count as qualifying opacities for this study. 1. Age less than 18 years 2. Greater than 120 hours since ARDS onset 3. Pregnant or breastfeeding 4. Prisoner 5. Patient, surrogate, or physician not committed to full support (exception: a patient will not be excluded if he/she would receive all supportive care except for attempts at resuscitation from cardiac arrest) 6. No consent/inability to obtain consent 7. Physician refusal to allow enrollment in the trial 8. Moribund patient not expected to survive 24 hours 9. No arterial line/no intent to place an arterial line 10. No intent/unwillingness to follow lung protective ventilation strategy 11. Severe hypoxemia defined as SpO2 &lt;95 or PaO2 &lt;80 on FiO2 ≥0.8 12. Hemoglobin &lt; 7.5 g/dl upon admission to the ICU or hemoglobin &lt; 8 g/dl and actively bleeding upon admission to the ICU 13. Subjects who are Jehovah's Witnesses or are otherwise unable or unwilling to receive blood transfusions during hospitalization 14. Acute myocardial infarction (MI) or acute coronary syndrome (ACS) within the last 90 days 15. Coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) surgery within 30 days 16. Angina pectoris or use of nitrates with activities of daily living 17. Cardiopulmonary disease classified as NYHA class IV 18. Stroke (ischemic or hemorrhagic) within the prior 3 months 19. Diffuse alveolar hemorrhage from vasculitis 20. Use of high frequency ventilation 21. Participation in other interventional studies 22. Burns &gt; 40% total body surface area 23. Use of inhaled vasodilator therapy (eg. NO or prostaglandins)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>