<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02250053</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Despite the success of surgery and chemotherapy among people with colon cancer, 30-50% of patients develop recurrent disease. Physical activity has emerged as a potential lifestyle intervention to reduce cancer recurrence and improve survival among people with colon cancer (CC). This pilot study aims to identify the dose-response effects of aerobic exercise on molecular and cellular pathways associated with physical activity and CC outcomes among patients with stage II and III CC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Exercise and Colon Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colonic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. histologically confirmed TNM stage IIIII CC; 2. completed surgical resection and adjuvant chemotherapy (if applicable) within 124 months before entering the study; 3. ≤120 min/wk of selfreported moderate or vigorous intensity physical activity using the Paffenbarger physical activity questionnaire; 4. age ≥18 years; 5. written physician approval; 6. no additional surgery planned within the 6month intervention (including colostomy reversal); 7. ability to walk unaided for 6minutes; 8. no contraindications to exercise using the PA readiness questionnaire (PARQ), unless physician approves participation with specific knowledge of this contraindication. 1. history of another primary invasive cancer (other than nonmelanoma skincancer); 2. evidence of metastatic CC (i.e., TNM M1); 3. planning to receive any additional adjuvant chemotherapy; 4. pregnant or breast feeding; 5. unable to provide baseline blood sample; 6. cardiac conditions, including the following: 1. myocardial infarction or coronary revascularization procedure within prior 3 months; 2. uncontrolled hypertension (systolic ≥180 mmHg or diastolic ≥100 mmHg); 3. highrisk or uncontrolled arrhythmias; 4. clinically significant valvular disease; 5. decompensated heart failure; 6. known aortic aneurysm; 7. any other condition that may impede testing of the study hypothesis or make it unsafe to engage in the exercise program (determined by the investigative team).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage II and stage III colon cancer survivors, who have completed curative treatment i.e., surgical resection and chemotherapy for their colon cancer</keyword>
</DOC>