<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01941030</DOC>
	<brief_summary>CLARITY I is a pilot study to identify the clinically appropriate endpoint(s) of a larger, statistically powered pivotal trial for treatment of patients with Critical Limb Ischemia (CLI).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Complete Lesion Assessment With Fractional ffR and IVUS TechnologY</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>50 subjects will be randomized 1:1 to Orbital Atherectomy (OA) performed with Cardiovascular Systems, Inc.'s Orbital Atherectomy System (OAS) followed by adjunctive balloon angioplasty (BA) vs. BA alone for treatment of tibial vessel disease, defined as ≥ 50 % stenosis of the tibial arteries (AT, PT, TPT, and PR) by angiography. All subjects will have a corresponding wound being fed by the target vessel which will be assessed during the study. Subjects enrolled in this study may be rolled into the larger pivotal trial, as appropriate.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>General Subject's age ≥ 18 years. Subject is an acceptable candidate for percutaneous intervention with the Sponsor's OAS and BA in accordance with their labeled indications and instructions for use; Subject is willing and able to sign an approved informed consent form(ICF); Subject is willing and able to attend followup and wound care visits. General Subject is pregnant or planning to become pregnant within the study period. Subject is currently participating in an investigational drug or other device study that can clinically interfere with the endpoints of this trial. Subject has a known sensitivity to contrast media and the sensitivity cannot be adequately premedicated. Uncontrolled allergy to nitinol, stainless steel, or other stent materials. Subject has known allergy to atherectomy lubricant components such as soybean oil, egg yolk phospholipids, glycerin or sodium hydroxide. Subject has a history of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy or will refuse blood transfusions. Subject has been diagnosed with chronic renal failure or has a creatinine level &gt; 2.5, unless on dialysis, prior to the index treatment. Subject has a planned major surgery (includes major amputation) scheduled within 60 days after treatment of the index limb. Subject has a planned interventional treatment to address stenosis of the contralateral limb scheduled within 60 days after the index treatment. Subject has a planned interventional treatment to address inflow stenosis of the ipsilateral limb scheduled within 60 days after the index treatment. Subject has previously had their other limb treated as part of the study Angiographic 1. Target lesion(s) located in the anterior tibial (AT), posterior tibial (PT), tibial peroneal trunk (TPT) or peroneal (PR) arteries. 2. Target lesion has ≥ 50 % stenosis by angiography. 3. Subject has a corresponding wound being fed by the target vessel Angiographic 1. Target limb does not have any visual flow to the foot confirmed via distal selective angiography. 2. Thrombus is present or suspected in the target treatment vessel. 3. Target lesion is within a bypass graft or near a previously placed stent. 4. The guide wire cannot be passed across the target lesion. 5. Anterograde access of the lesion is not possible. 6. Subject has angiographic evidence of significant dissection at or near the treatment site. 7. Interventional treatment is intended for instent restenosis at the peripheral vascular site. 8. Subject's wound(s) involve multiple angiosomes.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Peripheral Artery Disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Critical Limb Ischemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Orbital Atherectomy</keyword>
	<keyword>Balloon Angioplasty</keyword>
	<keyword>Intravascular Ultrasound (IVUS)</keyword>
	<keyword>Fractional Flow Reserve (FFR)</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
</DOC>