<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01941966</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The squamous cell carcinoma (SCC) of the anal canal is an uncommon neoplasia which corresponds to 1-5% of intestinal tumors. However the risk of SCC of the anal canal has been growing recently. The standard treatment of anal cancer stage II-III is multimodal and consists of combined chemotherapy (infusional 5-fluorouracil and mitomycin) and radiotherapy. This scheme currently used was proposed in 1974, and since then no other effective treatment has been developed. The purpose of this study is to determine the efficacy and toxicity of the combination of capecitabine and mitomycin with radiotherapy in patients with carcinoma of the anal canal. For this will be selected 51 patients to be treated with chemo-radiotherapy. The primary endpoint will be local control rate after 6 months of the end of radiotherapy and chemotherapy, defined by the rate of radiological and clinical neoplasia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Substitution of 5-FU (Fluorouracil) by Capecitabine in Scheme of Chemo-radiotherapy in Patients With Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Anal Canal.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anus Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitomycins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mitomycin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Invasive anal canal SCC histologically confirmed, T24 N0 M0, T (anyone) N13 M0 according to TNM staging system. Age ≥ 18 years. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 2. Adequate medullar function, defined as: Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,5×109/L; platelets ≥100×109/L; hemoglobin ≥10g/dl. Serum AST (aspartato aminotransferase) and ALT (alanine aminotransferase) &lt; 3 × ULN (upper limit of normal). Serum Creatinine ≤ 1,5 ULN and clearance of creatinine estimated (Cockcroft Gault) ≥ 50 ml/min. Signed written informed consent. Major surgical procedure within 4 weeks of the beginning of the treatment. History of severe systemic or psychiatric disease. Previous treatment for anal canal carcinoma or other cancer. For female patients, current pregnancy and/or lactation Unstable angina or acute myocardial infarction within 6 months. Concomitant use of oral anticoagulants HIV positive with result of CD4 ≤ 200. Previously pelvic radiotherapy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anal canal cancer;capecitabine; mitomycin; radiotherapy.</keyword>
</DOC>