<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02483130</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A double-blind, placebo controlled, crossover study to determine whether a single dose of N-acetylcysteine (a nutritional supplement) can reduce brain glutamate levels in patients with a psychotic disorder. Secondary outcomes are to determine the pattern of alteration in brain perfusion and activity following a single dose of N-acetylcysteine.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of N-acetylcysteine on Brain Glutamate</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a physiological, proof-of-concept study designed to investigate whether a single administration of N-acetylcysteine can reduce brain glutamate levels in people with psychotic disorders. Previous research suggests that poor response to antipsychotics may be linked to increased levels of glutamate in the brain (Egerton et al., 2012; Demjaha, Egerton et al., 2013). Reducing brain glutamate levels may therefore be therapeutic. This study tests whether it is possible to reduce brain glutamate levels in psychotic disorders. This is a small pilot study to determine whether a single administration of NAC can reduce brain glutamate levels in psychosis. At the same time, we will also examine the effects of NAC on brain resting perfusion and activity, to gain more information about how NAC may be acting. This study will recruit participants with a previous diagnosis of a psychotic disorder. There will be three study visits, 1-2 weeks apart. The first visit will involve a physical health check, blood sample and an interview to assess current symptoms and confirm medical history. On the second and third visits participants will have an MRI scan, lasting one hour, after taking capsules containing either 2400mg NAC or placebo.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Acetylcysteine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>N-monoacetylcystine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Over 18 years of age Diagnosis of a psychotic disorder Have mental capacity to consent Diagnosed drug or alcohol dependency, with the exception of nicotine Pregnancy, as determined through a urine pregnancy test Presence of any physical health abnormality which may impact on safety to participate in the research, as determined by a study clinician on the basis of the physical health check and the available medical information. Presence of electronic or metallic implants contraindicated to MRI scanning at 3 Tesla, or presence of any other contraindication to MRI History of asthma History of epilepsy or any other seizure Under 18 years of age Lacking mental capacity to consent Current or previous use of NAC Currently prescribed clozapine</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>