<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02483026</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will examine the effect of providing a structured program of daily nutritional supplements for a 6 weeks of intervention prior to Sleeve Gastrectomy bariatric surgery on bone mass density status and formation of critical nutritional deficiencies years after the surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nutritional Deficiencies Preventive Treatment Prior to Laparoscopic Sleeve Gastrectomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The present study hypothesis holds that providing an adequate nutritional supplements program prior to the surgery, combined with postoperative monitoring, will significantly lower the incidence of nutritional deficiencies in patients undergoing Sleeve Gastrectomy surgery, and will reduce complications arising from these pre-operative deficiencies. The investigators plan to examine the effect of Vitamins supplementation prior to surgery on the status of postoperative deficiencies one year after the surgery. Evaluation of outcomes will be made based on the results of blood tests specified, and related tests of bone density.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bone Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Candidates for bariatric surgery BMI over 35 kg / m 2 accompanying morbidity or BMI over 40 kg / m 2, preoperative evaluation standards with matching to carry sleeve gastrectomy surgery Vitamin D deficiency prior to surgery patients who underwent bariatric surgery in the past psychiatric or mentally contraindication for the procedure lack of consent to followup endocrine problem that affects the weight that is unbalanced. Chronic kidney disease (CKD), nephrolithiasis Hypercalcaemia Hypercalciuria and renal stones nephrolithiasis Known metabolic bone disease before surgery Pregnancy, breastfeeding Using medications or disease condition known as affecting the status of calcium or bone metabolism Taking any nutritional supplements 2 weeks before the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>