<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02119676</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if ruxolitinib, in combination with regorafenib, is safe and effective in the treatment of metastatic colorectal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Ruxolitinib in Colorectal Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The study consists of an open-label, Part 1 safety run-in (consisting of 1 to 3 cohorts of 9 subjects each), to confirm the safety of the regorafenib/ruxolitinib combination in subjects with relapsed or refractory metastatic colorectal cancer (CRC). If determined to be tolerable, Part 2 will proceed as a randomized, double-blind study evaluating ruxolitinib or placebo in combination with regorafenib in subjects with relapsed or refractory metastatic CRC previously treated with fluoropyrimidine, oxaliplatin, and/or irinotecan based chemotherapy, an anti-vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) therapy and if Kirsten rat sarcoma (KRAS) wild type an anti-epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) therapy. Subjects in the safety run-in will receive open-label ruxolitinib and regorafenib; for the randomized, double-blind portion of the study all subjects will receive regorafenib and either ruxolitinib or placebo in a 1:1 blinded manner. Treatment for all subjects will consist of repeating 28-day cycles. Regorafenib will be self-administered for the first 21 days of each cycle, and ruxolitinib/placebo will be self-administered during the entire 28-day cycle. Treatment cycles will continue as long as the regimen is tolerated, and the subject does not meet the discontinuation criteria. When subjects discontinue regorafenib, ruxolitinib or placebo they will remain in the study and be followed for subsequent treatment regimens which are initiated and survival.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the colon or rectum that is metastatic. Previous treatment with fluoropyrimidine, oxaliplatin and irinotecan based chemotherapy, an antiVEGF therapy (if no contraindication) and if KRAS wild type and no contraindication, an antiEGFR therapy. Radiographically measurable or evaluable disease (per RECIST v1.1) Life expectancy of ≥ 12 weeks. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 to 2 Three or more weeks have elapsed from the completion of previous treatment regimen and subjects must have recovered or be at a new stable baseline from any related toxicities. Prior radiotherapy to disease sites is allowed with certain protocoldefined restrictions. Prior treatment with regorafenib. Presence of active gastrointestinal disease or other condition that will interfere significantly with the absorption of drugs. Active peptic ulcer disease, inflammatory bowel disease (eg, ulcerative colitis, Crohn's disease), diverticulitis, or other gastrointestinal conditions with increased risk of perforation or gastrointestinal bleeding. Recent history (≤ 3 months) or ongoing partial or complete bowel obstruction unless due to disease under study and corrected with surgery. Blood pressure ≥ 140/90 mmHg. Active bleeding diathesis or history of any major bleeding (eg, requiring transfusion of red blood cells (RBCs), central nervous system (CNS) bleeding, or significant hemoptysis within 6 months of enrollment. Subjects with bleeding secondary to underlying disease (including gastrointestinal (GI) perforation or fistula) that has been corrected by surgery or alternative procedure may be included.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic Colorectal Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Colon Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Ruxolitinib</keyword>
	<keyword>adenocarcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>regorafenib</keyword>
	<keyword>Jakavi ®</keyword>
	<keyword>Jakafi ®</keyword>
	<keyword>Stivarga ®</keyword>
</DOC>