<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00363480</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The majority of asthma patients are not well controlled, despite the availability of asthma medication that could effectively treat the disease. In this study uncontrolled patients who are steroid-naive or on low dose inhaled corticosteroids will be treated with Seretide (salmeterol/fluticasone combination, SFC) 50/250 µg twice daily. The asthma control test (ACT) will be used to detect differences in the level of asthma control during treatment. The study aims to show a correlation between improvements of ACT und the level of asthma control which will be reached by the patients. The aim of the study is to show that most of symptomatic asthma patients can reach 'well controlled asthma' with SFC. We get information about ACT in daily practice and physicians are trained to use the asthma control test as a screening tool and for follow up of asthma management. Correlations are expected between the improvements in ACT, Quality of Life and asthma control according to the Gaining Optimal Asthma controL (GOAL) criteria.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Results Of Patient Rated Asthma Control Test In Comparison To Diary Card Data</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone Propionate, Salmeterol Xinafoate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Salmeterol Xinafoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluticasone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Diagnosis of asthma Reversibility &gt;12% after inhalation of 200 µg Salbutamol willingness and ability to complete daily record card on daily basis and to measure morning PEF on daily basis 80% compliance in diary card completion asthma control status: Uncontrolled based on the GOAL criteria Exclusion criteria: Change of asthma medication during the last 4 weeks Asthma exacerbation characterized by use of oral corticoids during the last 3 months Pretreatment with inhaled corticosteroids more than 500 mcg Beclometasondipropionat or equivalent per day or other controller therapy during the last 3 months upper or lower respiratory tract infection during the RUNIN period moderate or severe asthma exacerbation during the RUNIN period Non compliance with use of Discus, PEFmeter and incomplete diary card data</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Asthma</keyword>
	<keyword>Asthma Control Test</keyword>
	<keyword>SERETIDE</keyword>
</DOC>