<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01863576</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this trial is to study the effects of omega-3 PUFA supplementation on the inflammatory response and lipid profile in patients with chronic Chagas cardiomyopathy. Study Type: Interventional Study Design: A total 40 patients will be randomly assigned into two parallel groups. The intervention will be treatment with omega-3 PUFAs at a dose of 3 g/day for 8 weeks, compared to placebo (corn oil). The primary endpoints will be the concentrations of inflammatory markers (IL-1, IL-2, IL-4, IL-6, IL-10, TNF-alpha, IFN-γ, and TGF-β). Secondary endpoints will be the fasting glucose, lipid, and anthropometric profiles.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Omega-3 Supplementation on the Cytokine and Lipid Profiles in Patients With Chronic Chagas Cardiomyopathy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Several studies have shown the beneficial effects of polyunsaturated fatty acids on inflammatory processes, dyslipidemia, and cardiovascular diseases, there are no reports about food intake and PUFA supplementation in chronic Chagas cardiomyopathy patients. Thus, the objective of this study is to assess the effects of omega-3 PUFA supplementation on the lipid profile and the pro-inflammatory and anti-inflammatory cytokine profiles in chronic Chagas cardiomyopathy patients. After patients are selected by cardiologists, they will be seen by study nutritionists, who will explain the study procedures to the patients and administer the free and informed consent form. The patients who agree to participate in the study will sign the consent form and undergo the initial assessment. The following data will be collected and evaluated in the study: sociodemographic data (age, sex, ethnicity/race, education, and domicile), clinical data (functional class and vital signs), alcoholism, smoking, prescription drugs, 3-day food record, 24-hour recall, anthropometric assessment (height, weight, BMI, waist circumference, tricipital skinfold thickness, and arm circumference), lipid profile (total cholesterol, triglycerides, HDL-c, LDL-c, and VLDL-c), and cytokines (IL-1, IL-2, IL-4, IL-6, IL-10, TNF-alpha, IFN-γ, and TGF-β). Clinical, nutritional, and anthropometric assessments will take place immediately before starting the intervention and after 4 and 8 weeks during the study; lipid profile and cytokines will be evaluated before the intervention and at the end of 8 weeks. Each patient will be followed for 8 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiomyopathies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chagas Cardiomyopathy</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Volunteers with Chagas Cardiomyopathy at stage B (no heart failure symptoms but with segmental or global left ventricular systolic dysfunction), stage C (symptomatic heart failure), or stage D (endstage heart failure)), according to the current Brazilian Chagas' Disease Consensus; Subjects will include adults, men and women. diarrheal disease; inflammatory bowel syndrome; diagnosis of diabetes or other endocrine pathologies; use of fibrates, niacin, or statins; use of antiinflammatory drugs; pregnant and lactating women; vitamin mineral or omega3 supplementation during the previous 30 days; hospital admission during the study; presence of cardiomyopathies other than Chagas Cardiomyopathy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Chagas disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Chagas Cardiomyopathy</keyword>
	<keyword>Trypanosoma cruzi</keyword>
	<keyword>Omega-3</keyword>
	<keyword>Cytokines</keyword>
	<keyword>Lipid profile</keyword>
	<keyword>Nutritional assessment</keyword>
</DOC>