<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00371826</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this study is to assess the safety and efficacy of corticosteroid discontinuation versus cyclosporine micro emulsion discontinuation in recipients receiving reduced exposure cyclosporine micro emulsion and corticosteroids plus enteric-coated mycophenolate sodium (EC-MPS) initially, changed to everolimus at 2 weeks post-transplant. These two groups will be compared to a third control group, who will receive treatment consisting of cyclosporine micro emulsion, enteric-coated mycophenolate sodium (EC-MPS) and steroids.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>SOCRATES: Steroid or Cyclosporine Removal After Transplantation Using Everolimus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mycophenolate mofetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcineurin Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria 1. Males and females aged 1865 years inclusive. 2. First time recipients of cadaveric, living unrelated or living related donor kidney transplants. 3. Patients who are willing and able to participate in the study and from whom written informed consent has been obtained. Exclusion criteria 1. Patients who are recipients of multiple organ transplants, including more than one kidney, kidney and pancreas, or previous transplant with any organ other than kidney. 2. Patients at high immunological risk of graft loss, indicated by peak PRA &gt;50% or loss of a previous renal allograft within the first 6 months of transplantation due to acute rejection. 3. Patients who have received an investigational drug within 4 weeks prior to the screening visit. 4. Presence of any severe allergy or hypersensitivity to drugs similar to everolimus (e.g. antibiotics such as Clindamycin) Other protocoldefined inclusion/exclusion criteria may applied</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Renal transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>everolimus</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunosuppressants</keyword>
</DOC>