<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00365807</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The current study examined the effectiveness of a behaviorally-based group intervention for overweight children and their families. The target intervention was compared to an enhanced standard of care treatment. The impact of both treatment programs on numerous outcomes was explored.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Examination of a Treatment Program for Overweight Children, Adolescents, and Their Families</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective of the present investigation was to determine the effectiveness of an empirically supported intervention for pediatric overweight in two outpatient clinical settings. A number of previous randomized clinical trials have demonstrated the efficacy of behaviorally-based group interventions for overweight children and their families. As called for by Kazdin and Weisz (1998) and Chambless and Hollon (1998) the proposed investigation was designed to demonstrate the effectiveness of such a treatment in a clinical setting, and to examine the effects of the intervention on children's quality of life (QOL). Because the clinical impact of empirically supported interventions is mitigated by economic and consumer variables, a secondary aim of the proposed investigation was to examine (1) the cost-effectiveness of an outpatient group intervention for pediatric obesity, and (2) the consumer satisfaction with the proposed intervention. Finally, an additional exploratory aim was to examine predictors of adherence to treatment for the intervention.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Child between ages 7 and 17 (inclusive) Child BMI at or above the 85th percentile based on norms provided for age and gender Child's parent/guardian provides informed consent for treatment of the child as well as consent for study participation Child's parent/caregiver is willing to participate with the child in the program Presence of serious mental illnesses or significant developmental delay that would reasonably predict altered ability to adhere to the treatment protocol Current physical illness or hospitalization of the child that would interfere with group attendance or protocol adherence</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>Overweight</keyword>
	<keyword>Behavioral treatment</keyword>
	<keyword>Family involvement</keyword>
</DOC>