<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01908803</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate a single application of AL-60371/AL-817 Otic Suspension relative to ototopical CIPRODEX for microbiological success at Day 8 and time to cessation of otorrhea.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Proof-of-Concept Study of a Single Application of an Investigational Otic Suspension in Treatment of Acute Otitis Media With Tympanostomy Tubes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The results at the time of the interim analysis met the futility criteria and the study was subsequently stopped.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Otitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Otitis Media</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexamethasone 21-phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ciprofloxacin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>BB 1101</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Parent or guardian: Read and sign the informed consent. When required by the Institutional Review Board, child must agree to sign an approved assent form; Presence of otorrhea (visible by parent or guardian) of 21 days or less in duration; Presence of patent tympanostomy tubes; Refrain from water immersion of the ears following surgery without the use of adequate ear protection during swimming, bathing, showering and other waterrelated activities; Parent or guardian: Agree to comply with the requirements of the study, administer the study medication as directed, complete required study visits, and comply with the protocol; Other protocoldefined inclusion criteria may apply. NOT otorrheafree for at least seven days following tympanostomy tube surgery; Menarcheal females; Previous otologic surgery, except tympanic membrane, within one year of study entry; History of/or current acute or chronic nontube otorrhea (through existing perforation of the eardrum); Current acute otitis externa, malignant otitis externa, or other conditions which could interfere with evaluation of the study drug; Diabetic (controlled or uncontrolled); Use of prohibited medications; Other protocoldefined exclusion criteria may apply.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>AOMT</keyword>
	<keyword>tympanostomy tubes</keyword>
	<keyword>Otorrhea</keyword>
	<keyword>anti-infective</keyword>
</DOC>