<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01603069</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a study where AZD3241 or placebo is given to patients with Parkinson's disease in a blinded and randomized assignment. The main objective is to see if safety and tolerability of the drug is acceptable.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Assess Safety and Tolerability of Oral AZD3241 in Patients With Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Phase IIa, 12 Week, Multicentre, Double-Blind, Randomized, Placebo-Controlled, Parallel-Group Study to Assess the Safety and Tolerability of Oral AZD3241 in Patients with Parkinson's Disease</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Each patient must be able and willing to provide signed and dated informed consent prior to the study. Female and male patients aged 30 to 80 years at the day of enrollment (Visit 1). Patients must meet the criteria for "Diagnosis of idiopathic Parkinson's disease" according to the UKPDS Brain Bank criteria (Hughes et al 1992). Have a modified Hoehn and Yahr stage 12.5. Having no treatment for Parkinson's disease and have no need to add antiParkinson's disease treatment during the 14 weeks of study OR are on stable antiParkinson's disease medication. Diagnosis is unclear or a suspicion of other Parkinsonian syndromes exists, such as secondary Parkinsonism (caused by drugs, toxins, infectious agents, vascular disease, trauma, brain neoplasm), Parkinsonplus syndromes or heredodegenerative diseases. Have undergone surgery for the treatment of Parkinson's disease (eg, pallidotomy, deep brain stimulation, fetal tissue transplantation) or have undergone any other brain surgery at any time, even for nonParkinson's disease conditions. Presence of dyskinesias, motor fluctuations, swallowing difficulties or loss of postural reflexes, defined as scoring 2 or more on item 30 of the UPDRS. Current/history of psychiatric diagnosis of acute psychotic disorder or other primary psychiatric diagnoses, i.e. bipolar disorder or MDD, or other psychiatric, neurological or behavioral disorders/symptoms that may interfere with conduct of study. Current significant major or unstable respiratory disease, heart disease, cerebrovascular disease, hematological disease, hepatic disease, renal disease, gastrointestinal (GI) disease, or other major disease as judged by the investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Parkinson's disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Tolerability</keyword>
</DOC>