<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01603784</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this randomized, controlled, prospective study is to evaluate the benefits of combining aerobic exercise with cognitive training for optimizing cognitive function. The study will enroll 109 men and women, age 55-75 years who are in stable health and without contraindications to exercise or evidence of dementia or cognitive impairment. Individuals will be randomly assigned to one of four groups for six months: Aerobic Exercise and Health Education, Home Exercise and Cognitive Training, Aerobic Exercise and Cognitive Training, and Home Exercise and Health Education. Participants will undergo measurements of cognitive function, physical performance, and complete questionaires about daily activities, physical activity, and quality of life at baseline (pre-intervention), and at 6 and 12 months after baseline.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combining Exercise and Cognitive Training to Improve Everyday Function</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>age 5575 years (inclusive) Englishspeaking sufficient visual and auditory perception to complete testing available informant (someone who knows the individual well) Clinical Dementia Rating of 0 (nondemented per the screening assessment). participation in a regular exercise program in last 6 months participation in a cognitive training program in last 6 months inability to walk on a treadmill or ride an exercise bike less than a 10th grade education mild cognitive impairment or dementia cigarette smoking within the previous year history of alcohol or substance abuse BMI greater than 35 insulindependent diabetes major and/or unstable medical, neurological, or psychiatric disorder, including: active congestive heart failure unstable angina effort angina nocturnal angina MI within previous 6 months ECG evidence of serious arrhythmias and/or acute myocardial ischemia reflected by STsegment depression of 0.3 mm resting blood pressure above 170 systolic or 100 diastolic chronic infections advanced arthritis contractures or weakness due to CVA that would prevent adequate performance of the exercises. disabling stroke late stage renal or liver disease major affective disorder with active symptoms</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>exercise</keyword>
	<keyword>cognition</keyword>
	<keyword>memory</keyword>
	<keyword>adult</keyword>
</DOC>