<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02676271</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: Varus derotation osteotomy (VDRO) is one of the most popular surgical treatments for Legg-Calvé-Perthes disease yet its long term results have not been assessed. Our purpose was to determine the long term clinical and radiographic outcomes of these patients. Methods: Forty patients (43 hips) who had undergone VDRO for LCPD who participated in a long term follow-up study a decade ago were approached for the present study. All patients were treated in our institution during 1959 to 1983 with proximal VDRO. The patients were invited to for a medical interview and a physical examination. They were also asked to fill out questionnaires and to provide or undergo a standing anteroposterior (AP) pelvic and a lateral hip radiographs during the visit. Patients were asked to self-grade their hip pain as none, mild, moderate or severe and to grade their back pain using the Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) between 0-10. Details regarding daily function, physical activity, work status and family history were obtained. All participants completed the Harris Hip Score (HHS) with a maximum score of 100 and the Short Form-36 which is composed of 8 sections and has a maximum score of 100. The physical examination included an assessment of the hip range of motion, leg length discrepancy and the presence of a Trendelenburg sign. Radiographic parameters evaluated were the Tonnis grade (with a score between 0-3), head size ratio, and the center-edge (CE) angle.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Long Term Outcome of Varus Derotational Osteotomy for Legg-Calvé-Perthes' Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Legg-Calve-Perthes Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All patients were treated in our institution during 1959 to 1983 with proximal VDRO and were examined a decade ago</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>