<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01335646</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to determine if surgery is superior to non-operative care for sciatica caused by a lumbar disc herniation. This study will include patients that have had severe sciatica for greater than 4 months which reflects the wait time of the Canadian health care system. This study is an opportunity to make an important contribution to medical science as there is no "top tier" evidence for or against this highly prevalent surgery. Although there have been several recent randomized trials in the field, all have been marred by a large number of patient crossing over from non-operative to operative treatment. Due to the wait for spine surgery, the Canadian system has a built-in delay that prevents such a cross over of patients. This study capitalizes on this unique opportunity to perform a high caliber surgical trial. Patients consenting to be in the study will be randomly assigned to expedited surgery within three weeks or standardized non-operative care while they wait on the surgeons list for consultation and then surgery (minimum wait of 9 months). The study will assess pain, function, quality of life, satisfaction, and work status to determine if one treatment is superior.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Surgery Versus Standardized Non-operative Care for the Treatment of Lumbar Disc Herniations: A Canadian Trial</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Radiculopathy</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hernia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Analgesics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Inflammatory Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. 18 60 years old 2. Unilateral, single L5 or S1 radiculopathy (leg pain following dermatomal distribution of L5 or S1) Leg dominant pain over central back pain Positive straight leg raise &lt;70 degrees 3. MRI with corresponding L45 or L5S1 posterolateral disc herniation* 4. Radicular symptom duration greater than 4 months and less than 12 months. May be recurrent if first episode occurred within 12 months and duration of presenting episode is greater than 4 months. 5. Agree to possible discectomy 1. Radiculopathy secondary to foraminal stenosis 2. Radiculopathy secondary to intraforaminal or far lateral disc herniation 3. Radiculopathy secondary to lumbar central or lateral recess stenosis not caused by a posterolateral disc herniation 4. Previous lumbar surgery at involved level 5. Lumbar spondylolisthesis or lateral listhesis at level of disc herniation 6. Lumbar Scoliosis greater than 10 degrees</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>