<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02614807</DOC>
	<brief_summary>High blood pressure is very common among elderly Canadians. Clinical trials show clear benefit from lowering blood pressure in hypertensive elderly patients. These trials also demonstrate safety for several classes of blood pressure lowering drugs including water pills. However, water pills (thiazide diuretics) used for treatment of hypertension, can cause low sodium (hyponatremia), a significant clinical problem mainly among elderly and very elderly. Causes are age related decrease in kidneys' ability to get rid of water and low salt coupled with high water intake. A standard approach to treatment is lacking since higher salt intake may worsen hypertension, and lower water and higher protein intake is difficult to understand and actually implement. 'Nepro' is a nutritional drink high in protein, and low in potassium and sodium. It is used frequently as a dietary supplement in patients with kidney disease specifically for low sodium and high protein content. The high protein content in Nepro can help the kidney get rid of excess water, and the low sodium and potassium content will make this a safe option to use. Hence investigators propose a proof-of-concept trial on an easy to understand and administer, and relatively affordable solution to this issue. It could be summarized in one sentence: "Will a bottle of Nepro a day keep thiazide-caused hyponatremia and the doctor away?"</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Protein Supplementation in Thiazide-induced Hyponatremia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Hyponatremia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Elderly (&gt;65 years old) with diagnosed hypertension (HTN) treated with thiazide (hydrochlorothiazide) or thiazidelike (chlorthalidone and indapamide) diuretic and mild to moderate hyponatremia (Plasma sodium concentration 125133 mmol/L). Pregnancy estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt;45 ml/min/1.75 m2, Other causes of hyponatremia (liver cirrhosis, uncontrolled hypothyroidism, adrenal insufficiency) unable to provide informed consent; patients with generalized volume overload who may require immediate changes in diuretic therapy (at the discretion of treating HTN specialist); patients taking drugs which may interfere with urinary sodium excretion (such as carbamazepine, loop diuretics, potassium sparing diuretics, mineralocorticoid and glucocorticosteroids, selective serotonin receptor inhibitors, tricyclic antidepressants, amiodarone, and lithium); patients with moderate to severe hyponatremia (Plasma sodium concentration &lt; 125 mmol/L) who may require immediate discontinuation of the thiazide diuretic .</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dietary Supplement</keyword>
</DOC>