<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="197477">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00520130</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>070195</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>07-C-0195</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00520130</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Chemotherapy and Unrelated Donor Stem Cell Transplantation for Patients With Cancers of the Blood and Immune System</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Trial of Targeted Immune-Depleting Chemotherapy and Reduced-Intensity Allogeneic Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation Using 8/8 and 7/8 HLA-matched Unrelated Donors and Utilizing Two Graft-versus-Host Disease Prophylaxis Regimens for the Treatment of Leukemias, Lymphomas, and Pre-malignant Blood Disorders</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:

      Major problems with stem cell transplantation (SCT) for cancer treatment are a lack of
      suitable donors for patients without an HLA tissue-matched sibling and graft-versus-host
      disease (GVHD), a serious side effects of immune-suppressing chemotherapy that is given to
      bring the cancer under control before SCT. In GVHD, the patient s immune system attacks the
      transplanted donor cells.

      This study will try to improve the results of SCT from unrelated HLA-matched donors using
      targeted immune-depleting chemotherapy to bring the cancer under control before
      transplantation and to lower the chance of graft rejection, followed by reduced-intensity
      transplant chemotherapy to make the procedure less toxic.

      Objectives:

      To evaluate the safety and effectiveness of targeted immune-depleting chemotherapy followed
      by reduced-intensity transplant chemotherapy in patients with advanced cancers of the blood
      and immune system.

      To evaluate the safety and effectiveness of two different drug combinations to prevent GVHD.
      Both regimens have been successful in preventing GVHD, but they work by different mechanisms
      and affect the rebuilding of the immune system after the transplant.

      Eligibility:

      People 18 to 74 years of age with advanced or high-risk cancers of the blood and immune
      system who do not have a suitable HLA-matched sibling.

      Design:

      All patients receive chemotherapy before transplant to treat the cancer and suppress immune
      function.

      All patients receive a conditioning regimen of cyclophosphamide for 4 days and fludarabine
      for 4 days before SCT to prepare for the transplant.

      Patients are randomly assigned to one of two combination drug treatments to prevent GHVD as
      follows:

        -  Group 1: Tacrolimus starting 3 days before SCT and continuing for 6 months, plus
           methotrexate on days 1, 3, 6, and 11 post-SCT, plus sirolimus starting 3 days before
           the SCT and continuing through day 14 following SCT.

        -  Group 2: Alemtuzumab for 4 days starting 8 days before SCT, plus cyclosporine starting
           1 day before SCT and continuing for 6 months.

      Patients receive the donor s stem cells and immune cells 2 days after the conditioning
      regimen.

      Patients are followed at the clinic regularly for the first 6 months after SCT, and then
      less often for at least 5 years. Some visits may include bone marrow aspirates and biopsies,
      blood draws, and other tests to monitor disease status.

      A skin biopsy, oral mucosa biopsy, and saliva collection are done to study chronic GVHD.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:

        -  The major limitations to the broader applicability of allogeneic hematopoietic stem
           cell transplantation (HSCT) for the treatment of malignancies are lack of suitable
           donors and therapy-related toxicities which include delayed and incomplete immune
           reconstitution and graft-versus-host disease (GVHD). Based on the theory that the rapid
           establishment of donor chimerism was essential for an optimal graft-versus-tumor
           effect, we have employed a strategy of targeted immunedepleting chemotherapy prior to
           reduced-intensity allogeneic HSCT. It is our intent to investigate this approach in the
           setting of HLA-matched unrelated donors in a pilot manner.

        -  A clearly superior GVHD prophylaxis regimen has not been established in the unrelated
           donor transplant setting. The best results that have been reported are with the
           combination of alemtuzumab plus cyclosporine [AC] and the combination of tacrolimus,
           methotrexate, and sirolimus [TMS]. These two regimens work by mechanisms which are
           biologically distinct and potentially have markedly different effects upon immune
           reconstitution that have not been well studied. In addition neither of these regimens
           has been assessed for their affects on chronic GVHD using the NIH Consensus Conference
           Criteria. It is our intent to study the effects that these two regimens have on immune
           reconstitution and chronic GVHD in the setting sequential targeted immune-depleting
           chemotherapy and reduced-intensity allogeneic HSCT from HLA-matched unrelated donors.

      Objectives:

        -  Primary objectives:

             1. to assess the effects of two biologically distinct GVHD prophylaxis regimens, TMS
                and AC, on immune reconstitution in patients receiving targeted-immune depletion
                and reduced-intensity allogeneic HSCT from HLA-matched unrelated donors. As part
                of a comprehensive assessment of immune reconstitution, the primary immunologic
                endpoint will be the determination of CD4+ T cell receptor V BETA repertoire by
                CDR3 spectratyping at 3 months post-transplant.

             2. to assess overall safety of these two regimens in this setting, as determined by
                engraftment, acute GVHD, early and late treatment-related mortality, and overall
                survival.

             3. to determine and monitor incidence, organ severity and overall severity of chronic
                GVHD prospectively using the newly developed NIH Consensus Conference diagnosis
                and staging criteria and preliminarily validate those tools for use in clinical
                practice and trials (Pavletic, Imanguli, and Cowen).

        -  Secondary objectives include further assessment of immune reconstitution, study of
           engraftment kinetics, and assessment of those patients who receive higher doses of
           anthracyclines for long and short term toxicities

      Eligibility:

        -  Adults (18 74 years) with advanced or high risk hematologic malignancies including AML,
           ALL, MDS, CLL, NHL, HL,CML, multiple myeloma, and MPD who lack a suitable HLA matched
           sibling.

        -  An unrelated donor matched at a minimum of 7 of 8 alleles (HLA-A,-B,-C, and DRB1) by
           high resolution typing, identified through the National Marrow Donor Program.

        -  Life expectancy of at least 3 months, ECOG less than or equal to 2 and relatively
           normal major organ functions.

      Design:

        -  Patients will receive disease-specific induction chemotherapy (EPOCH-F/R or FLAG) prior
           to transplant for disease control and immune depletion. If disease is controlled
           (greater than PR) and immune depletion objectives have been met, patients may forgo
           induction chemotherapy and move forward to the transplant conditioning regimen.

        -  All patients will receive an identical conditioning regimen consisting of
           cyclophosphamide 1200 mg/m(2)/day IV for 4 days and fludarabine 30 mg/m(2)/day for 4
           days.

        -  Patients will be stratified according to degree of HLA-match and randomized at the time
           of enrollment to one of two GHVD prophylaxis regimens:

             -  Arm A (TMS): Tacrolimus, starting day -3 before transplant, given initially at
                0.02 mg/kg/day CIV and then an equivalent oral dose for six months, methotrexate 5
                mg/m(2) IV on days +1, +3, +6, and +11 post-transplant, and sirolimus given as an
                initial loading dose of 12 mg p.o. on day -3 pre-transplant and subsequently 4 mg
                daily through day +63 post transplant.

             -  Arm B (AC): Alemtuzumab at 20 mg/day IV over 8 h on days -8 to -4 pre-transplant
                and cyclosporine, starting day -1 before transplant, given initially at 2mg/kg IV
                every 12 hours and then an equivalent oral dose for six months and.

        -  A maximum of 105 patients will be enrolled and randomly assigned to the two arms in
           order to yield 44 patients per arm (88 total patients) who are able to be evaluated for
           development of severe chronic GVHD. This represents an increase of 20 patients over the
           number permitted prior to this amendment: 25 patients (50 total) randomly assigned to
           each arm within the 8/8 match group and 13/arm (26 total) within the 7/8 match group
           (maximum study enrollment = 76 transplanted patients from among up to 85 patients
           registered).
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the effects of two biologically distinct GVHD prophylaxis regimens</measure>
    <time_frame>1year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine and monitor incidence, organ severity and overall severity of chronic GVHD</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess overall safety of these two regimens in this setting, and overall survival.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Study of engraftment kinetics</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Toxicities</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">92</enrollment>
  <condition>Myelodysplastic Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Hodgkin's Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Non-Hodgkin's Disease</condition>
  <condition>Acute Leukemia</condition>
  <condition>Multiple Myeloma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TMS Arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>AC Arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rituximab</intervention_name>
    <description>Rituximab: 375 mg/m2 IV, day 1 for patients with CD20-positive disease</description>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cyclosporine</intervention_name>
    <description>Cyclosporine: IV over 2 hours or orally every 12 hours on days -1 to 100, followed by a taper if GVHD does not develop.</description>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Allogenic stem cell transplant (ASCT)</intervention_name>
    <description>Allogenic stem cell transplant</description>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Conditioning Chemotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Fludarabine:30 mg/m2 per day IV infusion over 30 minutes, daily On days -6, -5, -4, and -3 Cyclophosphamide:1200 mg/m2 per day IV infusion over 2 hours on Days 6, -5, -4, -3 Mesna: 1200 mg/m2 per day IV infusion, Daily on days 6, -5,-4, and -3</description>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TMS</intervention_name>
    <description>Tacrolimus: 0.02 mg/kg , start day 3. Continue IV or PO. Taper will begin at day +63 if no acute GVHD then at day +119 and discontinue at day +180 as tolerated Methotrexate: 5 mg/m2 IV over 15 minutes on days 1, 3, 6, and 11. Sirolimus: 12 mg PO on days -3 to 63, followed by a taper if GVHD does not develop.</description>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>FLAG</intervention_name>
    <description>Fludarabine:25 mg/m2 per day IV over 30 minutes, Daily on days 1-5 Cytarabine: 2,000 mg/m2 IV over 4 hours,on Days 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 Filgrastim: 5 mcg/kg per day SC beginning 24 hours PRIOR to initiation of chemotherapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>EPOCH-F</intervention_name>
    <description>Fludarabine:25 mg/m2 per day IV infusion over 30 minutes, daily on days 1-4 Etoposide :50 mg/m2 per day continuous IV infusion over 24 hours on days 1-4 Doxorubicin:10 mg/m2/day CIV, days 1-4 Vincristine:0.4 mg/m2 per day continuous IV infusion over 24 hours daily on days 1-4 Cyclophosphamide:750 mg/m2 IV infusion over 30 minutes on day 5</description>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alemtuzumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Alemtuzumab:20 mg/day IV over 8 h on days 8 to 4 pre-transplant.</description>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA RECIPIENT ON STANDARD CARE THERAPY:

          -  The patient is 18 74 years of age.

          -  The patient has a potentially suitable 8/8 donor if they are between the ages of
             69-74 years of age or a potentially suitable 8/8 or 7/8 unrelated donor(s) in the
             National Marrow Registry or Other Available Registry if they are between the ages of
             18-74.

          -  The patient currently does not meet the protocol s eligibility/enrollment criteria
             for any reason.

          -  There is a high likelihood that the patient, in the opinion of the PI or LAI, will
             meet the protocol s eligibility/enrollment criteria to proceed to transplant after
             standard therapy is completed.

          -  The patient or legal guardian is able to give informed consent.

        EXCLUSION CRITERIA RECIPIENT ON STANDARD CARE THERAPY:

          -  HIV infection. There is theoretical concern that the degree of immune suppression
             associated with the treatment may result in progression of HIV infection.

          -  Pregnant or lactating. Patients of childbearing potential must use an effective
             method of contraception. The effects of the chemotherapy, the subsequent transplant
             and the medications used after the transplant are highly likely to be harmful to a
             fetus. The effects upon breast milk are also unknown and may be harmful to the
             infant.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>74 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lauren M Curtis, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2007-C-0195.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pavletic SZ, Martin P, Lee SJ, Mitchell S, Jacobsohn D, Cowen EW, Turner ML, Akpek G, Gilman A, McDonald G, Schubert M, Berger A, Bross P, Chien JW, Couriel D, Dunn JP, Fall-Dickson J, Farrell A, Flowers ME, Greinix H, Hirschfeld S, Gerber L, Kim S, Knobler R, Lachenbruch PA, Miller FW, Mittleman B, Papadopoulos E, Parsons SK, Przepiorka D, Robinson M, Ward M, Reeve B, Rider LG, Shulman H, Schultz KR, Weisdorf D, Vogelsang GB; Response Criteria Working Group.. Measuring therapeutic response in chronic graft-versus-host disease: National Institutes of Health Consensus Development Project on Criteria for Clinical Trials in Chronic Graft-versus-Host Disease: IV. Response Criteria Working Group report. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2006 Mar;12(3):252-66.</citation>
    <PMID>16503494</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shaffer BC, Modric M, Stetler-Stevenson M, Arthur DC, Steinberg SM, Liewehr DJ, Fowler DH, Gale RP, Bishop MR, Pavletic SZ. Rapid complete donor lymphoid chimerism and graft-versus-leukemia effect are important in early control of chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Exp Hematol. 2013 Sep;41(9):772-8. doi: 10.1016/j.exphem.2013.04.015. Epub 2013 May 18.</citation>
    <PMID>23689118</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pavletic SZ, Lee SJ, Socie G, Vogelsang G. Chronic graft-versus-host disease: implications of the National Institutes of Health consensus development project on criteria for clinical trials. Bone Marrow Transplant. 2006 Nov;38(10):645-51. Epub 2006 Sep 18. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16980994</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 11, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 21, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Unrelated Donors</keyword>
  <keyword>Reduced Intensity Stem Cell Transplant</keyword>
  <keyword>Leukemia</keyword>
  <keyword>Lymphoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Allogeneic Stem Cell Transplant</keyword>
  <keyword>Myelodysplastic Syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>Multiple Myeloma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Alemtuzumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
