<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02438124</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The beneficial effects of rhythmical auditory stimulation (RAS) on spatio-temporal gait characteristics in Parkinson's disease (PD) are attested by clinical research. Nonetheless, it is still unclear which auditory information parameters (i.e. complexity, temporal regularity or adaptability to gait) maximize the effectiveness of RAS. Objectives: To evaluate the beneficial effects of RAS on spatio-temporal gait characteristics in PD patients with gait disorders according to: - RAS complexity (i.e. metronome, amplitude modulated noise, music) - RAS variability (i.e fixed, random, semi-random) - RAS adapted in real-time to gait Variability study: To study the impact of RAS variability (i.e fixed, random, semi-random) in 20 PD patients and 20 healthy controls on spatio-temporal gait characteristics with metronome, amplitude noise and music. Adaptability studyTo study the impact of RAS adaptability (i.e fixed, random, adapted in real-time to gait) in 20 PD patients and 20 healthy controls on spatio-temporal gait characteristics with metronome, amplitude noise and music.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Rhythmic Auditory Stimulation Optimalization for Gait Improvement in Parkinson's Disease - BeatPark Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>18 y.o. to be able to understand the study aims and to agree to participate to have signed the consent form to be registered to social security system to reach the diagnosis criteria of idiopathic PD (Queen Square Brain Bank) gait disorder clinically observable pregnant or lactating woman high probability of noncompliance curators , authorship or advisers to person of full age Specific exclusion criteria for PD patients clinical signs of parkinsonian syndrome Mini Mental State Examination &lt; 24/30 Specific exclusion criteria for controls neurological disease gait disorder</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Parkinson's disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Rhythmic auditory stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>Gait</keyword>
</DOC>