<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02438683</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial will be conducted to further evaluate, in a controlled setting, potential cardiac effects of an anticipated therapeutic and supra-therapeutic dose of BI 409306 under resting and exercise conditions. Since the drug is being developed in part for a disease with an expectedly high number of elderly (AD), the characterization of cardiac safety of BI 409306 is considered to be important for the development of this compound. This trial will be conducted to further evaluate, in a controlled setting, potential cardiac effects of an anticipated therapeutic and supra-therapeutic dose of BI 409306 under resting and exercise conditions. Since the drug is being developed in part for a disease with an expectedly high number of elderly (AD), the characterization of cardiac safety of BI 409306 is considered to be important for the development of this compound.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>BI 409306 Cardiac Safety Trial in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Healthy males according to the following criteria: Based upon a complete medical history, including the physical examination, vital signs (BP, PR), 12lead ECG, and clinical laboratory tests. Age of 18 to 45 years (incl.) BMI of 18.5 to 29.9 kg/m2 (incl.) Waisttoheight ratio less than 0.5 Signed and dated written informed consent prior to admission to the study in accordance with GCP and local legislation Ready and able to use highly effective methods of birth control that result in a low failure rate of less than 1% per year when used consistently and correctly. A list of contraception methods meeting these criteria is provided in the subject information. Exclusion criteria: Any finding in the medical examination (including BP, PR or ECG) is deviating from normal and judged as clinically relevant by the investigator Repeated measurement of Systolic blood pressure less than 90 mm Hg or more than140 mmHg Diastolic blood pressure less than 50 mm Hg or more than 90 mmHg Pulse rate less than 45 bpm or more than 90 bpm Any laboratory value outside the reference range that the investigator considers to be of clinical relevance Any evidence of a concomitant disease judged as clinically relevant by the investigator Gastrointestinal, hepatic, renal, respiratory, cardiovascular, metabolic, immunological or hormonal disorders Cholecystectomy and/or surgery of the gastrointestinal tract that could interfere with the PK of the trial medication (except appendectomy and simple hernia repair) Diseases of the central nervous system (including but not limited to any kind of seizures or stroke), and other relevant neurological or psychiatric disorders History of relevant orthostatic hypotension, fainting spells, or blackouts Chronic or relevant acute infections History of relevant allergy or hypersensitivity (including allergy to the trial medication or its excipients) Intake of drugs with a long halflife (more than 24 h) within 30 days or less than 10 halflives of the respective drug prior to administration of trial medication Within 10 days prior to administration of trial medication, use of drugs that might reasonably influence the results of the trial or that might prolong the QT/QTc interval Participation in another trial where an investigational drug has been administered within 60 days prior to planned administration of trial medication Smoker (unless the subject quit smoking for at least 30 days prior to screening) Alcohol abuse (consumption of more than 30 g per day) Drug abuse or positive drug screening Blood donation of more than 100 mL within 30 days prior to administration of trial medication or intended donation during the trial Intention to perform excessive physical activities within one week prior to administration of trial medication or during the trial Inability to comply with dietary regimen of trial site A marked baseline prolongation of QT/QTc interval (such as QTc intervals that are repeatedly greater than 450 ms) or any other relevant ECG finding at screening A history of additional risk factors for Torsades de Pointes (such as heart failure, hypokalaemia, or family history of Long QT Syndrome) Subject is assessed as unsuitable for inclusion by the investigator, for instance, because considered not able to understand and comply with study requirements, or has a condition that would not allow safe participation in the study Any suicidal ideation of type 2 to 5 on the CSSRS in the past 12 months (i.e. active suicidal thought, active suicidal thought with method, active suicidal thought with intent but without specific plan, or active suicidal thought with plan and intent) Any lifetime history of suicidal behaviour (i.e. actual attempt, interrupted attempt, aborted attempt, or preparatory acts or behaviour). In addition, the following trialspecific exclusion criteria apply: CYP2C19 PM (no treatment allocation) History of macular degeneration Beard or unwillingness to shave for the trial (to facilitate appropriate measurements during CPX which requires wearing a face mask) Physical disability that precludes safe and adequate CPX investigation Known latex allergy</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>