<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01233349</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Preparations that bind to nutritional fat and inhibit its absorption could be decisively meaningful for the regulation of bodyweight or obesity. Further, it is known that soluble fibres gel and swell in the stomach and thereby induce a feeling of satiety or fullness after eating. Such effects are supposed to facilitate adherence to energy-restricted diets. The medical device to be investigated contains a patented formula of fibre complex having a high ability to bind to dietary fat. Therefore, the rationale for this study is to confirm that Litramineʼs proven fat binding capacity to increase fat excretion and modulate the feeling of satiety will translate into measurable reduction in body weight. A double blind, randomized, placebocontrolled design has been chosen to assess the efficacy and safety of Litramine in overweight and obese subjects on a energy-restricted diet.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy of Litramine in Overweight and Obese Subjects</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
	<criteria>25 ≤ BMI ≤ 35 Expressed desire for weight loss Accustomed to 3 main meals/day Consistent and stable body weight 3 months prior to study enrolment Commitment to avoid the use of other weight loss products during study Commitment to adhere to diet recommendation Femalesʼ agreement to use appropriate birth control methods during the active study period Subject declares in writing his/her consent to participate, understands requirements of the study and is willing to comply Known sensitivity to the ingredients of the device Presence of any active gastrointestinal disease Malabsorption disorders (e.g. Coeliac disease) Pancreatitis Stenosis in the GI tract Bariatric surgery Abdominal surgery within the last 6 months prior to the study History of eating disorders like bulimia, anorexia nervosa History of renal disease History of nephrolithiasis History of cardiac diseases Osteoporosis Other serious organ or systemic diseases such as cancer, HIV, or diabetes mellitus Any medication that could influence GI functions such as antibiotics, laxatives, opioids, anticholinergics, or antidiarrheals (must have stopped 3 months before study start) Pregnancy or nursing Any medication or use of products for the treatment of obesity (e.g., Orlistat, other fatbinder, fatburner, satiety products etc.) More than 3 hours serious sport activity per week History of abuse of drugs, alcohol or medication Smoking cessation within the 6 months prior to this study Inability to comply due to language difficulties Participation in similar studies or weight loss programs within the 6 months prior to this study Participation in other studies within the last 4 weeks</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>overweight</keyword>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>weight loss</keyword>
	<keyword>body fat</keyword>
	<keyword>waist circumference</keyword>
	<keyword>satiety</keyword>
</DOC>