<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02591862</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Coversin in Paroxysmal Nocturnal Haemoglobinuria (PNH) in patients with resistance to Eculizumab due to complement C5 polymorphisms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Coversin in Paroxysmal Nocturnal Haemoglobinuria (PNH)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Coversin, a small protein complement C5 inhibitor which prevents the cleavage of C5 by C5 convertase into C5a and C5b, will be used in an open label, non-comparative clinical trial in patients with PNH and proven resistance to eculizumab due to C5 polymorphisms. Patients will be treated with Coversin by daily subcutaneous injection for 6 months in order to determine the safety and efficacy of the drug in these circumstances. If satisfactory control of the PNH is achieved, and at the discretion of the Principal Investigator (PI), patients will have the option of remaining on Coversin and being entered into the long term follow-up study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hemoglobinuria, Paroxysmal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hemoglobinuria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Complement System Proteins</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with known Paroxysmal Nocturnal Haemoglobinuria (PNH) LDH &gt;=1.5 Upper Limit of Normal (ULN) Resistance to Eculizumab proven by both a recognised C5 polymorphism on genetic screening and complement inhibition on CH50 ELISA of &lt;100% at concentrations of Eculizumab in excess of 5mug/mL Willing to selfinject Coversin daily or to receive daily subcutaneous injections by a home nurse or in a doctor's office or hospital clinic Males or females taking adequate contraceptive precautions if of childbearing potential, 18 80 years of age Body weight ≥50kg and ≤ 100kg The patient has provided written informed consent. Willing to avoid prohibited medications for duration of study Must agree to take appropriate prophylactic precautions against Neisseria infection. Must be counselled regarding the possible reproductive risks of using Coversin and be advised to use an adequate method of contraception pending further data on reproductive toxicology. Body weight &lt;50kg or&gt;100kg Pregnancy (females) Failure to satisfy the PI of fitness to participate for any other reason Known allergy to ticks or severe reaction to arthropod venom (e.g., bee or wasp venom)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>