<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02591771</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate efficacy and safety of i.v. adrenaline infusion as an early and fast haemodynamic stabilizer, associated with a tight tissue perfusion monitoring, in the context of a stepwise progression in the treatment of cardiogenic shock, including ventricular mechanical support.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Multistep Pharmacological and Invasive Management for Cardiogenic Shock</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Cardiogenic shock is characterized by a decrease in cardiac output and increased ventricular pressures, with subsequent symptoms and signs of systemic hypoperfusion. In spite of the multiple pharmacological chances the in-hospital mortality rate is still very high (around 60% of patients) and nowadays there is not a therapeutic "reference standard" associated with an improved survival at short and midterm. Adrenaline is a mainstay of resuscitation therapy during cardiopulmonary arrest, however, it is not clear whether this inotrope actually facilitates an improvement in patients affected by cardiogenic shock. In a small local evidence-based experience, contrary to current opinion, it has been shown that adrenaline may still have a role in the treatment of patients with low output state. This phase II study tests the hypothesis that adrenaline infusion, integrated in a multistep approach at increasing intensity, can be a valid support with limited side effects.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Shock</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Shock, Cardiogenic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epinephrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Racepinephrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epinephryl borate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18, males and females Eligible patients have to fit at least two of the following criteria/items: Systolic Blood Pressure &lt; 100 mmHg or Medium Arterial Pressure &lt; 60 mmHg, after fluid challenge (at least 1000 ml of a crystalloid solution or 500 ml of a colloidal solution with right atrial pressure &gt; 4 mmHg) or with a Central Venous Pressure &gt; 12 mmHg or Wedge Pressure &gt;14 mmHg. Mixed venous oxygen saturation &lt; 60% Arterial lactates &gt; 2 Oliguria &lt; 0.5 ml/Kg/h Pregnant, lactating or subjects planning pregnancy during the course of the trial. Participants involved in other clinical trial. Ongoing major arrhythmias: Ventricular Tachycardia or Ventricular Fibrillation or Atrial Fibrillation, with ventricular rate &gt; 160 bpm Inability to sign the informed consent Low output state due to hypovolemia (right atrial pressure &lt;4 mmHg) Septic shock Severe Aortic or mitral stenosis Obstructive hypertrophic cardiomyopathy or constrictive pericarditis or severe congenital cardiomyopathy Comorbidities with ominous prognosis (life expectancy &lt; 1 year) Overt infection, hepatic, renal or pulmonary dysfunction, altered neurological status without clear prognosis after an acute cardiac arrest or following cardiogenic shock Any other significant disease or disorder which, in the opinion of the Investigator, may either put the participants at risk because of participation in the trial, or may influence the result of the trial, or the participant's ability to participate in the trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Adrenaline</keyword>
	<keyword>Extra Corporeal Life Support</keyword>
	<keyword>Inotropes</keyword>
</DOC>