<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00878995</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Testosterone may lessen weight loss and improve muscle size and strength in patients with cachexia caused by cancer. PURPOSE: This randomized phase I trial is studying whether testosterone administered during standard of care chemotherapy and/or radiation works by helping patients with squamous cell carcinoma to maintain their body weight and muscle size and strength during treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Testosterone for Treating Cachexia in Patients With Squamous Cell Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - To determine the effect of testosterone therapy on lean body mass and muscle strength in patients with advanced or recurrent squamous cell carcinoma. - To determine the testosterone therapy on inflammatory biomarkers in patients with advanced or recurrent squamous cell carcinoma. OUTLINE: Patients are stratified according to age and disease stage. Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms. - Arm I: Patients receive standard of care chemotherapy and/or radiation and placebo testosterone intramuscularly (IM) weekly for 7 weeks. - Arm II: Patients receive standard of care chemotherapy and/or radiation and testosterone IM weekly for 7 weeks. Patients undergo dual energy x-ray absorptiometry, muscle strength tests, stable isotope metabolic studies, indirect calorimetry studies, and assessment of their physical activity level, and nutritional counseling. Patients also complete mood, fatigue, and quality-of-life questionnaires. Blood, muscle tissue, and urine samples are collected periodically for laboratory studies. Samples are analyzed for serum inflammatory biomarkers and inflammatory cytokines by immunoassay. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed periodically for 1 year.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cachexia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone enanthate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone undecanoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Testosterone 17 beta-cypionate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methyltestosterone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antineoplastic Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of advanced (stage IIB, IIIA, or IIIB) or recurrent squamous cell carcinoma Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 01 Mini Mental State Examination score &gt; 23 Pregnancy Evidence of hepatitis as indicated by a 3fold increase in 2 out of 3 liver enzymes Significant liver, renal, or heart disease Diabetes mellitus or other untreated endocrine disease Polycystic ovary syndrome and/or hyperthecosis Androgen secreting tumors of the ovary and adrenal or any ovarian tumors (e.g., Sertoli Leydig cell tumor) Nonclassical adrenal hyperplasia Cushing's syndrome Glucocorticoid resistance Hyperprolactinoma or hypothyroidism Lactose intolerance Alcohol or drug abuse Recent treatment (within 3 months) with anabolic steroids Ongoing anticoagulant therapy Any other circumstance that would preclude study participation, in the opinion of the principal investigator or study physician</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>stage IIB cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent cervical cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>cachexia</keyword>
	<keyword>advanced head/neck carcinoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent head/neck carcinoma</keyword>
</DOC>