<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02513108</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to provide information on safety of same day discharge after uncomplicated percutaneous intervention (PCI) for stable angina pectoris in Norwegian clinical practice. The investigators also think that is in patients interest to stay as short time as possible in hospital and this will be measured using standardised quality of life questionnaires.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Stavanger UncomPlicatEd Elective PCI Same DaY Discharge Study (SPEEDY Study)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The international literature has already provided documentation on the safety of same day discharge in various clinical scenario. In this particular study, the investigators focus on challenging the contemporary Norwegian practice where every body stays over night. Only patients with stable angina pectoris will be included in the study. After informed consent and successful procedure, the patients will be randomised to same day discharge or standard care. Same day discharge patients will be contacted by telephone the day after the procedure for follow-up conversation with particular emphasis on access site complications. Both groups will receive quality of life questionnaire within a month for assessment of difference between the two strategies.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Elective procedures Monday through Thursday Patient consenting for same day discharge Operator has assessed the patient and is in agreement Adequate observational facility Uncomplicated procedure Acceptable social network at home Uneventful post PCI ECG Adequate hemostasis of puncture site Angiographic Noreflow/slow flow post PCI Suboptimal PCI result Dissection type CE Rest dissection after stent deployment Angiographic thrombus Guidewire perforation Clinical Advanced age Severe renal failure (GFR &lt; 30ml/min) Excessive bleeding risk Symptomatic heart failure Severe visual or hearing impairment Multivessel PCI (2 main vessels or left main) Use of GP IIb/IIIa inhibitors Social Living alone or has no telephone Long driving distance (&gt; 3045 min) Patient/next to keen can´t communicate with health personnel without a translator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>