<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02513576</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Sternal instability caused by mediastinitis is one of the most feared complications for cardiac surgery team for generating large commitments and functional damages to patients. Biomechanically, the contraction of abdominal muscles such as transverse abdominal, produces forces that result in a "corset-like" action and anterior thoracic cage muscles too may assist in stabilizing the sternum. Thus, strengthening the abdominal muscles might contribute to the recovery of functional aspects. The aim was to evaluate whether contraction and strengthening the abdominal muscles could improve lung function and respiratory muscle strength in patients with sternal instability.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Physiotherapy Exercises in Patients With Sternal Instability After Cardiovascular Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Sternal instability was confirmed by physical examination and confirmed by chest tomography. The data were collected before and after the 3-week period of intervention. Sternal instability way assessed by the unstable sternal scale, graduated from zero to 4 points. The respiratory muscle strength was measured through Manuvacuometry and the pulmonary function by the spirometry. Pain was recorded by using a Visual Analog Scale (0 -10); Discomfort Scale( 0-10) and Identification of Activities that cause pain and discomfort. Patients underwent abdominal exercise protocol for three weeks once a day, lasting about 15 minutes followed by the physiotherapist.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Mediastinitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Postoperative period of cardiovascular surgery by median sternotomy with sternal instability Written Inform consent Chest Tube Hemodynamic instability Neurological alteration Active infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sternal instability</keyword>
	<keyword>physical therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Respiratory muscle strength</keyword>
</DOC>