<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00211042</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate the relationship of anti-erythropoietin antibodies to the clinical course and outcome of pure red cell aplasia (PRCA) in participants currently or previously treated with recombinant human erythropoietin.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Patients With Pure Red Cell Aplasia Associated With Recombinant Human Erythropoietin Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multicenter (study conducted at multiple sites), observational (study in which the investigators/physicians observe the participant's data and measure their outcomes) study. Approximately 150 participants will be enrolled in this study. The study consists of an initial observation phase and extended observation period. An initial observation phase starting at enrollment and ending when 24 months have elapsed since the date of loss of efficacy (LOE), supplemented with retrospective data collection for the period between LOE date and date of enrollment in the study. Participants remaining epoetin alfa (EPO-Ab) positive 24 months after LOE will enter a 2-year extended observation period. Study visits will take place every month during the initial observation phase and data will be collected every 6 months during the extended observation phase. Safety evaluations will include assessment of adverse events, clinical laboratory tests, vital signs, and physical examination which will be monitored throughout the study. The total study duration for each participant will be approximately for 4 years.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Red-Cell Aplasia, Pure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Epoetin Alfa</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pure red cell aplasia (PRCA) associated with recombinant human erythropoietin (rHuEPO) treatment Anemia unresponsive to rHuEPO treatment PRCA associated with erythropoietin treatment followed by a sudden decrease (more than or equal to 2 gram per deciliter within 30 days) in a previously stable hemoglobin level Exclusion criteria: Participants who are not fulfilling the inclusion criteria</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pure red-cell aplasia</keyword>
	<keyword>Anemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Red blood cells</keyword>
	<keyword>Epoetin alfa (Eprex)</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-erythropoietin antibodies</keyword>
	<keyword>Recombinant human erythropoietin</keyword>
</DOC>