<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01283048</DOC>
	<brief_summary>BKM-120 is a drug that may slow the growth of cancer cells. This drug has been used in laboratory experiments and information from those research studies suggests that this drug may help to slow the growth of renal cancer cells. In this research study, the investigators are testing the safety to BKM-120 at different dose levels. The investigators will also be studying how well tolerated BKM-120 is, and how effective BKM-120 can be in the treatment of kidney cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bevacizumab and BKM-120 in Patients With Metastatic Renal Cell Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Subjects will receive an intravenous infusion of Avastin on Day 1 and Day 15 of each month (cycle). Subjects will take a daily oral dose of BKM-120 at the dose level assigned. Subjects will have a clinic visit weekly during Cycle 1 and then on Day 1 and Day 15 of each cycle for blood tests and physical exam.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Metastatic RCC with clear cell component or papillary RCC Life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks Must have failed at least 1 prior antiVEGF systemic therapy for metastatic RCC Prior treatment with a P13K inhibitor or bevacizumab Untreated brain metastases Acute or chronic liver or pancreatic disease Major mood disorder Concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled medical condition Diabetes mellitus GI disease Currently taking therapeutic doses of warfarin sodium or any other coumadinderivative anticoagulant Pregnant or breastfeeding HIV positive History of another malignancy within 3 years except cured basal cell carcinoma of the skin or excised in situ carcinoma of the cervix Uncontrolled hypertension</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Kidney Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Avastin</keyword>
</DOC>