<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00925834</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this randomized controlled pilot study was to answer the following questions: 1. Is it possible to affect the diameter of coronary arteries through a placebo injection, which is administered intracoronarily together with a standardized verbal suggestion of coronary vasodilation? 2. Is it possible to affect the diameter of coronary arteries through a pharmacologically underdosed nitroglycerine injection, which is administered intracoronarily together with a standardized verbal suggestion of coronary vasodilation?</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Suggestive Effects on the Diameter of Coronary Arteries</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The present study is a randomized controlled double-blind single center study in order to investigate the effects of verbal suggestions ('vasodilatation') in combination with either a placebo-intervention (sodium chloride 0.9%) or an underdosed vasodilating medication (nitroglycerine) on the diameter of coronary arteries. 60 patients with a clinical indication to undergo a coronary angiogram were recruited in the German Heart Centre Munich. Patients with acute myocardial events and the necessity for coronary intervention were excluded from the study. Patients were randomized into one of four arms of the two experiments: Experiment A: Intracoronary (i.c.) placebo-infusion together with a standardized verbal suggestion of coronary vasodilation vs. i.c. placebo-infusion without verbal suggestion. Experiment B: i.c. infusion of a very low dosed nitroglycerin together with a standardized verbal suggestion of coronary vasodilation vs. i.c. nitroglycerine infusion without verbal suggestion. To our best knowledge this study is the first to investigate the modulating effects of verbal suggestions going along with medical interventions on the diameter of coronary arteries during heart catheterization.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Nitroglycerin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>medical indication for heart catheterization written informed consent acute myocardial infarction acute elevation of cardiac enzymes regular intake of drugs containing nitroglycerin intolerance of nitroglycerin hypotension renal insufficiency diabetes mellitus hyperthyroidism pregnancy acute psychiatric disease cognitive impairment prinzmetal's angina</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>Coronary angiography</keyword>
	<keyword>Placebo effect</keyword>
	<keyword>Suggestion</keyword>
</DOC>