<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02898077</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of the study drug known as ramucirumab in participants with gastric and gastroesophageal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Paclitaxel With or Without Ramucirumab (LY3009806) in Participants With Gastric or Gastroesophageal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ramucirumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status (ECOGPS) of 0 or 1 at study entry. Have a histopathologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of gastric or gastroesophageal junction (GEJ) adenocarcinoma. Have metastatic disease or locally advanced, unresectable disease. Have at least 1 measurable lesion based on Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST), Version 1.1. Have experienced documented objective radiographic or symptomatic disease progression during firstline therapy, or within 4 months after the last dose of firstline therapy with any platinum/fluoropyrimidine doublet for unresectable or metastatic disease. Have adequate organ function. Have urinary protein ≤1+ on dipstick or routine urinalysis. Have undergone major surgery within 28 days prior to randomization. Have received any firstline chemotherapy other than platinum and fluoropyrimidine with or without anthracycline for advanced gastric or GEJ adenocarcinoma. Have received any previous systemic therapy (including investigational agents) targeting vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) or the VEGF receptor signaling pathways. Have a history of deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, or any other significant thromboembolism during the 3 months prior to randomization. Have significant bleeding disorders, vasculitis, or had a significant bleeding episode from the gastrointestinal (GI) tract within 3 months prior to study entry. Have a history of GI perforation and/or fistulae within 6 months prior to randomization. Have experienced any arterial thromboembolic event within 6 months prior to randomization. Have uncontrolled arterial hypertension (systolic blood pressure ≥160 millimeters of mercury [mmHg] or diastolic blood pressure ≥100 mmHg) despite standard medical management. Have a serious or nonhealing wound, peptic ulcer, or bone fracture within 28 days prior to randomization. Have a serious illness or medical condition(s).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Second line</keyword>
	<keyword>Angiogenesis</keyword>
	<keyword>Vascular endothelial growth factor receptor 2</keyword>
</DOC>