<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03084861</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicenter, randomized, open-label, two-arms phase I/II, clinical trial, in which 42 patients will be enrolled with the principal objective to evaluate the efficacy through changes in lesion size and, secondary, to evaluate the safety and efficacy through corneal sensibility, corneal opacity, visual acuity and complications of Neurotrophic Keratopathy (NK). Patients will be randomized 1:1 to receive experimental treatment (cord blood eye drops) or conventional treatment (artificial tears and therapeutic contact lens).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Trial to Asses Efficacy and Safety of Cord Blood Eye Drops in Neurotrophic Keratopathy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multicenter, randomized, open-label, two-arms phase I/II, clinical trial, in which 42 patients will be enrolled with the principal objective to evaluate the efficacy through changes in lesion size and, secondary, to evaluate the safety and efficacy through corneal sensibility, corneal opacity, visual acuity and complications of NK. Patients will be randomized 1:1 to receive experimental treatment (cord blood eye drops) or conventional treatment (artificial tears and therapeutic contact lens). All patients, with conventional or experimental treatment, will be treated for 19 days. A topical antibiotic will be added too as a concomitant treatment to all treatment groups, until the injury closes or according to medical criteria. After signing informed consent, inclusion and exclusion criteria will be assessed, and if the patient meets all the requirements, the patient will be randomized. After initiation of the treatment, patients will be follow-up at 2-3 days and once a week for 3 weeks. A final follow-up is planned at 6 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tetrahydrozoline</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age ≥ 18 years old 2. NK stage 2 or 3 (Mackie classification) 3. Signed Informed Consent Form 4. The patient is able to understand the nature of the study and to participate throughout its duration 1. Medical history of eye tumors 2. Active eye infection 3. Eyelid bad position or eyelid closure problems 4. Conjunctiva scarring 5. Topic chronic eye treatments with corticoids 6. Acute corneal burns (&lt;3 months) 7. Intolerance to contact lens 8. Allergy or inability to receive concomitant treatment with Exocin® 9. Patients with immunosuppressive or chemotherapy treatment 10. Pregnant woman or woman without proper contraceptive methods according to the investigator (*), or lactating women 11. Participation in another clinical trial in the last month (*) Contraceptive methods accepted in the protocol are: hormonal, intrauterine device (IUD), barrier methods, voluntary sterilization or the patient has menopause &gt;1 year duration</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>