<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00054808</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Eligible patients will have low- or intermediate-grade Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma (NHL) that has progressed after standard chemotherapy. Patients will receive gallium nitrate 300 mg/m2/day by continuous IV infusion for 7 consecutive days using a portable infusion pump. Hospitalization is not required. Stable or responding patients will receive additional gallium nitrate infusions every 3 weeks until the time of disease progression, for a maximum total of 8 infusions, or 2 cycles after complete remission has been documented.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase II Gallium Nitrate in Relapsed or Refractory Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study seeks to define the role of gallium nitrate in a specific population of patients who are expected to have received prior therapy. Preliminary clinical studies have suggested substantial evidence of antitumor activity in patients with relapsed or refractory non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma treated with gallium nitrate.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gallium nitrate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Low or intermediategrade NHL using the International Working Formulation, subtypes IWF AG: Using the Updated REAL/WHO Classification, the following pathologic subtypes are eligible: Small lymphocytic lymphoma Lymphoplasmacytic lymphoma/immunocytoma Follicular lymphoma Diffuse large Bcell lymphoma Peripheral Tcell lymphoma, not otherwise characterized Progression of disease following treatment with standard chemotherapy Bidimensionally measurable disease Performance Status: ECOG &lt; = 2 Patients with mantle cell lymphoma or mycosis fungoides are not eligible Patients with known history of CNS metastasis are not eligible</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gallium Nitrate</keyword>
	<keyword>Ganite</keyword>
	<keyword>NHL</keyword>
	<keyword>Relapsed</keyword>
</DOC>