<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02087488</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This double-blind RCT will evaluate the therapeutic effectiveness and safety of auricular acupuncture(AA) for primary insomnia(PI) .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Auricular Acupuncture for Primary Insomnia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Investigators will conduct a 2-year clinical trial on auricular acupuncture (AA) for primary insomnia (PI), which is a double-blind (patient-blind and assessor-blind) RCT. 288 patients will be randomly assigned into 2 groups: the treatment group (Group A) and the control group (Group B). Group A will be treated with AA plus oral Eszopiclone, while Group B will be treated with sham AA plus oral Eszopiclone. All patients will receive a continuous 4-week treatment and 28-week follow-up. The data will be analyzed by the third party who is not clear about allocation and treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eszopiclone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Meet the diagnosis of PI according to DSM5; Aged 1864 (including 18 and 64); Provided a signed written consent form. The patient has somatic disease like severe respiratory, circulatory, endocrine system disease and hepatic/renal insufficiency; The patient suffers from moderate / major depression (BDI score ≧ 8 points), moderate / severe anxiety disorder (SAS score ≧ 61 points) or any other serious mental disease; The patient who abuse drug alcohol or substance; The patient suffers from dementia or any other severe cognitive impairment; The patient is in pregnancy or lactation period; Patient who is a night worker or stick to irregular sleep pattern, and can't or don't want to terminate this kind of work mode; The patient has history of suicide or suicidal tendency; The patient is allergic to Eszopiclone or any other sedativehypnotic drugs; The patient who has taken psychiatric, hypnotic or antihistamine drugs during the last 4 weeks before baseline, however, the patient who use the prescription or nonprescription hypnotic drugs no more than twice a week can be recruited as soon as drug withdrawal; The patient who is receiving ongoing psychological treatment; The patient who has obstructive sleep apnea, restless leg syndrome, sleep rhythm disorders, parasomnias, etc.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>primary insomnia</keyword>
	<keyword>auricular acupuncture</keyword>
</DOC>