<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01652417</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Renal sarcoidosis treatment is based on steroids, but the dose and duration are unknown. Despite this treatment, most patients will have chronic kidney disease. From our previous studies, the investigators believe that high dose steroids by methylprednisolone bolus will improve patient outcome and renal function.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Treatment of Renal Sarcoidosis by Methylprednisolone Bolus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In a multicentric, randomized, open trial, the investigators will assess the efficacy of methylprednisolone bolus at 15mg/kg/d for 3 days before oral steroids on renal function improvement in renal sarcoidosis patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoidosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 18 years Acute kidney injury with estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt; 60 mL/min/1,73 m2, defined by an increase of initial value &gt; 25% or an increase of &gt; 30 µmol/l, since at least 3 months. Sarcoidosis diagnostic criteria according to ATS/ERS/WASOG (Am J Respir Crit Care Med 1999) Renal biopsy compatible with renal sarcoidosis : Granulomatosis tubulointerstitial nephropathy and extrarenal damage of histologically proved or suggestive sarcoidosis Or Tubulointerstitial nephropathy without granuloma and extrarenal damage of histologically proved sarcoidosis Informed consent Patients with social security Corticosteroids greater than 0,25 mg/kg/j prednisone equivalent Introduction of an immunosuppressant in the month before inclusion Another cause of renal granulomatosis or tubulointerstitial nephropathy Isolated renal damage without extrarenal past or present damage for a sarcoidosis Chronic renal failure, prior sarcoidosis with eGFR &lt; 30 mL/min/1,73 m2 Acute renal failure from other causes. If hypercalcaemia is greater than 3 mmol/L, the correction of any dehydration will systematically salt intake, followed of renal function control before inclusion. Pregnancy, nursing Tuberculosis Uncontrolled sepsis Uncontrolled psychotic state Hypersensibility to methylprednisolone hemisuccinate Drugs prescription causing wave burst arrhythmia and/or long QT on ECG</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Methylprednisolone</keyword>
	<keyword>prednisone</keyword>
	<keyword>renal sarcoidosis treatment</keyword>
</DOC>