<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00217620</DOC>
	<brief_summary>RATIONALE: Sorafenib may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth and by blocking blood flow to the tumor. PURPOSE: This phase II trial is studying how well sorafenib works in treating patients with advanced soft tissue sarcomas.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>S0505 Sorafenib in Treating Patients With Advanced Soft Tissue Sarcomas</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>OBJECTIVES: - Determine the objective response rate (confirmed, complete, and partial) in patients with advanced soft tissue sarcomas treated with sorafenib. - Determine the 4-month progression-free survival rate in patients treated with this drug. - Determine the frequency and severity of adverse events in patients treated with this drug. OTHER OBJECTIVES (if funding permits): - Correlate, preliminarily, a decrease in standard uptake variable (SUV) of target lesions by positron-emission tomography scan at 4 weeks with response in patients treated with this drug. - Correlate, preliminarily, the phosphorylation status of KIT, PDGFR, VEGFR, and the raf/mek/erk pathway with response in patients treated with this drug. - Correlate, preliminarily, the most common B-raf kinase mutation with response in patients treated with this drug. OUTLINE: This is a multicenter study. Patients are stratified according to histology (leiomyosarcoma vs liposarcoma vs angiosarcoma, hemangiosarcoma, or hemangiopericytoma). Patients receive oral sorafenib twice daily on days 1-28. Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 8 weeks until disease progression and then every 6 months for 2 years and annually for up to 3 years. PROJECTED ACCRUAL: A total of 45-75 patients (15-25 per stratum) will be accrued for this study within 15-38 months.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Niacinamide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>DISEASE CHARACTERISTICS: Histologically confirmed soft tissue sarcoma of 1 of the following histologies: Angiosarcoma, cutaneous or visceral Malignant hemangiosarcoma Malignant hemangiopericytoma Grade 34 leiomyosarcoma Grade 34 liposarcoma Must have evidence of unresectable residual disease, metastatic disease, or recurrent disease by radiography Measurable disease by xray, scans, or physical examination Archived paraffinembedded tumor sections available No known brain metastases PATIENT CHARACTERISTICS: Age 18 and over Performance status Zubrod 01 Life expectancy Not specified Hematopoietic WBC ≥ 3,000/mm^3 Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mm^3 Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm^3 Hepatic SGOT and SGPT ≤ 2.5 times upper limit of normal (ULN) (5 times ULN if due to liver metastases) Bilirubin normal (≤ 2.5 times ULN if due to liver metastases) PT, PTT, and INR normal Renal Creatinine normal OR Creatinine clearance ≥ 60 mL/min Cardiovascular No history of thromboembolic disease No uncontrolled hypertension Other Not pregnant or nursing Fertile patients must use effective contraception Able to swallow oral medication No other malignancy within the past 5 years except adequately treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, carcinoma in situ of the cervix, or adequately treated stage I or II cancer in complete remission PRIOR CONCURRENT THERAPY: Biologic therapy Not specified Chemotherapy At least 28 days since prior chemotherapy (42 days for carmustine or mitomycin) and recovered Prior adjuvant chemotherapy allowed No more than 1 prior chemotherapy regimen for metastatic disease Endocrine therapy Not specified Radiotherapy At least 28 days since prior radiotherapy and recovered Must have evidence of disease progression within, or measurable disease outside of, the radiation field after completion of radiotherapy Surgery At least 28 days since prior major surgery and recovered Other No prior sorafenib No prior inhibitor of VEGFR or MAPK pathway No concurrent combination antiretroviral therapy for HIVpositive patients No other concurrent investigational agents No concurrent therapeutic anticoagulation No concurrent administration of any of the following medications: Rifampin Hypericum perforatum (St. John's wort) Cytochrome P450 enzymeinducing antiepileptic drugs, including any of the following: Phenytoin Carbamazepine Phenobarbital</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>adult angiosarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult leiomyosarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult liposarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>adult malignant hemangiopericytoma</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent adult soft tissue sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage III adult soft tissue sarcoma</keyword>
	<keyword>stage IV adult soft tissue sarcoma</keyword>
</DOC>