<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00174681</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary objective: The primary objective of this trial is: - To evaluate the efficacy of initiating Lantus in combination with oral antidiabetics drugs compared to oral antidiabetic treatment optimised by enhancing hygienic and dietary measures in type 2 diabetics whose blood glucose control is acceptable but not optimal on maximum oral treatment, based on the number of patients achieving a HbA1c value &lt; 7% at the end of treatment. Secondary objectives: The secondary objectives of this trial are to compare between the two treatment groups: - The variation in HbA1c between baseline and end of trial. - The frequency of episodes of symptomatic hypoglycaemia (diurnal and nocturnal), severe hypoglycaemia (diurnal and nocturnal) and asymptomatic hypoglycaemia. - Mean blood glucose levels at different times of the day. - The variation in weight and lipid in each group between baseline and end of trial. - The incidence of adverse events.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tulip Study: Testing the Usefulness of Lantus When Initiated Prematurely In Patients With Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Glargine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria : Subjects fulfilling all of the following criteria will be eligible for inclusion in the trial: Type 2 diabetes 24 ≤ BMI ≤ 35 kg/m2 7 % ≤ HbA1c ≤ 8 % Treated with OAD for at least 2 years Treated with at least two oral antidiabetics including one sulphonylurea at the maximum tolerated dosages and metformin at the maximum tolerated dosages Not treated with a glinide or thiazolidinedione. Capable of performing blood glucose selfmonitoring and a selfinjection of insulin. Funduscopy within the previous year at the time of inclusion. Patient with any of the following criteria will not be included in the trial: Type 1 diabetics Insulintreated type 2 diabetics or having previously received longterm insulin, or treated with a thiazolidinedione or glinide Fasting blood glucose &lt; 1.20 g/l. Pregnancy (nonmenopausal women must have a pregnancy test before the inclusion visit and effective contraception). Lactation. History of hypersensitivity to the investigational product or to drugs with similar chemical structures. Systemic treatment with corticosteroids irrespective of the dose and irrespective of the previous or anticipated duration of treatment. Treatment with another product under development in the 2 months preceding the date of inclusion in the study. Subject likely to receive treatments prohibited in the protocol during the trial. Cardiovascular, hepatic, neurological, endocrine or any other disease making it difficult to carry out the protocol or interpret the results. Proliferative or rapidly progressive or unstable retinopathy for at least 6 months after treatment by surgery or laser, or requiring surgery or laser in the 3 months following inclusion in the study. Hepatic impairment:ALT and/or AST more than three times the upper limit of normal at the initial assessment. Renal insufficiency:Serum creatinine &gt;177 µmol/l (&gt;20 mg/l) or creatinine clearance &lt;60 ml/min. Previous or current history of alcohol or drug abuse. Mental state rendering the subject incapable of understanding the nature, objectives and possible consequences of the trial. Inability to undertake blood glucose selfmonitoring and the injection of insulin alone. Subject unable to accept the restrictions of the protocol (uncooperative, unable to attend the followup visits and probably incapable of completing the trial). Subjects deprived of freedom by an administrative or judicial decision. The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>