<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00721591</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To determine, through pharmacokinetic parameters, the ideal dosing protocol for dalteparin (a low molecular weight heparin) and unfractionated heparin for women desiring pregnancy who have evidence of an acquired (specifically, antiphospholipid syndrome) or inherited thrombophilia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacokinetics of Low Molecular Weight and Unfractionated Heparin in Pregnancy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study's specific objectives include: 1. Evaluating pharmacokinetic (concentration-time) and pharmacodynamic (concentration- effect) parameters for dalteparin and UFH prior to pregnancy, during the 1st, 2nd and 3rd trimesters and postpartum, using revised dosing protocols based on previous study. 2. Determining therapeutic response to the heparins, i.e. live birth rate and lack of maternal or fetal complications, in relation to drug exposure, based on AUC. 3. Documenting maternal and fetal complications during pregnancy for dalteparin and UFH, using the revised dosing protocols.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Thrombophilia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fetal Death</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Abortion, Habitual</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcium heparin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heparin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Two or more consecutive, otherwise unexplained miscarriages under 10 weeks of gestation, or, an otherwise unexplained intrauterine fetal demise of at least 10 weeks of gestation, and, Persistently positive antiphospholipid antibodies, or, presence of Factor V Leiden, or, Prothrombin 20210A, or, antithrombin, protein S, or protein C deficiency, or, hyperhomocysteinemia associated with the methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR) polymorphism. Inability or refusal to give written informed consent. Inability or refusal to selfadminister heparin throughout pregnancy. Hemoglobin value below 9.5 g/dL Heparin use is contraindicated. Renal disease. Documented history of thrombosis.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>44 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Recurrent Pregnancy Loss</keyword>
	<keyword>Habitual abortion</keyword>
	<keyword>Fetal demise</keyword>
	<keyword>Antiphospholipid antibodies</keyword>
	<keyword>Inherited thrombophilia</keyword>
</DOC>