<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02104791</DOC>
	<brief_summary>It is hypothesized that the procalcitonin has a role to play in prediction of intra-amniotic subclinical infection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Role of Plasma Procalcitonin in Prediction of Intra-amniotic Infection in Preterm Premature Rupture of Membrane</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study population - This study will be conducted at the department of Obstetrics and Gynecology recruiting pregnant women selected from the attendees of antenatal clinic, emergency department and from inpatient wards of Ain Shams University Maternity Hospital from Mars2014. - This study will include 100 pregnant women these cases will be divided into 2 groups: - Group 1: Healthy preterm Group: will include 50 pregnant females all at 24-34 weeks of gestational age . - Group 2: Preterm premature rupture of membrane Group: will include 50 pregnant females all at 24-34 weeks of gestational age</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Asymptomatic Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Calcitonin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients are with singleton pregnancies. Rupture of membranes will be diagnosed by history, sterile speculum examination to confirm fluid leakage from the cervical canal and ultrasound to confirm oligohydraminos. Subclinical infection will be detected with laboratory indices (WBC count of ≥15, 000 c/mm3, CRP of ≥1 mg/dL) without any clinical symptoms and signs of infection as urinary tract infection in group 1 patients. Women with multiple pregnancies. Clinical signs of infection as (fever,abdominal tendernes). Cervical dilatations of 2 cm or more. Maternal disease like diabetes or fetal complications like intrauterine fetal death.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Procalcitonin</keyword>
	<keyword>intra-amniotic subclinical infection.</keyword>
</DOC>