<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01770431</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the efficacy and safety of Huaier Granule for prevention of recurrence and metastasis of hepatocarcinoma after radical hepatectomy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Huaier Granule for Prevention of Recurrence and Metastasis of Hepatocarcinoma After Radical Hepatectomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Multicenter, Randomized, Paralleled control Clinical Study Investigating Huaier Granule for Prevention of Recurrence and Metastasis of Hepatocarcinoma after Radical Hepatectomy,to evaluate the efficacy and safety.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age: ≥ 18 and ≤ 75 years, both male and female; Radical hepatectomy has been performed for hepatocellular carcinoma; The hepatocellular carcinoma has been confirmed by pathological examination; Barcelona clinic liver cancer(BCLC) stage A or B; Not receiving any preoperative anticancer drug; The liver and kidney function satisfies the following conditions within 15 days after surgery (excluding day 15): aspartate aminotransferase(AST), glutamicoxalacetic transaminase(ALT)&lt;3 upper limit of normal(ULN), total bilirubin≤2ULN, serum creatinine &lt;1.5 ULN; Other laboratory tests meet the following requirements within 15 days after surgery (excluding day 15): Hb≥9g/dl, platelet count≥60×109/L, absolute neutrophil count&gt;1.0×109/L; The expected survival time ≥ 12 weeks; The subjects volunteer to sign the informed consent. Hepatocellular carcinoma patients who received nonradical hepatectomy; Nonhepatocellular carcinoma patients; Those with ChildPugh C; Pregnant or lactating women; Those with active bleeding due to various reasons; Those with HIV infection or AIDSassociated diseases; Those with severe acute and chronic diseases; Those with severe diabetes; Those with serious infectious diseases; Those who can not take drugs by oral route; Drug abusers or those with psychological or mental diseases that may interfere with study compliance; Conditions that are considered not suitable for this study investigators</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Huaier Granule;</keyword>
	<keyword>After radical hepatectomy;</keyword>
	<keyword>Prevention of Recurrence and Metastasis;</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety.</keyword>
</DOC>