<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02811692</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The French CODEX study is designed as a national database to describe, in routine medical practice, functional and anatomical responses to intravitreal Aflibercept injection, in a large population of anti-VGEF-naïve patients presenting with wet Age-related Macular Degeneration (wAMD), Central Retinal Vein Occlusion (CRVO),Branch Retinal Vein Occlusion(BRVO), or Diabetic Macular Edema (DME). This national database will gather databases from French private and public ophthalmologic centers.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study for Collection of Aflibercept Data in Routine Practice</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The retrospective data will be gathered from the first injection of Aflibercept for the indications macular edema following Branch Retinal Vein Occlusion (BRVO) directly by each physician. For each patient, the first injection date of Aflibercept is defined as the index date. Electronic files from each ophthalmologist, containing patient medical records, will be periodically transmitted according to the milestones of the study with a maximum of 4 transfers (at Q2 2016 for the first transfer and then every 9 months thereafter). As each electronic transfer will be independent of each other and as patients' data will be anonymized by physicians before each transfer, data comparisons will be not possible between the four electronic files transfers planned over the study period.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Eye Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged ≥18 years old AntiVEGF (Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor) treatment naïve Intravitreal (IVT) aflibercept injection treatment follows the recommendations made within the EYLEA Summary of Product Characteristics Diagnosed with wAMD (wet Agerelated Macular Degeneration), macular edema following CRVO (Central Retinal Vein Occlusion), macular edema following BRVO (Branch Retinal Vein Occlusion), or DME (Diabetic Macular Edema). Who have any contraindications listed in the EYLEA Summary of Product characteristics Participating in an investigational program with interventions outside of routine clinical practice.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Database</keyword>
	<keyword>Diabetic Macular Edema (DME)</keyword>
	<keyword>Wet Age-related Macular Degeneration (wAMD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Retinal Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Optic Nerve Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Corneal Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Vision Disorders</keyword>
</DOC>