<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02651194</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the efficacy and safety of 12 weeks of treatment with the ABT-493/ABT-530 combination regimen in adults with chronic HCV genotype 1 - 6 infection and chronic renal impairment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of ABT-493/ABT-530 in Renally Impaired Adults With Chronic Hepatitis C Virus Genotype 1 - 6 Infection</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Chronic hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection Screening laboratory results indicating HCV genotype 1 6 (GT1 6) infection. Subject must be HCV treatmentnaïve or have failed previous HCV treatment. Subjects with underlying chronic renal impairment Noncirrhotic subjects must have documented absence of cirrhosis and subjects with cirrhosis must have documented compensated cirrhosis. History of severe, lifethreatening or other significant sensitivity to any excipients of the study drug. Female who is pregnant, planning to become pregnant during the study, or breastfeeding; or male whose partner is pregnant or planning to become pregnant during the study. Recent (within 6 months prior to study drug administration) history of drug or alcohol abuse that could preclude adherence to the protocol in the opinion of the investigator. Positive test result at Screening for hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) or antihuman immunodeficiency virus antibody (HIV Ab). HCV genotype performed during screening indicating coinfection with more than 1 HCV genotype.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Treatment-naïve</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Gentoype 6</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Gentoype 1</keyword>
	<keyword>Compensated cirrhotic</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Gentoype 2</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment-experienced</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-cirrhotic</keyword>
	<keyword>Chronic Hepatitis C</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Gentoype 5</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Gentoype 3</keyword>
	<keyword>HCV Gentoype 4</keyword>
</DOC>