<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="26007">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02768194</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>205699</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02768194</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dentine Tubule Occlusion Assessment in a Modified in Situ Model</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assessment of Dentine Tubule Occlusion in a Modified in Situ Model</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GlaxoSmithKline</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This will be a single centre, single blind, randomized, three treatment, three period
      crossover design, modified, in situ, study in healthy participants. In this in situ model
      the tubule occlusion properties of dentifrices will be evaluated by comparing an
      experimental dentifrice formulation to a regular fluoride dentifrice and a negative control
      (mineral water) over a ten day period.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This modified in situ model study will evaluate the mode-of-action of an experimental
      dentifrice containing stannous fluoride to occlude tubules compared to a regular fluoride
      dentifrice and a negative control (mineral water). The study treatments will be administered
      for a total of 10 days, with participants wearing two appliances in their mouth that will
      hold samples of dentine. The dentine samples will be examined after 1, 4, 8 and 10 days of
      treatment using scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and the resulting images graded for the
      amount of occlusion. In addition, the robustness of any occlusion generated by the
      treatments will be tested by exposing the dentine samples to an acid challenge (orange
      juice) after 9 and 10 days treatment.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Outcomes Assessor</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in mean occlusion scores after 8 days treatment application</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Day 8</time_frame>
    <description>To measure the degree of occlusion using the following classification grades; 0 Not Evaluable, 1 Occluded, 2 Mostly Occluded, 3 Equally Occluded/Unoccluded, 4 Mostly Unoccluded and 5 Unoccluded</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in mean occlusion scores after 1, 4, &amp; 10 days treatment application</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Day 1, Day 4, Day 10</time_frame>
    <description>To measure the degree of occlusion using the following classification grades; 0 Not Evaluable, 1 Occluded, 2 Mostly Occluded, 3 Equally Occluded/Unoccluded, 4 Mostly Unoccluded and 5 Unoccluded</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Dentin Sensitivity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Test Product (0.454% stannous fluoride)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will use dentifrice containing 0.454% stannous fluoride. Appliances brushed ex situ in 1:3 slurry of freshly prepared dentifrice twice daily will be then returned to the participant's mouth. Each appliance will be brushed for 1 minute (2 minutes total for both of the participant's appliances) using an electric toothbrush in a 1:3 slurry of assigned dentifrice. Appliances will be returned to the participant's mouth and the participant will rinse with 10 mls of mineral water for 5 seconds.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Reference Product (0.76% sodium monofluorophosphate)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will use dentifrice containing 0.76% sodium monofluorophosphate. Appliances brushed ex situ in 1:3 slurry of freshly prepared dentifrice twice daily will be then returned to the participant's mouth. Each appliance will be brushed for 1 minute (2 minutes total for both of the participant's appliances) using an electric toothbrush in a 1:3 slurry of assigned dentifrice. Appliances will be returned to the participant's mouth and the participant will rinse with 10 mls of mineral water for 5 seconds.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Negative Control (Mineral water)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will use commercially available mineral water. Appliances brushed ex situ in mineral water twice daily will be then returned to the participant's mouth. Each appliance will be brushed for 1 minute (2 minutes total for both of the participant's appliances) using an electric toothbrush in mineral water. Appliances will be returned to the participant's mouth and the participant will rinse with 10 mls of mineral water for 5 seconds.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Stannous fluoride</intervention_name>
    <description>Dentifrice containing 0.454% stannous fluoride</description>
    <arm_group_label>Test Product (0.454% stannous fluoride)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sodium monofluorophosphate</intervention_name>
    <description>Dentifrice containing 0.76% sodium monofluorophosphate</description>
    <arm_group_label>Reference Product (0.76% sodium monofluorophosphate)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mineral water</intervention_name>
    <description>Commercially available mineral water</description>
    <arm_group_label>Negative Control (Mineral water)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Demonstrates understanding of the study procedures, restrictions and willingness to
             participate as evidenced by voluntary written informed consent and has received a
             signed and dated copy of the informed consent form.

          -  Aged between 18 and 80 years

          -  Understands and is willing, able and likely to comply with all study procedures and
             restrictions.

          -  Good general and mental health with, in the opinion of the investigator or medically
             qualified designee: No clinically significant and relevant abnormalities in medical
             history or upon oral examination, absence of any condition that would impact on the
             participant's safety or well being or affect the individual's ability to understand
             and follow procedures and requirements.

          -  Be able to accommodate the lower bi-lateral buccal intra-oral appliances each fitted
             with four dentine samples

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Women who are known to be pregnant or who are intending to become pregnant over the
             duration of the study.

          -  Women who are breast-feeding

          -  Current or recurrent disease/dental pathology that in the opinion of the investigator
             could affect the study outcomes.

        Current susceptibility to acid regurgitation, any orthodontic appliances, restorations,
        bridgework or dentures that in the opinion of the investigator would interfere with the
        study outcomes, recurrent or regular aphthous ulcers, severe gingivitis, carious lesions
        and periodontal disease,signs of severe dental erosion, any condition or medication which
        in the opinion of the investigator is currently causing xerostomia, and individuals who
        require antibiotic prophylaxis for dental procedures

          -  Known or suspected intolerance or hypersensitivity to the study materials (or closely
             related compounds) or any of their stated ingredients

          -  Participation in another study (clinical or cosmetic studies) or receipt of an
             investigational drug within 15 days of the screening visit, previous participation in
             this study.

          -  Recent history (within the last year) of alcohol or other substance abuse

          -  An employee of the sponsor or the study site or members of their immediate family.
             The site for this protocol is the Clinical Trials Unit in the Bristol Dental School
             and Hospital. Employees of the Bristol Dental School and Hospital not associated with
             the Clinical Trials Unit are eligible to participate

          -  Any participant who, in the judgement of the investigator, should not participate in
             the study
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GSK Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>GlaxoSmithKline</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bristol</city>
        <zip>BS1 2LY</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 3, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 9, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Dentin Sensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Fluorophosphate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fluorides</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tin Fluorides</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
