<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02541708</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Intravenous iron preparations have been shown to be superior to oral iron and have largely replaced the treatment of anaemia in Northern countries. However, the socio-economic and medical conditions in low resource countries greatly differ from those in northern countries. Patients' different access to medication supply, perception of medication need and compliance as well as the burden of concomitant disease like malaria, soil-transmitted helminths, schistosomiasis, HIV and red blood cells (RBC) genetic disorders may influence effectiveness and safety of iron substitution modality. The aim of the present study is to compare iv iron substitution by ferric carboxymaltose (Ferinject®) to per oral iron substitution in a low resource country</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>IV Ferric Carboxymaltose Compared With Oral Iron in the Treatment of Iron Deficiency Anemia at Delivery in Tanzania</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The objectives of the study are as follows: Primary objective: To assess the superiority in terms of effectiveness of iv iron substitution with ferric carboxymaltose versus per oral iron substitution in women with iron deficient anemia at delivery in Tanzania. Secondary objectives - To evaluate safety and feasibility of intravenous ferric carboxymaltose substitution compared to per oral iron substitution in a resource limited country - To evaluate acceptance of intravenous ferric carboxymaltose substitution compared to per oral iron substitution in a resource limited country - To evaluate wellbeing of women receiving intravenous ferric carboxymaltose compared to women receiving per oral iron substitution - To evaluate the sensitivity of diagnosis of iron deficiency by measuring hemoglobin, mean corpuscular volume (MCV) and mean corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (MCHC) only, compared to the diagnosis by measuring iron metabolism parameters in a resource limited country</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Iron-Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deficiency Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ferric Compounds</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin B Complex</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Women close to delivery Screening will be performed using the HemoCue System. In case of anemia, defined by Hg &lt;110 g/l, a venous puncture will be performed and the blood analyzed on a 5 population analyzer with erythrocyte indices and Reticulocyte indices and ferritin determined. Then If the anemia defined as Hg &lt;110 g/l is confirmed and the if ferritin is below 50 ng/ml, the patient will be included in the present study Patient compliance and geographic proximity allow proper staging and followup Patient must give written informed consent before registration Active malaria; patients will be tested for malaria by Rapid Diagnostic Test and microscopy and if positive treated. Patient with treated malaria can be included Helminthic infection; patients will be tested for helminthic infections by a stool ova and parasite exam and if positive treated by single oral dose of 400 mg albendazole. Treated patients can be included. HIV positivity. Patients will be tested and if positive they will be referred to the Care and Treatment Clinic at Bagamoyo District Hospital and excluded from the study. Known hemoglobinopathy CReactive protein (CRP) &gt;20 Patients with chronic fever Psychiatric disorder precluding understanding of information on trial related topics or giving informed consent Concurrent treatment with other experimental drugs or treatment in another clinical trial within 30 days prior to trial entry Any serious underlying medical condition (at the judgment of the investigator) which could impair the ability of the patient to participate in the trial Known allergy or hypersensitivity to study drug.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>