<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01555671</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Labor pain is universal and occurs acutely. This is the most painful experience in a woman's life. Pain relief during labor is expected to have positive impact on the progress, outcome and cost of labor. However, it is controversial whether labor analgesia shortens the length of labor and influences progression to cesarean.Labor analgesia can be performed via spinal, epidural or systemic routes (intravenous or intramuscular). Opioid agonists (meperidine, fentanyl etc.) as well are the systemic agents frequently used for labor analgesia.Results of the studies concerning effect of meperidine on the length of labor are controversial. Many studies have expressed that meperidine has no effect or effect on the progress of labor.This study aims to evaluate the effect of meperidine on the length of active phase of labor in nulliparous or multiparous women, who will be randomized into case and control groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Effectiveness of Administration of Meperidine on the Length of Active Phase of Labor in Women</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>- Participant eligibility for the study included gestational age between 34 and 42 weeks, live fetus, cephalic presentation, and were in active phase of labour with well-establish uterine contractions (3 contractions within 10 min) and cervical dilatation between 3 and 5 cm with a partially effaced cervix ( %70 or more ). - Exclusion criteria are placenta previa, placental abruption, caesarean section or any uterine scarring, abnormal placentation (accreta, increta, or percreta), multiple gestation, fetal macrosomia (≥4000 g), suspicious of cephalopelvic disproportion, meperidine allergy, use any kind of labour induction or augmentation before on admission for delivery in our hospital. - A Simple randomisation using a random-number table was performed by the investigational pharmacy staff, who took no further part in the study. - The primary outcome of interest in this study is the labor duration.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Meperidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>gestational age between 34 and 42 weeks live fetus cephalic presentation in active phase of labour placenta previa, placental abruption caesarean section or any uterine scarring multiple gestation fetal macrosomia (≥4000 g) meperidine allergy use any kind of labour induction or augmentation before on admission for delivery in our hospital</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>labor,</keyword>
	<keyword>meperidine,</keyword>
	<keyword>active phase,</keyword>
	<keyword>duration of labor</keyword>
</DOC>