<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01826851</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Exparel is a new local analgesic (numbing medication) that is intended to be longer acting than currently available local analgesics. The purpose of this study is to determine whether use of Exparel to numb the nerves along the breastbone after open heart surgery, will decrease pain and pain medication use after surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Parasternal Nerve Block in Cardiac Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a Phase 2, single-institution, randomized, double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled trial of patients undergoing a median sternotomy for primary cardiopulmonary bypass grafting (CABG) surgery. 78 subjects (39 per treatment arm) will be randomized in a 1:1 ratio to receive a single-dose, parasternal nerve block with either 266 mg Exparel or placebo (0.9% normal saline solution). The nerve blocks will be performed under direct visualization at the end of surgery, just prior to sternal closure.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>≥ 18 years old nonemergent coronary artery bypass grafting surgery (on and off pump) median sternotomy Concomitant cardiac procedures (e.g. aortic valve repair/replacement, mitral valve repair/replacement, aortic root replacements). Redo sternotomy. &lt; 50 kg (Exparel® is currently only approved in patients &gt; 50 kg). Pregnant or nursing History of alcohol, narcotic or illicit drug abuse Participation in another study evaluating investigational medications within the past 30 days Taking narcotic analgesics within 3 days preoperatively or perioperative stressdose steroids. Chronic noncardiac pain (e.g. lower back pain, fibromyalgia) requiring narcotic analgesics. Preoperative mild liver insufficiency as defined by liver function tests [(i.e. alanine aminotransferase (ALT), aspartate aminotransferase (AST)] ≥ 1.5 times the upper limit of normal (ULN: ALT: 035 U/L, AST: 035 U/L, Alk Phos 35105 U/L, Total bilirubin: 01.2 mg/dL) Preoperative mild renal insufficiency (Cr ≥ 1.5 mg/dL) Allergy to amidetype anesthetics Recurrent ventricular arrhythmias, low cardiac output requiring inotrope and/or intraaortic balloon pump support, left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 30% at time of preoperative screening/evaluation. Unable to provide informed consent or unable to understand how to use pain rating scales. Inability to understand or operate the patientcontrolled analgesia (PCA) machine.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pain management</keyword>
	<keyword>Anesthetic, local</keyword>
	<keyword>Nerve blockade</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Bypass Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>Analgesics, opioid</keyword>
	<keyword>Postoperative complications</keyword>
	<keyword>Bupivacaine</keyword>
</DOC>