<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02778425</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study compare the efficiency of partial splenic embolization +endoscopical therapy with endoscopical therapy alone in gastroesophageal variceal haemorrhage accompanied with splenomegaly or hypersplenism of hepatocirrhosis and portal hypertension treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>The Treatment of Hepatocirrhosis and Portal Hypertension</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Endoscopic therapy is the mature treatment of gastroesophageal variceal haemorrhage and PSE is an effective method for treatment of the hypersplenism and portal hypertension. Existing researches show that endoscopic therapy + PSE is more effective than endoscopic therapy alone in prevention of esophageal varices bleeding recurrence in the patients with liver cirrhosis. However, there is few articles which proved long-term effectiveness of endoscopic therapy + PSE, it needs further research on this issue. This study compares the efficiency of partial splenic embolization +endoscopic therapy with endoscopic therapy alone in the treatment of gastroesophageal variceal haemorrhage accompanied with splenomegaly or hypersplenism in the patients with hepatocirrhosis and portal hypertension.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension, Portal</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At the risk of gastroesophageal variceal hemorrhage; Acute gastroesophageal variceal hemorrhage;Haematemesis and/or melena result in gastroesophageal variceal haemorrhage of liver cirrhosis in the past. Splenomegaly or hypersplenism acting as thrombocytopenia (PLT &lt; 75000 cells/mm^3). Consent form must be signed by patients or their guardians before entering the test. History of liver surgery or spleen surgery and liver cancer. Existence of gastrointestinal endoscopic therapy contraindication;Hemorrhagic shock has not be corrected;Hepatic encephalopathy. Sinus bradycardia, bronchial asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, heart failure, low blood pressure, atrioventricular block, insulin dependent diabetes, peripheral vascular disease, liver function Child Pugh class C. Pregnant women and nursing mothers.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>partial splenic embolization</keyword>
</DOC>