<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01011660</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of the study is to investigate the optimized treatment strategy of hypertension, so as to make more patients to reach the blood pressure goals and to reduce cardio-cerebrovascular events. Objective and Methods: Patients are eligible for inclusion in the study if they are essential hypertension, 50-79 years of age with at least one cardiovascular risk factor and sign the informed consent forms. This project is a multi-centre, prospective randomized,，openlabel blind-endpoint evaluation controlled (PROBE) trial. 12000 patients will be randomly assigned to either of low-dose Amlodipine+Telmisartan group or Amlodipine+ diuretics group. Among those patients with serum cholesterol between 4.0-6.1mmol/L, they will be also randomized into small dose of statin-based regimen or standard management regimen; Patients will also randomly assigned to intensive lifestyle intervention group or standard intervention group according to the community area where the patients in.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Angiotensin II Receptor Blocker Compared With Diuretics in High-risk Hypertensive Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is aimed to observe the main outcome (stroke, myocardial infarction and death from cardiovascular disease) differences between different groups.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diuretics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amiloride</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Telmisartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amlodipine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Simvastatin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>essential hypertension 5079 years old with at least one of the cardiovascular risk factor sign consent forms secondary hypertension attack of cerebrovascular events or myocardial infarction within recent 3 months coexistence of severe cardiomyopathy, rheumatic or congenital heart diseases unstable angina severe hepatopathy or nephropathy (ALT elevation &gt; 2 fold or serum creatinine &gt; 2.5mg/dl) malignant tumor gout women taking contraceptives or with pregnancy allergic history to the research drugs validated contradiction to the research drugs participating in other clinical trials unable for longterm followup or poor compliance unsuitable for clinical trial at the discretion of doctors in charge</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>cardiovascular risk factors</keyword>
	<keyword>drugs intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>lipid-lowering therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>50-79 years of age</keyword>
	<keyword>sign</keyword>
	<keyword>the informed</keyword>
	<keyword>consent</keyword>
	<keyword>forms</keyword>
</DOC>