<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01011179</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the feasibility of "Teens Taking Charge: Managing Arthritis On-line" intervention that will help adolescents with arthritis to better manage their disease and improve their health-related quality of life (HRQL).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Internet Self-Management Program With Telephone Support for Adolescents With Arthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This feasibility study will (1) assess adolescents' willingness to be randomized; (2) pilot the intervention, attention control strategies (e.g., adolescents' 'own best efforts' at managing arthritis), and outcome measures; (3) determine adolescents' perceptions regarding acceptability of the web-based intervention; and (4) obtain estimates of treatment effects in primary (HRQL) and secondary (knowledge, coping, self-efficacy, stress, treatment adherence, pain) outcome measures to inform the calculation of appropriate sample size for the future RCT. We hypothesize that adolescents with JIA in the web-based intervention will demonstrate: (a) improved HRQL; (b) increased disease-specific knowledge; (c) improved coping, self-efficacy, and adherence to prescribed management; and (d) decreased pain and stress compared to adolescents in the attention control group</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Arthritis, Juvenile</mesh_term>
	<criteria>adolescents 12 to 18 years diagnosed with JIA, able to speak and read English or French able to complete baseline online outcome measures. cognitive impairment major comorbid illnesses (medical or psychiatric) which may impact their ability to understand and use the webbased program.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Teens Taking Charge</keyword>
	<keyword>Managing Arthritis Online</keyword>
	<keyword>juvenile idiopathic arthritis</keyword>
	<keyword>internet</keyword>
	<keyword>self-management</keyword>
</DOC>