<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01011075</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will evaluate the clinical efficacy of combining Gleevec (imatinib mesylate), a PDGFR antagonist, with front-line, single-agent paclitaxel in a cohort of elderly patients with advanced, non-small cell lung cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Gleevec and Weekly Paclitaxel in Patients Aged 70 or Older With Advanced Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Paclitaxel 90 mg/m2 IV on days 3, 10, 17 Imatinib 600 mg/day, oral administration in 4-day pulses bracketing each paclitaxel infusion (days 1-4; 8-11; 15-18) Cycle length: 28 days Number of cycles: up to 6</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Imatinib Mesylate</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 70 years Histologic or cytologic diagnosis of nonsmall cell lung cancer At least one site of measurable disease, as defined by the modified RECIST criteria (See section 7.6) Stage IIIB with pleural effusion or Stage IV disease. Includes patients who received surgery alone for early stage disease, now in relapse with advanced disease. Staging is according to the American Joint Committee on Cancer classification scheme, 6th edition.48 Adequate hepatic, renal and marrow function Liver function tests: total bilirubin &lt; 1.25 x upper limit of normal (ULN), AST and ALT &lt; 2.5 x ULN, Creatinine &lt; 1.5 x ULN Baseline absolute neutrophil count &gt; 1500/μL Baseline platelet count &gt; 100,000/μL ECOG Performance Status 0, 1 or 2 at the time of informed consent. (See Appendix 1) Written, voluntary consent Patients with reproductive potential must use an acceptable contraceptive method. Such methods include: 1) Male hormonal contraception; 2) Partner without reproductive potential, including postmenopausal status or history of tubal ligation; 3) Partner with intrauterine device (IUD) or contraceptive vaginal ring; 4) Partner takes oral contraceptive pill, wears contraceptive patch, or has contraceptive implant; 5) Routine use of barrier method, such as condoms or diaphragm, during sexual intercourse. Uncontrolled brain metastasis. Patients with known brain metastasis must have completed treatment with surgery, radiation or both. In addition, they must be off corticosteroids. Symptomatic neuropathy (Grade 2 or higher) Prior chemotherapy for advanced nonsmall cell lung cancer. (Prior adjuvant, neoadjuvant, or chemoradiotherapy for NSCLC is permitted, provided at least 6 months elapsed prior to documented metastatic recurrence.) Patient is &lt; 5 years free of another primary malignancy, except: a) if the other malignancy is basal cell carcinoma or cervical carcinoma in situ or b) if the other primary malignancy is not considered clinically significant and is requiring no active intervention Prior radiation therapy to &gt; 25% of bone marrow Grade III/IV congestive heart failure, as defined by NYHA criteria, or myocardial infarction within 6 months. Any serious or uncontrolled concomitant disorder that, in the opinion of the investigator, would compromise the patient's ability to complete the study. Patient has known chronic liver disease, e.g. diagnosis of chronic active hepatitis or cirrhosis. Major surgery two weeks prior to study treatment Patient with any significant history of noncompliance to medical regimens or with inability to grant reliable informed consent Any condition requiring continuous administration of systemic corticosteroids. The patient is on therapeutic anticoagulation with warfarin.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>70 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lung cancer,</keyword>
	<keyword>Non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic</keyword>
	<keyword>Gleevec</keyword>
	<keyword>elderly</keyword>
</DOC>