<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01011231</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the efficacy, of treating patients with recurrent glioblastoma using Gamma-Knife Radiosurgery (GKS) to target a tumor volume defined by a combination of gadolinium enhancement and magnetic resonance spectroscopy (MRS). This is a single center, Phase II trial. A total of 40 glioblastoma patients will be enrolled into the primary arm of the trial. In addition, a minimum of 10 patients with recurrent anaplastic (grade III) gliomas and a minimum of 10 patients with recurrent low-grade (grade II) gliomas will be enrolled into exploratory arms. The investigators hypothesize that the use of a combination of gadolinium enhancement and elevated Cho:NAA ratio via MRS to determine the treatment target volume for Gamma Knife may be an effective way to treat focally-recurrent glioblastoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Gamma-Knife Radiosurgery Using Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) Spectroscopy for Recurrent Glioma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Design: A single-center, single-arm, one-stage phase II clinical trial for patients with recurrent grade IV glioma (glioblastoma), with two additional exploratory arms for patients with recurrent grade II and grade III gliomas. Patient Numbers: A total of 40 patients with recurrent glioblastoma will be enrolled. In addition, a minimum of 10 patients with recurrent grade III (anaplastic) glioma and a minimum of 10 patients with recurrent grade II (low-grade) glioma will be enrolled independently into separate exploratory arms. Summary of Patient Eligibility Criteria Histological confirmation of glioma, grades II - IV; prior first-line treatment with surgery, radiotherapy and chemotherapy for malignant (grades III and IV) gliomas; age &gt; 18 years; life expectancy &gt;8 weeks; Karnofsky Performance Status ≥ 60; adequate organ function; signed patient informed consent; willingness to forego additional therapy until evidence of disease progression. End Points Primary: Six-month progression-free survival (PFS-6) Secondary: Median overall survival (mOS), median progression-free survival (mPFS), location of recurrence, symptomatic necrosis rate, reoperation rate, reoperation findings (estimated percentage of viable tumor vs. radiation effect and necrosis), and safety</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Histologically confirmed glioblastoma, gliosarcoma, anaplastic astrocytoma, anaplastic oligodendroglioma, anaplastic oligoastrocytoma, malignant glioma not otherwise specified, lowgrade astrocytoma, lowgrade oligodendroglioma, lowgrade oligoastrocytoma, or lowgrade glioma not otherwise specified. 2. Prior firstline treatment with surgery or biopsy followed by fractionated radiotherapy with concurrent temozolomidecontaining chemotherapy is required for malignant (grade III or IV) glioma patients. Additional prior chemotherapy is allowed, without limitation on number of recurrences. In patients with lowgrade tumors, neither prior radiotherapy nor prior chemotherapy is required. 3. An interval of &gt; 2 months since completion of fractionated radiotherapy. 4. Age &gt; 18 years 5. Life expectancy of at least 8 weeks. 6. Karnofsky Performance Status score (KPS) of ≥ 60 7. Documented recurrent disease: Recurrent disease is defined either as histological confirmation of tumor, as an increase in tumor size of at least 25% based upon serial MR images, or as development of a new site of disease. Tumor size will be calculated using the sum of the largest crosssectional perpendicular diameters of contrastenhancing tumor for highgrade tumors, the sum of the largest crosssectional perpendicular diameters of FLAIR abnormality for lowgrade tumors, or as worsened spectroscopic characteristics for any tumor type (development of ≥ 2 new voxels with CNI ≥ 3, or ≥ 25% increase in the sum of the CNI ratios within a group of previously abnormal voxels [where abnormal is defined as CNI ≥ 3]). Disease must be evaluable, but does not need to be measurable. The target site for GKS does not need to be located in a previouslyirradiated area. 8. Eligibility for gammaknife radiosurgery: The decision to treat with gammaknife radiosurgery will be made by a consensus of the radiation oncology, neurosurgery and neurooncology cochairs or their alternates at the weekly Brain Tumor or GammaKnife Tumor Conferences. The MRS defined target volume must be ≤ 15 cc. and not involving eloquent brain (speech/language cortex, motor/sensory cortex, basal ganglia, brainstem, or corpus callosum 2) on an MRI done within 14 days of the planned GKS procedure. 9. BUN &lt; 25 and Cr &lt; 1.7 10. Negative pregnancy test at the time of GKS in any patient who could be pregnant. 11. Willingness to forego additional therapy until evidence of disease progression. 12. Signed and witnessed informed consent and signed authorization for the release of their protected health information. 1. MRS defined tumor volume greater than 15 cc. 2. MRS defined tumor volume involving eloquent brain (speech/language cortex, motor/sensory cortex, basal ganglia, brainstem, or corpus callosum). 3. Concurrent treatment with chemotherapy. 4. Active infectious process requiring IV antibiotics. 5. History of any other cancer (except nonmelanoma skin cancer or carcinoma insitu of the cervix), unless in complete remission and off of all therapy for that disease for a minimum of three years. 6. Other major medical illness judged by the investigator to preclude prolonged followup. 7. Any condition that compromises compliance with the objectives and procedures of this protocol, as judged by the principal investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Gamma Knife radiosurgery</keyword>
	<keyword>recurrent glioma</keyword>
	<keyword>MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>Spectroscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>Recurrent grade IV glioma (glioblastoma), with two additional exploratory arms for patients with recurrent grade II and grade III gliomas</keyword>
</DOC>