<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01417351</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Researchers at the USDA Western Human Nutrition Research Center and clinicians at UC Davis Medical Center are currently conducting a study on the effects of vitamin D supplementation during pregnancy on maternal health and immune function. The investigators believe that vitamin D supplementation at levels greater than the current recommendation is beneficial for maternal health during pregnancy. In particular, there is evidence that vitamin D deficiency during pregnancy puts women at greater risk for diseases like pre-eclampsia, which may be due to an imbalance in immune function at the placenta. This randomized, double-blind study is designed to test this hypothesis. Pregnant women who participate in the study receive either 400 IU or 2,000 IU of vitamin D per day for the duration of their pregnancy. The investigators will collect blood at three time points during pregnancy (16-20 weeks, 26-28 weeks, 36 weeks gestation) for analysis of immune function and vitamin D status. The investigators are also collecting data on clinical parameters, such as blood pressure and glucose tolerance.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Vitamin D Supplementation During Pregnancy on Clinical Outcomes and Immune Function</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Pregnant women Less than 20 weeks gestation Over 18 years of age Able to swallow nutritional supplements Use of medications known to affect vitamin D metabolism Diagnosis of type 1 diabetes History of thyroid, renal, or liver disease Problems with digestion or absorption</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
	<keyword>immune function</keyword>
</DOC>