<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01417104</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being done to assess the effectiveness of short term (~9 months) Aliskiren/Placebo therapy to slow down the progression of atherosclerotic disease in thoracic and abdominal aorta. This will be checked by comparing before and after therapy magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) pictures of the aortic wall. Aliskiren is an FDA approved drug for hypertension but in this study is used for a new indication. Recent studies with animals have shown that Aliskiren therapy reduces the atherosclerotic plaque. Therefore, in this study, the investigators would like to evaluate whether the investigational drug Aliskiren, which is not FDA approved for this indication has the same beneficial effects in people with atherosclerotic disease.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Aliskiren Effect on Aortic Plaque Progression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Treatments and Clinic Visits: The 36-week double-blind, randomized treatment phase of the trial is preceded by 2-week single-blind placebo period to assess eligibility into the active treatment period, compliance, and to confirm the baseline blood pressure values of the enrolled subjects. If at the end of the single-blind phase, inclusion criteria will not be met, the participants will not be allowed to continue on to the trial. If they are eligible they will undergo baseline MRI studies after being randomized to either placebo or Aliskiren 150 mg, with an escalation to 300 mg at 2 weeks into treatment. This dose will be maintained for the duration of the trial. After randomization and dose escalation visits (at 2 weeks), patients will return for scheduled clinic visits at weeks 12 and 36. Assessment of routine safety measures including serum creatinine and potassium will be performed at pre-designated visits (randomization, drug escalation and end-of trial). At each study visit, after having the patient in a sitting position for 5 minutes, SBP/diastolic blood pressure will be measured 3 times in accordance with the AHA Committee Report on blood pressure determination. The patient will be then asked to stand for 2 minutes, and a single blood pressure measurement will be measured in the standing position. Evidence of left ventricular hypertrophy (LVH) will be determined using the Romhilt-Estes scoring system at baseline. Specialized measurements of plasma including insulin, glucose measures, adipokines (leptin and adiponectin) and high- sensitivity C-reactive protein (hsCRP) will be performed at randomization and 12 weeks into the trial. Central aortic blood pressure assessment will be performed at randomization and end of trial/exit visits (SphygmoCor CP, AtCor Medical, Itaska, Illinois, USA). Plasma direct renin measurements will be obtained at baseline and 12 weeks in part to assess compliance of patients with their therapy (Diasource, Belgium).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients, both males and females, were eligible if they were ≥ 45 years of age, with previously documented cardiovascular disease, defined as at least one of the following: myocardial infarction (MI), cerebrovascular accident (CVA), coronary bypass surgery and/or percutaneous intervention, peripheral arterial disease (PAD), defined as ankle brachial index (ABI) &lt;0.9 and/or prior peripheral intervention/surgery. Subjects on angiotensinconverting enzyme inhibitor (ACEI) or angiotensin receptor blockers (ARB) therapy were eligible to participate, provided no dose adjustments were made during the course of the study. Contraindications to the MRI exam (pacemakers, metallic implants, severe claustrophobia); diagnosis of Type II Diabetes or use of hypoglycemic drugs; uncontrolled hypertension (&gt;145/90 mm Hg); low density lipoprotein (LDL) of ≥ 130mg/dL; renal insufficiency defined as glomerular filtration rate (GFR) ≤ 40 ml/minute (derived by the Modified Diet in Renal Disease (MDRD) equation); initiation of new therapy with statins, ACEI/ARBs, antioxidants, calcium channel blockers, diuretics, β blockers; transient ischemic cerebral attack during the prior 6 months; history of allergy to renin inhibitors; unstable cardiac syndromes; symptomatic arrhythmias; history of malignancy including leukemia and lymphoma (but not basal cell skin cancer, cured squamous cell cancer and localized prostate cancer) and history of allergy to renin inhibitors.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>plaque</keyword>
	<keyword>magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)</keyword>
	<keyword>high blood pressure</keyword>
	<keyword>MI</keyword>
	<keyword>heart attack</keyword>
	<keyword>CVA</keyword>
	<keyword>stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>PAD</keyword>
</DOC>