<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01262820</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is an open label Phase II Trial that using the investigational anti-cancer agent, Pazopanib to see whether non-squamous non-small cell lung cancer will respond to its use by decreasing the size of the tumor or stopping its growth.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pazopanib In Stage IIIB/IV NSCLC Lung Cancer After Progression on First Line Therapy Containing Bevacizumab</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This multi-centered phase II trial will examine pazopanib stage IIIB/IV non-squamous NSCLC patients who have progressed on first-line therapy containing bevacizumab. Treatment should continue until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, study withdrawal, or death. Patients who progress will be treated at the discretion of their physician. all patients who initiate treatment will be evaluated for disease control rate, which is the primary endpoint of this study. The primary objective is to estimate the disease control rate of pazopanib alone in patients with stage IIIB/IV non-squamous NSCLC who progressed while on bevacizumab. Disease control rate id defined as complete (CR) + partial response (PR) + stable disease (SD) lasting greater than or equal to 12 weeks as defined by RECIST. Secondary Objectives To estimate the combined response rate (CR + PR) of pazopanib according to RECIST To estimate the progression free survival (defined as time of enrollment until disease progression or death) and overall survival (defined as time of enrollment until death) of patients treated with pazopanib. To evaluate the safety and tolerability of pazopanib using the National Cancer Institute Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI CTCAE) version 4.0 To explore potential correlations between blood biomarkers and clinical response. Pazopanib is dosed continuously throughout the study. Cycle lengths are identified as 21 days for purposes of the calendar. The treatment dosage and administration for participating subjects will be, Pazopanib, 800 mg by mouth daily during a 21 day cycle until disease progression.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 or older Stage IIIB (with malignant pleural or pericardial effusion or supraclavicular lymph node involvement) or stage IV NSCLC Evidence of progression while on bevacizumab Patients treated for CNS metastases who are asymptomatic with no requirement for steroids for 2 weeks prior to first dose of study drug Prior malignancy Clinically significant gastrointestinal abnormalities Presence of uncontrolled infection or nonhealing wound, fracture, or ulcer History of cardiovascular conditions within the past 6 months</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pazopanib</keyword>
	<keyword>Non Squamous Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>After Progress on first line therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Using Bevacizumab</keyword>
</DOC>