<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01568489</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this phase 2 study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of HL-009 Liposomal Gel in adult patients with mild to moderate atopic dermatitis (AD).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Phase 2 Study of HL-009 Liposomal Gel to Treat Mild to Moderate Atopic Dermatitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group comparison study in subjects with mild to moderate AD. Following a 2-week screening period, subjects will be randomly assigned into one of four treatment arms. Placebo or HL-009 study treatments will be administrated to subjects twice daily for 8 consecutive weeks. After the randomization at Week 0 (Visit 2), subjects will visit their respective trial sites at Weeks 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 10 (Visits 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, and 9). All study drugs will be in identical laminated tubes to preserve double-blinding of the study.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatitis, Atopic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Eczema</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males or females aged 18 or older Clinical diagnosis of AD by a board certified/eligible dermatologist Subjects who have body surface area affected to at least 2% total body surface area (BSA) Subjects with IGA score 2 or 3 corresponding to mild to moderate AD at screening and baseline visits Subjects who can give written informed consent Subjects who had topical treatment with corticosteroids within 2 weeks before screening Subjects who had systemic treatment with corticosteroids or ciclosporin and photopheresis treatment within 2 weeks before screening Subjects who had ultraviolet irradiation within 2 weeks before screening Subjects who participated in another drug trial within 4 weeks before screening Subjects who have an allergy to one of the excipients Female subjects who have a positive serum pregnancy test at screening, plan a pregnancy during study period, or are breast feeding Female subjects who don't meet one of the following criteria: Be surgically sterile,Postmenopausal for at least 12 months, or If sexually active, they should use oral contraceptives, double barrier contraception, intrauterine device, or other methods approved by the sponsor Subjects who have other topical treatment of the AD area Subjects who take any systemic antiinfective or antibiotic treatment Subjects who had eczema herpeticum Subjects who have any clinically significant presence of skin disease or pigmentation other than atopic dermatitis, or wide scar on atopic dermatitis area Subjects who have poorlycontrolled chronic disease Subjects who have significant medical problems, including but not limited to uncontrolled hypertension and congestive heart failure Subjects who have clinically significant laboratory abnormalities at screening Subjects who have a marked prolongation of QT/QTc interval at screening Subjects who have a history of additional risk factors for TdP Subjects who use a medication that prolongs the QT/QTc interval Subjects who, in the opinion of the investigator, would be noncompliant with the visit schedule of study procedures</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>