<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02145546</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The current evidences indicate that ~30% patients with sick sinus syndrome(SSS) would develop persistent atrial fibrillation (AF) after a long term pacing therapy. However, the accurate influence of antiarrhythmic drugs on the AF is still not well defined. The purpose of the study is to assess the therapeutic effects of various antiarrhythmic drugs (Amiodarone, Sotalol and Propafenone) on the long term management of AF in SSS patients with AF, including the reduced AF burden (duration and episodes) and persistent AF free survival rate. All patients will be followed up for 12 months.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Antiarrhythmic Drugs Assessment in Preventing Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Amiodarone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sotalol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anti-Arrhythmia Agents</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Propafenone</mesh_term>
	<criteria>at least 18 years old sick sinus syndrome with pacemaker Class I or Class IIa indication has a pacemaker which can provide the daily AF burden monitor record for at least 28 days has at AF record in the past 6 months, the valid AF record includes any of 1. at least one 30 seconds AF holter record 2. at least one 15 seconds 12ECG record 3. at least 5 minutes long AF episodes record from pacemakers able and willing to give informed consent will have cardiac surgery in the next 6 month or in the waiting list of heart transplantation NYHA Class III or IV LVEF &lt;50% Reversible AF, such as AF caused by hyperthyroidism or severe postoperative atrial fibrillation Persistence AF Expected life expectancy less than 1 year Planned to be pregnant or be in the feeding period in the next year Nonstable, decompensated heart failure Allergy to Amiodarone, Propafenone or Sotalol Cancer Clear liver damage ( ALT and/or AST &gt; 2*normal limit) Patients with cardiogenic shock history Be in the treatment of Amiodarone for more than 3 months or less than 3 months with Amiodarone wash out period less than 30 days Coronary artery disease (CHD), cardiomyopathy, severe valvular heart disease, severe obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), long QT syndrome</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Pacing dependent</keyword>
	<keyword>Atrial Fibrillation</keyword>
	<keyword>Amiodarone</keyword>
	<keyword>Propafenone</keyword>
	<keyword>Sotalol</keyword>
	<keyword>AF burden</keyword>
</DOC>