<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02077621</DOC>
	<brief_summary>PG2 has been approved in Taiwan to treat cancer-related fatigue for advanced cancer patients. The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of PG2 on fatigue relief in patients undergoing palliative abdominal surgery for cancer. The secondary endpoints, including the length of hospital stay, postoperative complications, HRQL, inflammatory biomarkers, the duration of antibiotic therapy, mortality during the hospital stay, weight loss and body composition, will be evaluated among these patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of PG2 Injection for Improving Fatigue in Patients After Palliative Abdominal Surgery for Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This will be a double-blind, randomized, and placebo-controlled study. At least 40 evaluable patients who are scheduled for palliative abdominal surgery for cancer will be randomly assigned to the control or treatment group. Each group will have at least 20 patients and be treated as follows: 1) control group: patients will accept placebo 1 dose a day (POD-1) before surgery and 1 dose a day for 3 days after surgery (POD+0 to POD+2); 2) treatment group: patients will accept PG2 1 dose a day (POD-1) before surgery and 1 dose a day for 3 days after surgery (POD+0 to POD+2).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who have cancer and are scheduled for palliative abdominal surgery for cancer Age &gt; 20 years older Patients who signed the informed consent form Patients, at screening, has levels greater than 2.5 times the upper limit of normal liver function of alanine aminotransferase or aspartate aminotransferase. Patients has a severe renal impairment (defined as serum creatinine greater than 2 times the upper limit of normal or BUN greater than 2.5 times the upper limit of normal for range); or the subject is on dialysis. Patients have ongoing infection, respiratory tract dysfunction, cardiac dysfunction or immune disorder that, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with conduct of the study. Patients who are not suitable for undergoing surgery (e.g. congenital hemostatic disorders) by the investigator's judgment. Patients have enrolled or have not yet completed other investigational drug trials within 1 month before screening. Female patients are pregnant or breastfeeding. Patients who require preoperative nutritional support Patients with serious comorbidities (American Society of Anesthesiologists Risk Class of 4 or 5). Patients who is unwilling or unable to answer the quality of life questionnaires i.e. the BFIT and EORTC QLQC30.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>cancer-related fatigue</keyword>
	<keyword>Palliative Abdominal Surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>HRQL</keyword>
</DOC>