<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02077543</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine the innocuity and operability of the innovative tumor molecular and cellular print ProTool.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Multicenter Safety Trial Assessing an Innovative Tumor Molecular and Cellular Print Medical Device in Glioma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Diagnostic in cancerology keeps based on biopsy or exeresis tissues anatomopathologic analysis. Micro-invasive biopsy approaches reduces chirurgical aggressivity but also tissue amount The innovative Medical Device ProTool offers a micro-invasive biopsy approach in parallel with classical chirurgical proceeding. It allows to complete heterogeneity tumoral analysis and peri-tumoral tissue environment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Astrocytoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oligodendroglioma</mesh_term>
	<criteria>more or equal than 18 years old patient affiliated to social security or similarly regime informed consent form signed glial tumor suspicion Stereotaxic biopsy indication Karnofsky score &gt; 70% Hematological assessment : neutrophils &gt; 1500/mm3 Platelet &gt; 150 000 blood Creatinin normal alkaline Phosphatases and transaminases no more than two times normal Bilirubin &lt; 1.5 times normal Pregnant women and lactating mothers Ward of court or under guardianship Adult unable to express their consent Person deprived of freedom by judicial or administrative decision Person hospitalized without their consent Person under legal protection Person participating in another clinical study Intratumoral hemorrhage MRI detected Treatment anticoagulant or antisludge treatments Active Infections and non controled or medical affection or psychiatric intercurrent non treated Evolutive cerebral oedema without corticoid response Non controled Epilepsy without antiepileptics response Susceptibility to Medical Device materials allergy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>