<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02077140</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of MDT-10013 in men and women 18 to 80 years of age who are undergoing bunionectomy. The primary objective is to determine the analgesic efficacy of MDT-10013 compared with standard of care in the treatment of acute postoperative pain after subjects undergo bunionectomy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of MDT-10013 in the Treatment of Acute Postoperative Pain Following Bunionectomy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Is male or female aged 18 to 80 years. 2. Has a body mass index from 18 kg/m2 to 40 kg/m2. 3. Is scheduled to undergo primary, unilateral, first metatarsal bunionectomy (osteotomy and internal fixation) with no additional collateral procedures. 4. Is classified by American Society of Anesthesiologists Physical Status Classification System as Class I or II. 5. Must meet the following criteria if female: Is of nonchildbearing potential, defined as any woman who has undergone surgical sterilization or is more than 2 years postmenopausal If of childbearing potential, may be enrolled on the condition that results of a pregnancy test are negative at baseline (at Screening and before surgery) and that she is routinely using an effective method of birth control with a low failure rate (i.e., hormonal contraception, intrauterine device, condoms in combination with a spermicidal cream, or total sexual abstinence) 6. Has read, understood, and signed the informed consent prior to study entry. 7. Is mentally competent, reliable, and cooperative to undergo all visits and procedures scheduled in the study protocol and to record the required information. 8. Has medical history, physical examination, vital signs, laboratory tests, and 12lead electrocardiograms (ECGs) that are normal or without clinically relevant abnormalities as per investigator's judgment. 1. Is a female who is pregnant or breastfeeding. 2. Is not indicated for surgery because of an inflammatory process or risk of infection or delayed wound healing (e.g., autoimmune disorder). 3. Has a history of allergy or hypersensitivity to the components in the investigational product or to the opioid medication (oxycodone). 4. Before surgery, has current orthostatic hypotension (defined as systolic blood pressure decrease of at least 20 mm Hg or a diastolic blood pressure decrease of at least 10 mm Hg or an increase in heart rate by 20 beats per minute within 3 minutes of sitting up or standing). 5. Has severe asthma, defined as requiring frequent or ongoing treatment to control symptoms. Exerciseinduced asthma or mild asthma not requiring ongoing treatment may not be exclusionary at the discretion of the investigator. 6. Has a current gastrointestinal disorder associated with bleeding, a history of such a disorder, or gastrointestinal inflammatory diseases as Crohn's disease or ulcerative colitis. 7. Has any clinically significant cardiovascular condition as evidenced by physical examination, medical history, and/or baseline ECG. 8. Has evidence of bradycardia as shown by heart rate of &lt;50 beats per minute via screening ECG. 9. Has a known infection with human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis B virus, or hepatitis C virus. 10. Has a chronic pain condition that may interfere with the subject's assessment of pain postoperatively, as determined by the investigator. 11. Has any poorly controlled or serious medical conditions, psychiatric illnesses, or clinically significant laboratory values that, in the opinion of the investigator, could compromise the safety of the subject or the scientific integrity of the study (e.g., uncontrolled hypertension, autoimmune disease, or clinically relevant symptoms of thyroid dysfunction). 12. Has presence or history of local or systemic malignant disease in the past 5 years (history of basal cell carcinoma will be allowed). 13. Has impaired renal function (creatinine &gt;1.5 times upper limit of normal). 14. Has chronic impairment liver function (aspartate aminotransferase or alanine aminotransferase &gt;3 times upper limit of normal). 15. Has insulindependent diabetes or uncontrolled diabetes mellitus (glycosylated hemoglobin &gt;7%). 16. Has leukopenia (&lt;3500 leukocytes/μL). 17. Has current treatment with any of the following medications: 1. Systemic corticosteroids (intranasal/inhaled steroids are acceptable). 2. Immunosuppressant therapy to treat autoimmune diseases (e.g., rheumatoid arthritis, multiple sclerosis, myasthenia gravis, systemic lupus erythematosus, sarcoidosis, focal segmental glomerulosclerosis, Crohn's disease, Behcet's Disease, pemphigus, and ulcerative colitis). 3. Oral or topical products that contain clonidine (e.g., Catapres). 4. Herbal supplements that contain yohimbine. 5. Anticoagulant/antiplatelet therapy (prophylactic aspirin at 81 mg/day is acceptable). If applicable, aspirin therapy should be held before and after the study procedure on the basis of the investigator's discretion. 6. Antiepileptic drugs, antipsychotics, tricyclic antidepressants, monoamine oxidase inhibitors, lithium, and sulfonamides. 7. Calcium channel blocker, digoxin, or betaadrenergic blockers. 18. Has chronic use of opioids (including tramadol), defined as use 20 out of the last 30 days before study screening. 19. Has a history of or current diagnosis of epilepsy. 20. Has a known or suspected history of drug or alcohol abuse (as determined by the investigator). 21. Is judged by the investigator not to be a suitable candidate for study treatment and pain relief medication on the basis of medical history, concomitant medication, and concurrent systemic disease. 22. Is not stabilized on the following medications for at least 8 weeks prior to dosing: selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) and serotoninnorepinephrine reuptake inhibitors (SNRIs). 23. Is unable to refrain from taking nonsteroidal anti inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) or opioids within the 24hour period prior to surgery. 24. Has participated in any other clinical trial in the 4 weeks prior to Screening. 25. Experiences any surgical complication that, in the opinion of the investigator, precludes implantation of MDT10013.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>