<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01539850</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to evaluate the LGL102 implant safety in obese to morbidly obese subjects treated with OMS102 system. The effect of the therapy on body weight changes will be also evaluated.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety Evaluation of the LGL102 in Obese Subjects Treated With OMS102</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obesity, Morbid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age of 18 60 years old at time of screening BMI of 35 to 55 at time of screening History of obesity ≥ 5 years The subject has been under routine care of the investigator or another single physician that can supply a medical record for at least 6 months prior to enrollment Women with childbearing potential (i.e., not postmenopausal or surgically sterilized) must agree to use adequate birth control methods No significant weight loss (&lt; 5%) within four months prior to enrollment as documented in the subject's medical record. Successful psychological evaluation following the institution psychological evaluation protocol for bariatric surgery or successful historic assessment performed no more than 6 months prior to enrollment. Glycosylated Hemoglobin; HbA1c ≤ 7.0 % at Visit 2 or historic value performed no more than 3 months prior to enrollment. If taking antidepressant medications, they must be stable for at least six months prior to enrollment Willingness to refrain from using prescription, over the counter or herbal weight loss products for the duration of the trial Alert, mentally competent, and able to understand and willing to comply with the requirements of the clinical trial, and personally motivated to abide by the requirements and restrictions of the clinical trial Able to provide voluntary informed consent Any prior bariatric surgery Other implanted electrical stimulation devices (e.g. pacemaker, defibrillator, neurostimulator) Diagnosed with past or current psychiatric condition that may impair his/her ability to comply with the study procedures Use of antipsychotic medications Diagnosed with a eating disorder such as bulimia or binge eating Obesity due to an endocrinopathy (e.g. Cushing disease) Insulin therapy GI disease such as hiatal hernia (&gt; 5cm), gastroparesis, esophageal motility disorders or intractable constipation. Any history of peptic ulcer disease within 5 years prior to enrollment History of Barrett's esophagus Women who are pregnant, lactating or anticipate becoming pregnant within 24 months Arthritis or other pathologies limiting physical activities that physician feels should exclude the patient from the study. Cardiac history that physician feels should exclude the patient from the study. Use of another investigational device or agent in the 30 days prior to enrollment A history of lifethreatening disease within 5 years prior to enrollment Any other condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would make the subject unsuitable for the study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>gastric stimulation</keyword>
	<keyword>morbid obesity</keyword>
</DOC>