<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02122588</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a multicentre, non-interventional, prospective study to be carried out in representative hospitals in order to assess 1st line treatment management and diagnostic approaches applied to ovarian, peritoneal and fallopian tube cancer management in Russia and assess patients` characteristics and the occurrence of BRCA (Breast Cancer gene) mutations among Russian women with serous and endometrioid ovarian, peritoneal and fallopian tube cancer. No additional procedures besides those already used in the routine clinical practice will be applied to the patients. Treatment assignment will be done according to the current practice.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>OVArian Cancer Non-Interventional Study - OVATAR</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a multicentre, non-interventional, prospective study to be carried out in representative hospitals in order to assess ovarian, fallopian tube and peritoneal cancer management in Russia. No additional procedures besides those already used in the routine clinical practice will be applied to the patients. Treatment assignment will be done according to the current practice. It is planned to enrol 300 subjects in up to 30 sites in Russian Federation. The average number of patients per site is planned as 10-15; there are no restrictions on minimum and maximum number of subjects per site in this study. The disease treatments approaches in 1st line treatment of serous and endometrioid ovarian, peritoneal and fallopian tube cancer (both chemotherapy and surgery) is considered as the primary outcome variable in this study. Along with other diagnosis examinations the analysis of frequent mutations in the gen BRCA1 (5382insC, 4154delA, 185delAG and C61G (c.300T&gt;G)) will be performed by local or regional laboratories. Those patients with BRCAm+ OC (Ovarian Cancer) will be observed prospectively during 2 years after the baseline visit or till progression at the 1st line treatment with regards to OC treatment details and outcomes. The patients for whom BRCA mutations not found will participate in the baseline assessments only and will not be followed up. Accordingly, 1 study visit (screening/baseline) is planned for all patients and 2 additional once a year visits besides screening/baseline visit are planned for BRCAm+ patients. The subpopulation of the patients with the congenital serous and endometrioid ovarian, peritoneal and fallopian tube cancer with the corresponding family history will undergo the broadened genetic testing panel (sequencing of all coding areas of genes BRCA1 and BRCA2). Information regarding patient demographics, the disease characteristics, management approaches, diagnostic tests performed and medication received by the patient will be taken from the medical records.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. The voluntary obtained informed consent signed by both the subject and the investigator. 2. Confirmed serous and endometrioid ovarian cancer or fallopian tube cancer or peritoneal cancer diagnosed 3 months before enrolment into the study or later 3. Patients on treatment for OC (Ovarian Cancer) or FTC (Fallopian Tube Cancer) or PC (Peritoneal Cancer) 1. The ovarian cancer histology other than serous and endometrioid. 2. Patients participating in clinical studies. 3. Any medical condition which on the opinion of the investigator may interfere the patient's participation in the trial.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>serous and endometrioid ovarian, peritoneal, fallopian tube cancer, hereditary ovarian cancer, BRCA (breast cancer gene) mutation, genetic testing</keyword>
</DOC>