<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02443155</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This trial is conducted globally. The aim of this trial is to assess the clinical proof-of-principle of NNC0114-0006 and liraglutide on preservation of beta-cell function in adult subjects with newly diagnosed type 1 diabetes mellitus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Clinical Proof-of-principle Trial in Adult Subjects With Newly Diagnosed Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus Investigating the Effect of NNC0114-0006 and Liraglutide on Preservation of Beta-cell Function</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent obtained before any trialrelated activities. Trialrelated activities are any procedures that are carried out as part of the trial, including activities to determine suitability for the trial T1DM (type 1 diabetes mellitus) (as diagnosed clinically) for not more than 12 weeks prior to Randomisation Male or female, aged 1845 (both inclusive) at the time of signing the informed consent form Nonfasting Cpeptide higher or equal to 0.2 nmol/l BMI (body mass index) higher or equal to 18.5 kg/m^2 Presence of one or more islet specific auto antibodies (glutamic acid decarboxylase (GAD), islet antigen2 (IA2) or zinctransporter 8 (ZnT8)) at screening Insulin dependence unless in temporary spontaneous remission (honeymoon period) Daily insulin usage above 1 U/kg per day at screening or use of continuous subcutaneous insulin infusion (CSII) History of recurrent (e.g. several times a year) of severe (e.g. pneumonia) or chronic infections or conditions predisposing to chronic infections (e.g., bronchiectasis and chronic osteomyelitis) History of severe systemic fungal infection within the past 12 months prior to screening unless treated and resolved with appropriate documented therapy Vaccination within 4 weeks before randomisation, Visit 3 (V3) Receipt of any other concomitant medications or herbal products that can influence the immune system within 90 days prior to screening (V1) History of pancreatitis (acute or chronic) Family or personal history of Multiple Endocrine Neoplasia Type 2 (MEN2) or Medullary Thyroid Carcinoma (MTC) Any past or current diagnosis of malignant neoplasms Known impairment of the immune system, except for T1DM</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>