<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02727361</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Dystonia is defined as a syndrome of sustained muscle contractions resulting in repetitive movements and abnormal postures. DYT1 is the most common form of genetic dystonia, but the link between genomic mutations and phenotypic expression remains largely unknown. Furthermore, secondary forms of dystonia have highlighted the role of the basal ganglia, particularly the putamen in the pathophysiology of the disease. Experimental results in a genetic model of dystonia in rodents suggest that cholinergic inter-neurons (ACh-I) of the putamen play a critical role in the pathological process of plasticity in the cortico-striatal synapse. However, these results have not been demonstrated in humans.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Role of the Striatal Cholinergic System in the Pathophysiology of Dystonia</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to demonstrate that the phenotype of dystonia is associated with the degree of striatal ACh-I alterations. In this molecular imaging study, the investigators will directly test this hypothesis using a PET radiotracer of the vesicular acetylcholine transporter (VAT). Their goal is to explore the relationships between cholinergic dysfunction and clinical disease expression and the associated morphological and functional alterations. The experimental protocol will also include multimodal MRI, MRI diffusion tensor (to study the microscopic structure of white matter) and functional MRI of the resting state (to study the functional organization of cerebral cholinergic networks at rest).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Dystonia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dystonic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholinergic Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Man or woman 18 to 75 years, with health insurance Diagnosis of dystonia DYT1 confirmed by molecular biology (TORSINE A gene mutation) Patient who stopped his anticholinergic treatment 48 hours before imaging Patients who underwent surgery for deep brain stimulation or under cholinergic treatment. Presence of a counterindication for MRI Presence of a counterindication for TEP Scan with [18F]FEOBV Woman premenopausal without effective ongoing contraception (intrauterine device or combined hormonal) Patient who underwent a PET examination in the previous month Presence of any health problem preventing travel to the imaging service of the University Hospital Being under the legal guardianship of another person or being unable to provide consent to participate Pregnant or breastfeeding woman</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dystonia</keyword>
	<keyword>Binding potential</keyword>
	<keyword>FEOBV</keyword>
</DOC>