<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02727881</DOC>
	<brief_summary>A Phase 3 Study of the Efficacy and Safety of Squalamine Lactate Ophthalmic Solution 0.2% Twice Daily in Subjects with Neovascular Age-Related Macular Degeneration. Patients will receive injections of ranibizumab. In addition, patients will receive either Squalamine lactate 0.2% eye drops or Placebo eye drops. The study duration is 2 years</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Study of Squalamine Ophthalmic Solution in Subjects With Neovascular AMD</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Phase 3 Study of the Efficacy and Safety of Squalamine Lactate Ophthalmic Solution 0.2% Twice Daily in Subjects with Neovascular Age-Related Macular Degeneration Methodology: Phase III, multicenter, randomized, double-masked, placebo-controlled study conducted in 2 periods (Year 1 and Year 2). Year 1 (Screening/Baseline to Week 52): Patients will be randomly assigned to one of 2 treatment groups in a 1:1 ratio: - Squalamine lactate ophthalmic solution, 0.2% BID (Years 1 and 2) + ranibizumab every 4 weeks (Year 1) and PRN ranibizumab (as needed, Year 2) - Placebo ophthalmic solution BID (Years 1 and 2) + monthly ranibizumab every 4 weeks (Year 1) and PRN ranibizumab (Year 2), based on optical coherence tomography (OCT)-guided re-treatment criteria</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ophthalmic Solutions</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Squalamine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age ≥ 50 years A diagnosis of choroid neovascularization (CNV) secondary to AMD with CNV comprising at least 50% of the total lesion area on fluorescein angiography (FA) Central subfield thickness (spectral domain (SD)OCT central 1 mm) of ≥ 300 μm Bestcorrected visual acuity (BCVA) 20/40 to 20/320 (73 to 24letter score on the Early Treatment of Diabetic Retinopathy Study [ETDRS] chart) Neovascularization secondary to any other condition than AMD in the study eye; Blood occupying greater than 50% of the AMD lesion, or blood &gt; 1.0 sq. mm underlying the fovea Pigment epithelial detachment (PED) without associated subretinal fluid and/or cystic retinal changes Clinical evidence of diabetic retinopathy or diabetic macular edema in the study eye Confounding ocular conditions in the study eye which will affect interpretation of OCT, VA or assessment of macular appearance (e.g., cataract, epiretinal membrane, retinal vascular occlusive disease) Fibrosis or atrophy, retinal epithelial tear in the center of the fovea in the study eye or any condition preventing VA improvement Uncontrolled glaucoma in the study eye, or currently receiving topical glaucoma medication in the study eye</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>110 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>AMD, CNV, choroidal neovascularization, retinal eye disease</keyword>
</DOC>