<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03013439</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The trial is an open-label, 4 cohorts, sequential, dose-escalating, single dose trial.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dose-escalation Trial of the Safety, Pharmacokinetics, and Pharmacodynamics of Iron Isomaltoside (Monofer®)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>IDA is highly prevalent in subjects with cancer and gastrointestinal diseases such as inflammatory bowel diseases, menstruating or pregnant women, and subjects who have undergone bariatric procedure. IDA can have a substantial medical and quality of life (QoL) burden on the subjects, and treatment of these subjects includes controlling the bleeding and replenishing lost iron.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anemia, Iron-Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hematologic Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Deficiency Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron Metabolism Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Iron</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Japanese man or woman ≥ 20 years, &lt; 65 years of age 2. Hb of ≥ 9.0 g/dL, &lt; 12.0 g/dL for women and &lt; 13.0 g/dL for men 3. Serum ferritin &lt; 25 ng/mL 4. TIBC ≥ 360 μg/dL 5. Body weight ≥ 50 kg 6. Willingness to participate and signing the informed consent form Exclusion criteria include: 1. Anemia caused by conditions other than iron deficiency 2. Cancer 3. IV or oral iron treatment, or blood transfusion 4 weeks prior to screening 4. Erythropoiesis stimulating agent (ESA) treatment prior to screening 5. Imminent expectation of blood transfusion on part of treating physician 6. Iron overload or disturbances (e.g. hemochromatosis and hemosiderosis) 7. Known hypersensitivity reaction to iv iron preparations 8. Decompensated liver cirrhosis or active hepatitis 9. Active acute or chronic infections 10. Pregnant or nursing women. 11. Planned elective surgery during the trial</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>