<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03013504</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of the study is to determine whether HD201 is effective in the treatment of HER2+ metastatic breast cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Phase III Trial to Compare HD201 in Combination With Docetaxel to Herceptin® in Combination With Docetaxel in Patients With HER2+ Metastatic Breast Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomised, double-blind, parallel group, equivalence, multicentre Phase III study. 560 patients with HER2+ metastatic breast cancer (MBC) will be randomised (1:1) to receive either HD201 in combination with docetaxel (n=280) or Herceptin® in combination with docetaxel (n=280). HD201 or Herceptin® with concomitant docetaxel will be administered every 3 weeks until the end of the 8th cycle, disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, noncompliance or withdrawal of consent by the patient, or the investigator decides to discontinue treatment, whichever comes first. Patients without disease progression after the 8th cycle can continue to receive HD201 or Herceptin® with or without docetaxel for a total of 12 months after the first treatment administration. Continued treatment with docetaxel will be at the discretion of the treating physician. Patients completing the first 12 months of treatment and those discontinuing the study will attend an End of Study visit 4 weeks after last administration of study medication. After the last administration of study medication patients will be treated according to their physician's discretion. These patients will be followed every 3 months for an additional 12 months or until death, whichever occurs first, to collect data on cardiac safety and disease status. All procedures will be performed at the investigators discretion. All patients who withdraw from the study before the end of the first 12 months of treatment will be followed up for at least 12 months or until death, whichever occurs first. Patients will attend study visits every 3 weeks (+/- 3 days). At each visit, patients will undergo a complete physical examination, vital signs, 12-lead electrocardiogram (ECG), weight, performance status, clinical laboratory tests, adverse events (AEs), concomitant medication and patient compliance. Tumor response will be evaluated at screening and every 3 treatment cycles, using the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumours (RECIST). The same imaging techniques will be used throughout the entire duration of the study. Cardiac safety will be assessed at screening and every 3 treatment cycles throughout the study using echocardiography or multi gated acquisition (MUGA) scan to evaluate the left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF). The primary efficacy endpoint, ORR, will be defined as the proportion of patients whose best overall response is either complete response (CR) or partial response (PR) according to RECIST. The best overall response is the best response recorded from the start of study treatment to the end of the 8th cycle. Sparse sampling will be performed in a subset of patients (75 per treatment group) to facilitate a population-based pharmacokinetic (PK) approach using nonlinear mixed-effects modelling. An Independent Data Monitoring Committee will act in an advisory capacity to monitor patient safety and efficacy and PK data from the trial. The members will be selected on the basis of relevant experience and understanding of clinical research and the issues specific to the therapeutic area, as well as previous data monitoring committee experience.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Trastuzumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>• Signed written informed consent Females &gt; 18 years of age Cytologically or histologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the breast that is now metastatic or locally recurrent and inoperable with curative intent HER2 overexpression as assessed by: 1. Immunohistochemistry (IHC; HercepTest from Dako Corp, Carpinteria, CA) or 2. Fluorescent in situ hybridisation (FISH; PathVysion assay kit; Vysis Inc, Downers Grove, IL) 3. Patients with IHC score 3+ or positive FISH test 4. Patients with an IHC score 2+, must also have a positive FISH World Health Organization performance status &lt; 2 Patient must have at least one measurable disease according to the RECIST criteria 1.1 Life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks Adequate bone marrow, hepatic and renal functions as evidenced by the following: 1. Absolute neutrophils count &gt; 1,500/μL 2. Haemoglobin &gt; 9 g/dL 3. Platelet count &gt; 100,000/μL 4. Creatinine clearance &gt; 60 mL/min 5. Total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) 6. Aspartate aminotransferase (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase) and/or alanine aminotransferase (serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase) &lt; 2.5 x ULN, or &lt; 5 x ULN if liver metastasis, 7. Alkaline phosphatases &lt; 5 x ULN LVEF &gt; 50% or within the normal level of the institution, as assessed by echocardiography or MUGA scan Able to comply with the study protocol Female patients of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test within 14 days of first dose of study treatment and agree to use effective contraception (hormonal contraceptive, intrauterine device, diaphragm with spermicide or condom with spermicide) throughout the study period and 30 days after discontinuation of study drug Participation in any clinical study or having taken any investigational therapy during the 2 month period immediately preceding administration of the first study dose Patients who have received prior chemotherapy including taxanes or any prior anti HER therapy for their metastatic disease. Patients could have received prior (neo) adjuvant chemotherapy and HER2 targeted treatment. Taxanes and/or Herceptin® received &gt; 12 months as (neo) adjuvant therapy are allowed. Hormonal therapy is allowed for early or metastatic disease but should be stopped 4 weeks before the first study dose Surgery or radiotherapy during the 4 weeks immediately preceding administration of the first study dose, unless the indicator lesions are outside the irradiated fields and patients have fully recovered from surgery or radiotherapy Clinical or radiographic evidence of presence of brain or leptomeningeal metastases Current peripheral neuropathy &gt; National Cancer Institute Common Toxicity Criteria (CTC) grade 2 Patients with one or more of the following conditions: 1. Cardiac insufficiency (New York Heart Association III or IV), myocardial infarction within the previous 6 months, unstable angina pectoris, uncontrolled arrhythmia at time of inclusion 2. Clinically significant active infection 3. Poorly controlled diabetes mellitus 4. Uncontrolled hypertension History of malignancy within the last 5 years, except adequately excised squamous or basal cell carcinoma of the skin History or presence of a medical condition or disease that in the investigator's opinion would place the patient at an unacceptable risk for study participation Lactating or pregnant female</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>randomized</keyword>
	<keyword>double-blind</keyword>
	<keyword>parallel group</keyword>
	<keyword>equivalence</keyword>
	<keyword>multicentre</keyword>
	<keyword>phase III</keyword>
	<keyword>efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>safety</keyword>
	<keyword>pharmacokinetics</keyword>
	<keyword>HD201</keyword>
	<keyword>docetaxel</keyword>
	<keyword>Herceptin</keyword>
	<keyword>HER2 positive</keyword>
	<keyword>metastatic breast cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
</DOC>