<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01331057</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary purpose is the validation of an instrument of the first language assessment. The second purpose is to study the impact of familial and transcultural factors on early bilingualism in migrant children born in France.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Bilingualism: Validation Of "Avicenne's Elal"</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The research aims to validate a language instrument of the first language in migrants' children born in France. For that purpose, the investigators have built an instrument made of three sets of items: comprehension, production and narrative production. Children are elected if: they are four to six years old, in the third class of nursery school and if their first language is unique, and, one of the three languages that the investigators define for the first step of validation: tamil, SONINKE, Arabic. The PROTOCOLE is composed with two parts: 1. For children: - An assessment for children in French with items extracted from the NEEL test - An assessment of mother tongue with the ELAL of Avicenne 2. For parents: - A semi-structured interview. The data collected are: General DATA: - Social and professional categories - Economical status of parents - The conditions of living - Month and year of birth for the child - The language used during the interview About the child: - Age of language AQUISITION - Languages mastering - Language environment - The place among siblings - SCOLARISATION(DATA about cultural affiliations, representations of transmission, intra-familial relationship DATA about parental uses and representations of languages: - Social and economical DATA in the country of birth - Place of birth, languages - uses of languages - representations about languages</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Age : four to six years old SCOLARISATION : nursery school One language in the family house: tamil, Arabic, or SONINKE first class of elementary school two mother tongues in the family</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bilingualism</keyword>
	<keyword>Language</keyword>
	<keyword>Evaluation transcultural</keyword>
	<keyword>Intra Familial Relationship</keyword>
	<keyword>Transmissions mother</keyword>
	<keyword>Tongue french</keyword>
	<keyword>Language tamil</keyword>
	<keyword>Language arabic</keyword>
	<keyword>Language soninke</keyword>
	<keyword>Language cultural</keyword>
	<keyword>Affiliations crossbreeding</keyword>
</DOC>