<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01331200</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to study the safety and feasibility of mobilization of acute ischemic stroke patients treated with IV-tPA between 12-24 hours of treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Early Mobilization of Ischemic Stroke Patients Within 24-hours After Intravenous-Tissue Plasminogen Activator (IV-tPA)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Abstract: Introduction Historical precedence exists demonstrating that early intensive care unit (ICU) mobilization of patients reduces risks of complication and lengths of hospital stay, and may improve long-term health status of patients. Objective To determine the safety of early mobilization by physical and/or occupational therapy in acute ischemic stroke patients within 24-hours of IV-tPA infusion and to examine if early mobilization leads to shortened ICU and hospital length of stay. Methods Prospective study of incidence of adverse response and functional mobility status of study patients mobilized by occupational and/or physical therapy between 12- 24 hours after IV-tPA infusion with comparison of ICU and hospital Length of Stay data between study group and pre-study patients who were mobilized by occupational and/or physical therapy services at no pre-determined time after IV-tPA infusion. Additionally, patients will be contacted by study personnel approximately 3 to 5-days and 30-days post-infusion for completion of Modified Rankin Scale stroke disability survey as follow up of stroke recovery. Setting Medical and surgical intensive care units at Mayo Clinic Florida. Patients All patients with acute ischemic stroke who receive intravenous tissue plasminogen activator (IV-tPA) infusion, survive to discharge from the hospital, are hemodynamically stable, and are mobilized by physical and/or occupational therapy within 24 hours post-tPA infusion.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cerebral Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Plasminogen</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tissue Plasminogen Activator</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients post acute ischemic stroke that have been treated with intravenous tissue plasminogen activator (IVtPA) 13 hours have elapsed since initiation of intravenous TPA infusion Patients are hemodynamically stable (e.g., not on vasopressors or antihypertensive drips or requiring multiple IV PRN boluses of either medication) Patient is able to actively engage in the evaluation Patients with femoral sheaths or recent removal of femoral sheaths Patients who are hemodynamically unstable, with active bleeding from lines, catheters, INT site or wounds or angioedema Electrocardiogram showing (HR&gt;100) Vital signs (HR &gt; 100, SBP &lt;90 or &gt;180, DBP &lt;70 or &gt; 105) Patients experiencing marked diaphoresis, facial pallor, intense anxious or painful facial expression (especially in aphasic patients)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>ischemic stroke</keyword>
	<keyword>tissue plasminogen activator</keyword>
	<keyword>early mobilization</keyword>
	<keyword>patient safety</keyword>
	<keyword>length of stay</keyword>
</DOC>