<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="70553">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02187302</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CRLX101-208</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02187302</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CRLX101 in Combination With Bevacizumab for Metastatic Renal Cell Carcinoma (mRCC) Versus Standard of Care (SOC)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Phase 2 Study to Assess the Safety and Efficacy of CRLX101 in Combination With Bevacizumab in Patients With Metastatic Renal Cell Carcinoma (RCC) Versus Standard of Care (SOC) (Investigator's Choice)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cerulean Pharma Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cerulean Pharma Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study to evaluate treatment in patients with metastatic renal cell carcinoma (RCC)
      which has progressed through 2 to 3 prior lines of therapy, with the investigational drug
      CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab compared to treatment with a standard of care
      therapy. The study will compare which treatment resulted in longer time before progression
      of the RCC. Patients will be treated and followed for progression of their disease on
      average for up to 6 months.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Open-label, randomized, controlled study in patients with metastatic RCC (mRCC) who have
      completed 2 or 3 prior conventional molecularly targeted therapy regimens (i.e. lines)
      including ≥ 1 VEGF-inhibiting therapies.

      A total of 110 patients with 55 per treatment arm will be recruited from up to 40 clinical
      sites.

      Subjects will be randomized to either CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab (CRLX101 15
      mg/m^2 IV on days 1 and 15 of a 28-day cycle; in combination with bevacizumab 10 mg/kg IV on
      days 1 and 15 of 28-day cycle) or standard of care (SOC).

      Options for SOC treatment include the following agents to which the patient can have no
      prior exposure: sorafenib; everolimus; pazopanib; axitinib; bevacizumab; sunitinib, or other
      approved drug considered by the Medical Monitor to represent an acceptable standard of care
      therapy.

      Measurable disease will be assessed every 8 weeks (i.e. every 2 cycles). Study treatment,
      for both investigational and reference therapy, will continue until confirmed disease
      progression. Duration of study treatment on average is expected to be up to 6 months.

      Other reasons for discontinuation of treatment may include Investigator determination of
      clinical progression without CT-Scan confirmation, patient withdrawal, unresolved adverse
      event, unacceptable toxicity, Investigator decision in consultation with the patient, death,
      Sponsor determination due to protocol violation, or Sponsor decision to close the study.

      Cross-over treatment will not be permitted on-study for either assigned treatment arm.

      Bevacizumab has been chosen as a combination partner with CRLX101 for a number of reasons.

        -  Bevacizumab has proven activity in the treatment of patients with renal cell carcinoma.

        -  Bevacizumab has been successfully combined with many chemotherapy partners including
           the topoisomerase-1 inhibitor irinotecan.

        -  It has been hypothesized that the combination of bevacizumab with CRLX101 may have
           unique clinical activity in combination in the treatment of this disease due to the
           simultaneous inhibition of distinct steps along the ~vHL ┐ HIF → (CAIX) → VEGF → VEGFR2
           pathway

      Primary Objective:

      To assess progression free survival (PFS) in patients with metastatic renal cell carcinoma
      (mRCC) treated with CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab (CRLX101+bevacizumab) vs.
      standard of care (SOC) per investigator's choice. This primary endpoint will be evaluated
      according to Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1.

      Secondary Objectives

        -  To assess overall safety and tolerability of CRLX101+ bevacizumab compared to SOC.

        -  To assess overall survival (OS) of CRLX101+bevacizumab compared to SOC.

        -  To assess overall response rate (ORR) of CRLX101+bevacizumab compared to SOC.

        -  To assess overall PFS, OS, and ORR among patients with clear cell RCC treated with
           CRLX101+bevacizumab compared to SOC.

        -  To assess overall PFS, OS, and ORR among patients with non-clear cell RCC treated with
           CRLX101+bevacizumab compared to SOC.

        -  To describe the pharmacokinetics (PK) of CRLX101 when administered in combination with
           bevacizumab.

      Exploratory Objectives

        -  To analyze tumor tissue samples for biomarkers of efficacy in the CRLX101+bevacizumab
           treatment group.

        -  To analyze plasma samples for biomarkers of efficacy before and during treatment and
           correlate with efficacy outcomes for CRLX101+bevacizumab compared to SOC treatment
           groups.

        -  To evaluate the pharmacokinetics (PK) of CRLX101 in urine over time when administered
           in combination with bevacizumab in patients with and without non-infective cystitis.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Open Label</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>at least 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>This primary endpoint will compare investigational treatment of CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab compared to the standard of care (SOC) treatment and will be evaluated according to Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of serious and non-serious adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>at least 30 days post last dose of study drug</time_frame>
    <description>compare adverse event rates and severity for CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab treatment group versus SOC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>on average 12 months after discontinuation of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>compare time to death between treatment groups of CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab compared to SOC.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>at least 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate response rate per RECIST version 1.1 comparing the investigational treatment of CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab compared to SOC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic measures of CRLX101 in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>on days 1 (pre-infusion, end of infusion, 1,2,4 and 6 hrs post infusion), 2, 3, 8 and 15 of cycle 1 (month 1) and repeat in cycle 3 (month 3)</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples for plasma will be collected from a subset of up to 20 consenting patients randomized to the CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab treatment arm, in Cycle 1 and Cycle 3. The plasma samples will be analyzed for concentration levels of conjugated and unconjugated 20(S)-Camptothecin CPT levels at the collected time points.
ALL patients enrolled in the CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab treatment arm are required to collect urine samples for PK analyses at every infusion visit.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Tumor biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>prestudy and one collection within 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Collect pre-study tumor tissue samples from consenting patients to explore potential biomarkers of efficacy in the CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab treatment group. Tissue for retrospective correlative assessment including but not limited to analysis of tumor tissue using immunohistochemistry and quantitative polymerase chain reaction (PCR) to measure topoisomerase-1 and its phosphorylation status, vHL status, expression of hypoxia-inducible factor 1alpha (HIF-1alpha) and HIF-2alpha, and expression of genes and proteins that are downstream of HIF-1alpha or HIF-2alpha.
If available, compare above with post-treatment tumor tissue for in patients with available tumor tissue collected.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma biomarkers compare pre treatment and post study drug infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>on day 1 prior to start of study drug, and day 3 post infusion</time_frame>
    <description>Collect plasma samples from consenting patients to explore potential biomarkers of efficacy in the CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab treatment group compared to the SOC. Plasma will be analyzed for a panel of protein levels using a multiplexed immunoassay, before and after treatment, to determine whether a plasma-based surrogate marker can be developed to measure CRLX101 activity. The protein panel includes proteins that have been associated with HIF-1alpha, including angiogenic factors, markers of vascular activation and inflammation and matrix-derived factors.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic measure of CRLX101 in urine</measure>
    <time_frame>on day 1 and day 15 of each 28-day cycle (month) prior to start of study drug infusion and at 2 to 6 hours post study drug infusion, on average for 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Urine samples will be collected from all patients randomized to the investigational treatment with CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab at every infusion visit to assess pharmacokinetic measures in urine over time.
The urine samples will be evaluation for camptothecin concentrations to:
describe the PK of CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab compared to the phase 1/2a study evaluating the PK of CRLX101 monotherapy, and
evaluate urine camptothecin concentrations among patients reporting cystitis symptoms compared to patients without cystitis symptoms in this study.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Renal Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CRLX101 + bevacizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>CRLX101 in combination with bevacizumab:
CRLX101 15 mg/m^2 IV on days 1 and 15 of a 28-day cycle;
bevacizumab 10 mg/kg IV on days 1 and 15 of a 28-day cycle.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of care treatment include one of the following agents to which the patient can have no prior exposure: sorafenib; everolimus; pazopanib; axitinib; bevacizumab; sunitinib, or other approved drug considered by the Medical Monitor to represent an acceptable standard of care therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CRLX101 + bevacizumab</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>CRLX101 + bevacizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>sorafenib / everolimus / pazopanib / axitinib / bevacizumab / sunitinib / other approved drug</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>sorafenib (Nexavar), sunitinib (Sutent), axitinib (Inlyta), pazopanib (Votrient), bevacizumab (Avastin),</other_name>
    <other_name>everolimus (Afinitor)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Must have histologically confirmed renal cell carcinoma of any pathologic subtype.

          -  Must have unresectable metastatic disease, and have tumor(s) present that is (are)
             evaluable by the RECIST, v1.1; may have spinal-associated metastases but must have
             concluded dexamethasone therapy and be evaluated by the Investigator to have stable
             CNS disease.

          -  Must have received 2 or 3 prior lines of conventional molecularly targeted therapy

          -  Must have full recovery from any toxicities from prior therapy CTCAE Grade 1 or less
             with the exception of Grade 2 alopecia) prior to randomization.

          -  ECOG performance status 0 or 1.

          -  Age 18 years and older.

          -  Life expectancy of at least 3 months.

          -  Must have normal organ and marrow function reported within 14 days prior to
             randomization

          -  Ability to understand and willingness to sign a written informed consent document.

          -  Able to comply with study visit schedule and assessments.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Any conventional molecularly targeted therapy within 2 weeks or, chemotherapy or
             radiotherapy within 2 weeks (local) or 4 weeks (systemic) prior to entering the
             study.

          -  Failure to recover to grade 1 or less all prior adverse events.

          -  Any major surgery within 4 weeks of study randomization.

          -  Any prior treatment with topoisomerase I therapy.

          -  Prior treatment with any drugs or therapies that will be administered during the
             course of this trial including CRLX101, any topoisomerase 1 inhibitor, bevacizumab or
             the conventional molecularly targeted agent intended for use as standard of care
             treatment.

          -  Patients receiving any other current investigational therapeutic agent.

          -  Other active malignancies

          -  Patients with brain metastasis treated or untreated, or other CNS disease

          -  Any clinically significant cardiac disease defined as NYHA class III or IV.

          -  Uncontrolled hypertension

          -  Uncontrolled concurrent illness

          -  History of non-healing wounds or ulcers.

          -  Pregnancy, or inadequate contraception for men or women of childbearing age, or
             lactating / breast-feeding

          -  Patients with known HIV or with solid organ transplant
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Silvia Helou, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Cerulean Pharma Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>La Jolla</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92093</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>David Geffen School of Medicine UCLA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90024</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cedars Sinai Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90048</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rocky Mountain Cancer Centers</name>
      <address>
        <city>Denver</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80218</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kaiser Permanente</name>
      <address>
        <city>Honolulu</city>
        <state>Hawaii</state>
        <zip>96819</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Decatur Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Decatur</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>62526</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Indiana University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Franciscan St. Francis Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46237</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>June E. Nylen Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sioux City</city>
        <state>Iowa</state>
        <zip>51101</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Kansas Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fairway</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cancer Center of Kansas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wichita</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>67214</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Our Lady of the Lake Physician Group</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baton Rouge</city>
        <state>Louisiana</state>
        <zip>70808</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Maryland, Greenebaum Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ann Arbor Hematoloty-Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Karmanos Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>North Mississippi Hematology and Oncology Associates</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tupelo</city>
        <state>Mississippi</state>
        <zip>38801</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Nebraska Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Omaha</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68130</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Comprehensive Cancer Centers of Nevada</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Vegas</city>
        <state>Nevada</state>
        <zip>89169</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MD Anderson Cooper Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Voorhees</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>08043</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New York Oncology Hematology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Albany</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>12208</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SUNY Upstate Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Syracuse</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>13210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UNC Chapel Hill</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27599</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh Medical Center Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cancer Centers of the Carolinas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Greenville</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29615</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Oncology, Amarillo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amarillo</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>79106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Oncology P.A.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78745</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Oncology, Dallas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75246</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Oncology, El Paso</name>
      <address>
        <city>El Paso</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>79902</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Oncology, Flower Mound</name>
      <address>
        <city>Flower Mound</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75028</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Oncology, Fort Worth</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Worth</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>76104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Oncology, P.A.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77024</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cancer Center Network of South Texas</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78217</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Utah Cancer Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CAMC Health Education and Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>West Virginia</state>
        <zip>25304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Vincent Regional Cancer Center CCOP</name>
      <address>
        <city>Green Bay</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>54301</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Goyang-si Gyeonggi-do</city>
        <zip>410-769</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seoul National University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>110-744</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Severence Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>120-752</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Samsung Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>135-710</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Asan Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>138-736</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 5, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>June 30, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>nanopharmaceutical,</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sunitinib</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Axitinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
