<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02584283</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Rationale: Recent publications report good results of controlled donation after circulatory death (DCD) Maastricht category III liver transplantation when strict donor-recipient matching is applied and ischemia times are kept to a minimum. However a major concern remains the high rate of biliary complications after transplantation of DCD livers. Non-anastomotic biliary strictures (NAS) occur in 29% of patients receiving a DCD graft whereas the incidence of NAS in recipients of donation after brain death (DBD) liver grafts is 11%. NAS are associated with higher morbidity and increased cost of liver transplantation. Injury to the biliary epithelium and the peribiliary vascular plexus occurring during donor warm ischemia and static cold storage (SCS) has been identified as a major risk factor for development of NAS. Machine perfusion has been proposed as an alternative strategy for organ preservation, offering the opportunity to improve the quality of the organ by providing oxygen to the graft. Experimental studies have shown that end-ischemic dual hypothermic oxygenated machine perfusion (DHOPE) helps liver grafts to recover from ischemia by restoring mitochondrial function. Moreover, DHOPE has been shown to provide better preservation of peribiliary vascular plexus of the bile ducts, which could be an important step forward in reducing the incidence of NAS after transplantation. Objective: To study the efficacy of end-ischemic DHOPE in reducing the incidence of NAS within six months after controlled DCD (Maastricht category III) liver transplantation. Study design: An international, multicenter, prospective, randomized, controlled, interventional, clinical trial with a two parallel arm approach (treatment/control). Study population: Adult patients (≥18 yrs old) undergoing a liver transplantation with a liver graft procured from a controlled DCD donor (Maastricht category III) with a body weight ≥40 kg. Intervention: In the intervention group liver grafts will be subjected to two hours of hypothermic, oxygenated perfusion at the end of SCS and before implantation. In the control group donor liver grafts will be preserved in accordance to standard practice by SCS only. Main study parameters/endpoints: The incidence and severity of symptomatic NAS as diagnosed by an Adjudication committee (who are blinded for the group assignment) by means of magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography (MRCP).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Dual Hypothermic Oxygenated Perfusion of DCD Liver Grafts in Preventing Biliary Complications After Transplantation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>End Stage Liver Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hypothermia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Biliary Tract Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Extracts</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Adult patients (≥ 18 years old) Signed informed consent Willing and able to attend followup examinations Donor liver graft from a controlled donation after circulatory death (Maastricht category III) Donors with a body weight ≥40 kg Simultaneous participation in another clinical trial that might possibly influence this trial Mental conditions rendering the subject incapable to understand the nature, scope and consequences of the trial Listed for liver transplantation due to fulminant liver failure or retransplantation because of primary nonfunction Recipient positive test for HIV Donor positive for HIV, Hepatitis B or C Simultaneous transplantation of another organ Patients with contraindications for MRCP (i.e. pacemaker)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Liver Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Donation after Circulatory Death</keyword>
	<keyword>Machine Perfusion</keyword>
</DOC>