<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02584504</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Primary Objective: To demonstrate the reduction of low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) by alirocumab administration as add-on therapy to non-statin lipid modifying therapy (LMT) including diet therapy alone or the lowest strength of statin in comparison with placebo after 12 weeks of treatment in patients with hypercholesterolemia. Secondary Objective: - To evaluate the effect of two treatment regimens of alirocumab on other lipid parameters: apolipoprotein B (Apo-B), non-high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (non HDL-C), total cholesterol (TC), lipoprotein (a) [Lp(a)], high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C), triglyceride (TG), and apolipoprotein A-1 (Apo A-1). - To evaluate the safety and tolerability of alirocumab administration. - To evaluate the development of anti-alirocumab antibodies. - To evaluate the pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic profiles of alirocumab administration. - To evaluate the long-term safety in patients receiving open-label alirocumab administration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Alirocumab in Patients With Hypercholesterolemia Not Adequately Controlled With Non-statin Lipid Modifying Therapy or the Lowest Strength of Statin</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The duration of study per patient is approximately 79 weeks consisting of a run-in period (4 weeks), a screening period (3 weeks), a double-blind treatment period (12 weeks), an open-label treatment period (52 weeks), and a follow-up period (8 weeks).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypercholesterolemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atorvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ezetimibe</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fenofibrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bezafibrate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Patients with hypercholesterolemia (heterozygous familial hypercholesterolemia [heFH] or nonfamilial hypercholesterolemia [nonFH]) receiving non statin LMTs or the lowest strength of statin. Exclusion criteria: LDLC &lt;100 mg/dL (&lt;2.59 mmol/L) at the screening visit (Week 3) in patients with heFH or in patients with nonFH who have a history of documented coronary heart disease. LDLC &lt;120 mg/dL (&lt;3.10 mmol/L) at the screening visit (Week 3) in patients with nonFH patients who have a history of documented diseases or other risk factors classified as primary prevention category III. Not on a stable dose of LMTs (including diet therapy alone) in the runin period or the screening period. Fasting serum TG &gt;400 mg/dL (&gt;4.52 mmol/L) at the screening period. Systolic blood pressure (BP) &gt;160 mmHg or diastolic BP &gt;100 mmHg at the runin visit (Week 7) or the screening visit (Week 3) or the randomization visit (Week 0). The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's potential participation in a clinical trial.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>