<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01195116</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the effects of dexmedetomidine while patients undergo treatment for Interstitial Cystitis (IC). The investigators goal is to demonstrate in patients with IC undergoing bladder hydrodistension that the use of dexmedetomidine as a supplemental anesthetic agent will result in better postoperative pain management.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Usefulness of Dexmedetomidine on Post-operative Pain Management in Patients With Interstitial Cystitis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Inclusion Criteria: Patients with a clinical diagnosis of IC scheduled for cystoscopy and hydrodistension for both diagnostic and therapeutic indications. Data collected will include: I. Postoperative Outcomes i. Pain Reported (Visual Analogue Scale) ii. Post-operative opiate use iii. Time in PACU iv. Time until discharge v. Adverse Events (i.e. nausea/vomiting, nursing intervention) II. Intermediate-term Outcomes (4-6 weeks) i. Interstitial Cystitis Symptom &amp; Problem Index ii. Revised McGill Pain Score</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cystitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystitis, Interstitial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with a clinical diagnosis of IC scheduled for cystoscopy and hydrodistension for both diagnostic and therapeutic indications. 2. Gender of Patients: Male &amp; female,Age of Patients: 18 and older Conduction disturbance (second degree AV block or greater), or previous reaction to medications used in this study. Patients receiving spinal anesthesia will not be included.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Post-operative pain management</keyword>
	<keyword>Pain Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Painful bladder syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>frequency and urgency</keyword>
	<keyword>Dexmedetomidine</keyword>
	<keyword>hydrodistension</keyword>
</DOC>