<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01195389</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if low level magnetic fields can help to improve memory in patients diagnosed with Alzheimer's dementia.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of Magnetic Fields to Treat Alzheimer's Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this pilot study is to determine whether application of magnetic fields generated by the Resonator result in statistically significant improvements in cognitive functioning and memory in patients with a diagnosis of Alzheimer's dementia.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Current diagnosis of Alzheimer's Disease appropriately documented by the patients physician and/or neurologist Documentation verifying that other generally recognized causes of dementia have been ruled out by prior physician evaluations Mild to Moderate Dementia, as evidenced by a score of not less than 12 nor greater than 26 on the Mini Mental Status Exam (MMSE). Subject is ambulatory. A Study Partner who can attend all study visits with the subject. Study Partner being defined as an adult who has at least 10 hours/week of contact with the subject, and can accompany the subject to all testing and treatment study visits. Stable "antidementia" medication regimen without significant side effects for at least 3 months, and on stable medication (unrelated to antidementia) without significant side effects for at least 1 month; willingness and ability to maintain the stable medication regimen throughout the course of the study. Willingness and ability to present to the testing center for all study evaluations Willingness and ability to present to the treatment center for all study treatments (exposure to the Resonator™) Willingness to maintain stable diet and activity regimen for the duration of the study. Willing and able to abstain from partaking in any nonessential (not physician ordered) existing or new treatments to improve cognition and mental functioning Willing and able to abstain from any medications that could affect cognition and mental functioning during the course of the study Male or female. Any ethnic background. Age 55 and older. Change in antidementia medical regimen within 3 months prior to initiation of study. Confirmed diagnosis other nonAlzheimer's type of dementia Significant neurologic or psychiatric illness other than Alzheimer's disease Unstable cardiac disease, such as any history of cardiac arrhythmias (including atrial fibrillation, ventricular fibrillation, or irregular atrialventricular conduction time), or any incidences of congestive heart failure, or myocardial infarction, within the last six months. Previous surgical interventions involving prosthetics or implants comprised of ferrous metals, or pacemakers, vagus nerve stimulators, or other functional electrical stimulators such as those commonly used for pain. Reported consumption of more than 14 alcoholic drinks per week. Uncontrolled hypertension. Uncontrolled atrial fibrillation or other uncontrolled arrhythmias, e.g. tachycardia, bradycardia. Uncontrolled seizure disorder. History of seizures or usage of antiseizure medications that, in the opinion of the investigator, participation in this trial would represent a risk to the subject. Uncontrolled, unstable, or untreated medical conditions which may significantly impact the subject's health or ability to complete the entire study, in the opinion of the investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>dementia</keyword>
	<keyword>memory loss</keyword>
	<keyword>cognitive decline</keyword>
</DOC>