<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01332942</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The drug that is under investigation during this study is BAY85-3934 which is intended to be used as a treatment for patients suffering from renal anemia due to chronic kidney disease (stage 3 and 4). The purpose of this study is to provide safety and tolerability information on the drug. Other objectives of the study are to investigate the effect of the drug on the body (pharmacodynamics) as well as the absorption, breakdown, metabolism, distribution and excretion (pharmacokinetics) by measuring the concentration in blood and urine. The study will be conducted in one study center in the United Kingdom and several centers in Germany. 84 (of which 36 are optional) patients who meet the inclusion criteria will participate in the study. BAY 85-3934 will be given following a combined single / multiple dose escalation design in seven (of which three are optional) dose steps.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Combined Single / Multiple Dose Escalation Study in Patients With Renal Anemia Due to CKD (Chronic Kidney Disease)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The informed consent must be signed before any study specific tests or procedures are done Renal anemia due to CKD (stage 3 and 4) not on dialysis assessed by medical history and Creatine Clearance (CLCR) between 15 to 59 mL/min ± 10 % (ie CLCR between 13 65 mL/min) estimated at the prestudy visit from the creatinine concentration measured in serum (Modification of Diet in Renal Disease (MDRD) formula) Stable renal disease, ie without major changes in therapy within the last 6 weeks and not expected to begin dialysis within the study. Female subjects with no childbearing potential (postmenopausal women with 12 month of spontaneous amenorrhea or with 6 month of spontaneous amenorrhea and serum FSH levels &gt; 30 mIU/mL, women with 6 weeks post bilateral ovariectomy, woman with bilateral tubal ligation, and women with hysterectomy). Male subjects who agree to use two forms of effective contraception during the study and for 12 weeks after receiving the study drug. This must include a condom with spermicide gel for 21 days after drug administration. Male subjects who agree not to act as sperm donors for 12 weeks after dosing. Age: ≥ 18 and ≤ 85 years at the prestudy visit Body mass index (BMI): ≥ 18 and ≤ 35 kg / m2 at the prestudy visit Hemoglobin (Hb) of 8.0 12 g/dL (male) or 8.0 11.5 g/dL (female) at two consecutive measurements (1 measurement performed within 12 weeks to 2 days before the prestudy visit during routine diagnostics independently of the study and 1 measurement at the prestudy visit) Ability to understand and follow studyrelated instructions Incompletely cured preexisting diseases for which it can be assumed that the absorption, distribution, metabolism, elimination and effects of the study drugs will not be normal Known hypersensitivity to the study drugs (active substances or excipients of the preparations) Known severe allergies, nonallergic drug reactions, or multiple drug allergies Patients with impaired liver function (Child Pugh B and C based on medical history) Patients with hemolysis/hemolytic anemia or active bleeding/blood loss Major surgery or an intervention causing relevant blood loss or inflammation within the last 2 month Planned intervention or surgery during the study which might impact the study objectives. Febrile illness within 1 week before the first study drug administration or clinically significant infection. Patients with chronic inflammatory diseases (eg systemic lupus erythematosis, rheumatoid arthritis, Crohn´s disease) that could impact erythropoiesis or with persistent inflammatory activity (eg Creactive protein (CRP) &gt; 20mg/L) History of thrombotic or thromboembolic events (e.g. myocardial infarction, stroke, transient ischemic attack, deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism) within the recent 6 months Proliferative choroidal or retinal disease, such as neovascular agerelated macular degeneration or proliferative diabetic retinopathy that required or is likely to require treatment (intraocular injections or laser photocoagulation) during the study. History of myelodysplastic syndrome, multiple myeloma, bone marrow fibrosis, or pure red cell aplasia. History of hemosiderosis or hemochromatosis. Patients with a history of malignant disease during the last 5 years Treatment with erythropoiesis stimulating agents (ESA) within the last 4 weeks before first intake of study drug Intravenous iron substitution 2 weeks before and during the treatment period with BAY 853934 RBC transfusion during previous 8 weeks Use of products containing carnitine and/or anabolics Use of medicines or substances which oppose the study objectives or which might influence them within 14 days before the first study drug administration Significant uncorrected rhythm or conduction disturbances such as a second or thirddegree AV block without a cardiac pacemaker or episodes of sustained ventricular tachycardia Systolic blood pressure below 100 or above 160 mmHg at the prestudy visit Diastolic blood pressure below 50 or above 100 mmHg at the prestudy visit Positive results for hepatitis B virus surface antigen (HBsAg), hepatitis C virus antibodies (antiHCV), human immune deficiency virus antibodies (antiHIV 1+2) at the prestudy visit Heart rate above 110 bpm Ferritin levels ≤ 30 ng/mL at the prestudy visit Transferrinsaturation &lt; 15% at the prestudy visit</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Anemia</keyword>
</DOC>