<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02956304</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is determine the involvement of motor system in the memory of manipulable objects. The idea is to stimulate the ventral premotor cortex with transcranial magnetic stimulation to see whether this stimulation will affect memory of manipulable objects.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>" Effect of Affordance of Objects on the Memory: Study in Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation "</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Embodied cognition claims that representations shares processing resources with sensorimotor systems. More specifically, it has been proposed that language comprehension relies on internal simulation of the meaning. For instance, numerous studies have shown that the processing of action-related concepts involve a motor activation similar to when the action is actually performed. However, even if those studies show clearly that action-related concepts involve a motor activation, such activations may be incidental to the activation of their representations, rather than part of it. Another way to show that this motor component takes part in the representation of manipulable objetcs is to investigate whether an impairment of motor system would impair the memory of manipulable object. In this study, investigators will use Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS) to stimulate ventral premotor cortex (PMv) to see whether this stimulation will affect memory of manipulable objects, but not memory of nonmanipulable objects. For this purpose, three TMS conditions will be assessed: cTBS to inhibit the motor cortex, iTBS to excite the motor cortex, and a SHAM condition as control.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>18 and 35 years Righthanders (score between 70 and 100 on the scale of Edinburgh) Native language : French Not depressed (score lower than 14 in the BDI) health insurance Consent Psychiatric family history up to the second degree Medical treatment, in particular psychotropic being able to affect the memory and the attention view or hearing disorders (not compensated) neurological histories (epilepsy, alcoholism in particular) or psychiatric or important memory complaints Contraindications for the SMT contraindications in the MRI</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>