<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02956915</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Transcatheter aortic valve implantation (TAVI) has been rapidly adopted worldwide since the first-in-man TAVI performed in 2002. With increasing experience and improvements in valve design, the "minimalist" approach to transfemoral TAVI (using local anesthesia and fluoroscopic guidance) has become an attractive concept, and the technical feasibility of this approach has been well documented. While earlier data showed prolonged length of stay after TF-TAVI [10.5 ± 8.1 days in the FRANCE 2 registry and 10.2 ± 11.1 days in the PARTNER Cohort A data, the UK TAVI registry (reference) showed a decline in post-TAVI length of stay from 10 days to 8 days over the time period of 2007 to 2012. More contemporary data from other centers has been published showing that 23% of TF-TAVI patients were discharged within 3 days after TAVI. With an increasingly minimalist approach to TF-TAVI, the duration of monitoring required post-procedure remains indeterminate with a lack of formal consensus. Early discharge (within 3 days of TAVI) is hypothesized to have multiple potential advantages, including reduction in unnecessarily lengthy hospitalization of frail and elderly patients in addition to cost-saving benefits. Rouen University Hospital has previously published a retrospective study on the feasibility and safety of early discharge, in which discharge within 72 hours of uncomplicated TF-TAVI was safe and attained in 36% of our patients. Pre-existing pacemaker and the absence of acute kidney injury were independent predictors of a successful early discharge.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Feasibility and Safety of a Strategy of Early Discharge After TF-TAVI</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Aortic Valve Stenosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Stable patients with severe symptomatic aortic stenosis Patient undergoing planned TFTAVI with the SAPIEN3 prosthesis, TFTAVI using a minimalist approach of local anesthesia and conscious sedation The use of other (than Edwards SAPIEN3 or XT) transcatheter aortic valve devices. TFTAVI requiring general anesthesia or surgical cutdown. TFTAVI performed in unstable patients or on an urgent/emergent basis. Nontransfemoral routes of valve delivery (eg. transapical, transaortic, etc). Discharge back home impossible (including transfer in another hospital)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Transcatheter aortic valve implantation</keyword>
</DOC>