<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02220569</DOC>
	<brief_summary>PULSE-ECCho will focus on trying to detect cardiotoxicity in cancer patients receiving chemotherapy early on in order to avoid irreversible damage. In addition to that, we will test if the PhysioFlow is non-inferior to the conventional MUGA scan.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>PhysioFlow to Detect Cardiotoxicity in Chemo</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Our objective is to compare the PhysioFlow to the MUGA scan and see if the results are statistically the same using both techniques. This is what is known as a non-inferior study. The advantage of PhysioFlow is that it is non-invasive, fast and it is done at the bedside or while the patient is receiving his or her chemotherapy. The patient will be tested with the MUGA scan, as per the standard of care, before chemotherapy is initiated and at every 3 months. The patient will also be tested with the PhysioFlow at the same dates of the MUGA scan. In addition to that, the patients will be tested at each chemotherapy cycle with the PhysioFlow. Should the PhysioFlow indicate the patient has a cardiac toxicity as the patient is receiving chemotherapy, the results will be confirmed with the MUGA scan.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiotoxicity</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age above 18 years old 2. Histologically confirmed diagnosis of cancer 3. ECOG 0 to 2 4. Provide written consent after the investigational nature, study design, risks and benefits of the study have been explained 5. Able to adhere to the study visit schedule and other protocol requirements Control Group 1. Age above 18 years old 2. No previous history of cancer 3. ECOG 0 to 2 4. Did not receive chemotherapeutic agents (even if outside the context of cancer) 5. Provide written consent after the investigational nature, study design, risks and benefits of the study have been explained 6. Able to adhere to the study visit schedule and other protocol requirements 1. Age less than 18 years 2. ECOG 34 3. Suspected or proven severe aortic insufficiency 4. Patient under cardiopulmonary bypass assistance (I.e.: Left ventricular assisting device) 5. Congenital cardiac deformities ,such as septal defects 6. Refuse to comply with the specified visit schedules and requirements</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>