<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02220920</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of Canagliflozin (TA-7284) in combination with Insulin in patients with type 2 Diabetes for 16 weeks administration.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Study of Canagliflozin (TA-7284) in Combination With Insulin in Patients With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a randomized, 2-arm, parallel group, double blind study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of Canagliflozin (TA-7284) in Japanese patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus, who are receiving treatment with insulin therapy on diet and exercise and have inadequate glycemic control. The patients will receive either TA-7284 100mg or Placebo orally for 16 weeks.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Canagliflozin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients who has been receiving a stable dose and regimen of insulin over 12 weeks before administration of investigational dug Patients who are under dietary management and taking therapeutic exercise for diabetes over 12 weeks before administration of investigational drug Patients with HbA1c of ≥7.5% and &lt;10.5% Patients who were not administered diabetes therapeutic drugs prohibited for concomitant use within 12 weeks before administration of investigational drug Patients with type 1 diabetes mellitus, diabetes mellitus resulting from pancreatic disorder, or secondary diabetes mellitus (Cushing's syndrome, acromegaly, etc.) Patients with severe diabetic complications (proliferative diabetic retinopathy, stage 4 nephropathy, or serious diabetic neuropathy) Patients with hereditary glucosegalactose malabsorption or primary renal glucosuria Patients with systolic blood pressure of ≥160 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure of ≥100 mmHg Patients with serious renal or hepatic disease Patients with eGFR of &lt;45 mL/min/1.73 m2 Patients who are the excessive alcohol addicts Patients who are pregnant, lactating and probably pregnant patients and patients who can not agree to contraception</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>insulin resistance</keyword>
</DOC>