<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02220309</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This research study is aimed at understanding behaviors and brain circuits that relate to anxiety and depression. Our goal is to learn which circuits of the brain are involved in anxiety and how these circuits might affect daily functioning. The ultimate goal of the study is to apply this knowledge to help personalize treatments. We invite anyone who has recently experienced any symptoms of anxiety and/or depression to participate (no diagnosis is required to participate).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Stanford RAD Study (Research on Anxiety and Depression)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>If you are eligible and choose to participate, we'll ask you to come in for a visit during which you would complete some game-like tasks on the computer, undergo a non-invasive brain scan, and answer some questions about your emotional health. The entire visit takes place during one day at Stanford and lasts about 4-5 hours. We'll also ask you to do a follow-up 12 weeks later, from home, during which we'll again ask you some questions on your emotional health. To inquire more about participation, you can either sign up online or contact us. Sign up online: http://med.stanford.edu/williamslab/research/current/rad.html Contact us: Call or text (650) 600-1609 or email radproject@stanford.edu</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Recent experiences of anxiety and/or depression 18 years of age and older Specific psychiatric medications (casebycase basis) Bipolar 1 Disorder Schizophrenia</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>depression</keyword>
	<keyword>SAD</keyword>
	<keyword>bipolar disorder II</keyword>
	<keyword>PTSD</keyword>
	<keyword>GAD</keyword>
	<keyword>Phobia</keyword>
</DOC>