<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02220101</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Comparison of four methods for measuring temperature perioperatively in patients scheduled for laparoscopic surgery and intensive care patients who are hypo-, normo-and hyper terme; Bladder Monitoring, Nasopharyngeal, SpotOn TM, Zero heat flux method and Temporal Scanner. The study is a single-center, observational study carried out by the Central Surgical and Intensive Section at Vestfold Hospital Trust.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Temperature Measurement in Surgical and Intensive Care Patients - Comparison of Four Measurement Methods</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Issues - Perioperative hypothermia is associated with several serious complications and therefore most likely to be avoided. Monitoring of body temperature is therefore required perioperatively . - There are in the literature concerns that some methods of measuring temperature perioperatively is accurate enough and whether they reflect core temperature adequate. - Some authors have questioned whether temporal scanner (TS ) - and nasopharynx ( NP) - measurements are accurate enough to measure the actual core temperature. Much of the research on TS measurements have been done on children and newborns in an intensive setting, but little perioperatively . A total of 120 patients will be included ; 60 at Central Operations and 60 at Intensive Section at the Vestfold Hospital Trust. Duration of inclusion will be approximately one year . Starting around January 2014. The study emanates from Vestfold Hospital Trust and was designed by Espen Lindholm who is responsible for the project , Camilla B Norén who is principal investigator and project manager. Kjetil G Ringdal , Karl - André Wian and Knut Arvid Kirkebøen (University Hospital of Oslo ) are supervisors. The study is supported by research, Vestfold Hospital Trust and 3M Company Norway (study material ) and it is applied Regional Ethics Committee. Patients will not get different treatment than standard treatment in hospital and it causes no follow-up calls or hospital visits. All patients (if possible) give written consent for participation.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypothermia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Surgical Patient group: &gt; 18 years ASA 13 Laparoscopic surgery Elective surgery Intensive Patient group: &gt; 18 years Defined as intensive patient ASA 15 Surgical Patient group: BMI&gt; 30 kg/m2 No bladder (ileumbladder) Known malignant hyperthermia Malformations of the face that prevents nasopharynx and temporal scanner measurements Patient is participating in another study that may influence the results of the Tempstudy The patient is not competent to give consent, eg severe dementia The patient INR&gt; 2.0 and / or Trc &lt;50 Intensive Patient group: BMI&gt; 30 kg/m2 No bladder (ileumbladder) Malformations of the face that prevents nasopharynx and temporal scanner measurements Hypothermic patient below 32 ° C (bladder temperature) Hyperterm patient over 40 ° C (bladder temperature) Active cooling of the bladder The patient is under ongoing cooling or heating Patient is participating in another study that may influence the results of the Tempstudy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>hypothermia</keyword>
	<keyword>core temperature</keyword>
	<keyword>temperature measurement methods</keyword>
</DOC>