<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00990639</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Background: Alcohol is one of principal causes of hepatic fibrosis. Although the most effective treatment for alcoholic hepatic fibrosis is abstinence of alcohol consumption, additive treatment to reduce the accumulation of scar tissue can accelerate the improvement of hepatic fibrosis in alcoholic liver disease. The renin-angiotensin system can be an attractive antifibrotic target in liver. Several lines of evidence indicate that overproduction of angiotensin II(ANG II) in chronic liver injury stimulates the activation of hepatic stellate cells(HSCs) attributed to fibrogenesis. Additionally, the antifibrotic effect of ANG II blocking agent has been shown in various animal models and hepatitis C patients. Hence, drugs that inhibit the renin-angiotensin system have promise in ameliorating hepatic fibrosis in chronic liver injury. However, no study has been conducted in patients with alcoholic liver disease to evaluate the effect ANG II type I receptor blocking agent on hepatic fibrosis. Aim: This study aimed to investigate the safety and the efficacy of chronic administration of candesartan to hepatic fibrosis patients with alcoholic liver disease. Methods 1) Patients with liver fibrosis(F2) were randomized to receive either the angiotensin receptor blocker(ARB), candesartan(8 mg/day) with ursodeoxycholic acid(UDCA)(600 mg/day)(n = 42), or UDCA alone(n = 43) as control for 6 months. 2)All enrolled patients underwent liver biopsies twice for measurement of fibrosis score, area of fibrosis and alpha-smooth muscle actin(SMA) positive and hydroxyproline. 3) Transforming growth factor-beta1(TGF-beta1), collagen-1, angiotensin II type I receptor(AT1-R), tissue inhibitor of metalloproteinase-1(TIMP-1), Rac1 and p22phox which represent oxidant stress were also measured by real-time RT-PCR before and after 6 months of therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Candesartan in Alcoholic Liver Fibrosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases, Alcoholic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Candesartan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Candesartan cilexetil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ursodeoxycholic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of alcoholic liver disease METAVIR fibrosis score ≥ 2 in liver biopsy Alcohol intake has stop during at least 6 months until study enrollment Hepatocellular carcinoma or other malignancy Clinically decompensated cirrhosis (Total bilirubin ≥ 5mg/dL or variceal hemorrhage or ascites development or hepatic encephalopathy developement) Chronic liver disease related with other causes except alcohol</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2009</verification_date>
	<keyword>hepatic fibrosis</keyword>
	<keyword>angiotensin II blocking agents</keyword>
	<keyword>alcoholic liver disease</keyword>
</DOC>