<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00990821</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This 5-part study will evaluate the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics of two formulations of MK-0517 (with and without polysorbate 80) and aprepitant in healthy adults. Parts I to IV of this study will examine different doses of MK-0517 as well as two different formulations of MK-0517 (with and without polysorbate 80). Part V of the study will compare single doses of intravenous non-PS80 MK-0517 to oral 125-mg capsule of aprepitant. The primary hypothesis for Part V of the study is that a single intravenous dose of 100-mg or 115-mg MK-0517 is area under the plasma-time curve (AUC) equivalent to that of the 125-mg oral aprepitant capsule in young healthy participants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study to Investigate the Safety and Tolerability of MK-0517 in Healthy Subjects (MK-0517-012)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Nausea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aprepitant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fosaprepitant</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Midazolam</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subject is neither grossly overweight nor underweight for his/her height and body build Subject is in good health Subject is a nonsmoker Subject is willing to avoid excessive alcohol consumption for the duration of the study Subject is willing to avoid strenuous physical activity (i.e. unaccustomed weight lifting, running, bicycling) for the duration of the study Subject agrees to refrain from consumption of grapefruit (and grapefruit products) before and during the study Subject has a history of multiple and/or severe allergies to drugs or food Subject has donated blood or taken an investigational drug in another clinical trial within the last 4 weeks Subject has an infection, including Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection Subject is a regular user of any illicit drug Subject consumes excessive amounts of alcohol Subject drinks excessive amounts of coffee, tea, cola or other caffeinated beverages Subject currently uses on a regular basis, any prescription or non prescription medications</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>