<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02084524</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Malnutrition priori a major abdominal surgery is frequent and increases morbidity and mortality. The management of malnutrition has an impact in reducing postoperative complications. However malnutrition is rarely detected and Guidelines infrequently followed. Recovery time and nutritional evaluation in elderly patients are major criteria in their postoperative management. Identifying malnutrition or malnutrition risk is fundamental to its treatment. It is therefore unsurprising that many validated tools for nutrition risk screening and nutrition assessment exist for the clinician to use in assisting with the accurate identification, referral and treatment of patients who are malnourished or at risk of malnutrition. And nutritional management must be adapted and based on this evaluation and evolution of the general status (Guidelines Grade A). A geriatric evaluation based on a screening of preoperative malnutrition should allow a better implementation of the European Society of Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition (ESPEN) guidelines.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>ANC1 Study Impact of a Geriatric and Nutritional Evaluation for the Malnutrition and Malnutrition Risk Screening in Patients Over 70 Years With Colorectal Surgery.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Assessing the impact of a geriatric action (Team Mobile Geriatrics, EMG, or if the geriatric facility team when it does not have EMG) on the rate of nutritional support perioperative elderly subjects (≥ 70 years) who underwent a colorectal cancer according to ESPEN recommendations and SFNEP.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged ≥ 70 years Colorectal or tumor resection with/without synchronous metastases Emergency resection of colorectal tumor Unresectable colorectal tumor with/without synchronous metastases</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>70 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>vulnerable</keyword>
	<keyword>nutrition</keyword>
	<keyword>cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>colorectal</keyword>
	<keyword>tumor</keyword>
</DOC>