<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02084238</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This clinical study will test the efficacy and safety of low dose IL-2 treatment in Systemic lupus erythematosus.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Low-dose IL-2( Interleukin-2) Treatment in SLE</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a chronic autoimmune syndrome affecting various organs. While available therapies, such as corticosteroids and immunosuppressive agents have improved the outcome of patients, there remains a significant unmet need for safe and more effective treatments. Dysfunction of regulatory T (Treg) cells has been detected in diverse autoimmune diseases, which can be promoted by interleukin-2 (IL-2). We hypothesized that low-dose IL-2 could be a novel therapy in active SLE patients. This is a single center, uncontrolled, open-label study to assess the efficacy/safety of low dose IL-2 plus standard therapy in active SLE. Methods: Each SLE patients (n=40) with Scores&gt;=8 on the Safety of Estrogens in Lupus Erythematosus National Assessment (AELENA) version of the SLE Disease Activity Index (SLEDAI) that was refractory or relaps to glucocorticoid therapy received low-dose IL-2 (1 million units every other day subcutaneously (HrIL-2 1X 106, ip, Qod) for a period of 14 days. After a 14-day rest, another cycle started) for 3-6 cycles according to the situation of the disease. The end points were safety and clinical and immunologic response. Expected Results: This trail will define low-dose IL-2 plus standard therapy is efficacy and safety with active lupus patients, which could be relevant to the amelioration the abnormity of T help cells in SLE patients.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interleukin-2</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Meet the American College of Rheumatology criteria for the diagnosis of SLE. Under standard treatment (≥ 2 months) at the time of inclusion Background treatment failed to control flares or to permit prednisone tapering With at least one of the following manifestations: thrombocytopenia, diseaseassociated rash, mouth ulcer, noninfectious type of fever, active vasculitis, renal disorder(proteinuria&gt;0.5g/day), neuropsychiatric SLE. Positive for at least one of the following laboratory tests: ANA&gt;1:160, antidsDNA, immunoglobulin&gt;20g/L, decreased C3 or C4, leukopenia&lt;3×10^9/L, thrombocytopenia&lt;100×10^9/L; SLE disease activity index(SLEDAI) ≥ 8. Negative HIV test. Negative for hepatitis B and C virus. Written informed consent form. Sever chronic liver, kidney, lung or heart dysfunction; (heart failure (≥ grade III NYHA), hepatic insufficiency (transaminases&gt; 3N) ) Serious infection such as bacteremia, sepsis; Cancer or history of cancer cured for less than five years (except in situ carcinoma of the cervix or Basocellular carcinoma); Highdose steroid pulse therapy (&gt;1.5mg/kg) or IV bolus of corticosteroids in the last 2 months. History of administration of rituximab or other biologics; Purified protein derivative (tuberculin) &gt;10mm Mental disorder or any other chronic illness or drugabuse that could interfere with the ability to comply with the protocol or to give information; Inability to comply with IL2 treatment regimen.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>SLE, IL-2</keyword>
</DOC>