<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02568709</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The specific aim of this proposal is to investigate the neurophysiological mechanisms of oxytocin's (OT) prosocial effects in patients with schizophrenia and healthy subjects using magnetoencephalography. Hypothesis A: When OT is administered to patients with schizophrenia, fear-related amygdala hyperreactivity and fusiform gyrus (FG) and anterior cingulate cortex (ACC) hypoactivity will be normalized. Hypothesis B: When OT is administered to patients with schizophrenia, the decreased functional connectivity (FC) between the amygdala, FG, and ACC will be normalized. By elucidating the neurophysiological mechanisms of OT administration on emotional face processing, investigators will bee able to: 1. understand the pathophysiology of the functionally debilitating social cognitive deficits of schizophrenia, 2. test the efficacy of OT in normalizing the neural abnormalities underlying these social deficits, and 3. develop and optimize novel treatments for these currently untreatable deficits.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Oxytocin MEG Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Oxytocin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria for Patients: 1840 years of age Male Must comprehend English Meet DSMIV criteria for schizophrenia, schizophreniform or schizoaffective disorder None or only minor changes to medications in the past week Able to use nasal spray Must be capable of providing informed consent Clinically stable Inclusion Criteria for Healthy Controls: 1840 years of age Male Must comprehend English No diagnosis of mental disorder according to DSMIV TR Able to use nasal spray Must be capable of providing informed consent Clinically stable Female Active substance abuse or dependence as determined by a Urine Toxicology Drug Screening DSMIV diagnosis of any disorder other than schizophrenia Medical conditions (atrophic rhinitis, recurrent nose bleeds and cranial surgical procedures (hypophysectomy), congestion or sinus problems that could interfere with the study as per the opinion of the investigator Hearing deficits A pacemaker, extensive dental work, or any magnetic metal implants Any history of severe brain trauma</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Oxytocin</keyword>
	<keyword>Syntocinon</keyword>
	<keyword>Social Cognition</keyword>
	<keyword>Schizophrenia</keyword>
	<keyword>Magnetoencephalography (MEG)</keyword>
</DOC>