<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02568046</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a phase 1b/2a study investigating the safety and effect of Sym004 in combination with FOLFIRI (chemotherapy) when administered every second week. The phase 1b (dose-escalation) portion of the trial is expected to begin Q1 2016. Patients will be sequentially enrolled to dose-escalation cohorts until establishment of the Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) and Recommended Phase 2 Dose (RP2D) of Sym004 in combination with FOLFIRI. The phase 2a (dose-expansion) portion of the trial is expected to begin after establishing the RP2D.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Sym004 in Combination With FOLFIRI in Metastatic Colorectal Cancer Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Camptothecin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluorouracil</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leucovorin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Levoleucovorin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Main inclusion Criteria: 1. Male or female, at least 18 years of age at the time of informed consent 2. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) of 0 or 1 3. Histologically or cytologically confirmed, locally advanced or metastatic colorectal cancer (CRC) that is documented to be without Kirsten rat sarcoma (KRAS) or Neuroblastoma rat sarcoma (NRAS) gene mutations (i.e. tumors must express the KRAS and NRAS wild type (WT), exon 2, 3 and 4). 4. Failed* treatment for locally advanced or metastatic disease with firstline combination therapy of oxaliplatin and a fluoropyrimidine, with or without bevacizumab, during treatment or &lt; 3 months after the last dose of firstline therapy and within &lt; 3 months of C1/D1. Patients who discontinued firstline therapy due to toxicity may be enrolled provided progression occurred &lt; 6 months after the last dose of the firstline therapy regimen. or Failed* adjuvant therapy with combination therapy of oxaliplatin and a fluoropyrimidine during treatment or within &lt; 6 months after the last dose of oxaliplatin and within &lt; 6 months of C1/D1. Failure is defined as radiologic progression 5. Eligible for FOLFIRI 6. Measurable disease according to RECIST v1.1 Main exclusion Criteria: 1. Prior therapy with antiEGFR antibodies, antiEGFR small molecule inhibitors or irinotecan (CPT11) 2. Any antineoplastic agent (standard or investigational) within 4 weeks prior to C1/D1 3. Significant gastrointestinal abnormalities 4. Patients with a significant cardiovascular disease or condition 5. Abnormal hematologic, renal or hepatic function</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Metastatic Colorectal Cancer</keyword>
</DOC>