<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02306226</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Post-market registry aimed at further evaluating the safety and performance of the ACURATE neo™ Aortic Bioprosthesis and ACURATE TF™ Transfemoral Delivery System in patients with severe aortic stenosis treated with the commercialized device</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Symetis ACURATE Neo™ Valve Implantation SAVI TF Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The SAVI TF is s single arm, multicenter, non-randomized and open registry. The purpose of this registry is to collect and monitor ongoing safety and performance data from commercial use of the ACURATE neo™ Aortic Bioprosthesis and ACURATE TF™ Transfemoral Delivery System. The ACURATE neo™ and its Transfemoral Delivery System are intended for use in minimally invasive, transcatheter aortic valve replacement (TAVR) using transfemoral access in patients presenting with severe aortic valve stenosis. The primary objective is to further evaluate the safety and performance of the ACURATE neo™ Aortic Bioprosthesis and ACURATE TF™ Transfemoral Delivery System in the first 1000 consecutive patients with severe aortic stenosis treated with the newly marketed device. The secondary objective is to evaluate adverse events and device performance of the newly marketed device.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Aortic Valve Stenosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patient is included in the registry if eligible for transcatheter treatment of severe aortic stenosis with the ACURATE neo™ Aortic Bioprosthesis and ACURATE TF™ Transfemoral Delivery System as per the Instructions for Use 2. Patient is willing to participate in the study, provides signed Informed Consent/Data Authorization Form and authorizes the sharing of data in the registry 3. The subject and treating physician agree the subject will return for all required postprocedure followup visits 1. Patients are excluded from the registry if they are not eligible for transcatheter treatment of severe aortic stenosis with the ACURATE neo™ Aortic Bioprosthesis and ACURATE TF™ Transfemoral Delivery System as per the Instructions For Use.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>75 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>TAVI</keyword>
	<keyword>Aortic stenosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Transcatheter aortic valve replacement</keyword>
	<keyword>Transcatheter aortic valve implantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Transfemoral access</keyword>
</DOC>