<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00477893</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Spondyloarthropathies (SpA) are often diagnosed with a considerable delay (often 8-10 years from symptom onset), because the available clinical, biochemical and radiological methods are not sufficiently sensitive. TNF-a antagonists have recently been introduced for treatment of SpA, and current data indicate a higher efficacy than previously available therapies. The improved treatment options have increased the need for improved methods for diagnosis, monitoring and prognostication of these diseases, so that the efficient therapies can be initiated at the optimal time point and monitored optimally. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and a number of biomarkers are promising, but not yet sufficiently studied, methods for this.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Danish Multicenter Study of Adalimumab in Spondyloarthritis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>See brief summary</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Spondylarthritis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Diagnosis of spondyloarthritis according to the European Spondyloarthritis Study Group (ESSG) criteria 2. Clinical active disease, defined as a BASDAI score &gt; 4 despite concurrent NSAID therapy 3. Presence of sacroiliitis on conventional radiography or MRI. 4. Among other issues: Age &gt;18 years; adequate birth control; no contraindications for antiTNFatherapy, no previous TNFaantagonists 1. Previous TNFα inhibitor therapy 2. Treatment with disease modifying antirheumatic drugs within 4 weeks before screening 3. Oral, intraarticular, intramuscular or intravenous glucocorticoid within 4 weeks before screening 4. Pregnancy or lactation 5. HIV, hepatitis B or C, tuberculosis, other infections 6. Malignancies 7. Other serious concomitant diseases (uncontrolled/severe kidney, liver, haematological, gastrointestinal, endocrine, cardiovascular, pulmonary, neurological ore cerebral disease (including demyelinating disease) 8. Contraindications to antiTNFatherapy 9. Contraindications to MRI</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>