<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00477737</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In vitro studies and in vivo animal experiments have shown that halogenated volatile anesthetics have a protective effect on the ischemic myocardium. In clinical settings however, anesthetic preconditioning may be of more interest. The aim of our study was to evaluate the cardioprotective effect of sevoflurane in patients undergoing off-pump coronary artery bypass surgery. We proposed that a cardioprotective effect of sevoflurane would save myocardial function, which we measured acceleration by esophageal Doppler and cardiac index with bolus thermodilution methods, both during brief ischemia and reperfusion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Early Cardioprotective Effect of Sevoflurane</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Studies have been performed on human patients undergoing CABG surgery with cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB). Only a few studies however have evaluated the effects of volatile anesthetics during coronary artery bypass grafting on a beating heart (OPCABG) with conflicting results as far as cardiac biomarker release is concerned. Because CPB is known to have a profound impact on cardiac function, studies performed on patients scheduled for OPCABG could evaluate more specifically the effects of the anesthetic agents themselves. Patients undergoing OPCABG have a predictable and predefined ischemic zone during surgery and represent an extremely interesting and safe model for the study of ischemia and cardiac damage in humans. Presently, there is still no consensus on the method of administration of volatile anesthetics, including the time to begin administration, its duration, the dosage and selection of volatile anesthetics.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Propofol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sevoflurane</mesh_term>
	<criteria>the degree I or II of Cardiac Anesthesia Risk Evaluation score angiographically verified coronary artery disease left ventricular ejection fraction higher than 40% atrioventricular conduction disturbances previously ventricular arrhythmias requiring antiarrhythmic treatment atrial fibrillation with rapid ventricular response myocardial infarction or stroke within 6 months diabetes mellitus endstage of obstructive or restrictive pulmonary disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>cardioprotection</keyword>
	<keyword>sevoflurane</keyword>
	<keyword>esophageal Doppler</keyword>
	<keyword>thermodilution</keyword>
	<keyword>coronary artery bypass</keyword>
</DOC>