<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00374868</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To assess the anti-tumor activity, as measured by response rate to bi-weekly pemetrexed plus cisplatin, in chemo-naive patients with diagnosed metastatic or locally advanced (non-resectable) urothelial cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pemetrexed Plus Cisplatin Bi-Weekly, in Patients With Urothelial Cancer (Metastatic, Locally Advanced or Non-Resectable)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Urologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically proven locally advanced disease or metastatic transitional cell carcinoma of the urothelium including bladder, urethra, ureter, and renal pelvis. Patients should not be suitable for surgery or radiation with curative intent. However patients whose prechemotherapy sites of disease are restricted to the primary or regional lymph node sites and who have a major response to chemotherapy will be evaluated for postchemotherapy surgical resection of residual cancer if the tumor has become resectable at the end of chemotherapy. Measurable disease status, as defined in the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) criteria (Therasse et al., 2000) One course of prior radiation therapy is allowed. Prior radiation must have been completed at least 4 weeks before enrolment into the study and the patients must have recovered from all toxic effects. Have central nervous system (CNS) or leptomeningeal metastases (unless the patient has completed successful local therapy for CNS metastases and has been off corticosteroids for at least 4 weeks before starting study therapy). A screening computed tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) before enrollment in the absence of a clinical suspicion of brain metastases is not required. Inability to interrupt aspirin or other nonsteroidal antiinflammatory agents 2 days before, the day of, and 2 days after the dose of pemetrexed plus cisplatin or cisplatin alone. If a patient is taking a nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug (NSAID) or salicylate with a long halflife (for example, naproxen, piroxicam, diflunisal) it should not be taken 5 days before the dose of pemetrexed (8day period for longacting agents such as piroxicam), the day of, and 2 days after the dose of pemetrexed plus cisplatin.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2010</verification_date>
</DOC>