<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00374361</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to determine whether there is a relationship between the way insulin and blood vessels work. The difference in the interaction between Caucasian and African American adolescents will also be examined. This may play a role in the differing rates of heart disease and diabetes between the two groups.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of the Relationship Between Blood Vessels and Insulin Response in Adolescents</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Purpose: The purpose of the research is to learn more about how the lining of arteries in the body (called the endothelium) and insulin work in adolescents. Abnormalities in how the blood vessels and insulin work in adolescents may cause high blood pressure, type 2 diabetes, stroke and heart disease. Healthy adolescents between 8 and 18 years of age are being studied in the Ohio State University General Clinical Research Center. Two visits will be necessary. One will be a screening visit to determine the child's stage of puberty and obtain a medical history. The second will be the study visit. During the latter, blood vessel function will be determined by studying the change in forearm blood flow before and after blood flow to the forearm is stopped. Insulin sensitivity will be determined using glucose water given into a vein.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Caucasian or African American adolescent Between 8 and 18 years of age Pregnancy Chronic Disease Acute Disease Medication Requirement</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>insulin sensitivity</keyword>
	<keyword>endothelial function</keyword>
	<keyword>adolescence</keyword>
	<keyword>lipids</keyword>
	<keyword>puberty</keyword>
</DOC>