<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00804609</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To evaluate the levels of morphine in a patient's blood when morphine is given into the epidural space in the form of DepoDur速 either alone or following a dose of lidocaine also given in the epidural space.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Epidural Lidocaine on the Pharmacokinetic and Pharmacodynamic Profiles of DepoDur速 After Cesarean Delivery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To evaluate the levels of morphine in a patient's blood when morphine is given into the epidural space in the form of DepoDur速 either alone or following a dose of lidocaine also given in the epidural space. Specifically, we are looking at pregnant women undergoing cesarean delivery who will be receiving these medications. A secondary objective is to evaluate how well DepoDur速 works for pain control, as well as its safety, when it is given either alone or following a dose of epidural lidocaine.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Polystyrene sulfonic acid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria will include healthy parturients between the ages of 18 and 40 who have American Society of Anesthesiologists physical status I or II, have an uncomplicated, singleton, term pregnancy, and are scheduled to undergo cesarean delivery. Exclusion criteria for the study will included refusal to participate, American Society of Anesthesiologists physical status III or higher or any severe uncontrolled medical condition, significant systemic medical or obstetric disease, morbid obesity, opioid, Nonsteroidal Antiinflammatory Drug (NSAID), or local anesthetic allergy or intolerance, chronic analgesic or antidepressant use, accidental dural puncture, ineffective spinal or epidural, and conversion to general anesthesia.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>