<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00804908</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of ABT-888 in combination with temozolomide versus temozolomide alone in subjects with metastatic melanoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study Evaluating Efficacy of ABT-888 in Combination With Temozolomide in Metastatic Melanoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Skin Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Veliparib</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically (or cytologically) confirmed metastatic melanoma. Unresectable Stage III or Stage IV metastatic melanoma. Measurable disease by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) criteria. Subjects with no history of brain metastases demonstrated by a baseline MRI, or subjects with a history of previously treated brain metastases who have history of operable/SRS treatable brain metastases and completed surgical resection/stereotactic radiosurgery with or without adjuvant whole brain radiation at least 28 days prior to Day 1; have baseline MRI that shows no evidence of active intercranial disease; have discontinued taking medications for symptom management of brain metastases at least 7 days prior to Day 1 28 days since prior anticancer therapy. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Score of 01. Adequate hematologic, renal and hepatic function. Partial Thromboplastin Time (PTT) is &lt;= 1.5 x upper normal limit of institution's normal range and international normalized ratio (INR) &lt; 1.5. Subject's with significant fluid retention may be allowed at the discretion of the investigator. Life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks. Females must not be pregnant. Voluntarily signed informed consent. Lactate Dehydrogenase (LDH) &gt; 2 x Upper Limit of Normal (ULN). Ocular malignant melanoma. History of central nervous system metastases or leptomeningeal disease. Prior treatment with Dacarbazine (DTIC) or Temozolomide (TMZ). Prior DNA damaging agents or cytotoxic chemotherapy. Prior Whole Brain Radiation Therapy (with exceptions). Received an investigational agent within 28 days of study. History of seizure disorder and/or taking medication for seizure disorder. Active malignancy within the past 5 years, except cervical cancer in situ, in situ carcinoma of the bladder or nonmelanoma carcinoma of the skin. Medical condition that would cause a high risk for toxicities.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Temozolomide</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Metastatic Melanoma</keyword>
	<keyword>ABT-888</keyword>
	<keyword>MM</keyword>
</DOC>