<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02872324</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Mindfulness is both a natural resource of individuals present in all individuals in varying degrees characteristic ability of attention to the experience that unfolds moment by moment without judgment and a practice based on meditation, mindfulness exercises, which aims to enhance two central skills of mindfulness that are the presence and acceptanc. In the context of recurrent depression, the practice of mindfulness meditation in the frame of MBCT is recognized as effective in psychological suffering and relapse. The mechanisms implied in MBCT efficacy are emotional but especially cognitive. Among the cognitive mechanisms, reduction of rumination is a major factor in the action of MBCT, especially for patients with less than three depressive relapses. This exploratory research focuses on the impact of mindfulness functioning (mindfulness resource level at baseline) on the benefits of MBCT for patients with recurrent depressive disorder. The objective is to assess whether the level of mindfulness resource of patients with recurrent depression is a factor contributing to the positive effect of a MBCT applied in add-on to conventional care. This objective will be measured by comparing the clinical improvement of patients secondary to MBCT according to the initial categorization of the mindfulness resource. Clinical improvement will be more important for patients characterized by a lower initial level of mindfulness resource.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Impact of the Level of Mindfulness on the Management of Patients With Recurrent Depressive Disorders by the Mindfulness Based Cognitive Therapy ( MBCT ): an Exploratory Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Major patient Patient with recurrent depression Patient have read, understood and signed the nonopposition form. Inability to understand or read English or French. Individuals unable to personally express their opposition not under whose major legal or private protection of liberty by judicial or administrative decision, or hospital emergency</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>