<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02872766</DOC>
	<brief_summary>43 Subjects (43 eyes) qualified for participation will undergo the required screening procedures to determine study eligibility. The surgical protocol involves applying riboflavin 0,22% to 0,25 % up to 20 minutes . Then, the eyes will be exposed to UVA light with the KXL II system according to the programmed treatment pattern. All use of the KXL II system will be in accordance with the general instructions in the operator's manual. All subjects will be evaluated at screening, Day 3, and 1, 3, 6 ,12 and 24 months after treatment. Manual keratometry, manifest refraction, uncorrected visual acuity, best corrected visual acuity, slit lamp biomicroscopy, pentacam measurements and placido disc topography (TMS), will be obtained at baseline and at appropriate times after the treatment.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Evaluation of the Safety and Efficacy of Corneal Cross Linking for the Treatment of Myopia.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Myopia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Provide written informed consent Willingness to folow all instructions and comply with schedule for follow up visits Having myopia with manifest refraction spherical equivalent of 1.00 to 2.50 D, with cylindral component pl to 0.75 D Social security insurance or equivalent sensitivity to the use of the test article(s) hypersensitivity to local anesthesics Corneal pachymetry that is &lt; 480 microns Eyes with keratoconus Eyes which are aphakic or with corneal intacs Previous ocular condition (other than refractive error) in the eye to be treated that may predispose the eye for future complications. For example: History of corneal disease (e.g., herpes simplex, recurrent erosion syndrome, corneal dystrophy, refractive keratotomy etc.), clinically significant corneal scarring in the crosslinking treatment zone Pregnancy or lactation Patients with a current condition that, in the investigator's opinion, would interfere with or prolong epithelial healing Taking Vitamin C (ascorbic acid) supplements within 1 week of the crosslinking treatment. Juridical protection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>