<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02284776</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to assess the effect of a therapeutic education program in addition of a hydrotherapeutic cure on obese patients. The therapeutic education program at the thermal baths of Brides-les-Bains is composed of a dietary follow-up, a physical activities program, working group.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Preliminary Evaluation Study of Therapeutic Education on Overweight People in Addition to a Hydrotherapeutic Cure</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The participants are people that come to the thermal baths in order to follow an hydrotherapeutic cure (of about 3 weeks). For the Action group, they also follow a course of therapeutic education where they are given advices on how they should eat and have a regular physical activity. This therapeutic education in addition of the hydrotherapeutic cure should help them lose weight and not gain in again. The participants are followed for 18 months (17 months after leaving the thermal baths).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Body Mass Index (BMI) over 27 kg/m² (or equal) Has a valid email address, has access to the internet and to a telephone line Has a domestic scale compatible with its weight Signed the consent form Susceptible to accept the obligations generated by the study Has a health insurance Has a progressive illness at the time of the study (cancer, neurodegenerative disease...) Is pregnant Follows the hydrotherapeutic cure in order to cure rheumatism Trying to lose weight prior to a surgery Has a diagnosed eating disorder Has no physical activity due to a handicap or a serious osteoarthritis Has taken a weightloss drug (Orlistat) in the past month or will likely do so in the future Is taking a Desmopressinbased drug Is unable to understand or follow the protocol Is deprived of liberty Is under judicial protection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Therapeutic education</keyword>
</DOC>