<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01104363</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of heavy Vinyl PolySiloxane (VPS) and splinted implants impression (Study Group, SG) technique versus plaster implant impression (Control Group, CG) technique, in 12 edentulous patients rehabilitated with the All-on-4 concept and Procera® Implant Bridge (P.I.B.). A longitudinal, double blinded, randomised clinical trial (RCT) was designed to evaluate the accuracy of the impression. All patients were monitored from implant placement until prosthetic loading.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Enhancing Prosthetic Results by Predictable Impression Technique and Reliable NobelProcera™ Systems</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: Various implant impression techniques and materials have been proposed. Some clinical factors, such as the angulation or depth of implants, may affect the accuracy of the implant impressions. Lee et al. (Lee JPD 2008) reported that the splint-technique ensures a greater accuracy if compared to the non-splint technique, and, in case of 4 or more implants, the pick-up technique proves most appropriate. Polyether (PE) and VPS were the recommended materials for the implant impressions. Aim: to investigate the accuracy of pick-up, splinted implants, and heavy VPS impression techniques (Aquasil Putty DECA™ and Aquasil Ultra Light Viscosity (LV) Regular Set, Dentsply International Inc, Caulk, USA); to compare two splint materials for implants: Primopattern LC gel (Primotec, Bad Homburg, Germany), and Smart Dentin Replacement (SDR™, Dentsply International Inc, Caulk, USA); to examine the clinical factors affecting the accuracy of implant impressions; to test the tension-free fit of the new scanner and software NobelProcera™ (NobelBiocare, AB, Göteborg, Sweden) titanium frameworks. The hypothesis to demonstrate is that all impression techniques and used materials reduce time for final restoration and improve the accuracy of the impression.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Age 21 years or older. Both genders. Fully edentulous patients. Both maxilla and mandible. Dental implant rehabilitation utilizing the Allon4 concept at least 8 weeks before impression. External hex dental implant. Patients with ability to understand and sign the informed consent prior to starting the study. Adequate oral hygiene. Immediate functional loading. Implant stability quote value =/&gt; 65 from implant placement to final prosthetic rehabilitation. Failure of one or more inclusion criteria.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Dental implants</keyword>
</DOC>