<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01104922</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objectives of this study are to determine the 1-year progression-free survival (PFS) of previously irradiated patients with squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck (SCCHN) treated with radiosurgery and cetuximab and to evaluate the acute and late toxicities associated with the above therapy.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Re-irradiation With Fractionated Stereotactic Radiosurgery Plus Cetuximab in Patients With Recurrent Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Head and Neck</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically proven recurrent squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck (SCCHN), who has received prior radiotherapy with or without chemotherapy. New primary is allowed if location is in a previously irradiated field. Biopsy is recommended for each recurrence; but is not mandated per study. This will be at the discretion of the principal investigator. Prior radiation dose of at least 60 Gy. Disease confined to locoregional site and can be encompassed in a stereotactic radiosurgery "portal" Tumor must be deemed to be inoperable or unresectable either by clinical or radiographic criteria. These criteria include encasement of great vessels, vertebral invasion or undue perioperative risk. Prior surgery for recurrent or new SCCHN is allowed in previously irradiated patients. A minimum of 4 weeks should elapse between any surgery and treatment on study. However, high risk pathologic features should be present, such as positive margins, positive lymphadenopathy, perineural or angiolymphatic invasion. Measurable disease must be present for assessment of response. Karnofsky performance status &gt; 60 (ECOG 02) Prior treatment with an EGFR Inhibitor is allowed if it was a part of prior curative therapy and was completed at least 30 days prior to commencement of study therapy Any number of prior chemotherapy regimens are allowed Measurable disease on imaging studies (MRI, CT, PETCT or physical exam) Age &gt; 18 Estimated life expectancy &gt; 12 weeks No prior radiation therapy or chemotherapy within 1 month of study enrollment No prior chemotherapy or targeted therapy within the previous 4 weeks ANC &gt; 1000, PLT&gt;75,000, Serum creatinine&lt;2.5 mg/dL, Bilirubin &lt;1.5 x upper limits of normal (ULN) Diabetes must be controlled prior to PETCT scanning (blood glucose &lt;200 mg/dL) Ability to provide written informed consent Evidence of distant metastasis on upright chest xray (CXR), computed tomography (CT) or other staging studies History of any cancer other than SCCHN (except nonmelanoma skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix) within the last 5 years. Patients in their reproductive age group should use an effective method of birth control. Patients who are breastfeeding, or have a positive pregnancy test will be excluded from the study Any comorbidity or condition of sufficient severity to limit full compliance with the protocol per assessment by the investigator Concurrent serious infection History of known hypersensitivity to cetuximab or similar agents</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Re-irradiation with Fractionated Stereotactic Radiosurgery for Head and Neck</keyword>
</DOC>