<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01909284</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is being conducted to investigate the effectiveness and safety of acupuncture for alleviating pain of spondylosis.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Study of Acupuncture to Treat Spinal Pain</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study is being conducted at the Daegu Catholic University Medical Center. Enrolled participants will be randomized into two groups : acupuncture treatment plus epidural block and epidural block alone. This trial will include treatments during 3 weeks, and then follow up after 2 weeks. Participants will have acupuncture treatments of three times per week and epidural block of once per week. All examinations and treatments will be provided free of charge. Compared with epidural block group, acupuncture plus epidural block group will give more effectiveness for alleviate pain caused by lumbar spondylosis.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age 18 to 65 years Meyerding Grade III spondylolisthesis Low back pain of at least 1year duration Followup possible during the clinical trial Written informed consent voluntarily Cauda equina syndrome, persistently exacerbated symptoms, progressive neurologic signs (sensory or motor changes) Previous spine surgery Senile dementia, impaired cognitive function or other cerebral disease, severe psychiatric or psychological disorders Severe, concomitant disease (neuromuscular scoliosis, neurodegenerative disease) All contraindications to corticosteroid injection (e.g., insulindependent diabetes) Alcohol/drug abuse Significant renal or hepatic disease Pregnant, lactating or planning a pregnancy Hypersensitive reaction to acupuncture treatment Inability to comprehend or express oneself in the Korean language An individual deemed to be ineligible by a physician Refusal to participate in the trial or to provide informed consent</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
</DOC>