<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01909934</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a single-arm, open-label, multicenter, phase 4 clinical trial to evaluate the efficacy and safety of brentuximab vedotin as a single agent in patients with relapsed or refractory Systemic Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma (SALCL).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Study of Brentuximab Vedotin in Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Systemic Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large-Cell, Anaplastic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patients age 18 years or older, with relapsed or refractory sALCL who have previously received at least 1 multiagent chemotherapy Bidimensional measurable disease An Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1 Female patients who are postmenopausal for at least 1 year before the screening visit, surgically sterile, or agree to practice 2 effective methods of contraception, at the same time, from the time of signing the informed consent form through 30 days after the last dose of study drug, or agree to practice true abstinence Male patients who agree to practice effective barrier contraception during the entire study treatment period through 6 months after the last dose of study drug or agree to practice true abstinence Clinical laboratory values as specified in the study protocol Previous treatment with brentuximab vedotin. Previously received an allogeneic transplant. Patients with current diagnosis of primary cutaneous ALCL (patients whose ALCL has transformed to sALCL are eligible). Known cerebral/meningeal disease including signs or symptoms of progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy (PML) Female patients who are lactating and breastfeeding or pregnant Known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) positive Known hepatitis B surface antigenpositive, or known or suspected active hepatitis C infection</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lymphoma</keyword>
	<keyword>Anaplastic Large-cell</keyword>
	<keyword>Relapsed</keyword>
	<keyword>Refractory</keyword>
	<keyword>Antigens, CD30</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibody-Drug Conjugate</keyword>
	<keyword>Antibodies, Monoclonal</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</keyword>
	<keyword>Lymphoma, Large-Cell, Anaplastic</keyword>
	<keyword>monomethyl auristatin E</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Hematologic Diseases</keyword>
</DOC>