<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01591772</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to learn about possible changes in brain anatomy and function, and in thinking abilities, such as memory skills, in patients with ovarian cancer who receive treatment with chemotherapy. Cancer patients treated with chemotherapy may experience changes in thinking abilities, and these may interfere with quality of life. Most of the research to date has involved patients with breast cancer, and there are no studies in women with ovarian cancer looking at at treatment-related changes in brain anatomy and function.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Structural and Functional Imaging and Cognitive Functions in Ovarian Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>diagnosed with stage IIV ovarian, peritoneal or fallopian tube cancer completed firstline taxane and platinumbased chemotherapy 14 months prior to being enrolled in the study (can be on bevacizumab maintenance) in remission of their disease at the time of enrollment between 21 and 70 years of age fluent in English in the judgment of the consenting professional, have capacity to give consent Healthy Control no diagnosis of cancer except basal cell carcinoma between 21 and 70 years of age fluent in English has a minimental state exam (MMSE) score of 26 or higher in the judgment of the consenting professional, have capacity to give consent active or recurrent disease, or diagnosis of another cancer (except basal cell carcinoma) as per medical records at the time of enrollment exposure to chemotherapy or radiation therapy for any medical condition unrelated to ovarian cancer on hormonal therapy at the time of enrollment neurological disorder or moderate to severe head trauma (loss of consciousness &gt; 60 min) neurodegenerative disorders such as Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's disease, multiple sclerosis, etc. selfreported Axis I psychiatric disorder (DSMIV), major affective disorder (untreated), bipolar disorder, schizophrenia unable to complete cognitive tests with standard contraindications to MRI examinations Healthy Control exposure to chemotherapy or radiation therapy for any medical condition on hormone replacement therapy at the time of enrollment neurological disorder or moderate to severe head trauma (loss of consciousness &gt; 60 min) neurodegenerative disorders such as Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's disease, multiple sclerosis, etc.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>FALLOPIAN TUBE</keyword>
	<keyword>OVARY</keyword>
	<keyword>PERITONEUM</keyword>
	<keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
	<keyword>structural MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>functional MRI</keyword>
	<keyword>neuropsychological assessment</keyword>
	<keyword>12-075</keyword>
</DOC>