<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02272166</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Recovery of hunger is a source of comfort for patients after general anesthesia. Moreover, this aspect of post-operative period is often required for discharging patients from hospital after ambulatory surgery. Indeed, this item is part of a multi-parameter score (Chung score) whose validation evaluates patient's ability to return home. The impact of anesthetics on hunger is largely unknown but few studies suggest an orexigenic effect of propofol compared to halogenated gases. These studies had neither the power nor the methodology to answer the question. The aim of our study is to evaluate the impact of propofol versus sevoflurane on early recovery of hunger after ambulatory surgery.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Propofol on Early Recovery of Hunger After Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Propofol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sevoflurane</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1845 years old women American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) score 12 Affiliated to a social security system Undergoing an ambulatory surgery during more than 15 minutes with general anesthesia and control of upper airways (tracheal intubation or supraglottic mask or facial mask ventilation) for oocytes punction before in vitro fertilization General anesthesia occuring between 8 and 10 am with respect of preoperative fasting rules APFEL risk score for nausea and vomiting ≤ 2/4 Ability to understand and read french Signature of understood consent Other surgery than oocytes punction Cognitive dysfunction Undernutrition or risk factor of undernutrition (evolutive neoplasia, chronic alcoholism …) BMI ≥ 35 kg/m² Eating disorders Diabetes mellitus Chronic treatment with drugs modifying feeding behavior : Benzodiazepines Inhibitors of serotonin reuptake Others Non respect of preoperative fasting rules Indication for rapid sequence induction (gastrooesophageal reflux, absence of gastric emptying …) Contraindication to propofol (allergia to propofol, soybean or peanuts, past history of propofol infusion syndrome, unstable cardiovascular disease) or to sevoflurane (past history of malignant hyperthermia, epilepsy or liver disorders after administration of a halogenated anesthetic) Pregnant or breastfeeding woman Involvement in another clinical trial under 4 previous weeks</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>