<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02272738</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the clinical safety and efficacy of Gemcitabine plus nab-Paclitaxel chemoradiotherapy and to determine the Maximal Tolerated Dose (MTD) for unresectable locally advanced pancreatic adenocarcinoma.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Chemoradiotherapy Using Gem Plus Nab-paclitaxel for Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Gemcitabine plus nab-Paclitaxel is one of the standard chemotherapy for metastatic pancreatic adenocarcinoma. Gemcitabine plus nab-Paclitaxel realize the favorable anti-tumor effect and tolerable toxicity. Gemcitabine plus nab-Paclitaxel is a promising regimen for concurrent chemoradiotherapy, but the investigators need to know the safety in the case of the concurrent chemoradiotherapy.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed advanced pancreatic cancer Locally advanced pancreatic cancer is defined as the presence of a surgically unresectable tumor(involving the celiac axis or the superior mesenteric artery) Performance Status:01(ECOG) Patients of age =&gt;20 and 75&gt; White Blood Cell (WBC) &gt;=3,500/mm3,12,000/mm3, Neutrophils &gt;=1,500/mm3, platelets=100,000/mm3, Hemoglobin &gt;=9.5 g/dl, GOT &lt;/=2.0 X Upper Limit Number (ULN), Glutamate Pyruvate Transaminase (GPT) &lt;/=2.0 X ULN, Alkaline Phosphatase (ALP) &lt;/=2.0 X ULN, Total bilirubin &lt;=1.5mg/dl, Serum creatinine &lt;=1.2mg/dl, Creatinine clearance&gt;=50 ml/min arterial O2 pressure (PaO2) &gt;=70torr or arterial O2 saturation (SpO2) &gt;=96% Life expectancy more than 3 months. Written informed consent. Active infection Lung fibrosis or intestinal pneumonia detectable on chest Xray and CT Severe complication (heart disease, cirrhosis, diabetes) Myocardial infarction within 3 months Active synchronous or metachronous malignancy Pregnant or lactation women, or women with known or suspected pregnancy Symptomatic brain metastasis History of severe drug allergy Peripheral neuropathy Patients who are judged inappropriate for the entry into the study by the investigator</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>