<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02272985</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effect of the hemodialysis procedure on cerebral blood flow (CBF) in elderly maintenance hemodialysis (HD) patients. The investigators hypothesize that HD induced blood pressure changes are associated with a fall in global and/or regional CBF during HD. Second, the investigators hypothesize that near infrared spectroscopy (NIRS) will correlate with CBF measured by[15O]H2O PET.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cerebral Blood Flow During Hemodialysis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The investigators aim to include 14 participants. Each participant will undergo a single HD study session in the PET center of the UMCG. During this study session, each participant will undergo three gated [15O]H2O PET-CT scans before, during (after 20 minutes) and at the end of the HD session. NIRS will be used to measure cerebral tissue regional oxygen saturation (rSO2) during the HD study session. INVOS (In Vivo Optical Spectroscopy), a monitoring device, will be used to measure rSO2, with sensors placed bilaterally on the patient forehead. Participants will further undergo a MRI scan of the brain, bilateral carotid artery duplex echosonography, cognitive testing, blood pressure and heart rate measurements during the HD study session, and laboratory measurements during the HD study session.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Adult, age ≥ 65 years, HD patients who have been treated with maintenance HD, of which at least 6 patients for a longer period of time (&gt;1 year). Patients must have an arteriovenous fistula without recirculation The hemoglobin value must be in the target range (6.2 8mmol/l) since at least 1 month The absence of informed consent Diagnosis of dementia, hydrocephalus, history of raised intracranial pressure, significant (&gt;70%) carotid artery stenosis, endstage liver disease. Actively treated cancer Actual hospital admission at timing of HD study session MRI incompatible implants in the body or any other contraindication for MRI Claustrophobia The refusal to be informed of significant carotid artery stenosis or structural brain abnormalities that could be detected during the study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>cerebral blood flow</keyword>
	<keyword>hemodialysis</keyword>
</DOC>