<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02272452</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main ambition of this project is to develop, and provide the medical community, an innovative method to analyze extemporaneously, during a neurosurgery operation, excised tissues. This method is based on the analysis of the metabolic profile of excised tissues by the technique of High-Resolution Magic-Angle Spinning (HR-MAS) Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) spectroscopy. Indeed HRMAS NMR method can provide in a sufficiently short time lapse (currently about 30 minutes but within our project a time lapse of 15 min or even less is ultimately intended), medical information that can complement those obtained by classic histological examination. Primary purpose: The main objective of this study is to determine the sensitivity of HRMAS NMR spectroscopy in detecting residual tumor infiltration at the brain resection cavity. The investigators aim to determine the relevance of the metabolic analysis compared to histological analysis during a neurosurgery operation. This involves analyzing excised tissue samples, obtained from the operating rooms of Strasbourg University Hospitals, and Colmar Hospital Center, with no return to neurosurgeon for surgery. Secondary purposes: The secondary objectives of the protocol are to investigate the metabolome of different types of brain tumors, in order to find prognostic and diagnostic markers. It consists in detecting metabolomic factors of bad prognosis, and potential marker of good prognosis such as the IDH mutation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Assistance in Neurosurgery (ExtempoRMN)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Male or female Age 18 years of age or older at the time of surgery Primary brain tumors (gliomas mainly) or epilepsy, for which neurosurgical intervention is programmed In the case of brain tumors: primarylesions or transformation of lowgrade gliomas into highgrade gliomas not treated with radiotherapy Affiliated with a social security Having signed the informed consent Having been informed of the results of the medical examination prior Exclusion criteria: Relapse of tumors previously treated with radiotherapy or chemotherapy Subject under treatment (radiotherapy or chemotherapy) prior to surgery Metastatic lesions (location of the primary lesion outside the central nervous system) Inability to give to the subject or his/her family enlightened information (subject in emergency situation, difficulties of understanding...) Subject under judicial protection Subject under guardianship or curatorship Patients' Refusal</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>High resolution magic angle spinning Nuclear magnetic resonance</keyword>
	<keyword>Nuclear magnetic resonance</keyword>
	<keyword>Spectroscopy</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary brain tumors</keyword>
	<keyword>Gliomas</keyword>
	<keyword>extemporaneous analysis</keyword>
</DOC>