<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02207166</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Medical devices are designed and manufactured by subjective design process that was only based on engineers' direct concepts to essential principles sets for the device. A home user may not easily use or operate the piece of medical device through the interfacing components as the designer's expected such as the meaning when pushing a button or switching a knob, even the required procedure needed when a certain display shown to fulfill some knowledge dependent judgment. In addition, the incompatible interfacing designed communication between a user and the device may cause possible errors that may trigger further negative consequences during the use of the device to a innocent home user. The aim of this research is to closely understand the consequent results of human factor engineering or usability engineering practices of various types or models of marketed home-use blood pressure monitors (BPM) in real use.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Identify Possible Errors on Home Use Blood Pressure Monitors by Usability Reasoning</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The aim of this research is to closely understand the consequent results of human factor engineering or usability engineering practices of various types or models of marketed home-use blood pressure monitors (BPM) in real use. Participants of the intended user population interact with marketed BPMs in research to assess ease of learning, ease of use, effectiveness and efficiency of use, memorability, safety, and/or user appeal among the many possible attributes of interest. With these understanding and analysis of human factors engineering / usability engineering (HFE/UE) practiced status, it can help manufacturers to capture the required and diversified HFE/UE essences with the minimum or limited professional technical resources in hand some more efficiently.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
	<criteria>age between 2075 years capable of operating the blood pressure measure machine provided by the study willing to operate the provided device and accept video taping from shoulder and below willing to fill the study questionnaire and to provide feedback after use of the device vulnerable population (including pregnant woman, disabled, etc)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>hypertension</keyword>
	<keyword>device</keyword>
	<keyword>errors</keyword>
	<keyword>human factor engineering</keyword>
	<keyword>usability engineering</keyword>
</DOC>