<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02343445</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of the study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of P-1037 and to determine whether the combination of P-1037 with hypertonic saline or P-1037 alone has a greater effect on lung function in patients with CF than placebo (0.17% saline).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Clearing Lungs With ENAC Inhibition in Cystic Fibrosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female, 12 years of age or older. Diagnosis of cystic fibrosis as determined by the 1997 CF Consensus criteria (NIH Consensus Statement, 1997) Nonsmoker FEV1 at Screening Visit 1 between 40% and 90% Stable regimen of CF medications and chest physiotherapy for the 28 days prior to Screening. Must be willing to discontinue use of hypertonic saline for the duration of the study. Clinically stable for at least 2 weeks All females of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test and if sexually active must agree to practice a highly effective form of contraception throughout the study and for 28 days after the last dose of study medication. History of any organ transplantation or any significant disease or disorder Use of diuretics (including amiloride) or reninangiotensin antihypertensive drugs or trimethoprim in the 28 days prior to Screening History of significant intolerance to inhaled hypertonic saline, as determined by the Investigator Known hypersensitivity to the study drug or amiloride Any clinically significant laboratory abnormalities at Screening Visit 1 as judged by the investigator, or any of the following: Potassium ≥ 5 mEq/L Abnormal renal function Abnormal liver function, defined as ≥ 3 x upper limit of normal (ULN) Hemoglobin level &lt; 10.0 g/dL Female who is pregnant or lactating History of sputum or throat swab culture yielding Burkholderia species or Mycobacterium abscessus within 2 years of screening Has previously participated in an investigational trial involving administration of any investigational compound or use of an investigational device with 28 days prior to Screening Currently being treated with any ivacaftor containing regimen</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>