<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01571193</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In the present study, the investigators will examine and determine whether pomegranate extract benefits cognitive abilities in middle-aged and older non-demented volunteers. More specifically, the investigators will test the following primary hypothesis: 1. Non-demented volunteers aged 50-75 who receive a daily dietary supplement of pomegranate extract will show improved cognitive performance compared to baseline versus those receiving a placebo after one, six, and twelve months. The investigators will also explore the following secondary hypothesis: 2. Cognitive change in the pomegranate intervention group will vary according to genotypes found to influence age-related cognitive decline (i.e., apolipoprotein E [APOE]).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Twelve-Month Study of Pomegranate Extract in Normal Aging</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To test the primary hypothesis, up to 212 non-demented subjects will be enrolled. Subjects will be randomized, using a double-blind design, to one of two treatment groups: supplement (1,000 mg pomegranate extract per day) or placebo, and followed for 12 months. Neuropsychological assessments will determine cognitive change, and be repeated at 1, 6 and 12 months. All subjects will receive a baseline assessment (clinical examination, MRI scan, and screening laboratory tests) in order to exclude volunteers with dementia or other conditions that might influence results. We will draw additional blood for freezing and possible later assessment of inflammatory measures to explore whether pomegranate extract has effects on measures of inflammation. These samples will only be analyzed if we find that the extract shows cognitive benefits.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Agreement to participate in the 12month doubleblind, placebocontrolled clinical trial of pomegranate extract. Nondemented subjects either those with normal cognition or with amnestic Mild Cognitive Impairment will be included. Age 50 to 75 years. No significant cerebrovascular disease: modified Ischemic Score of &lt; 4 (Rosen et al, 1980). Adequate visual and auditory acuity to allow neuropsychological testing. Screening laboratory tests and EKG without significant abnormalities that might interfere with the study. Diagnosis of probable Alzheimer's disease (AD) or any other dementia (e.g., vascular, Lewy body, frontotemporal) (McKhann et al, 1984). Evidence of other neurological or physical illness that can produce cognitive deterioration. Volunteers with a history of stroke, TIA, carotid bruits, or lacunes on MRI scans will be excluded. Determination of dementia will be based on the clinical evaluation including assessment of functional abilities, and cognitive screening. Contraindication to the MRI including claustrophobia, metal in body, surgery within 60 days, certain implants or previous abnormal MRI results. Evidence of Parkinson's disease as determined by the motor examination (items 1831) of the Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale (Fahn et al, 1987). History of myocardial infarction within the previous year, or unstable cardiac disease. Uncontrolled hypertension (systolic BP &gt; 170 or diastolic BP &gt; 100). History of significant liver disease, clinicallysignificant pulmonary disease, diabetes, or cancer. Current diagnosis of any major psychiatric disorder according to the DSMIV TR criteria (APA, 2000). Current diagnosis or history of alcoholism or substance addiction. Regular use of any medication that may affect cognitive functioning including: centrally active betablockers, narcotics, Clonidine, antiParkinsonian medications, antipsychotics, benzodiazepines, systemic corticosteroids, medications with significant cholinergic or anticholinergic effects, anticonvulsants, or Warfarin. Occasional chloral hydrate use will be allowed, but discouraged, for insomnia. Use of more than one multivitamin per day. Vitamins other than the standard multivitamin supplement will not be allowed. Use of cognitive enhancing supplements (e.g. Ginkgo biloba). Use of any medications metabolized by 2C9 including: fluconazole, amiodarone, fenofibrate, fluvastatin, fluvoxamine, isoniazid, lovastatin, phenylbutazone, probenecid, sertraline, sulfamethoxazole, sulfaphenazole teniposide, voriconazole, and zafirlukast. Use of more than one daily baby aspirin (81mg) and/or use of any supplement containing pomegranate. Use of any investigational drugs within the previous month or longer, depending on drug halflife. Pregnancy.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
</DOC>