<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="126038">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01461668</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OCRT10049</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01461668</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Retapamulin for Reducing MRSA Nasal Carriage</brief_title>
  <official_title>Retapamulin for Reducing MRSA Nasal Carriage</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, Irvine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ)</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Irvine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will conduct a randomized placebo-controlled double-blinded study of nasal
      decolonization with retapamulin vs. placebo for the eradication of MRSA nasal carriage among
      adult carriers with low-level (MIC 8-256) and high-level mupirocin resistant (MIC &gt;256)
      strains.

      Objectives:

        1. To determine the percent of intervention vs. control patients with successful MRSA
           nasal decolonization as determined by bilateral nares swabs following a 5-day
           twice-a-day regimen of retapamulin.

        2. To determine the time to decolonization based upon interim and final bilateral nares
           swabs.

        3. To determine the acceptability of retapamulin by surveying participants about their
           experience and adverse events experienced during this study.

      The duration of participant follow-up is expected to last up to 7 weeks.

      This study will evaluate the safety and effectiveness of Altabax (retapmulin) during
      decolonization of MRSA carriers with mupirocin-resistant strains, stratified by low-level
      and high-level resistance to mupirocin. Mupirocin resistance is increasingly common and
      there is no approved substitute topical agent for decolonization of the MRSA nasal
      reservoir.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will evaluate the utility of retapamulin, a topical ointment FDA approved for
      skin infection, as a novel agent for MRSA decolonization and prevention of
      healthcare-associated MRSA infection. Retapamulin is a first-in-class semi-synthetic
      pleuromutilin antibiotic that inhibits protein synthesis by interacting with the bacterial
      ribosome 50S subunit. It received FDA approval in 2007 for the topical treatment of impetigo
      in adults and pediatric patients.

      We propose to evaluate retapamulin as an investigational agent for the nasal decolonization
      of MRSA carriers whose strains demonstrate low-level and high-level resistance to mupirocin.
      Mupirocin resistance is increasingly common and there is no approved substitute topical
      agent for decolonization of the MRSA nasal reservoir.

      We will conduct a randomized placebo-controlled double-blinded study of nasal decolonization
      with retapamulin vs. placebo for the eradication of MRSA nasal carriage among adult carriers
      with low-level (MIC 8-256) and high-level mupirocin resistant (MIC &gt;256) strains.
      Randomization will be stratified by low vs high level resistance.

      Consenting adult (at least 18 years old) subjects will be randomized to 1% retapamulin or
      placebo ointment intra-nasally twice a day for 5 days (D1-5) with follow up bilateral nares
      swab one week following completion of therapy (~D12) to assess clearance. If follow up swabs
      are positive for MRSA, patients will be given a second course of the same agent (retapamulin
      or placebo) to begin one week following swab collection (~D19-23) so that up to two
      decolonization attempts will be made. A final set of bilateral nares swabs will be obtained
      from all subjects six weeks from the completion of initial treatment (~D47).

      Consenting adult (at least 18 years old)subjects will be given retapamulin or placebo. At
      the time of recruitment, all subjects will complete a detailed survey administered by
      trained research staff. This survey will include questions related to self care, home
      hygiene practices, and known risk factors for MRSA acquisition. Subject follow up will
      include repeat bilateral nares swabs and follow up surveys related to compliance, experience
      (side effects/concerns) with the assigned regimen, and ongoing risk factors will occur
      either during a home visit (or facility visit if the patient is admitted to a hospital or
      nursing home at the time of the required visit) or at the University of California Irvine
      (UCI) Institute for Clinical and Translational Science (ICTS), a Clinical and Translational
      Science Award (CTSA) site which provides clinic visit support for pilot studies.

      Outcomes will include successful nares decolonization at the end of the follow up period
      (D47). We will detail the sequence of clearance or re-colonization based upon the two follow
      up nares swabs, as well as any adverse events, which are expected to be related to local
      irritation in a small percent of subjects.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to MRSA clearance</measure>
    <time_frame>47 days</time_frame>
    <description>Successful nares decolonization at the end of the follow up period</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Methicillin-Resistant Staphylococcus Aureus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Retapamulin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will be instructed to complete a decolonization regimen that will involve a 5-day application of retapamulin with follow up bilateral nares swab one week following completion of therapy (~D12) to assess clearance. If follow up swabs are positive for MRSA, patients will be given a second course of the same agent (retapamulin) to begin one week following swab collection (~D19-23) so that up to two decolonization attempts will be made. A final set of bilateral nares swabs will be obtained from all subjects six weeks from the completion of initial treatment (~D47).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will be instructed to complete a decolonization regimen that will involve a 5-day application of a placebo with follow up bilateral nares swab one week following completion of therapy (~D12) to assess clearance. If follow up swabs are positive for MRSA, patients will be given a second course of the same agent (placebo) to begin one week following swab collection (~D19-23) so that up to two decolonization attempts will be made. A final set of bilateral nares swabs will be obtained from all subjects six weeks from the completion of initial treatment (~D47).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Retapamulin</intervention_name>
    <description>Two times a day for 5 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Retapamulin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Altabax</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Two times a day for 5 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  18 years of age or older

          -  Have a type of MRSA that is resistant to mupirocin (a drug used to treat MRSA)

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Allergic to retapamulin

          -  Unable to use retapamulin via your nose (i.e. nose surgery, etc.)

          -  Are pregnant and/or breastfeeding
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Susan Huang, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, Irivne - School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, Irivne</name>
      <address>
        <city>Irvine</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92617</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>October 25, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>October 26, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, Irvine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Susan Huang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of Epidemiology and Infection Prevention</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>MRSA</keyword>
  <keyword>MRSA resistant to mupirocin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Staphylococcal Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
