<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02280278</DOC>
	<brief_summary>We hypothesize through this randomized, prospective, single center adjuvant study, that cytokine-induced killer cell in patients with stage III colon cancer can improve survival in this patient population over control. Stage III colon cancer patients can benefit most from adjuvant chemotherapy, but the 5 year survival rate is still around 60%. We wish CIK cell therapy can improve the survival rate of stage III colon cancer patients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Cytokine-induced Killer Cell Immunotherapy for Surgical Resected Stage III Colorectal Cancer Patients After Chemotherapy</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Colonic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female outpatient of ≥ 18 years of age or ≥ country's legal age for adult consent Stage III colon cancer undergone complete resection of primary tumor Completed standard adjuvant chemotherapy within 120 days of completion of standard therapy ECOG performancer status 02 Satisfactory haematological or biochemical functions (tests should be carried out within 8 weeks prior to randomisation): Results of clinical investigations carried out within 8 weeks prior to randomisation can be used in place of the required screening investigations. Patients with mild laboratory abnormalities can be included at the discretion by the site principal investigator, and after approval by ASCOLT Trial Management Group ANC ≥ 1.0 x 109/L Platelets ≥ 100 x 109/L Creatinine clearance ≥ 30 mL/min Total bilirubin ≤ 2.0 x the upper limit normal AST &amp; ALT ≤ 5 x the upper limit normal Completed the following investigations Completed the following investigations HIV positive or other Immunodeficiency disease recently use of high dose glucocorticoid Uncontrolled hypertension (untreated systolic blood pressure &gt; 160 mmHg, or diastolic blood pressure &gt; 95 mmHg) History of recent cancers (except for colorectal cancers, nonmelanoma skin cancers, basal cell carcinomas, squamous cell carcinomas) in the past 5 years Patient having known allergy to capecitabine or Oxaliplatin Pregnant, lactating</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>colon cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>cytokine-induced killer cell immunotherapy</keyword>
</DOC>