<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01423708</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Safety and Efficacy of Everolimus in adult de novo liver transplant recipients.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Everolimus in de Novo Liver Transplantation: a Multicentre Randomized Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This prospective study was designed to evaluate the feasibility and effectiveness of the use of Everolimus in the minimization and possible suspension of calcineurin inhibitors in adult liver transplant patients. The study will take into account a control group (standard immunosuppression with tacrolimus and steroids) after induction with anti-IL2 Antibodies.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Failure</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male or female patients between 18 and 70 years of age, Patients undergoing de novo liver transplantation from cadaveric donor with a functional graft at the time of randomization, Transplantation from cadaveric donor whole or split liver, Patients able to communicate properly with the study investigators, to understand and respond to the needs of the protocol and who have given written consent Cold ischemia time &lt;12 hours Physical or laboratory abnormalities or mental illness within 2 weeks before randomization such that, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with participation in the study Women who are pregnant (positive test with hCG values&gt; 5mUI/ml) or breastfeeding Women of childbearing potential, with the following exceptions: a) women in menopause (spontaneous amenorrhea for at least 12 months, spontaneous amenorrhea for at least 6 months with FSH levels &gt;40 mIU/ml, surgical bilateral oophorectomy at least 6 weeks before baseline, with or without hysterectomy) b) women who use one or more reliable and approved methods of contraception for the duration of the study and for the three months following discontinuation of study treatment. Patients who undergo transplantation or multivisceral transplantation of pancreatic islets, or who have previously undergone organ transplantation or tissue. Patients who undergo combined liverkidney transplantation Patients who undergo living donor liver transplantation Patients who undergo ABOincompatible liver transplantation Patients who undergo transplantation from donors positive for HBV surface antigen or HIV History of malignant disease at any site in the 3 year period prior, regardless of whether or not there is evidence of recurrence or metastasis. (Except nonmetastatic skin cancers such as basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, or hepatocellular carcinoma) Patients receiving other investigational drugs within 4 weeks before baseline or who are currently enrolled in other clinical trials Patients who show hypersensitivity to the drug (or drugs similar to Everolimus Former macrolides) or class or pharmaceutical excipients. Also, when there are contraindications A history of coagulopathy or the presence of any medical condition that requires longterm anticoagulant therapy after transplantation (The use of lowdose ASA is admissible) Platelet count &lt;=40.000/mm3 or WBC count &lt;2000/mm3 or hemoglobin &lt;=7g/dl at the time of randomization Severe systemic infections High cholesterol levels (&gt;350mg/dl) or severe hypertriglyceridemia (&gt;500mg/dl). Patients with compensated hyperlipidemia are eligible. Diagnosis of pretransplant autoimmune liver disease (PBC, sclerosing cholangitis) Acute Liver Failure</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Liver Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Graft Rejection</keyword>
	<keyword>Graft Survival</keyword>
	<keyword>Transplantation Immunology</keyword>
	<keyword>Anti-Rejection Therapy</keyword>
	<keyword>Immunosuppression</keyword>
	<keyword>Organ Transplantation</keyword>
	<keyword>Host vs Graft Reaction</keyword>
	<keyword>Gastroenterology</keyword>
	<keyword>Hepatology</keyword>
</DOC>