<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00689364</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Comprehensive therapy of traditional Chinese medicine (CTTCM) could relieve risk of recurrence and metastasis for stage II &amp; III colorectal cancer, the investigators take this clinical trial with retrospective-prospective cohort study based on previous studies by international multi-center way. If the study shows a positive result, a pragmatic randomized controlled study with prospective, multi-centre and large-sample design will be given continuously. The aim is to establish recommended programs suggested by CTTCM strategies under conventional Western medicine therapy (CWMT) for stage II &amp; III colorectal cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comprehensive Therapy to Relieving the Risk of Recurrence and Metastasis for Colorectal Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>CTTCM: taking TCM decoction based on syndrome differentiation daily and each dosage is decocted two times for intervention one year with a Chinese patent medicine at least. CWMT: with or without chemotherapy/or radiotherapy after the radical operation (R0) (according to the latest NCCN clinical guideline).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patient who is diagnosed colorectal cancer by patho&amp; cytologic diagnosis since accepting radical operation within half a year. Stage II or III colorectal cancer. 18－75 yr. Being able to participate and sign the informed consent. Pregnant woman, Psychotic. Patient who put together with other cancer. Existed serious complaint and functional disturbance (impairment) with nontumorous in archorgan. Reactiveness cerebrovascular disease (CVD) . Uncontrolled infection and metabolic disease. One item of tumor marks is progressed, and it still is progressed when patient recheck. Tumor that it is neooccurred in each organ or pelvic cavity or abdominal cavity without definite pathoquality.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cohort Study</keyword>
	<keyword>Colorectal Cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Traditional Chinese Medicine</keyword>
	<keyword>Risk of recurrence and metastasis</keyword>
</DOC>