<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02431325</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this research study is to determine whether teduglutide can repair a "leaky" gut, decrease inflammation, and prevent or treat plaque, a build-up of fat and other materials in the blood vessels of the heart, in people with HIV. HIV disease is linked to inflammatory changes and leakiness of the gut. These changes or conditions may increase the risk of developing heart and blood vessel disease. The investigators believe teduglutide can help repair the gut barrier in people with HIV, leading to a decrease in inflammation and plaque in the blood vessels of the heart.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of the Gut Barrier and Blood Vessel Inflammation in Individuals With and Without HIV</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>As more people with HIV gain access to combination antiretroviral therapy (cART), cardiovascular disease has become increasingly prevalent and a significant cause of mortality. Activation of the innate immune system may stimulate inflammatory mechanisms of atherosclerosis development. Loss of gastrointestinal (GI) mucosal epithelial integrity and loss of CD4+ T-lymphocytes in the intestinal lamina propria occur in HIV-infected patients and are not fully restored by cART. Translocation of microbial products from the intestinal lumen into the systemic circulation has been demonstrated to be increased in HIV-infected patients and the investigators hypothesize that it is a key driver of monocyte and macrophage activation. In turn, these pro-inflammatory monocytes and macrophages can induce atherosclerotic disease development. The purpose of the research study is to determine the effects of a glucagon-like peptide-2 analog, teduglutide, on intestinal epithelial integrity, microbial translocation across the gut lumen, markers of innate immune system activation including the monocyte transcriptome, bone, arterial inflammation, and atherosclerosis in a 6-month randomized, double-blind placebo-controlled proof of concept trial in HIV-infected individuals.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Men and women age 2165 with previously diagnosed HIV disease 2. Stable antiretroviral therapy (ART) as defined by no changes in ART regimen for &gt;6 months 3. HIV viral load &lt; 200 copies/mL 4. To be eligible for colonoscopy procedure, laboratory values that meet the following criteria: 1. Hemoglobin &gt; 9.0 g/dL 2. Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1000/mm3 3. Platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm3 4. Prothrombin time (PT) &lt; 1.2 x upper limit of normal (ULN) 5. Partial thromboplastin time (PTT) &lt; 1.5 x ULN 4. Ability and willingness to give written informed consent and to comply with study requirements 1. History of clinically significant gastrointestinal disease including but not limited to: colon cancer, intestinal obstruction, ulcerative colitis, Crohn's disease, or history of C. difficile within the past 3 months 2. Firstdegree relative with history of colon cancer 3. Active gall bladder, biliary or pancreatic disease 4. Female subject who is pregnant, nursing or less than 8 weeks post partum. 5. Use of any immunomodulatory agents within 30 days prior to study enrollment 6. History of intolerance, sensitivity, allergy or anaphylaxis to benzodiazepines or other narcotics to be used during the colonoscopy or upper endoscopy procedure 7. Contraindication to betablocker (including moderate to severe asthma or heart block) or nitroglycerin use as these drugs are given as part of the standard cardiac CT protocol. Previous allergic reaction to beta blocker or nitroglycerin. 8. Patients with previous allergic reactions to iodinecontaining contrast media 9. Renal disease or creatinine &gt;1.5 mg/dL (contrast will be administered during CT angiography of the heart) 10. History of requiring antibiotic prophylaxis for invasive procedures 11. History of myocardial infarction, decompensated cirrhosis, or any other condition that in the opinion of the investigator will compromise ability to participate in the study 12. Currently taking anticoagulants including but not limited to: heparin (HepLock, HepPak), HepPak CVC, Heparin Lock Flush), warfarin (Coumadin), tinzaparin (Innohep), enoxaparin (Lovenox), danaparoid (Orgaran), dalteparin (Fragmin), clopidogrel (Plavix), prophylactic aspirin, and regular NSAID use 13. Subject taking any of the following medications: statins, systemic steroids (inhaled or nasal steroid therapy is permitted), interleukins, systemic interferons (e.g. local injection of interferon alpha for treatment of HPV is permitted), systemic chemotherapy including oral chemotherapeutic agents, methotrexate, octreotide, growth hormone, antiarrhythmics including digoxin, antiepileptics, immunosuppressants, vancomycin, rifampin, aminoglycosides, clonidine, prazosin, lithium and ritonavirboosted lopinavir (Kaletra). 14. Subject has had two or more endoscopy procedures (sigmoidoscopy, upper endoscopy or colonoscopy) within the past 12 months for clinical purposes or other research studies. 15. Body weight greater than 300 lbs due to CT scanner table limitations 16. Active illicit drug use 17. Patients who report any significant radiation exposure over the course of the year prior to randomization. Significant exposure is defined as: 1. More than 2 percutaneous coronary interventions (PCI) within 12 months of randomization 2. More than 2 myocardial perfusion studies within the past 12 months 3. More than 2 CT angiograms within the past 12 months 4. Any subjects with history of radiation therapy 18. Patients already scheduled or being considered for a procedure or treatment 1. requiring significant radiation exposure (e.g., radiation therapy, PCI, or catheter 2. ablation of arrhythmia) within 12 months of randomization 19. History of malignancy 20. Prior recipient of a HIV vaccine</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>Atherosclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Microbial Translocation</keyword>
	<keyword>Teduglutide</keyword>
	<keyword>Gastrointestinal Permeability</keyword>
	<keyword>Inflammation</keyword>
</DOC>