<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02431845</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether pharmacogenetic study predict selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor (SSRI) responsiveness in advance before the appearance of the drug effect until 4 months(16 weeks), 6 months, and 1 year after administration of SSRIs.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pharmacogenetic Study of Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to determine the effects of genetic variants on the response to SSRIs in obsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) subject. The investigators will recruit drug-naive or drug-free(&gt; 3 months) OCD subjects (n=200). The participants will get SSRIs for their OCD symptoms. The type and dose of SSRIs will not be restricted and will depend on the individual participant's state. However, the investigators will be recommended to follow usual clinical guideline (the Korean treatment algorithm for OCD, 2004). At baseline, 4 month, 6 months, and 1 year after treatment, the participants will be evaluated by Yale-Brown Obsessive-Compulsive Scale(YBOCS), Montgomery Asberg Depression Rating Scale(MADRS), Dimensional Obsessive-Compulsive Scale(DOCS), Toronto alexithymia scale (TAS), interpersonal reactivity index (IRI), Barratt impulsiveness scale (BIS), and the Measure of Constructs Underlying Perfectionism(M-CUP). And all the participants will donate 5 ml of whole blood and DNA will be extracted. Using various genetic analyses methods such as genotyping, exome sequencing, and so on we will analyze the association of various genetic variants and the anti-obsessive-compulsive responses.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Compulsive Behavior</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fluoxetine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. age 19~ 60 2. OCD by Diagnostic and Statistical Manual for Mental disorders, 4th edition (DSMIV) 3. drug naive or drug free for more than 3 months 1. any neurological disorder 2. comorbid psychotic disorders 3. alcohol or other substance dependence within past 6 months 4. any evidences for brain diseases</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Pharmacogenetics</keyword>
</DOC>