<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02431195</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The main objective of this study is to identify changes in eating behaviors and physical activity in patients after bariatric surgery and their family members living in same household: children aged between 11-17 years, spouse, parents, cohabitee or partner in a civil union.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Analysis of Changes in Eating Habits on Post Bariatric Surgery Patients and Their Family Members</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>As secondary objectives, the study aims to: - Describe the sociodemographic and clinical characteristics of post bariatric surgery patients. - Assess changes in quality of life of the post-surgery patients. - Explain changes of post-surgery in eating behavior and activity varied according to gender - Explain changes of post-surgery in eating behavior and activity varied according to socio-economic conditions - Explain changes of post-surgery in eating behavior and activity varied according to inter-generational relation - Have a overview on the surgery as a turning point in the life of patients - Estimate the relevant message of cares given to patients, in order to better adjust medical intervention, in conjunction with patients and their family members. This is a prospective observational study. It will be performed in two university hospitals: CHU Ambroise Paré at Boulogne-Billancourt city and CHU Pitié Salpétrière at Paris, in nutrition department and metabolic surgery department. The study will involve collaboration of a team of social researchers.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Aged ≥ 18 years Eligible to undergo bariatric surgery Post bariatric surgery followup visits will take place in the nutrition department Living together with family member (children aged 1117 years, parents, spouse, cohabitee or partner in civil union) Informed consent signed Higherorder cognitive disorders Language difficulties in understanding Living alone or living without any family member</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>obesity</keyword>
	<keyword>bariatric surgery</keyword>
	<keyword>physical activity</keyword>
	<keyword>eating habits</keyword>
</DOC>