<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00879203</DOC>
	<brief_summary>LO5 study: The investigators are inviting a new group of youth (ages 7-16) who have been recently diagnosed with type 1 diabetes and their non-diabetic siblings. These youth will complete cognitive tests and a MRI scan of the brain. This scan uses strong magnets to obtain pictures and does not involve any radiation or injections. The investigators will recruit patients within three months of their diagnosis date. The study entails 1 study visit that lasts 3.5 hours. Evening and weekend times are available. The investigators plan to enroll 135 participants. HY5 study: The investigators are inviting a cohort of youth and young adults (ages 9-21) with type 1 diabetes and their non-diabetic siblings for a follow-up to a study they have already completed. This group of people will complete several memory and thinking tests along with several MRI scans of their brain, just as they did at their previous visits. The investigators plan to enroll 150 participants.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Glycemic Control, Brain Structure and Cognition in Youth With Type 1 Diabetes (T1DM)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>LO5: Inclusion Criteria for Participants with Type 1 Diabetes: Between the ages of 7 and 16 Diagnosed with type 1 diabetes within 3 months Inclusion Criteria for Participants without Type 1 Diabetes: Between the ages of 7 and 16 Exclusion Criteria for Participants with Type 1 Diabetes: Pregnant or lactating Chronic disease other than T1DM, wellcontrolled asthma, or Hashimoto's thyroiditis Other current serious medical illness Psychiatric illness Psychoactive drug dependence Neurological illness (except T1DMrelated): stroke, seizure, major loss of consciousness, head injuries, encephalitis, or hydrocephalus, blindness, deafness Use of psychoactive medications or exposure to neuroleptics (except that exposures of less than 1 month, occurring more than 5 years ago, will be allowed) Use of dopamine depleting agents or stimulants such as Ritalin, Cylert, Adderall Prematurity at birth of more than 4 wks early with complications (e.g. on respirator at NICU) Inability to complete MRI scan (e.g. claustrophobia, metal implants) Full set (top and bottom) of orthodontic braces (Half set braces, fillings, and retainers are OK) Exclusion Criteria for Participants without Type 1 Diabetes: Same as above (except cannot have type 1 diabetes) HY5: Must have been a participant in our earlier study.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Type 1 Diabetes Mellitis</keyword>
	<keyword>Youth</keyword>
	<keyword>Hypoglycemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Hyperglycemia</keyword>
	<keyword>Cognition</keyword>
	<keyword>Memory</keyword>
	<keyword>Brain Growth &amp; Development</keyword>
	<keyword>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</keyword>
</DOC>