<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00748098</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the efficacy and safety of GSK1838262 extended release tablets in the treatment of patients with Restless Legs Syndrome and associated sleep disturbance.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Polysomnography Study of GSK1838262 Extended Release Tablets Versus Placebo in RLS and Associated Sleep Disturbance</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Double-blind, multi-center, placebo-controlled, 2-period crossover study which assessed the efficacy and safety of gabapentin enacarbil (GEn; GSK1838262; XP13512) extended release tablets in adults with Restless Legs Syndrome (RLS)-associated sleep disturbance. One hundred thirty-six (136) adult subjects with RLS-associated sleep disturbance and periodic limb movements (PLM) were randomized from 23 centers in the United States. Subjects who met all eligibility criteria were randomized to receive a treatment sequence of GEn:placebo or placebo:GEn. Investigational product was taken with food at approximately 5pm. Investigational product was dosed as 600mg/day x3 days followed by 1200mg/day x25 days for each 4-week treatment period. There was a 1-week taper at 600mg after each treatment period followed by a 1-week washout between treatments. Polysomnography (PSG) was used to objectively evaluate changes in sleep and PLMs.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Psychomotor Agitation</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Restless Legs Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dyssomnias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gabapentin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>gamma-Aminobutyric Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Provided written informed consent. Diagnosed with primary RLS using the International RLS Study Group Diagnostic Criteria with a total score of 15 or greater on the International RLS (IRLS) Rating Scale and significant sleep disturbance indicated on Item 4 of the IRLS rating scale. Have history of RLS symptoms at least 15 nights/month. Minimum average of 15 Periodic Limb Movements during Sleep per hour (measured using actigraphy). Exclusion criteria: Secondary RLS Primary sleep disorder Sleep apnea Have any medical conditions that may impact efficacy assessments or that may present a safety concern. Pregnant or lactating or women of childbearing potential who are not practicing an acceptable method of birth control. Use of any prohibited medication.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>PSG</keyword>
	<keyword>Restless Legs Syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>gabapentin enacarbil</keyword>
	<keyword>XP13512</keyword>
	<keyword>GSK1838262</keyword>
	<keyword>sleep disturbance</keyword>
	<keyword>RLS</keyword>
	<keyword>polysomnography</keyword>
</DOC>