<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00748618</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Vitamin D deficiency accelerates vascular risk progression after kidney transplant.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vitamin D Replacement After Kidney Transplant</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This trial will assess the following aims: 1. Time to plateau vitamin D concentrations after initiating vitamin D supplements 2. Safety of vitamin D replacement based on serum and urine calcium 3. Effect of vitamin D on PTH concentration in individuals with elevated parathyroid hormone 4. Effect of vitamin D on markers of insulin resistance and inflammation</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Kidney transplant more than 6 months ago 19 years or older 25OH vitamin D ≤30 ng/ml Estimated GFR&lt;30 ml/min/1.73m² Previous small bowel or lung transplant Pancreas transplant less than 6 months ago Cancer or any condition that would change their weight dramatically in the near future such as malabsorption Willing to return for testing every two months Women who are pregnant or &lt; 6 weeks postpartum Calcium &gt; 10.5 mg/dl Phosphate &gt; 4.8 mg/dl Taking 10,000 I.U. or more of vitamin D per week Drinking more than 2 alcohol drinks a day or 14 drinks per week History of parathyroid surgery Known granulomatous disease Magnesium &lt; 1.6 mg/dL Taking any seizure medication that affects vitamin D Taking zempler ® and/or Rocaltrol ® History of kidney stones Not on a stable dose of bisphosphonate for the past three months Planning on a pancreas transplant within the next year In any other research study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>Kidney transplantation (KTX)</keyword>
	<keyword>Vitamin D deficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular Disease (CVD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Vascular risk</keyword>
	<keyword>Parathyroid hormone (PTH)</keyword>
	<keyword>Carotid intima media thickness (CIMT)</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin resistance (IR)</keyword>
</DOC>