<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01187992</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study was designed to test the hypothesis that the addition of full-dose atorvastatin (80 mg/day) to conventional medical treatment could reduce ischaemic recurrences after non-ST-elevation acute myocardial infarction (NSTE-AMI) in patients with severe and diffuse coronary artery disease (CAD) not amenable to any form of mechanical revascularisation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Full-dose Atorvastatin After Acute Coronary Syndrome (ACS) in Non-revascularisable Coronary Artery Disease</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Atorvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
	<criteria>nonSTsegment elevation acute myocardial infarction. coronary angiography within 48 hours from admission. angiographic evidence of severe and diffuse coronary artery disease,not amenable to conventional direct revascularisation techniques by coronary artery bypass graft (CABG) or percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI). STsegment elevation acute myocardial infarction, clinical history of heart failure left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;35%, any form of severe valvular dysfunction, previous implantation or indication to implant a cardioverterdefibrillator during the index admission, any increase in liver enzymes, history of any liver or muscle disease, renal failure with serum creatinine &gt;2.5 mg/dL (221 mmol/L), need for continued use of intravenous medications to relieve anginal symptoms, presence of any major comorbidity with life expectancy &lt;24 months.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Atorvastatin</keyword>
	<keyword>Acute coronary syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Advanced coronary artery disease</keyword>
</DOC>