<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02892227</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Our hypothesis: a daily bedside echocardiographic assessment, protocolized, simple and, filling pressures with an evaluation of mitral inflow and the inferior vena cava, allow a more reliable estimate of the true blood volume the patient and thus lead to a therapeutic adjustment more suitable. This therapeutic adjustment closer to patient's needs would impact fewer readmissions at 30 days and mortality, less alteration of biological parameters myocardial, kidney and liver.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Management of Acute Heart Failure: Contribution of Ultrasound Daily "in Bed Patient" Adjustment on Therapy With Impact Measure on re Hospital Rate During 30 Days</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient or his representative must be given free and informed consent and signed consent. The patient must be affiliated or beneficiary of a health insurance plan. The patient is available for a followup 6 months. The patient is of age or older (&gt;) 18. Patients hospitalized for acute heart failure who received at least 40mg of furosemide IV. Patient with impaired LVEF &lt;50%. Patient with NtproBNP values&gt; 1200pg / ml. The subject takes part in another study. The subject is exclusion period determined by a previous study. The subject is under judicial protection. The subject or his representative refuses to sign the consent. It is not possible to give the subject or his representative informed information. Noninclusion criteria for those diseases or conditions associated (s) interfere (s): The patient is pregnant or is breastfeeding. The patient is already included in a surveillance program (PRADO, OSICAT). Patient with a mechanical or biological mitral prosthesis. History of mitral stenosis. severe valvular surgery with maturity in months (&lt;30 days). chronic renal impairment on dialysis. High grade AV block (AVB and BAV3 2/1). Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy. Cardiogenic shock. Contraindications to furosemide.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>bedside echography</keyword>
</DOC>