<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01880723</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Our aims were to determine if exhaled breath condensate (EBC) could detect differences in ion regulation between cystic fibrosis (CF) and healthy and measure the effect of the albuterol on EBC ions in these populations. We hypothesized EBC chloride and sodium would be lower in CF patients at baseline and that albuterol would decrease EBC sodium and increase EBC chloride.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Utilizing Exhaled Breathe Condensate Collection to Study Ion Regulation in Cystic Fibrosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albuterol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Healthy subjects: no cardiovascular abnormalities not overweight BMI&gt;25 1855 years of age CF subjects: mild to moderate CF (FEV1&gt;40% predicted) clinically diagnosed with positive sweat test (sweat Cl&gt;60mmol/L) 1055 years of age clinically stable Healthy subjects will be excluded if: If unable to consent for him/herself (cognitive impairment) Have a history or evidence of cardiovascular and/or pulmonary abnormalities. Have an abnormal 12lead EKG Have an abnormal pulmonary function test Have a history of asthma Have a history of renal disease or estimated creatinine clearance &lt; 55ml/min Women who are pregnant or planning to become pregnant during the study CF subjects: If unable to consent for him/herself (cognitive impairment) Physically unable to perform exercise or breathing tests Have a history of renal disease or estimated creatinine clearance &lt; 55ml/min Women who are pregnant or planning to become pregnant during the study. Have an abnormal 12lead EKG Cystic Fibrosis related diabetes is uncontrolled Forced Expiratory Volume after 1 second (FEV1) is less than 40% predicted Have a history of joint disease Have history of pulmonary exacerbation within the last two weeks Experienced pulmonary hemorrhage within 6 months resulting in greater than 50cc of blood in the sputum not currently enrolled in any other research study</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>exhaled breath condensate</keyword>
	<keyword>diffusion capacity of the lungs for carbon monoxide and nitric oxide</keyword>
	<keyword>albuterol</keyword>
	<keyword>peripheral oxygen saturation</keyword>
	<keyword>ion regulation</keyword>
</DOC>