<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01880515</DOC>
	<brief_summary>1. Advanced NSCLC have a poor prognosis and the positive impact of chemotherapy is limited by the development of intrinsic and acquired resistance. 2. Over the past decade, less toxic agents such as the innovative targeted therapies, i.e. erlotinib or gefitinib, have the potential to improve the effectiveness and keep a good quality of life with a low toxicity 3. BIBW 2992, an aniline-quinazoline, is an EGFR and HER-2 irreversible inhibitor, and it has activity against erlotinib-resistant isoforms having mutations in EGFR and HER-2 4. This molecule have shown benefits as a single agent in pre-treated patients who have progressed despite platinum-based chemotherapy, with a minimal toxicity compared to chemotherapy 5. BIBW 2992 is associated with adverse effects similar to those for erlotinib and gefitinib, such as rash and diarrhea. These symptoms can reduce the quality of life in patients and lead to inconsistent EGFR inhibitor dose administration 6. There is no a standard treatment for rash, but case reports have tried to demonstrate the benefit obtained with alcohol-free emollients, sunscreen with titanium dioxide or antibiotic (topic or oral) treatment such as clindamycin or doxycycline, anti-inflammatory drugs such as steroids and isotretinoin in the treatment of these cutaneous injuries. 7. In order to reduce the incidence and severity of cutaneous toxicities, we will compare the prophylactic antibiotic treatment using tetracycline and general dermatological recommendations versus using only dermatological recommendations, in patients initiating the treatment with BIBW 2992</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tetracycline as a Prophylaxis for Rash in Patients With NSCLC Receiving Treatment With BIBW 2992</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Case reports have tried to demonstrate the benefit obtained with alcohol-free emollients used 2-3 times daily, sunscreen with titanium dioxide or zinc oxide with a SPF greater than 15, antibiotic (topic or oral) treatment (such as clindamycin, metronidazole, tetracyclines) secondary to infection and steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (betamethasone, triamcinolone) and isotretinoin in the treatment of these cutaneous injuries. The objective for this project is to evaluate whether prophylactic treatment with tetracycline can reduce dermatological occurrences such as rash, induced by EGFR and HER-2 tyrosine kinase inhibitor BIBW 2992 in patients with non-small cell lung cancer, and improve the patient's quality of life.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Exanthema</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tetracycline</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dermatologic Agents</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Diagnosis of nonoperable, locally advanced, recurrent or metastatic, histologically or cytologically documented nonsmall cell lung cancer (stage IIIB or IV). Patients should have an evidence of measurable disease. 18 years or older ECOG performance status 03 At least 12 weeks of life expectancy Patients with nonsmall cell lung cancer stages IIIB/IV who have received at least one cycle of platinumbased, first or second line systemic standard chemotherapy, and have a documented failure for this treatment. More than 2 previous chemotherapy regimens are not allowed. The patients should have recovered from any toxic effect and at least 2 weeks should have elapsed from last dose before their entry (14 days for vinorelbine and other vinca alkaloids or gemcitabine). Patients who in the investigator's opinion are fully recovered from surgery for at least 4 weeks may also be considered for the study. Patients should have recovered from any severe toxicity (CTC &gt; 1) caused by any previous therapy. Granulocyte count &gt; 1.5x 109/L and platelet count &gt; 100x 109/L. Serum bilirubin &gt; 1.5 upper limit normal (ULN) AST and/or ALT &gt; 2 ULN (or &gt;5 x ULN when clearly attributable to presence of hepatic metastases). Serum creatinine &gt; 1.5 ULN or creatinine clearance &lt; 60 mL/min Capability to fulfill the study and followup procedures. A negative pregnancy test should be obtained from all women of childbearing potential within 72 hours previous to therapy beginning. Patients of reproductive potential should use effective contraceptive methods. Written (signed) informed consent to participate in the study Patients allergic to the antibiotic therapy used. Any unsteady systemic disease (including active infection, hypertension grade unsteady angina, congestive cardiac failure, hepatic, renal or metabolic disease). A previous treatment using a systemic antitumor therapy with EGFR inhibitors (tyrosine kinase inhibitors). Any other malignant pathology within 5 previous years (except for carcinoma in situ of cervix or basalcell type skin cancer appropriately treated). Patients with cerebral metastases or spinal marrow compression recently diagnosed and/or definitely surgery and/or radiation naïvetreatment patients are excluded. Those with previously diagnosed and treated metastasis to CNS or spinal marrow compression, having an evidence of steady disease (clinically steady in imaging studies) are accepted for at least 2 months. Any significant ophthalmologic abnormality, especially severe dryeye syndrome, keratoconjunctivitis sicca, Sjögren's syndrome, severe exposure keratitis and any other disorder that may increase the risk for corneal epithelial injure. Contact lens use during the study is not recommended. The decision to continue to use contact lens should be discussed with the oncologist responsible for patient treatment and the ophthalmologist. Patients who cannot take oral medication, requiring intravenous nutrition, who underwent previous surgical procedures affecting absorption, or with active peptic ulcer. Nursing women.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>BIBW 2992</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Rash</keyword>
	<keyword>Tetracycline</keyword>
</DOC>