<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00140790</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to investigate if an angiotensin II receptor blocker, valsartan 160 mg/day is more effective to reduce the incidence of cardiovascular events as compared to 40 mg/day in patients with moderate renal dysfunction.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Valsartan in Cardiovascular Disease With Renal Dysfunction (The V-CARD) Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>It is well known that patients with renal dysfunction have a poor prognosis concerning cardiovascular diseases. That is called "cardiorenal syndrome". It was reported that valsartan was effective in reducing the urine albumin extraction rate in patients with hyper- or normotension. We hypothesized that valsartan was more effective to prevent cardiovascular events by the intermediary of improving renal function. The primary endpoints are: - cardiovascular events (cardiac death, non-fatal myocardial infarction, unstable angina requiring rehospitalization, congestive heart failure requiring rehospitalization, revascularization procedures including coronary angioplasty or coronary artery bypass grafting;Stroke or transient ischaemic attack, dissociation aneurysm of the aorta needing hospitalisation;Lower limbs artery obstruction needing hospitalisation . - end-stage renal dysfunction (introduction of hemodialysis or kidney transplantation) - 50% reduction of creatinine clearance The secondary endpoints are: - systolic and diastolic function of the left ventricle estimated by echocardiography (% FS and E/A ratio) - specific biochemical markers for cardiac or renal function (urine microalbumin, plasma B-type natriuretic peptide, plasma type 1 plasminogen activator inhibitor, plasma cystatin C) - % changes of creatinine clearance between start and end of the study period - transition of 1/(serum Cr) in patients whose u-prot/u-Cr is equal to or more than 1.0 - transition of serum K - HbA1c - New onset Atrial Fibrillation - New onset Diabetes</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Valsartan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria (all required): Systolic blood pressure (SBP) &gt;/= 140 and/or diastolic blood pressure (DBP) &gt;/= 90 (untreated hypertension cases); or SBP&gt;/=130 and/or DBP&gt;/=80 (treated hypertension cases) Patients with coronary artery disease (more than 50% stenosis on coronary angiography [CAG], coronary computed tomography [CT] or coronary magnetic resonance angiography [MRA]; coronary spasm; or history of percutaneous coronary intervention [PCI]);Unstable angina patient Creatinine clearance between 30.0 and 89.9 ml/min Exclusion Criteria (at least one of following): Reduced left ventricular (LV) function (ejection fraction [EF] equal to or less than 40%) Hyperpotassemia (serum potassium equal to or more than 5.5 mEq/l) Rapid progressive glomerular nephritis Nephrotic syndrome Renal artery stenosis Uncontrolled diabetes (HbA1c equal to or more than 9.0%) History of allergy to valsartan Pregnant women</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cardiorenal syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>Renal dysfunction</keyword>
	<keyword>Cardiovascular events</keyword>
	<keyword>Valsartan</keyword>
</DOC>