<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00553397</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The use of live donors for solid organ transplantation has increased the number of available organs for those waiting for a transplant. Donation of an organ may have significant effects on a donor's health. This study will determine the baseline characteristics, early postoperative morbidity, and long-term survival for participants who underwent donor lobectomy between 1993 and 2006.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Live Lung Donor Retrospective Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>As the number of patients requiring organ transplants continues to increase, the number of organs available from deceased donors cannot meet demands. Beginning in the early 1990s, organs from living donors became a widely-available option, increasing the number of available organs for transplant. However, because organ donation has the potential to adversely affect a living donor's health, long-term studies to determine the effect of donation on these donors are needed. The purpose of this study is to determine the mortality, the early postoperative morbidity, and the occurrence of end stage lung disease for participants who underwent donor lobectomy between 1993 and 2006. Participants in this study will have had donor lobectomy at the University of Southern California in Los Angeles or the Washington University Medical Center and Barnes-Jewish Hospital in St. Louis. There will be no study visits for retrospective cohort study. Investigators will collect data from existing medical records and databases.</detailed_description>
	<criteria>Had living donor lobectomy at one of the two participating study centers, the University of Southern California and the Washington University Medical Center between 1993 and 2006 (inclusive)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
	<keyword>Living donor lung transplant</keyword>
	<keyword>End stage lung disease</keyword>
</DOC>