<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="18057">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02871817</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SPD02000-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02871817</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Comparison of the Paxos Mobile App to Standard Vision Assessment Tools</brief_title>
  <acronym>CLEAR</acronym>
  <official_title>The Correlation of Paxos Checkup Mobile App to Standard in Office Visual Assessement</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Digisight Technologies, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Digisight Technologies, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The CLEAR study is testing the level of agreement between in office visual acuity and Amsler
      grid testing using a mobile vision testing application, Paxos Checkup Study and standard in
      office methods. In addition the percent of patients able to successfully complete home
      testing on the digital device will be assessed.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BACKGROUND AND INTRODUCTION Neovascular Age - related Macular Degeneration (AMD) is the most
      common cause of vision loss in subjects over the age of 60. Today in the US over 15 million
      people live with some form of AMD, and approximately 1.6-1.75 million people have
      neovascular AMD associated with vision loss. Approximately 200,000 new cases are diagnosed
      in the US annually; worldwide, approximately 500,000 new cases are diagnosed each year. With
      the aging of the overall population, prevalence of all forms of AMD is expected to rise to
      as many as 42 million by 2030, and it is projected that as many as 8 million seniors are at
      risk for losing vision from AMD within the next 5 years. Economic analysis indicates that
      vision impairment and eye disease cost the US an estimated $68 billion annually in
      healthcare expenditures, reduced productivity, and diminished quality of life, with AMD
      itself having at least a $30 billion dollar negative impact on gross domestic product.

      Diabetes is the leading cause of blindness among working-age adults in the United States.
      According to recent studies funded by the National Eye Institute, diabetic retinopathy, one
      of the most common and debilitating complications of diabetes, increased by 3.7 million new
      cases over the last decade. Approximately 7.7 million Americans are now affected by diabetic
      retinopathy. Even more alarming, the rate is projected to climb to 11 million by 2030.
      People with diabetes are also at greater risk for cataracts and glaucoma. But diabetic
      retinopathy (DR) is by far the most common sight-threatening condition among people with
      diabetes and is the leading cause of blindness in adults aged 20 to 74 years. Diabetic
      retinopathy has an enormous impact on national health care spending: Twenty-one percent of
      national medical expenditures for ophthalmic complications are attributable to diabetes.

      The current standard of care for DR is to identify and treat the disease just before
      irreversible visual loss occurs. In practice, this means that accurate, early diagnosis of
      severe Non-Proliferative DR and/or Diabetic Macular Edema (DME) is needed to identify
      suitable candidates for Laser Photocoagulation, vitrectomy or Intra-vitreal Triamcinolone,
      as appropriate. Because DR is frequently asymptomatic, and any degree of DR is a risk factor
      for further progression, annual comprehensive eye exams are recommended for all individuals
      with diabetes.

      Use of home - based smartphone visual acuity testing apps has the potential to diagnose and
      monitor the progression of DR at a very early stage of the disease and to monitor visual
      changes in macular degeneration. Additionally, The AREDS2-HOME study showed early detection
      of neovascular AMD resulted in better vision outcomes compared to standard monitoring of
      neovascular AMD. Identification of changes in vision would trigger further clinical
      attention and possible interventions. It is conceivable that this would ultimately reduce
      the economic burden of DR and AMD.

      DigiSight's Paxos Checkup Mobile Vision Assessment System allows subjects to frequently
      check their vision in a rapid, quantitative and reproducible way, and transmit that
      information in a secure and organized fashion, enabling their physicians to optimize and
      administer treatment in a timely manner. We designed the CLEAR study to evaluate the
      agreement between Paxos Checkup Application and standard office based visual acuity tests.
      Because the Paxos Checkup test is a near vision test we are using the Lebensohn Near Card as
      the main comparator. Recognizing the sensitivity and widespread use of distance visual
      acuity assessment we will also be testing the Paxos Checkup Application against the Early
      Test Diabetes Retinopathy Study (ETDRS) visual acuity chart as an exploratory endpoint at
      selected sites. The ETDRS visual acuity test has been shown in multiple studies to be the
      most accurate distance vision test in use and therefore has gained widespread acceptance in
      both research and for regulatory purposes.

      CLEAR STUDY OBJECTIVES:

        -  Evaluate the performance of the Paxos Checkup visual test device compared to standard
           in-office procedures for assessing near visual acuity (VA) and metamorphopsia (Amsler
           grid), and,

        -  Document the ability of patients to perform the Paxos Checkup tests at home and ease of
           use.

      OVERVIEW The CLEAR study is a prospective, single arm evaluation of the Paxos Checkup app
      tests, to be conducted in two phases under a common protocol. In the first phase the
      comparative performance of the Paxos Checkup to the pre-specified reference methods in
      assessing near vision and in the presence of normal, AMD or DR will be documented in up to
      20 enrolled subjects. Results of the first phase will be used to finalize the protocol and
      estimated sample size for Phase 2. There will be no formal statistical tests of Phase 1
      results, and data from Phase 1 will not be pooled with Phase 2 results. The study will
      transition from Phase 1 (up to 20 enrolled subjects) to Phase 2 when it is believed that
      sufficient data have been collected in Phase 1 to plan and implement Phase 2. Phase 2 is
      expected to enroll between 100 and 150 subjects based on Phase 1 results.

      Subjects will be enrolled into three subpopulations based on eye health status: subjects
      with AMD (approximately 50% of total), subjects with DR (approximately 30% of total), and
      subjects with normal eye health (approximately 20% of total).

      In Phase 2 the hypotheses associated with the two primary endpoints for the study will be
      statistically tested against pre-specified performance goals. These performance goals are
      based on the test-retest correlation of findings from the reference test methods in the
      study population.

      Primary Endpoint 1:

      Near Corrected Visual Acuity (NCVA) assessed with the Paxos Checkup will be compared to the
      reference method NCVA (Lebensohn Near Card) in replicated measurements at each of two
      in-office visits. At each office visit, two Paxos Checkup and two reference NCVA assessments
      will be made (4 assessments in all). The Paxos Checkup and reference methods tests will be
      administered in an alternating manner to each enrolled subject, with the choice of first
      test randomly chosen, and with at least 10 minutes between individual tests. Test results
      for the Paxos Checkup and Lebensohn assessments will be expressed in LogMAR units for
      purposes of analysis.

      Primary Endpoint 2:

      The evaluation of Primary Endpoint 2 is similar to that of Primary Endpoint 1. The Amsler
      Grid assessment of AMD (outcome: Normal / Abnormal) with the Paxos Checkup will be compared
      to the reference method Amsler Grid in replicated measurements at each of two in-office
      visits. At each office visit, two Paxos Checkup and two reference Amsler Grid assessments
      will be made (4 assessments in all). The Paxos Checkup and reference methods tests will be
      administered in an alternating manner to each enrolled subject, with the choice of first
      test randomly chosen, and with at least 10 minutes between individual tests. The Amsler Grid
      evaluations can be done in parallel with those of CNVA (that is, between CNVA evaluations)
      for purposes of time efficiency.

      All subjects, coordinators, Primary Investigators and sponsor will be masked to the
      aggregate results. The testing sequence is predetermined by the app as visual acuity
      followed by Amsler grid. Standard in office testing will follow the same sequence. The first
      test in a subjects sequence of tests will be randomized to either the mobile app or standard
      methods.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Near Corrected Visual Acuity</measure>
    <time_frame>Eight weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Near Corrected Visual Acuity measured using Lebensohn near card by comparison to Paxos Checkup using the Lin Concordance Coefficient as the statistical test for agreement between the two methods.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Amsler Grid</measure>
    <time_frame>Eight weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of Paxos Checkup to standard methods measured by Amsler Grid using McNemar table as the test statistic.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of home testing using Paxos Checkup Mobile application</measure>
    <time_frame>Eight weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of study subjects ability to successfully complete a home test using the Feasibility of home testing measured by Paxos Checkup Mobile application.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Age - Related Macular Degeneration</condition>
  <condition>Diabetic Retinopathy</condition>
  <condition>Metamorphopsia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Observational</arm_group_label>
    <description>This is an observational study testing the Paxos Checkup Study Mobile Medical Application compared to standard reference methods.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paxos Checkup Study Mobile Medical Application</intervention_name>
    <description>The Digisight Paxos Checkup TM is mobile vision assessment system which consists of an application installed on a mobile device with an Internet connection, an Internet Cloud-based vision care network and a web site. The Paxos Checkup app contains a set of quantitative near vision tests, which a patient can take at home or elsewhere using an Internet capable mobile device.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Observational</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Checkup Study</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Study population includes patients with no pathology, patients with Diabetic Retinopathy
        and patients with Adult Macular Degeneration.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Male or female 18 years of age and older

          -  Best Corrected Near Visual acuity 20/200 or better in study eye(s)

          -  Able and willing to make the required study visits

          -  Able and willing to provide consent and comply with study assessments for the full
             duration of the study.

        Specific Inclusion Criteria for Subgroup with Normal Eyes

          -  Best Corrected Near Visual acuity 20/32 or better in each eye

          -  No concurrent systemic illness affecting the retina and vision.

        Specific Inclusion Criteria for Subgroups with AMD or DR

          -  Diagnosis of either AMD or DR (all subgroups qualify)

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Dementia or other neurologic or psychological limitation that would prevent the
             patient from performing regular self-testing of visual function

          -  Other comorbid ocular pathology affecting vision (with the exception of cataract,
             pseudophakia, refractive error, and/or presbyopia)

          -  Inability to successfully undergo training and certify ability to self-test with
             Paxos Checkup

          -  Inability to return for follow up
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Russell J Ivanhoe, MD MBA</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Digisight Technologies, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Retinal Associates of Cleveland</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44122</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 4, 2017</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 18, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Near Corrected Visual Acuity</keyword>
  <keyword>Early Treatment Diabetes Retinopathy Study</keyword>
  <keyword>Amsler Grid</keyword>
  <keyword>Home Monitoring</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Retinal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetic Retinopathy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vision Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
