<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01179269</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Lung cancer is the leading cause of cancer worldwide with approximately 1.2 million new cases each year. Non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) accounts for greater than 80% of all lung carcinomas in Western countries. Surgical resection is the treatment of choice for patients with early stage disease (Stage I and II), but at least 50% of these patients will relapse locally and/or develop distant metastases. Furthermore, 70% of patients with NSCLC are non-resectable at the time of their diagnosis due to either locally advanced or metastatic disease. The long-term prognosis for patients with NSCLC remains poor with the overall 5-year survival rate less than 15%. The low survival rate may be attributed to the high incidence of unresectable disease at presentation and the inability of systemic therapy to cure metastatic disease. There is a clear need for improvement in the treatment of NSCLC.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pazopanib and Paclitaxel for Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the objective response rate of pazopanib in combination with paclitaxel in the treatment of subjects with advanced NSCLC. Tumor response will be assessed according to the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) criteria (version 1.1). A subject is defined as a responder if he/she sustains a complete response (CR) or a partial response (PR) for at least 4 weeks at any time during treatment. A subject without a post-baseline assessment of response will be considered a non-responder. A secondary objective of this study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of pazopanib in combination with paclitaxel in the treatment of subjects with advanced NSCLC. Safety and tolerability endpoints will consist of the evaluation of adverse events (AEs), exposure, withdrawals due to AEs, dose reductions or interruptions, and changes from baseline in vital signs and clinical laboratory parameters.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of Stage IIIB (with confirmed malignant pleural effusion) or Stage IV NSCLC. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 02 No prior systemic firstline therapy for Stage IIIB/IV NSCLC with chemotherapy or any other biologic therapy. Prior surgery and/or localized irradiation for NSCLC are permitted. Palliative radiation therapy must have ended 14 days prior to first dose of pazopanib. Subject with recurrence after previous NSCLC that has been treated with surgery with or without adjuvant chemotherapy/radiation for curative intent are eligible, provided 12 months have passed since this treatment ended. Appropriate for doublet therapy as first line therapy. At discretion of investigator.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
	<keyword>Pazopanib</keyword>
	<keyword>Stage IIIB/IV non small cell lung cancer</keyword>
</DOC>