<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01179776</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Acute myocardial infarct patients with STEMI (ST-elevation on ECG) whom undergo a primary percutaneous cardiac intervention will following the standard treatment , received low dose of Ilomedin and to low dose of standard treatment for another 24 hours.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Ilomedin Treatment for Patients Having Undergone Primary Percutaneous Coronary Intervention (PCI)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Age &gt; 18 years 2. Undergoing primary PCI due to STEMI (TIMI flow I III before PCI and symptom duration &lt; 12 hours) 6) Following receipt of verbal and written information about the study, the patient must provide signed informed consent before any study data is used. 2) Not able to give informed consent 3) Women with childbearing potential 4) Ongoing concomitant treatment with Kvitamin antagonists (one bolus dose prePCI allowed) 5) Known congenital or acquired coagulopathy and/or thrombocytopathy s 8) Participation in a clinical study and/or another investigational device within the past four weeks prior to Day 1 9) Major surgery or trauma within the past 6 weeks prior to Day 1 10) A blood coagulation disorder (i.e. international normalized ratio [INR] &gt; 2.0, platelet count &lt; 100,000/mm3, or hematocrit &lt; 30%) 11) Renal insufficiency (creatinine &gt; 140 mmol/l) 12) Major procedure related bleeding (TIMI major criteria); GI or urinary tract bleeding prior to inclusion in the trial 13) Known active hepatitis B and/or hepatitis C or HIV 14) Known or suspected hypersensitivity to components of the investigational medicinal product</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
	<keyword>ST-eleveation</keyword>
	<keyword>Myocardial infarct</keyword>
	<keyword>Percutaneous coronary intervention</keyword>
	<keyword>Myocardial infarct STEMI patients</keyword>
</DOC>