<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01182207</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study was designed to compare the relative bioavailability (rate and extent of absorption) of 3 mg/0.02 mg Drospirenone/Ethinyl Estradiol Tablets with that of YAZ® Tablets (by Berlex, Inc.) following a single, oral dose (2 x 3 mg/0.02 mg tablets) in healthy, adult subjects under non-fasting conditions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Drospirenone/Ethinyl Estradiol (3 mg/0.02 mg) Tablets Under Non-Fasting Conditions</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Criteria for Evaluation: FDA Bioequivalence Criteria Statistical Methods: FDA Bioequivalence Statistical Methods</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Ethinyl Estradiol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Polyestradiol phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Drospirenone</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol 3-benzoate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol 17 beta-cypionate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Estradiol valerate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Drospirenone and ethinyl estradiol combination</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who were informed of the nature of the study and agreed to read, review, and sign the informed consent document prior to Period I dosing. Subjects who completed the screening process within 28 days prior to Period I dosing. Subjects who were healthy, adult, menstruating women 18 to 35 years of age, inclusive, at the time of dosing. Subjects with a body mass index (BMI) between 19 and 30 kg/m2, inclusive, and weighed at least 110 pounds. Subjects who were healthy as documented by the medical history, physical examination, vital sign assessments, 12lead electrocardiogram, clinical laboratory assessments, and by general observations. The physical examination also included a gynecological exam. If the subject had completed an acceptable Pap smear and gynecological exam in the previous 12 months (prior to study Day 1) and the documentation of acceptable results were provided, both were deferred. Any abnormalities/deviations from thee normal range which were considered clinically relevant by the study physician and investigator were evaluated for individual cases, documented in study files, and agreed upon by the study physician and investigator prior to enrolling a volunteer in the study and for continued enrollment. Female subjects who practice an acceptable nonhormonal method of birth control as judged by the investigator(s) at least 14 days prior to Period I dosing, throughout the study, and until 14 days after Period II dosing. The acceptable nonhormonal birth control methods included: double barriers, nonhormone releasing intrauterine device in place for at least 30 days prior to dosing, abstinence throughout the duration of the study, or surgically sterile for at least 6 months prior to Period I dosing. Volunteers who report receiving any investigational drug within 30 days prior to Period I dosing. Volunteers who reported taking any oral contraceptives including estrogen and progestin combined pills and progestin only pills or patch within 28 days prior to Period I dosing, or using injectable contraceptives within 6 months of Period I dosing. Volunteers who have ever had progestational hormone implants. Volunteers who reported any presence or history of a clinically significant disorder involving the cardiovascular, respiratory, renal, liver, gastrointestinal, immunologic, hematologic, endocrine, or neurologic system(s), or psychiatric or epilepsy disease as determined by the clinical investigator(s). Volunteers who reported any presence or history of migraines or severe headaches. Volunteers who had a systolic blood pressure lower than 90 or over 140 mmHg, or diastolic blood pressure lower than 45 or over 90 mmHg were excluded from the study. Volunteers who had a history of thrombotic disorders, have ever had a cerebrovascular accident, or had transient ischemic attacks. Volunteers with a history of breast cancer or undiagnosed breast nodules, active malignancies, or undiagnosed vaginal bleeding. Volunteers having other conditions that may be aggravated by fluid retention (as determined by principle investigator). Volunteers who had a history of jaundice with previous use of oral contraceptives or any other kinds of hormonal contraceptives. Volunteers whose clinical laboratory test values outside the acceptable range and when confirmed on reexamination were deemed to be clinically significant. Volunteers who demonstrated a reactive screen for hepatitis B surface antigen, hepatitis C antibody, or HIV antibody. Volunteers who reported a history of allergic response(s) to drospirenone/ethinyl estradiol, progestin/estrogens, or related drugs. Volunteers who reported the use of any systemic prescription medications in the 14 days prior to Period 1 dosing (with the exception of hormonal contraceptives). Volunteers who reported the use of any drug known to induce or inhibit hepatic drug metabolism in the 28 days prior to Period I dosing. Volunteers who reported a history of clinically significant allergies including drug allergies. Volunteers who reported a clinically significant illness during the 4 weeks prior to Period I dosing (as determined by the clinical investigators). Volunteers who reported a history of drug or alcohol addiction or abuse within the past year. Volunteers who demonstrated a positive drug abuse screen for the study prior to Period I dose administration. Volunteers who used tobacco products in the past 6 months. Volunteers who reported donating greater than 150 mL of blood within 30 days prior to Period I dosing. All subjects were advised not to donate blood for 4 weeks after completing the study. Volunteers who reported donating plasma within 30 days prior to Period I dosing. All subjects were advised not to donate blood for 4 weeks after completing the study. Volunteers who demonstrate a positive pregnancy screen. Volunteers who were currently breastfeeding. Subjects who had used within the 3 months preceding Period I dosing any vaginally administered estrogen or progestin containing products. Any volunteer who engaged in unprotected sexual intercourse during the time interval starting 14 days prior to the first period until 14 days after Period II dosing. Volunteers who had a hysterectomy or oophorectomy.</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Bioequivalence</keyword>
	<keyword>Healthy Subjects</keyword>
</DOC>