<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00139958</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Objectives: Evaluate differences for mortality, morbidity and the cardiovascular risk factors between HIV and non-HIV patients with an acute coronary syndromes (ACS) after a 3-years follow up.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Prognosis of Acute Coronary Syndrome in HIV-infected Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Background: There have been many cases of myocardial infarction reported in HIV-infected young adults treated with HAART. Little is known to date, concerning the outcome and prognostic factors of patients with acute coronary syndrome and HIV-infection. Methods: Prospective cohort study to compare the evolution and prognosis between HIV and non-HIV patients with an ACS. Duration of the study: Two years for including patients. Three years of follow-up 100 HIV-patients with ACS and 200 non-HIV patients with ACS will be included in the study. All patients will be included in the study from 30 Intensive Care Unit of Cardiology departments in France. Results: To compare the incidence of total mortality, cardiovascular mortality (myocardial infarction, sudden death, cardiogenic shock, fatal stroke), morbidity (non fatal myocardial infarction, unstable angina, recurrence of ischemia, cardiac failure, non fatal stroke) and revascularization (percutaneous coronary intervention, coronary artery bypass graft surgery) during a 3-year follow-up between HIV and non-HIV patients with ACS. Univariate and multivariate analysis of predictive factors for cardiovascular events will be done.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients &gt; 18 year's old Man or woman HIVinfected for HIV 1 with or without highly active antiretroviral therapy Acute coronary syndromes (STEMI, NSTEMI and unstable angina) Known atherosclerotic artery disease (MI, ACS, PCI, CABG, coronary stenosis, stroke, peripheral arteriopathy)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Acute coronary syndrome</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Prognosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary heart disease</keyword>
	<keyword>Revascularization</keyword>
</DOC>