<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02791685</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The goal of this study is to determine if a remote cardiac or pulmonary rehabilitation program delivered via a smartphone application and regular telephone calls will lead to improved patient outcomes as measured by functional capacity, improved patient compliance in monitoring symptoms and medication adherence, improved self-efficacy and knowledge in managing disease and, a decreased rate of hospitalization and re-admissions.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Smartphone Delivered In-home Cardiopulmonary Rehabilitation</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This project aims to determine if a smartphone-delivered cardiac rehabilitation (CR) program could show similar clinical outcomes to in-person programs at a low cost in a large population of patients. Investigators will also assess the feasibility of tailoring a virtual CR program to a small sample of COPD participants who also stand to benefit in the absence of an established pulmonary rehabilitation (PR) program. This is a randomized controlled clinical trial of participants at the Atlanta Veterans Affairs Medical Center with an applicable diagnosis for cardiac or pulmonary rehabilitation versus usual care during the study period. The study team plans to simultaneously recruit two cohorts of participants referred for CR (Cohort A) and PR (Cohort B) to take part in an in-home, virtual rehabilitation program. To compare this intervention to traditional CR, investigators will perform an observational cohort study of patients who are already enrolled through the CHOICE program in conventional CR. Furthermore, to better understand the potential impact of this intervention, investigators will perform a retrospective chart review of patients referred for CR over the past 5-years. Investigators seek to address the following: 1. Determine whether a home-based cardiac or pulmonary rehabilitation program delivered through smartphones is feasible and improves functional status. 2. Determine if education and lifestyle counseling lead to increased adherence with prescribed follow-up, pharmacotherapy, quality of life, self-efficacy and lifestyle changes. 3. Determine if a home-based cardiac or pulmonary rehabilitation program reduces health system utilization, including ED visits and readmission rates.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Cohort A: Meet eligibility for cardiac rehabilitation program as defined by Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) 1. Following acute myocardial infarction (within the preceding 12 months) 2. Coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) 3. Current stable angina pectoris 4. Heart valve repair or replacement 5. Percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty (PTCA) or coronary stenting 6. Heart or heartlung transplant 7. Other diagnosis by specific physician referral Unstable angina Resting systolic blood pressure &gt;200 mm Hg or resting diastolic blood pressure &gt;110 mm Hg Significant drop (&gt;=20 mm Hg) in resting systolic blood pressure from the patient's average level that cannot be explained by medications Moderate to severe aortic stenosis Acute systemic illness or fever Uncontrolled atrial or ventricular arrhythmias Symptomatic congestive heart failure (stage C) Thirddegree heart block without pacemaker Active pericarditis or myocarditis Recent venous thromboembolism (VTE, as determined by physician) Current Thrombophlebitis Uncontrolled diabetes (A1c &gt; 7.0 or as determined by physician) Orthopedic problems that would prohibit exercise Other by specific physician instruction Peripheral vascular disease (PVD; symptomatic or that would prohibit exercise) Cohort B: Meet eligibility for pulmonary rehabilitation as defined by the American Thoracic Society (ATS): 1. Symptomatic impairment attributable to pulmonary disability 2. Failure of standard medical regimen to achieve adequate symptomatic relief 3. Motivated, adherent patient Lack of motivation Nonadherence Severe cognitive dysfunction or psychiatric illness Unstable comorbidity (unstable angina, decompensated heart failure) Severe exerciseinduced hypoxemia, not correctable with O2 supplementation Inability to exercise due to severe lung or other disease (arthritis, stroke) Cigarette smoking</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Cardiac Rehabilitation</keyword>
</DOC>