<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT03024866</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a retrospective-prospective study design. Patients who completed treatment approximately 3 years (range of 2-4 years) at time of IRB approval of this study will be identified and any existing data in the patient's record will be collected in addition to conducting office visits for long-term follow-up.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Electronic Brachytherapy (eBx)-Mohs Matched Pair - Cohort Study A Multi-Center Retrospective-Prospective Matched Pairs Cohort Study to Assess Long-term Clinical Outcomes of Non-melanoma Skin Cancer Patients Treated With eBx Compared to Non-melanoma Skin Cancer Patients Treated With Mohs Surgery</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This is a retrospective-prospective study design. Patients who completed treatment approximately 3 years (range of 2-4 years) at time of IRB approval of this study will be identified and any existing data in the patient's record will be collected in addition to conducting office visits for long-term follow-up. The study will include 2 parts: 1. Retrospective chart review: Collect data from patient records who completed treatment a minimum of 2 years prior to study onset and determine the feasibility of doing a matched pair cohort study comparison of eBx versus Mohs surgery. The history, demographic and treatment data will be retrospectively collected from up to 320 subjects previously treated with eBx for the treatment of NMSC and up to 320 subjects previously treated with Mohs surgery for the treatment of NMSC. 2. Prospective Follow-up: Patients will return for long-term follow-up visits for the investigators to assess the lesion site, document absence of recurrence/ absence of recurrence, toxicities, and collect patient reported outcomes.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Skin Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Previously completed treatment for nonmelanoma skin cancer using Xoft eBx Electronic Brachytherapy System or Mohs surgery; 2. Provides informed Consent; 3. Greater than 40 years of age; 4. Pathological diagnosis confirmed to be squamous cell or basal cell carcinoma prior to treatment; 5. Cancer Staging included in this study: Stage 0: Tis, N0, M0 Stage 1: T1, N0, M0 Stage 2: T2, N0, M0 and ≤ 4cm in diameter 1. Target area is adjacent to a burn scar 2. Any prior definitive surgical resection of the cancer, prior to Radiation Treatment 3. Known perineural invasion 4. Actinic Keratosis 5. Known spread to regional lymph nodes 6. Known metastatic disease</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>41 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>