<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01083862</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Study objective was to explore the impact of health literacy on effectiveness of an educational intervention describing life-style and behavior modification for patients "Living with Coronary Artery Disease." Our hypothesis was that a VHS/DVD version of this educational program would be "superior" to printed material alone in its impact on patients' knowledge about coronary artery disease and important life-style changes. Furthermore, we believed this effect would be most notable among patients with low health literacy. We also were interested in the impact of the interventions on secondary outcomes including - health behaviors, health outcomes and patients' subjective experiences.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Impact of Health Literacy on Outcomes and Effectiveness of Shared Decision Making Programs in Patients With Chronic Diseases</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>187 patients with coronary artery disease (CAD) were randomized to one of two educational interventions prior to scheduled ambulatory visit: VHS/DVD plus printed booklet; or booklet alone. Main measures included health literacy, CAD knowledge assessment; clinical outcomes and health behaviors including - blood pressure, weight, smoking status, exercise and dietary habits.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Age &gt;= 18, Diagnosis of ischemic heart disease. Nursing home resident, Did not speak English, or Had a significant visual impairment that precluded their ability to read or watch television.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2010</verification_date>
	<keyword>Health literacy</keyword>
	<keyword>patient education</keyword>
	<keyword>health behaviors</keyword>
	<keyword>chronic disease management</keyword>
	<keyword>shared decision-making</keyword>
	<keyword>patient-centered decision making</keyword>
</DOC>