<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01083628</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study will assess the feasibility and acceptability of using mobile phone text messages (SMS) as adjuncts to existing group cognitive-behavioral treatment (CBT) for depression at San Francisco General Hospital. Patients in current groups will be given the option to participate in a text-messaging adjunct in lieu of the usual paper and pencil "homework" that is typically assigned during group sessions. They will also be provided with CBT relevant "tips and skills" to employ during particularly stressful times. Participants will receive daily text messages asking them what their mood is, this will help them become aware of their mood state and provide feedback to the group leaders as to the progress of the patient. Patients will also receive 1-2 additional messages a day depending on the module of focus for that month (i.e. thoughts, activities, people, and health). These additional messages include 1) thought tracking (both positive and negative), 2) tracking of pleasant activities, 3) tracking of positive and negative contacts, 4) tracking of physical wellbeing. Additionally, participants will receive reminders of weekly group meetings in an attempt to improve adherence. Patients that are taking medication will be offered to receive reminders to take medication according to their prescribed regimen. Another component of the SMS messages will allow patients to text the keyword STRESSED and receive a randomly generated message that will suggest cognitive and behavioral tips to counteract the stress or sad mood. They will also be able to text the word HELP and receive the number for a suicide hotline or be prompted to contact 911 for an emergency. Lastly, participants will be given feedback on their mood, behaviors and cognitions through visual graphs that display their status over time. This will allow patients to see the connection between mood behavior and cognition. This study is not intended to test hypotheses.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Text Messaging and Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Depression</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Participation in CBT group at San Francisco General Hospital</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
</DOC>