<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00331136</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate three dose levels of a combination of pyronaridine and artesunate for the treatment of uncomplicated falciparum malaria in children.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pyronaridine and Artesunate (3:1) in Children With Acute Uncomplicated Plasmodium Falciparum Malaria</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Plasmodium falciparum malaria kills over one million people and results in up to 500 million cases annually affecting mainly young children and pregnant women. The economic consequences of malaria are enormous in endemic regions with an estimated USD 12 billion per year lost GDP and a loss of 45 million years of productive life due to deaths and disability. Malaria is curable and preventable, with principal control strategies including rapid diagnosis, effective treatment and personal protection with bed nets. Currently a number of antimalarials are available, however two of the most widely used drugs, chloroquine and sulfadoxine-pyrimethamine are not effective in many parts of the world due to drug resistance. Artemisinin-based combination therapies (ACT) are effective and today are considered by experts the best antimalarials in terms of efficacy and a lower propensity to resistance. Cost and access to appropriate quality raw materials remain major issues with the currently available artemisinins. In order to prevent the occurrence of drug resistance to artemisinins and to address the issue of its relatively short half-life, artemisins are recommended to be given in combination with another antimalarial agent. In this development programme, artemisinin, as artesunate, is being partnered with an established antimalarial agent pyronaridine. The objective of the development programme for the pyronaridine artesunate combination is to develop a three day oral therapy for use in children and adults to treat acute, uncomplicated malaria.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Malaria, Falciparum</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artesunate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artemisinins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pyronaridine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients presenting with symptoms of acute uncomplicated falciparum malaria with the following inclusion criteria : Male or female children, being between 2 and 14 years of age inclusive Weight between 10 and 40 kg inclusive Written informed consent, in accordance to local practice, provided by parent/guardian. If the parent/guardian is unable to write, witnessed consent is permitted according to local ethical considerations. Where possible, parent assent will be sought. Absence of severe malnutrition (defined as Mid Upper arm Circumference &lt;110mm) Presence of acute symptomatic uncomplicated P. falciparum malaria with a diagnosis confirmed by a positive blood smear with asexual forms of P. falciparum only (i.e. no mixed infection) plus measured temperature of ≥37.5°C (depending on method of measurement as below) or history of fever within the past 24 hours : the acceptable range is between 1,000 and 200,000 asexual parasite count/μl of blood and axillary/tympanic temperature of ≥37.5°C or oral/rectal temperature of ≥38.0°C Patients with signs and symptoms of severe/complicated malaria requiring parenteral antimalarial treatment according to the World Health Organization Criteria 2000 Mixed Plasmodium infection Severe vomiting, defined as more than three times in the 24 hours prior to inclusion in the study or inability to tolerate oral treatment, or severe diarrhoea defined as 3 or more watery stools per day Known history or evidence of clinically significant disorders such as cardiovascular (including arrhythmia, acute QTc interval greater or equal to 450 mseconds), respiratory (including active tuberculosis), hepatic, renal, gastrointestinal, immunological (including active HIVAIDS), neurological (including auditory), endocrine, infectious, malignancy, psychiatric or other abnormality (including head trauma) Presence of febrile conditions caused by diseases other than malaria Known history of hypersensitivity, allergic or adverse reactions to pyronaridine or artesunate or other artemisinins Use of any other antimalarial treatment within 2 weeks prior to start of the study as confirmed by Lignin test and Saker Solomon urine test</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>14 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2008</verification_date>
	<keyword>malaria</keyword>
	<keyword>pyronaridine</keyword>
	<keyword>artesunate</keyword>
	<keyword>falciparum</keyword>
	<keyword>ACT</keyword>
</DOC>