<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00740779</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The primary objective is to compare the efficacy of silodosin 4 and 8 mg once daily with placebo in the treatment of subjects with moderate to severe abacterial chronic prostatitis/chronic pelvic pain syndrome during a 12 week treatment period. The secondary objective is to compare the safety of silodosin 4 and 8 mg once daily with placebo.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Use of Silodosin to Treat Moderate to Severe Abacterial Chronic Prostatitis/Chronic Pelvic Pain Syndrome.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>A Multi-Center, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Investigation of Silodosin in the Treatment of Subjects With Moderate to Severe Abacterial Chronic Prostatitis/Chronic Pelvic Pain Syndrome.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Somatoform Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pelvic Pain</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Prostatitis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Silodosin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Male, at least 18 years of age Has a total NIHCPSI total score of 15 Has a NIHCPSI pain score of 8 Has had pain in the pelvic region for at least 3 months prior to screening Has previously participated in a Watson study with silodosin Has previously received αblocked therapy for chronic prostatitis/chronic pelvic pain syndrome or is currently receiving αblocked therapy for any condition Has experience ≥2 urinary tract infections within the previous 12 months Has any medical condition that in the opinion of the investigator precludes safe participation in the study Has any medical condition that could confound the efficacy evaluation Is receiving ketoconazole, or other known potent inhibitors of cytochrome P450 3A4 or any medication in the opinion of the investigator that precludes safe participation in the study Is receiving any medication that in the opinion of the investigator that could confound the efficacy evaluation Has participated in a study involving the administration of an investigational agent within the past 30 days</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>prostatitis, chronic pelvic pain</keyword>
</DOC>