<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00117559</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate a group psychotherapy intervention and a telehealth intervention for veterans undergoing interferon treatment for the hepatitis C virus. It is hypothesized that the cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) condition and the telehealth condition will result in significantly improved outcomes, including enhanced adherence, quality of life, and psychological status.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Improving Quality of Life for Veterans Undergoing Interferon Treatment</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of the proposed pilot study is to evaluate a rehabilitative cognitive-behavioral group psychotherapy intervention and a telehealth intervention for veterans undergoing interferon treatment for the hepatitis C virus (HCV). The specific objectives of the proposed pilot study are: 1) develop study methods and materials; 2) evaluate study feasibility; and 3) assess the efficacy of a cognitive-behavioral group therapy approach and a telehealth approach as compared to care as usual in a randomized design. Participants will be 45 patients (15 participants in each condition) from the VA Boston Healthcare System who are undergoing interferon treatment for HCV. Assessment will occur at pre-treatment, post-treatment, and 3-month follow-up. Assessments will measure key areas, including adherence, quality of life, and psychological distress. Analyses will examine study feasibility and the effects of the treatment condition. It is hypothesized that the CBT condition and the telehealth condition will result in significantly improved outcomes, including enhanced adherence, quality of life, and psychological status. This treatment approach addresses initiatives by the National VHA Hepatitis C Program by optimizing the care of veterans experiencing the devastating side effects of interferon treatment.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Clinical diagnosis of hepatitis C. Must be on the interferon treatment Need to have access to telephone. Life threatening or acute illness Current alcohol or substance abuse or dependence Individuals already receiving psychological interventions specifically to manage the side effects of the IFN treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>Psychotherapy,group</keyword>
	<keyword>Rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword>Telecommunications</keyword>
</DOC>