<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00117728</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to test if a sequential protease-inhibitor (PI) - / nevirapine (NVP) -based regimen is effective for the treatment of HIV-infected children when previous NVP exposure has occurred as part of programs to prevent mother-to-child transmission (pMTCT).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Pediatric Nevirapine Resistance Study</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The wide use of NVP in pMTCT-prophylaxis may result in resistance to NNRTI and concomitantly limits the use of these drugs for the treatment of HIV-infected children. To avoid restricting treatment options for children, it is desirable to preserve NVP for both pMTCT and first line treatment. This study will therefore test whether resistance-caused treatment failures of HIV-infected and previously NVP-exposed children can be avoided if the NVP treatment is preceded by an initial PI-based regimen. Comparison: HIV-infected children less than 24 months of age, exposed to any pMTCT regimen that included NVP and who achieve and maintain viral suppression for at least 3 months with a PI-based regimen will be randomized to one of the two groups: (1) to continue on PI-containing regimen or (2) to be switched off the PI-containing regimen onto the NVP-containing regimen. The study outcome will be proportions in the two groups who have complete virologic suppression at 6 months after randomization.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nevirapine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>NVPexposure as part of pMTCTprophylaxis around delivery HIVpositive Eligible for treatment Plans to stay in the area for the next 6 months Already on antiretroviral treatment History of toxicity to perinatal NVP Grade 3 or greater elevation of liver function tests Being treated for a severe acute opportunistic infection or tumor</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Months</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2006</verification_date>
	<keyword>Non-nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitor</keyword>
	<keyword>Drug Resistance</keyword>
	<keyword>HIV Seronegativity</keyword>
	<keyword>Treatment Naive</keyword>
</DOC>