<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00929383</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The IRISS study is designed to collect clinical and angiographic outcomes data when stenting intracranial atherosclerotic lesions using the Wingspan™ Stent System with Gateway™ PTA Balloon Catheter in routine clinical practice.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>An International Registry of the Wingspan™ Stent System for the Treatment of Intracranial Atherosclerotic Stenosis</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Wingspan™ Stent System and Gateway™ PTA Balloon Catheter have CE mark and are commonly used in Europe. All the data collected in this registry will be from patients treated according to the physician's choice, per instructions for use, per approved indications and per local standard of care. The results from this registry will provide an understanding of the use and outcomes associated with the Wingspan™ Stent in a real world setting.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Atherosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Constriction, Pathologic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Intracranial Arteriosclerosis</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Symptomatic stenosis of one of those intracranial arteries: Internal carotid artery (ICA ), M1 segment of the MCA, V4 segment of vertebral artery, basilar artery A Modified Rankin Score of ≤ 3 A target vessel diameter between 2mm and ≤ 4.5mm Length of the target lesion of ≤ 14 mm Patient older than 40 years old Patient previously stented at the target lesion Intracranial stenosis related to disease such as: arterial dissection, Moya Moya disease, vasculitis, radiation induced vasculopathy or fibromuscular dysplasia Complete occlusion of the artery on the imaging assessment Contraindications to antithrombotic and/or anticoagulant therapies Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding Patient not likely to be available for followup Patient protected by the law (safeguard of justice, supervision or trusteeship)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>41 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Intracranial Atherosclerosis</keyword>
	<keyword>Stenosis</keyword>
	<keyword>ICAD</keyword>
	<keyword>atherosclerotic lesions</keyword>
	<keyword>stenting</keyword>
</DOC>