<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01458171</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The objective of this study is to assess the long-term safety, tolerability, and efficacy of IgPro20 in subjects with primary immunodeficiency (PID) as a follow-up to the pivotal study ZLB06_002CR (NCT01199705).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Follow-up Study of Subcutaneous Immune Globulin in Patients Requiring IgG Replacement Therapy (Japan Study)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>gamma-Globulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Rho(D) Immune Globulin</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects who have participated in study ZLB06_002CR and who have tolerated IgPro20 well. Written informed consent by the subject/parent/legally acceptable representative. Written assent for an underage subject (≥7 years at the time of obtaining informed consent), as far as possible. Ongoing serious bacterial infections (SBIs) (pneumonia, bacteremia/septicemia, osteomyelitis/septic arthritis, bacterial meningitis, or visceral abscess) at the time of the first infusion. Hypoalbuminemia, proteinlosing enteropathies, and any proteinuria (known total urine protein concentration &gt;0.2 g/L or urine protein ++ by dipstick). Pregnancy or nursing mother. Participation in a study with an investigational medicinal product (IMP) within 3 months prior to enrollment except for ZLB06_002CR. Subjects who are planning to donate blood during the study. Reentry of subjects previously participating in the current followup study. Known or suspected antibodies to the IMP, or to excipients of the IMP.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Immune globulin subcutaneous</keyword>
	<keyword>SCIG</keyword>
	<keyword>Primary immunodeficiency</keyword>
	<keyword>PID</keyword>
</DOC>