<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01458587</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine if Levulan PDT is safe and effective in the treatment of actinic keratoses on the upper arms and hands.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Levulan PDT Versus Vehicle for Extremity Actinic Keratoses (AK)</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Keratosis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Keratosis, Actinic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Aminolevulinic Acid</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 4 Grade 1/2 AKs on each upper extremity Pregnancy history of cutaneous photosensitization, porphyria, hypersensitivity to porphyrins or photodermatosis lesions suspicious for skin cancer (skin cancer not ruled out by biopsy) or untreated skin cancers within the Treatment Area skin pathology or condition which could interfere with the evaluation of the test product or requires the use of interfering topical or systemic therapy Subject is immunosuppressed unsuccessful outcome from previous ALAPDT therapy currently enrolled in an investigational drug or device study has received an investigational drug or been treated with an investigational device within 30 days prior to the initiation of treatment known sensitivity to one or more of the vehicle components (ethyl alcohol, isopropyl alcohol, laureth 4, polyethylene glycol) use of the following topical preparations on the extremities to be treated: Keratolytics including urea (greater than 5%), alpha hydroxyacids [e.g.glycolic acid, lactic acid, etc. greater than 5%], salicylic acid (greater than 2%) within 2 days of initiation of treatment. Cryotherapy within 2 weeks of initiation of treatment Retinoids, including tazarotene, adapalene, tretinoin, retinol, within 4 weeks of initiation of treatment. Microdermabrasion, laser ablative treatments, ALAPDT, chemical peels, 5FU, diclofenac, imiquimod or other topical treatments for AK within 8 weeks of initiation of treatment. Two or more ALA PDT treatments in the past 6 months use of systemic retinoid therapy within 6 months of initiation of treatment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2013</verification_date>
	<keyword>Actinic keratosis</keyword>
</DOC>