<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="35344">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 10, 2017</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02646449</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1R21AA022863-01A1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02646449</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Young Adults With Comorbid AUD/MDD: A Pilot Medication Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>YAAD-P</acronym>
  <official_title>Treatment of Young Adults With Comorbid AUD/MDD: A Pilot Medication Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pittsburgh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pittsburgh</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Recent reports have shown that alcohol misuse is a particularly serious problem among the 18
      to 25 year old age group. Previous medication trials with SSRI antidepressants among young
      adults with co-occurring depressive disorders, including our own recent trials with SSRI
      medications, have produced disappointing results, especially for decreasing the level of
      alcohol consumption. Mirtazapine is a non-SSRI medication with a unique structure and
      mechanism of action. Recent study results suggest that mirtazapine is more effective than
      other antidepressants for treating non-comorbid depression. A few recent studies with
      mirtazapine have been conducted among subjects with comorbid AUD/MDD, and those studies have
      demonstrated efficacy for mirtazapine for decreasing the depressive symptoms and the alcohol
      craving of subjects with comorbid AUD/MDD. However, those studies did not measure level of
      alcohol consumption, so it is unclear whether mirtazapine decreases the level of alcohol use
      of that comorbid population. The results of our own very recent open label pilot study
      suggest robust within-group efficacy for mirtazapine for decreasing both the level of
      alcohol use and the depressive symptoms of comorbid subjects. However, that pilot study did
      not include a placebo control group, so the efficacy of mirtazapine versus placebo for
      decreasing the level of alcohol use among persons with comorbid AUD/MDD remains unclear.
      This grant submission proposes to conduct a first double-blind, placebo-controlled pilot
      study to provide a preliminary assessment of the efficacy of mirtazapine versus placebo for
      decreasing both the alcohol use and depressive symptoms of young adults with comorbid
      AUD/MDD. If results (effect sizes) from the proposed study are found to be promising
      concerning outcome differences between the mirtazapine and placebo groups, then we will use
      those findings to apply for an R01 study to definitively assess the efficacy of mirtazapine
      for treating young adults with AUD/MDD.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      MDD and AUD are each highly prevalent among young adults, and the comorbidity of those two
      disorders occurs more often than would be expected by chance alone. The presence of this
      comorbidity is associated with increased risk for motor vehicle accidents, relapse to
      alcohol use, suicide, recurrence of depressive illness, increased morbidity, and costly
      hospitalization. Thus, the comorbidity of AUD/MDD is a highly significant public health
      problem among young adults, with considerable unmet treatment needs. Previous medication
      trials with SSRI antidepressants involving those co-occurring conditions, including our own
      recent trials with SSRI medications, have produced disappointing results, especially for
      decreasing the level of alcohol consumption. Mirtazapine is an FDA-approved medication for
      treating MDD with a unique pharmacological profile, unrelated to SSRIs. Recent study results
      suggest that mirtazapine is more effective than other antidepressants for treating
      non-comorbid depression. A few recent studies have demonstrated efficacy for mirtazapine for
      decreasing the depressive symptoms and the alcohol craving of subjects with comorbid
      AUD/MDD, but those studies did not measure level of alcohol consumption. Therefore, it is
      unclear whether mirtazapine decreases the level of alcohol use of that comorbid population.
      Our own recent pilot data suggest within-group efficacy for mirtazapine for decreasing both
      the excessive alcohol use and the depressive symptoms of persons with comorbid AD/MDD.
      However, that pilot study did not include a placebo control group, so the efficacy of
      mirtazapine for decreasing the level of alcohol use among persons with comorbid AUD/MDD
      remains unclear. To date, no double-blind, placebo-controlled study has even been conducted
      to assess whether mirtazapine decreases both the level of drinking and the depressive
      symptoms of young adults with comorbid AD/MDD. In this submission, we propose a proof of
      concept, double-blind, placebo-controlled pilot trial to provide a preliminary assessment of
      the efficacy of the medication mirtazapine vs. placebo in the treatment of young adults with
      co-occurring alcohol use disorders (AUD) and major depression (MDD). If results (effect
      sizes) from the proposed study are found to be promising concerning outcome differences
      between the mirtazapine and placebo groups, then we will use those findings to apply for an
      R01 study to definitively assess the efficacy of mirtazapine for treating young adults with
      AUD/MDD.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double Blind (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of drinks per week</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Level of drinking, as indicated by the number of drinks per day as recorded on the Timeline Follow-Back calendar.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of Depressive Symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>2 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Level of depressive symptoms, as indicated by the score on the Beck Depression Inventory.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Major Depressive Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Alcohol Use Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mirtazapine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Gelatin capsules mirtazapine 15 mg, 1 capsule every a.m. Medication will be increased by one capsule, to a dose of 2 capsules barring side effects, at Week 2.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Gelatin capsules Placebo capsules, identical to mirtazapine capsules, 1 capsule every a.m. Medication will be increased by one capsule to 2 capsules at Week 2, barring any side effects.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mirtazapine</intervention_name>
    <description>Gelatin capsules mirtazapine 15 mg, 1 capsule every a.m. Medication will be increased by one capsule, to a dose of 2 capsules barring side effects, at Week 2.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mirtazapine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Remeron</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Gelatin capsules Placebo capsules, identical to mirtazapine capsules, 1 capsule every a.m. Medication will be increased by one capsule to 2 capsules at Week 2, barring any side effects.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  DSM-IV-TR diagnosis of current alcohol dependence, confirmed by the Mini
             International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI)

          -  DSM-IV-TR diagnosis of current major depressive disorder, confirmed by the Mini
             International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI)

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Any person who meets criteria for alcohol-induced depression

          -  Any psychotic disorder bipolar disorder, mental retardation, impaired cognitive
             functioning, or use of any psychotropic medication in the previous month

          -  Current Diagnostic and Statistical Manual (DSM-IV) criteria for dependence on
             substances other than alcohol, cannabis, nicotine, or caffeine

          -  Significant neurological conditions or medical conditions

          -  Persistent elevation of liver function enzymes indicating active liver disease
             (elevated t. bilirubin or elevation to three-time normal range of liver enzymes,
             SGOT, SGPT, or g-GTP)

          -  The presence of renal function impairment defined as serum creatinine &gt;2x upper limit
             of normal

          -  Pregnancy, inability or unwillingness to use contraceptive methods

          -  Use of any antidepressant medication in the prior two months, or any lifetime use of
             mirtazapine

          -  Inability to read or understand study forms and agree to informed consent
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jack R Cornelius, M.D., M.P.H.</last_name>
    <phone>412-246-5149</phone>
    <email>corneliusjr@upmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Maribeth A Wesesky, CMA</last_name>
    <phone>412-246-6906</phone>
    <email>weseskyma@upmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maribeth A Wesesky, C.M.A.</last_name>
      <phone>412-246-6906</phone>
      <email>weseskyma@upmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Jack R Cornelius, M.D., M.P.H.</last_name>
      <phone>412-246-5149</phone>
      <email>corneliusjr@upmc.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jack R. Cornelius, M.D., M.P.H.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 4, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 4, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Major Depressive Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Alcohol Use Disorder</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alcohol Drinking</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Mirtazapine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mianserin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
