<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02814149</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The aim of this prospective randomized controlled clinical trial is to compare the esthetic, clinical and patient-centered outcomes following immediate and early implant placement protocols.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Esthetic, Clinical and Radiographic Outcomes of Immediate and Early Implant Placement</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patients are randomized to two groups: immediate and early implant placement. The investigators are asking subjects to take part in a research study of soft tissue and bone healing around dental implants following tooth extraction. The investigators want to compare how the gums and the bone changes shape with healing in two different scenarios.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Jaw, Edentulous, Partially</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Jaw, Edentulous</mesh_term>
	<criteria>At least 18 years old and able to understand an informed consent Adequate oral hygiene to allow for implant therapy consistent with standards of care. Missing a single tooth in the maxillary anterior region Presence of adjacent natural teeth Poor oral hygiene Severe parafunctional habits, for example, bruxing and clenching Presence of clinically active periodontal disease as expressed by probing pocket depths≥4 mm in combination with bleeding on probing. Conditions that might lead to a possibly lowered regenerative capacity of the bone, for example, osteoporosis and Paget's disease Pregnant or expecting to be pregnant History of drug and alcohol abuse History of systemic diseases that would contraindicate oral surgical treatment, for example, uncontrolled diabetes (defined as HBA1c level &gt;7%) Radiotherapy in the head and neck area, On certain medications like bisphosphonates or steroids currently or within the past three months Absence of adjacent teeth Unwillingness to return for the followup examination Smokers (more than 20 cigarettes per day). Subjects smoking &lt;20 cigarettes per day were requested to stop smoking before and after surgery</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>early implant</keyword>
	<keyword>esthetics</keyword>
	<keyword>immediate implant</keyword>
	<keyword>bone augmentation</keyword>
</DOC>