<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02814123</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The closed-loop delivery system is composed of an insulin pump, a continuous glucose sensor and a dosing algorithm that calculates the insulin dose to infuse based on sensor readings. Pramlintide is a drug and an analog of amylin, a hormone that is co-secreted with insulin in healthy individuals, and is deficient in people with type 1 diabetes. Co-injection of pramlintide with insulin at meal times improves glucose control in type 1 diabetes. The purpose of this study is to compare the effectiveness of 2 strategies to control your day-and-night glucose levels: 1) insulin-plus-placebo closed-loop delivery and 2) insulin-plus-pramlintide closed-loop delivery. The hypothesis is that a basal-bolus infusion of insulin-plus-pramlintide in the closed-loop system will improve blood glucose control compared to insulin-plus-placebo infusion.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effect of Basal-Bolus Closed-Loop Co-Administration of Insulin and Pramlintide on Improving the Glycemic Control in Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The closed-loop delivery system is composed of an insulin pump, a continuous glucose sensor and a dosing algorithm that calculates the insulin dose to infuse based on sensor readings. Pramlintide is a drug and an analog of amylin, a hormone that is co-secreted with insulin in healthy individuals, and is deficient in people with type 1 diabetes. Co-injection of pramlintide with insulin at meal times improves glucose control in type 1 diabetes. The aim of the study is to assess the efficacy of the simultaneous, closed-loop, basal-bolus infusion of pramlintide and insulin with fixed ratio (i.e., mimicking co-formulation) in controlling glucose levels compared to insulin-plus-placebo closed-loop infusion. The investigators aim to conduct a double-blinded, randomized, crossover trial to compare the efficacy of insulin-plus-placebo closed-loop delivery and insulin-plus-pramlintide closed-loop delivery in regulating glucose levels over a period of 24 hours in a study of adults in inpatient settings. At a minimum of ten days prior to the closed-loop interventions, pramlintide or a placebo will be initiated (basal and bolus) using a second pump. The hypothesis is that a basal-bolus infusion of insulin-plus-pramlintide in the closed-loop system will improve blood glucose control compared to insulin-plus-placebo infusion.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Pramlintide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Islet Amyloid Polypeptide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Males and females ≥ 18 years of age. Clinical diagnosis of type 1 diabetes for at least 12 months. (The diagnosis of type 1 diabetes is based on the investigator's judgment; C peptide level and antibody determinations are not needed.) The subject will have been on insulin pump therapy for at least 6 months. HbA1c ≤ 10%. Current or ≤ 1 month use of other antihyperglycemic agents (SGLT2, GLP1, Metformin, Acarbose, etc.…). Severe hypoglycemic episode within one month of screening. Severe diabetes ketoacidosis episode within one month of screening. Planned or ongoing pregnancy. Known or suspected allergy to the study drugs. Gastroparesis. Use of prokinetic drugs that stimulate gastric emptying (domperidone, cisapride, metoclopramide). Clinically significant nephropathy, neuropathy or retinopathy as judged by the investigator. Recent (&lt; 6 months) acute macrovascular event e.g. acute coronary syndrome or cardiac surgery. Current use of glucocorticoid medication. Other serious medical illness likely to interfere with study participation or with the ability to complete the trial by the judgment of the investigator. Failure to comply with team's recommendations (e.g. not willing to eat meals/snacks, not willing to change pump parameters, etc.).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</keyword>
	<keyword>Pramlintide</keyword>
	<keyword>Artificial Pancreas</keyword>
	<keyword>Closed-Loop System</keyword>
	<keyword>Insulin</keyword>
</DOC>