<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00264654</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This study is designed to evaluate the efficacy and safety in Social Anxiety Disorder (SAD)</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Long-term Study Of Paroxetine in Women and Men</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Phobic Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paroxetine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion criteria: Diagnosis of Social Anxiety Disorder (SAD) (300.23 Social Phobia/Social Anxiety Disorder) according to DSMIVTR criteria. Must give a written informed consent. If the patient is under 20, both the patient himself/herself and his/her proxy consenter must give written informed consent. Patients have a minimum score of 60 on the LSAS total score. Exclusion criteria: Patients primarily diagnosed with a disorder that is categorized into Axis I excluding SAD by DSMIVTR (e.g. major depression, dysthymic disorder, specific phobia (simple phobia) , obsessive compulsive disorder, panic disorder) within 24 weeks before week 2. Patients with a history or complication of schizophrenia and bipolar disorder Patients with a complication of body dysmorphic disorder. Patients with evidence of substance abuse (alcohol or drugs). substance dependence by DSMIVTR criteria within 24 weeks before week 2. Patients who started psychotherapy and cognitivebehavioural therapy within 24 weeks before week2, except for supportive psychotherapy. Patients receiving electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) within 12 weeks before week 2. Patients being pregnant, lactating or are of childbearing potential and are likely to become pregnant. Patients with 3 or more points of HAMD Item No. 3, or who are likely to attempt suicide. Patients with a history or complication of cancer or malignant tumor. Patients receiving MAO inhibitors (FP®) within 14 days before expected week 0 visit date.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>May 2012</verification_date>
	<keyword>Social</keyword>
	<keyword>(SAD)</keyword>
	<keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
	<keyword>Disorder</keyword>
</DOC>