<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02871271</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the tolerability and benefit of IQP-AS-121 on reducing fatigue and tiredness and to improve mental alertness.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Tolerability and Benefit of IQP-AS-121 on Fatigue and Mental Alertness</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Caucasian males and females, 2155 years of age 2. Body mass index (BMI) 18.529.9 kg/m2 3. Generally in good health without clinically significant findings at screening 4. No chronic fatigue syndrome according to the Fukuda Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) criteria at screening 5. Subjective feeling of chronic stress and tiredness for 312 last months prior to screening 6. Screening Scale of Chronic Stress (SSCS) score &gt;18 7. Fatigue Severity Scale score &gt;4 8. ≤ 3 cups/portions of coffee and/or caffeinecontaining food/beverages per day in the 3 last months prior to screening and during the study 9. Regular stable continuous level of daily activities 10. Regular sleepwake cycle 11. Normal dietary habits according to investigator's judgement 12. ≤ moderate level of physical exercise 13. Readiness to comply with study procedures, in particular: Consumption of the IP during the treatment period Filling in all questionnaires Keep habitual diet and level of physical exercise 14. No change in smoking habits during the study 15. Women of childbearing potential only: 1. negative pregnancy testing (ßHCG in urine at screening) 2. commitment to use reliable contraception methods during the entire study Participation is based upon written informed consent form (ICF) by the participant following written and oral information by the investigator regarding nature, purpose, consequences and possible risks of the clinical study. 1. Known sensitivity to any components of the IP 2. Any medical condition associated with tiredness (e.g. iron deficiency, hypotension etc.) 3. History and/or presence of clinically significant disease, which per investigator's judgement could interfere with the results of the study or the safety of the subject: 1. Psychiatric diseases, e.g. depression, schizophrenia 2. Eating disorders such as anorexia 3. Untreated or nonstabilized metabolic diseases, e.g. diabetes mellitus 4. Untreated or nonstabilized thyroid disorder 5. Untreated or nonstabilized hypertension (systolic blood pressure ≥140 mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure ≥90 mmHg) 6. Significant gastrointestinal diseases 7. Insomnia 8. Known bleeding disorders such as haemophilia 9. Any other known significant or serious condition / disease that renders subjects ineligible (e.g. history of malignancy within the past 5 years prior to screening, any clinically significant cardiovascular, renal, liver disease etc.) 4. Use of medication which in the investigator's judgement could interfere with the results of the study (e.g. psychoactive medication, statins, proton pump inhibitors, bloodpressure medications, antihistamines, antibiotics, diuretics) within the last 4 weeks prior to screening and during the study 5. Consumption of vitamins, nutritional supplements, supplementary balanced diet, mineral products which in the investigator's judgement could interfere with the results of the study within last 4 weeks prior to screening and during the study 6. Consumption of adaptogens (e.g. ginseng or Schisandra) or St. John's Wort within last 4 weeks prior to screening and during the study 7. Consumption of energy drinks during the study 8. Start of use of contraception medication during the last 3 months prior to screening and during the study 9. Use of anticoagulants such as warfarin 10. Clinically significant deviation of laboratory parameters and/or deviations &gt; 2 x ULN (upper limit of normal) at screening 11. Recent or current significant stressors (e.g. active grieving) 12. Chronic pain 13. Chronic sleep deficiency (&lt; 5 hours/night) 14. Alcohol abuse (men: ≥21 units/week, women: ≥14 units/ week; 1 unit equals approximately 250 mL of beer, 100 mL of wine or 35 mL of spirits) 15. Drug abuse 16. Participation in another study during the last 30 days prior to screening 17. Women of childbearing potential: pregnant or breastfeeding 18. Any situation expected during the study causing acute high level of stress 19. Any other reason deemed suitable for exclusion as per investigator's judgment, e.g. insufficient compliance with study procedures</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>