<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02871011</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine the fungicidal efficacy of nitric oxide releasing solution footbath and it's effect on the clinical signs and symptoms associated with Tinea Pedis</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Nitric Oxide Releasing Solution (NORS) Footbath to Treat Athlete's Foot</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Study Type: Interventional Study Design: Allocation: Randomized Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study Intervention Model: Sequential Assignment Masking: Double Blind (Subject &amp; Assessor) Primary Purpose: Treatment</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Tinea</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Tinea Pedis</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Nitric Oxide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Endothelium-Dependent Relaxing Factors</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Positive clinical findings for moccasin, interdigital or bullous tinea pedis as determined by direct clinical examination Must have a clinical symptom severity score of at least 20 on a possible 64 point scale Written informed consent must be obtained from the subject. Must ≥ 19 years of age, for study sites located in British Columbia. For other locations the subject must be ≥ 18 years of age, unless local laws dictate otherwise. Must agree to avoid professional pedicures or application of any nail polish product or nail cosmetic to the toenails after the screening visit until the conclusion of the trial. Must agree to take measures to avoid pregnancy during the 31 day study period Has a diagnosis of either psoriasis or eczema, in or immediately around the area under evaluation. Has a visual diagnosis, by the investigator, of onychomycosis at a level, which in the opinion of the investigator could compromise the integrity of the study. Use of topical antifungals e.g. (clotrimazole, ketoconazole,miconazole, oxiconazole (Oxistat®, Glaxo Smith Kline), sulconazole, naftifine (Naftin®, Merz), terconazole, econazole nitrate (Spectazole®, OrthoMcNeil), butoconazole ,Fluconazole, ciclopirox olamine(Loprox®, Medicis), tolnaftate, haloprogin), ZeasorbAF , antibacterials and corticosteroids in the preceding 5 days of screening visit (Day 1) on or immediately around the area under evaluation. Use of systemic corticosteroids in the preceding 7 days respectively, of screening visit (Day 1) Use of systemic antifungals in the preceding 7 days of screening visit (Day1) including (terbinafine (Lamisil®, Novartis), Itraconazole (Sporanox®, Janssen), fluconazole (Diflucan®, Pfizer), ketoconazole, miconazole, griseofulvin (GrisPEG®, Pedinol), butoconazole, terconazole, Potassium iodide) Has used any investigational drug(s) within 30 days preceding screening visit (Day 1) Is pregnant or is a nursing mother Is a woman of child bearing potential who is not using an adequate form of contraception (or abstinence) Is &lt; 19 years of age, for study sites located in British Columbia. For other locations subject is &lt; 18 years of age, unless local laws dictate otherwise. Suffers from a condition, which, in the opinion of the medical investigator, would compromise his/her safety and / or the quality of the data. Such conditions may include collagen vascular disease, diabetes mellitus, Cushing's Disease, hematological malignancy, chronic mucocutaneous candidiasis or atopy</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Tinea Bronchodilator Agents</keyword>
	<keyword>Tinea Pedis</keyword>
	<keyword>Nitric Oxide</keyword>
	<keyword>Dermatomycoses</keyword>
	<keyword>Endothelium-Dependent Relaxing Factors</keyword>
	<keyword>Infectious</keyword>
	<keyword>Infection</keyword>
	<keyword>Mycoses</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Foot Dermatoses</keyword>
	<keyword>Foot Diseases</keyword>
	<keyword>Pruritus</keyword>
	<keyword>Skin Manifestations Signs and Symptoms</keyword>
</DOC>