<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02871349</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to find out how the brain of people with autism is affected by Propranolol. Propranolol is not FDA approved for the treatment of autism. Propranolol is FDA approved for the treatment of heart conditions such as blood pressure This research is being done because there are currently no drug treatment options for language impairments and social difficulties often experienced by people with autism.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Trial of Propranolol in Children and Youth With Autism Spectrum Disorder and Predictors of Response</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The specific aim of this study is to examine the effects of serial doses of propranolol on social interaction, and secondarily on language tasks, anxiety, adaptive behaviors, and global function in high functioning adults and adolescents with autism in a double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial. The investigators will also examine whether response to treatment can be predicted based upon markers of autonomic functioning, such as skin conductance, heart rate variability (HRV), and the pupillary light reflex (PLR), and whether anxiety can predict treatment response. The hypothesis is that social functioning and language abilities will benefit from serial doses of propranolol, and that those with the greatest degree of autonomic dysregulation, or the lowest functional connectivity, will demonstrate the greatest benefit from the drug.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Child Development Disorders, Pervasive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Propranolol</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Autism intelligence quotient (IQ) &gt;= 85 (if aged 1524) Native English speaker Parent or caregiver must older than 18 years and be a native English speaker Taking Alpha 2 agonists Nonautism learning disorder Other major psychiatric disorders Other neurological disorders Major head trauma Reaction to adhesives Diabetes Reactive airway disease Thyroid disease Bradyarrhythmias Unexplained syncope Pregnancy Possible interacting drugs Underweight (&lt;20kg if aged 714 years) Factors affecting ability to have an MRI (if aged 714 years)</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Autism</keyword>
	<keyword>ASD</keyword>
</DOC>