<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02602418</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Despite potent combination antiretroviral therapy, cognitive (memory and concentration) problems continue to occur in up to 50% of HIV-infected individuals, especially in older infected individuals, and those who abuse alcohol, marijuana or psychostimulants. Since no effective treatments are available to these individuals with cognitive problems, conservative estimates indicate that the cost of care for these patients could double in the next two decades. To address this urgent problem, this study will use a comprehensive approach (cognitive tests, functional MRI and several biomarkers) to evaluate whether a novel computer-based training program would improve the brain function, especially working memory and attention, in HIV-infected and infected individuals.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Neural Correlates of Working Memory Training for HIV Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The Overall Goals are to perform a double blind placebo-controlled study using Cogmed™ to determine whether this adaptive WM training program will benefit HIV-infected individuals, and whether the investigators can identify individuals who might benefit most from the WM training. Lastly, the investigators will explore how brain activation, neuroinflammation and CSF monoamine levels might be related to WM function before and after the training.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Criteria for HIVinfected participants : 1. Men or women of any ethnicity, ages&gt;18 years and able to provide informed consent, 2. HIV seropositive (with documentation from medical records), 3. Stable on an antiretroviral regimen for 6 months or will remain without antiretroviral treatment during the duration of the study. Inclusion Criteria for Seronegative (SN) healthy participants : 1. Men or women of any ethnicity, ages &gt; 18 years and able to give informed consent, 2. Seronegative for HIV Exclusion criteria : 1. History of comorbid psychiatric illness 2. Confounding neurological disorders 3. Abnormal screening laboratory tests (&gt;2 SD) that might indicate a chronic medical condition (e.g. diabetes, severe cardiac, renal or liver disorders) 4. Medications 5. Current or history of drug dependence within the past two years 6. Positive urine toxicology screen 7. Pregnancy 8. Inability to read at an 8th grade level 9. Other contraindications for MR studies</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>HIV</keyword>
	<keyword>working memory training</keyword>
	<keyword>brain function</keyword>
	<keyword>fMRI</keyword>
</DOC>