<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02879032</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Exercise treadmill test (ETT) is frequently done, inexpensive, relatively safe investigation for diagnosis of ischemic heart disease and prediction of exercise capacity. Ischemic heart disease is increasing by leaps and bounds all over the world even in the developing countries like Bangladesh. The incidence rate of coronary artery disease (CAD) is not limited to male gender as previously seen. As a cause of industrialization and increased life expectancy, incidence of ischemic heart disease in females is escalating now in Bangladesh also. Though ETT is a well accepted investigation to diagnose CAD, it has a high false positive and false negative result if ST segment response alone is calculated for interpretation of the test. Duke Treadmill Test and Simple Treadmill Test are valid and well known scores which can predict coronary artery disease burden more efficiently than ST segment response alone. Computer generated Cleveland clinic score is another valid treadmill score which has a complex algorithm but effective way to predict 3 year and 5 year survivability. These three scores are well tested on western population but to our best knowledge there is little or no information regarding their predictability of CAD in Bangladesh. It's well known that ETT has a high false positive result in female population, so applying the scores may render ETT more efficient and abrogate unwanted risk of undergoing coronary angiography to diagnose CAD in females. In this study the investigator will try to find out the accuracy of commonly applied treadmill scores and ST segment response to diagnose CAD as well as accuracy of computer generated Cleveland Clinic Score will be tested. Total 110 people including male and female will be included according to inclusion and exclusion criteria and informed written consent will be taken. The patients who have undergone ETT and coronary angiogram with in six months for confirmation and identification of coronary artery disease in accordance with the recommendation of ACC guideline for CAG will be selected . All available data will be analyzed using SPSS. The accuracy of different scores will be calculated and compared with each other. According to currently available data from studies in western population the treadmill scores will have good predictability and will be efficient to abolish high false positive result in female population in Bangladesh.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Comparative Study of Different Treadmill Scores to Diagnose Coronary Artery Disease in a Tertiary Care Hospital</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Patients undergone CAG and ETT within 6 months interval for stable ischemic heart disease. 2. Age between 3069 years 1. Any contraindication for Exercise Tolerance test 2. Previous myocardial infarction by history or ECG 3. Previous revascularization or valvular heart disease 4. Baseline abnormalities that may obscure electrocardiographic changes during exercise</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>69 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Treadmill Scores</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary Angiogram</keyword>
	<keyword>Coronary Artery Disease</keyword>
</DOC>