<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02879110</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In this proposed study, the investigators will evaluate the the efficacy, safety and related mechanism of sulforaphane in treatment of autism spectrum disorder (ASD). The study will recruit 120 ASD patients, then these patients will be randomized to sulforaphane group or placebo group (60 patients per arm) for 12 weeks clinic trial. Clinical efficacy and safety assessment will be done at screen/baseline, 4 week, 8 week and 12 week. The specific aims are to compare sulforaphane versus placebo on: 1) clinical core symptoms; 2) other behavioral problems and adaptive behaviors. Biological samples also will be collected, and stored to research related mechanisms.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A 12-weeks Study to Evaluate Sulforaphane in Treatment of Autism Spectrum Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>In this proposed study, the investigators will evaluate the the efficacy, safety and related mechanism of sulforaphane in treatment of autism spectrum disorder (ASD). The study will recruit 120 ASD patients, then these patients will be randomized to sulforaphane group or placebo group (60 patients per arm) for 12 weeks clinic trial. Clinical efficacy and safety assessment will be done at screen/baseline, 4 week, 8 week and 12 week. The specific aims are to compare sulforaphane versus placebo on: 1) clinical core symptoms; 2) other behavioral problems and adaptive behaviors. The investigators hypothesize that (1) sulforaphane is superior to placebo in the treatment of clinical symptoms in patients with ASD, measured by the Social Responsiveness Scale, Aberrant Behavior Checklist, Repetitive Behavior Scale - Revised and Ohio State University Autism Clinical Global Impression; (2) sulforaphane is superior to placebo in the treatment of other behavioral problems and adaptive behaviors patients with ASD, measured by Achenbach's Child Behavior Checklist and Adaptive Behavior Assessment System, Second Edition; and (3) Biological samples will be collected, and stored so that the hypothesis sulforaphane may alter oxidative stress indexes or inflammatory biomarkers, and influence histone deacetylase inhibitor mechanism or inflammatory mechanism et al that may be significantly correlated with clinical improvement.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Child Development Disorders, Pervasive</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Sulforafan</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Male with aged 10 to 15 years. 2. Meet DSMV diagnostic criteria for autism spectrum disorder, and been checked with Autism Diagnostic InterviewRevised (ADIR) and Autism Diagnostic Observation Schedule (ADOS). 1. With severe physical disease (i.e. congenital heart disease, thyroid disease, diseases with severe abnormality of liver or kidney function, diseases with abnormality vision or hearing et al.) 2. With severe central nervous system disease (i.e. epilepsy et al). 3. With other specific genetic syndromes (i.e. FragileX syndrome, Down's syndrome et al.)</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Sulforaphane</keyword>
	<keyword>clinic trial</keyword>
	<keyword>Autism Spectrum Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>Efficacy</keyword>
	<keyword>Safety</keyword>
	<keyword>Mechanism</keyword>
</DOC>