<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02879643</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This is a pilot study utilizing Marqibo® (vincristine sulfate liposome injection) combined with dexamethasone, mitoxantrone and asparaginase (UK ALL R3) for relapsed acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vincristine Sulfate Liposome Injection (Marqibo®) in Combination With UK ALL R3 Induction Chemotherapy for Children, Adolescents, and Young Adults With Relapsed ALL</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will utilize Marqibo® as a replacement for standard vincristine in combination with UK ALL R3 induction for children with relapsed ALL. The hypothesis is that the incorporation of Marqibo® with combination chemotherapy will be safe and feasible. In the context of this pilot study, overall outcomes and efficacy will be a secondary objective. It is hypothesized that data from this combination may show improved efficacy including, complete remission (CR), minimal residual disease (MRD) negativity, and progression free survival (PFS) rates and safety (i.e., neurotoxicity) in comparison to outcomes in historical regimens, including the UK ALL R3 with standard vincristine.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vincristine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Inclusion Eligibility Criteria Age Patients must be ≥ 1 and ≤ 21 years of age at the time of enrollment. Diagnosis Patients must have a diagnosis of acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) with ≥ 5% blasts in the bone marrow (M2 or M3), with or without extramedullary disease (excluding active Central Nervous System 3 involvement). Subjects with first relapse must have an M3 marrow to be eligible. Performance Level Karnofsky &gt; 50% for patients &gt; 16 years of age and Lansky &gt; 50% for patients ≤ 16 years of age. Prior Therapy 1. Patients must have recovered from the acute toxic effects (≤ Grade 2 or baseline) of all prior chemotherapy, immunotherapy, or radiotherapy prior to entering this study, unless otherwise specified. Subjects with disease related cytopenias will be eligible. 2. Patients must have relapsed disease after attaining at least a first remission. They may be in first to third relapse. 3. Patients with Philadelphia chromosome t(9;22) positive disease must have received at least two prior tyrosine kinase inhibitors. 4. Patients who have experienced their relapse after a Hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) are eligible, provided they have no evidence of graftversushost disease (GVHD) and are at least 100 days posttransplant at the time of enrollment. 5. Prior anthracycline lifetime cumulative exposure: Patients must have less than 320 mg/m2 (or 400 mg/m2 if prior cardioprotection) lifetime exposure of anthracycline chemotherapy. 6. Hematopoietic growth factors: It must have been at least seven days since the completion of therapy with granulocyte colonystimulating factor (GCSF) or other growth factors at the time of enrollment. It must have been at least 14 days since the completion of therapy with pegfilgrastim (Neulasta®). 7. Biologic antineoplastic agents: At least seven days after the last dose of a biologic agent. For agents that have known adverse events occurring beyond seven days after administration, this period must be extended beyond the time during which adverse events are known to occur. The duration of this interval must be discussed with the study chair or vice chair. 8. Monoclonal antibodies: At least three halflives (or 30 days—whichever is longer) of the antibody must have elapsed after the last dose of monoclonal antibody. (e.g., Rituximab = 66 days, Epratuzumab = 69 days) 9. Immunotherapy: At least 30 days after the completion of any type of immunotherapy, e.g. tumor vaccines, chimeric antigen receptor Tcells. 10. Recent prior chemotherapy: At least 14 days after standard vincristine and the completion of any type of chemotherapy induction regimen. At least 3 weeks after radiation therapy. At least 30 days after the completion of any investigational neoplastic agent is also required. An investigational agent is defined as any drug that is not approved and licensed for sale by the FDA for institutions in the United States, by Health Canada for institutions in Canada and by The Therapeutic Goods Administration for institutions in Australia. Exceptions: 1. There is no time restriction in regard to prior intrathecal chemotherapy provided there is complete recovery from any acute toxic effects of such; it is allowable to enroll a patient that has received IT Cytarabine (ARAC), IT Methotrexate (MTX) or triple IT therapy within 14 days of enrollment as part of their evaluation to diagnose disease relapse. The IT therapy given within 14 days of initiation of protocol specified chemotherapy, will substitute for the day 1 IT. 2. Subjects with rapidly progressive disease may receive hydroxyurea until they begin study therapy; 3. Patients who relapse while on maintenancetype ALL therapy or are receiving maintenance therapy for disease stabilization will not require a washout period before entry into this study. However, there must be at least 14 days after any dose of standard vincristine. Renal and Hepatic Function 1. Renal function: Patient's serum creatinine must be ≤ 1.5 x institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) according to age. If the serum creatinine is greater than 1.5 times normal, the patient must have a calculated creatinine clearance or radioisotope glomerular filtration rate (GFR) ≥ 70milliliter/min/1.73m2. Alternatively, a 24hour creatinine clearance may also be used. 2. Hepatic function: alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) must be &lt; 3 x institutional upper limit of norm ULN. Total bilirubin must be ≤ 1.5 x ULN (except in the case of subjects with documented Gilbert's disease ≤ 5 × ULN). Cardiac Function Patients must have a shortening fraction ≥ 27% or an ejection fraction ≥ 55% by echocardiogram, cardiac MRI or multigated acquisition scan (MUGA). Reproductive Function 1. Female patients must not be pregnant and those of childbearing potential must have a negative urine or serum pregnancy test confirmed within one week prior to enrollment. 2. Female patients with infants must agree not to breastfeed their infants while on this study. 3. Male and female patients of childbearing potential must agree to use an effective method of contraception during the study. Exclusion Eligibility Criteria Patients will be excluded if they have active Central Nervous System (CNS) 3 status. Patients will be excluded if they have isolated testicular disease. Patients with biphenotypic leukemia will be excluded. Patients will be excluded if they have refractory disease or fourth relapse and beyond, defined as any of the following: 1. Patients with four or more prior induction attempts, 2. Refractory disease after first or greater relapse and a reinduction attempt, 3. Failing to go into remission from original diagnosis after two previous induction attempts. Patients will be excluded if they have previously received Marqibo®. Patients will be excluded if they have a known allergy to any of the drugs used in the study, with the exception that patients with an allergy to PEGasparaginase who can receive Erwinia are eligible. Patients will be excluded if they have active, uncontrolled systemic fungal, bacterial, viral or other infection despite appropriate antibiotics or other treatment. Patients who require azole antifungal agents will be excluded. Azoles must be discontinued at least one week prior to the start of Marqibo®. Patients will be excluded if there is a plan to administer nonprotocol chemotherapy, radiation therapy, another investigational agent or immunotherapy during the study period. Patients with preexisting, persistent grade 2 or greater sensory or motor neuropathy from any cause will be excluded. Patients will be excluded if they have Down syndrome, significant concurrent disease, illness, psychiatric disorder or social issue that would compromise patient safety or adherence with the protocol treatment or procedures or interfere with consent, study participation, follow up, or interpretation of study results. Patients positive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) will be excluded due to the increased risk of complications such as severe infection and unknown interaction of Marqibo® with antiretroviral drugs. Active hepatitis B or C infection as defined by seropositive for hepatitis B (hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg)) or hepatitis C and elevated liver transaminases (defined as above the ULN per the institution normal ranges).</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>January 2017</verification_date>
</DOC>