<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02879097</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to determine whether CBT124 and Avastin® are comparable in terms of efficacy, safety, immunogenicity; and whether the pharmacokinetics of CBT124 matches that of Avastin® (pharmacokinetics is nested in this study for Indian patients).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy-Safety-Immunogenicity Study of CBT124&amp;EU-sourced Avastin® in Stage 4 NSCLC</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>The purpose of this study is to determine whether CBT124 and Avastin® are comparable in terms of efficacy, safety, immunogenicity; and whether the pharmacokinetics of CBT124 matches that of Avastin® (pharmacokinetics is nested in this study for Indian patients). To test the clinical equivalence in terms of efficacy and safety, a two-sided test approach based on a pre-specified range to test the null hypothesis that the proposed biosimilar is either (1) inferior to the reference product or (2) superior to the reference product based on the pre-specified equivalence margin will be used. The equivalence margins are chosen to enable detection of clinically meaningful differences in effectiveness between CBT124, candidate biosimilar bevacizumab and reference product (EU-sourced Avastin®) at the 95% confidence interval (CI). In this trial, asymmetric equivalence margins will be used, i.e., the upper (superiority) and the lower (inferiority) bounds of the equivalence margin are not symmetric. The goal is to reject the null hypothesis of non-equivalence and accept the alternative hypothesis that the two treatments (in this case, CBT124 and EU-sourced Avastin®) are equivalent (i.e., the differences between the two are not clinically and statistically meaningful). The hypothesis testing will be performed by determining if the difference in the primary end point (Objective Response Rate [ORR]) between the reference product (EUsourced Avastin®) and proposed biosimilar (CBT124) is within the equivalence margin at the 95% CI.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Subjects may be entered in the study only if they meet all of the following criteria: Adult subjects aged ≥ 18 to 75 years (≥ 18 to 65 years for India) with histologically or cytologically confirmed advanced nonsquamous NSCLC. Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) negative or wild type mutations Stage IV (Unresectable recurrent disease or metastatic) NSCLC Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) of 0 or 1. Evaluable disease status or measurable tumor Adequate hepatic, renal, and bone marrow function Subjects with preexisting hypertension must be well controlled on a stable regimen of antihypertensive therapy. Have systolic blood pressure ≤ 140 and ≥ 90 mmHg, diastolic blood pressure ≤ 90 and ≥ 50 mmHg and heart rate ≥ 40 and ≤ 90 bpm at screening and admission. Ability to understand risks of participation in the study and willingness provide informed consent. Subjects will not be entered in the study for any of the following reasons: Small cell lung cancer (SCLC) or combination of SCLC and NSCLC. Squamouscell tumors and mixed adenosquamous carcinomas of predominantly squamous nature Prior therapy with monoclonal antibodies or small molecule inhibitors against VEGF or VEGF receptors, including bevacizumab Prior therapy with carboplatin or paclitaxel Prior systemic therapy for metastatic disease. Prior systemic anticancer therapy or radiotherapy for locallyadvanced NSCLC if completed &lt; 12 months prior to screening Evidence of a tumor that compresses or invades major blood vessels or tumor cavitation that in the opinion of the Investigator is likely to bleed Symptomatic brain metastasis Previous malignancy other than NSCLC in the last 5 years except for basal cell cancer of the skin or preinvasive cancer of the cervix Any unresolved toxicity &gt; Common Toxicity Criteria Grade 1 (except alopecia) from previous anticancer therapy (including radiotherapy) History or evidence of inherited bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy with the risk of bleeding. Thrombotic or hemorrhagic event ≤ 6 months prior to screening History of hemoptysis greater than ½ teaspoon of bright red (fresh) blood in the past 4 weeks Subjects receiving longterm aspirin (&gt; 325 mg/day), or other nonsteroidal antiinflammatory agents, or other drugs known to inhibit platelet function, treatment with dipyridamole, ticlopidine, or clopidogrel Subjects receiving anticoagulants Subjects who plan to undergo surgery during the study period Subjects who have undergone a major surgery, or have had a significant traumatic injury within 4 weeks prior to randomization Subjects who have a significant nonhealing wound, or bone fracture within 4 weeks prior to randomization Subjects with history of gastrointestinal perforation or fistula formation Subjects with known hypersensitivity to any of the ingredients of the investigational products, or mammalian cellderived products Female subjects who are pregnant, breastfeeding, planning to be pregnant during the study, or women of childbearing potential (any woman who is not surgically sterile i.e., bilateral tubal ligation, total hysterectomy or &lt; 2 years post menopause) not using a reliable method of double contraception (e.g. condom plus diaphragm, condom or diaphragm plus spermicidal gel/foam, tubal ligation, or stable dose of hormonal contraception) throughout the study period Male subject with a partner of childbearing potential who does not consent to the use of a reliable method of double contraception Subjects with uncontrolled hypertension Subjects with active infection assessed to be clinically significant by Investigator Known history of, or positive test result for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis C virus (test for hepatitis C virus antibody [HCVAb]) or hepatitis B virus (test for Hepatitis B surface Antigen [HBsAg]) History of alcohol or substance abuse Prior treatment with any investigational drug within the 30 days prior to screening, or within 5 halflives of the drug, whichever is longer Inability to comply with study requirements Other unspecified reasons that, in the opinion of the Investigator or Sponsor, make the subject unsuitable for enrollment.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>