<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00717457</DOC>
	<brief_summary>This 3-arm study will assess the efficacy, safety and tolerability of taspoglutide compared with exenatide in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus inadequately controlled with metformin, thiazolidinedione or a combination of both. Patients will be randomized to receive taspoglutide (10mg once weekly or 10mg once weekly for 4 weeks followed by 20mg once weekly) or exenatide (5 micrograms twice daily for 4 weeks followed by 10 micrograms twice daily) in a ratio of 1:1:1 in addition to continued prestudy metformin and thiazolidinedione either alone or in combination. The anticipated time on study treatment is 3+ years, and the target sample size is &gt;500 individuals.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Taspoglutide Versus Exenatide for the Treatment of Patients With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus Inadequately Controlled With Metformin, Thiazolidinedione or a Combination of Both.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Exenatide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>2,4-thiazolidinedione</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Glucagon-Like Peptide 1</mesh_term>
	<criteria>adult patients, 1875 years of age; type 2 diabetes receiving metformin and/or pioglitazone or rosiglitazone for at least 12 weeks; HbA1c &gt;=7.0% and &lt;=10% at screening; BMI &gt;=25kg/m2 (&gt;23kg/m2 for Asians) and &lt;=45kg/m2 at screening; stable weight +/ 5% for at least 12 weeks prior to screening. history of type 1 diabetes, diabetes resulting from pancreatic injury or secondary forms of diabetes; history of acute metabolic diabetic complications within the previous 6 months; evidence of clinically significant diabetic complications; known proliferative diabetic retinopathy; myocardial infarction (MI), coronary artery bypass surgery, posttransplantation cardiomyopathy (PTCM) or stroke within the past 6 months; any abnormality in clinical laboratory test or ECG, which precludes safe involvement in the study as judged by the investigator; known hemoglobinopathy or chronic anemia; clinically significant gastrointestinal disease.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>