<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01664260</DOC>
	<brief_summary>It has been suggested that N-acetylcysteine exerts neuroprotective effects by regulating neurotransmitters and cell signaling pathways. We hypothesize that oral N-acetylcysteine augmentation will help reduce symptoms in patients with posttraumatic stress disorder as well as improve cognitive functions. We also expect that the N-acetylcysteine augmentation will induce change in structural, functional, and neurochemical aspects of the brain. In this study, we plan to conduct a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled augmentation study with N-acetylcysteine in addition to escitalopram. We will assess the efficacy and safety of the N-acetylcysteine augmentation.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Efficacy Mechanism of N-acetylcysteine in Patients With Posttraumatic Stress Disorder</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acetylcysteine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>N-monoacetylcystine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Citalopram</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Dexetimide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>2065 yearold male or female Posttraumatic stress disorder diagnosed by SCIDIV Written informed consent Medication treatment for posttraumatic stress disorder within 2 weeks Neurologic disease (eg., penetrating or open head injury, epilepsy, multiple sclerosis, brain tumor, cerebrovascular diseases) Any other axis I psychiatric disorder IQ below 80 Contraindications to magnetic resosnance imaging (e.g., pacemaker implantation, claustrophobia, etc.) Any psychotropic medication within 2 weeks Unstable medical illness or severe abnormality in laboratory test at screening assessment Women who are pregnant, breastfeeding, or planning pregnancy History of myocardial infarction within 6 months Current diagnosis of duodenal ulcer or asthma Contraindications to drugs used in the study (e.g., epilepsy, uncontrolled narrowangle glaucoma, etc.) Allergy or intolerance to the study drug</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
	<keyword>Posttraumatic Stress Disorder</keyword>
	<keyword>N-acetylcysteine</keyword>
	<keyword>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</keyword>
</DOC>