<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01664676</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Recent studies in rodents show that glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) analogues protect against diabetic nephropathy. We hypothesise that this is also the case in humans. This study will investigate the short-term effect of liraglutide (GLP-1 analogue) on the kidneys in type 2 diabetic patients. Impact on basic kidney physiological will be determined and kidney injury markers will be measured as surrogate parameters of kidney protection.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effects of Liraglutide on Kidney Function in Type 2 Diabetic Patients</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Liraglutide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Informed consent obtained before any trialrelated activities. Male gender T2DM, diagnosed according to international guidelines Age 2060 years, both included Body Mass Index (BMI): 2032 kg/m2, both included Metformin treatment Albumin/creatinine ratio &lt;25 mg/mmol Known or suspected allergy to trial product or related products Previous participation in this trial Previous treatment with GLP1 analogues or DPP4 inhibitors Current treatment with any antidiabetic drug other than metformin Poorly regulated glycemic control (HbA1c &gt; 8%) Impaired kidney function: estimated GFR &lt; 70ml/min Impaired liver function: liver parameters exceed 2 times upper normal limit Subjects with active malignancy Severe cardiac insufficiency classified according to NYHA IIIIV Unstable angina pectoris, acute myocardial infarction (AMI) within the last 12 months Severe, uncontrolled hypertension: sitting blood pressure (BP) &gt; 180/110 mmHg Antihypertensive treatment consisting of more than two different pharmaceutical products Symptoms related to benign prostate hyperplasia Claustrophobia Any metal body implants History of pancreatitis, type 1 diabetes, gastroparesis or multiple endocrine neoplasia syndrome type 2 Personal or family history of medullary thyroid carcinoma Any diseases judged by the investigator that could affect the trial Any medication judged by the investigator that could affect the trial</criteria>
	<gender>Male</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>February 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>liraglutide</keyword>
	<keyword>victoza</keyword>
	<keyword>GLP-1</keyword>
	<keyword>kidney</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetes</keyword>
	<keyword>renal</keyword>
	<keyword>diabetic nephropathy</keyword>
</DOC>