<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02593916</DOC>
	<brief_summary>To create a registry/database of patients who either have taken drugs that treat cardiovascular conditions or that have presented with cardiovascular symptoms that may be related to medication.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Response to Medication Registry</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>To create a registry/database of patients who either have taken drugs that treat cardiovascular conditions or that have presented with cardiovascular symptoms that may be related to medication. Potential enrollees are those receiving (presently or in the past) the medicine(s) of interest. Subjects will be identified from computerized Intermountain Healthcare records. Patients receiving a drug of interest, both with and without an ADE will be enrolled in approximately equal numbers. Outpatients will be contacted by mail and invited to participate. Interested subjects will be instructed to return the enclosed response card with their intent indicated. The registry coordinator will contact interested subjects and the project will be explained. Willing participants will be enrolled either in person or via mail with the assistance of the project coordinator. Persons presenting in person for enrollment will be given the choice of venipuncture or buccal swab for sample collection for DNA extraction. In all cases informed consent will be obtained before collecting samples.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Drug-Related Side Effects and Adverse Reactions</mesh_term>
	<criteria>The patient must be &gt; 18 years of age. The patient or legally authorized representative must sign a written informed consent, prior to sample collection, using a form that is approved by the local Institutional Review Board. The patient must have taken a medication of interest or have presented with a cardiovascular symptom possibly related to medication. The current medications of interest are as follows: ACE inhibitors ARBs Aldosterone Antagonists AlphaAndrenergic Agonists Anticoagulants BType Natriuretic Peptides Betablockers Calcium Channel Blockers Cardiac Glycosides Antiarrhythmics Combination Drugs Diuretics Electrolyte/Mineral Replacements Lipidlowering Medications Positive Inotropes Vasodilators/Nitrates Statins Antibiotics Anthrocyclines There are no exclusion criteria for this registry.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>December 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>