<DOC>
	<DOCNO>NCT01315704</DOCNO>
	<brief_summary>The purpose study compare characteristic gait balance measure among patient Alzheimer 's disease relate disorder separate 3 group accord stage disease ( i.e. , pre-dementia , mild moderate dementia stage ) ; determine effect anti-dementia drug vitamin D cognitive motor abnormality ; establish database Angers University Memory Centre .</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Alzheimer 's Disease Related Disorders</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Although gait disorder frequently associate Alzheimer 's disease relate disorder ( ADRD ) , study focus cognitive motor effect anti-dementia drug vitamin D. The objective study - Compare characteristic gait balance measure among patient ADRD separate 3 group accord stage disease ( i.e. , pre-dementia , mild moderate dementia stage ) - To determine effect anti-dementia drug vitamin D cognitive motor abnormality - To determine whether motor abnormality could associate cognitive impairment , specifically executive dysfunction - To establish database Angers University Memory Center .</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Apraxias</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Gait Apraxia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ergocalciferols</mesh_term>
	<criteria>All elderly patient University Memory Center Angers University Hospital . Able walk without walk aid 15 meter MiniMental Status Examination score &gt; 10 Being affiliate social security regime MiniMental Status Examination score ≤ 10 Subject suffer preexist impellent disturbance History cerebrovascular accident cerebrospinal pathology Poor workmanship write oral French language Use walk aid walking frame wheels tricycle . Acute medical surgical disease past 3 month Refusal participate ( trustworthy person ) Near visual acuity &lt; 2/10</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2011</verification_date>
</DOC>