<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00315705</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Clofarabine (injection) is approved by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for the treatment of pediatric patients 1 to 21 years old with relapsed or refractory acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) who have had at least 2 prior treatment regimens. This use is based on the induction of complete responses. Randomized trials demonstrating increased survival or other clinical benefit have not been conducted. The purpose of the phase 1 portion of this study was to determine if clofarabine added to a combination of etoposide and cyclophosphamide is safe in children with relapsed or refractory acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) or acute myelogenous leukemia (AML). The purpose of the phase 2 portion of the study was to measure the effectiveness of the combination therapy in children with ALL.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>A Study of Clofarabine in Combination With Etoposide and Cyclophosphamide in Children With Acute Leukemias.</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Clofarabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
	<criteria>NOTE: the following eligibility criteria were applicable to acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) and acute myelogenous leukemia (AML) patients for the Phase 1 portion of this study, and to ALL patients for the Phase 2 portion of the study (only ALL patients were allowed in the Phase 2 portion of the study). ALL with &gt; 25% blasts in bone marrow; AML with ≥ 5% blasts in bone marrow; ALL and AML patients may have extramedullary disease Karnofsky Performance Status ≥ 50 for patients &gt; 10 years old; Lansky Performance Status ≥ 50 for patients ≤ 10 years old Prior therapy: AML: 12 prior induction regimens and ≤ 1 hematopoietic stem cell transplant (HSCT); ALL: 13 prior induction regimens Adequate liver, renal, pancreatic, and cardiac function Have received no prior HSCT (study amended in Phase 2 to exclude patients with prior HSCT) NOTE: the following eligibility criteria were applicable to ALL and AML patients for the Phase 1 portion of this study, and to ALL patients for the Phase 2 portion of the study (only ALL patients were allowed in the Phase 2 portion of the study). Burkitt's leukemia Previous treatment with clofarabine Uncontrolled systemic fungal, bacterial or other infection and 48 hrs negative blood cultures required for patients with a history of fever within 3 days of enrollment Active CNS involvement (i.e., should be CNS1 or CNS2) Inadequate time since last therapy: ≤ 14 days since last cytotoxic chemotherapy; ≤ 7 days since last biologic therapy; ≤ 14 days since last monoclonal antibody therapy Have received prior HSCT (study amended in Phase 2 to exclude patients with prior HSCT) Pregnant or lactating Have tested positive for hepatitis B or hepatitis C infection or history of cirrhosis</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2014</verification_date>
	<keyword>clofarabine</keyword>
	<keyword>acute leukemia</keyword>
	<keyword>ALL</keyword>
	<keyword>AML</keyword>
	<keyword>clolar</keyword>
	<keyword>CLO218</keyword>
</DOC>