<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01391351</DOC>
	<brief_summary>In order to search for predictors of response to chemotherapy in patients with ovarian carcinoma of the ovary, the fallopian tube or peritoneal serous-type advanced stage, we will define the comparative profiles of miRNA expression of serum polymorphisms and determine differential in 2 patient populations (with or without recurrence 6 months after completion of chemotherapy) with (i) the miRNA profile of serum before treatment and (ii) identification of polymorphisms or SNP (Single Nucleotide Polymorphism) in particular genes involved in the metabolism of chemotherapy agents In the case of miRNA, expression profiles will also be studied during the first course in response to chemotherapy. Indeed, the miRNA profile of serum may be different at baseline among the 2 types of populations (or non-recurrence at 6 months).</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Search for Predictors of Therapeutic Response in Ovarian Carcinoma</brief_title>
	<detailed_description />
	<mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Fallopian Tube Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms, Glandular and Epithelial</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Patients with cancer of the ovary, peritoneum or of the fallopian tube Stage III or IV Cancer of serous histology Patients of any chemotherapy naive Patients should receive treatment with chemotherapy for first line by Taxol Carboplatin. Avastin is authorized in concomitant. An initial surgery or through authorized Patients who signed informed consent Patients over the age of 18 years Patients being treated for another cancer chemotherapy and / or hormone therapy Patients receiving other chemotherapy Taxolcarboplatin associated or not to avastin Patients under guardianship Previous history of pelvic radiotherapy History of malignancy blood</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>July 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>carcinoma of the ovary, the fallopian tube or peritoneal serous-type advanced stage</keyword>
	<keyword>chemotherapy with Taxol and Carboplatin</keyword>
	<keyword>predictors of therapeutic response</keyword>
	<keyword>serum miRNA</keyword>
	<keyword>identification of polymorphisms or SNPs (Single Nucleotide Polymorphism)</keyword>
</DOC>