<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT01391871</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to compare vascular healing of the stented segment after deployment of new PRO-Kinetic drug eluting stent and Endeavor Resolute zotarolimus-eluting stent in patients with acute coronary syndromes requiring percutaneous coronary intervention.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Vascular Healing of DES at 3 Months</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Objective: The aim of the trial is to compare vascular healing and vasodilation at 3 months after deployment of PRO-Kinetic drug-eluting stent and Endeavor Resolute zotarolimus-eluting stent in patients with acute coronary syndrome. Design: A prospective, randomized and controlled study comparing coronary flow reserve and coverage of the PRO-Kinetic DES and Endeavor Resolute DES implanted in acute coronary syndrome. OCT and CFR measurement at 3 months. Clinical follow up is scheduled at 3, 6 and 12 months. Primary endpoint: Uncovered stent struts and CFR at 3 months after stent implantation. Secondary clinical endpoints: MACE and stent thrombosis. Enrollment: 40 patients (20 receiving PRO-Kinetic DES and 20 receiving Endeavor Resolute DES).</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Acute Coronary Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>STEMI or NSTEMI or unstable angina Patient or legally authorized representative has been informed of the nature of the study, agrees to its provisions and has been provided written informed consent, approved by the appropriate Medical Ethics committee or Institutional Review Board. Single de novo or nonstented restenosis lesion of LAD Patients with twovessel disease may have undergone successful treatment of the nontarget vessel with approved devices up to and including the index procedure but must be treated prior to the index target vessel treatment. Target lesion (maximum 20 mm length by visual estimate) to be covered by a single stent of maximum 23mm length. Reference vessel diameter must be &gt;2.5mm and &lt;4.0mm by visual estimate. The vessel diameter should be measured after predilation procedure and after intracoronary nitroglycerin if vasospasm is suspected. Target lesion &gt;50% and &lt;100% stenosed by visual estimate. Preexisting diagnosis of diabetes irrespective of its type. Impaired renal function (serum creatinine &gt;177micromol/l) or on dialysis Platelet count &lt; 10 e5 cells/mm3 Patient has a history of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy or patients in whom antiplatelet and and/or anticoagulation therapy is contraindicated. Patient has received organ transplant or is on a waiting list for any organ transplant. Patient has a known hypersensitivity or contraindication to aspirin, heparin/bivalirudin, clopidogrel/prasugrel, stainless steel alloy, or contrast agent that cannot be adequately premedicated. Patient presents with cardiogenic shock. Any significant medical condition which in the Investigator's opinion may interfere with the patient's optimal participation in the study. Currently participating in another investigational drug or device study. Unprotected left main disease. Ostial target lesions. Chronic total occlusion. Calcified target lesions that cannot be adequately predilated. Target lesion has excessive tortuosity unsuitable for stent delivery and deployment. Target lesion involving bifurcation with a side branch larger than 2.0mm in diameter. A &gt;30% stenosis proximal or distal to the target lesion that cannot be covered with the same stent.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>August 2013</verification_date>
</DOC>