<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02707679</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Patellofemoral Pain Syndrome (PFPS), also known as the anterior knee pain, is one of the most common musculoskeletal disorders. Most of the patients suffer from knee pain for long time. The aim of this study was to investigate the short-term effects of Mobilization with movement and Kinesiotaping on pain, function and balance in patient with PFPS.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Comparison of Effects of Mobilization With Movement and Kinesiotaping in Patellofemoral Pain Syndrome</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Patellofemoral Pain Syndrome is one of the most common musculoskeletal problem in the world. It's incidence is also becoming higher and most people who have knee pain suffer from it for long time. In the treatment of PFPS, conservative treatment methods are preferred prior to surgical ones. When the literature was reviewed, no study in which Mobilization with movement (MWM) method was used and in which the effects of it was shown and compared with (Kinesiotaping) KT has been found so far with respect to the treatment of PFPS. Thirty-five female patients diagnosed with unilateral PFPS were randomly assigned into 2 groups. The patients in the first group (n=18) received two techniques of Mobilization with movement intervention while Kinesiotaping was applied to the other group (n=17). Both groups were treated with exercise. All patients received 4 sessions of treatment twice a week for a period of 2 weeks and followed up in accordance with a 6-week-home exercise program. Primary outcomes: pain severity, knee range of motion, hamstring flexibility, and physical performance (10-step stair climbing test, timed up and go test), Kujala Patellofemoral Pain Scoring and Y-Balance test were assessed.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Somatoform Disorders</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Patellofemoral Pain Syndrome</mesh_term>
	<criteria>having knee pain at least 3 months and more than 3 points according to visual analog scale no complying to the rehabilitation if patient wants to finished and want to complete study, they were excluded having meniscus, bursa, ligament, patellar tendon lesions, patellofemoral dislocation and/or recurrent subluxation, undergone lower extremity surgery</criteria>
	<gender>Female</gender>
	<minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>Knee</keyword>
	<keyword>Mobilization</keyword>
	<keyword>Taping</keyword>
	<keyword>Function</keyword>
	<keyword>Balance</keyword>
</DOC>