<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02961517</DOC>
	<brief_summary>Questionnaire study to investigate the effect of individual characteristics such as age, sex, ethnicity, educational level and socioeconomic status on the preferred format of patient education delivery, for patients with diabetes and/or cardiovascular disease</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Format of Patient Education for Different Sociodemographic Groups</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>An anonymous questionnaire will be used to collect basic demographic data for patients with the conditions of interest, in addition to information about their preferences for the format in which they receive patient education information. This data will be statistically analysed to address the primary and secondary outcomes of the study: 1. To investigate the effect of individual characteristics such as age, sex, ethnicity, educational level and socioeconomic status on the preferred format of patient education delivery. 2. To identify reasons for preference of patient education delivery, and whether these are associated with sociodemographic factors. 3. To assess the distribution of sociodemographic factors from participants who prefer online education, in order to identify whether preference for online education is associated with particular sociodemographic factors.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
	<criteria>Aged 18 years or over. Diagnosed with cardiovascular disease (defined as heart disease, peripheral vascular disease or stroke) or Type 2 diabetes Has not already completed the questionnaire Able and willing to complete questionnaire Participant unable or unwilling to complete questionnaire Under the age of 18 Not diagnosed with any of the conditions of interest Participant has already completed the questionnaire Unable to communicate (assisted or otherwise) in written English</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
</DOC>