<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT02961101</DOC>
	<brief_summary>The purpose of this study is to assess the feasibility, safety, and efficacy of anti-PD-1 antibody in combination with low-dose decitabine in patients with relapsed or refractory malignancies, including Non-Hodgkin'lymphoma, anti-PD-1-resistant Hodgkin'lymphoma, gastrointestinal cancers, hepatocellular carcinoma, breast cancer, ovarian cancer or lung cancer or renal-cell cancer or pancreatic cancer or bile duct cancer.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Anti-PD-1 Antibody in Combination With Low-dose Decitabine in Relapsed or Refractory Malignancies</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>Primary objective: To assess the feasibility and safety for Anti-PD-1 antibody in combination with decitabine administered every 3 weeks to subjects with relapsed or refractory malignancies. Secondary objectives: 1) To assess the antitumor activity of Anti-PD-1 antibody in combination with decitabine in subjects with relapsed or refractory malignancies. 2) To characterize the immunological effects of Anti-PD-1 antibody in combination with decitabine. 3) To characterize the immunological effects of Anti-PD-1 antibody in combination with decitabine. Exploratory objectives: 1) To analysis of potential biological parameters correlated to clinical response and toxicities. 2) To search predictive biomarkers to guide the choose of patients undergoing the treatment of Anti-PD-1 antibody in combination with decitabine. Safety Evaluation: Adverse events will be assessed continuously during the study and for 100 days post last treatment,and will be evaluated according to the NCI CTCAE Version 4.0. Efficacy Evaluation: 1) Treatment response to lymphoma was defined using the International Workshop to Standardize Response Criteria for non-Hodgkin's Lymphomas; 2) Treatment response to solid tumors was defined using Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST1.1). evaluation index: BOR; ORR; PFS and OS.</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Decitabine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Azacitidine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Subjects must have histological confirmation of relapsed or refractory malignancies,including NonHodgkin'lymphoma, antiPD1resistant Hodgkin'lymphoma, gastrointestinal cancers, hepatocellular carcinoma, breast cancer, ovarian cancer or lung cancer or renalcell cancer or pancreatic cancer or bile duct cancer. 2. 12 to 80 years of age. 3. ECOG performance of less than 2. 4. Life expectancy of at least 3 months. 5. Subjects with lymphoma must have at least one measureable lesion &gt;1 cm as defined by lymphoma response criteria; with solid tumors must have at least one measureable lesion &gt;1 cm per RECIST1.1. 6. Subjects must have received at least two prior chemotherapy regimen, and must be off therapy for at least 4 weeks prior to Day 1. Subjects with autologous hematopoietic stemcell transplantation are eligible which must be more than 3 months. 7. Subjects must have adequate bone marrow, live, renal, lung and heart functions. 1. Absolute neutrophil count greater than or equal to 1,000/μL. 2. Platelet count greater than or equal to 70,000/µL. 3. Serum bilirubin level less than or equal to 1.5 x upper limits of normal (ULN). 4. Serum creatinine less than or equal to 1.5 x ULN. 5. Alanine aminotransferase [ALT or SGPT] and aspartate aminotransferase [AST or SGOT] less than or equal to 2.5 x ULN. 1. Subjects with any autoimmune disease or history of syndrome that requires corticosteroids or immunosuppressive medications. 2. Serious uncontrolled medical disorders or active infections, pulmonary and intestinal infection especially. 3. Active alimentary tract hemorrhage or history of alimentary tract hemorrhage in 1 month . 4. Prior organ allograft. 5. Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding. 6. Subjects who are compulsorily detained for treatment of either a psychiatric or physical (eg, infectious disease) illness.</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
	<keyword>relapsed or refractory</keyword>
	<keyword>malignancies</keyword>
	<keyword>decitabine</keyword>
	<keyword>anti-PD-1 antibody</keyword>
</DOC>