<DOC>
	<DOC>NCT00540202</DOC>
	<brief_summary>We will test the hypothesis that there is a difference in effectiveness of oral quinine in comparison to artemether Lumefantrine in the treatment of uncomplicated malaria in children.</brief_summary>
	<brief_title>Effectiveness of Oral Quinine and Artemether-Lumefantrine in the Treatment of Uncomplicated Malaria in Ugandan Children</brief_title>
	<detailed_description>This study will be designed as an open randomized effectiveness study assessing the parasitological and clinical cure rates and adherence to oral quinine monotherapy in comparison to artemether-Lumefantrine. We will also describe some of the adverse events to the two drugs.The measurements will include age, sex, weight, hemoglobin levels on days 0, 7, 14 and 28, parasite density on days 0, 7, 14 and 28 and clinical examination findings. Adverse events will also be documented</detailed_description>
	<mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Lumefantrine</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artemether</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artemisinins</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Artemether-lumefantrine combination</mesh_term>
	<mesh_term>Quinine</mesh_term>
	<criteria>1. Aged between 6 and 59 months of age seen at the assessment centre during the study period 2. With fever defined as axillary temperature ≥37.5 °C or history of fever in the past 24 h 3. With a microscopically confirmed monoinfection of Plasmodium falciparum 4. Able to tolerate oral therapy, 5. Whose parents/guardians have provided written informed consent. 1. Children with a history of allergy to quinine, artemetherLumefantrine or milk. 2. Evidence of severe malaria. 3. Residence at more than 20km from the health clinic. 4. Evidence of a significant concomitant febrile illness that would require hospitalization or chronic medical illness</criteria>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
	<verification_date>October 2007</verification_date>
	<keyword>Effectiveness</keyword>
	<keyword>Oral quinine</keyword>
	<keyword>Coartem</keyword>
	<keyword>Uncomplicated malaria</keyword>
	<keyword>Children</keyword>
</DOC>